<?xml version="1.0"?><!DOCTYPE legisdoc SYSTEM "c:\program files\epic\custom\doctypes\legisdoc\legisdoc.dtd"><legisdoc xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" doc-id="docID" public-private="private"><metadata><doc-state state="none"></doc-state></metadata><article id="dummy"><section id=":c11c:::::1:" db-date="20060801"><enum>1.</enum>
<text>The General Assembly of Maryland, by public local law, may authorize the Mayor and City Council of Baltimore:</text>
<subsection id=":c11c:::::1:a:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(a)</enum>
<text>Within the City of Baltimore to acquire land and property of every kind, and any right, interest, franchise, easement or privilege therein, by purchase, lease, gift, condemnation or any other legal means, for storing, parking and servicing self&ndash;propelled vehicles, provided, that no petroleum products shall be sold or offered for sale at any entrance to or exit from, any land so acquired or at any entrance to, or exit from, any structure erected thereon, when any entrance to, or exit from, any such land or structure faces on a street or highway which is more than 25 feet wide from curb to curb; and</text>
</subsection><subsection id=":c11c:::::1:b:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(b)</enum>
<text>To sell, lease, convey, transfer or otherwise dispose of any of said land or property, regardless of whether or not it has been developed, redeveloped, altered, or improved and irrespective of the manner or means in or by which it may have been acquired, to any private, public or quasi public corporation, partnership, association, person or other legal entity.</text>
<text>No land or property taken by the Mayor and City Council of Baltimore for any of the aforementioned purposes or in connection with the exercise of any of the powers which may be granted to the Mayor and City Council of Baltimore pursuant to this Article by exercising the power of eminent domain, shall be taken without just compensation, as agreed upon between the parties, or awarded by a jury, being first paid or tendered to the party entitled to such compensation.</text>
<text>All land or property needed, or taken by the exercise of the power of eminent domain, by the Mayor and City Council of Baltimore for any of the aforementioned purposes or in connection with the exercise of any of the powers which may be granted to the Mayor and City Council of Baltimore pursuant to this Article is hereby declared to be needed or taken for a public use.</text>
</subsection></section><section id=":c11c:::::2:" db-date="20060801"><enum>2.</enum>
<text>The General Assembly of Maryland may grant to the Mayor and City Council of Baltimore any and all additional power and authority necessary or proper to carry into full force and effect any and all of the specific powers which the General Assembly is authorized to grant to the Mayor and City Council of Baltimore pursuant to this Article and to fully accomplish any and all of the purposes and objects contemplated by the provisions of this Article, provided such additional power or authority is not inconsistent with the terms and provisions of this Article or with any other provision or provisions of the Constitution of Maryland. The General Assembly may place such other and further restrictions or limitations on the exercise of any of the powers which it may grant to the Mayor and City Council of Baltimore under the provisions of this Article as it may deem proper and expedient.</text>
</section><section id=":c11c:::::3:" db-date="20060801"><enum>3.</enum>
<text>In addition to the powers granted and exercised under Sections 1 and 2, the Mayor and City Council of Baltimore may, by ordinance, borrow money to finance the establishment, construction, erection, alteration, expansion, enlarging, improving, equipping, repairing, maintaining, operating, controlling, and regulating of off&ndash;street parking facilities owned or to be owned by the Mayor and City Council of Baltimore, and evidence such borrowing by the issuance of revenue bonds, notes or other obligations to be secured by a pledge of the revenues derived from such facilities, and may further pledge revenues collected from parking taxes, parking fees or charges, parking fines or any other revenue derived from the parking of motor vehicles in the City of Baltimore to or for the payment of such revenue bonds, notes or other obligations; and for such purposes the Commissioners of Finance are empowered to maintain a fund consisting of the revenue pledged herein. The bonds, notes or other obligations issued hereunder and the pledge of revenues, taxes, fees, charges or fines provided for herein shall not constitute a general obligation of nor a pledge of the faith and credit or taxing power of the Mayor and City Council of Baltimore and shall not constitute a debt of the Mayor and City Council of Baltimore within the meaning of Section 7 of Article XI of the Constitution of Maryland. The ordinance may prescribe the form and terms of the bonds, notes or other obligations, the time and manner of public or private sale thereof, and the method and terms of payment therefor, and may authorize the Commissioners of Finance by resolution to determine any matters hereinabove recited and to do any and all things necessary or appropriate in connection with the issuance and sale thereof.</text>
</section></article></legisdoc>