<?xml version="1.0"?><!DOCTYPE legisdoc SYSTEM "c:\program files\epic\custom\doctypes\legisdoc\legisdoc.dtd"><legisdoc xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" doc-id="docID" public-private="private"><metadata><doc-state state="none"></doc-state></metadata><article id="dummy"><section id=":g19::35:::35:" db-date="20060801"><enum>35.</enum>
<text>Each county, incorporated city or town, and taxing district situated within this State, if it has not already done so on or before June 30, 1966, shall adopt as its period for recording and reporting all of its fiscal transactions, the fiscal year defined in Article 24, &sect; 1-102 of the Code, as amended from time to time. Each county, incorporated city or town and taxing district shall thereafter keep and maintain its books, records, journals, and fiscal reports by such method or methods as will permit the accounting and reporting of all data, statistics, and financial information contained therein for this fiscal period, and it shall be the fiscal year for all such political subdivisions.</text>
</section><section id=":g19::35:::36:" db-date="20060801"><enum>36.</enum>
<text>Each county and each incorporated city or town and taxing district within this State shall maintain the uniform system of financial reporting provided by the Department of Legislative Services.</text>
</section><section db-date="20120611" id=":g19::35:::37:"><enum>37.</enum><subsection db-date="20120611" id=":g19::35:::37:a:"><enum>(a)</enum><paragraph db-date="20120611" id=":g19::35:::37:a:1:"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, each county, municipal corporation, and taxing district in the State shall by the first day of November after the close of the fiscal year file with the Department of Legislative Services its financial report covering the full period of that fiscal year.</text></paragraph><paragraph db-date="20120611" id=":g19::35:::37:a:2:"><enum>(2)</enum><subparagraph db-date="20120611" id=":g19::35:::37:a:2:i:"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Each county, municipal corporation, or taxing district with a population of more than 400,000 may by the first day of January after the close of the fiscal year file with the Department of Legislative Services its financial report covering the full period of that fiscal year.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph db-date="20120611" id=":g19::35:::37:a:2:ii:"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Unless subparagraph (i) of this paragraph applies, Howard County may by the first day of December after the close of the fiscal year file with the Department of Legislative Services its financial report covering the full period of that fiscal year.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph db-date="20120611" id=":g19::35:::37:a:2:iii:"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>Calvert County may by the first day of January after the close of the fiscal year file with the Department of Legislative Services its financial report covering the full period of that fiscal year.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph db-date="20120611" id=":g19::35:::37:a:2:iv:"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>Frederick County may by the first day of January after the close of the fiscal year file with the Department of Legislative Services its financial report covering the full period of that fiscal year.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph db-date="20120611" id=":g19::35:::37:a:2:v:"><enum>(v)</enum><text>Queen Anne&rsquo;s County may by the first day of January after the close of the fiscal year file with the Department of Legislative Services its financial report covering the full period of that fiscal year.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph db-date="20120611" id=":g19::35:::37:a:2:vi:"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>St. Mary&rsquo;s County may by the first day of January after the close of the fiscal year file with the Department of Legislative Services its financial report covering the full period of that fiscal year.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph db-date="20120611" id=":g19::35:::37:a:2:vii:"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>Wicomico County may by the first day of January after the close of the fiscal year file with the Department of Legislative Services its financial report covering the full period of that fiscal year.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection db-date="20120611" id=":g19::35:::37:b:"><enum>(b)</enum><text>The reports required by subsection (a) of this section shall be:</text><paragraph db-date="20120611" id=":g19::35:::37:b:1:" role="item"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Properly filled in on the form or forms established by the Department as provided in this subtitle; and</text></paragraph><paragraph db-date="20120611" id=":g19::35:::37:b:2:" role="item"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Verified by the chief executive officer of each county, municipal corporation, and taxing district.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id=":g19::35:::38:" db-date="20060801"><enum>38.</enum>
<text>Should any county or any incorporated city or town or taxing district situated within this State fail or refuse to adopt or to continue in use the uniform system of municipal financial reporting applicable to it as provided in this subtitle, the Comptroller, after notification by the Executive Director of the Department of Legislative Services of such failure or refusal, shall be authorized to order the discontinuance of payment of all funds, grants or State aid which said county, incorporated city or town or taxing district is entitled to receive under State law. This section shall have specific reference to all funds, grants or State aid which said county or incorporated city or town or taxing district is entitled to receive under applicable provisions of State law relating to the income tax, the tax on racing, the recordation tax, the admissions and amusement tax and the license tax.</text>
</section><section id=":g19::35:::39:" db-date="20060801"><enum>39.</enum>
<text>Should any county or incorporated city or town or taxing district situated within this State fail or refuse to file with the Department of Legislative Services, within the time herein prescribed the financial report or reports as provided in this subtitle, the Comptroller, acting upon the advice of the Executive Director of the Department, shall be authorized to order the discontinuance of payment of all funds, grants or State aid which said county, incorporated city or town or taxing district is entitled to receive under State law. This section shall have specific reference to all funds, grants, or State aid which said county, incorporated city or town or taxing district is entitled to receive under applicable provisions of State law relating to the income tax, the tax on racing, the recordation tax, the admissions and amusement tax, and the license tax.</text>
</section><section db-date="20090618" id=":g19::35:::40:"><enum>40.</enum><subsection db-date="20090618" id=":g19::35:::40:a:"><enum>(a)</enum><paragraph db-date="20090618" id=":g19::35:::40:a:1:"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, each county, municipal corporation, and taxing district created by and situated within the State shall have its books, accounts, records, and reports examined at least once during each fiscal year by the persons and for the purposes specified in this section. The examination shall be made by a certified public accountant in the capacity of either an independent auditor or official auditor of any county or municipal corporation. The auditor shall be in compliance with the provisions of the Maryland Public Accountancy Act. The official auditor shall be approved by the Legislative Auditor for the purposes specified in this section. On such examination, inquiry shall be made into the methods, accuracy, and legality of the accounts, records, files, and reports of each county, municipal corporation, and taxing district. The Legislative Auditor upon the Legislative Auditor&rsquo;s own initiative may review or audit the books, records, and reports of any county, municipal corporation, or taxing district. Any county, municipal corporation, or taxing district may request the Legislative Auditor to audit its books, records, and reports. If the request is approved, the costs of the examination shall be borne by the auditee. The results of the audit shall be reported, subject to &sect; 2&ndash;1246 of the State Government Article, to the Legislative Auditor on such form or forms and in such manner as the Legislative Auditor may prescribe. This report shall be made to the Legislative Auditor by the date the county&rsquo;s, municipal corporation&rsquo;s, or taxing district&rsquo;s financial report is required to be submitted under &sect; 37 of this subtitle. An audit report filed with the Legislative Auditor is a public record under the provisions of &sect; 10&ndash;611 of the State Government Article. Each year the Legislative Auditor shall review the audit reports submitted and shall make a full and detailed report in writing to the State Comptroller and, subject to &sect; 2&ndash;1246 of the State Government Article, to the Executive Director of the State Department of Legislative Services of the result of the examination of the books, accounts, records, and reports of each county, municipal corporation, and taxing district, together with such suggestions as the Legislative Auditor may think advisable to be made with respect to methods of bookkeeping, changes in the uniform system of financial reporting, and changes in the reports of the counties, municipal corporations, and taxing districts. In conducting the reviews specified in this section, the Legislative Auditor may review the working papers and other documentation of the auditor. As a result of the Legislative Auditor&rsquo;s reviews, audit reports, working papers, or other documentation may be referred to the State Board of Public Accountancy for action as prescribed in the Maryland Public Accountancy Act. It shall also be the duty of the Legislative Auditor to report all violations by any county, municipal corporation, and taxing district of the requirement and provisions specified in the sections of this subtitle to the State Comptroller and, subject to &sect; 2&ndash;1246 of the State Government Article, to the Executive Director of the State Department of Legislative Services. Should any county or municipal corporation, or taxing district fail or refuse to file the audit reports as provided in this section with the Legislative Auditor within the time prescribed or fail or refuse to submit an audit report including financial statements that have been prepared in accordance with generally accepted accounting principles and audited in accordance with generally accepted auditing standards, the State Comptroller, acting upon the advice of the Executive Director of the State Department of Legislative Services, shall be authorized to order the discontinuance of payment of all funds, grants, or State aid which the county, municipal corporation, or taxing district is entitled to receive under State law. This provision shall have specific reference to all funds, grants, or State aid which the county, municipal corporation, or taxing district is entitled to receive under applicable provisions of State law distributed by the State Comptroller, the clerks of the court, or other units of State government.</text></paragraph><paragraph db-date="20090618" id=":g19::35:::40:a:2:"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Unless the Legislative Auditor determines, on a case&ndash;by&ndash;case basis, that more frequent audits are required, the Legislative Auditor may authorize a municipal corporation or taxing district created by the State with annual revenues of less than $250,000 in the prior 4 fiscal years to have an audit conducted once every 4 years.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection db-date="20090618" id=":g19::35:::40:b:"><enum>(b)</enum><text>Each county shall establish uniform rules and regulations for the examination and auditing of the books, accounts, and records of every special taxing district created by and situated within the county which:</text><paragraph db-date="20090618" id=":g19::35:::40:b:1:" role="item"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Is not subject to the provisions of subsection (a) of this section;</text></paragraph><paragraph db-date="20090618" id=":g19::35:::40:b:2:" role="item"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Receives moneys which were collected by the county from a county property tax levy imposed at the request of the special taxing district;</text></paragraph><paragraph db-date="20090618" id=":g19::35:::40:b:3:" role="item"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Has annual expenditures of over $250,000; and</text></paragraph><paragraph db-date="20090618" id=":g19::35:::40:b:4:" role="item"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Has moneys disbursed and expended by a person or body independent of the county government.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection db-date="20090618" id=":g19::35:::40:c:"><enum>(c)</enum><text>At a minimum, the rules and regulations required by subsection (b) of this section shall provide for the examination and audit to:</text><paragraph db-date="20090618" id=":g19::35:::40:c:1:" role="item"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Be conducted by a certified public accountant in the capacity of either an independent auditor or official auditor of the county who shall be in compliance with the provisions of the Maryland Public Accountancy Act or by an auditing committee approved by the official auditor of the county;</text></paragraph><paragraph db-date="20090618" id=":g19::35:::40:c:2:" role="item"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Determine whether tax funds have been received, deposited and disbursed in accordance with approved appropriations and State and local law;</text></paragraph><paragraph db-date="20090618" id=":g19::35:::40:c:3:" role="item"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Include the following financial statements:</text><subparagraph db-date="20090618" id=":g19::35:::40:c:3:i:" role="item"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Balance sheet;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph db-date="20090618" id=":g19::35:::40:c:3:ii:" role="item"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Statement of revenues;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph db-date="20090618" id=":g19::35:::40:c:3:iii:" role="item"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>Statement of expenditures and encumbrances; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph db-date="20090618" id=":g19::35:::40:c:3:iv:" role="item"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>Statement of changes in fund balance; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph db-date="20090618" id=":g19::35:::40:c:4:" role="item"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Be completed and filed with the appropriate county officials not later than 90 days following the close of the fiscal year.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection db-date="20090618" id=":g19::35:::40:d:"><enum>(d)</enum><text>For a special district created by and situated within the county with annual expenditures of less than $250,000, the county shall require annual financial reports and shall require an audit every 4 years, unless the county determines, on a case&ndash;by&ndash;case basis, that more frequent audits are required.</text></subsection><subsection db-date="20090618" id=":g19::35:::40:e:"><enum>(e)</enum><text>If a special district subject to subsection (b) or (d) of this section does not submit a financial report or audit report as required by the county, the county may withhold the distributions of taxes imposed on behalf of the special district until the financial report and/or audit report is received.</text></subsection><subsection db-date="20090618" id=":g19::35:::40:f:"><enum>(f)</enum><text>At the time it forwards its audit report to the Legislative Auditor, the county also shall forward copies of all audit reports and financial reports received from the special districts subject to subsection (b) or (d) of this section, together with a separate report to the Legislative Auditor on the results of the county&rsquo;s review of each district&rsquo;s compliance with the provisions of subsections (b) through (e) of this section. The Legislative Auditor shall review the audit reports and information received from the county and submit recommendations as appropriate based on the results of the review.</text></subsection></section><section id=":g19::35:::41:" db-date="20060801"><enum>41.</enum>
<text>If the Legislative Auditor shall make the examination of the books, accounts, records and reports of the counties, incorporated cities or towns and taxing districts as provided in this subtitle, the expense incurred in making the examination shall be paid by the county, incorporated city or town and taxing district for which the examination has been made. As soon as is practical after such examination has been concluded, the Legislative Auditor shall certify the total expense thereof to the proper official of each county, incorporated city or town and taxing district who shall thereafter issue his warrant for the payment of the same to the State Comptroller.</text>
</section></article></legisdoc>