<?xml version="1.0"?><!DOCTYPE legisdoc SYSTEM "c:\program files\epic\custom\doctypes\legisdoc\legisdoc.dtd"><legisdoc xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" doc-id="docID" public-private="private"><metadata><doc-state state="none"></doc-state></metadata><article id="dummy"><section id=":g23::III:140::140:" db-date="20061025"><enum>140.</enum><text>If any corporation formed under the provisions of this article shall desire to erect any bridge over any river, creek or stream of water in this State, or between this and another state, or shall desire to dig, construct or maintain any canal for transportation by means of water, the said corporation must have obtained or shall first obtain the consent, in writing, of the county commissioners of the county in which said bridge or said canal may be proposed to be located; or if said bridge be proposed to be erected over a stream dividing two counties, or if the said canal be proposed to be dug, constructed or maintained through or over the lands of two or more counties, then such corporation shall obtain the consent, in writing, of the county commissioners of both of said counties; and the resolution of the said county commissioners giving said consent shall be recorded amongst the proceedings of said commissioners, and also in the journal or book of proceedings of said corporation.</text></section>
<section id=":g23::III:140::141:" db-date="20061025"><enum>141.</enum><text>The corporation may agree with the owners for the lands or property of any kind whatsoever, or interest therein, necessary for the abutments of the bridge and the lands necessary for the digging, constructing and maintaining of a canal, and for roads and ways thereto, and for earth or stone required in the construction of said bridge or of said canal and of said ways, approaches, terminals, docks and wharves; and the rights acquired by agreement shall be conveyed by deed, duly acknowledged and recorded. In case of failure to agree, or of disability of the owners to contract, or of their absence from the State, the corporation may obtain the lands, or property of any kind, or interest therein, earth and stone by condemnation. The corporation may proceed to condemn under the provisions of Title 12 of the Real Property Article.</text></section>
<section id=":g23::III:140::142:" db-date="20061025"><enum>142.</enum><text>When any bridge or canal shall be erected or constructed pursuant to consent of the county commissioners under &sect; 140 of this article, the corporation shall report in writing to the county commissioners, under the oath or affirmation of the president or vice president; and the county commissioners shall appoint three persons to examine the same and report whether it has been erected or constructed in such a substantial and durable manner as is required to promote the public convenience, and the report shall be reviewed and ratified, or rejected by the county commissioners, who may appoint other persons to report thereon in their discretion.</text></section>
<section id=":g23::III:140::143:" db-date="20061025"><enum>143.</enum><text>No bridge may be erected on a navigable river, unless authorized by the State Highway Administration.</text></section>
<section id=":g23::III:181::181:" db-date="20061025"><enum>181.</enum><text>Any municipal corporation in this State, against which there is a judgment or decree in any court of law or equity in this State, shall have power to levy a sum of money upon the assessable property of such municipality sufficient to pay such judgments.</text></section>
<section id=":g23::III:181::182:" db-date="20100618"><enum>182.</enum><subsection db-date="20100618" id=":g23::III:181::182:a:"><enum>(a)</enum><text>Subject to subsection (b) of this section, a municipal corporation of this State now owning or hereafter acquiring an electric plant or gas plant, as defined in &sect; 1&ndash;101 of the Public Utilities Article, may sell, lease, exchange or otherwise dispose of the electric plant or gas plant, or any part of or interest in either, to any electric company or gas company, as defined in &sect; 1&ndash;101 of the Public Utilities Article, on terms and conditions determined by the municipal corporation.</text></subsection><subsection id=":g23::III:181::182:b:" db-date="20100618"><enum>(b)</enum><paragraph id=":g23::III:181::182:b:1:" db-date="20100618"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The sale, lease, exchange or other disposition shall be approved by the Public Service Commission of Maryland.</text></paragraph><paragraph id=":g23::III:181::182:b:2:" db-date="20100618"><enum>(2)</enum><text>At least twice within 15 days after the date of the order of approval by the Public Service Commission, the municipal corporation shall publish notice of the sale, lease, exchange or other disposition, and of the approval of the Commission in a newspaper published in the:</text><subparagraph id=":g23::III:181::182:b:2:i:" role="item" db-date="20100618"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Municipal corporation; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id=":g23::III:181::182:b:2:ii:" role="item" db-date="20100618"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>The county in which the municipal corporation is located if no newspaper is published in the municipal corporation.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id=":g23::III:181::183:" db-date="20061025"><enum>183.</enum><text>In addition to the conditions and limitations imposed by &sect; 182 of this article, any such proposed sale, lease, exchange or other disposition of any municipally owned electric plant and/or gas plant, as defined and contemplated by said section, shall also be ratified by the affirmative vote of a majority of such persons, residing within the corporate limits of such municipal corporation and eligible to vote at the last preceding regular election therein for municipal officers, who shall cast ballots at a special election for that purpose, to be arranged for and held at such time and place within such municipal corporation and in such manner as such municipal corporation shall prescribe, provided and on condition that a written petition to such municipal corporation requesting it to arrange for and hold such special election for such ratification or disapproval of any such sale, lease, exchange or other disposition, shall be signed by at least ten percent of the voters in such municipal corporation, qualified as aforesaid in this section, and shall be delivered to said municipal corporation within thirty days after the date of publication of the second notice required by &sect; 182; and if any such sale, lease, exchange or other disposition shall be ratified as aforesaid at such special election, then such municipal corporation shall forthwith execute all transfers or other title papers necessary to consummate and effectuate any such sale, lease, exchange or other disposition. But if no such petition for a special election be signed and delivered to said municipal corporation, as aforesaid, within the said period of thirty days after the date of publication of the second notice required by said &sect; 182, as aforesaid, then ratification of any such proposed sale, lease, exchange or other disposition by said voters, as heretofore authorized in this section, shall not be required and no such special election for that purpose shall be held, and any such municipal corporation shall forthwith execute all transfers or other title papers necessary to consummate and effectuate any such sale, lease, exchange or other disposition, and any such sale, lease, or other disposition shall be as valid and effective as though the same had been actually ratified by the said voters at a special election petitioned for and held as herein authorized; and provided further, that nothing contained in said &sect; 182 or in this section shall in any way be construed to qualify, limit or abridge the power and authority, now or hereafter conferred upon any such municipal corporation by its charter or by special act of the General Assembly, to sell, lease, exchange or otherwise dispose of any such electric plant and/or gas plant, or to qualify, limit or abridge the manner of exercise of such power and authority as prescribed in any such charter or special act, and provided further, that nothing contained in &sect; 182 or in this section shall apply to Washington County, Talbot County, or the municipalities of Centreville, Snow Hill, Rock Hall, Hagerstown and Berlin.</text></section>
<section id=":g23::III:235::235:" db-date="20061025"><enum>235.</enum><text>No mining company formed or organized under any of the provisions of this article, or which has organized under any existing laws, charter or act of the General Assembly of this State, shall own, conduct or carry on any store, or have any interest in any store, or receive any portion of the profits thereof; but nothing herein contained shall prevent the employees of any corporation from forming cooperative stores.</text></section>
</article></legisdoc>