<?xml version="1.0"?><!DOCTYPE legisdoc SYSTEM "c:\program files\epic\custom\doctypes\legisdoc\legisdoc.dtd"><legisdoc xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" doc-id="docID" public-private="private"><metadata><doc-state state="none"></doc-state></metadata><article id="dummy"><section id=":g23a::1:::1:" db-date="20060801"><enum>1.</enum>
<text>The inhabitants of every incorporated municipality in Maryland constitute and shall continue to be a body corporate, and under the corporate name shall have perpetual succession, may sue and be sued, and may pass and adopt all ordinances, resolutions or bylaws necessary or proper to exercise the powers granted herein or elsewhere.</text>
</section><section id=":g23a::1:::1A:" db-date="20060801"><enum>1A.</enum>
<subsection id=":g23a::1:::1A:a:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(a)</enum>
<text>Unless otherwise specifically provided by the laws of Maryland, a municipal corporation, and every officer, department, agency, board, commission, or other unit of municipal government may not raise the defense of sovereign immunity in the courts of this State in an action in contract based upon a written contract executed on behalf of the municipal corporation, or its department, agency, board, commission, or unit by an official or employee acting within the scope of his authority.</text>
</subsection><subsection id=":g23a::1:::1A:b:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(b)</enum>
<text>In any action in contract described under subsection (a) of this section, the municipal corporation, or its officer, department, agency, board, commission, or other unit of government shall have the immunity from liability described under &sect; 5-507(a) of the Courts and Judicial Proceedings Article.</text>
</subsection><subsection id=":g23a::1:::1A:c:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(c)</enum>
<text>A claim is barred unless the claimant files suit within one year from the date on which the claim arose or within one year after completion of the contract giving rise to the claim, whichever is later.</text>
</subsection><subsection id=":g23a::1:::1A:d:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(d)</enum>
<text>In order to provide for the implementation of this section, the governing body of every municipal corporation shall make available adequate funds for the satisfaction of any final judgment, after the exhaustion of any right of appeal, which has been rendered against the municipal corporation, or any officer, department, agency, board, commission, or other unit of government in an action in contract as provided in this section.</text>
</subsection><subsection id=":g23a::1:::1A:e:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(e)</enum>
<text>Except as provided in subsections (f) and (g) of this section, a municipal corporation may not require in a construction contract, or otherwise provide with regard to a construction contract, to which it is a party, that a dispute between the parties involving $10,000 or more regarding the terms of the contract or performance under the contract, be subject to final binding or conclusive determination by an officer or official body of a municipal corporation.</text>
</subsection><subsection id=":g23a::1:::1A:f:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(f)</enum>
<text>A municipal corporation may require or provide, with regard to a construction contract to which it is a party, that if there is a dispute regarding the terms of the contract or performance under the contract, the question or questions involved in the dispute shall be subject to a determination which is final and conclusive on all parties, made either by:</text>
<paragraph id=":g23a::1:::1A:f:1:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(1)</enum>
<text>A neutral person or entity selected by or in accordance with a procedure established by the highest executive authority of a municipal corporation, or</text>
</paragraph><paragraph id=":g23a::1:::1A:f:2:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(2)</enum>
<text>In the event that the other party does not accept as neutral a person or entity selected under paragraph (1) of this subsection, by an arbitration panel composed of the following:</text>
<subparagraph id=":g23a::1:::1A:f:2:i:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(i)</enum>
<text>One member designated by the highest executive authority of a municipal corporation;</text>
</subparagraph><subparagraph id=":g23a::1:::1A:f:2:ii:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(ii)</enum>
<text>One member designated by the other party to the dispute; and</text>
</subparagraph><subparagraph id=":g23a::1:::1A:f:2:iii:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(iii)</enum>
<text>One member to be selected by mutual agreement of the two designated members from lists to be submitted by the parties to the dispute.</text>
</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id=":g23a::1:::1A:g:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(g)</enum>
<text>Notwithstanding the provisions of subsections (e) and (f) of this section, a municipal corporation may provide or require, with regard to a construction contract to which it is a party, that a dispute between the parties involving $10,000 or more regarding the terms of the contract or performance under the contract, be subject to a determination of questions of fact by an officer or official body of a municipal corporation, provided that the decision of the officer or official body of a municipal corporation is subject to review on the record by a court of competent jurisdiction.</text>
</subsection></section><section id=":g23a::1:::1B:" db-date="20060801"><enum>1B.</enum>
<text>Officials of a municipal corporation shall have the immunity from liability described under &sect; 5-507(b) of the Courts and Judicial Proceedings Article.</text>
</section><section id=":g23a::1:::2:" db-date="20100618"><enum>2.</enum><subsection id=":g23a::1:::2:a:" db-date="20100618"><enum>(a)</enum><text>The legislative body of every incorporated municipality in this State, except Baltimore City, by whatever name known, shall have general power to pass such ordinances not contrary to the Constitution of Maryland, public general law, or, except as provided in &sect; 2B of this article, public local law as they may deem necessary in order to assure the good government of the municipality, to protect and preserve the municipality&rsquo;s rights, property, and privileges, to preserve peace and good order, to secure persons and property from danger and destruction, and to protect the health, comfort and convenience of the citizens of the municipality; but nothing in this article shall be construed to authorize the legislative body of any incorporated municipality to pass any ordinance which is inconsistent or in conflict with any ordinance, rule or regulation passed, ordained or adopted by the Maryland-National Capital Park and Planning Commission and the Washington Suburban Sanitary Commission, and nothing in this article shall be taken or construed to affect, change, modify, limit or restrict in any manner any of the corporate powers of the Mayor and City Council of Baltimore which it now has or which hereafter may be granted to it.</text></subsection><subsection db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::1:::2:b:"><enum>(b)</enum><text>In addition to, but not in substitution of, the powers which have been, or may hereafter be, granted to it, such legislative body also shall have the following express ordinance&ndash;making powers:</text><paragraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::1:::2:b:1:" role="item"><enum>(1)</enum><text>To provide for municipal advertising, for the printing and publication of statements of the receipts and expenditures of the municipality, and the publication and codification of all laws, ordinances, resolutions, or regulations adopted by or affecting the municipality.</text></paragraph><paragraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::1:::2:b:2:" role="item"><enum>(2)</enum><text>To expend municipal funds for any purpose deemed to be public and to affect the safety, health, and general welfare of the municipality and its occupants, provided that funds not appropriated at the time of the annual levy, shall not be expended, nor shall any funds appropriated be expended for any purpose other than that for which appropriated, except by a two&ndash;thirds vote of all members elected to said legislative body.</text></paragraph><paragraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::1:::2:b:3:" role="item"><enum>(3)</enum><text>To provide for the appointment of an auditor or accountant to audit the books and accounts of all municipal officers collecting, handling, or disbursing funds belonging to the municipality.</text></paragraph><paragraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::1:::2:b:4:" role="item"><enum>(4)</enum><text>To establish, maintain and support a municipal band or musical organization.</text></paragraph><paragraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::1:::2:b:5:" role="item"><enum>(5)</enum><text>To make reasonable regulations concerning buildings and signs to be erected within the limits of the municipality, including a building code and the requirement for building permits.</text></paragraph><paragraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::1:::2:b:6:" role="item"><enum>(6)</enum><text>To regulate the interment of bodies and to control the location and establishment of cemeteries.</text></paragraph><paragraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::1:::2:b:7:" role="item"><enum>(7)</enum><text>To provide, maintain and operate such community and social services for the preservation and promotion of the health, recreation, welfare and enlightenment of the inhabitants of the municipality as the legislative body may determine.</text></paragraph><paragraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::1:::2:b:8:" role="item"><enum>(8)</enum><text>To change the corporate name of the municipality, provided that no such change shall affect any rights, duties or obligations held by the municipality, and provided further that such ordinance shall first be submitted to and approved by the qualified voters of the municipality at a regular or special municipal election.</text></paragraph><paragraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::1:::2:b:9:" role="item"><enum>(9)</enum><text>To prohibit the youth from being on the streets and public places at unreasonable hours of the night.</text></paragraph><paragraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::1:::2:b:10:" role="item"><enum>(10)</enum><text>To control the use and handling of dangerous and explosive materials, and to prevent the firing of any firearms or other explosive instrument.</text></paragraph><paragraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::1:::2:b:11:" role="item"><enum>(11)</enum><text>To have the general management and control of the finances of the municipality, and to designate by ordinance or resolution the banks or trust companies of this State in which shall be deposited all funds belonging to the municipality.</text></paragraph><paragraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::1:::2:b:12:" role="item"><enum>(12)</enum><text>To establish and maintain a fire department; and to provide for the removal of fire hazards.</text></paragraph><paragraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::1:::2:b:13:" role="item"><enum>(13)</enum><text>To grant franchises as provided under existing public general or public local laws; to grant one or more exclusive or nonexclusive franchises for a community antenna system or other cable television system that utilizes any public right&ndash;of&ndash;way, highway, street, road, lane, alley, or bridge, to impose franchise fees, and to establish rates, rules, and regulations for franchises granted under this section.</text></paragraph><paragraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::1:::2:b:14:" role="item"><enum>(14)</enum><text>To regulate or prevent the throwing or depositing of any dirt, garbage, trash, or liquids in any public place and to provide for the proper disposal of such material.</text></paragraph><paragraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::1:::2:b:15:" role="item"><enum>(15)</enum><text>To appoint a board of health, and to define and regulate its powers and duties; to establish quarantine regulations, and to authorize the removal or confinement of persons having infectious or contagious diseases; to prevent and remove nuisances; to prevent the introduction of contagious diseases into the municipality; to regulate the places of manufacturing soap, fertilizer, and other noxious things; to regulate slaughterhouses, packing houses, and all places where offensive trades may be carried on; to regulate places which cause or may cause unsanitary conditions, or conditions detrimental to health. Provided, that nothing herein shall be construed to affect in any manner any of the powers and duties of the Secretary of Health and Mental Hygiene or any county board of health or any public general or public local law relating to the subject of health.</text></paragraph><paragraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::1:::2:b:16:" role="item"><enum>(16)</enum><text>To authorize and require the inspection of gas pipes, water pipes, plumbing apparatus, electric lines and wires, and drainage and sewage systems on private property, and to compel repairs thereon.</text></paragraph><paragraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::1:::2:b:17:" role="item"><enum>(17)</enum><text>To provide that any valid charges, taxes or assessments made against any real property within the municipality shall be liens upon such property to be collected in the same manner as municipal taxes are collected.</text></paragraph><paragraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::1:::2:b:18:" role="item"><enum>(18)</enum><text>To establish and to regulate markets, and to license the sale of marketable commodities therein.</text></paragraph><paragraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::1:::2:b:19:" role="item"><enum>(19)</enum><text>To establish a merit system in connection with the appointment of all municipal officials and employees not elected or appointed under the Constitution or public general or public local laws of the State, and to request and avail themselves of the facilities of the Department of Budget and Management, as provided in &sect; 4&ndash;303 of the State Personnel and Pensions Article, for the administration of such merit system without unnecessary expense.</text></paragraph><paragraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::1:::2:b:20:" role="item"><enum>(20)</enum><text>To establish and maintain such parks, gardens, playgrounds, and recreational facilities as in the discretion of the legislative body are deemed to be for the health and welfare of the municipality and its inhabitants.</text></paragraph><paragraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::1:::2:b:21:" role="item"><enum>(21)</enum><text>To provide a retirement or pension system or a group insurance plan for its officers or employees or for including its officers and employees in any retirement or pension system operated by or in conjunction with the State, on such terms and conditions as State laws may prescribe.</text></paragraph><paragraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::1:::2:b:22:" role="item"><enum>(22)</enum><text>To establish and maintain an adequate police force.</text></paragraph><paragraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::1:::2:b:23:" role="item"><enum>(23)</enum><text>To punish and suppress vagrancy, vice, gambling, and the owning or keeping of houses of ill fame within the limits of the town.</text><text>To enforce all ordinances relating to disorderly conduct and the suppression of nuisances equally within the limits of the municipality and beyond those limits for one half mile, or for so much of this distance as does not conflict with the powers of another municipal corporation.</text></paragraph><paragraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::1:::2:b:23A:" role="item"><enum>(23A)</enum><text>The municipal corporation may provide for the creation, appointment, duties, and powers of a board of port wardens to exercise jurisdiction within the limits of the municipal corporation.</text><subparagraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::1:::2:b:23A:i:"><enum>(i)</enum><text>A board of port wardens may regulate the placement, erection, or construction of structures or other barriers within or on the waters of the municipality, including but not limited to the issuing of licenses to create or build wharves or piers and the issuing of permits for mooring piles, floating wharves, buoys, or anchors, taking into account the present and proposed uses, and the effect of present and proposed uses on marine life, wildlife, conservation, water pollution, erosion, navigational hazards, the effect of the proposed use on congestion within the waters, the effect on other riparian property owners, and the present and projected needs for any proposed commercial or industrial use. The port wardens shall have the power to regulate the materials and construction for the aforesaid improvements and to make certain that any improvements in the waters within the municipality do not render the navigation too close and confined. This provision in no way intends to affect or conflict with any zoning power of a municipality.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::1:::2:b:23A:ii:"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>No person may build any wharf or pier, or carry out any earth or other material for the purpose of building a wharf or pier, nor shall any persons place or erect mooring piles, floating wharves, buoys, or anchors without a license or permit from the port wardens. If any person violates the provisions of this section, or if any person builds any wharf or pier a greater distance into the waters of the port, or in a different form, or of different materials than determined and allowed by the wardens, he is subject to a fine as imposed by the legislative body of the municipal corporation.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::1:::2:b:23A:iii:"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>In all differences that arise between any aggrieved party and the port wardens of that municipal corporation concerning the discharge of the duties of the port wardens, an appeal may be taken to the legislative body of the municipal corporation or, if authorized by the municipal corporation by ordinance, to the circuit court for the appropriate county.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::1:::2:b:24:" role="item"><enum>(24)</enum><text>To acquire by conveyance, purchase or condemnation real or leasehold property needed for any public purpose; to erect buildings thereon for the benefit of the municipality; and to sell at public or private sale after twenty days&rsquo; public notice and to convey to the purchaser or purchasers thereof any real or leasehold property belonging to the municipality when such legislative body determines that the same is no longer needed for any public use.</text><text>To take by gift, grant, bequest, or devise and to hold real and personal property absolutely or in trust for parks or gardens, or for the erection of statues, monuments, buildings or structures, or for any public use, upon such terms and conditions as may be prescribed by the grantor or donor, and accepted by the municipality; to provide for the proper administration of the same; and to convey the same when such legislative body determines that it is no longer needed for public purposes, subject to the terms and conditions of the original grant.</text></paragraph><paragraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::1:::2:b:24A:" role="item"><enum>(24A)</enum><text>To provide for the purchase of materials, supplies, and equipment through the Purchasing Bureau of the State Department of General Services whenever desirable.</text></paragraph><paragraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::1:::2:b:25:" role="item"><enum>(25)</enum><text>To remove or temporarily suspend from office any person who has been appointed to any municipal office and who after due notice and hearing is adjudged to have been guilty of inefficiency, malfeasance, misfeasance, nonfeasance, misconduct in office, or insubordination; and to fill the vacancy caused by such removal or suspension.</text></paragraph><paragraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::1:::2:b:26:" role="item"><enum>(26)</enum><text>To fix the salary or compensation of all municipal officers and employees.</text></paragraph><paragraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::1:::2:b:27:" role="item"><enum>(27)</enum><text>To make, have and use, and from time to time, alter, a common seal.</text></paragraph><paragraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::1:::2:b:28:" role="item"><enum>(28)</enum><text>To require the owners of premises to keep the sidewalks thereon clean and free from snow, ice, or other obstructions.</text></paragraph><paragraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::1:::2:b:29:" role="item"><enum>(29)</enum><text>To provide for special elections for municipal purposes, at such times and places as may be determined, and subject to the provisions of the charter of said municipality.</text></paragraph><paragraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::1:::2:b:30:" role="item"><enum>(30)</enum><text>To provide reasonable zoning regulations subject to the referendum of the voters at regular or special elections.</text></paragraph><paragraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::1:::2:b:31:" role="item"><enum>(31)</enum><text>To make use of federal or State financial assistance for commercial or industrial redevelopment projects, for the purpose of making grants, loans, or guaranteeing loans to private entities; provided, that the authority granted by this subsection may be used only for commercial or industrial redevelopment projects and may not be used for residential or housing projects.</text></paragraph><paragraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::1:::2:b:32:" role="item"><enum>(32)</enum><text>To exercise the licensing authority granted in the Business Regulation Article and other provisions of law.</text></paragraph><paragraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::1:::2:b:33:" role="item"><enum>(33)</enum><text>Subject to the limitations imposed under Article 24 of the Code, the Tax &ndash; General Article, and the Tax &ndash; Property Article, to establish and collect reasonable fees and charges:</text><subparagraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::1:::2:b:33:i:" role="item"><enum>(i)</enum><text>For the franchises, licenses, or permits authorized by law to be granted by a municipal corporation; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::1:::2:b:33:ii:" role="item"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Associated with the exercise of any governmental or proprietary function authorized by law to be exercised by a municipal corporation.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::1:::2:b:34:" role="item"><enum>(34)</enum><text>To offer and pay rewards for information relating to criminal activity committed within the municipality.</text></paragraph><paragraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::1:::2:b:35:" role="item"><enum>(35)</enum><subparagraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::1:::2:b:35:i:"><enum>(i)</enum><text>In accordance with the provisions of this paragraph, to establish a commercial district management authority for any commercial district within its geographical limits. As to each authority it establishes, the legislative body shall:</text><sub-subparagraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::1:::2:b:35:i:1:" role="item"><enum>1.</enum><text>Specify the membership, organization, jurisdiction, and geographical limits of the authority;</text></sub-subparagraph><sub-subparagraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::1:::2:b:35:i:2:" role="item"><enum>2.</enum><text>Specify one or more of the following as the purposes of the authority:</text><sub-sub-subparagraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::1:::2:b:35:i:2:A:" role="item"><enum>A.</enum><text>Promotion;</text></sub-sub-subparagraph><sub-sub-subparagraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::1:::2:b:35:i:2:B:" role="item"><enum>B.</enum><text>Marketing; and</text></sub-sub-subparagraph><sub-sub-subparagraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::1:::2:b:35:i:2:C:" role="item"><enum>C.</enum><text>The provision of security, maintenance, or amenities within the district; and</text></sub-sub-subparagraph></sub-subparagraph><sub-subparagraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::1:::2:b:35:i:3:" role="item"><enum>3.</enum><text>Provide such financing as it deems appropriate for the authority through fees which may be charged to, or taxes which may be levied against, businesses subject to the authority&rsquo;s jurisdiction.</text></sub-subparagraph></subparagraph><subparagraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::1:::2:b:35:ii:"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>An authority established pursuant to this paragraph may not:</text><sub-subparagraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::1:::2:b:35:ii:1:" role="item"><enum>1.</enum><text>Exercise the power of eminent domain;</text></sub-subparagraph><sub-subparagraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::1:::2:b:35:ii:2:" role="item"><enum>2.</enum><text>Purchase, sell, construct, or, as a landlord, lease office or retail space; or</text></sub-subparagraph><sub-subparagraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::1:::2:b:35:ii:3:" role="item"><enum>3.</enum><text>Except as otherwise authorized by law, otherwise engage in competition with the private sector.</text></sub-subparagraph></subparagraph><subparagraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::1:::2:b:35:iii:"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>Any fees or taxes imposed under this paragraph shall be used only for the purposes stated in this paragraph and may not revert to the general fund of the municipal corporation.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::1:::2:b:36:" role="item"><enum>(36)</enum><subparagraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::1:::2:b:36:i:"><enum>(i)</enum><text>It has been and shall continue to be the policy of this State that the orderly development and use of land and structures requires comprehensive regulation through implementation of planning and zoning controls.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::1:::2:b:36:ii:"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>It has been and shall continue to be the policy of this State that planning and zoning controls shall be implemented by local government.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::1:::2:b:36:iii:"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>To achieve the public purposes of this regulatory scheme, the General Assembly recognizes that local government action will displace or limit economic competition by owners and users of property.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::1:::2:b:36:iv:"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>It is the policy of the General Assembly and of this State that competition and enterprise shall be so displaced or limited for the attainment of the purposes of the State policy for implementing planning and zoning controls as set forth in this article and elsewhere in the public local and public general law.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::1:::2:b:36:v:"><enum>(v)</enum><text>The powers granted to the municipality pursuant to this subsection shall not be construed:</text><sub-subparagraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::1:::2:b:36:v:1:" role="item"><enum>1.</enum><text>To grant to the municipality powers in any substantive area not otherwise granted to the municipality by other public general or public local law;</text></sub-subparagraph><sub-subparagraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::1:::2:b:36:v:2:" role="item"><enum>2.</enum><text>To restrict the municipality from exercising any power granted to the municipality by other public general or public local law or otherwise;</text></sub-subparagraph><sub-subparagraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::1:::2:b:36:v:3:" role="item"><enum>3.</enum><text>To authorize the municipality or its officers to engage in any activity which is beyond their power under other public general law, public local law, or otherwise; or</text></sub-subparagraph><sub-subparagraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::1:::2:b:36:v:4:" role="item"><enum>4.</enum><text>To preempt or supersede the regulatory authority of any State department or agency under any public general law.</text></sub-subparagraph></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::1:::2:b:37:" role="item"><enum>(37)</enum><subparagraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::1:::2:b:37:i:"><enum>(i)</enum><text>In addition to the authority provided elsewhere in this subsection, and provided the municipal corporation has urban renewal authority granted under Article III, Section 61 of the Maryland Constitution:</text><sub-subparagraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::1:::2:b:37:i:1:" role="item"><enum>1.</enum><text>Subject to the provisions of subparagraph (iv) of this paragraph, to acquire, within the boundary lines of the municipal corporation, land and property of every kind, and any right, interest, franchise, easement or privilege therein, by purchase, lease, gift, condemnation or any other legal means, for development or redevelopment, including, but not limited to, the comprehensive renovation or rehabilitation thereof; and</text></sub-subparagraph><sub-subparagraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::1:::2:b:37:i:2:" role="item"><enum>2.</enum><text>To sell, lease, convey, transfer or otherwise dispose of any of said land or property, regardless of whether or not it has been developed, redeveloped, altered or improved and irrespective of the manner or means in or by which it may have been acquired, to any private, public or quasi&ndash;public corporation, partnership, association, person or other legal entity.</text></sub-subparagraph></subparagraph><subparagraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::1:::2:b:37:ii:"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>No land or property taken by a municipal corporation for any of the aforementioned purposes or in connection with the exercise of any of the powers which may be granted to a municipal corporation pursuant to this paragraph by exercising the power of eminent domain, shall be taken without just compensation, as agreed upon between the parties, or awarded by a jury, being first paid or tendered to the party entitled to such compensation.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::1:::2:b:37:iii:"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>All land or property needed, or taken by the exercise of the power of eminent domain, by any municipal corporation for any of the aforementioned purposes or in connection with the exercise of any of the powers which may be granted to a municipal corporation pursuant to this paragraph is hereby declared to be needed or taken for a public use or a public benefit.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::1:::2:b:37:iv:"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>Before the acquisition of any single family or multiple family dwelling unit, or other structure, is made under this paragraph, a finding or determination shall be made that:</text><sub-subparagraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::1:::2:b:37:iv:1:" role="item"><enum>1.</enum><text>The dwelling unit or structure has deteriorated to such extent as to constitute a serious and growing menace to the public health, safety, and welfare;</text></sub-subparagraph><sub-subparagraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::1:::2:b:37:iv:2:" role="item"><enum>2.</enum><text>The dwelling unit or structure is likely to continue to deteriorate unless corrected;</text></sub-subparagraph><sub-subparagraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::1:::2:b:37:iv:3:" role="item"><enum>3.</enum><text>The continued deterioration of the dwelling unit or structure will contribute to the blighting or deterioration of the area immediately surrounding the dwelling unit or structure; and</text></sub-subparagraph><sub-subparagraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::1:::2:b:37:iv:4:" role="item"><enum>4.</enum><text>The owner of the dwelling unit or structure has failed to correct the deterioration thereof.</text></sub-subparagraph></subparagraph><subparagraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::1:::2:b:37:v:"><enum>(v)</enum><text>The legislative body of a municipal corporation shall adopt an ordinance for each acquisition of land or property made under the provisions of this paragraph.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::1:::2:b:38:" role="item"><enum>(38)</enum><text>To enter into agreements with one or more other municipalities for purposes that include:</text><subparagraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::1:::2:b:38:i:" role="item"><enum>(i)</enum><text>The joint administration of the municipalities;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::1:::2:b:38:ii:" role="item"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>The cooperative procurement of goods and services, including construction services;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::1:::2:b:38:iii:" role="item"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>The provision of municipal services; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::1:::2:b:38:iv:" role="item"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>The joint funding and management of projects that are centrally located to the municipalities.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id=":g23a::1:::2A:" db-date="20060801"><enum>2A.</enum>
<subsection id=":g23a::1:::2A:a:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(a)</enum>
<paragraph id=":g23a::1:::2A:a:1:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(1)</enum>
<text>It has been and shall continue to be the policy of the State to authorize each municipal corporation to displace or limit competition in the area of public transportation in order to provide for adequate, economical and efficient delivery of transportation services; to protect its citizens from inconsistent and excessive prices; to provide necessary and desired services in all areas of the municipality; to enable the municipality to provide public transportation in order to conserve energy and reduce air pollution, congestion, traffic hazards and accidents; to encourage the use of public transportation by the contribution by the municipality of capital and operating funds to enable transportation to be provided at the lowest cost to all citizens, especially the indigent; and to promote the general welfare by conducting a comprehensive transportation system.</text>
</paragraph><paragraph id=":g23a::1:::2A:a:2:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(2)</enum>
<text>Each municipal corporation has the authority to grant one or more franchises for a transportation system on an exclusive or nonexclusive basis, to impose franchise fees, to establish certain rates and to establish rules, regulations and licensing requirements to govern the operation of the franchises and to provide for the enforcement of any such measure; to conduct a public transportation system on an exclusive basis, including the establishment of rules, regulations, and rates, notwithstanding any anticompetitive effect.</text>
</paragraph></subsection><subsection id=":g23a::1:::2A:b:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(b)</enum>
<paragraph id=":g23a::1:::2A:b:1:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(1)</enum>
<text>It has been and shall continue to be the policy of the State to authorize each municipal corporation to displace or limit competition in the area of water and sewerage systems in order to assure delivery of adequate, economical, and efficient services to its citizens, to avoid duplication of facilities, to provide for the health and safety of its citizens, to control disease, to prevent blight and other environmental degradation, to utilize efficiently the public right-of-way; to protect limited natural resources for the benefit of the citizens of the municipality; and to promote the general health and welfare by providing for adequate water and sewerage systems.</text>
</paragraph><paragraph id=":g23a::1:::2A:b:2:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(2)</enum>
<subparagraph id=":g23a::1:::2A:b:2:i:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(i)</enum>
<text>Each municipal corporation has the authority to grant one or more franchises or enter into contracts for water and sewerage systems on an exclusive or nonexclusive basis to any person, to impose franchise fees, to establish certain rates and charges, and to establish rules, regulations, and licensing requirements, and to provide for the enforcement of any such measure notwithstanding any anticompetitive effect.</text>
</subparagraph><subparagraph id=":g23a::1:::2A:b:2:ii:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(ii)</enum>
<text>In the event that any municipal corporation has the enabling authority granted by any other law to operate water and sewerage systems, such systems shall be operated by the municipality without regard to any anticompetitive effect.</text>
</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id=":g23a::1:::2A:b:3:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(3)</enum>
<text>It has been and shall continue to be the policy of the State that each municipal corporation is directed and authorized to exercise all powers regarding waste collection and disposal notwithstanding any anticompetitive effect. This subsection does not apply to any portion of a generator&rsquo;s waste which is directed by the generator to a specific facility for reuse, reclamation or recycling, or for disposal on its own property.</text>
</paragraph></subsection><subsection id=":g23a::1:::2A:c:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(c)</enum>
<paragraph id=":g23a::1:::2A:c:1:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(1)</enum>
<text>It has been and shall continue to be the policy of the State to authorize each municipal corporation to displace or limit competition in the area of port regulation undertaken by a board of port wardens pursuant to &sect; 2(b)(23A)(i) of this article, to provide for safe harbors, free of congestion and navigational hazards, to provide benefits to municipal citizens by protecting marine life and wildlife, and to avoid water pollution and erosion.</text>
</paragraph><paragraph id=":g23a::1:::2A:c:2:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(2)</enum>
<text>Each municipal corporation has the authority to grant one or more franchises or enter into contracts for the placement, erection or construction of structures within or on the waters of the municipality, including but not limited to the issuing of licenses for wharves or piers, or the issuing of permits for mooring piles, floating wharves, buoys or anchors notwithstanding any anticompetitive effect.</text>
</paragraph></subsection><subsection id=":g23a::1:::2A:d:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(d)</enum>
<paragraph id=":g23a::1:::2A:d:1:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(1)</enum>
<text>It has been and shall continue to be the policy of the State to authorize each municipal corporation to displace or limit competition in the award of concessions on, over or under property owned, or leased, by the municipality and in the leasing or subleasing of property owned or leased by the municipality in order to utilize properly the assets of the municipality for the best public purpose; to provide necessary or desirable governmental services at the lowest possible cost; to protect the public from unscrupulous business practices and excessive prices; to provide for the accessibility to public property by as many citizens as possible; and to promote the general welfare by utilizing public property for the benefit of the citizens of the community.</text>
</paragraph><paragraph id=":g23a::1:::2A:d:2:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(2)</enum>
<text>Each municipal corporation shall have the authority to displace or limit competition by granting one or more franchises for any concession on, over or under property owned or leased by the municipality on an exclusive or nonexclusive basis, to control prices and rates for such franchises; to establish rules and regulations to govern the operation of the franchises, to provide for the enforcement of any such measure; and to lease or sublease publicly owned or leased land, improvements to land, or both on terms to be determined by the municipality without regard to any anticompetitive effect.</text>
</paragraph></subsection><subsection id=":g23a::1:::2A:e:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(e)</enum>
<text>The powers granted to any municipal corporation pursuant to this section shall not be construed:</text>
<paragraph id=":g23a::1:::2A:e:1:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(1)</enum>
<text>To grant to such municipality powers in any substantive area not otherwise granted to such municipality by other public general or public local law;</text>
</paragraph><paragraph id=":g23a::1:::2A:e:2:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(2)</enum>
<text>To restrict such municipality from exercising any power granted to such municipality by other public general or public local law or otherwise;</text>
</paragraph><paragraph id=":g23a::1:::2A:e:3:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(3)</enum>
<text>To authorize such municipality or its officers to engage in any activity which is beyond their power under other public general law, public local law, or otherwise; or</text>
</paragraph><paragraph id=":g23a::1:::2A:e:4:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(4)</enum>
<text>To preempt or supersede the regulatory authority of any State department or agency under any public general law.</text>
</paragraph></subsection></section><section id=":g23a::1:::2B:" db-date="20060801"><enum>2B.</enum>
<subsection id=":g23a::1:::2B:a:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(a)</enum>
<text>Except as provided in subsection (b) of this section, legislation enacted by a county does not apply in a municipality located in such county if the legislation:</text>
<paragraph id=":g23a::1:::2B:a:1:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(1)</enum>
<text>By its terms exempts the municipality;</text>
</paragraph><paragraph id=":g23a::1:::2B:a:2:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(2)</enum>
<text>Conflicts with legislation of the municipality enacted under a grant of legislative authority provided either by public general law or its charter; or</text>
</paragraph><paragraph id=":g23a::1:::2B:a:3:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(3)</enum>
<text>Relates to a subject with respect to which the municipality has a grant of legislative authority provided either by public general law or its charter and the municipality, by ordinance or charter amendment having prospective or retrospective applicability, or both:</text>
<subparagraph id=":g23a::1:::2B:a:3:i:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(i)</enum>
<text>Specifically exempts itself from such county legislation; or</text>
</subparagraph><subparagraph id=":g23a::1:::2B:a:3:ii:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(ii)</enum>
<text>Generally exempts itself from all county legislation covered by such grants of authority to the municipality.</text>
</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id=":g23a::1:::2B:b:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(b)</enum>
<text>Notwithstanding the provisions of subsection (a)(2) and (3) of this section, the following categories of county legislation, if otherwise within the scope of legislative powers granted the county by the General Assembly, shall nevertheless apply within all municipalities in the county:</text>
<paragraph id=":g23a::1:::2B:b:1:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(1)</enum>
<text>County legislation where a law enacted by the General Assembly so provides;</text>
</paragraph><paragraph id=":g23a::1:::2B:b:2:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(2)</enum>
<text>County revenue or tax legislation, subject to the provisions of Article 24 of the Code, the Tax - General Article, and the Tax - Property Article, or legislation adopting a county budget; and</text>
</paragraph><paragraph id=":g23a::1:::2B:b:3:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(3)</enum>
<text>County legislation which is enacted in accordance with requirements otherwise applicable in such county to legislation that is to become effective immediately and which also meets the following requirements:</text>
<subparagraph id=":g23a::1:::2B:b:3:i:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(i)</enum>
<text>The legislative body of the county makes a specific finding based on evidence of record after a hearing held in accordance with the requirements of subparagraph (ii) hereof that there will be a significant adverse impact on the public health, safety, or welfare affecting residents of the county in unincorporated areas if such county legislation does not apply in all municipalities located in such county;</text>
</subparagraph><subparagraph id=":g23a::1:::2B:b:3:ii:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(ii)</enum>
<text>The legislative body of the county conducts a public hearing at which all municipalities in the county and interested persons shall be given an opportunity to be heard, notice of which is given by the mailing of certified mail notice to each municipality in the county not less than 30 days prior to the hearing and by publication in a newspaper of general circulation in the county for 3 successive weeks, the first publication to be not less than 30 days prior to the hearing; and</text>
</subparagraph><subparagraph id=":g23a::1:::2B:b:3:iii:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(iii)</enum>
<text>The county legislation is enacted by the affirmative vote of not less than two-thirds of the authorized membership of the county legislative body.</text>
</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id=":g23a::1:::2B:b:4:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(4)</enum>
<text>County legislation which is enacted in accordance with the procedures set forth in paragraph (3) of this subsection shall be subject to judicial review of the finding made under paragraph (3)(i) of this subsection and of the resultant applicability of such legislation to municipalities in the county by the circuit court of the county in accordance with the provisions of the Maryland Rules governing appeals from administrative agencies. Any appeal shall be filed within 30 days of the effective date of such county legislation. In any judicial proceeding commenced under the provisions of this paragraph, the sole issues are whether the county legislative body (1) complied with the procedures of paragraph (3) of this subsection, and (2) had before it sufficient evidence from which a reasonable person could conclude that there will be a significant adverse impact on the public health, safety, or welfare affecting residents of the county in unincorporated areas if such county legislation does not apply in all municipalities located in the county. The issues shall be decided by the court without a jury. In the event that the court reverses such finding, the legislation shall continue to apply in unincorporated areas of the county and the applicability of such county legislation in municipalities shall be governed by the provisions of subsection (a) of this section. The decision of the circuit court in any such proceeding shall be subject to further appeal to the Court of Special Appeals by the county or any municipality in the county.</text>
</paragraph></subsection><subsection id=":g23a::1:::2B:c:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(c)</enum>
<text>Notwithstanding the provisions of subsection (b)(3) of this section, county legislation enacted in accordance with the procedures and requirements thereof shall nevertheless be or become inapplicable in any municipality which has enacted or enacts municipal legislation that:</text>
<paragraph id=":g23a::1:::2B:c:1:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(1)</enum>
<text>Covers the same subject matter and furthers the same policies as the county legislation;</text>
</paragraph><paragraph id=":g23a::1:::2B:c:2:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(2)</enum>
<text>Is at least as restrictive as the county legislation; and</text>
</paragraph><paragraph id=":g23a::1:::2B:c:3:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(3)</enum>
<text>Includes provisions for enforcement.</text>
</paragraph></subsection><subsection id=":g23a::1:::2B:d:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(d)</enum>
<text>Any municipality may, by ordinance, request and authorize the county within which it is located to administer or enforce any municipal legislation. Upon the enactment of such an ordinance, such county may administer or enforce such municipal legislation on such terms and conditions as may mutually be agreed.</text>
</subsection><subsection id=":g23a::1:::2B:e:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(e)</enum>
<text>As used in this section:</text>
<paragraph id=":g23a::1:::2B:e:1:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(1)</enum>
<text>&ldquo;County&rdquo; means any county, regardless of the form of county government, including charter home rule, code home rule, and county commissioners; and</text>
</paragraph><paragraph id=":g23a::1:::2B:e:2:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(2)</enum>
<text>&ldquo;Legislation&rdquo; means any form of county or municipal legislative enactment, including a law, ordinance, resolution and any action by which a county budget is adopted.</text>
</paragraph></subsection></section><section db-date="20110811" id=":g23a::1:::2C:"><enum>2C.</enum><text>The other provisions of this article and the provisions of Articles 25, 25A, and 25B of the Code are intended to be and shall be deemed amended and modified as provided in &sect; 2B of this article.</text></section><section id=":g23a::1:::3:" db-date="20060801"><enum>3.</enum>
<subsection id=":g23a::1:::3:a:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(a)</enum>
<text>The legislative body of any municipality shall have power to provide that violations of ordinances and resolutions authorized by this article shall be punishable as misdemeanors, but no penalty shall exceed a fine of $1,000 and imprisonment for 6 months. Imprisonment in default of fine and costs shall be regulated by the provisions of &sect;&sect; 7-504 and 7-505 of the Courts Article.</text>
</subsection><subsection id=":g23a::1:::3:b:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(b)</enum>
<paragraph id=":g23a::1:::3:b:1:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(1)</enum>
<text>The legislative body of a municipality may provide that violations of any municipal ordinance shall be a &ldquo;municipal infraction&rdquo; unless the violation is declared to be a felony or a misdemeanor by State law. In addition, the legislative body of a municipality may classify as a &ldquo;municipal infraction&rdquo;: (i) a violation of any zoning or land use ordinance or regulation authorized to be adopted or enacted by that municipality; and (ii) littering within the municipality as prohibited under &sect; 10-110 of the Criminal Law Article. For purposes of this article a municipal infraction is a civil offense.</text>
</paragraph><paragraph id=":g23a::1:::3:b:2:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(2)</enum>
<text>A fine not to exceed $1,000 may be imposed for each municipal infraction. The fine is payable to the municipality by the person charged in the citation within 20 calendar days of service of the citation.</text>
</paragraph><paragraph id=":g23a::1:::3:b:3:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(3)</enum>
<subparagraph id=":g23a::1:::3:b:3:i:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(i)</enum>
<text>Those officials authorized by the legislative body of the municipality to act as enforcement officers may serve a citation on any person:</text>
<sub-subparagraph id=":g23a::1:::3:b:3:i:1:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>1.</enum>
<text>Whom they believe is committing or has committed a municipal infraction; or</text>
</sub-subparagraph><sub-subparagraph id=":g23a::1:::3:b:3:i:2:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>2.</enum>
<text>On the basis of an affidavit submitted to an appropriate official of the municipality, to be named by the municipality, citing the facts of the alleged infraction.</text>
</sub-subparagraph></subparagraph><subparagraph id=":g23a::1:::3:b:3:ii:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(ii)</enum>
<text>The citation shall be served on the defendant:</text>
<sub-subparagraph id=":g23a::1:::3:b:3:ii:1:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>1.</enum>
<text>In accordance with Maryland Rule 3-121; or</text>
</sub-subparagraph><sub-subparagraph id=":g23a::1:::3:b:3:ii:2:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>2.</enum>
<text>For real property-related violations, if proof is made by affidavit that good faith efforts to serve the defendant under Maryland Rule 3-121(a) have not succeeded, by:</text>
<sub-sub-subparagraph id=":g23a::1:::3:b:3:ii:2:A:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>A.</enum>
<text>Regular mail to the defendant&rsquo;s last known address; and</text>
</sub-sub-subparagraph><sub-sub-subparagraph id=":g23a::1:::3:b:3:ii:2:B:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>B.</enum>
<text>Posting of the citation at the property where the infraction has occurred or is occurring, and, if located within the municipality in which the infraction has occurred or is occurring, at the residence or place of business of the defendant.</text>
</sub-sub-subparagraph></sub-subparagraph></subparagraph><subparagraph id=":g23a::1:::3:b:3:iii:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(iii)</enum>
<text>The citation shall contain:</text>
<sub-subparagraph id=":g23a::1:::3:b:3:iii:1:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>1.</enum>
<text>The enforcement officer&rsquo;s certification:</text>
<sub-sub-subparagraph id=":g23a::1:::3:b:3:iii:1:A:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>A.</enum>
<text>Attesting to the truth of the matter set forth in the citation; or</text>
</sub-sub-subparagraph><sub-sub-subparagraph id=":g23a::1:::3:b:3:iii:1:B:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>B.</enum>
<text>That the citation is based on an affidavit;</text>
</sub-sub-subparagraph></sub-subparagraph><sub-subparagraph id=":g23a::1:::3:b:3:iii:2:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>2.</enum>
<text>The name and address of the person charged;</text>
</sub-subparagraph><sub-subparagraph id=":g23a::1:::3:b:3:iii:3:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>3.</enum>
<text>The nature of the infraction;</text>
</sub-subparagraph><sub-subparagraph id=":g23a::1:::3:b:3:iii:4:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>4.</enum>
<text>The location and time that the infraction occurred;</text>
</sub-subparagraph><sub-subparagraph id=":g23a::1:::3:b:3:iii:5:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>5.</enum>
<text>The amount of the infraction fine assessed;</text>
</sub-subparagraph><sub-subparagraph id=":g23a::1:::3:b:3:iii:6:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>6.</enum>
<text>The manner, location, and time in which the fine may be paid to the municipality;</text>
</sub-subparagraph><sub-subparagraph id=":g23a::1:::3:b:3:iii:7:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>7.</enum>
<text>The person&rsquo;s right to elect to stand trial for the infraction; and</text>
</sub-subparagraph><sub-subparagraph id=":g23a::1:::3:b:3:iii:8:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>8.</enum>
<text>The effect of failing to pay the assessed fine or demand a trial within the prescribed time.</text>
</sub-subparagraph></subparagraph><subparagraph id=":g23a::1:::3:b:3:iv:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(iv)</enum>
<text>The enforcement officer shall retain a copy of the citation.</text>
</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id=":g23a::1:::3:b:4:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(4)</enum>
<subparagraph id=":g23a::1:::3:b:4:i:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(i)</enum>
<text>If a citation is served without a summons as provided in paragraph (6) of this subsection, the person charged in the citation may elect to stand trial for the infraction by notifying the municipality in writing of the person&rsquo;s intent to stand trial. The written notice shall be given at least 5 days prior to the date of payment as set forth in the citation.</text>
</subparagraph><subparagraph id=":g23a::1:::3:b:4:ii:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(ii)</enum>
<text>Upon receipt of the written notice of the intent to stand trial, the municipality shall forward to the District Court having venue a copy of the citation and the written notice.</text>
</subparagraph><subparagraph id=":g23a::1:::3:b:4:iii:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(iii)</enum>
<text>Upon receipt of the citation and the written notice, the District Court shall schedule the case for trial and notify the defendant of the trial date.</text>
</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id=":g23a::1:::3:b:5:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(5)</enum>
<subparagraph id=":g23a::1:::3:b:5:i:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(i)</enum>
<text>If a person charged in a citation fails to pay the fine by the date of payment set forth on the citation and fails to deliver to the municipality the written notice of intent to stand trial, the person is liable for the assessed fine.</text>
</subparagraph><subparagraph id=":g23a::1:::3:b:5:ii:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(ii)</enum>
<text>The municipality may double the fine to an amount not to exceed $1,000 and request adjudication of the case through the District Court, including the filing of a demand for judgment on affidavit.</text>
</subparagraph><subparagraph id=":g23a::1:::3:b:5:iii:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(iii)</enum>
<text>The District Court shall promptly schedule the case for trial and summons the defendant to appear.</text>
</subparagraph><subparagraph id=":g23a::1:::3:b:5:iv:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(iv)</enum>
<text>The defendant&rsquo;s failure to respond to such summons shall result in the entry of judgment against the defendant in favor of the municipality in the amount then due if a proper demand for judgment on affidavit has been made.</text>
</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id=":g23a::1:::3:b:6:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(6)</enum>
<subparagraph id=":g23a::1:::3:b:6:i:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(i)</enum>
<sub-subparagraph id=":g23a::1:::3:b:6:i:1:" db-date="20060801"><enum>1.</enum>
<text>An enforcement officer may also serve a summons with a citation that requires the person to appear in District Court on a specified date and time.</text>
</sub-subparagraph><sub-subparagraph id=":g23a::1:::3:b:6:i:2:" db-date="20060801"><enum>2.</enum>
<text>The summons shall specify that the person is not required to appear in District Court if the fine is paid as provided in the citation.</text>
</sub-subparagraph><sub-subparagraph id=":g23a::1:::3:b:6:i:3:" db-date="20060801"><enum>3.</enum>
<text>If approved by the Chief Judge of the Maryland District Court, the citation form may contain the summons.</text>
</sub-subparagraph><sub-subparagraph id=":g23a::1:::3:b:6:i:4:" db-date="20060801"><enum>4.</enum>
<text>The enforcement officer shall coordinate the selection of court dates with the appropriate District Court officials.</text>
</sub-subparagraph></subparagraph><subparagraph id=":g23a::1:::3:b:6:ii:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(ii)</enum>
<text>If the defendant fails to pay the fine as provided in the citation and fails to appear in District Court as provided in the summons:</text>
<sub-subparagraph id=":g23a::1:::3:b:6:ii:1:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>1.</enum>
<text>The municipality may double the fine to an amount not to exceed $1,000; and</text>
</sub-subparagraph><sub-subparagraph id=":g23a::1:::3:b:6:ii:2:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>2.</enum>
<text>The Court may enter judgment against the defendant in the amount then due if the proper demand for judgment on affidavit has been made.</text>
</sub-subparagraph></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id=":g23a::1:::3:b:7:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(7)</enum>
<text>If any person shall be found by the District Court to have committed a municipal infraction:</text>
<subparagraph id=":g23a::1:::3:b:7:i:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(i)</enum>
<sub-subparagraph id=":g23a::1:::3:b:7:i:1:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>1.</enum>
<text>The District Court shall order the person to pay the fine, including any doubling of the fine, not to exceed the limits under paragraph (2) of this subsection;</text>
</sub-subparagraph><sub-subparagraph id=":g23a::1:::3:b:7:i:2:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>2.</enum>
<text>The fines imposed shall constitute a judgment in favor of the municipality; and</text>
</sub-subparagraph><sub-subparagraph id=":g23a::1:::3:b:7:i:3:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>3.</enum>
<text>If the fine remains unpaid for 30 days following the date of its entry, the judgment shall be enforceable in the same manner and to the same extent as other civil judgments for money unless the Court has suspended or deferred the payment of the fine as provided under subparagraph (ii) of this paragraph;</text>
</sub-subparagraph></subparagraph><subparagraph id=":g23a::1:::3:b:7:ii:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(ii)</enum>
<text>The District Court may suspend or defer the payment of any fine under conditions that the Court sets;</text>
</subparagraph><subparagraph id=":g23a::1:::3:b:7:iii:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(iii)</enum>
<text>The person shall be liable for the costs of the proceedings in the District Court; and</text>
</subparagraph><subparagraph id=":g23a::1:::3:b:7:iv:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(iv)</enum>
<text>The Court may order the person to abate the infraction or enter an order permitting a municipality to abate any such infraction at the person&rsquo;s expense.</text>
</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id=":g23a::1:::3:b:8:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(8)</enum>
<subparagraph id=":g23a::1:::3:b:8:i:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(i)</enum>
<text>If a municipality abates an infraction pursuant to an order of the District Court, the municipality shall present the defendant with a bill for the cost of abatement by:</text>
<sub-subparagraph id=":g23a::1:::3:b:8:i:1:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>1.</enum>
<text>Regular mail to the defendant&rsquo;s last known address; or</text>
</sub-subparagraph><sub-subparagraph id=":g23a::1:::3:b:8:i:2:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>2.</enum>
<text>Any other means that are reasonably calculated to bring the bill to the defendant&rsquo;s attention.</text>
</sub-subparagraph></subparagraph><subparagraph id=":g23a::1:::3:b:8:ii:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(ii)</enum>
<text>If the defendant does not pay the bill within 30 days after presentment, upon a motion of the municipality, the District Court shall enter a judgment against the defendant for the cost of the abatement.</text>
</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id=":g23a::1:::3:b:9:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(9)</enum>
<text>All fines, penalties, or forfeitures collected by the District Court for a municipal infraction shall be remitted to the municipality in which the infraction occurred.</text>
</paragraph><paragraph id=":g23a::1:::3:b:10:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(10)</enum>
<text>If a defendant fails to pay any fine or cost imposed by the District Court without good cause, the District Court may punish the failure as contempt of court.</text>
</paragraph><paragraph id=":g23a::1:::3:b:11:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(11)</enum>
<text>Adjudication of a municipal infraction, as defined in paragraph (1) of this subsection, is not a criminal conviction for any purpose, nor does it impose any of the civil disabilities ordinarily imposed by a criminal conviction.</text>
</paragraph><paragraph id=":g23a::1:::3:b:12:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(12)</enum>
<text>In any proceeding for a municipal infraction:</text>
<subparagraph id=":g23a::1:::3:b:12:i:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(i)</enum>
<text>It shall be the burden of the municipality to prove that the defendant has committed the infraction by clear and convincing evidence, and in any such proceeding, the District Court shall apply the evidentiary standards as prescribed by law or rule for the trial of civil causes;</text>
</subparagraph><subparagraph id=":g23a::1:::3:b:12:ii:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(ii)</enum>
<text>The District Court shall ensure that the defendant has received a copy of the charges against the defendant and that the defendant understands those charges;</text>
</subparagraph><subparagraph id=":g23a::1:::3:b:12:iii:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(iii)</enum>
<text>The defendant shall be entitled to cross-examine all witnesses who appear against the defendant, to produce evidence or witnesses in the defendant&rsquo;s own behalf, or to testify in the defendant&rsquo;s own behalf, if the defendant elects to do so;</text>
</subparagraph><subparagraph id=":g23a::1:::3:b:12:iv:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(iv)</enum>
<text>The defendant shall be entitled to be represented by counsel of the defendant&rsquo;s own selection and at the defendant&rsquo;s own expense; and</text>
</subparagraph><subparagraph id=":g23a::1:::3:b:12:v:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(v)</enum>
<text>The defendant may enter a plea of guilty or not guilty of the infraction as charged, and the verdict of the District Court shall be guilty of a municipal infraction or not guilty of a municipal infraction, or the District Court may, before rendering judgment, place the defendant on probation.</text>
</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id=":g23a::1:::3:b:13:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(13)</enum>
<text>The court costs in a municipal infraction proceeding in which costs are imposed are $5. A defendant may not be liable for payment to the Criminal Injuries Compensation Fund.</text>
</paragraph><paragraph id=":g23a::1:::3:b:14:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(14)</enum>
<text>The State&rsquo;s Attorney of any county is authorized to prosecute a municipal infraction and is authorized to enter a nolle prosequi in such cases or to place such cases on the stet docket.</text>
</paragraph><paragraph id=":g23a::1:::3:b:15:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(15)</enum>
<text>Notwithstanding the provisions of paragraph (14) of this subsection, a municipality may designate an attorney to prosecute any municipal infraction in the same manner as the State&rsquo;s Attorney of any county.</text>
</paragraph></subsection></section><section id=":g23a::1:::4:" db-date="20060801"><enum>4.</enum>
<subsection id=":g23a::1:::4:a:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(a)</enum>
<text>The legislative body of a municipal corporation may adopt an ordinance for the licensing, control, location, or maintenance within its jurisdiction of:</text>
<paragraph id=":g23a::1:::4:a:1:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(1)</enum>
<text>Junkyards;</text>
</paragraph><paragraph id=":g23a::1:::4:a:2:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(2)</enum>
<text>Public or private dumps;</text>
</paragraph><paragraph id=":g23a::1:::4:a:3:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(3)</enum>
<text>Automobile junkyards;</text>
</paragraph><paragraph id=":g23a::1:::4:a:4:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(4)</enum>
<text>Automotive dismantler and recycler facilities;</text>
</paragraph><paragraph id=":g23a::1:::4:a:5:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(5)</enum>
<text>Scrap metal processing facilities;</text>
</paragraph><paragraph id=":g23a::1:::4:a:6:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(6)</enum>
<text>Outdoor places where old motor vehicles are stored in quantity or dismantled; and</text>
</paragraph><paragraph id=":g23a::1:::4:a:7:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(7)</enum>
<text>Lots on which refuse, trash, or junk is deposited.</text>
</paragraph></subsection><subsection id=":g23a::1:::4:b:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(b)</enum>
<text>An ordinance adopted under this section shall be designed to:</text>
<paragraph id=":g23a::1:::4:b:1:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(1)</enum>
<text>Protect the residents of the municipal corporation from unpleasant and unwholesome conditions and deteriorating neighborhoods;</text>
</paragraph><paragraph id=":g23a::1:::4:b:2:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(2)</enum>
<text>Preserve the beauty and esthetic value of rural or residential areas;</text>
</paragraph><paragraph id=":g23a::1:::4:b:3:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(3)</enum>
<text>Safeguard the public health and welfare;</text>
</paragraph><paragraph id=":g23a::1:::4:b:4:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(4)</enum>
<text>Promote good civic design; and</text>
</paragraph><paragraph id=":g23a::1:::4:b:5:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(5)</enum>
<text>Promote the health, safety, morals, order, convenience, and prosperity of the community.</text>
</paragraph></subsection><subsection id=":g23a::1:::4:c:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(c)</enum>
<text>An ordinance adopted under this section may prohibit the operation or maintenance of a junkyard, dump, or other facility within the limits of the municipal corporation until an annual license has been obtained from the legislative body of the municipal corporation, at a reasonable fee specified in the ordinance.</text>
</subsection><subsection id=":g23a::1:::4:d:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(d)</enum>
<paragraph id=":g23a::1:::4:d:1:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(1)</enum>
<subparagraph id=":g23a::1:::4:d:1:i:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(i)</enum>
<text>Before the legislative body of a municipal corporation adopts an ordinance under this section, the legislative body shall give notice of a public hearing on the proposed ordinance by publishing notice in a newspaper of general circulation in the municipal corporation not less than four times, at weekly intervals within a period of at least 30 days before the date of the hearing.</text>
</subparagraph><subparagraph id=":g23a::1:::4:d:1:ii:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(ii)</enum>
<text>The notice shall specify the date, time, and place at which the legislative body will conduct the public hearing on the ordinance.</text>
</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id=":g23a::1:::4:d:2:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(2)</enum>
<text>The ordinance is not valid unless the public hearing actually is held as specified in the notice.</text>
</paragraph></subsection><subsection id=":g23a::1:::4:e:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(e)</enum>
<paragraph id=":g23a::1:::4:e:1:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(1)</enum>
<text>A person who violates an ordinance adopted under this section, including the maintenance or operation of a junkyard, dump, or other facility without a license, is guilty of a misdemeanor, and on conviction, is subject to a fine of at least $25.</text>
</paragraph><paragraph id=":g23a::1:::4:e:2:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(2)</enum>
<text>Each day on which a violation continues is a separate offense.</text>
</paragraph></subsection><subsection id=":g23a::1:::4:f:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(f)</enum>
<text>The legislative body of a municipal corporation may declare a violation of an ordinance adopted under this section to be a municipal infraction that shall be enforced in accordance with the provisions of &sect; 3(b) of this article.</text>
</subsection><subsection id=":g23a::1:::4:g:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(g)</enum>
<text>If the legislative body of a municipal corporation adopts an ordinance under this section, the provisions of the ordinance may not be construed to apply to any business licensed on or before June 30, 2004 as an automotive dismantler and recycler or a scrap processor under &sect; 15-502 of the Transportation Article.</text>
</subsection></section><section id=":g23a::1:::4A:" db-date="20060801"><enum>4A.</enum>
<subsection id=":g23a::1:::4A:a:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(a)</enum>
<text>The legislative body of each municipal corporation may adopt an ordinance for the licensing, control, location, or maintenance within its jurisdiction of a business establishment that allows on its premises any activity involving nudity and sexual displays listed in Article 2B, &sect; 10-405(c) through (f) of the Code.</text>
</subsection><subsection id=":g23a::1:::4A:b:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(b)</enum>
<paragraph id=":g23a::1:::4A:b:1:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(1)</enum>
<text>A person who violates an ordinance adopted under this section is guilty of a misdemeanor and on conviction is subject to imprisonment not exceeding 6 months and a fine of not less than $500.</text>
</paragraph><paragraph id=":g23a::1:::4A:b:2:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(2)</enum>
<text>Each day on which a violation continues is a separate offense.</text>
</paragraph></subsection></section><section id=":g23a::1:::5:" db-date="20060801"><enum>5.</enum>
<text>If any provision of this article, or the applicability thereof to any person or circumstances, is held invalid, the remainder of this article and the applicability thereof to other persons and circumstances shall not be affected thereby.</text>
</section><section id=":g23a::1:::7:" db-date="20060801"><enum>7.</enum>
<text>The legislative body of every incorporated municipality in this State by whatsoever name known, and the governing authorities of the several counties, within those areas of the respective counties which lie without the boundaries of any such incorporated municipality therein, shall have power to establish conservation areas within said municipality and to define the boundaries thereof and to vest, for a period not exceeding five years, exclusive jurisdiction or authority to enforce, within any conservation area, such laws, ordinances, codes, rules and regulations, or portions or parts thereof, as the legislative body of said municipality may deem expedient in any suitable board, commission, department, bureau or agency of such municipality, which it is hereby empowered to create and establish for such purposes; provided that nothing contained in this section shall authorize any such board, commission, department, bureau or agency to conflict, impede, obstruct, hinder or interfere with the powers of the police commissioner, police department or police force of such municipality.</text>
<text>For the purposes of this section the term &ldquo;conservation area&rdquo; shall mean any area within a municipality which the legislative body thereof shall find to be so affected by blight and community or property deterioration as to require comprehensive renovation and rehabilitation. Provided that, the provisions of this section shall not apply to Baltimore City. Nothing in this section shall be construed to apply to or affect Anne Arundel, Calvert, Howard, Kent, Wicomico, Worcester and Somerset counties.</text>
</section><section id=":g23a::1:::7A:" db-date="20060801"><enum>7A.</enum>
<text>An incorporated municipality may exercise any power or authority conferred by the provisions of Article 25 of this Code, in the subtitle &ldquo;Public Recreation and Parks&rdquo;.</text>
</section><section id=":g23a::1:::8:" db-date="20060801"><enum>8.</enum>
<text>All meetings, regular and special, of the legislative body, by whatever name known, in every municipal corporation in Maryland, including the City of Baltimore, shall be public meetings and open to the public at all times. Nothing contained herein shall be construed to prevent any such body from holding an executive session from which the public is excluded but no ordinance, resolution, rule or regulation shall be finally adopted at such an executive session.</text>
</section><section id=":g23a::8C:::8C:" db-date="20060801"><enum>8C.</enum>
<subsection id=":g23a::8C:::8C:a:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(a)</enum>
<text>The mayor and city council, by whatever name known, of every municipal corporation in this State is authorized and empowered to lend or provide, upon such terms as may be agreed upon, the use of tools, vehicles, implements, materials, consultants, services, and other assistance to another political subdivision for purposes deemed to be public and of benefit to the municipal corporation and the other political subdivision.</text>
</subsection><subsection id=":g23a::8C:::8C:b:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(b)</enum>
<paragraph id=":g23a::8C:::8C:b:1:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(1)</enum>
<text>If a county provides for the levy and collection of a development impact fee on new residential construction to finance the costs of school construction, a municipal corporation shall assist the county in the collection of the fee for new residential construction within the municipal corporation by:</text>
<subparagraph id=":g23a::8C:::8C:b:1:i:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(i)</enum>
<text>Collecting and remitting the fee to the county; or</text>
</subparagraph><subparagraph id=":g23a::8C:::8C:b:1:ii:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(ii)</enum>
<text>Requiring the fee to be paid to the county in accordance with the county development impact fee law or ordinance.</text>
</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id=":g23a::8C:::8C:b:2:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(2)</enum>
<text>The application of any impact fees paid under paragraph (1) of this subsection shall have a rational nexus to the project for which the fees are assessed.</text>
</paragraph><paragraph id=":g23a::8C:::8C:b:3:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(3)</enum>
<text>The provisions of this subsection may not be construed to affect any existing agreements between a county and municipal corporation concerning the levying and collection of development impact fees.</text>
</paragraph></subsection></section><section db-date="20120611" id=":g23a::9:1::9:"><enum>9.</enum><subsection db-date="20120611" id=":g23a::9:1::9:a:"><enum>(a)</enum><text>As used in this subtitle the term &ldquo;municipal corporation&rdquo; shall include all cities, towns and villages, now or hereafter created under any general or special law of this State for general governmental purposes, which are subject to the provisions of Article XI-E of the Maryland Constitution, which possess legislative, administrative and police powers for the general exercise of municipal functions, and which carry on such functions through a set of elected and other officials. The term is not to include any special tax area or district, sanitary district, park or planning district, soil conservation district or other public agency exercising specific powers within a defined area but which does not exercise general municipal functions and the term is not to include the Mayor and City Council of Baltimore. Nothing herein contained shall be construed to confer upon any municipal corporation, as herein defined, located within any such tax area or district, the power by incorporation, charter amendment, annexation or otherwise to exercise or perform, divest or duplicate, within its corporate limits any of the special powers or duties theretofore conferred upon the board, commission, authority or public corporation, created or appointed in accordance with law, to administer any such special tax area or district except that, subject to the consent or approval of the board, commission, authority or public corporation having jurisdiction, any municipal corporation may provide within its corporate limits parks, gardens, playgrounds and other recreational facilities, nor shall any provision of this subtitle be construed to empower any municipal corporation as herein defined, by incorporation, charter amendment, annexation, or otherwise, to exclude the area within its corporate limits from the levy of taxes upon property in such area or the imposition therein of special benefit assessments or service charges for the support of any such board, commission, authority or other public corporation. No local law conferring special powers or duties on any such board, commission, authority or public corporation shall be construed to divest any municipal corporation exercising the same powers or performing the same duties within its corporate limits, in accordance with law, of its right to continue the exercise of such powers or the performance of such duties, it being the intent hereof to avoid duplication in the rendition of public services. The General Assembly hereby finds, determines and declares that the term &ldquo;municipal corporation&rdquo; in Article XI-E of the Maryland Constitution does not embrace or include any such special tax area or district or the board, commission, authority or public corporation administering the same.</text></subsection><subsection db-date="20120611" id=":g23a::9:1::9:b:"><enum>(b)</enum><text>The term &ldquo;municipal corporation&rdquo; does not embrace or include the Washington Suburban Sanitary Commission, or the Washington Suburban Sanitary District under the jurisdiction of such Commission; the term &ldquo;municipal corporation&rdquo; does not embrace or include the Maryland-National Capital Park and Planning Commission, or the Maryland-Washington Metropolitan District or the Maryland-Washington Regional District under the jurisdiction of such Commission.</text></subsection><subsection db-date="20120611" id=":g23a::9:1::9:c:"><enum>(c)</enum><paragraph db-date="20120611" id=":g23a::9:1::9:c:1:"><enum>(1)</enum><text>A municipal corporation which is subject to the provisions of Article XI&ndash;E of the Maryland Constitution may not amend its charter or exercise its powers of annexation, incorporation or repeal of charter as to affect or impair in any respect the powers relating to sanitation, including sewer, water and similar facilities, and zoning, of the Washington Suburban Sanitary Commission or of the Maryland&ndash;National Capital Park and Planning Commission. Except that where any area is annexed to a municipality authorized to have and having then a planning and zoning authority, the municipality shall have exclusive jurisdiction over planning and zoning and subdivision control within the area annexed; provided nothing in this exception shall be construed or interpreted to grant planning and zoning authority or subdivision control to a municipality not authorized to exercise that authority at the time of such annexation; and further provided, that no municipality annexing land may for a period of five years following an annexation, permit development of the annexed land for land uses substantially different than the use authorized, or at a substantially higher, not to exceed 50&percnt;, density than could be granted for the proposed development, in accordance with the zoning classification of the county applicable at the time of the annexation without the express approval of the board of county commissioners or county council of the county in which the municipality is located.</text></paragraph><paragraph db-date="20120611" id=":g23a::9:1::9:c:2:"><enum>(2)</enum><text>If the county expressly approves, the municipality, without regard to the provisions of &sect; 4&ndash;204 of the Land Use Article, may place the annexed land in a zoning classification that permits a land use or density different from the land use or density specified in the zoning classification of the county or agency having planning and zoning jurisdiction over the land prior to its annexation applicable at the time of the annexation.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection db-date="20120611" id=":g23a::9:1::9:d:"><enum>(d)</enum><text>As used in this subtitle, the term &ldquo;qualified to vote&rdquo; or &ldquo;qualified voter&rdquo; shall mean those persons who under the terms of a municipal charter shall be authorized to vote in elections within that municipal corporation.</text></subsection><subsection db-date="20120611" id=":g23a::9:1::9:e:"><enum>(e)</enum><text>As used in this subtitle, the term &ldquo;municipal charter&rdquo; shall include the existing charter and all local laws of the General Assembly relating to the incorporation, organization, government, or affairs concerning administration and services, of said municipal corporation.</text></subsection></section><section id=":g23a::9:2::9A:" db-date="20060801"><enum>9A.</enum>
<subsection id=":g23a::9:2::9A:a:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(a)</enum>
<text>Whenever the mayor and city council, by whatever name known, of any municipal corporation in this State (as defined in &sect; 9(a) of this article) causes, or is required to cause any of the following documents to be created, implemented or otherwise established, the respective documents shall be deposited with the Department of Legislative Services, and in the manner, as prescribed by this section.</text>
<paragraph id=":g23a::9:2::9A:a:1:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(1)</enum>
<text>A code or compilation containing all or a portion of the municipal charter, published or issued in printed, mimeographed or similar duplicated form; as provided for in &sect; 9(e) of this article.</text>
</paragraph><paragraph id=":g23a::9:2::9A:a:2:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(2)</enum>
<text>A charter amendment or amendments ordained or passed by the legislative body of the municipal corporation, or as adopted by the vote on the question at a public referendum; including (i) the complete text of it, (ii) the date of the referendum election, if any, (iii) the number of votes cast for or against each question containing the charter amendment or amendments, whether in the legislative body or in a referendum, and (iv) the effective date of the charter amendment or amendments; as provided for in &sect; 17(f) of this article.</text>
</paragraph><paragraph id=":g23a::9:2::9A:a:3:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(3)</enum>
<text>A complete list of the measures which enact, amend, or repeal sections in the municipal charter, identifying each charter section affected by number and title; as provided for in &sect; 17A(a), (b), and (c) of this article.</text>
</paragraph><paragraph id=":g23a::9:2::9A:a:4:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(4)</enum>
<text>A charter amendment, ordinance, referendum or any other device by which the corporate boundaries of the municipality are enlarged or otherwise changed; including (i) a copy of the complete text of it with a statement of the new boundaries, (ii) the date of the referendum election, if any, (iii) the number of votes cast for or against the annexation, whether in the legislative body or in a referendum, and (iv) the effective date of the annexation; as provided for in &sect; 19(p) of this article.</text>
</paragraph><paragraph id=":g23a::9:2::9A:a:5:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(5)</enum>
<text>A unified charter providing for the merger of two or more municipal corporations; including (i) the complete text of it, (ii) the date of the referendum election, if any, (iii) the number of votes cast for or against the adoption of the unified charter, whether in the legislative bodies or in a referendum, and (iv) the effective date of the unified charter; as provided for in &sect; 19A(j) of this article.</text>
</paragraph><paragraph id=":g23a::9:2::9A:a:6:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(6)</enum>
<text>A charter providing for the creation of a new municipal corporation; including (i) the complete text of it, (ii) the date of the referendum election, (iii) the number of votes cast for and against the question of incorporation, under the charter, and (iv) the effective date of the charter; as provided for in &sect; 27(a) of this article.</text>
</paragraph><paragraph id=":g23a::9:2::9A:a:7:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(7)</enum>
<text>A charter amendment providing for the entire repeal of the charter of a municipal corporation, ordained or passed by the legislative body of the municipal corporation, or as adopted by the vote on the question at a public referendum; including (i) the complete text of it, (ii) the date of the referendum election, if any, (iii) the number of votes cast for or against the charter amendment, whether in the legislative body or in a referendum, and (iv) the effective date of the charter amendment; as provided for in &sect; 41 of this article.</text>
</paragraph><paragraph id=":g23a::9:2::9A:a:8:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(8)</enum>
<text>In addition to the document and referenda enumerated elsewhere in this subsection, a statement on the results of any referendum on any proposed charter amendment held during the year, and any referendum pending, actually or potentially, but not yet held, at the end of the year; as provided for in &sect; 17A(d) of this article.</text>
</paragraph></subsection><subsection id=":g23a::9:2::9A:b:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(b)</enum>
<text>The mayor or other chief executive officer, by whatever name known, of each municipal corporation shall send, or cause to be sent, separately by mail, bearing a postmark from the United States Postal Service, one copy of each of the documents, as appropriate, enumerated in subsection (a) of this section to the Department of Legislative Services.</text>
</subsection><subsection id=":g23a::9:2::9A:c:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(c)</enum>
<text>The mayor or other chief executive officer, by whatever name known, of each municipal corporation shall send to the Department of Legislative Services:</text>
<paragraph id=":g23a::9:2::9A:c:1:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(1)</enum>
<text>A charter amendment resolution within 10 days after the resolution becomes effective under &sect; 13(f) or &sect; 16(c) of this article; or</text>
</paragraph><paragraph id=":g23a::9:2::9A:c:2:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(2)</enum>
<text>An annexation resolution within 10 days after the resolution becomes effective under &sect; 19(e) or (l) of this article.</text>
</paragraph></subsection></section><section id=":g23a::9:3::10:" db-date="20060801"><enum>10.</enum>
<text>Pursuant to the provisions of &sect; 2 of Article XI-E of the Constitution of Maryland, requiring the General Assembly to group the several municipal corporations in this State into not more than four classes based upon population, the General Assembly hereby declares that there is one class of such municipal corporations. Every municipal corporation in this State, as defined by &sect; 9 above, shall be taken and considered as a member of that class, and as subject to the constitutional and statutory laws applicable thereto.</text>
</section><section id=":g23a::9:4::11:" db-date="20060801"><enum>11.</enum>
<text>Every municipal corporation in this State shall proceed as in this subheading provided in exercising and applying the powers for the amendment of municipal charters which are granted thereto by Article XI-E of the Constitution of Maryland.</text>
</section><section id=":g23a::9:4::12:" db-date="20060801"><enum>12.</enum>
<text>An amendment of a municipal charter may be initiated by the legislative body of the municipal corporation or by a petition of qualified voters of the municipal corporation.</text>
</section><section id=":g23a::9:4::13:" db-date="20060801"><enum>13.</enum>
<subsection id=":g23a::9:4::13:a:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(a)</enum>
<text>The legislative body of the municipal corporation, by whatever name known, may initiate a proposed amendment or amendments to the municipal charter, by a resolution which, except as otherwise specified in this subtitle, is ordained or passed as in the usual course of considering resolutions in the government of the municipal corporation by a majority of all the persons elected to the legislative body.</text>
</subsection><subsection id=":g23a::9:4::13:b:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(b)</enum>
<text>In conformity with a requirement imposed upon the General Assembly by Article III, &sect; 29 of the Constitution of Maryland, the resolution shall contain the complete and exact wording of the proposed amendment or amendments, prepared so that the section or sections are set forth as they would read when amended or enacted. No charter and no section of a charter may be revised or amended by reference to its title or section only.</text>
</subsection><subsection id=":g23a::9:4::13:c:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(c)</enum>
<text>In conformity with a requirement imposed upon the General Assembly by Article III, &sect; 29 of the Constitution of Maryland, every charter amendment adopted by a municipal corporation shall embrace but one subject, and that shall be described in its title.</text>
</subsection><subsection id=":g23a::9:4::13:d:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(d)</enum>
<text>The mayor or other chief executive officer of the municipal corporation, by whatever name known, shall give notice by posting and publication of any resolution which proposes an amendment or amendments to the municipal charter. A complete and exact copy of the resolution containing the proposed amendment or amendments shall be posted at the town hall or other main municipal building or public place for a period of at least forty days following its adoption.</text>
</subsection><subsection id=":g23a::9:4::13:e:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(e)</enum>
<text>A fair summary of the proposed amendment or amendments shall be published in a newspaper of general circulation in the municipal corporation not less than four times, at weekly intervals within a period of at least forty days starting immediately after the date of the adoption of the resolution containing the proposed amendment or amendments.</text>
</subsection><subsection id=":g23a::9:4::13:f:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(f)</enum>
<text>The amendment or amendments so proposed by the legislative body of the municipal corporation shall become and be considered a part of the municipal charter, according to the terms of the amendment or amendments, in all respects to be effective and observed as such, upon the fiftieth day after being so ordained or passed, unless on or before the fortieth day after being so ordained or passed there shall be presented to the legislative body of the municipal corporation, or mailed to it by certified mail, return receipt requested, bearing a postmark from the United States Postal Service, a petition meeting the requirements of this section.</text>
</subsection><subsection id=":g23a::9:4::13:g:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(g)</enum>
<text>The petition shall be signed by twenty per centum or more of the persons who are qualified to vote in municipal general elections of the particular municipal corporation and shall request that the proposed amendment or amendments be submitted on referendum to the voters of the municipal corporation. Each person signing the petition shall indicate thereon both his name and residence address. Upon receiving the petition for a referendum, the legislative body of the municipal corporation is directed to verify that any person who signed it is qualified to vote in its municipal general elections and shall consider the petition as of no effect if it is signed by fewer than twenty per centum of the persons who are qualified to vote in municipal general elections.</text>
</subsection><subsection id=":g23a::9:4::13:h:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(h)</enum>
<text>If the petition for a referendum complies with the requirements of this section, the legislative body shall by resolution, passed as in its normal legislative procedure, specify the day and the hours for the election at which the question shall be submitted to the voters of the municipal corporation. This may be at either the next regular municipal general election or at a special election, in the discretion of the legislative body. In the event a special election is designated, it shall be held within a period of not less than forty days nor more than sixty days after the final passage of the resolution providing for the referendum. The resolution providing for the referendum shall specify the exact wording which is to be placed on the ballots or voting machines when the question is submitted to the voters of the municipal corporation.</text>
</subsection></section><section id=":g23a::9:4::14:" db-date="20060801"><enum>14.</enum>
<subsection id=":g23a::9:4::14:a:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(a)</enum>
<text>Twenty per centum or more of the persons who are qualified to vote in municipal general elections in the particular municipal corporation may initiate a proposed amendment or amendments to the municipal charter, by a petition presented to the legislative body of the municipal corporation, by whatever name known. The petition shall contain the complete and exact wording of the proposed amendment or amendments, and the proposed amendment or amendments shall be prepared in conformity with the several requirements contained in subsections (b) and (c) of &sect; 13 of this subtitle. Each person signing it shall indicate thereon both his name and residence address. Upon receiving the petition, the legislative body is directed to verify that any person who signed it is qualified to vote in municipal general elections, and shall consider the petition as of no effect if it is signed by fewer than twenty per centum of the persons who are qualified to vote in municipal general elections. If the petition complies with the requirements of this section, the legislative body shall by resolution, passed as in its normal legislative procedure, and not later than sixty days after the petition shall have been presented to it, specify the day and the hours for the election at which the question shall be submitted to the voters of the municipal corporation. This may be at either the next regular municipal general election or at a special election, in the discretion of the legislative body. In the event a special election is designated, it shall be within a period of not less than forty days nor more than sixty days after the final passage of the resolution. In the resolution, the exact wording shall be specified which is to be placed on the ballots or voting machines when the question is submitted to the voters of the municipal corporation.</text>
</subsection><subsection id=":g23a::9:4::14:b:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(b)</enum>
<text>Provided, however, that if the legislative body shall approve of the amendment or amendments provided for in the petition presented to it under subsection (a) above, it shall have the right by resolution to adopt the amendment or amendments thereby proposed and to proceed thereafter in the same manner as if the amendment or amendments had been initiated by such legislative body and in compliance with the provisions of &sect; 13 of this article.</text>
</subsection></section><section id=":g23a::9:4::15:" db-date="20060801"><enum>15.</enum>
<text>The mayor or other chief executive officer of the municipal corporation, by whatever name known, shall give notice by posting and publication of any submission of a proposed charter amendment to the voters thereof. For not less than the four weeks immediately preceding the election at which the question is to be submitted a complete and exact copy of the wording of the proposed amendment or amendments shall be posted at the town hall or other main municipal building or in a public place. On the day of the election, a similar copy shall be posted at the place or places for voting. Notice of the election, together with a fair summary of the proposed amendment or amendments, shall be published in a newspaper of general circulation in the municipal corporation, not less than once in each of the four weeks immediately preceding the election.</text>
</section><section id=":g23a::9:4::16:" db-date="20060801"><enum>16.</enum>
<subsection id=":g23a::9:4::16:a:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(a)</enum>
<text>On the day and during the hours specified for any referendum, the proposed charter amendment or amendments shall be submitted to the qualified voters of the municipal corporation. The official or officials thereof whose duty it is to arrange for and conduct the regular municipal elections shall perform the same duties so far as relevant to the referendum election on the proposed charter amendment or amendments. It is the intent of this section that the referendum election shall be conducted generally according to the procedures and practices observed for regular municipal elections, except as specifically or necessarily modified by the provisions of this subheading. The wording specified by the legislative body of the municipal corporation, in the resolution providing for a referendum on the charter amendment or amendments, shall be placed on the ballots or voting machines used at the referendum election. The expenses of the referendum election shall be defrayed by the municipal corporation.</text>
</subsection><subsection id=":g23a::9:4::16:b:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(b)</enum>
<text>The official or officials charged with the duty to arrange for and conduct the referendum, promptly following the closing of the polls, shall tally the results thereof, and shall forthwith certify the results of the referendum to the mayor or other chief executive officer of the municipal corporation.</text>
</subsection><subsection id=":g23a::9:4::16:c:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(c)</enum>
<text>If a majority of those who vote on any question so submitted to the voters of the municipal corporation shall cast their votes in favor of the proposed charter amendment or amendments, the mayor or other chief executive officer of the municipal corporation shall so proclaim publicly within ten days after receiving a certification of the votes from the officials conducting the referendum; and on the thirtieth day following the public proclamation the proposed charter amendment or amendments shall become a part of the charter of the municipal corporation, according to its terms, in all respects to be effective and observed as such. If less than a majority of those who vote on any such question shall cast their votes in favor of the proposed charter amendment or amendments, the mayor or other chief executive officer likewise shall so proclaim, adding to his proclamation the statement that the proposed charter amendment or amendments contained in said question are null and void and of no effect whatsoever.</text>
</subsection></section><section id=":g23a::9:4::17:" db-date="20060801"><enum>17.</enum>
<subsection id=":g23a::9:4::17:a:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(a)</enum>
<text>In any proposal to amend an existing charter of a municipal corporation, the new matter, if any, to be added to the charter shall be indicated by being underscored or in italics or typed or printed completely in capital letters and all matter to be eliminated from the existing charter, if any, shall be indicated in its proper place by enclosing such matter in double parentheses or in boldface brackets. Where the subject matter consists of an entirely new section or sections the words of such new section or sections shall also be underscored or in italics or typed or printed completely in capital letters or contain some marginal or other notation to that effect. When the purpose of any proposal is to repeal in entirety any section or sections of the existing charter, the matter intended to be repealed need not be written out in full and enclosed in either double parentheses or boldface brackets.</text>
</subsection><subsection id=":g23a::9:4::17:b:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(b)</enum>
<text>The resolution to amend a charter shall identify the source of the existing section or sections, citing the code or other publication or amendment in which appears the most recent text of the section or sections to be amended.</text>
</subsection><subsection id=":g23a::9:4::17:c:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(c)</enum>
<text>Amendments to the charter of any municipal corporation shall be in a consecutively numbered series.</text>
</subsection><subsection id=":g23a::9:4::17:d:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(d)</enum>
<text>The resolution to amend a charter shall provide specifically (and not simply by implication) for the repeal of any section or sections of the existing charter which are inconsistent with the amended section or sections.</text>
</subsection><subsection id=":g23a::9:4::17:e:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(e)</enum>
<text>A proposal to amend a charter, whether initiated by the legislative body of the municipal corporation or by a petition of qualified voters of the municipal corporation, may not be rescinded after its adoption by the legislative body or after its formal submission in a petition, in any manner other than that of another charter amendment.</text>
</subsection><subsection id=":g23a::9:4::17:f:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(f)</enum>
<text>At the time a charter amendment or amendments become effective by reason of having been ordained or passed by the legislative body of the municipal corporation, or at the time of making public proclamation as to the vote on any question containing a proposed charter amendment or amendments which have been adopted, the mayor or other chief executive officer of the municipal corporation shall send the information concerning the charter amendment or amendments to the Department of Legislative Services as provided in &sect; 9A of this article.</text>
</subsection></section><section id=":g23a::9:4::17A:" db-date="20060801"><enum>17A.</enum>
<subsection id=":g23a::9:4::17A:a:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(a)</enum>
<text>At the end of each calendar or fiscal year, each municipal corporation shall furnish in a convenient and legible compilation a complete set of the measures dealt with during that year which enact, amend, or repeal sections in its municipal charter. The measures in the compilation shall be in a numerical sequence, beginning with No. 1, and in a separate series for each year.</text>
</subsection><subsection id=":g23a::9:4::17A:b:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(b)</enum>
<text>Copies of this compilation shall be made available for inspection at the office of the mayor and town council, by whatever name known, during normal business hours; and copies shall be kept on permanent record in the same office. The foregoing copies shall be furnished without charge, and the county also may make other copies available at a reasonable cost to any person.</text>
</subsection><subsection id=":g23a::9:4::17A:c:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(c)</enum>
<text>Not later than March 1 of the next succeeding year, the municipal corporation, without charge, shall furnish copies of the compilation to the Department of Legislative Services as provided in &sect; 9A of this article.</text>
</subsection><subsection id=":g23a::9:4::17A:d:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(d)</enum>
<text>In addition to furnishing copies of the compilation, the municipal corporation shall provide to the Department of Legislative Services as provided in &sect; 9A of this article, a statement concerning any referendum on any proposed charter amendment.</text>
</subsection><subsection id=":g23a::9:4::17A:e:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(e)</enum>
<text>At the end of each calendar year the Department of Legislative Services shall address an inquiry to each municipal corporation inquiring whether or not during that calendar year or its latest fiscal year it has enacted, amended or repealed any portion of its municipal charter. The municipal corporation shall promptly answer the inquiry and shall verify, by a signed and notarized statement, that copies of all such enactments, amendments, or repeals have already been sent to the Department.</text>
</subsection><subsection id=":g23a::9:4::17A:f:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(f)</enum>
<text>If the municipal corporation fails or refuses to supply copies of this compilation and of the results of any referenda thereon to the Department of Legislative Services by March 1 of the next succeeding year, or fails or refuses to certify that there have been no such enactments, amendments, or repeals, or referenda, during the last calendar or fiscal year, the Department shall promptly certify that fact to the State Comptroller, who then may order the discontinuance of all funds, grants or State aid which the municipal corporation is entitled to receive under State law. The section refers specifically to all funds, grants or State aid which the municipal corporation is entitled to receive under applicable provisions of State law relating to the income tax, the tax on racing, the recordation tax, the admissions and amusement tax, and the license tax.</text>
</subsection><subsection id=":g23a::9:4::17A:g:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(g)</enum>
<text>The Department of Legislative Services shall receive the several compilations and statements thus delivered to it. The titles of the laws of the several municipal corporations which amend their charters shall be arranged in a logical and convenient order and shall be delivered to the State printer for inclusion in the Session Laws of the General Assembly for its regular session in that year. The titles of the laws of the municipal corporations which amend their charters shall be printed and identified as such, and they shall be indexed with or in a supplemental volume to the laws enacted by the General Assembly.</text>
</subsection></section><section id=":g23a::9:4::17B:" db-date="20060801"><enum>17B.</enum>
<subsection id=":g23a::9:4::17B:a:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(a)</enum>
<text>The Department of Legislative Services shall compile the charters of all municipal corporations in this State into a single publication.</text>
</subsection><subsection id=":g23a::9:4::17B:b:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(b)</enum>
<text>The Department shall update the compilation of charters on a regular basis.</text>
</subsection></section><section id=":g23a::9:4::17C:" db-date="20060801"><enum>17C.</enum>
<text>At least once each year the Department of Legislative Services shall forward all documents that it receives under this article to the State Archives for permanent retention and storage.</text>
</section><section id=":g23a::9:4::17D:" db-date="20060801"><enum>17D.</enum>
<subsection id=":g23a::9:4::17D:a:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(a)</enum>
<text>For the purpose of providing ready access to a current compilation of the municipal corporation&rsquo;s ordinances, the mayor and city council (by whatever name known) of each municipal corporation in the State subject to Article XI-E of the Constitution of Maryland, and the Mayor and City Council of Baltimore, shall provide annually (if the municipal corporation during the past year has enacted any ordinances appropriate for codification) for the editing, preparation, publication, and sale or other distribution of a supplement to its most recent code of ordinances, or of a new edition of the code.</text>
</subsection><subsection id=":g23a::9:4::17D:b:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(b)</enum>
<text>A supplement shall contain all public ordinances of general application and continuing force which for the municipal corporation are in effect and have been enacted or amended since publication of the most recent code of public ordinances; and a new code shall contain all public ordinances of general application in effect for the municipal corporation at the time of publication. A supplement or a code need not contain ordinances of less than general application and continuing force, including (without limitation) the budget ordinance.</text>
</subsection><subsection id=":g23a::9:4::17D:c:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(c)</enum>
<text>For the purposes of this section, an ordinance is any legislative enactment (by whatever name known) of general application and continuing force for the municipal corporation, other than a public local law referred to in &sect; 32A of Article 25 of this Code.</text>
</subsection><subsection id=":g23a::9:4::17D:d:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(d)</enum>
<text>Each municipal corporation shall levy and appropriate its public funds for expenditures necessary under this section.</text>
</subsection></section><section id=":g23a::9:4::18:" db-date="20060801"><enum>18.</enum>
<text>The exact text of any amendment or amendments to the charter of any municipal corporation, adopted as in this subheading specified, shall thereafter be included in any subsequent edition or codification of the charter of the municipal corporation, until altered, modified or repealed by a subsequent amendment or amendments to the charter.</text>
</section><section db-date="20120613" id=":g23a::9:5::19:"><enum>19.</enum><subsection db-date="20120613" id=":g23a::9:5::19:a:"><enum>(a)</enum><text>The legislative body, by whatever name known, of every municipal corporation in this State may enlarge its corporate boundaries as provided in this subheading; but this power shall apply only to land:</text><paragraph db-date="20120613" id=":g23a::9:5::19:a:1:" role="item"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Which is contiguous and adjoining to the existing corporate area; and</text></paragraph><paragraph db-date="20120613" id=":g23a::9:5::19:a:2:" role="item"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Which does not create any unincorporated area which is bounded on all sides by real property presently within the corporate limits of the municipality, real property proposed to be within the corporate limits of the municipality as a result of the proposed annexation, or any combination of such properties.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection db-date="20120613" id=":g23a::9:5::19:b:"><enum>(b)</enum><paragraph db-date="20120613" id=":g23a::9:5::19:b:1:"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The proposal for change may be initiated by resolution regularly introduced into the legislative body of the municipal corporation, in accordance with the usual requirements and practices applicable to its legislative enactments, and also in conformity with the several requirements contained in subsections (b) and (c) of &sect; 13 of this subtitle, but only after the legislative body has obtained the consent for the proposal from not less than 25 percent of the persons who reside in the area to be annexed and who are registered as voters in county elections and from the owners of not less than 25 percent of the assessed valuation of the real property located in the area to be annexed. The resolution shall describe by a survey of courses and distances, and may also describe by landmarks and other well&ndash;known terms, the exact area proposed to be included in the change, and shall contain complete and detailed provisions as to the conditions and circumstances applicable to the change in boundaries and to the residents and property within the area to be annexed.</text></paragraph><paragraph db-date="20120613" id=":g23a::9:5::19:b:2:"><enum>(2)</enum><subparagraph db-date="20120613" id=":g23a::9:5::19:b:2:i:"><enum>(i)</enum><text>The requirements of paragraph (1) for consent of resident voters and property owners do not apply if on or before January 1, 1983 the property to be annexed is:</text><sub-subparagraph db-date="20120613" id=":g23a::9:5::19:b:2:i:1:" role="item"><enum>1.</enum><text>Bounded on all sides by real property presently within the corporate limits of the municipality, and the entire area is to be included in the same annexation;</text></sub-subparagraph><sub-subparagraph db-date="20120613" id=":g23a::9:5::19:b:2:i:2:" role="item"><enum>2.</enum><text>The size of the area does not exceed 1.5 percent of the present area of the municipal corporation; and</text></sub-subparagraph><sub-subparagraph db-date="20120613" id=":g23a::9:5::19:b:2:i:3:" role="item"><enum>3.</enum><text>The number of residents in the area does not exceed 1 percent of the population of the municipal corporation.</text></sub-subparagraph></subparagraph><subparagraph db-date="20120613" id=":g23a::9:5::19:b:2:ii:"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>A resolution of annexation under this paragraph is not subject to the referendum provisions of subsection (f) of this section.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph db-date="20120613" id=":g23a::9:5::19:b:2:iii:"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>The provisions of this paragraph shall be of no effect and may not be exercised after June 30, 1984.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection db-date="20120613" id=":g23a::9:5::19:c:"><enum>(c)</enum><text>The proposal for change also may be initiated by a written petition signed by not less than twenty&ndash;five per centum (25&percnt;) of the persons who reside in the area to be annexed and who are registered as voters in county elections in the precinct or precincts in which the territory to be annexed is located, and by the owners of not less than twenty&ndash;five per centum (25&percnt;) of the assessed valuation of the real property located in the area to be annexed. Upon the presentation of a petition to the legislative body of the municipal corporation, the presiding officer thereof shall cause to be made a verification of the signatures thereon and shall ascertain that the persons signing the petition represent at least twenty&ndash;five per centum (25&percnt;) of the persons who reside in the area to be annexed and who are registered as voters in county elections in the precinct or precincts in which the territory to be annexed is located, and the owners of twenty&ndash;five per centum (25&percnt;) of the assessed valuation of the real property located in the area to be annexed. Upon verifying that the requirements of this subsection have been complied with, the presiding officer of the legislative body shall promptly cause to be introduced therein a resolution proposing the change of boundaries as requested by the petition. The resolution in form and content shall conform to the requirements of this section.</text></subsection><subsection db-date="20120613" id=":g23a::9:5::19:d:"><enum>(d)</enum><text>After the introduction of the resolution into the legislative body of the municipal corporation, the chief executive and administrative officer of the municipal corporation shall cause a public notice thereof to be published not fewer than four times or, if the total area of the proposed annexation is for 25 acres of land or less, not fewer than two times, at not less than weekly intervals in a newspaper or newspapers of general circulation in the municipal corporation and the area to be annexed, briefly and accurately describing the proposed change and the conditions and circumstances applicable. The public notices shall specify a time and place at which a public hearing will be held by the legislative body on the resolution; the hearing shall be set for not less than 15 days after the fourth publication of the notices or, if the total area of the proposed annexation is for 25 acres of land or less, not less than 15 days after the second publication of the notices, and shall be held either within the boundaries of the municipal corporation or within the area to be annexed. The public hearing may be continued or rescheduled for a subsequent time not to exceed 30 days from the day for which the meeting was originally scheduled, or the day on which the hearing commenced but was not completed. In the event of a continuation or rescheduling, a single public notice shall be given at least seven days prior to the continued or rescheduled date in a newspaper of general circulation in the municipal corporation and in the area whose annexation is to be discussed, briefly and accurately describing the property whose annexation is to be discussed, and specifying the day, time, and place of the public hearing. Immediately upon the first publication of the public notice, a copy of the public notice shall be provided to the governing body of the county and any regional and State planning agencies having jurisdiction within the county. Each of these agencies and jurisdictions shall have the first right to be heard at the scheduled public hearing, after which the hearing shall be open to the general public.</text></subsection><subsection db-date="20120613" id=":g23a::9:5::19:e:"><enum>(e)</enum><text>Following the public hearing, the legislative body may proceed to enact the resolution, in accordance with the usual requirements and practices applicable to its legislative enactments. The resolution shall not become effective until at least forty&ndash;five (45) days following its final enactment.</text></subsection><subsection db-date="20120613" id=":g23a::9:5::19:f:"><enum>(f)</enum><text>At any time within the 45 day period following the final enactment of the resolution, a number of persons equal to not less than 20 percent of the persons who reside in the area to be annexed and who are registered as voters in county elections in the precinct or precincts in which the territory to be annexed is located may, in writing, petition the chief executive and administrative officer of the municipal corporation for a referendum on the resolution. Upon the presentation of a petition to the officer, he shall cause to be made a verification of the signatures thereon and shall ascertain that the persons signing the petition represent at least 20 percent of the persons who reside in the area to be annexed and who are registered as voters in county elections in the precinct or precincts in which the territory to be annexed is located. Upon verifying that the requirements of this subsection have been complied with, the officer shall by proclamation suspend the effectiveness of the resolution, contingent upon the results of the referendum.</text></subsection><subsection db-date="20120613" id=":g23a::9:5::19:g:"><enum>(g)</enum><text>At any time within the forty&ndash;five (45) day period following the final enactment of the resolution, a number of persons equal to not less than twenty per centum (20&percnt;) of the qualified voters of the municipal corporation may, in writing, petition the chief executive and administrative officer of the municipal corporation for a referendum on the resolution. Upon the presentation of a petition to the officer, he shall cause to be made a verification of the signatures thereon and shall ascertain that the persons signing the petition represent at least twenty per centum (20&percnt;) of the qualified voters of the municipal corporation. Upon verifying that the requirements of this subsection have been complied with, the officer shall by proclamation suspend the effectiveness of the resolution, contingent upon the results of the referendum.</text></subsection><subsection db-date="20120613" id=":g23a::9:5::19:h:"><enum>(h)</enum><text>At any time within the 45&ndash;day period following the final enactment of the resolution, the governing body of the county or counties in which the municipality is located, by at least a two&ndash;thirds majority vote, may petition in writing the chief executive and administrative officer of the municipal corporation for a referendum on the resolution. Upon verifying that there has been compliance with the requirements of this subsection, the officer by proclamation shall suspend the effectiveness of the resolution, contingent upon the results of the referendum.</text></subsection><subsection db-date="20120613" id=":g23a::9:5::19:i:"><enum>(i)</enum><text>The chief executive and administrative officer of the city, town or village shall set a date for the referendum on the ordinance or resolution, which shall be not less than fifteen (15) days and not more than ninety (90) days from the publication of notices therefor. Such notices shall be published twice at not less than weekly intervals in a newspaper or newspapers of general circulation in the municipal corporation and the area to be annexed. The notices shall specify the time and place or places at which the referendum will be held; the place or places shall be within the limits of the area to be annexed for the referendum within that area, and shall be within the limits of the municipal corporation for the referendum in this latter place.</text></subsection><subsection db-date="20120613" id=":g23a::9:5::19:j:"><enum>(j)</enum><text>On the date and at the places specified, the resolution proposing a change in the corporate boundaries of the municipal corporation shall be submitted to a referendum election of the qualified voters of the municipal corporation or of the persons who reside in the area to be annexed and who are registered as voters in county elections in the precinct or precincts in which the territory to be annexed is located, or both, depending upon whether a petition for referendum has been presented by the residents of the municipal corporation, or by the residents of the area proposed to be annexed or by both such sets of residents. The petition for referendum presented by the governing body of the county shall be acted upon in the same manner as a petition for referendum presented by the residents of the area proposed to be annexed. The ballots or the voting machines, as the case may be, shall contain a summary of the resolution, with suitable provision for the voter to indicate a choice for or against it.</text></subsection><subsection db-date="20120613" id=":g23a::9:5::19:k:"><enum>(k)</enum><text>For the purposes of this section, in any instance in which there are fewer than twenty persons living in any area proposed to be annexed who are eligible to sign a petition and to participate in a referendum election under the provisions of this section, any person owning real property in the area proposed to be annexed (the word &ldquo;person&rdquo; here including an association, the two or more joint owners of jointly&ndash;owned property, a firm or corporation) shall have a right equal to that of a natural person to sign a petition or to participate in a referendum election.</text></subsection><subsection db-date="20120613" id=":g23a::9:5::19:l:"><enum>(l)</enum><text>If only one petition for a referendum is filed and if a majority of the persons voting on the question in that referendum shall vote in favor of the proposal for change, the change shall become effective as proposed on the fourteenth day following the referendum. If two petitions for referendum are filed, the votes cast for the two referenda shall be tabulated separately, so as to show individually the tabulation of votes cast in the municipal corporation and in the area to be annexed. If in both tabulations, each being reckoned separately, a majority of the persons voting on the question shall vote in favor of the proposal for change, the change shall become effective as proposed on the fourteenth day following the referendum. In the event there are two referenda, unless there is such a favorable majority in both tabulations, reckoned separately, the proposal for change shall be void and of no further effect whatsoever.</text></subsection><subsection db-date="20120613" id=":g23a::9:5::19:m:"><enum>(m)</enum><text>The provisions of this section shall authorize an increase in the area within any municipal corporation only as to land which is not then within the corporate limits of any other municipal corporation.</text></subsection><subsection db-date="20120613" id=":g23a::9:5::19:n:"><enum>(n)</enum><text>The resolution to add to the corporate boundaries of a municipal corporation shall provide generally that the persons residing in the area to be annexed, and their property, shall be added to the corporate boundaries, generally subject or not subject, as the case may be, to the provisions of the charter of the municipal corporation; except that for stated periods and under specific conditions provision may be made for special treatment of the residents and property in the area to be annexed, as to rates of municipal taxation and as to municipal services and facilities. No change shall be made in these provisions for special treatment for stated periods and under specific conditions, except by resolution enacted in accordance with the provisions and requirements of this section.</text></subsection><subsection db-date="20120613" id=":g23a::9:5::19:o:"><enum>(o)</enum><paragraph db-date="20120613" id=":g23a::9:5::19:o:1:"><enum>(1)</enum><text>In addition to, but not as a part of the resolution, the legislative body of the municipal corporation shall adopt an annexation plan for the area proposed to be annexed.</text></paragraph><paragraph db-date="20120613" id=":g23a::9:5::19:o:2:"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The annexation plan shall be open to public review and discussion at the public hearing, but amendments to the annexation plan may not be construed in any way as an amendment to the resolution, nor may they serve in any manner to cause a reinitiation of the annexation procedure then in process.</text></paragraph><paragraph db-date="20120613" id=":g23a::9:5::19:o:3:"><enum>(3)</enum><subparagraph db-date="20120613" id=":g23a::9:5::19:o:3:i:"><enum>(i)</enum><text>A copy of the annexation plan shall be provided to the governing body of the county or counties in which the municipal corporation is located, the Department of Planning, and any regional and State planning agencies having jurisdictions within the county at least 30 days prior to the holding of the public hearing required by this section.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph db-date="20120613" id=":g23a::9:5::19:o:3:ii:"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Except as provided in paragraph (4) of this subsection, for annexations that begin before October 1, 2009, the annexation plan shall contain a description of the land use pattern proposed for the area to be annexed, which may include any county master plan already in effect for the area. It shall be presented so as to demonstrate the available land for public facilities which may be considered reasonably to be necessitated by the proposed use, such as school sites, water or sewage treatment facilities, libraries, recreation, fire or police. It shall contain also a statement describing the schedule for extending to the area to be annexed each municipal service performed within the municipality at the time of annexation and a statement as to the general methods by which the municipality anticipates to finance the extension of municipal services into the area to be annexed.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph db-date="20120613" id=":g23a::9:5::19:o:3:iii:"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>Except as provided in paragraph (4) of this subsection, for annexations that begin on or after October 1, 2009, the annexation plan shall be consistent with the municipal growth element of the comprehensive plan of the municipal corporation.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph db-date="20120613" id=":g23a::9:5::19:o:3:iv:"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>For the purposes of subparagraphs (ii) and (iii) of this paragraph, an annexation begins if:</text><sub-subparagraph db-date="20120613" id=":g23a::9:5::19:o:3:iv:1:" role="item"><enum>1.</enum><text>A proposal for change is initiated by resolution in accordance with subsection (b) of this section; or</text></sub-subparagraph><sub-subparagraph db-date="20120613" id=":g23a::9:5::19:o:3:iv:2:" role="item"><enum>2.</enum><text>A proposal for change is initiated by written petition in accordance with subsection (c) of this section.</text></sub-subparagraph></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph db-date="20120613" id=":g23a::9:5::19:o:4:"><enum>(4)</enum><subparagraph db-date="20120613" id=":g23a::9:5::19:o:4:i:"><enum>(i)</enum><text>A municipal corporation may submit an annexation plan in accordance with paragraph (3)(ii) of this subsection, if on or after October 1, 2009, a municipal corporation is granted an extension for the inclusion of a municipal growth element in accordance with &sect; 3&ndash;304 of the Land Use Article.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph db-date="20120613" id=":g23a::9:5::19:o:4:ii:"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>After the expiration of a final extension granted under &sect; 3&ndash;304 of the Land Use Article for the inclusion of a municipal growth element, an annexation plan shall be submitted in accordance with paragraph (3)(iii) of this subsection.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection db-date="20120613" id=":g23a::9:5::19:p:"><enum>(p)</enum><text>The chief executive and administrative officer of a municipal corporation which has enlarged its corporate boundaries under the provisions of this section shall promptly send the annexation resolution with the new boundaries to the clerk or similar official, to the clerk of the court in the county or counties in which the municipal corporation is located, to the Department of Legislative Services as provided in &sect; 9A of this article, and for those municipalities lying within the regional district, to the Maryland&ndash;National Capital Park and Planning Commission. Each such official shall hold the annexation resolution with the new boundaries on record and shall make it available for public inspection during all normal business hours.</text></subsection><subsection db-date="20120613" id=":g23a::9:5::19:q:"><enum>(q)</enum><text>Repealed.</text></subsection><subsection db-date="20120613" id=":g23a::9:5::19:r:"><enum>(r)</enum><text>The mayor and council, by whatever name known, of every municipal corporation is hereby authorized and empowered, by ordinance, resolution or regulation, to make proper provision for conducting, and for tabulating the results of any referendum to be held under the provisions of this section. The mayor and council of the municipal corporation shall pay in full for the expenses of any such referendum.</text></subsection><subsection db-date="20120613" id=":g23a::9:5::19:s:"><enum>(s)</enum><text>The powers granted to municipal corporations by Article XI&ndash;E of the Constitution, by this article, and by Division I of the Land Use Article, shall not be deemed to authorize any municipal corporation, either through procedures under this subheading or other changes in its charter, to exercise planning (including subdivision control) and zoning jurisdiction or power within any political subdivision in which such planning and zoning jurisdiction or power, or either, is exercised by any State, regional or county agency or authority. Except that where any area is annexed to a municipality authorized to have and having then a planning and zoning authority, the said municipality shall have exclusive jurisdiction over planning and zoning and subdivision control within the area annexed; provided that nothing in this exception shall be construed or interpreted to grant planning and zoning authority to a municipality not authorized to exercise such authority at the time of such annexation.</text></subsection></section><section id=":g23a::9:6::19A:" db-date="20060801"><enum>19A.</enum>
<subsection id=":g23a::9:6::19A:a:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(a)</enum>
<text>Two or more municipal corporations situated within the same county may unite to form one municipal corporation if any part of the legal boundary of one of the municipal corporations abuts on the legal boundary of the other uniting municipal corporations. No merger shall become effective without the prior approval of the governing body of the county in which the municipal corporations are situated.</text>
</subsection><subsection id=":g23a::9:6::19A:b:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(b)</enum>
<text>Unification of the municipal corporations shall be initiated by the passage of a &ldquo;proposal of unification&rdquo; in substantially the same form by the legislative bodies of each of the uniting corporations. The proposal of unification shall include a detailed description of the boundaries of the area of proposed unification. The description shall comprise a survey of courses and distances and may also be by general landmarks and place names. The proposal of unification must be approved by each of the municipal corporations in the manner provided for the adoption of other ordinary legislation by the municipal charter or bylaws of the municipal corporation which is considering the proposal of unification. Upon approval of the proposal of unification, the municipal corporations shall prepare a unified charter.</text>
</subsection><subsection id=":g23a::9:6::19A:c:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(c)</enum>
<text>Each of the unifying municipal corporations shall designate the same number of representatives, which may not be less than three nor more than five, who shall meet together as a charter commission to draft a unified charter within six months of the adoption of the proposal of unification required by this section. These representatives shall adopt rules and elect officers from among their number as they feel necessary to govern their meetings and expedite the drafting of the unified charter; but none of these rules may conflict with any of the provisions and requirements of Article 23A of the Code.</text>
</subsection><subsection id=":g23a::9:6::19A:d:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(d)</enum>
<text>The unified charter shall provide that the unified municipal corporation receive all of the assets and unpaid debts of the individual municipal corporations.</text>
</subsection><subsection id=":g23a::9:6::19A:e:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(e)</enum>
<text>The unified charter may contain all the powers held by the separate municipal corporations, but if all of the corporations to be included in the unified municipal corporation do not possess planning and zoning powers, the land of those corporations not having that power shall not, for a period of five years following the effective date of the unified charter, be placed in a zoning classification which permits a land use substantially different from the use for such land specified in the current and duly adopted master plan or plan of the county or agency having planning and zoning jurisdiction over that land prior to its inclusion in the unified municipal corporation, unless amended under the procedures required by the county in which the municipal corporation is situated. Nothing in this section shall be construed to provide planning and zoning power to any unified municipal corporation if none of the separate corporations to be included in the unified corporation possess that power.</text>
</subsection><subsection id=":g23a::9:6::19A:f:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(f)</enum>
<paragraph id=":g23a::9:6::19A:f:1:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(1)</enum>
<text>The draft of the unified charter shall be submitted by the representatives to each of the legislative bodies of the municipal corporations. The draft shall be included in a resolution to be adopted and conform to the procedural requirements provided for amendments in &sect; 13 of this article; and for the purposes of subsection (c) of &sect; 13 of this article, the resolution shall be regarded as embracing only one subject.</text>
</paragraph><paragraph id=":g23a::9:6::19A:f:2:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(2)</enum>
<text>The legislative bodies of the municipal corporations may adopt or reject the resolution as a whole. No amendment or change may be made in any part of the resolution unless the other legislative bodies of the municipalities concur in the change.</text>
</paragraph></subsection><subsection id=":g23a::9:6::19A:g:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(g)</enum>
<text>The municipal corporations which approve the unified charter shall transfer those assets and liabilities not otherwise disposed of by the effective date of the unification charter, to the unified corporation. The transfer shall be accomplished by legal instruments separate and apart from the unified charter or the resolution, and the invalidity of any of the legal instruments which transfer or dispose of the property of the municipal corporations shall not affect the validity or legal force and effect of the unified charter. The unified charter shall be considered and promulgated as a legal document separate from any other legal instrument.</text>
</subsection><subsection id=":g23a::9:6::19A:h:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(h)</enum>
<text>If a referendum election is required pursuant to &sect; 13 of this article, it shall be conducted on the same day in all areas to be included in the unified municipal corporation. The cost and administration of the referendum shall be borne by the municipal corporations proportionately to the population of each of the municipalities. The approval of a majority of the voters casting votes in each of the uniting municipal corporations is necessary to adopt the unified charter in a referendum election. Approval of the unified charter by voters in a referendum election when required, or by the legislative bodies of each of the uniting municipal corporations when a referendum election is not required, is final and not subject to further action.</text>
</subsection><subsection id=":g23a::9:6::19A:i:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(i)</enum>
<text>If the unified municipal charter is not approved by the required vote at a referendum election held pursuant to this article, the proposed unification shall be null and void.</text>
</subsection><subsection id=":g23a::9:6::19A:j:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(j)</enum>
<text>Within 60 days after the unified charter is adopted by the legislative bodies of the unifying municipal corporations or by a referendum election, the legislative bodies of the unifying municipal corporations shall jointly send the information concerning the charter adopted by the unified municipal corporation to the Department of Legislative Services, as provided in &sect; 9A of this article.</text>
</subsection><subsection id=":g23a::9:6::19A:k:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(k)</enum>
<text>The exact text of the charter of the unified municipal corporation, adopted under the provisions of this article and as amended from time to time, shall thereafter be included in any edition or codification of the charter of the unified municipal corporation.</text>
</subsection></section><section id=":g23a::9:7::20:" db-date="20060801"><enum>20.</enum>
<subsection id=":g23a::9:7::20:a:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(a)</enum>
<paragraph id=":g23a::9:7::20:a:1:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(1)</enum>
<text>In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated.</text>
</paragraph><paragraph id=":g23a::9:7::20:a:2:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(2)</enum>
<text>&ldquo;County governing body&rdquo; means the board of county commissioners or county council of a county.</text>
</paragraph><paragraph id=":g23a::9:7::20:a:3:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(3)</enum>
<text>&ldquo;County liaison&rdquo; means a county official, or the designee of the county official, who is responsible for coordinating communication between the organizing committee and the county.</text>
</paragraph><paragraph id=":g23a::9:7::20:a:4:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(4)</enum>
<text>&ldquo;Organizing committee&rdquo; means the group of individuals from the organizing community that is responsible for working with the county governing body on the proposed municipal incorporation after a petition for incorporation is verified.</text>
</paragraph><paragraph id=":g23a::9:7::20:a:5:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(5)</enum>
<text>&ldquo;Organizing community&rdquo; means individuals residing within a particular unincorporated area who are interested in forming a municipal corporation.</text>
</paragraph></subsection><subsection id=":g23a::9:7::20:b:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(b)</enum>
<text>This subtitle governs the incorporation of any area and group of individuals, not then existing as a municipal corporation. An area proposed for incorporation shall contain at least 300 bona fide residents before it may proceed under the provisions of this subtitle.</text>
</subsection></section><section id=":g23a::9:7::21:" db-date="20060801"><enum>21.</enum>
<subsection id=":g23a::9:7::21:a:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(a)</enum>
<paragraph id=":g23a::9:7::21:a:1:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(1)</enum>
<text>At least 20&percnt; of the individuals who reside within any particular area in a county and who are registered to vote in county elections, together with the owners of at least 25&percnt; of the assessed valuation of the real property of the area to be incorporated, may initiate a proposal to incorporate that area as a municipal corporation, by presenting a valid petition to the county governing body.</text>
</paragraph><paragraph id=":g23a::9:7::21:a:2:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(2)</enum>
<text>At least 25&percnt; of the individuals who reside within any particular area in a county and who are registered to vote in county elections may initiate a proposal to incorporate that area as a municipal corporation, by presenting a valid petition to the county governing body.</text>
</paragraph></subsection><subsection id=":g23a::9:7::21:b:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(b)</enum>
<paragraph id=":g23a::9:7::21:b:1:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(1)</enum>
<text>The Office of the Attorney General shall create a standard petition form for use by any organizing community within the State.</text>
</paragraph><paragraph id=":g23a::9:7::21:b:2:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(2)</enum>
<text>The Attorney General shall provide the board of supervisors of elections of each county with the form created under paragraph (1) of this subsection for dissemination to any organizing community.</text>
</paragraph></subsection><subsection id=":g23a::9:7::21:c:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(c)</enum>
<text>A petition presented under subsection (a) of this section shall:</text>
<paragraph id=":g23a::9:7::21:c:1:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(1)</enum>
<text>Express the interest of the subscribing individuals in the incorporation of their area;</text>
</paragraph><paragraph id=":g23a::9:7::21:c:2:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(2)</enum>
<text>Contain a detailed description of the boundaries of the area proposed to be incorporated, including a survey of courses and distances or general landmarks and place names;</text>
</paragraph><paragraph id=":g23a::9:7::21:c:3:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(3)</enum>
<text>State the name chosen for the new municipal corporation, which may not be the same name as that used by any existing municipal corporation or county in the State; and</text>
</paragraph><paragraph id=":g23a::9:7::21:c:4:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(4)</enum>
<text>State the names of the individuals who will initially represent the organizing community on the organizing committee.</text>
</paragraph></subsection><subsection id=":g23a::9:7::21:d:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(d)</enum>
<text>The organizing community shall obtain the minimum number of required valid signatures within 18 months from the date that the organizing community received the standard petition form from the county board of supervisors of elections.</text>
</subsection><subsection id=":g23a::9:7::21:e:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(e)</enum>
<text>Each person signing the petition shall indicate on the petition the person&rsquo;s name and residential address and the location and assessed valuation of the person&rsquo;s property, if the person owns real property in the area to be incorporated and if the organizing community pursues the incorporation petition under subsection (a)(1) of this section.</text>
</subsection><subsection id=":g23a::9:7::21:f:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(f)</enum>
<text>Within 60 days of receiving a petition, the county governing body:</text>
<paragraph id=":g23a::9:7::21:f:1:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(1)</enum>
<text>Shall verify that each person who signed the petition resides in the particular area to be incorporated, is registered to vote in county elections, and, if applicable, owns real property within the area to be incorporated;</text>
</paragraph><paragraph id=":g23a::9:7::21:f:2:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(2)</enum>
<text>Shall verify that the petition meets the requirements of this section; and</text>
</paragraph><paragraph id=":g23a::9:7::21:f:3:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(3)</enum>
<text>If the petition meets the requirements of this section, shall appoint a county liaison.</text>
</paragraph></subsection><subsection id=":g23a::9:7::21:g:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(g)</enum>
<text>A petition when filed becomes the property of the county governing body and may not be used for the purposes of initiating further referenda.</text>
</subsection></section><section id=":g23a::9:7::22:" db-date="20060801"><enum>22.</enum>
<subsection id=":g23a::9:7::22:a:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(a)</enum>
<paragraph id=":g23a::9:7::22:a:1:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(1)</enum>
<text>Within 90 days from the verification of a valid petition, the organizing committee shall:</text>
<subparagraph id=":g23a::9:7::22:a:1:i:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(i)</enum>
<text>Actively seek information and input from the county government;</text>
</subparagraph><subparagraph id=":g23a::9:7::22:a:1:ii:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(ii)</enum>
<text>Hold a public meeting to collect public testimony on the proposed incorporation; and</text>
</subparagraph><subparagraph id=":g23a::9:7::22:a:1:iii:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(iii)</enum>
<text>Present the county governing body with a report on issues related to the proposed incorporation.</text>
</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id=":g23a::9:7::22:a:2:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(2)</enum>
<text>During the 90-day period required under paragraph (1) of this subsection, the county government shall cooperate fully with the organizing committee.</text>
</paragraph><paragraph id=":g23a::9:7::22:a:3:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(3)</enum>
<text>The organizing committee shall:</text>
<subparagraph id=":g23a::9:7::22:a:3:i:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(i)</enum>
<text>Notify the county liaison of all meetings and deliberations of the organizing committee; and</text>
</subparagraph><subparagraph id=":g23a::9:7::22:a:3:ii:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(ii)</enum>
<text>Ensure that the county liaison is given full opportunity to participate in all meetings and deliberations of the organizing committee.</text>
</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id=":g23a::9:7::22:b:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(b)</enum>
<text>Within 45 days of the receipt of the report required under subsection (a)(1)(iii) of this section, the county governing body or its designee may review the report and provide comments to the organizing committee on issues relating to the proposed incorporation.</text>
</subsection></section><section id=":g23a::9:7::23:" db-date="20060801"><enum>23.</enum>
<subsection id=":g23a::9:7::23:a:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(a)</enum>
<text>The organizing committee shall present to the county governing body a proposed charter for use in the referendum election:</text>
<paragraph id=":g23a::9:7::23:a:1:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(1)</enum>
<text>Within 45 days of receipt of the comments submitted to the organizing committee under &sect; 22(b) of this subtitle; or</text>
</paragraph><paragraph id=":g23a::9:7::23:a:2:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(2)</enum>
<text>If the county governing body has not submitted comments, no later than 90 days after the date the report is sent by the organizing committee under &sect; 22(a)(1)(iii) of this subtitle.</text>
</paragraph></subsection><subsection id=":g23a::9:7::23:b:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(b)</enum>
<text>The organizing committee shall also submit with the proposed charter statements that describe:</text>
<paragraph id=":g23a::9:7::23:b:1:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(1)</enum>
<text>The likely fiscal effect of the proposed incorporation on residents of the proposed municipality, residents in the vicinity of the proposed municipality, and the county as a whole;</text>
</paragraph><paragraph id=":g23a::9:7::23:b:2:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(2)</enum>
<text>The services the proposed municipality will provide; and</text>
</paragraph><paragraph id=":g23a::9:7::23:b:3:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(3)</enum>
<text>The impact the proposed incorporation will have on property tax rates.</text>
</paragraph></subsection></section><section id=":g23a::9:7::24:" db-date="20060801"><enum>24.</enum>
<subsection id=":g23a::9:7::24:a:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(a)</enum>
<text>Between 40 and 60 days after the county governing body receives the proposed charter from the organizing committee, the county governing body may specify, by resolution, the day and hours for a special referendum election on the proposed incorporation for the voters of the area to be incorporated.</text>
</subsection><subsection id=":g23a::9:7::24:b:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(b)</enum>
<text>The resolution described in subsection (a) of this section shall contain the exact wording of the proposed charter, as submitted by the organizing committee, to be voted on at the time of the referendum.</text>
</subsection><subsection id=":g23a::9:7::24:c:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(c)</enum>
<paragraph id=":g23a::9:7::24:c:1:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(1)</enum>
<text>If the county governing body rejects the referendum request, the county governing body shall provide in writing and make available to the general public within a reasonable time the reasons for rejecting the referendum request.</text>
</paragraph><paragraph id=":g23a::9:7::24:c:2:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(2)</enum>
<text>The county governing body shall establish reasonable procedures by which a reconsideration of a rejection of a referendum request can be undertaken, including an opportunity for a public hearing with sufficient advance public notice.</text>
</paragraph><paragraph id=":g23a::9:7::24:c:3:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(3)</enum>
<text>On completion of the hearing and review process, the county governing body shall by resolution affirm the rejection or grant the referendum request.</text>
</paragraph></subsection></section><section id=":g23a::9:7::25:" db-date="20060801"><enum>25.</enum>
<text>The county governing body shall give notice by posting and publication of the submission of the proposal of incorporation, including a fair summary of the proposed charter, to the voters of the area proposed to be incorporated. For not less than the 4 weeks immediately preceding the election at which the question is to be submitted, a complete and exact copy of the wording of the proposed charter shall be posted or available for public inspection at the office of the county governing body. On the day of the election a copy shall be posted or available for public inspection at the place or places for voting on the question of incorporation. Notice of the election, together with a fair summary of the proposed charter, shall be published in a newspaper or newspapers of general circulation in the particular area proposed to be incorporated not less than once in each of the 4 weeks immediately preceding the election.</text>
</section><section id=":g23a::9:7::26:" db-date="20060801"><enum>26.</enum>
<subsection id=":g23a::9:7::26:a:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(a)</enum>
<text>On the day and during the hours specified for the referendum, the question of incorporation under the proposed charter shall be submitted to the registered voters of the area proposed to be incorporated. The board of supervisors of elections of the county, and its clerks, judges of election and subordinates, shall arrange for and conduct the referendum. It is the intent of this section that the referendum election shall be conducted generally according to the procedures and practices observed for regular countywide elections, except as specifically or necessarily modified by the provisions of this subtitle. The wording specified by the county governing body, in the resolution providing for a referendum on the question of the proposed incorporation, shall be placed on the ballots or voting machines used at the referendum election.</text>
</subsection><subsection id=":g23a::9:7::26:b:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(b)</enum>
<text>The board of supervisors of elections, and its clerks, judges of election and subordinates, promptly following the closing of the polls shall tally the results thereof, and shall forthwith certify the results of the referendum to the county governing body.</text>
</subsection><subsection id=":g23a::9:7::26:c:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(c)</enum>
<text>If a majority of those who vote on any question so submitted to the voters of a particular area, proposing the incorporation thereof, shall cast their votes in favor of the incorporation under the proposed charter, the county governing body shall within 10 days after receiving a certification of the vote from the board of supervisors of elections so proclaim publicly, and on the 30th day following the public proclamation the area specified, and the residents thereof, shall be deemed to be a municipal corporation operating under and in accordance with the charter so proposed, in all respects to be effective and observed as the charter of the municipal corporation. If less than a majority of those who vote on any such question of proposed incorporation shall cast their votes in favor of the incorporation under the proposed charter, the county governing body likewise shall so proclaim, adding to the proclamation the statement that the proposed incorporation is of no effect and that as to the said proposed municipal incorporation the proposed charter is null and void and of no effect whatsoever.</text>
</subsection></section><section id=":g23a::9:7::27:" db-date="20060801"><enum>27.</enum>
<subsection id=":g23a::9:7::27:a:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(a)</enum>
<text>Subject to the provisions of subsection (b) of this section, the county governing body shall defray the expenses of:</text>
<paragraph id=":g23a::9:7::27:a:1:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(1)</enum>
<text>The referendum election;</text>
</paragraph><paragraph id=":g23a::9:7::27:a:2:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(2)</enum>
<text>The original election of officers; and</text>
</paragraph><paragraph id=":g23a::9:7::27:a:3:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(3)</enum>
<text>The reasonable costs of any third party consultants hired by the county governing body to analyze issues related to the proposed incorporation.</text>
</paragraph></subsection><subsection id=":g23a::9:7::27:b:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(b)</enum>
<text>If the referendum vote results in incorporation, the municipal corporation shall repay the total amount of the expenses specified in subsection (a) of this section to the county governing body, within 1 year following the effective date of the incorporation.</text>
</subsection><subsection id=":g23a::9:7::27:c:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(c)</enum>
<text>After 1 year from the effective date of the incorporation, a county governing body may withhold any payments due to the municipal corporation for purposes of satisfying any unpaid expenses specified in subsection (a) of this section.</text>
</subsection></section><section id=":g23a::9:7::28:" db-date="20060801"><enum>28.</enum>
<subsection id=":g23a::9:7::28:a:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(a)</enum>
<text>At the time of making public proclamation as to the vote on the question of incorporation under the proposed charter, the county governing body shall send the information concerning the charter adopted by the municipal corporation to the Department of Legislative Services, as provided in &sect; 9A of this article for municipal officials.</text>
</subsection><subsection id=":g23a::9:7::28:b:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(b)</enum>
<text>A proposal to incorporate a municipal corporation and to adopt a charter may not be rescinded after its formal submission, in any manner other than that of a formal charter repeal as provided in the subheading &ldquo;Repeal of Charter&rdquo; in this subtitle.</text>
</subsection><subsection id=":g23a::9:7::28:c:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(c)</enum>
<text>The charter is included in the requirements of &sect; 17A of this subtitle, including its printing and indexing in the laws enacted by the General Assembly.</text>
</subsection><subsection id=":g23a::9:7::28:d:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(d)</enum>
<text>The exact text of the charter of the municipal corporation, adopted under the provisions of this subtitle and as amended from time to time, shall thereafter be included in any edition or codification of the charter of the municipal corporation.</text>
</subsection></section><section id=":g23a::9:7::29:" db-date="20060801"><enum>29.</enum>
<subsection id=":g23a::9:7::29:a:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(a)</enum>
<text>If the referendum results in the creation of a new municipal corporation, the local income tax payments authorized under &sect; 2-607 of the Tax - General Article shall be distributed to the municipal corporation as follows unless the county governing body agrees to an accelerated payment schedule:</text>
<paragraph id=":g23a::9:7::29:a:1:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(1)</enum>
<text>In the first full fiscal year following the effective date of the municipal incorporation, one-third of the distribution otherwise required under &sect; 2-607 of the Tax - General Article;</text>
</paragraph><paragraph id=":g23a::9:7::29:a:2:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(2)</enum>
<text>In the second full fiscal year following the effective date of the municipal incorporation, two-thirds of the distribution otherwise required under &sect; 2-607 of the Tax - General Article; and</text>
</paragraph><paragraph id=":g23a::9:7::29:a:3:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(3)</enum>
<text>In the third full fiscal year following the effective date of the municipal incorporation and each subsequent year, all of the distribution required under &sect; 2-607 of the Tax - General Article.</text>
</paragraph></subsection><subsection id=":g23a::9:7::29:b:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(b)</enum>
<paragraph id=":g23a::9:7::29:b:1:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(1)</enum>
<text>For those municipal corporations that are eligible to assume planning and zoning authority, the county governing body and the municipal corporation shall cooperate in developing the first comprehensive land use plan of the municipal corporation.</text>
</paragraph><paragraph id=":g23a::9:7::29:b:2:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(2)</enum>
<text>The initial zoning designations used by the municipal corporation shall comply with the provisions of &sect; 9(c) of this article, including the 5-year zoning classification restriction, unless the county governing body expressly approves otherwise.</text>
</paragraph></subsection></section><section id=":g23a::9:7::30:" db-date="20060801"><enum>30.</enum>
<subsection id=":g23a::9:7::30:a:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(a)</enum>
<text>Town officers shall be nominated by a certificate of nomination filed by each candidate, with the county governing body, giving in each instance the name and residence address of the candidate, together with a statement of the particular office to which he aspires. Thereupon, the county governing body, together with the board of supervisors of elections for the county, shall prepare ballots or the voting machines so as to permit the registered voters of the particular area to vote upon the several candidates who are so nominated. The election of officers for the municipal corporation shall be arranged for and conducted at the same time and at the same place or places as the referendum election on the question of incorporation, and subject generally to the same procedures and practices. A vote cast against the proposed incorporation of the municipal corporation shall not be held to bar the voter from expressing his choices among the nominees for the several offices, and if less than a majority of those who vote on the question of incorporation cast their votes in favor thereof, the votes cast for election to the several offices shall be null and void and of no effect whatsoever.</text>
</subsection><subsection id=":g23a::9:7::30:b:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(b)</enum>
<text>The board of supervisors of elections, and its clerks, judges of election and subordinates, shall tally the results of the votes cast for candidates for office, and shall certify them along with the tally on the question of incorporation, to the county governing body.</text>
</subsection><subsection id=":g23a::9:7::30:c:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(c)</enum>
<text>Any person who receives a plurality of the votes cast for any particular office, whether or not he receives a majority of all the votes cast for that office, shall be publicly proclaimed by the county governing body to have been elected thereto. The persons so named by proclamation shall at the effective time for the charter become the several respective officers of the municipal corporation. Each officer shall continue to hold such position until regularly superseded by a new elective officer, elected as may be provided in the charter of the municipal corporation; and during such period he shall be taken and accepted in all respects as the elected officer of the municipal corporation in his respective position, with the powers, authority and duties as set forth and prescribed in the charter.</text>
</subsection><subsection id=":g23a::9:7::30:d:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(d)</enum>
<text>If no person is nominated for an office in the government of the municipal corporation, or if a person elected thereto is unable to assume his office, or if for any other reason no person is elected to fill an office, the county governing body shall name a resident of the particular area to the office, and upon assuming it he shall hold it in all respects as if regularly elected thereto as in this section provided.</text>
</subsection><subsection id=":g23a::9:7::30:e:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(e)</enum>
<text>No person shall be either nominated or elected to any office in the government of the municipal corporation unless he qualifies under whatever requirements may be specified for that office according to the charter proposed for the municipal corporation.</text>
</subsection></section><section id=":g23a::9:8::31:" db-date="20060801"><enum>31.</enum>
<text>Every municipal corporation shall have the power under this subheading to borrow money for any proper public purpose and to evidence such borrowing by the issue and sale of its general obligation bonds in the manner herein prescribed, unless the charter of said municipal corporation shall provide a different procedure for the borrowing of money or shall be amended so to provide in the manner set forth in this subtitle. Charter amendments for such purpose are hereby authorized. Notwithstanding the provisions of this subheading or of any such charter, every such municipal corporation shall also have the authority to exercise all powers conferred upon municipal corporations by Title 9 of the Environment Article. Every such municipal corporation shall likewise have authority to borrow money in anticipation of the receipt of current taxes and to evidence such borrowing by the issuance and sale of tax anticipation notes, payable as to principal and interest from said taxes when received, unless the charter of such municipal corporation shall otherwise provide or unless any such charter shall be amended pursuant to this subtitle so to provide otherwise. The procedure for the issuance of tax anticipation notes shall be as prescribed in &sect; 32 of this article, except that such notes may be sold by private negotiations. Whenever there shall be any conflict between the provisions of this subheading and the charter of any municipal corporation, the provisions of said charter shall control.</text>
</section><section id=":g23a::9:8::32:" db-date="20060801"><enum>32.</enum>
<subsection id=":g23a::9:8::32:a:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(a)</enum>
<text>All bonds of a municipal corporation shall be authorized by resolution or ordinance of the legislative body of said municipal corporation which shall contain the following:</text>
<paragraph id=":g23a::9:8::32:a:1:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(1)</enum>
<text>A statement of the public purpose upon which the proceeds of said bonds are to be expended;</text>
</paragraph><paragraph id=":g23a::9:8::32:a:2:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(2)</enum>
<text>The complete form of said bonds, which shall include the place or places and time or times of payment thereof, the rate or rates of interest payable thereon or space for the insertion of such rate or rates of interest upon the determination thereof, the titles of the officials whose signatures shall be affixed to or imprinted on such bonds, the authority for the issuance thereof and the taxes and any special revenues from which the principal of and interest on said bonds will be payable;</text>
</paragraph><paragraph id=":g23a::9:8::32:a:3:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(3)</enum>
<text>The form of the notice soliciting bids for the purchase of said bonds which shall set forth the date, place and time for receiving and opening bids and a brief description of the purpose or purposes for which said bonds are to be issued, a brief description of the denominations, maturities, terms and conditions of said bonds, a statement of the rate or rates of interest to be borne by said bonds or the manner of determining the same, a precise statement of the manner in which the best offer for said bonds will be determined and a reference to the resolution authorizing the same. Said notice of sale may also require prospective purchasers to submit bids on specified forms, may require such prospective purchasers to accompany their bids with good faith deposits in specified amounts, may make appropriate provisions for approval of the legality of such bonds, and may contain a financial statement of such municipal corporation. The foregoing provisions which may be included in any such notice of sale may also be separately set forth in a circular or official statement. The form of which shall likewise be adopted by a resolution or ordinance of said municipal corporation;</text>
</paragraph><paragraph id=":g23a::9:8::32:a:4:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(4)</enum>
<text>Specific provision for the appropriation and disposal of the proceeds of sale of any such bonds and a specific provision for the payment of the principal thereof and the interest thereon, which such provision shall specify the source or sources of payment and shall constitute a covenant binding the municipal corporation to provide the funds from such source or sources as and when said principal and interest shall be due and payable.</text>
</paragraph></subsection><subsection id=":g23a::9:8::32:b:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(b)</enum>
<text>Each such resolution shall be adopted by the legislative body of the municipal corporation in the manner prescribed by the charter of said municipal corporation for the adoption of ordinances and resolutions having the force of law but it shall not be necessary to submit any such resolution or ordinance or the question of the issuance of bonds authorized thereby to a referendum of the qualified voters of said municipal corporation unless said resolution or ordinance shall so provide or unless the charter of such municipal corporation shall so require. Each such resolution or ordinance may contain such other provisions, not inconsistent with this subheading, as the legislative body of such municipal corporation may deem appropriate, and may expressly permit the executive of such municipal corporation to make such modifications in the forms adopted by such resolution or ordinance as will not alter the substance of such forms.</text>
</subsection></section><section id=":g23a::9:8::33:" db-date="20060801"><enum>33.</enum>
<text>With respect to any bonds of a municipal corporation the resolution or ordinance authorizing the same may provide:</text>
<subsection id=":g23a::9:8::33::" role="item" db-date="20060801"> 
<paragraph id=":g23a::9:8::33::1:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(1)</enum>
<text>That the principal of and interest on said bonds shall be payable at one or more banks or trust companies, which may be either within or without the State;</text>
</paragraph><paragraph id=":g23a::9:8::33::2:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(2)</enum>
<text>That the official signatures and seals to be affixed to any such bonds, or the coupons if any attached thereto, except the signature of the clerk or secretary of such municipal corporation which shall be manually affixed, shall be imprinted on said bonds or coupons in facsimile;</text>
</paragraph><paragraph id=":g23a::9:8::33::3:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(3)</enum>
<text>That any such bonds shall be redeemable in whole or in part at the option of the municipal corporation at any time prior to the respective maturities thereof at such price or prices, either at or above the par value of such bonds as the municipal corporation may prescribe in the enabling resolution or ordinance, provided that any such bonds shall contain a statement of such redemption provisions and provided further that such enabling resolution or ordinance shall make provision for due and proper prior published notice of any such redemption;</text>
</paragraph><paragraph id=":g23a::9:8::33::4:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(4)</enum>
<text>That any such issue of bonds shall be in varying denominations and shall be in coupon form, registerable as to principal only, or in fully registered form, or both, provided that if both forms are authorized, the same shall be interchangeable;</text>
</paragraph><paragraph id=":g23a::9:8::33::5:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(5)</enum>
<text>That, in the event any official whose signature shall appear on any such bonds shall cease to be such official prior to the delivery of such bonds, or, in the event any such official whose signature shall appear on any such bonds shall have become such after the date of issue thereof, said bonds shall nevertheless be valid and binding obligations of any such municipal corporation in accordance with their terms.</text>
</paragraph></subsection></section><section id=":g23a::9:8::34:" db-date="20060801"><enum>34.</enum>
<text>The authority conferred on municipal corporations by this subheading is subject to the following limitations:</text>
<subsection id=":g23a::9:8::34::" role="item" db-date="20060801"> 
<paragraph id=":g23a::9:8::34::1:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(1)</enum>
<text>No tax anticipation notes shall be issued which shall mature later than eighteen months from their respective dates of issue and no bonds shall be issued by any municipal corporation which shall mature later than forty years from their respective date of issue;</text>
</paragraph><paragraph id=":g23a::9:8::34::2:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(2)</enum>
<text>No bonds or tax anticipation notes shall be issued by any municipal corporation except for cash or be sold at less than par value thereof;</text>
</paragraph><paragraph id=":g23a::9:8::34::3:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(3)</enum>
<text>If the charter of any municipal corporation shall require a referendum on the issue of all or any particular type of bonds of such municipal corporation, such bonds shall be issued only if a majority of the qualified voters voting on the referendum held on such issuance shall favor the same but if the majority of said qualified voters shall vote against such issuance then another referendum shall not be held on the question of issuing bonds for the same public purpose until the expiration of one year from the date upon which the issuance of said bonds shall have been so disapproved;</text>
</paragraph><paragraph id=":g23a::9:8::34::4:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(4)</enum>
<text>No bonds shall be sold by a municipal corporation except by the solicitation of competitive bids at public sale after the publication in a newspaper of general circulation in the municipal corporation, and such other publication as may be specified in the enabling resolution or ordinance, of the notice of sale in the form prescribed by such resolution or ordinance by two insertions thereof over a period of not less than ten days next preceding the date fixed for such sale.</text>
</paragraph></subsection></section><section id=":g23a::9:8::35:" db-date="20060801"><enum>35.</enum>
<text>All bonds and tax anticipation notes issued by any municipal corporation in accordance with its charter or in accordance with this subheading, shall have and possess all the attributes of negotiable instruments as provided in &sect; 8 of Article 31 of this Code. The principal of and interest on any such bonds or tax anticipation notes in the hands of the owner or owners thereof from time to time, shall be and remain exempt from taxation of any kind or nature whatsoever by the State of Maryland and by any county, municipal corporation or other political subdivision thereof.</text>
</section><section id=":g23a::9:8::36:" db-date="20060801"><enum>36.</enum>
<text>Any sinking fund established by any municipal corporation to provide for the payment of the principal of or interest on any bonds issued by any such municipal corporation pursuant to the provisions of its charter or of this subheading, shall not be invested by the fiscal officer of said municipal corporation having custody of said sinking fund except in the manner prescribed by &sect;&sect; 6 and 7 of Article 31 of this Code. Any such fiscal officer having custody of the proceeds of sale of any such bonds is hereby authorized and empowered to invest said proceeds, pending the expenditure thereof, in the manner and pursuant to the provisions of &sect; 22 of Article 95 of this Code.</text>
</section><section id=":g23a::9:8::37:" db-date="20060801"><enum>37.</enum>
<subsection id=":g23a::9:8::37:a:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(a)</enum>
<text>All bonds or tax anticipation notes issued by any municipal corporation pursuant to its charter or this subheading shall constitute pledges of the faith and credit of the issuing municipal corporation to the prompt payment, from the tax and other revenues described in the enabling resolution, of the principal of and interest on said bonds or tax anticipation notes when due.</text>
</subsection><subsection id=":g23a::9:8::37:b:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(b)</enum>
<text>If at the time of the issuance of any such bonds, there shall be no charter or statutory limit on the power of any such municipal corporation to levy property taxes, such pledge shall constitute a covenant on the part of the municipal corporation issuing any such bonds to levy upon all real and tangible personal property within its corporate limits subject to assessment for unlimited municipal taxation, ad valorem taxes in rate and amount sufficient in each year in which any of said bonds are outstanding to provide for the payment of the principal of and the interest on such bonds.</text>
</subsection><subsection id=":g23a::9:8::37:c:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(c)</enum>
<text>If at the time of issuance of any such bonds there shall be a charter or statutory limitation upon the power of any such municipal corporation to levy property taxes, then such pledge shall constitute a covenant on the part of said municipal corporation to levy ad valorem taxes as above described within the limitations so prescribed by law.</text>
</subsection><subsection id=":g23a::9:8::37:d:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(d)</enum>
<text>No charter provision or statute adopted or enacted after the date of issue of bonds of the types described in subparagraphs (b) and (c) above, which places a maximum limit on the rate at which property taxes may be imposed by any municipal corporation, or which removes any such limit theretofore existing, shall be taken or construed as impairing or in any manner affecting the covenants of said municipal corporation with respect to its bonds outstanding at the time any such charter provision or statute shall become effective.</text>
</subsection><subsection id=":g23a::9:8::37:e:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(e)</enum>
<text>No bonds shall be issued by a municipal corporation pursuant to its charter or the provisions of this subheading, if, by the issuance thereof, existing maximum limits on the power of such municipal corporation to incur indebtedness fixed by the charter of said municipal corporation or by statute, shall be exceeded, but no such maximum limitation imposed subsequent to the issue of any such bonds shall be taken or construed as impairing or in any manner affecting the obligation thereof, nor shall the obligation of any outstanding bonds of a municipal corporation be taken or construed as having been impaired or in any manner affected by the issuance of bonds pursuant to an increase in such maximum limitation on the power to incur indebtedness, or the elimination of such maximum limitation, enacted subsequent to the issue of said outstanding bonds.</text>
</subsection><subsection id=":g23a::9:8::37:f:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(f)</enum>
<text>Any such municipal corporation may, in addition to the pledge of its faith and credit and taxing power for the payment of the principal of and interest on any such bonds, secure such payment by the additional pledge thereto of any other revenues of said municipal corporation, including payments to said municipal corporation from the State or federal governments and special benefit assessments, taxes, fees or service charges which such municipal corporation is authorized and empowered to impose, levy or charge, and to the extent that any such revenues are sufficient in any year to provide for the payment of the principal of and interest on the bonds to which they are pledged, such municipal corporation shall not be obligated in such year to levy property taxes also pledged thereto and the failure of such municipal corporation to levy such property taxes, so long as said additional revenues are sufficient to satisfy said pledge, shall not be taken or construed as a breach of any of the above-described covenants of such municipal corporation.</text>
</subsection></section><section id=":g23a::9:8::38:" db-date="20060801"><enum>38.</enum>
<text>Every municipal corporation is hereby authorized by amendment of its charter in the manner prescribed in this subtitle or in any charter adopted hereunder, to provide for the issuance by such municipal corporation of bonds payable as to principal and interest solely from the revenues of one or more revenue-producing projects of such municipal corporation, which bonds shall not constitute an indebtedness of such municipal corporation to which its faith and credit or taxing power are pledged, and nothing contained in this subheading shall be construed as a limitation on the power of a municipal corporation so to make provision for the issuance of revenue bonds in its charter.</text>
</section><section id=":g23a::9:8::39:" db-date="20060801"><enum>39.</enum>
<text>Nothing contained in this article shall be deemed or construed to impair the terms and conditions of any bonds, notes or other obligations of any municipal corporation issued by such municipal corporation prior to the effective date of Article XI-E of the Constitution of this State.</text>
</section><section id=":g23a::9:9::40:" db-date="20060801"><enum>40.</enum>
<text>The legislative body of any municipal corporation is authorized and empowered to fix a date and to establish procedures for the submission of any local law, enacted pursuant to the provisions of &sect; 5 of Article XI-E of the Constitution of Maryland, placing a maximum limit on the rate at which property taxes may be imposed or regulating the maximum amount of debt which may be incurred by such municipal corporation, at any regular or special municipal election, to the voters of such municipal corporation for their approval; and to do whatever shall be necessary and proper in order to give effect to the requirement of &sect; 5 of Article XI-E of the Constitution of Maryland, that no such local law shall become effective in regard to a municipal corporation until and unless it shall have been approved at a regular or special municipal election by a majority of the voters of that municipal corporation voting on the question. The provisions of this section shall apply to any such local law enacted after the effective date of said Article XI-E.</text>
</section><section id=":g23a::9:10::41:" db-date="20060801"><enum>41.</enum>
<text>An entire repeal of the charter of a municipal corporation, and the termination of the existence of the municipal corporation, may be accomplished as generally provided above in the subheading &ldquo;Charter Amendments&rdquo;. The resolution of the legislative body of the municipal corporation or the petition of 20 percent or more of the qualified voters need not contain the text of the charter which it is proposed to repeal, but may simply state the fact of the proposed repeal. The posting and publication of the proposed repeal also may simply state that fact, as may the submission of the charter amendment resolution reflecting a favorable vote with the Department of Legislative Services, as provided in &sect; 9A of this article. From and after the time that the charter stands repealed it no longer may be included in any subsequent edition or printing of the code of public local laws of the county or State.</text>
</section><section id=":g23a::9:10::42:" db-date="20060801"><enum>42.</enum>
<text>The resolution or petition by which the proposal is initiated to repeal the charter of the municipal corporation may provide for the disposition of the property and assets thereof and the liquidation of its unpaid indebtedness. If no such disposition is made, the board of county commissioners or the county council shall succeed to full ownership, title and control of the property and assets after the charter stands repealed and shall likewise be responsible for payment of the debts and obligations of said municipal corporation in accordance with the terms thereof. The board or council also is authorized, in its discretion, to provide by written agreement with the proper officers of the municipal corporation, while the charter remains in effect, for taking over some or all of the property and assets or some or all of the liabilities and obligations of the municipal corporation, at the time the repeal of its charter becomes effective. The board or council shall establish a special tax area with boundaries coincident with those of the municipal corporation for which a charter was repealed, and tax or assess the residents of such area in such manner as other residents of the county may be taxed or assessed, in order to provide the revenue necessary to defray any obligations or debts of the municipal corporation as of the time the charter is repealed. Such taxes or assessments shall be imposed and collected with the same powers and procedures as exist for general county taxation; the proceeds thereof are to be applied only to such obligation or debt, and the tax or assessment shall be discontinued when all such obligations or debts have been paid in full.</text>
</section><section id=":g23a::9:10::43:" db-date="20060801"><enum>43.</enum>
<text>If any municipal corporation, subject to any of the provisions of this article, shall fail for three successive years to file with the Department of Legislative Services a comprehensive statement of financial condition as required by Article 24, &sect; 2-101 of the Code, and the Executive Director of the Department of Legislative Services shall have reasonable cause to suppose that the municipal corporation is no longer actively operating as such under its charter, and the Legislative Auditor shall certify that the municipal corporation has no obligations or debts outstanding and unpaid, the Executive Director of the Department of Legislative Services shall promptly certify all such facts to the Secretary of State. Upon receiving such a certification, the Secretary of State shall forthwith issue a public proclamation, declaring that the charter of the municipal corporation, including all amendments and additions thereto, is repealed under the provisions of this section. Copies of the proclamation shall be filed by the Secretary of State with the clerk of the Court of Appeals, the clerk of the circuit court of the county in which the municipal corporation is located, and the Department of Legislative Services. Upon the first day of the month next after the issue of any such proclamation, the charter of the town, including all amendments and additions thereto, shall be and the same is hereby declared to be repealed. From such latter date, the municipal corporation shall not be construed to be or treated as a municipal corporation and the charter so repealed shall no longer be included in any subsequent edition or printing of the code of public local laws of the State or of the particular county. If no other disposal of the property, assets and liabilities of the municipal corporation has previously been made by the proper officers of the municipal corporation, the board of county commissioners or the county council of the county in which the municipal corporation is located, shall succeed to full ownership, title and control of the property and assets after the charter stands repealed and shall be responsible for liquidation of the indebtedness of said municipal corporation as provided in &sect; 42 of this subtitle.</text>
</section><section id=":g23a::9:11::44:" db-date="20060801"><enum>44.</enum>
<subsection id=":g23a::9:11::44:a:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(a)</enum>
<text>Pursuant to the provisions of &sect; 5 of Article XI-E of the Constitution of Maryland prohibiting any municipal corporation classified by the General Assembly under the provisions of &sect; 2 of Article XI-E of the Constitution of Maryland from levying any type of tax, license fee, franchise tax or fee which was not in effect in the municipal corporation on January 1, 1954, unless it has received the express authorization of the General Assembly for that purpose, by a general law which in its terms and its effect applies alike to all similarly classified municipal corporations, the General Assembly hereby expressly authorizes all municipal corporations in this State within the class created by &sect; 10 of this article for the purpose of financing the design, construction, establishment, extension, alteration or acquisition of adequate storm drainage systems, for the purpose of financing the design, acquisition, establishment, improvement, extension, operation or alteration of public parking facilities, or pedestrian malls, for the purpose of financing the design, acquisition, erection, construction, improvement and maintenance of street and area lighting, for the purpose of financing the capital and operating costs to enhance police, fire protection, and rescue services, and for the purposes set forth in &sect; 2(b)(35) of this article, to create within their respective corporate limits special taxing districts for these purposes and to levy on all real and personal property located within these special taxing districts an ad valorem tax at a rate sufficient to provide adequate annual revenues to pay the principal and interest on any bonds or other obligations of the municipality issued for these purposes as the principal and interest become due, and to pay the costs of operating and maintaining these facilities and activities. These taxes shall be levied in the same manner, upon the same assessments, for the same period or periods, and as of the same date or dates of finality as are now or may hereafter be prescribed.</text>
</subsection><subsection id=":g23a::9:11::44:b:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(b)</enum>
<text>A municipal corporation subject to Article XI-E of the Constitution, whether through its municipal charter or otherwise, may through ordinance or resolution create a special taxing district for the purpose of financing the design, acquisition, establishment, improvement, extension, operation, alteration, or maintenance of a ride sharing or bus system. In the creation of such a taxing district, the municipal corporation shall fix, impose, and collect a combination of development impact fees and ad valorem taxes for financing, in whole or in part, the capital and operating costs of the additional or expanded ride sharing or bus system.</text>
</subsection></section><section id=":g23a::9:11::44A:" db-date="20100618"><enum>44A.</enum><subsection db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::9:11::44A:a:"><enum>(a)</enum><paragraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::9:11::44A:a:1:"><enum>(1)</enum><text>In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</text></paragraph><paragraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::9:11::44A:a:2:"><enum>(2)</enum><text>&ldquo;Bond&rdquo; means a revenue bond, note, or other similar instrument issued by a municipal corporation in accordance with this section.</text></paragraph><paragraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::9:11::44A:a:3:"><enum>(3)</enum><text>&ldquo;Cost&rdquo; includes the cost of:</text><subparagraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::9:11::44A:a:3:i:" role="item"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Construction, reconstruction, and renovation, and acquisition of all lands, structures, property, real or personal, rights, rights&ndash;of&ndash;way, franchises, easements, and interests acquired or to be acquired by the Maryland Economic Development Corporation, the State, any unit or department or political subdivision of the State, or any other governmental unit having jurisdiction over the infrastructure improvement;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::9:11::44A:a:3:ii:" role="item"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>All machinery and equipment including machinery and equipment needed to expand or enhance municipal services to the special taxing district;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::9:11::44A:a:3:iii:" role="item"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>Financing charges and interest prior to and during construction, and, if deemed advisable by the municipal corporation, for a limited period after completion of the construction, interest and reserves for principal and interest, including costs of municipal bond insurance and any other type of financial guaranty and costs of issuance;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::9:11::44A:a:3:iv:" role="item"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>Extensions, enlargements, additions, and improvements;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::9:11::44A:a:3:v:" role="item"><enum>(v)</enum><text>Architectural, engineering, financial, and legal services;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::9:11::44A:a:3:vi:" role="item"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>Plans, specifications, studies, surveys, and estimates of cost and of revenues;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::9:11::44A:a:3:vii:" role="item"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>Administrative expenses necessary or incident to determining to proceed with the infrastructure improvements; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::9:11::44A:a:3:viii:" role="item"><enum>(viii)</enum><text>Other expenses as may be necessary or incident to the construction, acquisition, and financing of the infrastructure improvements.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::9:11::44A:a:4:"><enum>(4)</enum><text>&ldquo;MEDCO obligation&rdquo; means any bond, note, or other similar instrument that the Maryland Economic Development Corporation issues under authority other than this section to finance the purposes specified in subsection (b)(2) or (d)(3) of this section only with respect to infrastructure improvements located in or supporting a transit&ndash;oriented development or a State hospital redevelopment.</text></paragraph><paragraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::9:11::44A:a:5:"><enum>(5)</enum><text>&ldquo;State hospital redevelopment&rdquo; means any combination of private or public commercial, residential, or recreational uses, improvements, and facilities that:</text><subparagraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::9:11::44A:a:5:i:" role="item"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Is part of a comprehensive coordinated development plan or strategy involving:</text><sub-subparagraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::9:11::44A:a:5:i:1:" role="item"><enum>1.</enum><text>Property that was occupied formerly by a State facility, as defined in &sect; 10&ndash;101 of the Health &ndash; General Article, or a State residential center, as defined in &sect; 7&ndash;101 of the Health &ndash; General Article; or</text></sub-subparagraph><sub-subparagraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::9:11::44A:a:5:i:2:" role="item"><enum>2.</enum><text>Property that is adjacent or reasonably proximate to property that was occupied formerly by a State facility, as defined in &sect; 10&ndash;101 of the Health &ndash; General Article, or a State residential center, as defined in &sect; 7&ndash;101 of the Health &ndash; General Article;</text></sub-subparagraph></subparagraph><subparagraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::9:11::44A:a:5:ii:" role="item"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>In accordance with design development principles, maximizes use of the property by those constituencies it is intended to serve; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::9:11::44A:a:5:iii:" role="item"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>Is designated as a State hospital redevelopment by:</text><sub-subparagraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::9:11::44A:a:5:iii:1:" role="item"><enum>1.</enum><text>The Smart Growth Subcabinet established under &sect; 9&ndash;1406 of the State Government Article; and</text></sub-subparagraph><sub-subparagraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::9:11::44A:a:5:iii:2:" role="item"><enum>2.</enum><text>The local government or multicounty agency with land use and planning responsibility for the relevant area.</text></sub-subparagraph></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::9:11::44A:a:6:"><enum>(6)</enum><text>&ldquo;Transit&ndash;oriented development&rdquo; has the meaning stated in &sect; 7&ndash;101 of the Transportation Article.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::9:11::44A:b:"><enum>(b)</enum><paragraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::9:11::44A:b:1:"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Subject to the provisions of this section, and for the purpose stated in paragraph (2) of this subsection, each municipal corporation in the State may:</text><subparagraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::9:11::44A:b:1:i:" role="item"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Create a special taxing district;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::9:11::44A:b:1:ii:" role="item"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Levy ad valorem or special taxes; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::9:11::44A:b:1:iii:" role="item"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>Issue bonds and other obligations.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::9:11::44A:b:2:"><enum>(2)</enum><subparagraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::9:11::44A:b:2:i:"><enum>(i)</enum><text>The purpose of the authority granted under paragraph (1) of this subsection is to provide financing, refinancing, or reimbursement for the cost of the design, construction, establishment, extension, alteration, or acquisition of adequate storm drainage systems, sewers, water systems, roads, bridges, culverts, tunnels, streets, sidewalks, lighting, parking, parks and recreation facilities, libraries, schools, and other infrastructure improvements as necessary, whether situated within the special taxing district or the municipal corporation or outside of the municipal corporation if notification is given to the governmental unit having jurisdiction over the infrastructure improvement and if the infrastructure improvement is reasonably related to other infrastructure improvements within the special taxing district, for the development and utilization of the land, each with respect to any defined geographic region within the municipal corporation.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::9:11::44A:b:2:ii:"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>The authority granted under paragraph (1)(i) and (ii) of this subsection also makes available a source of funding for payment of costs of:</text><sub-subparagraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::9:11::44A:b:2:ii:1:" role="item"><enum>1.</enum><text>Infrastructure improvements located in or supporting a transit&ndash;oriented development or a State hospital redevelopment; and</text></sub-subparagraph><sub-subparagraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::9:11::44A:b:2:ii:2:" role="item"><enum>2.</enum><text>Operation and maintenance of infrastructure improvements located in or supporting a transit&ndash;oriented development or a State hospital redevelopment.</text></sub-subparagraph></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id=":g23a::9:11::44A:c:" db-date="20100618"><enum>(c)</enum><paragraph id=":g23a::9:11::44A:c:1:" db-date="20100618"><enum>(1)</enum><text>In addition to other powers a municipal corporation may have, and notwithstanding the provisions of any other public local law, public general law, or municipal charter, a municipal corporation may borrow money by issuing and selling bonds for the purpose stated in subsection (b)(2) of this section if a request to the municipal corporation is made by both:</text><subparagraph id=":g23a::9:11::44A:c:1:i:" role="item" db-date="20100618"><enum>(i)</enum><text>At least two-thirds of the owners of the real property located within the special taxing district, provided that:</text><sub-subparagraph id=":g23a::9:11::44A:c:1:i:1:" role="item" db-date="20100618"><enum>1.</enum><text>Multiple owners of a single parcel are treated as a single owner; and</text></sub-subparagraph><sub-subparagraph id=":g23a::9:11::44A:c:1:i:2:" role="item" db-date="20100618"><enum>2.</enum><text>A single owner of multiple parcels is treated as one owner; and</text></sub-subparagraph></subparagraph><subparagraph id=":g23a::9:11::44A:c:1:ii:" role="item" db-date="20100618"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>The owners of at least two-thirds of the assessed valuation of the real property located within the special taxing district.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id=":g23a::9:11::44A:c:2:" db-date="20100618"><enum>(2)</enum><text>This section is self-executing and does not require any municipal corporation to amend its charter to exercise the powers granted under this section.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id=":g23a::9:11::44A:d:" db-date="20100618"><enum>(d)</enum><paragraph id=":g23a::9:11::44A:d:1:" db-date="20100618"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Bonds shall be payable from the special fund required under subsection (e) of this section.</text></paragraph><paragraph id=":g23a::9:11::44A:d:2:" db-date="20100618"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The governing body of a municipal corporation that issues bonds under this section may also:</text><subparagraph id=":g23a::9:11::44A:d:2:i:" role="item" db-date="20100618"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Establish sinking funds;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id=":g23a::9:11::44A:d:2:ii:" role="item" db-date="20100618"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Establish debt service reserve funds;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id=":g23a::9:11::44A:d:2:iii:" role="item" db-date="20100618"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>Pledge other assets and revenues towards the payments of the principal and interest; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id=":g23a::9:11::44A:d:2:iv:" role="item" db-date="20100618"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>Provide for municipal bond insurance or any other type of financial guaranty of the bonds.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id=":g23a::9:11::44A:d:3:" db-date="20100618"><enum>(3)</enum><text>All proceeds received from any bonds issued and sold shall be applied solely to pay the cost of infrastructure improvements, including:</text><subparagraph id=":g23a::9:11::44A:d:3:i:" role="item" db-date="20100618"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Costs of design, construction, establishment, extension, alteration, or acquisition of infrastructure improvements;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id=":g23a::9:11::44A:d:3:ii:" role="item" db-date="20100618"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Costs of issuing bonds;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id=":g23a::9:11::44A:d:3:iii:" role="item" db-date="20100618"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>Payment of the principal and interest on loans, money advances, or indebtedness incurred by a municipal corporation for any of the purposes stated in subsection (b)(2) of this section, including the refunding of bonds previously issued under this section; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id=":g23a::9:11::44A:d:3:iv:" role="item" db-date="20100618"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>Funding of a debt service reserve fund or payment of interest prior to, during, or for a limited period of time after construction.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::9:11::44A:e:"><enum>(e)</enum><paragraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::9:11::44A:e:1:"><enum>(1)</enum><subparagraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::9:11::44A:e:1:i:"><enum>(i)</enum><text>The governing body of the municipal corporation may:</text><sub-subparagraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::9:11::44A:e:1:i:1:" role="item"><enum>1.</enum><text>Designate by resolution an area or areas as a special taxing district;</text></sub-subparagraph><sub-subparagraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::9:11::44A:e:1:i:2:" role="item"><enum>2.</enum><text>Subject to paragraph (2) of this subsection, adopt a resolution creating a special fund with respect to the special taxing district; and</text></sub-subparagraph><sub-subparagraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::9:11::44A:e:1:i:3:" role="item"><enum>3.</enum><text>Provide for the levy of an ad valorem or special tax on all real and personal property within the special taxing district at a rate or amount designed to provide adequate revenues to pay the principal of, interest on, and redemption premium, if any, on the bonds, to replenish any debt service reserve fund, and for any other purpose related to the ongoing expenses of or security for the bonds, and, as the governing body of the municipal corporation determines, to:</text><sub-sub-subparagraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::9:11::44A:e:1:i:3:A:" role="item"><enum>A.</enum><text>Pay costs of infrastructure improvements located in or supporting a transit&ndash;oriented development or a State hospital redevelopment;</text></sub-sub-subparagraph><sub-sub-subparagraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::9:11::44A:e:1:i:3:B:" role="item"><enum>B.</enum><text>Pay costs of operation and maintenance of infrastructure improvements located in or supporting a transit&ndash;oriented development or a State hospital redevelopment; or</text></sub-sub-subparagraph><sub-sub-subparagraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::9:11::44A:e:1:i:3:C:" role="item"><enum>C.</enum><text>Secure payment by the municipal corporation of its obligations under an agreement described in subsection (f)(3) of this section.</text></sub-sub-subparagraph></sub-subparagraph></subparagraph><subparagraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::9:11::44A:e:1:ii:"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Ad valorem taxes shall be levied in the same manner, upon the same assessments, for the same period or periods, and as of the same date or dates of finality as are now or may hereafter be prescribed for general ad valorem tax purposes within the district.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::9:11::44A:e:1:iii:"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>Special taxes shall be levied pursuant to subsection (n) of this section.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::9:11::44A:e:2:"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The resolution creating a special fund under paragraph (1)(i)2 of this subsection shall:</text><subparagraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::9:11::44A:e:2:i:" role="item"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Pledge to the special fund the proceeds of the ad valorem or special tax to be levied as provided under paragraph (1)(i)3 of this subsection; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::9:11::44A:e:2:ii:" role="item"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Require that the proceeds from the tax be paid into the special fund.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::9:11::44A:f:"><enum>(f)</enum><paragraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::9:11::44A:f:1:"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, when no bonds authorized by this section and no MEDCO obligations described in paragraph (3) of this subsection are outstanding with respect to a special taxing district, and the governing body of the municipal corporation determines not to use moneys in the special fund for the payment of costs of infrastructure improvements located in or supporting a transit&ndash;oriented development or a State hospital redevelopment, or the payment of costs of operation and maintenance of infrastructure improvements located in or supporting a transit&ndash;oriented development or a State hospital redevelopment:</text><subparagraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::9:11::44A:f:1:i:" role="item"><enum>(i)</enum><text>The special taxing district shall be terminated; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::9:11::44A:f:1:ii:" role="item"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Any moneys remaining in the special fund on the date of termination of the special taxing district may be paid to the general fund of the municipal corporation.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::9:11::44A:f:2:"><enum>(2)</enum><text>When no bonds authorized by this section are outstanding with respect to a special taxing district, and the governing body of the municipal corporation so determines, moneys in the special fund may be:</text><subparagraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::9:11::44A:f:2:i:" role="item"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Used for any purposes described in this section;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::9:11::44A:f:2:ii:" role="item"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Accumulated for payment of debt service on bonds subsequently issued under this section;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::9:11::44A:f:2:iii:" role="item"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>Used to pay or reimburse the municipal corporation for debt service that the municipal corporation is obligated to pay or has paid, either as a general or a limited obligation, on MEDCO obligations, or any bond, note, or other similar instrument issued by the State, or any unit, department, or political subdivision of the State, the proceeds of which have been used for any of the purposes specified in this section; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::9:11::44A:f:2:iv:" role="item"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>Paid to the municipal corporation to provide funds to be used for any legal purposes as the governing body of the municipal corporation may determine.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::9:11::44A:f:3:"><enum>(3)</enum><subparagraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::9:11::44A:f:3:i:"><enum>(i)</enum><text>A municipal corporation that has created a special fund for a special taxing district may pledge under an agreement that amounts deposited to the special fund shall, as the governing body of the municipal corporation may determine, be paid over to:</text><sub-subparagraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::9:11::44A:f:3:i:1:" role="item"><enum>1.</enum><text>Secure payment on MEDCO obligations;</text></sub-subparagraph><sub-subparagraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::9:11::44A:f:3:i:2:" role="item"><enum>2.</enum><text>Provide for the payment of costs of infrastructure improvements located in or supporting a transit&ndash;oriented development or a State hospital redevelopment; and</text></sub-subparagraph><sub-subparagraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::9:11::44A:f:3:i:3:" role="item"><enum>3.</enum><text>Provide for the payment of costs of operation and maintenance of infrastructure improvements located in or supporting a transit&ndash;oriented development or a State hospital redevelopment.</text></sub-subparagraph></subparagraph><subparagraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::9:11::44A:f:3:ii:"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>The agreement shall:</text><sub-subparagraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::9:11::44A:f:3:ii:1:" role="item"><enum>1.</enum><text>Be authorized by ordinance or resolution of the municipal corporation;</text></sub-subparagraph><sub-subparagraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::9:11::44A:f:3:ii:2:" role="item"><enum>2.</enum><text>Be in writing;</text></sub-subparagraph><sub-subparagraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::9:11::44A:f:3:ii:3:" role="item"><enum>3.</enum><text>Be executed on behalf of the municipal corporation making the pledge, the Maryland Economic Development Corporation, and the other persons or entities that the governing body of the municipal corporation determines; and</text></sub-subparagraph><sub-subparagraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::9:11::44A:f:3:ii:4:" role="item"><enum>4.</enum><text>Run to the benefit of and be enforceable on behalf of the holders of any MEDCO obligations secured by the agreement.</text></sub-subparagraph></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id=":g23a::9:11::44A:g:" db-date="20100618"><enum>(g)</enum><paragraph id=":g23a::9:11::44A:g:1:" db-date="20100618"><enum>(1)</enum><text>In order to implement the authority conferred upon it by this section to issue bonds, the governing body of a municipal corporation shall adopt an ordinance or resolution that:</text><subparagraph id=":g23a::9:11::44A:g:1:i:" role="item" db-date="20100618"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Specifies and describes the proposed undertaking and states that it has complied with subsection (e) of this section;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id=":g23a::9:11::44A:g:1:ii:" role="item" db-date="20100618"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Specifies the maximum principal amount of bonds to be issued;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id=":g23a::9:11::44A:g:1:iii:" role="item" db-date="20100618"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>Specifies the maximum rate or rates of interest for the bonds; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id=":g23a::9:11::44A:g:1:iv:" role="item" db-date="20100618"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>Agrees to a covenant to levy upon all real and personal property within the special taxing district ad valorem taxes or special taxes in rate and amount at least sufficient in each year in which any of the bonds are outstanding to provide for the payment of the principal of and the interest on the bonds.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id=":g23a::9:11::44A:g:2:" db-date="20100618"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The ordinance or resolution may specify or may authorize its finance board or other appropriate financial officer, by resolution or ordinance, or its chief executive officer, by executive order, to specify any of the following as it deems appropriate to effect the financing of the proposed undertaking:</text><subparagraph id=":g23a::9:11::44A:g:2:i:" role="item" db-date="20100618"><enum>(i)</enum><text>The actual principal amount of the bonds to be issued;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id=":g23a::9:11::44A:g:2:ii:" role="item" db-date="20100618"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>The actual rate or rates of interest for the bonds;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id=":g23a::9:11::44A:g:2:iii:" role="item" db-date="20100618"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>The manner in which and the terms upon which the bonds are to be sold;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id=":g23a::9:11::44A:g:2:iv:" role="item" db-date="20100618"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>The manner in which and the times and places that the interest on the bonds is to be paid;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id=":g23a::9:11::44A:g:2:v:" role="item" db-date="20100618"><enum>(v)</enum><text>The time or times that the bonds may be executed, issued, and delivered;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id=":g23a::9:11::44A:g:2:vi:" role="item" db-date="20100618"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>The form and tenor of the bonds and the denominations in which the bonds may be issued;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id=":g23a::9:11::44A:g:2:vii:" role="item" db-date="20100618"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>The manner in which and the times and places that the principal of the bonds is to be paid, within the limitations set forth in this section;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id=":g23a::9:11::44A:g:2:viii:" role="item" db-date="20100618"><enum>(viii)</enum><text>Provisions pursuant to which any or all of the bonds may be called for redemption prior to their stated maturity dates; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id=":g23a::9:11::44A:g:2:ix:" role="item" db-date="20100618"><enum>(ix)</enum><text>Any other provisions not inconsistent with this section as shall be determined by the governing body of the municipal corporation to be necessary or desirable to effect the financing of the proposed undertaking.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id=":g23a::9:11::44A:g:3:" db-date="20100618"><enum>(3)</enum><subparagraph id=":g23a::9:11::44A:g:3:i:" db-date="20100618"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Except as may be required by the Maryland Constitution, an ordinance or resolution authorizing the bonds required under this subsection, an ordinance, resolution, or executive order passed or adopted in furtherance of the required ordinance or resolution, the bonds, the designation of a special taxing district, or the levy of a special ad valorem tax or special tax may not be subject to any referendum by reason of any other State or local law.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id=":g23a::9:11::44A:g:3:ii:" db-date="20100618"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>The ordinance or resolution authorizing the bonds required under this subsection, any ordinance, resolution, or executive order passed or adopted in furtherance of the required ordinance or resolution, the bonds, the designation of a special taxing district, or the levy of a special ad valorem tax or special tax shall be subject to the request of the landowners as specified under subsection (c)(1) of this section.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id=":g23a::9:11::44A:g:4:" db-date="20100618"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The special fund and any sinking fund established by any municipal corporation to provide for the payment of the principal of or interest on any bonds issued by the municipal corporation under the provisions of this section may not be invested by the fiscal officer of the municipal corporation having custody of the special fund and any sinking fund except in the manner prescribed by Article 31, &sect;&sect; 6 and 7 of the Code. Any such fiscal officer having custody of the proceeds of sale of any such bonds may invest the proceeds, pending the expenditure thereof, as prescribed under the provisions of Article 95, &sect; 22 of the Code.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id=":g23a::9:11::44A:h:" db-date="20100618"><enum>(h)</enum><text>The principal amount of the bonds, the interest payable on the bonds, their transfer, and any income derived from the transfer, including any profit made in the sale or transfer of the bonds, shall be exempt from taxation by the State and by the counties and municipal corporations of the State but shall be included, to the extent required under Title 8, Subtitle 2 of the Tax - General Article, in computing the net earnings of financial institutions.</text></subsection><subsection id=":g23a::9:11::44A:i:" db-date="20100618"><enum>(i)</enum><paragraph id=":g23a::9:11::44A:i:1:" db-date="20100618"><enum>(1)</enum><text>All bonds may be in bearer form or in coupon form or may be registrable as to principal alone or as to both principal and interest. Each of the bonds shall be deemed to be a security as defined in &sect; 8-102 of the Commercial Law Article, whether or not it is either one of a class or series or by its terms is divisible into a class or series of instruments.</text></paragraph><paragraph id=":g23a::9:11::44A:i:2:" db-date="20100618"><enum>(2)</enum><text>All bonds shall be signed manually or in facsimile by the chief executive officer of the municipal corporation, and the seal of the municipal corporation shall be affixed to the bonds and attested by the clerk or other similar administrative officer of the municipal corporation. If any officer whose signature or countersignature appears on the coupons ceases to be such officer before delivery of the bonds, the officer&rsquo;s signature or countersignature shall nevertheless be valid and sufficient for all purposes the same as if the officer had remained in office until delivery.</text></paragraph><paragraph id=":g23a::9:11::44A:i:3:" db-date="20100618"><enum>(3)</enum><text>All bonds shall mature not later than 30 years from their date of issuance.</text></paragraph><paragraph id=":g23a::9:11::44A:i:4:" db-date="20100618"><enum>(4)</enum><text>All bonds shall be sold in the manner, either at public or private sale, and upon the terms as the governing body of the municipal corporation deems best. Any contract for the acquisition of property may provide that payment shall be made in bonds. Bonds issued under this section are not subject to Article 31, &sect;&sect; 9, 10, and 11 of the Code.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id=":g23a::9:11::44A:j:" db-date="20100618"><enum>(j)</enum><text>Bonds issued under this section are securities:</text><paragraph id=":g23a::9:11::44A:j:1:" role="item" db-date="20100618"><enum>(1)</enum><text>In which all public officers and public bodies of the State and its political subdivisions, all insurance companies, State banks and trust companies, national banking associations, savings banks, savings and loan associations, investment companies, executors, administrators, trustees and other fiduciaries may properly and legally invest funds, including capital in their control or belonging to them; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id=":g23a::9:11::44A:j:2:" role="item" db-date="20100618"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Which may properly and legally be deposited with and received by any State or municipal officer or any agency or political subdivision of the State for any purpose for which the deposit of bonds or obligations of the State is now or may hereafter be authorized by law.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id=":g23a::9:11::44A:k:" db-date="20100618"><enum>(k)</enum><text>The powers granted under this section shall be regarded as supplemental and additional to powers conferred by other laws, and may not be regarded as in derogation of any powers now existing.</text></subsection><subsection id=":g23a::9:11::44A:l:" db-date="20100618"><enum>(l)</enum><text>This section, being necessary for the welfare of the State and its residents, shall be liberally construed to effect the purpose stated in subsection (b)(2) of this section.</text></subsection><subsection id=":g23a::9:11::44A:m:" db-date="20100618"><enum>(m)</enum><text>Unless otherwise provided in the charter, bylaws, or code of a municipal corporation, a municipal corporation shall hold a public hearing after not less than 10 days notice, published in a newspaper of general circulation in the municipal corporation, before an ordinance or resolution that designates a special taxing district, authorizes the issuance of bonds, or levies ad valorem taxes or special taxes under the provisions of this section may be finally enacted.</text></subsection><subsection id=":g23a::9:11::44A:n:" db-date="20100618"><enum>(n)</enum><paragraph id=":g23a::9:11::44A:n:1:" db-date="20100618"><enum>(1)</enum><text>As an alternative to levying ad valorem taxes under this section, the governing body of the municipal corporation may levy special taxes on property in a special taxing district to cover the cost of infrastructure improvements.</text></paragraph><paragraph id=":g23a::9:11::44A:n:2:" db-date="20100618"><enum>(2)</enum><text>In determining the basis for and amount of the tax, the cost of an improvement may be calculated and levied:</text><subparagraph id=":g23a::9:11::44A:n:2:i:" role="item" db-date="20100618"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Equally per front foot, lot, parcel, dwelling unit or square foot;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id=":g23a::9:11::44A:n:2:ii:" role="item" db-date="20100618"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>According to the value of the property as determined by the governing body, with or without regard to improvements on the property; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id=":g23a::9:11::44A:n:2:iii:" role="item" db-date="20100618"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>In any other reasonable manner that results in fairly allocating the cost of the infrastructure improvements.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id=":g23a::9:11::44A:n:3:" db-date="20100618"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The governing body of the municipal corporation may provide by ordinance or resolution for:</text><subparagraph id=":g23a::9:11::44A:n:3:i:" role="item" db-date="20100618"><enum>(i)</enum><text>A maximum amount to be assessed with respect to any parcel of property located within a special taxing district;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id=":g23a::9:11::44A:n:3:ii:" role="item" db-date="20100618"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>A tax year or other date after which no further special taxes under this section shall be levied or collected on a parcel; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id=":g23a::9:11::44A:n:3:iii:" role="item" db-date="20100618"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>The circumstances under which the special tax levied against any parcel may be increased, if at all, as a consequence of delinquency or default by the owner of that parcel or any other parcel within the special taxing district.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id=":g23a::9:11::44A:n:4:" db-date="20100618"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The governing body by ordinance or resolution may establish procedures allowing for the prepayment of special taxes under this section.</text></paragraph><paragraph id=":g23a::9:11::44A:n:5:" db-date="20100618"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Special taxes levied under this subsection shall be collected and secured in the same manner as general ad valorem taxes unless otherwise provided in the ordinance or resolution and shall be subject to the same penalties and the same procedure, sale and lien priority in case of delinquency as is provided for general ad valorem taxes.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section db-date="20110627" id=":g23a::9:13::46:"><enum>46.</enum><text>A municipal corporation subject to Article XI&ndash;E of the Maryland Constitution, whether through its municipal charter or otherwise, shall not impose or continue any requirement, distinction, or provision in or connected with municipal elections, the right to vote therein, or the right to hold municipal office, which in any way requires the ownership of property, any property&ndash;ownership interest, or any form of control of property as a necessity or qualification for the right to vote, to participate in elections, or to hold office, in the municipal corporation. This section shall not act to deprive any person of existing rights to participate in elections, to hold public office, or to vote, which he presently has under municipal charters in the State of Maryland.</text></section><section id=":g23a::47:::47:" db-date="20060801"><enum>47.</enum>
<subsection id=":g23a::47:::47:a:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(a)</enum>
<text>Any qualified voter registered to vote in a municipality is entitled to vote in the municipal election by absentee ballot. All municipal corporations shall provide the procedure to vote by absentee ballot.</text>
</subsection><subsection id=":g23a::47:::47:b:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(b)</enum>
<text>The municipalities are generally authorized and empowered to do any and all acts providing for voting by persons who are absentee voters. They are severally authorized and empowered to use any of their facilities to transmit and receive applications for absentee ballots, envelopes, instructions and printed matter to enable absentee voters to vote.</text>
</subsection></section><section id=":g23a::48:::48:" db-date="20060801"><enum>48.</enum>
<text>Before a municipal agency may issue a license or permit to an employer to engage in an activity in which the employer may employ a covered employee, as defined in &sect; 9-101 of the Labor and Employment Article, the employer shall file with the agency:</text>
<subsection id=":g23a::48:::48::" role="item" db-date="20060801"> 
<paragraph id=":g23a::48:::48::1:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(1)</enum>
<text>A certificate of compliance with the Maryland Workers&rsquo; Compensation Act; or</text>
</paragraph><paragraph id=":g23a::48:::48::2:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(2)</enum>
<text>The number of a workers&rsquo; compensation insurance policy or binder.</text>
</paragraph></subsection></section><section id=":g23a::49:::49:" db-date="20060801"><enum>49.</enum>
<subsection id=":g23a::49:::49:a:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(a)</enum>
<text>In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated.</text>
</subsection><subsection id=":g23a::49:::49:b:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(b)</enum>
<text>&ldquo;Privately owned residential community&rdquo; means:</text>
<paragraph id=":g23a::49:::49:b:1:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(1)</enum>
<text>A homeowners association, as defined under the Maryland Homeowners Association Act;</text>
</paragraph><paragraph id=":g23a::49:::49:b:2:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(2)</enum>
<text>A condominium, as defined under the Maryland Condominium Act; or</text>
</paragraph><paragraph id=":g23a::49:::49:b:3:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(3)</enum>
<text>A cooperative housing association, as defined under the Maryland Cooperative Housing Corporation Act.</text>
</paragraph></subsection><subsection id=":g23a::49:::49:c:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(c)</enum>
<text>&ldquo;Residential street service&rdquo; means:</text>
<paragraph id=":g23a::49:::49:c:1:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(1)</enum>
<text>The removal of snow, ice, or other obstructions from roadways;</text>
</paragraph><paragraph id=":g23a::49:::49:c:2:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(2)</enum>
<text>The lighting of roadways and maintenance of the lighting equipment;</text>
</paragraph><paragraph id=":g23a::49:::49:c:3:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(3)</enum>
<text>The collection of leaves, recyclable materials, or garbage along roadways; or</text>
</paragraph><paragraph id=":g23a::49:::49:c:4:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(4)</enum>
<text>The maintenance of roadways.</text>
</paragraph></subsection><subsection id=":g23a::49:::49:d:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(d)</enum>
<paragraph id=":g23a::49:::49:d:1:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(1)</enum>
<text>&ldquo;Roadway&rdquo; means a paved surface that provides vehicular access.</text>
</paragraph><paragraph id=":g23a::49:::49:d:2:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(2)</enum>
<text>&ldquo;Roadway&rdquo; includes a paved surface designated for parking.</text>
</paragraph></subsection></section><section id=":g23a::49:::50:" db-date="20060801"><enum>50.</enum>
<text>The governing body of a municipal corporation that provides a residential street service may make an agreement with the governing body of a privately owned residential community that qualifies under the provisions of &sect; 51 of this subtitle concerning:</text>
<subsection id=":g23a::49:::50::" role="item" db-date="20060801"> 
<paragraph id=":g23a::49:::50::1:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(1)</enum>
<text>The delivery of the residential street service to the privately owned residential community by the municipal corporation; or</text>
</paragraph><paragraph id=":g23a::49:::50::2:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(2)</enum>
<text>Instead of delivering the residential street service, the reimbursement to the governing body of the privately owned residential community of an amount not to exceed the cost that would be incurred by the municipal corporation to deliver the residential street service.</text>
</paragraph></subsection></section><section id=":g23a::49:::51:" db-date="20060801"><enum>51.</enum>
<text>The governing body of a municipal corporation may make an agreement under &sect; 50 of this subtitle with the governing body of a privately owned residential community that:</text>
<subsection id=":g23a::49:::51::" role="item" db-date="20060801"> 
<paragraph id=":g23a::49:::51::1:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(1)</enum>
<text>Lies wholly or partially in the boundaries of the municipal corporation;</text>
</paragraph><paragraph id=":g23a::49:::51::2:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(2)</enum>
<text>Has at least one-quarter mile of roadway;</text>
</paragraph><paragraph id=":g23a::49:::51::3:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(3)</enum>
<text>Regarding a roadway in the privately owned residential community that is to be used for the delivery of a residential street service:</text>
<subparagraph id=":g23a::49:::51::3:i:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(i)</enum>
<text>Permits the roadway to be dedicated to public use; and</text>
</subparagraph><subparagraph id=":g23a::49:::51::3:ii:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(ii)</enum>
<text>Unless maintenance of the roadway is provided by the municipal corporation, maintains the roadway at a level of service satisfactory to the municipal corporation; and</text>
</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id=":g23a::49:::51::4:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(4)</enum>
<text>Agrees to pay any insurance riders that the municipal corporation requires to enable vehicles owned or contracted by the municipal corporation to operate on a roadway in the privately owned residential community.</text>
</paragraph></subsection></section><section db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::52:"><enum>52.</enum><subsection db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::52:a:"><enum>(a)</enum><text>In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated.</text></subsection><subsection db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::52:b:"><enum>(b)</enum><text>&ldquo;Authority&rdquo; means a nonprofit or quasi&ndash;governmental entity created by a municipal corporation under &sect; 54 of this subtitle.</text></subsection><subsection db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::52:c:"><enum>(c)</enum><text>&ldquo;Board&rdquo; means the board of directors of an authority.</text></subsection><subsection db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::52:d:"><enum>(d)</enum><paragraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::52:d:1:"><enum>(1)</enum><text>&ldquo;Bond&rdquo; means a bond issued by an authority under this subtitle.</text></paragraph><paragraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::52:d:2:"><enum>(2)</enum><text>&ldquo;Bond&rdquo; includes a bond, a refunding bond, a note, and any other obligation.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::52:e:"><enum>(e)</enum><text>&ldquo;Cost&rdquo; includes:</text><paragraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::52:e:1:" role="item"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The purchase price of property;</text></paragraph><paragraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::52:e:2:" role="item"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The cost to acquire any right, title, or interest in property;</text></paragraph><paragraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::52:e:3:" role="item"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The cost of any improvements made to property;</text></paragraph><paragraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::52:e:4:" role="item"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The amount to be paid to discharge each obligation necessary or desirable to vest title to any part of property in an authority or other owner;</text></paragraph><paragraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::52:e:5:" role="item"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The cost of any property, right, easement, franchise, and permit associated with a project;</text></paragraph><paragraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::52:e:6:" role="item"><enum>(6)</enum><text>The cost of labor, machinery, and equipment necessary to implement a project;</text></paragraph><paragraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::52:e:7:" role="item"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Financing charges;</text></paragraph><paragraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::52:e:8:" role="item"><enum>(8)</enum><text>Interest and reserves for principal and interest and for improvements;</text></paragraph><paragraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::52:e:9:" role="item"><enum>(9)</enum><text>The cost of revenue and cost estimates, engineering and legal services, plans, specifications, studies, surveys, and other expenses necessary or incident to determining the feasibility or practicability of a project;</text></paragraph><paragraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::52:e:10:" role="item"><enum>(10)</enum><text>Administrative expenses; and</text></paragraph><paragraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::52:e:11:" role="item"><enum>(11)</enum><text>Other expenses as necessary or incident to:</text><subparagraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::52:e:11:i:" role="item"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Financing a project;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::52:e:11:ii:" role="item"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Acquiring and improving a project;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::52:e:11:iii:" role="item"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>Placing a project in operation, including reasonable provisions for working capital; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::52:e:11:iv:" role="item"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>Operating and maintaining a project.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::52:f:"><enum>(f)</enum><text>&ldquo;Finance&rdquo; includes refinance.</text></subsection><subsection db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::52:g:"><enum>(g)</enum><paragraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::52:g:1:"><enum>(1)</enum><text>&ldquo;Project&rdquo; means any organized plan carried out by an authority in relation to:</text><subparagraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::52:g:1:i:" role="item"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Acquiring and rehabilitating abandoned and dilapidated properties; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::52:g:1:ii:" role="item"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Marketing and leasing or selling the rehabilitated properties.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::52:g:2:"><enum>(2)</enum><text>&ldquo;Project&rdquo; includes:</text><subparagraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::52:g:2:i:" role="item"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Acquiring land or an interest in land;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::52:g:2:ii:" role="item"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Acquiring structures, equipment, and furnishings located on a property;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::52:g:2:iii:" role="item"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>Acquiring property that is functionally related and subordinate to a project; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::52:g:2:iv:" role="item"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>Obtaining or contracting for any services necessary for the rehabilitation of a property.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::52:h:"><enum>(h)</enum><paragraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::52:h:1:"><enum>(1)</enum><text>&ldquo;Revenues&rdquo; means the income, revenue, and other money an authority receives from or in connection with a project and all other income of an authority.</text></paragraph><paragraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::52:h:2:"><enum>(2)</enum><text>&ldquo;Revenues&rdquo; includes grants, rentals, rates, fees, and charges.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::52:i:"><enum>(i)</enum><text>&ldquo;Tax sale property&rdquo; means property or an interest in property sold by the tax collector of the county in accordance with Title 14, Subtitle 8, Part III of the Tax &ndash; Property Article.</text></subsection><subsection db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::52:j:"><enum>(j)</enum><paragraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::52:j:1:"><enum>(1)</enum><text>&ldquo;Trust agreement&rdquo; means an agreement entered into by an authority to secure a bond.</text></paragraph><paragraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::52:j:2:"><enum>(2)</enum><text>&ldquo;Trust agreement&rdquo; may include a bond contract, bond resolution, or other contract with or for the benefit of a bondholder.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::53:"><enum>53.</enum><subsection db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::53:a:"><enum>(a)</enum><text>This subtitle shall be liberally construed to accomplish its purposes.</text></subsection><subsection db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::53:b:"><enum>(b)</enum><text>The powers granted to an authority under this subtitle shall be construed as supplemental and in addition to powers granted to an authority under any State or local law.</text></subsection><subsection db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::53:c:"><enum>(c)</enum><text>This subtitle does not authorize an authority to:</text><paragraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::53:c:1:" role="item"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Exercise the power of eminent domain; or</text></paragraph><paragraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::53:c:2:" role="item"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Levy any tax or special assessment.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::54:"><enum>54.</enum><subsection db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::54:a:"><enum>(a)</enum><text>By ordinance, the legislative body of a municipal corporation may establish a land bank authority in accordance with this subtitle.</text></subsection><subsection db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::54:b:"><enum>(b)</enum><text>An ordinance adopted under subsection (a) of this section shall include proposed articles of incorporation of an authority that state:</text><paragraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::54:b:1:" role="item"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The name of the authority, which shall be &ldquo;Land Bank Authority of (name of the incorporating municipal corporation)&rdquo;;</text></paragraph><paragraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::54:b:2:" role="item"><enum>(2)</enum><text>That the authority is formed under this subtitle;</text></paragraph><paragraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::54:b:3:" role="item"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The names, addresses, and terms of office of the initial members of the board of directors of the authority;</text></paragraph><paragraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::54:b:4:" role="item"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The address of the principal office of the authority;</text></paragraph><paragraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::54:b:5:" role="item"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The purposes for which the authority is formed; and</text></paragraph><paragraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::54:b:6:" role="item"><enum>(6)</enum><text>The powers of the authority subject to the limitations on the powers of an authority under this subtitle.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::54:c:"><enum>(c)</enum><paragraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::54:c:1:"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The chief executive of the incorporating municipal corporation, or any other official designated in the ordinance establishing an authority, shall execute and file the articles of incorporation of the authority for recordation with the State Department of Assessments and Taxation.</text></paragraph><paragraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::54:c:2:"><enum>(2)</enum><text>When the State Department of Assessments and Taxation accepts the articles of incorporation for recordation, the authority becomes a body politic and corporate and an instrumentality of the incorporating municipal corporation.</text></paragraph><paragraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::54:c:3:"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Acceptance of the articles of incorporation for recordation by the State Department of Assessments and Taxation is conclusive evidence of the formation of the authority.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::54:d:"><enum>(d)</enum><paragraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::54:d:1:"><enum>(1)</enum><text>By ordinance, the legislative body of the incorporating municipal corporation may adopt an amendment to the articles of incorporation of an authority.</text></paragraph><paragraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::54:d:2:"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Articles of amendment may contain any provision that lawfully could be contained in articles of incorporation at the time of the amendment.</text></paragraph><paragraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::54:d:3:"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The articles of amendment shall be filed for recordation with the State Department of Assessments and Taxation.</text></paragraph><paragraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::54:d:4:"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The articles of amendment are effective as of the time the State Department of Assessments and Taxation accepts the articles for recordation.</text></paragraph><paragraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::54:d:5:"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Acceptance of the articles of amendment for recordation by the State Department of Assessments and Taxation is conclusive evidence that the articles have been lawfully and properly adopted.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::54:e:"><enum>(e)</enum><paragraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::54:e:1:"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Subject to the provisions of this section and any limitations imposed by law on the impairment of contracts, the incorporating municipal corporation, in its sole discretion, by ordinance may:</text><subparagraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::54:e:1:i:" role="item"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Set or change the structure, organization, procedures, programs, or activities of an authority; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::54:e:1:ii:" role="item"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Terminate the authority.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::54:e:2:"><enum>(2)</enum><text>On termination of the authority:</text><subparagraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::54:e:2:i:" role="item"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Title to all property of the authority shall be transferred to and shall vest in the incorporating municipal corporation; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::54:e:2:ii:" role="item"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>All obligations of the authority shall be transferred to and assumed by the incorporating municipal corporation.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::55:"><enum>55.</enum><text>An ordinance that creates a land bank authority shall establish a board of directors to govern an authority and shall include provisions for:</text><subsection db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::55::"><paragraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::55::1:"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Appointment procedures;</text></paragraph><paragraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::55::2:"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Term lengths;</text></paragraph><paragraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::55::3:"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Removal procedures;</text></paragraph><paragraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::55::4:"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The election of a chair; and</text></paragraph><paragraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::55::5:"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Powers of the board.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::56:"><enum>56.</enum><subsection db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::56:a:"><enum>(a)</enum><text>Except as limited by the authority&rsquo;s articles of incorporation, an authority has all the powers set forth in this subtitle.</text></subsection><subsection db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::56:b:"><enum>(b)</enum><text>An authority may:</text><paragraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::56:b:1:" role="item"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Adopt bylaws for the conduct of business of the authority;</text></paragraph><paragraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::56:b:2:" role="item"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Sue and be sued;</text></paragraph><paragraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::56:b:3:" role="item"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Maintain an office at a place the authority designates;</text></paragraph><paragraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::56:b:4:" role="item"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Borrow money;</text></paragraph><paragraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::56:b:5:" role="item"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Issue bonds and other obligations for any corporate purpose in accordance with this subtitle or an ordinance adopted under this subtitle;</text></paragraph><paragraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::56:b:6:" role="item"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Invest money of the authority in instruments, obligations, securities, or property;</text></paragraph><paragraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::56:b:7:" role="item"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Enter into contracts and execute the instruments or agreements necessary or convenient to carry out this subtitle or an ordinance adopted under this subtitle to accomplish the purposes of the authority;</text></paragraph><paragraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::56:b:8:" role="item"><enum>(8)</enum><text>Solicit and accept gifts, grants, loans, or other assistance in any form from any public or private source, subject to the provisions of this subtitle or any ordinance adopted under this subtitle;</text></paragraph><paragraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::56:b:9:" role="item"><enum>(9)</enum><text>Participate in any way in a program of the federal government, the State, a political subdivision of the State, or an intergovernmental entity created under the laws of the State;</text></paragraph><paragraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::56:b:10:" role="item"><enum>(10)</enum><text>Contract for goods and services;</text></paragraph><paragraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::56:b:11:" role="item"><enum>(11)</enum><text>Study, develop, and prepare reports or plans to assist in the authority&rsquo;s exercise of powers and to monitor and evaluate the authority&rsquo;s progress;</text></paragraph><paragraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::56:b:12:" role="item"><enum>(12)</enum><text>Contract with public or private entities for the provision of services necessary for the management and operation of the authority;</text></paragraph><paragraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::56:b:13:" role="item"><enum>(13)</enum><text>Provide acquisition, management, and sale services to a municipal corporation for property owned by the municipal corporation;</text></paragraph><paragraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::56:b:14:" role="item"><enum>(14)</enum><text>Create, own, control, or be a member of a corporation, limited liability company, partnership, or other person, whether operated for profit or not for profit, for the purposes of developing property in order to maximize marketability;</text></paragraph><paragraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::56:b:15:" role="item"><enum>(15)</enum><text>Exercise a power usually possessed by a private corporation in performing similar functions unless to do so would conflict with State law; and</text></paragraph><paragraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::56:b:16:" role="item"><enum>(16)</enum><text>Do all things necessary or convenient to carry out the powers expressly granted by this subtitle or by an ordinance adopted under this subtitle.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::56:c:"><enum>(c)</enum><text>An authority may delegate to a member or officer a power granted to the authority by this subtitle, including the power to execute a bond, obligation, certificate, deed, lease, mortgage agreement, or other document or instrument.</text></subsection></section><section db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::57:"><enum>57.</enum><subsection db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::57:a:"><enum>(a)</enum><text>An authority may:</text><paragraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::57:a:1:" role="item"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Acquire, directly or through a person or governmental entity, by gift, devise, transfer, exchange, foreclosure, purchase, or otherwise on terms and conditions and in a manner the authority considers proper, real property or rights or interests in real property;</text></paragraph><paragraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::57:a:2:" role="item"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Own in the authority&rsquo;s name property acquired by or conveyed to the authority by the State, a local government, an intergovernmental agency created under the laws of this State, or any other public or private person, including tax foreclosed property and property without clear title;</text></paragraph><paragraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::57:a:3:" role="item"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Sell, lease as lessor, transfer, and dispose of the authority&rsquo;s property or interest in property;</text></paragraph><paragraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::57:a:4:" role="item"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Procure insurance against loss in connection with the property, assets, or activities of the authority; and</text></paragraph><paragraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::57:a:5:" role="item"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Execute deeds, mortgages, contracts, leases, purchases, or other agreements regarding the property of the authority.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::57:b:"><enum>(b)</enum><text>Property purchased, owned, or sold under this section may not be located outside the municipal corporation in which the authority is located.</text></subsection></section><section db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::58:"><enum>58.</enum><text>An authority may employ staff and retain consultants as employees or agents that the authority considers necessary, and set their compensation.</text></section><section db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::59:"><enum>59.</enum><text>The court may appoint an authority to serve as a receiver in a receivership proceeding filed by a municipal corporation.</text></section><section db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::60:"><enum>60.</enum><subsection db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::60:a:"><enum>(a)</enum><text>An authority shall:</text><paragraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::60:a:1:" role="item"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Adopt a code of ethics for the authority&rsquo;s directors, officers, and employees;</text></paragraph><paragraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::60:a:2:" role="item"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Establish policies and procedures requiring the disclosure of relationships that may give rise to a conflict of interest, and requiring that any member of the board with a direct or indirect interest in a matter before the authority disclose the member&rsquo;s interest to the board before the board takes any action on the matter; and</text></paragraph><paragraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::60:a:3:" role="item"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Comply with the State Open Meetings Act under Title 10, Subtitle 5 of the State Government Article.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::60:b:"><enum>(b)</enum><text>Except as otherwise provided in this subtitle or the ordinance establishing an authority, the procedures of the incorporating municipal corporation control any matter relating to the internal administration of an authority.</text></subsection></section><section db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::61:"><enum>61.</enum><text>An authority may have the same immunities as a municipal corporation.</text></section><section db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::62:"><enum>62.</enum><subsection db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::62:a:"><enum>(a)</enum><text>With respect to property held or owned by the authority, the authority may:</text><paragraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::62:a:1:" role="item"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Grant or acquire a license, easement, or option;</text></paragraph><paragraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::62:a:2:" role="item"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Fix, charge, and collect rents, fees, and charges for use of the property;</text></paragraph><paragraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::62:a:3:" role="item"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Pay taxes or special assessments due;</text></paragraph><paragraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::62:a:4:" role="item"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Take any action, provide any notice, or institute any proceeding required to clear or quiet title in order to establish ownership by and vest title to property in the authority;</text></paragraph><paragraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::62:a:5:" role="item"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Abate violations of the local and State building, fire, health, and related codes; and</text></paragraph><paragraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::62:a:6:" role="item"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Hold, manage, maintain, operate, repair, lease as lessor, secure, prevent the waste or deterioration of, demolish, and take all other actions necessary to preserve the value of the property it owns or holds.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::62:b:"><enum>(b)</enum><text>An authority shall be made a party to, and shall defend any action or proceeding concerning, claims against property held by the authority.</text></subsection></section><section db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::63:"><enum>63.</enum><subsection db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::63:a:"><enum>(a)</enum><text>Property held by an authority shall be inventoried and classified according to title status and suitability for use.</text></subsection><subsection db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::63:b:"><enum>(b)</enum><text>A register of deeds in a county in which property owned by an authority is located may not charge a fee to record a document evidencing the transfer under this subtitle of property to the authority by the State or a municipal corporation.</text></subsection></section><section db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::64:"><enum>64.</enum><subsection db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::64:a:"><enum>(a)</enum><text>Following an unsuccessful attempt on the part of the municipal corporation to collect outstanding liens at tax sale and subject to the approval of the local tax collecting unit of the jurisdiction where the property is located, an authority may accept from a person with an interest in a parcel of tax delinquent property or tax sale property a deed or assignment conveying that person&rsquo;s interest in the property instead of:</text><paragraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::64:a:1:" role="item"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The foreclosure or sale of the property for delinquent taxes, penalties, and interest, as defined by &sect; 14&ndash;801(c) of the Tax &ndash; Property Article; or</text></paragraph><paragraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::64:a:2:" role="item"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Delinquent specific taxes imposed by a local taxing jurisdiction.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::64:b:"><enum>(b)</enum><text>Except as otherwise provided by law, conveyance of property by deed instead of foreclosure under this section may not affect or impair any other lien against the property or any existing recorded or unrecorded interest in the property, including:</text><paragraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::64:b:1:" role="item"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Future installments of special assessments;</text></paragraph><paragraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::64:b:2:" role="item"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Liens recorded by the State;</text></paragraph><paragraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::64:b:3:" role="item"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Easements or rights&ndash;of&ndash;way;</text></paragraph><paragraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::64:b:4:" role="item"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Private deed restrictions;</text></paragraph><paragraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::64:b:5:" role="item"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Security interests and mortgages; or</text></paragraph><paragraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::64:b:6:" role="item"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Tax liens of other taxing jurisdictions that do not consent to a release of their liens.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::64:c:"><enum>(c)</enum><text>A tax lien against property held by or under the control of an authority may be released or abated at any time by one or more of the following:</text><paragraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::64:c:1:" role="item"><enum>(1)</enum><text>A county or municipal corporation with respect to a lien held by the county or municipal corporation;</text></paragraph><paragraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::64:c:2:" role="item"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The governing body of any taxing jurisdiction other than the State, county, or municipal corporation with respect to a lien held by the taxing jurisdiction;</text></paragraph><paragraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::64:c:3:" role="item"><enum>(3)</enum><text>A public water or sewer authority with respect to a tax lien or right to collect a tax held by the public water or sewer authority; or</text></paragraph><paragraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::64:c:4:" role="item"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The State Comptroller with respect to a State tax lien.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::65:"><enum>65.</enum><subsection db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::65:a:"><enum>(a)</enum><text>Money received by an authority as payment of taxes, penalties, or interest, or from the redemption or sale of property subject to a tax lien of any taxing unit shall be returned to the local tax collecting unit in the jurisdiction where the property is located for distribution on a pro rata basis to the appropriate taxing units in an amount equal to delinquent taxes, penalties, and interest owed on the property.</text></subsection><subsection db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::65:b:"><enum>(b)</enum><text>Proceeds received by an authority may be retained by the authority for the purposes of this subtitle, unless otherwise designated by:</text><paragraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::65:b:1:" role="item"><enum>(1)</enum><text>This subtitle;</text></paragraph><paragraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::65:b:2:" role="item"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The provisions of a deed;</text></paragraph><paragraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::65:b:3:" role="item"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Any other law; or</text></paragraph><paragraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::65:b:4:" role="item"><enum>(4)</enum><text>An agreement of the authority.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::66:"><enum>66.</enum><subsection db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::66:a:"><enum>(a)</enum><text>Except as provided in subsection (b) of this section, an authority is exempt from any requirement to pay State or local taxes or assessments on the authority&rsquo;s properties, activities, or any revenue from the properties or activities.</text></subsection><subsection db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::66:b:"><enum>(b)</enum><text>Property that an authority sells or leases to a private entity is subject to State and local property taxes from the time of the sale or lease.</text></subsection><subsection db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::66:c:"><enum>(c)</enum><text>The principal of and interest on bonds, the transfer of bonds, and any income derived from the bonds, including profits made on their sale or transfer, are forever exempt from all State and local taxes.</text></subsection></section><section db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::67:"><enum>67.</enum><subsection db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::67:a:"><enum>(a)</enum><text>An authority may bring a civil action to prevent, restrain, or enjoin the waste of or unlawful removal of any property from real property held by the authority.</text></subsection><subsection db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::67:b:"><enum>(b)</enum><paragraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::67:b:1:"><enum>(1)</enum><text>An authority shall be made a party to any action or proceeding instituted for the purpose of setting aside title to property held by the authority or for the sale of property by the authority.</text></paragraph><paragraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::67:b:2:"><enum>(2)</enum><text>A hearing in any such proceeding may not be held until the authority is served in accordance with the Maryland Rules.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::68:"><enum>68.</enum><subsection db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::68:a:"><enum>(a)</enum><text>Property of an authority is public property devoted to an essential public and governmental function and purpose.</text></subsection><subsection db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::68:b:"><enum>(b)</enum><text>Income of an authority is considered to be for a public and governmental purpose.</text></subsection></section><section db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::69:"><enum>69.</enum><text>An authority is subject to any local:</text><subsection db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::69::"><paragraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::69::1:"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Zoning laws;</text></paragraph><paragraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::69::2:"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Permitting processes for construction, demolition, or repair of a property; and</text></paragraph><paragraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::69::3:"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Land use controls.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::70:"><enum>70.</enum><text>An authority shall report annually to the municipal corporation where the authority is located and, in accordance with &sect; 2&ndash;1246 of the State Government Article, the General Assembly on the activities of the authority.</text></section><section db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::71:"><enum>71.</enum><subsection db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::71:a:"><enum>(a)</enum><paragraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::71:a:1:"><enum>(1)</enum><text>An authority may periodically:</text><subparagraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::71:a:1:i:" role="item"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Issue bonds to pay all or part of the cost of acquiring or improving property;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::71:a:1:ii:" role="item"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Fund or refund those bonds;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::71:a:1:iii:" role="item"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>Purchase bonds with any funds available; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::71:a:1:iv:" role="item"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>Hold, pledge, cancel, or resell bonds.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::71:a:2:"><enum>(2)</enum><text>By resolution, an authority may authorize the chair, one of the authority&rsquo;s members, or a committee of the members to determine or provide for any matters relating to bonds that the authority considers appropriate, including:</text><subparagraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::71:a:2:i:" role="item"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Specifying, determining, prescribing, and approving matters, documents, and procedures that relate to the authorization, sale, security, issuance, delivery, and payment of and for the bonds;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::71:a:2:ii:" role="item"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Creating security for the bonds;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::71:a:2:iii:" role="item"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>Providing for the administration of bond issues; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::71:a:2:iv:" role="item"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>Taking other actions it considers appropriate concerning the bonds.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::71:a:3:"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The power granted in paragraph (2) of this subsection is in addition to powers conferred on the authority by this subtitle and does not limit any power of the authority under this subtitle.</text></paragraph><paragraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::71:a:4:"><enum>(4)</enum><subparagraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::71:a:4:i:"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Subject to subparagraph (ii) of this paragraph, the authority may authorize the executive director to take any of the actions described in paragraph (2) of this subsection.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::71:a:4:ii:"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>If the authority authorizes the executive director to take any of the actions described in paragraph (2) of this subsection, the authority shall prescribe limits within which the executive director may exercise discretion.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::71:b:"><enum>(b)</enum><text>An authority may issue the bonds at one time or in one or more series from time to time.</text></subsection><subsection db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::71:c:"><enum>(c)</enum><text>For each issue of an authority&rsquo;s bonds, the authority shall pass a resolution that:</text><paragraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::71:c:1:" role="item"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Specifies and describes the project for which the proceeds of the bond issuance are intended;</text></paragraph><paragraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::71:c:2:" role="item"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Generally describes the public purpose and the financing transaction to be accomplished;</text></paragraph><paragraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::71:c:3:" role="item"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Specifies the maximum principal amount of the bonds that may be issued by the authority; and</text></paragraph><paragraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::71:c:4:" role="item"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Imposes any terms or conditions on the issuance and sale of the bonds that the authority considers appropriate.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::71:d:"><enum>(d)</enum><text>Subject to any provisions for their registration, bonds are negotiable instruments for all purposes regardless of whether they are payable from a special fund.</text></subsection><subsection db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::71:e:"><enum>(e)</enum><paragraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::71:e:1:"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The bonds may be:</text><subparagraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::71:e:1:i:" role="item"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Serial bonds;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::71:e:1:ii:" role="item"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Term bonds; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::71:e:1:iii:" role="item"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>Both in the discretion of the authority.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::71:e:2:"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Subject to any delegation under subsection (a)(2) of this section, the resolution authorizing bonds may provide:</text><subparagraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::71:e:2:i:" role="item"><enum>(i)</enum><text>The dates of the bonds;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::71:e:2:ii:" role="item"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>The maturity dates of the bonds;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::71:e:2:iii:" role="item"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>The interest rates on the bonds;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::71:e:2:iv:" role="item"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>The time at which the bonds will be payable;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::71:e:2:v:" role="item"><enum>(v)</enum><text>The denominations of the bonds;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::71:e:2:vi:" role="item"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>Whether the bonds will be in coupon or registered form;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::71:e:2:vii:" role="item"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>Any registration privileges of the bonds;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::71:e:2:viii:" role="item"><enum>(viii)</enum><text>The manner of execution of the bonds;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::71:e:2:ix:" role="item"><enum>(ix)</enum><text>The place at which the bonds will be payable; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::71:e:2:x:" role="item"><enum>(x)</enum><text>Any terms of redemption of the bonds.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::71:e:3:"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The bonds shall mature within a period not to exceed 50 years after the date of issue.</text></paragraph><paragraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::71:e:4:"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The bonds shall be payable in United States currency.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::71:f:"><enum>(f)</enum><paragraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::71:f:1:"><enum>(1)</enum><text>An authority shall sell the bonds at competitive or negotiated sale in a manner and for a price the authority determines to be in the authority&rsquo;s best interests.</text></paragraph><paragraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::71:f:2:"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Bonds are exempt from &sect;&sect; 8&ndash;206 and 8&ndash;208 of the State Finance and Procurement Article.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::71:g:"><enum>(g)</enum><text>An officer&rsquo;s signature or facsimile on a bond remains valid even if the officer leaves office before the bond is delivered.</text></subsection><subsection db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::71:h:"><enum>(h)</enum><text>Pending preparation of the definitive bonds, an authority may issue interim receipts or certificates that will be exchanged for definitive bonds.</text></subsection><subsection db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::71:i:"><enum>(i)</enum><paragraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::71:i:1:"><enum>(1)</enum><text>A trust agreement authorizing bonds may contain provisions that are part of the contract with the bondholders.</text></paragraph><paragraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::71:i:2:"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The provisions may include:</text><subparagraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::71:i:2:i:" role="item"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Pledging the following to secure payment of bonds, subject to any existing agreements with bondholders:</text><sub-subparagraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::71:i:2:i:1:" role="item"><enum>1.</enum><text>The full faith and credit of an authority;</text></sub-subparagraph><sub-subparagraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::71:i:2:i:2:" role="item"><enum>2.</enum><text>Revenues of a project;</text></sub-subparagraph><sub-subparagraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::71:i:2:i:3:" role="item"><enum>3.</enum><text>A revenue&ndash;producing contract the authority has made with a person or public entity; or</text></sub-subparagraph><sub-subparagraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::71:i:2:i:4:" role="item"><enum>4.</enum><text>The proceeds of the sale of bonds;</text></sub-subparagraph></subparagraph><subparagraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::71:i:2:ii:" role="item"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>The rates, rentals, fees, and other charges, the amounts to be raised in each year, and the use and disposition of the revenues;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::71:i:2:iii:" role="item"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>Setting aside of reserves and sinking funds and their disposition;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::71:i:2:iv:" role="item"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>Limits on the right of the authority or the authority&rsquo;s agents to restrict and regulate the use of a project;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::71:i:2:v:" role="item"><enum>(v)</enum><text>Limits on the purpose to which the proceeds of sale of bonds may be applied;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::71:i:2:vi:" role="item"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>Limits on issuing additional bonds and refunding bonds and the terms under which additional bonds may be issued and secured;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::71:i:2:vii:" role="item"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>The procedure to amend or abrogate the terms of a contract with bondholders and the requirements for consent;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::71:i:2:viii:" role="item"><enum>(viii)</enum><text>Limits on the amount of project revenues to be expended for operating, administrative, or other expenses of the authority;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::71:i:2:ix:" role="item"><enum>(ix)</enum><text>The acts or omissions that constitute default by the authority and the rights and remedies of the bondholders in the event of a default;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::71:i:2:x:" role="item"><enum>(x)</enum><text>The conveyance or mortgaging of a project and its site to secure the bondholders; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::71:i:2:xi:" role="item"><enum>(xi)</enum><text>Creation and disposition of a collateral fund for the purpose of securing the bondholders.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::71:j:"><enum>(j)</enum><text>The members of an authority and a person executing the bonds may not be held liable personally on the bonds.</text></subsection></section><section db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::72:"><enum>72.</enum><subsection db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::72:a:"><enum>(a)</enum><text>The corporate trustee under a trust agreement may be a trust company or bank that has the powers of a trust company in or outside the State.</text></subsection><subsection db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::72:b:"><enum>(b)</enum><text>An expense incurred in carrying out the trust agreement or a resolution may be treated as part of the cost of the operation of a project.</text></subsection></section><section db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::73:"><enum>73.</enum><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of this subtitle, in a proceeding involving the validity or enforceability of a bond or the security for a bond, the determination of an authority under this subtitle is conclusive and binding.</text></section><section db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::74:"><enum>74.</enum><text>Bonds are securities:</text><subsection db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::74::"><paragraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::74::1:"><enum>(1)</enum><text>In which any of the following persons may legally and properly invest money, including capital that the person owns or controls:</text><subparagraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::74::1:i:" role="item"><enum>(i)</enum><text>An officer or a unit of the State or a political subdivision;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::74::1:ii:" role="item"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>A bank, a trust company, a savings and loan association, an investment company, or any other person conducting a banking business;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::74::1:iii:" role="item"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>An insurance company, insurance association, or any other person conducting an insurance business;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::74::1:iv:" role="item"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>A personal representative, guardian, trustee, or any other fiduciary; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::74::1:v:" role="item"><enum>(v)</enum><text>Any other person; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::74::2:"><enum>(2)</enum><text>That may be deposited with and received by a unit of the State or a political subdivision of the State for any purpose for which the deposit of bonds or obligations of the State is authorized by law.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::75:"><enum>75.</enum><subsection db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::75:a:"><enum>(a)</enum><text>A bond is not:</text><paragraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::75:a:1:" role="item"><enum>(1)</enum><text>A debt or liability of the State or a political subdivision of the State; or</text></paragraph><paragraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::75:a:2:" role="item"><enum>(2)</enum><text>A pledge of the faith and credit of the State or a political subdivision of the State.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::75:b:"><enum>(b)</enum><text>Each bond shall state on the face of the bond that neither the State nor a political subdivision of the State is obliged to pay the principal of or interest on the bond except from revenues pledged to the payment of the bond.</text></subsection><subsection db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::75:c:"><enum>(c)</enum><text>The issuance of bonds does not directly, indirectly, or contingently obligate the State or its political subdivisions:</text><paragraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::75:c:1:" role="item"><enum>(1)</enum><text>To impose or pledge a tax to pay the bonds; or</text></paragraph><paragraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::75:c:2:" role="item"><enum>(2)</enum><text>To make an appropriation to pay the bonds.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::75:d:"><enum>(d)</enum><text>Nothing in this subtitle prohibits an authority from pledging its full faith and credit in connection with the issuance of bonds.</text></subsection></section><section db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::76:"><enum>76.</enum><subsection db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::76:a:"><enum>(a)</enum><text>An authority may:</text><paragraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::76:a:1:" role="item"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Fix and collect rates, rents, fees, and charges related to a project and for the services related to a project; and</text></paragraph><paragraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::76:a:2:" role="item"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Contract with any person or governmental entity to exercise its authority under this section.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::76:b:"><enum>(b)</enum><text>The rates, rents, fees, and charges established by an authority under this section shall be fixed and adjusted so that the aggregate amount of the rates, rents, fees, and charges from the project, when added to other available money, is sufficient to:</text><paragraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::76:b:1:" role="item"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Pay for the expenses of the project;</text></paragraph><paragraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::76:b:2:" role="item"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Pay the principal of and the interest on the bonds that the authority issued for the project as they become due and payable; and</text></paragraph><paragraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::76:b:3:" role="item"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Create and maintain reserves required or provided for in a trust agreement.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::76:c:"><enum>(c)</enum><text>The rates, rents, fees, and charges established by an authority under this section are not subject to supervision or regulation by any unit of the State other than the authority.</text></subsection></section><section db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::77:"><enum>77.</enum><subsection db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::77:a:"><enum>(a)</enum><paragraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::77:a:1:"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Any pledge of revenues and other money under &sect; 71(i) of this subtitle is valid and binding from the time the pledge is made.</text></paragraph><paragraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::77:a:2:"><enum>(2)</enum><subparagraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::77:a:2:i:"><enum>(i)</enum><text>The revenue or money that an authority pledges and receives is subject immediately to the lien of the pledge.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::77:a:2:ii:"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Neither physical delivery of the revenue or money nor any other act is required to validate the lien.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::77:a:3:"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The lien of the pledge is valid and binding against each party with a claim against the authority in tort, contract, or otherwise, regardless of whether the party has notice of the lien.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::77:b:"><enum>(b)</enum><text>The trust agreement and any other agreement or lease creating a pledge under this section need not be filed or recorded, except in the records of the authority.</text></subsection></section><section db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::78:"><enum>78.</enum><subsection db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::78:a:"><enum>(a)</enum><text>Proceeds from the sale of bonds and other revenues received under this subtitle are trust funds to be held and applied solely as provided in this subtitle.</text></subsection><subsection db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::78:b:"><enum>(b)</enum><paragraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::78:b:1:"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Each officer, bank, or trust company that receives trust money from an authority under this subtitle shall act as trustee of the money and shall hold and apply the money for the purposes specified under this subtitle.</text></paragraph><paragraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::78:b:2:"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The officer, bank, or trust company holding money is subject to:</text><subparagraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::78:b:2:i:" role="item"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Any regulation adopted under this subtitle; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::78:b:2:ii:" role="item"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>The resolution authorizing the issuance of bonds or the trust agreement.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::79:"><enum>79.</enum><subsection db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::79:a:"><enum>(a)</enum><paragraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::79:a:1:"><enum>(1)</enum><text>An authority may issue bonds to refund outstanding bonds of the authority, including paying:</text><subparagraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::79:a:1:i:" role="item"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Any redemption premium;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::79:a:1:ii:" role="item"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Interest accrued or to accrue to the date of redemption, purchase, or maturity of the bonds; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::79:a:1:iii:" role="item"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>If considered advisable by the authority, any part of the cost of acquiring or improving property as part of a project.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::79:a:2:"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Refunding bonds may be issued for any corporate purpose, including:</text><subparagraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::79:a:2:i:" role="item"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Realizing savings in the effective costs of debt service, directly or through a debt restructuring; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::79:a:2:ii:" role="item"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Alleviating a potential or actual default.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::79:b:"><enum>(b)</enum><text>A refunding bond that an authority issues under this section shall be issued in the same manner and is subject to this subtitle to the same extent as any other bond.</text></subsection><subsection db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::79:c:"><enum>(c)</enum><text>An authority may issue refunding bonds in one or more series in an amount greater than the amount of the bonds to be refunded.</text></subsection></section><section db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::80:"><enum>80.</enum><subsection db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::80:a:"><enum>(a)</enum><text>An authority may issue negotiable bond anticipation notes in anticipation of the sale of bonds for any corporate purpose.</text></subsection><subsection db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::80:b:"><enum>(b)</enum><text>Bond anticipation notes issued under this section shall be issued in the same manner as bonds.</text></subsection><subsection db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::80:c:"><enum>(c)</enum><text>Bond anticipation notes issued under this section and the resolution authorizing them may contain any provisions, conditions, or limitations that may be included in a trust agreement.</text></subsection><subsection db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::80:d:"><enum>(d)</enum><text>An authority may issue bond anticipation notes to pay any other bond anticipation notes.</text></subsection><subsection db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::80:e:"><enum>(e)</enum><text>Bond anticipation notes shall be paid from:</text><paragraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::80:e:1:" role="item"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Revenues of the authority;</text></paragraph><paragraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::80:e:2:" role="item"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Money available and not otherwise pledged; or</text></paragraph><paragraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::80:e:3:" role="item"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The proceeds of the sale of the bonds in anticipation of which the notes were issued.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::81:"><enum>81.</enum><subsection db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::81:a:"><enum>(a)</enum><text>An authority shall convey title to property relating to a project and release collateral in accordance with this section when the following conditions are met:</text><paragraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::81:a:1:" role="item"><enum>(1)</enum><subparagraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::81:a:1:i:"><enum>(i)</enum><text>The principal of and interest on bonds issued to finance the project, including any refunding bonds, have been fully paid and retired; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::81:a:1:ii:"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Adequate provision has been made to fully pay and retire the bonds;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::81:a:2:" role="item"><enum>(2)</enum><text>All other conditions of the trust agreement have been satisfied; and</text></paragraph><paragraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::81:a:3:" role="item"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The lien of the trust agreement has been released.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::81:b:"><enum>(b)</enum><text>On satisfaction of the conditions under subsection (a) of this section, an authority promptly shall execute any deeds, conveyances, releases, and documents and take any other action necessary to convey title to the property and release collateral free of all liens and encumbrances created through the authority.</text></subsection></section><section db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::82:"><enum>82.</enum><subsection db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::82:a:"><enum>(a)</enum><text>A bondholder, a holder of any coupons attached to bonds, or a trustee under a trust agreement securing the bonds may sue:</text><paragraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::82:a:1:" role="item"><enum>(1)</enum><text>To protect and enforce rights under laws of the State or a trust agreement; and</text></paragraph><paragraph db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::82:a:2:" role="item"><enum>(2)</enum><text>To enforce and compel the performance of duties by an authority or its officer, employee, or agent that this subtitle or a trust agreement requires, including fixing and collecting rates, rents, fees, and charges that the trust agreement requires to be fixed and collected.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection db-date="20100618" id=":g23a::52:::82:b:"><enum>(b)</enum><text>The rights under this section are subject to any trust agreement.</text></subsection></section></article></legisdoc>