<?xml version="1.0"?><!DOCTYPE legisdoc SYSTEM "c:\program files\epic\custom\doctypes\legisdoc\legisdoc.dtd"><legisdoc xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" doc-id="docID" public-private="private"><metadata><doc-state state="none"></doc-state></metadata><article id="dummy"><section id=":g25b::1:::1:" db-date="20070227"><enum>1.</enum><subsection id=":g25b::1:::1:a:" db-date="20070227"><enum>(a)</enum><text>&ldquo;Code county&rdquo; (as defined in Article XI&ndash;F of the Maryland Constitution, &sect; 1) means a county which is not a charter county under Article XI-A of the Maryland Constitution and which has adopted the optional powers of home rule provided in Article XI-F of the Maryland Constitution and this article.</text></subsection><subsection id=":g25b::1:::1:b:" db-date="20070227"><enum>(b)</enum><text>&ldquo;Code home rule status&rdquo; means a county under and having the authority of Article XI-F of the Maryland Constitution and this article.</text></subsection><subsection db-date="20070227" id=":g25b::1:::1:c:"><enum>(c)</enum><text>&ldquo;Public local law&rdquo; (as defined in Article XI-F, &sect; 1 of the Maryland Constitution) means a law applicable to the incorporation, organization, or government of a code county and contained in the county&rsquo;s code of public local laws. The term does not include: (1) the charters of municipal corporations under Article XI-E of the Maryland Constitution, (2) the laws or charters of counties under Article XI-A of the Maryland Constitution, (3) laws, whether or not statewide in application, in the Code of Public General Laws, (4) laws which apply to more than one county, (5) ordinances and resolutions of a code county enacted under public local laws.</text></subsection><subsection id=":g25b::1:::1:d:" db-date="20070227"><enum>(d)</enum><text>&ldquo;Registered voter&rdquo; means a person who is registered to vote in State and county elections under the provisions of the Election Law Article.</text></subsection></section><section id=":g25b::2:::2:" db-date="20060801"><enum>2.</enum>
<subsection id=":g25b::2:::2:a:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(a)</enum>
<paragraph id=":g25b::2:::2:a:1:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(1)</enum>
<text>In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</text>
</paragraph><paragraph id=":g25b::2:::2:a:2:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(2)</enum>
<text>&ldquo;Central Maryland&rdquo; means Anne Arundel County, Baltimore City, Baltimore County, Carroll County, Frederick County, Harford County, Howard County, Montgomery County, and Prince George&rsquo;s County.</text>
</paragraph><paragraph id=":g25b::2:::2:a:3:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(3)</enum>
<text>&ldquo;Eastern Shore&rdquo; means Caroline County, Cecil County, Dorchester County, Kent County, Queen Anne&rsquo;s County, Somerset County, Talbot County, Wicomico County, and Worcester County.</text>
</paragraph><paragraph id=":g25b::2:::2:a:4:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(4)</enum>
<text>&ldquo;Southern Maryland&rdquo; means Calvert County, Charles County, and St. Mary&rsquo;s County.</text>
</paragraph><paragraph id=":g25b::2:::2:a:5:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(5)</enum>
<text>&ldquo;Western Maryland&rdquo; means Allegany County, Garrett County, and Washington County.</text>
</paragraph></subsection><subsection id=":g25b::2:::2:b:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(b)</enum>
<paragraph id=":g25b::2:::2:b:1:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(1)</enum>
<text>The General Assembly determines that there are four classes of code counties, based on the geographic region of the State where a county that adopts home rule under Article XI-F of the Maryland Constitution is located.</text>
</paragraph><paragraph id=":g25b::2:::2:b:2:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(2)</enum>
<text>The classes are as follows:</text>
<subparagraph id=":g25b::2:::2:b:2:i:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(i)</enum>
<text>Central Maryland;</text>
</subparagraph><subparagraph id=":g25b::2:::2:b:2:ii:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(ii)</enum>
<text>Eastern Shore;</text>
</subparagraph><subparagraph id=":g25b::2:::2:b:2:iii:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(iii)</enum>
<text>Southern Maryland; and</text>
</subparagraph><subparagraph id=":g25b::2:::2:b:2:iv:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(iv)</enum>
<text>Western Maryland.</text>
</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id=":g25b::2:::2:c:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(c)</enum>
<text>Unless limited to one or more classes listed under this section, any public general law enacted by the General Assembly applicable to code counties applies to each code county, regardless of class.</text>
</subsection></section><section id=":g25b::3:::3:" db-date="20060801"><enum>3.</enum>
<text>Authority to adopt the code form of home rule is vested in the board of county commissioners of the county, subject to being approved by the registered voters of the county at referendum.</text>
</section><section id=":g25b::3:::4:" db-date="20060801"><enum>4.</enum>
<text>Upon determination by the board of county commissioners that the board will formally consider adopting the code form of home rule, the board shall make known this intent by publication of notice that the board is considering the adoption of the code form of home rule. The notice shall contain dates, times, and place or places of public hearings thereon. The notice shall be published in at least one newspaper of general circulation in the county not less than three times, at weekly intervals, within a period of not more than thirty days prior to the first public hearing.</text>
</section><section id=":g25b::3:::5:" db-date="20060801"><enum>5.</enum>
<text>The board of county commissioners shall hold at least two public hearings on the proposal to adopt code home rule status. The hearings may be held in the courthouse or at some other appropriate place or places in the county. At these hearings the residents and taxpayers, or either, within the county shall be given the opportunity to be heard on the proposal to adopt code home rule status.</text>
</section><section id=":g25b::3:::6:" db-date="20060801"><enum>6.</enum>
<text>Within sixty days following the last public hearing, the board of county commissioners shall make a decision on having code home rule status. Adoption of code home rule status shall be done by resolution, passed as in the usual course of considering resolutions, by at least a two-thirds majority of all members elected to the board of county commissioners. The resolution shall state that the county shall operate under Article XI-F of the Maryland Constitution, subject to approval at referendum. A certified copy of the resolution shall be sent to the board of supervisors of elections for the county.</text>
</section><section db-date="20060801" id=":g25b::3:::7:"><enum>7.</enum><subsection db-date="20060801" id=":g25b::3:::7:a:"><enum>(a)</enum><text>The board of supervisors of elections, at the next regular congressional election and in accordance with requirements as to time, notice, and form in the Election Law Article, shall submit the question of code home rule status to the registered voters of the county for their adoption or rejection. The ballots or voting machine labels, as the case may be, shall contain the words &ldquo;For Adoption of Code Home Rule Status&rdquo; and &ldquo;Against Adoption of Code Home Rule Status&rdquo;. If a majority of those who vote on the question cast their votes in favor of adoption, the board of county commissioners publicly shall so proclaim within ten days after receiving a certification of the votes from the board of supervisors of elections; and on the thirtieth day following the public proclamation the county shall become a code home rule county. If a majority of those persons who vote on the question cast their votes against adoption, the board of county commissioners likewise shall so proclaim, and in this event the proposal is rejected at that election.</text></subsection><subsection db-date="20060801" id=":g25b::3:::7:b:"><enum>(b)</enum><text>Whenever the county commissioners proclaim the adoption or rejection of code home rule status, they shall send notification promptly to the following State agencies:</text></subsection><table frame="none" line-rules="no-gen"><tgroup cols="2"><colspec align="right" coldef="align-on-char" colname="col1" colwidth="0.34*" min-data-value="0"/><colspec coldef="align-on-char" colname="col2" colwidth="1.66*" min-data-value="0"/><tbody><row><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0"></entry><?Pub Caret1?><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0"></entry></row><row><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0">(1)</entry><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0">State Department of Legislative Services <?Pub _newline?>Legislative Services Building <?Pub _newline?>90 State Circle <?Pub _newline?>Annapolis, Maryland 21401 (five copies) </entry></row><row><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0"></entry><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0"></entry></row><row><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0">(2)</entry><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0">Secretary of State of Maryland <?Pub _newline?>State House <?Pub _newline?>Annapolis, Maryland 21401 (one copy) </entry></row><row><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0"></entry><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0"></entry></row><row><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0">(3)</entry><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0">State Archives <?Pub _newline?>350 Rowe Boulevard <?Pub _newline?>Annapolis, Maryland 21401 (one copy) </entry></row><row><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0"></entry><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0"></entry></row><row><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0">(4)</entry><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0">State Law Library <?Pub _newline?>Courts of Appeal Building <?Pub _newline?>Rowe Boulevard and Taylor Avenue <?Pub _newline?>Annapolis, Maryland 21401 (one copy)</entry></row></tbody></tgroup></table></section><section id=":g25b::3:::7A:" db-date="20060801"><enum>7A.</enum>
<text>After having become a code county according to the procedure required in this subtitle, any such county may elect to return to its form of government prior to the adoption of code county status by following the same procedure required hereunder for the adoption of such status.</text>
</section><section id=":g25b::8:::8:" db-date="20060801"><enum>8.</enum>
<text>Every code county shall proceed as provided in this subtitle in exercising the powers for the enactment, amendment, or repeal of public local laws or for the issuance of bonds under the subtitle &ldquo;Creation of Public Debt by Code Counties&rdquo; in this article.</text>
</section><section id=":g25b::8:::9:" db-date="20060801"><enum>9.</enum>
<text>Every code county, by public local law, shall establish a specified number of days, not to exceed forty-five, in which the board of county commissioners may meet in each year for the purpose of enacting public local laws. These legislative days may but need not be consecutive and may be allotted as the legislative body, by public local law determines. The first legislative session shall be held on the first ordinary business day which is sixty days subsequent to the effective date of code home rule status and shall be fifteen days long. These fifteen days shall not count as part of the annual forty-five legislative days. Any legislative day not specified or not determinable by the local law shall be preceded by a notice published in a newspaper of general circulation in the county within a period of from not less than three to not more than fourteen days prior thereto.</text>
</section><section id=":g25b::8:::10:" db-date="20060801"><enum>10.</enum>
<subsection id=":g25b::8:::10:a:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(a)</enum>
<text>All legislative sessions shall be open to the public.</text>
</subsection><subsection id=":g25b::8:::10:b:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(b)</enum>
<text>The style of the enacting clause for all bills shall be &ldquo;Be it enacted by ..........&rdquo; and all public local laws shall be passed by original bill.</text>
</subsection><subsection id=":g25b::8:::10:c:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(c)</enum>
<text>Each public local law enacted shall embrace but one subject, and that shall be described in its title; and no public local law, or section of public local law, shall be repealed, revised, or amended by reference to its title only.</text>
</subsection><subsection id=":g25b::8:::10:d:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(d)</enum>
<text>A bill may be introduced by any member of the board of county commissioners on any legislative session day. Not later than the next calendar day following the introduction of a bill the president of the board of county commissioners shall schedule a public hearing on the bill, that shall not be less than seven calendar days after its introduction; but the board of county commissioners may reject any bill on its introduction without a hearing by a vote of at least two thirds of its total membership. The hearing may but need not be held on a legislative session day and may be adjourned from time to time. After a public hearing, a bill may be finally passed on a legislative session day with or without amendment; but if a bill is amended before final passage, it shall not be passed until it is reprinted or reproduced as amended.</text>
</subsection><subsection id=":g25b::8:::10:e:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(e)</enum>
<text>Upon introduction of an emergency bill the president of the board of county commissioners shall schedule a public hearing thereon, which shall not be less than three calendar days after its introduction. The public hearing may but need not be held on a legislative session day and may be adjourned from time to time. After public hearing, the bill may be passed with or without amendment on a legislative session day by an affirmative vote of at least four fifths of the total membership of the board of county commissioners or two thirds where total board membership is three members. Emergency bills which are amended are not subject to the requirement for reprinting or reproduction contained in subsection (d) of this section.</text>
</subsection><subsection id=":g25b::8:::10:f:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(f)</enum>
<text>Subject to the provisions of subsection (e) above, no bill shall become public local law unless it be passed by a majority of the total membership of the board of county commissioners, and on its final passage the yeas and nays shall be recorded in a journal.</text>
</subsection><subsection id=":g25b::8:::10:g:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(g)</enum>
<text>On the introduction of any bill, a copy thereof and notice of the time and place of the hearing shall be posted as soon as practicable on an official bulletin board in a public place in the building in which the county commissioners usually meet, and so that the public may have ready access thereto during normal business hours; and additional copies of the bill, with notice of the date of hearing, shall be made available to the public and to the press. Every copy of each bill shall bear the name of the member introducing it and the date it was introduced; and no bill, unless it be an emergency bill, may be passed before the seventh calendar day after introduction. Any amendments proposed to a bill shall be in writing, and copies of the amendments shall be made available for inspection by the press and public. Upon the passage of any bill, the bill or a fair summary thereof shall be published in at least one newspaper of general circulation in the county, not less than three times, at weekly intervals, within a four-week period following its passage.</text>
</subsection><subsection id=":g25b::8:::10:h:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(h)</enum>
<paragraph id=":g25b::8:::10:h:1:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(1)</enum>
<text>Any public local law enacted by the board of county commissioners of a code county shall take effect forty-five days after it is enacted, unless by a provision of the public local law it is to take effect at a later date. If a public local law is passed as an emergency bill or if a bill is declared by at least a four-fifths vote of the total membership of the board of county commissioners or two thirds where total board membership is three members to be an emergency bill affecting the public health, safety, or welfare of the county, the law shall take effect from the date of its passage. The term &ldquo;emergency bill&rdquo; shall not include one abolishing or creating any office, changing any salary, term, or duty of any officer, granting any franchise or special privilege or creating any vested right or interest.</text>
</paragraph><paragraph id=":g25b::8:::10:h:2:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(2)</enum>
<text>The citizens of a code county, by petition, may submit to the registered voters of the county any public local law or portion thereof enacted under this subtitle. The submission shall be:</text>
<subparagraph id=":g25b::8:::10:h:2:i:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(i)</enum>
<text>At the next regular congressional election or, in accordance with a resolution adopted by the county commissioners, at a special election;</text>
</subparagraph><subparagraph id=":g25b::8:::10:h:2:ii:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(ii)</enum>
<text>In accordance with requirements as to time, notice, and form in the Election Law Article; and</text>
</subparagraph><subparagraph id=":g25b::8:::10:h:2:iii:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(iii)</enum>
<text>For adoption or rejection by a majority of those voting on the question.</text>
</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id=":g25b::8:::10:h:3:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(3)</enum>
<text>The referendum petition shall be filed with the board of supervisors of elections within forty days after a bill is enacted and shall contain the signatures of at least ten per centum of the registered voters of the county. If more than one half but less than the full number of signatures required to complete any referendum petition against a public local law are filed within forty days from the date it is enacted, the time for the public local law to take effect and the time for filing the remainder of signatures to complete the petition shall be extended for an additional forty days, with like effect.</text>
</paragraph><paragraph id=":g25b::8:::10:h:4:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(4)</enum>
<text>A petition may consist of several papers, but each paper shall contain the full text of the public local law or part of the public local law petitioned to referendum, and there shall be attached to each paper an affidavit of the person procuring the signatures thereon that, to his personal knowledge, each signature thereon is genuine and bona fide, and that to the best of his knowledge, information, and belief the signers are registered voters of the State of Maryland and of the code county, as set opposite their names. The board of supervisors of elections shall verify the registration of the petitioners.</text>
</paragraph><paragraph id=":g25b::8:::10:h:5:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(5)</enum>
<text>If the petition is filed with the board of supervisors of elections in compliance with all provisions of law, the public local law shall not take effect until thirty days after its approval by a majority of the registered voters voting on the question. An emergency bill shall remain in force from its effective date notwithstanding the filing of the petition, but it shall be repealed thirty days after having been rejected by a majority of the registered voters voting thereon.</text>
</paragraph></subsection></section><section id=":g25b::8:::11:" db-date="20060801"><enum>11.</enum>
<text>The board of county commissioners of a code county shall provide for the keeping of a journal, which shall be open to public inspection at all reasonable times.</text>
</section><section db-date="20100618" id=":g25b::8:::12:"><enum>12.</enum><subsection db-date="20100618" id=":g25b::8:::12:a:"><enum>(a)</enum><text>At the end of each calendar or fiscal year, each code county shall furnish in a convenient and legible compilation a complete set of all local laws enacted, amended, or repealed by the code county during that year.</text></subsection><subsection db-date="20100618" id=":g25b::8:::12:b:"><enum>(b)</enum><paragraph db-date="20100618" id=":g25b::8:::12:b:1:"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Copies of this compilation shall be:</text><subparagraph db-date="20100618" id=":g25b::8:::12:b:1:i:" role="item"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Made available for inspection at the office of the board of county commissioners during normal business hours; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph db-date="20100618" id=":g25b::8:::12:b:1:ii:" role="item"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Kept on permanent record at the office of the board of county commissioners.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph db-date="20100618" id=":g25b::8:::12:b:2:"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Each code county shall:</text><subparagraph db-date="20100618" id=":g25b::8:::12:b:2:i:" role="item"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Furnish printed copies to the State Archives and to the State Law Library; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph db-date="20100618" id=":g25b::8:::12:b:2:ii:" role="item"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Once each year:</text><sub-subparagraph db-date="20100618" id=":g25b::8:::12:b:2:ii:1:" role="item"><enum>1.</enum><text>Notify each member of the county&rsquo;s legislative delegation that a digital copy of the compilation is available on the Internet; or</text></sub-subparagraph><sub-subparagraph db-date="20100618" id=":g25b::8:::12:b:2:ii:2:" role="item"><enum>2.</enum><text>Furnish a printed copy of the compilation to each member of the county&rsquo;s legislative delegation.</text></sub-subparagraph></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph db-date="20100618" id=":g25b::8:::12:b:3:"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Copies under paragraph (2) of this subsection shall be furnished without charge, and the county also may make other copies available at a reasonable cost to any person.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection db-date="20100618" id=":g25b::8:::12:c:"><enum>(c)</enum><text>Not later than March 1 of the next succeeding year, the code county, without charge, shall furnish 4 printed copies of this compilation to the State Department of Legislative Services.</text></subsection><subsection db-date="20100618" id=":g25b::8:::12:d:"><enum>(d)</enum><paragraph db-date="20100618" id=":g25b::8:::12:d:1:"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Each code county shall provide to the State Department of Legislative Services a statement concerning any referendum on any proposed local law.</text></paragraph><paragraph db-date="20100618" id=":g25b::8:::12:d:2:"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The statement shall include information on the results of any referendum held during the year, and it shall include information as to any referendum pending actually or potentially, but not yet held, at the end of the year.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection db-date="20100618" id=":g25b::8:::12:e:"><enum>(e)</enum><paragraph db-date="20100618" id=":g25b::8:::12:e:1:"><enum>(1)</enum><text>At the end of each calendar year the State Department of Legislative Services shall address an inquiry to each code county inquiring whether or not during that calendar year or its latest fiscal year it has enacted, amended or repealed any portion of its public local laws.</text></paragraph><paragraph db-date="20100618" id=":g25b::8:::12:e:2:"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The code county shall promptly answer the inquiry and shall verify that printed copies of all such enactments, amendments, or repeals have already been sent to the Department.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection db-date="20100618" id=":g25b::8:::12:f:"><enum>(f)</enum><paragraph db-date="20100618" id=":g25b::8:::12:f:1:"><enum>(1)</enum><text>If the code county fails or refuses to supply printed copies of this compilation and of the results of any referenda thereon to the State Department of Legislative Services by March 1 of the next succeeding year, or fails or refuses to certify that there have been no such enactments, amendments, or repeals, or referenda, during the last calendar or fiscal year, the Department shall promptly certify that fact to the State Comptroller, who then may order the discontinuance of all funds, grants or State aid which the code county is entitled to receive under State law.</text></paragraph><paragraph db-date="20100618" id=":g25b::8:::12:f:2:"><enum>(2)</enum><text>This section refers specifically to all funds, grants or State aid which the code county is entitled to receive under applicable provisions of State law relating to the income tax, the tax on racing, the recordation tax, the admissions and amusement tax, and the license tax.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection db-date="20100618" id=":g25b::8:::12:g:"><enum>(g)</enum><paragraph db-date="20100618" id=":g25b::8:::12:g:1:"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The State Department of Legislative Services shall receive the compilations and statements delivered to it.</text></paragraph><paragraph db-date="20100618" id=":g25b::8:::12:g:2:"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The titles of the laws of the several code counties which amend their codes of public local laws shall be arranged in a logical and convenient order and shall be delivered to the State printer for inclusion in the Session Laws of the General Assembly for its regular session in that year.</text></paragraph><paragraph db-date="20100618" id=":g25b::8:::12:g:3:"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The titles of the laws of the code counties which amend their codes of public local laws shall be printed and identified as such, and they shall be indexed with or in a supplemental volume to the laws enacted by the General Assembly.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection db-date="20100618" id=":g25b::8:::12:h:"><enum>(h)</enum><text>Whenever a code county in this State publishes or issues in printed, mimeographed, or similar duplicated form a code or compilation containing all or a portion of the public local laws of the county, the code county shall deposit printed copies free of charge with the following State agencies: State Archives, 1 copy; State Law Library, 1 copy; State Department of Legislative Services, 5 copies.</text></subsection></section><section db-date="20100618" id=":g25b::13:::13:"><enum>13.</enum><text>If a county adopts code home rule status under the provisions of Article XI&ndash;F of the Maryland Constitution and this article, it may exercise those powers enumerated in Article 25 and in &sect; 5 of Article 25A, except for subsections (A), (P) and (S) of &sect; 5 of Article 25A, of the Annotated Code of Maryland, 1957 Edition as amended; and no county adopting code home rule status shall be excepted. These powers are in addition to any powers any county may now have under any public general or local law applicable to the county.</text></section><section id=":g25b::13:::13A:" db-date="20060801"><enum>13A.</enum>
<subsection id=":g25b::13:::13A:a:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(a)</enum>
<text>Unless otherwise specifically provided by the laws of Maryland, a code county, and every officer, department, agency, board, commission, or other unit of county government may not raise the defense of sovereign immunity in the courts of this State in an action in contract based upon a written contract executed on behalf of the county, or its department, agency, board, commission, or unit by an official or employee acting within the scope of his authority.</text>
</subsection><subsection id=":g25b::13:::13A:b:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(b)</enum>
<text>In any action in contract described under subsection (a) of this section, the county, or its officer, department, agency, board, commission, or other unit of government shall have the immunity from liability described under &sect; 5-510 of the Courts and Judicial Proceedings Article.</text>
</subsection><subsection id=":g25b::13:::13A:c:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(c)</enum>
<text>A claim is barred unless the claimant files suit within one year from the date on which the claim arose or within one year after the completion of the contract giving rise to the claim, whichever is later.</text>
</subsection><subsection id=":g25b::13:::13A:d:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(d)</enum>
<text>In order to provide for the implementation of this section, the governing body of every code county shall make available adequate funds for the satisfaction of any final judgment, after the exhaustion of any right of appeal, which has been rendered against the county, or any officer, department, agency, board, commission, or other unit of government in an action in contract as provided in this section.</text>
</subsection><subsection id=":g25b::13:::13A:e:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(e)</enum>
<text>Except as provided in subsections (f) and (g) of this section, a code county may not require in a construction contract, or otherwise provide with regard to a construction contract, to which it is a party, that a dispute between the parties involving $10,000 or more regarding the terms of the contract or performance under the contract, be subject to final binding or conclusive determination by an officer or official body of a code county.</text>
</subsection><subsection id=":g25b::13:::13A:f:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(f)</enum>
<text>A code county may require or provide, with regard to a construction contract, to which it is a party, that if there is a dispute regarding the terms of the contract or performance under the contract, the question or questions involved in the dispute shall be subject to a determination which is final and conclusive on all parties, made either by:</text>
<paragraph id=":g25b::13:::13A:f:1:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(1)</enum>
<text>A neutral person or entity selected by or in accordance with a procedure established by the highest executive authority of a code county, or</text>
</paragraph><paragraph id=":g25b::13:::13A:f:2:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(2)</enum>
<text>In the event that the other party does not accept as neutral a person or entity selected under paragraph (1) of this subsection, by an arbitration panel composed of the following:</text>
<subparagraph id=":g25b::13:::13A:f:2:i:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(i)</enum>
<text>One member designated by the highest executive authority of a code county;</text>
</subparagraph><subparagraph id=":g25b::13:::13A:f:2:ii:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(ii)</enum>
<text>One member designated by the other party to the dispute; and</text>
</subparagraph><subparagraph id=":g25b::13:::13A:f:2:iii:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(iii)</enum>
<text>One member to be selected by mutual agreement of the two designated members from lists to be submitted by the parties to the dispute.</text>
</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id=":g25b::13:::13A:g:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(g)</enum>
<text>Notwithstanding the provisions of subsections (e) and (f) of this section, a code county may provide or require, with regard to a construction contract to which it is a party, that a dispute between the parties involving $10,000 or more regarding the terms of the contract or performance under the contract, be subject to a determination of questions of fact by an officer or official body of a code county, provided that the decision of the officer or official body of a code county is subject to review on the record by a court of competent jurisdiction.</text>
</subsection></section><section id=":g25b::13:::13B:" db-date="20060801"><enum>13B.</enum>
<subsection id=":g25b::13:::13B:a:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(a)</enum>
<paragraph id=":g25b::13:::13B:a:1:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(1)</enum>
<text>It has been and shall continue to be the policy of the State to authorize each code county to displace or limit competition in the area of public transportation in order to provide for adequate, economical, and efficient delivery of transportation services; to protect its citizens from inconsistent and excessive prices; to provide necessary and desired services in all areas of the county; to enable the county to provide public transportation in order to conserve energy and reduce air pollution, congestion, traffic hazards, and accidents; to encourage the use of public transportation by the contribution by the county of capital and operating funds to enable transportation to be provided at the lowest cost to all citizens, especially the indigent; and to promote the general welfare by conducting a comprehensive transportation system.</text>
</paragraph><paragraph id=":g25b::13:::13B:a:2:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(2)</enum>
<text>Each code county has the authority to grant one or more franchises for a transportation system on an exclusive or nonexclusive basis, to impose franchise fees, to establish certain rates, to establish rules, regulations, and licensing requirements to govern the operation of the franchises, to provide for the enforcement of any such measure, and to conduct a public transportation system on an exclusive basis, including the establishment of rules, regulations, and rates, notwithstanding any anticompetitive effect.</text>
</paragraph></subsection><subsection id=":g25b::13:::13B:b:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(b)</enum>
<paragraph id=":g25b::13:::13B:b:1:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(1)</enum>
<text>It has been and shall continue to be the policy of the State to authorize each code county to displace or limit competition in the area of water and sewerage systems in order to assure delivery of adequate, economical, and efficient services to its citizens, to avoid duplication of facilities, to provide for the health and safety of its citizens, to control disease, to prevent blight and other environmental degradation, to utilize efficiently the public right-of-way; to protect limited natural resources for the benefit of the citizens of the county; and to promote the general health and welfare by providing for adequate water and sewerage systems.</text>
</paragraph><paragraph id=":g25b::13:::13B:b:2:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(2)</enum>
<subparagraph id=":g25b::13:::13B:b:2:i:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(i)</enum>
<text>Each code county has the authority to grant one or more franchises or enter into contracts for water and sewerage systems on an exclusive or nonexclusive basis to any person, to impose franchise fees, to establish certain rates and charges and to establish rules, regulations, and licensing requirements and to provide for the enforcement of any such measure notwithstanding any anticompetitive effect.</text>
</subparagraph><subparagraph id=":g25b::13:::13B:b:2:ii:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(ii)</enum>
<text>In the event that any code county has the enabling authority granted by any other law to operate water and sewerage systems, such systems shall be operated by such county without regard to any anticompetitive effect.</text>
</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id=":g25b::13:::13B:b:3:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(3)</enum>
<text>It has been and shall continue to be the policy of the State that each code county is directed and authorized to exercise all powers regarding waste collection and disposal notwithstanding any anticompetitive effect. This subsection does not apply to any portion of a generator&rsquo;s waste which is directed by the generator to a specific facility for reuse, reclamation or recycling, or for disposal on its own property.</text>
</paragraph></subsection><subsection id=":g25b::13:::13B:c:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(c)</enum>
<paragraph id=":g25b::13:::13B:c:1:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(1)</enum>
<text>It has been and shall continue to be the policy of this State to authorize each code county to displace or limit competition in the area of port regulation to provide for safe harbors, free of congestion and navigational hazards, to provide benefits to county citizens by protecting marine life and wildlife and to avoid water pollution and erosion.</text>
</paragraph><paragraph id=":g25b::13:::13B:c:2:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(2)</enum>
<text>Each code county has the authority to grant one or more franchises or enter into contracts for the placement, erection or construction of structures within or on the waters of the county, including but not limited to the issuing of licenses for wharves or piers, or the issuing of permits for mooring piles, floating wharves, buoys or anchors, notwithstanding any anticompetitive effect.</text>
</paragraph></subsection><subsection id=":g25b::13:::13B:d:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(d)</enum>
<paragraph id=":g25b::13:::13B:d:1:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(1)</enum>
<text>It has been and shall continue to be the policy of the State to authorize each code county to displace or limit competition in the award of concessions on, over or under property owned or leased by the county and in the leasing or subleasing of property owned or leased by the county in order to utilize properly the assets of the county for the best public purpose; to provide necessary or desirable governmental services at the lowest possible cost; to protect the public from unscrupulous business practices and excessive prices; to provide for the accessibility to public property by as many citizens as possible; and to promote the general welfare by utilizing public property for the benefit of the citizens of the community.</text>
</paragraph><paragraph id=":g25b::13:::13B:d:2:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(2)</enum>
<text>Each code county has the authority to displace or limit competition by granting one or more franchises for any concession on, over or under property owned or leased by the county on an exclusive or nonexclusive basis, to control prices and rates for such franchises; and to establish rules and regulations to govern the operation of the franchises and for the enforcement thereof; and to lease or sublease publicly owned or leased land improvements to land or both on terms to be determined by the county or counties without regard to any anticompetitive effect.</text>
</paragraph></subsection><subsection id=":g25b::13:::13B:e:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(e)</enum>
<text>The powers granted to any county pursuant to this section shall not be construed:</text>
<paragraph id=":g25b::13:::13B:e:1:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(1)</enum>
<text>To grant to such county powers in any substantive area not otherwise granted to such county by other public general or public local law;</text>
</paragraph><paragraph id=":g25b::13:::13B:e:2:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(2)</enum>
<text>To restrict such county from exercising any power granted to such county by other public general or public local law or otherwise;</text>
</paragraph><paragraph id=":g25b::13:::13B:e:3:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(3)</enum>
<text>To authorize such county or its officers to engage in any activity which is beyond their power under other public general law, public local law, or otherwise; or</text>
</paragraph><paragraph id=":g25b::13:::13B:e:4:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(4)</enum>
<text>To preempt or supersede the regulatory authority of any State department or agency under any public general law.</text>
</paragraph></subsection></section><section id=":g25b::13:::13C:" db-date="20070608"><enum>13C.</enum><subsection id=":g25b::13:::13C:a:" db-date="20070608"><enum>(a)</enum><paragraph id=":g25b::13:::13C:a:1:" db-date="20070608"><enum>(1)</enum><text>In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</text></paragraph><paragraph id=":g25b::13:::13C:a:2:" db-date="20070608"><enum>(2)</enum><subparagraph id=":g25b::13:::13C:a:2:i:" db-date="20070608"><enum>(i)</enum><text>&ldquo;Civil infraction&rdquo; means a violation of a county ordinance, resolution, or public local law which has been designated a civil infraction by the legislative body of a code home rule county.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id=":g25b::13:::13C:a:2:ii:" db-date="20070608"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>A civil infraction is a civil offense.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id=":g25b::13:::13C:a:3:" db-date="20070608"><enum>(3)</enum><text>&ldquo;Defendant&rdquo; means a person receiving a citation for a civil infraction.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id=":g25b::13:::13C:b:" db-date="20070608"><enum>(b)</enum><text>Unless a violation of a county ordinance, resolution, or public local law is declared to be a felony or a misdemeanor by law, resolution, or ordinance, the legislative body of a code county may provide that a violation of a county ordinance, resolution, or public local law shall be a civil infraction.</text></subsection><subsection id=":g25b::13:::13C:c:" db-date="20070608"><enum>(c)</enum><paragraph id=":g25b::13:::13C:c:1:" db-date="20070608"><enum>(1)</enum><text>An official authorized by the legislative body of a code county may deliver a citation to a person whom the official determines to be committing a civil infraction. A copy of the citation shall be retained by the issuing authority and shall bear the official&rsquo;s certification attesting to the truth of the matter set forth in the citation.</text></paragraph><paragraph id=":g25b::13:::13C:c:2:" db-date="20070608"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The citation shall also contain:</text><subparagraph id=":g25b::13:::13C:c:2:i:" role="item" db-date="20070608"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Name and address of the defendant;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id=":g25b::13:::13C:c:2:ii:" role="item" db-date="20070608"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>The nature of the infraction;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id=":g25b::13:::13C:c:2:iii:" role="item" db-date="20070608"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>The location and time that the infraction occurred;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id=":g25b::13:::13C:c:2:iv:" role="item" db-date="20070608"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>The amount of the infraction fine assessed;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id=":g25b::13:::13C:c:2:v:" role="item" db-date="20070608"><enum>(v)</enum><text>The manner, location, and time in which the fine may be paid to the county; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id=":g25b::13:::13C:c:2:vi:" role="item" db-date="20070608"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>The defendant&rsquo;s right to elect to stand trial for the infraction.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id=":g25b::13:::13C:d:" db-date="20070608"><enum>(d)</enum><paragraph id=":g25b::13:::13C:d:1:" db-date="20070608"><enum>(1)</enum><text>A code county may impose a fine not to exceed $500 for each commission of a civil infraction. The defendant may pay the fine to the county within 20 calendar days of receipt of the citation.</text></paragraph><paragraph id=":g25b::13:::13C:d:2:" db-date="20070608"><enum>(2)</enum><text>For each repeat offense a code county may assess against the defendant a fine not to exceed $1,000.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id=":g25b::13:::13C:e:" db-date="20070608"><enum>(e)</enum><paragraph id=":g25b::13:::13C:e:1:" db-date="20070608"><enum>(1)</enum><text>A defendant may elect to stand trial for the offense by notifying the county of the defendant&rsquo;s intention to stand trial. The defendant shall give the notice at least 5 days before the date of payment in the citation.</text></paragraph><paragraph id=":g25b::13:::13C:e:2:" db-date="20070608"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Upon receipt of the notice of the intention to stand trial, the county shall forward to the District Court having venue a copy of the citation.</text></paragraph><paragraph id=":g25b::13:::13C:e:3:" db-date="20070608"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Upon receipt of the citation, the District Court shall schedule the case for trial and notify the defendant of the trial date.</text></paragraph><paragraph id=":g25b::13:::13C:e:4:" db-date="20070608"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The District Court shall remit to the county any fine, penalty, or forfeiture the court collects.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id=":g25b::13:::13C:f:" db-date="20070608"><enum>(f)</enum><paragraph id=":g25b::13:::13C:f:1:" db-date="20070608"><enum>(1)</enum><text>If a defendant fails to file a notice of his intention to stand trial for the offense within the time required by subsection (e) of this section, and fails to pay the fine for the infraction by the date of payment in the citation, the county shall send a formal notice of the infraction to the defendant&rsquo;s last known address.</text></paragraph><paragraph id=":g25b::13:::13C:f:2:" db-date="20070608"><enum>(2)</enum><text>If the citation has not been satisfied within 15 days from the date of the notice, the county shall assess an additional fine not to exceed twice the original fine.</text></paragraph><paragraph id=":g25b::13:::13C:f:3:" db-date="20070608"><enum>(3)</enum><text>If after 35 days the citation has not been satisfied, the county may request adjudication of the case through the District Court.</text></paragraph><paragraph id=":g25b::13:::13C:f:4:" db-date="20070608"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Upon receipt of a request from the county, the District Court shall promptly schedule the case for trial and summons the defendant to appear. The defendant&rsquo;s failure to respond to such summons shall be contempt of court.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id=":g25b::13:::13C:g:" db-date="20070608"><enum>(g)</enum><text>Adjudication of a civil infraction is not a criminal conviction for any purpose, and does not impose any of the civil disabilities imposed by a criminal conviction.</text></subsection><subsection id=":g25b::13:::13C:h:" db-date="20070608"><enum>(h)</enum><text>In a proceeding for a civil infraction, the burden of proof shall be the same as required by law in the trial of criminal cases, and the court shall apply the evidentiary standards prescribed by law or rule for the trial of criminal cases.</text></subsection><subsection id=":g25b::13:::13C:i:" db-date="20070608"><enum>(i)</enum><paragraph id=":g25b::13:::13C:i:1:" db-date="20070608"><enum>(1)</enum><text>In a proceeding for a civil infraction, the court shall ensure that the defendant has received a copy of the charges against the defendant and that the defendant understands the charges.</text></paragraph><paragraph id=":g25b::13:::13C:i:2:" db-date="20070608"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The defendant may:</text><subparagraph id=":g25b::13:::13C:i:2:i:" role="item" db-date="20070608"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Cross-examine a witness who appears against the defendant;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id=":g25b::13:::13C:i:2:ii:" role="item" db-date="20070608"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Produce evidence or witnesses in the defendant&rsquo;s behalf; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id=":g25b::13:::13C:i:2:iii:" role="item" db-date="20070608"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>Testify in the defendant&rsquo;s behalf.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id=":g25b::13:::13C:j:" db-date="20070608"><enum>(j)</enum><text>In a proceeding for a civil infraction, a defendant may be represented by counsel of the defendant&rsquo;s selection and at the defendant&rsquo;s expense.</text></subsection><subsection id=":g25b::13:::13C:k:" db-date="20070608"><enum>(k)</enum><paragraph id=":g25b::13:::13C:k:1:" db-date="20070608"><enum>(1)</enum><text>In a proceeding for a civil infraction a defendant may enter a plea of guilty or not guilty.</text></paragraph><paragraph id=":g25b::13:::13C:k:2:" db-date="20070608"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The court may:</text><subparagraph id=":g25b::13:::13C:k:2:i:" role="item" db-date="20070608"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Render a verdict of:</text><sub-subparagraph id=":g25b::13:::13C:k:2:i:1:" role="item" db-date="20070608"><enum>1.</enum><text>Guilty of a civil infraction; or</text></sub-subparagraph><sub-subparagraph id=":g25b::13:::13C:k:2:i:2:" role="item" db-date="20070608"><enum>2.</enum><text>Not guilty of a civil infraction; or</text></sub-subparagraph></subparagraph><subparagraph id=":g25b::13:::13C:k:2:ii:" role="item" db-date="20070608"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Before rendering judgment, place the defendant on probation, in the same manner and to the same extent as is permitted by law in the trial of a criminal case.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id=":g25b::13:::13C:l:" db-date="20070608"><enum>(l)</enum><paragraph id=":g25b::13:::13C:l:1:" db-date="20070608"><enum>(1)</enum><text>If a defendant is found by the District Court to have committed a civil infraction, the defendant shall pay:</text><subparagraph id=":g25b::13:::13C:l:1:i:" role="item" db-date="20070608"><enum>(i)</enum><text>The fine imposed under this section; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id=":g25b::13:::13C:l:1:ii:" role="item" db-date="20070608"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Court costs of $5.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id=":g25b::13:::13C:l:2:" db-date="20070608"><enum>(2)</enum><text>A defendant is not liable for payment of costs under the Criminal Injuries Compensation Act.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id=":g25b::13:::13C:m:" db-date="20070608"><enum>(m)</enum><paragraph id=":g25b::13:::13C:m:1:" db-date="20070608"><enum>(1)</enum><text>When a defendant has been found guilty of a civil infraction and a fine has been imposed by the court, the court may direct that the payment of the fine be suspended or deferred under such conditions as the court may establish.</text></paragraph><paragraph id=":g25b::13:::13C:m:2:" db-date="20070608"><enum>(2)</enum><text>When a defendant has been found guilty of a civil infraction and willfully fails to pay the fine imposed by the court, the court may treat the failure as a criminal contempt of court.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id=":g25b::13:::13C:n:" db-date="20070608"><enum>(n)</enum><paragraph id=":g25b::13:::13C:n:1:" db-date="20070608"><enum>(1)</enum><text>A defendant who has been found guilty of a civil infraction has the same rights to file a motion for a new trial or a motion for a revision of a judgment as are now provided by law or rule in the trial of a criminal case.</text></paragraph><paragraph id=":g25b::13:::13C:n:2:" db-date="20070608"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The defendant shall make the motions in the same manner as provided in the trial of criminal cases, and the court, in ruling on the motions, has the same authority as provided in the trial of criminal cases.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection db-date="20070608" id=":g25b::13:::13C:o:"><enum>(o)</enum><paragraph db-date="20070608" id=":g25b::13:::13C:o:1:"><enum>(1)</enum><text>In a proceeding for a civil infraction:</text><subparagraph db-date="20070608" id=":g25b::13:::13C:o:1:i:" role="item"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Subject to the provisions of paragraphs (2) and (3) of this subsection, the State&rsquo;s Attorney for a county shall prosecute the civil infraction in the same manner as a violation of the criminal laws of this State; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph db-date="20070608" id=":g25b::13:::13C:o:1:ii:" role="item"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>The State&rsquo;s Attorney may enter a nolle prosequi or place the case on the stet docket in the same manner as is now prescribed by law or rule for violation of the criminal laws of this State.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph db-date="20070608" id=":g25b::13:::13C:o:2:"><enum>(2)</enum><subparagraph db-date="20070608" id=":g25b::13:::13C:o:2:i:"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Subject to the approval of the county commissioners, the State&rsquo;s Attorney for a county may designate in writing the county attorney or any assistant county attorney in a county to exercise the power to prosecute civil infractions.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph db-date="20070608" id=":g25b::13:::13C:o:2:ii:"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Upon a designation described under this paragraph of the county attorney or any assistant county attorney, the designated county attorney or assistant county attorney shall have, and be authorized to exercise, the power and authority of the State&rsquo;s Attorney with respect to the prosecution of a civil infraction.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph db-date="20070608" id=":g25b::13:::13C:o:3:"><enum>(3)</enum><text>In Allegany County, during a prosecution for a civil infraction under Article 25, &sect; 122A of the Code, the presence of the State&rsquo;s Attorney for the county is not required at the trial for the civil infraction if the official who issued the citation for the civil infraction is present at the trial on behalf of the county.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id=":g25b::13:::13C-1:" db-date="20060801"><enum>13C&ndash;1.</enum>
<subsection id=":g25b::13:::13C-1:a:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(a)</enum>
<paragraph id=":g25b::13:::13C-1:a:1:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(1)</enum>
<text>In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</text>
</paragraph><paragraph id=":g25b::13:::13C-1:a:2:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(2)</enum>
<text>&ldquo;Curfew hours&rdquo; means 12:00 a.m. until 5:00 a.m.</text>
</paragraph><paragraph id=":g25b::13:::13C-1:a:3:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(3)</enum>
<text>&ldquo;Emergency&rdquo; means a sudden or unexpected happening or an unforeseen combination of circumstances that calls for immediate action to protect the health, safety, welfare, or property of an individual from actual or threatened harm or from an unlawful act.</text>
</paragraph><paragraph id=":g25b::13:::13C-1:a:4:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(4)</enum>
<text>&ldquo;Establishment&rdquo; means a privately owned place of business operated for a profit to which the public is invited.</text>
</paragraph><paragraph id=":g25b::13:::13C-1:a:5:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(5)</enum>
<text>&ldquo;Guardian&rdquo; means a person who is appointed by a court as a guardian of a minor.</text>
</paragraph><paragraph id=":g25b::13:::13C-1:a:6:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(6)</enum>
<subparagraph id=":g25b::13:::13C-1:a:6:i:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(i)</enum>
<text>&ldquo;Public place&rdquo; means a place to which the general public has access and a right to resort for business, entertainment, or other lawful purpose.</text>
</subparagraph><subparagraph id=":g25b::13:::13C-1:a:6:ii:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(ii)</enum>
<text>&ldquo;Public place&rdquo; includes:</text>
<sub-subparagraph id=":g25b::13:::13C-1:a:6:ii:1:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>1.</enum>
<text>A public street, sidewalk, alley, highway, and right-of-way of a public street or highway; and</text>
</sub-subparagraph><sub-subparagraph id=":g25b::13:::13C-1:a:6:ii:2:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>2.</enum>
<text>The common areas of a transport facility, school, hospital, apartment building, office building, shopping center, park, playground, parking lot, theater, restaurant, bowling alley, tavern, cafe, arcade, and shops.</text>
</sub-subparagraph></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id=":g25b::13:::13C-1:a:7:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(7)</enum>
<text>&ldquo;Remain&rdquo; means to:</text>
<subparagraph id=":g25b::13:::13C-1:a:7:i:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(i)</enum>
<text>Linger or stay unnecessarily in a public place; or</text>
</subparagraph><subparagraph id=":g25b::13:::13C-1:a:7:ii:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(ii)</enum>
<text>Fail to leave the premises of an establishment or public place when asked by a local law enforcement officer or employee of the establishment or public place.</text>
</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id=":g25b::13:::13C-1:b:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(b)</enum>
<text>The provisions of this section apply to code counties in the Eastern Shore class as established by Article 25B, &sect; 2.</text>
</subsection><subsection id=":g25b::13:::13C-1:c:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(c)</enum>
<text>After making independent factual findings demonstrating a local need for a juvenile curfew, the county commissioners in their respective jurisdictions may adopt a juvenile curfew ordinance which may be adopted by a municipal corporation in the county.</text>
</subsection><subsection id=":g25b::13:::13C-1:d:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(d)</enum>
<text>A juvenile curfew ordinance shall state that:</text>
<paragraph id=":g25b::13:::13C-1:d:1:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(1)</enum>
<text>A minor may not remain in a public place or on the premises of an establishment within the local jurisdiction during curfew hours;</text>
</paragraph><paragraph id=":g25b::13:::13C-1:d:2:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(2)</enum>
<text>A parent or guardian of a minor may not knowingly allow the minor to remain in a public place or on the premises of an establishment within the local jurisdiction during curfew hours; and</text>
</paragraph><paragraph id=":g25b::13:::13C-1:d:3:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(3)</enum>
<text>The owner, operator, or employee of an establishment may not knowingly allow a minor to remain on the premises of the establishment within the local jurisdiction during curfew hours.</text>
</paragraph></subsection><subsection id=":g25b::13:::13C-1:e:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(e)</enum>
<text>A juvenile curfew ordinance adopted under this section does not apply to a minor who is:</text>
<paragraph id=":g25b::13:::13C-1:e:1:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(1)</enum>
<text>Accompanied by the minor&rsquo;s parent or guardian;</text>
</paragraph><paragraph id=":g25b::13:::13C-1:e:2:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(2)</enum>
<text>Performing an errand at the direction of the minor&rsquo;s parent or guardian, without a detour or stop, until 12:30 a.m.;</text>
</paragraph><paragraph id=":g25b::13:::13C-1:e:3:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(3)</enum>
<text>Accompanied by a person at least 18 years of age and authorized by the minor&rsquo;s parent or guardian to have temporary care or custody of the minor for a designated period of time within a specified area;</text>
</paragraph><paragraph id=":g25b::13:::13C-1:e:4:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(4)</enum>
<text>With consent of the minor&rsquo;s parent or guardian, involved in interstate travel through the local jurisdiction or beginning or ending in the local jurisdiction;</text>
</paragraph><paragraph id=":g25b::13:::13C-1:e:5:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(5)</enum>
<text>Engaged in legal employment activity or is going to or returning home from a legal employment activity;</text>
</paragraph><paragraph id=":g25b::13:::13C-1:e:6:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(6)</enum>
<text>Involved in an emergency;</text>
</paragraph><paragraph id=":g25b::13:::13C-1:e:7:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(7)</enum>
<text>On the property where the minor resides or on the sidewalk abutting the minor&rsquo;s residence or abutting the residence of a next-door neighbor, if the adult resident of that property has given permission for the minor&rsquo;s presence;</text>
</paragraph><paragraph id=":g25b::13:::13C-1:e:8:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(8)</enum>
<text>Attending or returning directly home from:</text>
<subparagraph id=":g25b::13:::13C-1:e:8:i:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(i)</enum>
<text>A school, religious, or recreational activity supervised by adults and sponsored by the local jurisdiction, a civic organization, or a voluntary association that takes responsibility for the minor; or</text>
</subparagraph><subparagraph id=":g25b::13:::13C-1:e:8:ii:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(ii)</enum>
<text>A place of public entertainment, including a movie, play, or sporting event;</text>
</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id=":g25b::13:::13C-1:e:9:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(9)</enum>
<text>Exercising First Amendment rights under the United States Constitution, if the minor has first submitted to the chief of the local law enforcement agency a written communication that:</text>
<subparagraph id=":g25b::13:::13C-1:e:9:i:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(i)</enum>
<text>Is signed by the minor and countersigned, if practicable, by the parent or guardian of the minor;</text>
</subparagraph><subparagraph id=":g25b::13:::13C-1:e:9:ii:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(ii)</enum>
<text>Includes the parent&rsquo;s or guardian&rsquo;s home address and telephone number; and</text>
</subparagraph><subparagraph id=":g25b::13:::13C-1:e:9:iii:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(iii)</enum>
<text>Specifies when, where, and in what manner the minor will be in a public place during curfew hours; or</text>
</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id=":g25b::13:::13C-1:e:10:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(10)</enum>
<text>Remaining in a public place in a case of reasonable necessity if the minor&rsquo;s parent or guardian has communicated to the chief of the local law enforcement agency facts:</text>
<subparagraph id=":g25b::13:::13C-1:e:10:i:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(i)</enum>
<text>Establishing the reasonable necessity; and</text>
</subparagraph><subparagraph id=":g25b::13:::13C-1:e:10:ii:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(ii)</enum>
<text>Designating:</text>
<sub-subparagraph id=":g25b::13:::13C-1:e:10:ii:1:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>1.</enum>
<text>The specific public place and the points of origin and destination for the minor&rsquo;s travel; and</text>
</sub-subparagraph><sub-subparagraph id=":g25b::13:::13C-1:e:10:ii:2:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>2.</enum>
<text>The times the minor will be in the public place or traveling to or from the public place.</text>
</sub-subparagraph></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id=":g25b::13:::13C-1:f:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(f)</enum>
<paragraph id=":g25b::13:::13C-1:f:1:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(1)</enum>
<text>If a law enforcement officer reasonably believes that a minor is in a public place or on the premises of an establishment in violation of the juvenile curfew ordinance, the officer shall:</text>
<subparagraph id=":g25b::13:::13C-1:f:1:i:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(i)</enum>
<text>Notify the minor that the minor is in violation of the juvenile curfew ordinance;</text>
</subparagraph><subparagraph id=":g25b::13:::13C-1:f:1:ii:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(ii)</enum>
<text>Require the minor to tell the officer the minor&rsquo;s name, address, telephone number, and where to contact the minor&rsquo;s parent or guardian;</text>
</subparagraph><subparagraph id=":g25b::13:::13C-1:f:1:iii:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(iii)</enum>
<text>Issue the minor a written warning that the minor is in violation of the juvenile curfew ordinance; and</text>
</subparagraph><subparagraph id=":g25b::13:::13C-1:f:1:iv:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(iv)</enum>
<text>Order the minor to promptly go home.</text>
</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id=":g25b::13:::13C-1:f:2:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(2)</enum>
<text>The chief of the local law enforcement agency shall send written notice of the violation of the juvenile curfew ordinance to the minor&rsquo;s parent or guardian.</text>
</paragraph></subsection><subsection id=":g25b::13:::13C-1:g:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(g)</enum>
<text>The local law enforcement agency may take the minor:</text>
<paragraph id=":g25b::13:::13C-1:g:1:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(1)</enum>
<text>To the minor&rsquo;s home, if appropriate; or</text>
</paragraph><paragraph id=":g25b::13:::13C-1:g:2:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(2)</enum>
<text>Into custody and transport the minor to a local law enforcement station or designated curfew center when:</text>
<subparagraph id=":g25b::13:::13C-1:g:2:i:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(i)</enum>
<text>The minor has received one previous written warning for a violation of the juvenile curfew ordinance;</text>
</subparagraph><subparagraph id=":g25b::13:::13C-1:g:2:ii:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(ii)</enum>
<text>The local law enforcement officer has reasonable grounds to believe that the minor has committed a delinquent act; or</text>
</subparagraph><subparagraph id=":g25b::13:::13C-1:g:2:iii:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(iii)</enum>
<text>Taking the minor into custody is authorized under &sect; 3-8A-14 of the Courts Article.</text>
</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id=":g25b::13:::13C-1:h:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(h)</enum>
<text>When a minor is taken into custody for a violation of the juvenile curfew ordinance, the local law enforcement officer shall:</text>
<paragraph id=":g25b::13:::13C-1:h:1:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(1)</enum>
<text>Immediately notify the parent or guardian of the minor to come to the local law enforcement station to take custody of the minor; and</text>
</paragraph><paragraph id=":g25b::13:::13C-1:h:2:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(2)</enum>
<text>Determine whether, consistent with constitutional safeguards, the minor or the parent or guardian, or both, are in violation of the juvenile curfew ordinance.</text>
</paragraph></subsection><subsection id=":g25b::13:::13C-1:i:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(i)</enum>
<paragraph id=":g25b::13:::13C-1:i:1:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(1)</enum>
<text>When a parent or guardian arrives at the local law enforcement station as a result of subsection (h) of this section, and the appropriate information is recorded, the minor shall be released to the custody of the parent or guardian.</text>
</paragraph><paragraph id=":g25b::13:::13C-1:i:2:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(2)</enum>
<text>If the parent or guardian cannot be located or fails to take charge of the minor, then the minor shall be released to the local Department of Social Services, the Department of Juvenile Services, or to another adult who will, on behalf of the parent or guardian, assume the responsibility of caring for the minor pending the availability or arrival of the parent or guardian.</text>
</paragraph></subsection><subsection id=":g25b::13:::13C-1:j:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(j)</enum>
<paragraph id=":g25b::13:::13C-1:j:1:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(1)</enum>
<text>A law enforcement officer may issue a civil citation for a violation of a juvenile curfew ordinance to:</text>
<subparagraph id=":g25b::13:::13C-1:j:1:i:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(i)</enum>
<text>A minor;</text>
</subparagraph><subparagraph id=":g25b::13:::13C-1:j:1:ii:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(ii)</enum>
<text>A parent or guardian of a minor; or</text>
</subparagraph><subparagraph id=":g25b::13:::13C-1:j:1:iii:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(iii)</enum>
<text>An owner, operator, or employee of an establishment.</text>
</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id=":g25b::13:::13C-1:j:2:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(2)</enum>
<text>The civil citation shall include a fine of:</text>
<subparagraph id=":g25b::13:::13C-1:j:2:i:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(i)</enum>
<text>Not more than $500 for a first offense; or</text>
</subparagraph><subparagraph id=":g25b::13:::13C-1:j:2:ii:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(ii)</enum>
<text>Not more than $1,000 for a second or subsequent offense.</text>
</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id=":g25b::13:::13D:" db-date="20060801"><enum>13D.</enum>
<text>The county commissioners of a code county, by public local law, may fix, impose, and provide for the collection of development impact fees for financing, in whole or in part, the capital costs of additional or expanded public works, improvements and facilities required to accommodate new construction or development.</text>
</section><section id=":g25b::13:::13E:" db-date="20060801"><enum>13E.</enum>
<subsection id=":g25b::13:::13E:a:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(a)</enum>
<text>In this section, &ldquo;Department&rdquo; means a Department of Public Facilities and Services.</text>
</subsection><subsection id=":g25b::13:::13E:b:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(b)</enum>
<text>The county commissioners of a code county, by public local law, may:</text>
<paragraph id=":g25b::13:::13E:b:1:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(1)</enum>
<text>Establish a Department of Public Facilities and Services; and</text>
</paragraph><paragraph id=":g25b::13:::13E:b:2:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(2)</enum>
<text>Provide for the organization and functions of the Department.</text>
</paragraph></subsection><subsection id=":g25b::13:::13E:c:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(c)</enum>
<text>The county commissioners may assign to the Department:</text>
<paragraph id=":g25b::13:::13E:c:1:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(1)</enum>
<text>Responsibility for construction, maintenance, repair, service, and management of:</text>
<subparagraph id=":g25b::13:::13E:c:1:i:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(i)</enum>
<text>Public works, public buildings, publicly owned water and sewerage facilities and projects, and capital projects;</text>
</subparagraph><subparagraph id=":g25b::13:::13E:c:1:ii:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(ii)</enum>
<text>Water supply facilities and projects;</text>
</subparagraph><subparagraph id=":g25b::13:::13E:c:1:iii:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(iii)</enum>
<text>Wastewater collection, treatment, and disposal facilities and projects;</text>
</subparagraph><subparagraph id=":g25b::13:::13E:c:1:iv:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(iv)</enum>
<text>Solid waste collection, recycling, and disposal facilities and projects;</text>
</subparagraph><subparagraph id=":g25b::13:::13E:c:1:v:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(v)</enum>
<text>Storm drainage, erosion, and sediment control facilities and projects;</text>
</subparagraph><subparagraph id=":g25b::13:::13E:c:1:vi:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(vi)</enum>
<text>Lighting for roads, highways, alleys, and other public places; or</text>
</subparagraph><subparagraph id=":g25b::13:::13E:c:1:vii:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(vii)</enum>
<text>Mosquito control facilities and programs; and</text>
</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id=":g25b::13:::13E:c:2:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(2)</enum>
<text>Any other function or duty that is not inconsistent with this section.</text>
</paragraph></subsection><subsection id=":g25b::13:::13E:d:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(d)</enum>
<paragraph id=":g25b::13:::13E:d:1:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(1)</enum>
<text>If the county commissioners assign to a Department the responsibility for water and sewerage functions, in accordance with paragraph (3) and subject to paragraph (4) of this subsection, the county commissioners shall abolish by public local law:</text>
<subparagraph id=":g25b::13:::13E:d:1:i:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(i)</enum>
<text>Any water or sewer authority established for the county under Title 9, Subtitle 9 of the Environment Article; and</text>
</subparagraph><subparagraph id=":g25b::13:::13E:d:1:ii:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(ii)</enum>
<text>Any sanitary district or commission established for the county under Title 9, Subtitle 6 of the Environment Article.</text>
</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id=":g25b::13:::13E:d:2:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(2)</enum>
<text>Before abolishing a water or sewer authority or sanitary district or commission, the county commissioners may request that the entity provide to the county appropriate information to assist the county commissioners in complying with paragraph (3) of this subsection.</text>
</paragraph><paragraph id=":g25b::13:::13E:d:3:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(3)</enum>
<text>The public local law shall provide:</text>
<subparagraph id=":g25b::13:::13E:d:3:i:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(i)</enum>
<text>For the retiring, refunding, refinancing, transfer, or assumption of any applicable outstanding bonds of the abolished entity;</text>
</subparagraph><subparagraph id=":g25b::13:::13E:d:3:ii:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(ii)</enum>
<text>For the assumption of all existing assets and liabilities of the abolished entity by the county, subject to an audit of the assets and liabilities by a certified public accountant;</text>
</subparagraph><subparagraph id=":g25b::13:::13E:d:3:iii:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(iii)</enum>
<text>For the transfer of all real and personal property of the abolished entity to the county;</text>
</subparagraph><subparagraph id=":g25b::13:::13E:d:3:iv:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(iv)</enum>
<text>For the transfer of responsibility and administration of any legally enforceable agreement between the abolished entity and another party to the county;</text>
</subparagraph><subparagraph id=":g25b::13:::13E:d:3:v:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(v)</enum>
<text>For the continued effect of orders, rules, and regulations of the abolished entity, until revoked or modified by the county commissioners;</text>
</subparagraph><subparagraph id=":g25b::13:::13E:d:3:vi:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(vi)</enum>
<text>That any revenues of an abolished entity remain dedicated for the purpose collected and are not transferred into the county&rsquo;s general fund; and</text>
</subparagraph><subparagraph id=":g25b::13:::13E:d:3:vii:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(vii)</enum>
<text>That all matters pending before the abolished entity may continue and shall be completed by the Department.</text>
</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id=":g25b::13:::13E:d:4:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(4)</enum>
<text>Any employee of a water or sewer authority or of a sanitary commission employed on the date that the authority or commission is abolished who transfers to the Department or to a municipal corporation or local community under &sect; 13E-1 of this article shall transfer without any loss of salary, retirement benefits, insurance benefits, leave time, seniority level, or other employee benefits.</text>
</paragraph></subsection><subsection id=":g25b::13:::13E:e:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(e)</enum>
<paragraph id=":g25b::13:::13E:e:1:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(1)</enum>
<text>If the county commissioners abolish a water or sewer authority or sanitary district or commission, the county commissioners then shall exercise the powers of a water or sewer authority or sanitary district or commission.</text>
</paragraph><paragraph id=":g25b::13:::13E:e:2:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(2)</enum>
<text>The county commissioners may:</text>
<subparagraph id=":g25b::13:::13E:e:2:i:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(i)</enum>
<text>Adopt regulations for water and sewerage management;</text>
</subparagraph><subparagraph id=":g25b::13:::13E:e:2:ii:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(ii)</enum>
<text>Acquire, construct, operate, or maintain water and sewerage systems as the county commissioners consider to be in the public interest and necessary to protect the general health and welfare; and</text>
</subparagraph><subparagraph id=":g25b::13:::13E:e:2:iii:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(iii)</enum>
<text>Set rates, fees, and assessments for water and sewerage services and benefits.</text>
</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id=":g25b::13:::13E:f:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(f)</enum>
<text>The powers granted code counties under this section may be exercised notwithstanding any other law in effect when the county commissioners exercise the power granted under this section.</text>
</subsection></section><section id=":g25b::13:::13E-1:" db-date="20060801"><enum>13E&ndash;1.</enum>
<subsection id=":g25b::13:::13E-1:a:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(a)</enum>
<paragraph id=":g25b::13:::13E-1:a:1:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(1)</enum>
<text>In this section, &ldquo;local community&rdquo; means an incorporated or unincorporated community, other than a municipal corporation, with a governing body or governing board that is elected by the property owners or residents of the community.</text>
</paragraph><paragraph id=":g25b::13:::13E-1:a:2:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(2)</enum>
<text>&ldquo;Local community&rdquo; may include a community association or similar association or a special taxing district if the association or district has a governing body or governing board elected by the property owners or residents of the community.</text>
</paragraph></subsection><subsection id=":g25b::13:::13E-1:b:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(b)</enum>
<text>This section only applies if a code county establishes a Department of Public Facilities and Services and assumes the responsibilities of a sanitary district or commission or a water or sewer authority under &sect; 13E of this article.</text>
</subsection><subsection id=":g25b::13:::13E-1:c:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(c)</enum>
<text>Subject to subsections (d) and (e) of this section, the county commissioners of a code county may enter into an agreement with the governing body of a municipal corporation or of a local community that transfers responsibility for water or sewerage services to the municipal corporation or local community.</text>
</subsection><subsection id=":g25b::13:::13E-1:d:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(d)</enum>
<text>An agreement made under this section shall be in writing and shall require that:</text>
<paragraph id=":g25b::13:::13E-1:d:1:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(1)</enum>
<text>The municipal corporation or local community continues to serve any area, within or outside its boundaries, that is served by the facilities transferred when the transfer occurs;</text>
</paragraph><paragraph id=":g25b::13:::13E-1:d:2:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(2)</enum>
<text>Any increase in fees or taxes for water or sewerage services following the transfer be applied uniformly within and outside the boundaries of the municipal corporation or local community;</text>
</paragraph><paragraph id=":g25b::13:::13E-1:d:3:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(3)</enum>
<text>The municipal corporation or local community, in accordance with the agreement, assumes legal responsibility for the payment of principal and interest on any applicable outstanding bonds issued by the county or by a water or sewer authority or a sanitary district or commission with respect to facilities being transferred to the municipal corporation or local community;</text>
</paragraph><paragraph id=":g25b::13:::13E-1:d:4:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(4)</enum>
<text>The disposal of sewage sludge by the municipal corporation or local community be conducted in accordance with county regulations;</text>
</paragraph><paragraph id=":g25b::13:::13E-1:d:5:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(5)</enum>
<text>The municipal corporation or local community honors, in accordance with the agreement, any obligation that exists when the transfer occurs, for the treatment at a treatment facility of leachate generated at a landfill in the county;</text>
</paragraph><paragraph id=":g25b::13:::13E-1:d:6:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(6)</enum>
<text>The municipal corporation or local community complies with the terms of any grant or requirement involving a federal or State agency concerning facilities or operations transferred to the municipal corporation under the agreement; and</text>
</paragraph><paragraph id=":g25b::13:::13E-1:d:7:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(7)</enum>
<text>Any revenues from an entity abolished under &sect; 13E of this article and transferred under the agreement remain dedicated for the purpose collected and are not transferred into the municipal corporation or local community&rsquo;s general fund.</text>
</paragraph></subsection><subsection id=":g25b::13:::13E-1:e:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(e)</enum>
<text>The agreement made under this section shall specify:</text>
<paragraph id=":g25b::13:::13E-1:e:1:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(1)</enum>
<text>The obligation of the parties to cooperate in the operation of any laboratory, the sharing of equipment, and other related matters in which the county and municipal corporation or local community might mutually benefit;</text>
</paragraph><paragraph id=":g25b::13:::13E-1:e:2:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(2)</enum>
<text>The obligation of the parties to satisfy any vested retirement rights for employees who transfer from the county to the municipal corporation or local community under the agreement;</text>
</paragraph><paragraph id=":g25b::13:::13E-1:e:3:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(3)</enum>
<text>The obligation of the parties to assure the maintenance of salary levels, retirement benefits, insurance benefits, vacation benefits, leave time, seniority levels, and other employee benefits, which are in effect for county employees who transfer to the municipal corporation or local community under the agreement; and</text>
</paragraph><paragraph id=":g25b::13:::13E-1:e:4:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(4)</enum>
<text>Any other matter relating to water or sewerage services on which the county and municipal corporation or local community agree that are consistent with this section.</text>
</paragraph></subsection></section><section id=":g25b::13:::13F:" db-date="20060801"><enum>13F.</enum>
<subsection id=":g25b::13:::13F:a:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(a)</enum>
<paragraph id=":g25b::13:::13F:a:1:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(1)</enum>
<text>The county commissioners of a code county, by public local law, may impose a development excise tax when a subdivision lot is initially sold or transferred, for financing, in whole or in part, the capital costs of additional or expanded public school facilities or improvements.</text>
</paragraph><paragraph id=":g25b::13:::13F:a:2:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(2)</enum>
<subparagraph id=":g25b::13:::13F:a:2:i:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(i)</enum>
<text>Before passing a public local law imposing a development excise tax or altering the amount of the tax, the county commissioners shall hold a public hearing.</text>
</subparagraph><subparagraph id=":g25b::13:::13F:a:2:ii:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(ii)</enum>
<text>Notice of the hearing shall be published in at least one newspaper of general circulation in the county not less than 3 or more than 14 days before the hearing.</text>
</subparagraph><subparagraph id=":g25b::13:::13F:a:2:iii:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(iii)</enum>
<text>The notice shall state the subject of the hearing and the time and place that the hearing will occur.</text>
</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id=":g25b::13:::13F:a:3:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(3)</enum>
<text>The county commissioners shall specify and the notice shall state the amount of the tax and the time during the subdivision process that the tax shall be paid.</text>
</paragraph><paragraph id=":g25b::13:::13F:a:4:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(4)</enum>
<text>Except as provided in paragraph (6) of this subsection, a development excise tax imposed under this section may not exceed $2,000 per lot.</text>
</paragraph><paragraph id=":g25b::13:::13F:a:5:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(5)</enum>
<text>A development excise tax may not be imposed under this section, in a county that imposes a development impact fee.</text>
</paragraph><paragraph id=":g25b::13:::13F:a:6:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(6)</enum>
<text>A development excise tax imposed under this section by a code county in the Eastern Shore class may not exceed $5,000 per lot.</text>
</paragraph></subsection><subsection id=":g25b::13:::13F:b:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(b)</enum>
<paragraph id=":g25b::13:::13F:b:1:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(1)</enum>
<text>The county commissioners shall deposit development excise taxes in an account known as the &ldquo;educational facilities improvement fund&rdquo;.</text>
</paragraph><paragraph id=":g25b::13:::13F:b:2:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(2)</enum>
<text>Money in the educational facilities improvement fund may only be used to pay for capital projects, or for debt incurred for capital projects, for additional or expanded public school facilities or improvements.</text>
</paragraph></subsection></section><section id=":g25b::13:::13G:" db-date="20060801"><enum>13G.</enum>
<subsection id=":g25b::13:::13G:a:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(a)</enum>
<paragraph id=":g25b::13:::13G:a:1:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(1)</enum>
<text>The county commissioners of a code county, by public local law, may impose a development excise tax when a subdivision lot is initially sold or transferred, for financing, in whole or in part, the costs of purchasing development rights on agricultural land.</text>
</paragraph><paragraph id=":g25b::13:::13G:a:2:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(2)</enum>
<subparagraph id=":g25b::13:::13G:a:2:i:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(i)</enum>
<text>Before passing a public local law imposing a development excise tax or altering the amount of the tax, the county commissioners shall hold a public hearing.</text>
</subparagraph><subparagraph id=":g25b::13:::13G:a:2:ii:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(ii)</enum>
<text>Notice of the hearing shall be published in at least one newspaper of general circulation in the county not less than 3 or more than 14 days before the hearing.</text>
</subparagraph><subparagraph id=":g25b::13:::13G:a:2:iii:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(iii)</enum>
<text>The notice shall state the subject of the hearing and the time and place that the hearing will occur.</text>
</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id=":g25b::13:::13G:a:3:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(3)</enum>
<text>The county commissioners shall specify and the notice shall state the amount of the tax and the time during the subdivision process that the tax shall be paid.</text>
</paragraph><paragraph id=":g25b::13:::13G:a:4:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(4)</enum>
<text>A development excise tax imposed under this section may not exceed $750 per lot.</text>
</paragraph><paragraph id=":g25b::13:::13G:a:5:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(5)</enum>
<text>A development excise tax may not be imposed under this section, in a county that imposes a development impact fee.</text>
</paragraph></subsection><subsection id=":g25b::13:::13G:b:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(b)</enum>
<paragraph id=":g25b::13:::13G:b:1:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(1)</enum>
<text>The county commissioners shall deposit development excise taxes in an account known as the &ldquo;agricultural land preservation fund&rdquo;.</text>
</paragraph><paragraph id=":g25b::13:::13G:b:2:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(2)</enum>
<text>Money in the agricultural land preservation fund may only be used to pay for the purchase of development rights on agricultural land.</text>
</paragraph></subsection></section><section db-date="20120611" id=":g25b::13:::13H:"><enum>13H.</enum><subsection db-date="20120611" id=":g25b::13:::13H:a:"><enum>(a)</enum><paragraph db-date="20120611" id=":g25b::13:::13H:a:1:"><enum>(1)</enum><text>In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</text></paragraph><paragraph db-date="20120611" id=":g25b::13:::13H:a:2:"><enum>(2)</enum><text>&ldquo;Food&rdquo;, &ldquo;premises&rdquo;, and &ldquo;substantial grocery or market business&rdquo; have the meanings stated in &sect; 11&ndash;206 of the Tax &ndash; General Article.</text></paragraph><paragraph db-date="20120611" id=":g25b::13:::13H:a:3:"><enum>(3)</enum><text>&ldquo;Beverage&rdquo; does not include an alcoholic beverage, as defined in &sect; 5&ndash;101 of the Tax &ndash; General Article, if the alcoholic beverage is sold for consumption off the premises.</text></paragraph><paragraph db-date="20120611" id=":g25b::13:::13H:a:4:"><enum>(4)</enum><text>&ldquo;Convention center facility&rdquo; means a convention center of at least 150,000 net square feet, that is used for the holding of conventions, trade shows, meetings, displays, entertainment shows, or similar events but does not have lodging facilities.</text></paragraph><paragraph db-date="20120611" id=":g25b::13:::13H:a:5:"><enum>(5)</enum><text>&ldquo;Resort area&rdquo; means any portion or portions of a county, as specified by the county commissioners of the county, that:</text><subparagraph db-date="20120611" id=":g25b::13:::13H:a:5:i:" role="item"><enum>(i)</enum><text>By reason of natural, scenic, or man&ndash;made attractions or development, has or have an unusual influx of visitors, sojourners, and temporary residents; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph db-date="20120611" id=":g25b::13:::13H:a:5:ii:" role="item"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>By reason of the influx requires municipal services in unusual number or magnitude.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph db-date="20120611" id=":g25b::13:::13H:a:6:"><enum>(6)</enum><text>&ldquo;Taxable price&rdquo; has the meaning stated in &sect; 11&ndash;101 of the Tax &ndash; General Article.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection db-date="20120611" id=":g25b::13:::13H:b:"><enum>(b)</enum><paragraph db-date="20120611" id=":g25b::13:::13H:b:1:"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Except as otherwise provided in this section, the county commissioners of a code county, by public local law, may impose a tax on the sale of food and beverages in a resort area in the county for the sole purpose of providing revenues to pay the principal and interest on bonds issued relating to the construction, reconstruction, repair, renovation, or equipping of a convention center facility in the resort area. The total outstanding principal amount of the bonds issued by the local governing body for this purpose may not exceed $20,000,000.</text></paragraph><paragraph db-date="20120611" id=":g25b::13:::13H:b:2:"><enum>(2)</enum><subparagraph db-date="20120611" id=":g25b::13:::13H:b:2:i:"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Before passing a public local law imposing a tax under this section or altering the amount of the tax, the county commissioners shall hold a public hearing.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph db-date="20120611" id=":g25b::13:::13H:b:2:ii:"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Notice of the hearing shall be published in at least one newspaper of general circulation in the county not less than 3 or more than 14 days before the hearing.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph db-date="20120611" id=":g25b::13:::13H:b:2:iii:"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>The notice shall state the subject of the hearing and the time and place that the hearing will occur.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection db-date="20120611" id=":g25b::13:::13H:c:"><enum>(c)</enum><text>A tax imposed under this section does not apply to:</text><paragraph db-date="20120611" id=":g25b::13:::13H:c:1:" role="item"><enum>(1)</enum><text>A sale of food that is exempt from the State sales and use tax under &sect; 11&ndash;206 of the Tax &ndash; General Article;</text></paragraph><paragraph db-date="20120611" id=":g25b::13:::13H:c:2:" role="item"><enum>(2)</enum><text>A sale of food or beverages for consumption off the premises if sold by a vendor that operates a substantial grocery or market business at the same location where the food is sold, even if the sale is subject to the State sales and use tax under Title 11 of the Tax &ndash; General Article; or</text></paragraph><paragraph db-date="20120611" id=":g25b::13:::13H:c:3:" role="item"><enum>(3)</enum><text>A sale of food or beverages in vending machines.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection db-date="20120611" id=":g25b::13:::13H:d:"><enum>(d)</enum><text>A tax imposed under this section may not exceed 1&percnt; of the taxable price of a sale of food and beverages that are subject to the tax.</text></subsection><subsection db-date="20120611" id=":g25b::13:::13H:e:"><enum>(e)</enum><text>A tax imposed under this section shall be:</text><paragraph db-date="20120611" id=":g25b::13:::13H:e:1:" role="item"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Collected from the buyer on behalf of the county by the vendor who makes a sale that is subject to the tax; and</text></paragraph><paragraph db-date="20120611" id=":g25b::13:::13H:e:2:" role="item"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Held in trust by the vendor for the county.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection db-date="20120611" id=":g25b::13:::13H:f:"><enum>(f)</enum><paragraph db-date="20120611" id=":g25b::13:::13H:f:1:"><enum>(1)</enum><text>A vendor required to collect a tax imposed under this section shall file a return with the county on or before the 21st day of each month.</text></paragraph><paragraph db-date="20120611" id=":g25b::13:::13H:f:2:"><enum>(2)</enum><text>A return required under this section:</text><subparagraph db-date="20120611" id=":g25b::13:::13H:f:2:i:" role="item"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Shall be made on the form that the county requires; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph db-date="20120611" id=":g25b::13:::13H:f:2:ii:" role="item"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Shall contain the information that the county requires, including:</text><sub-subparagraph db-date="20120611" id=":g25b::13:::13H:f:2:ii:1:" role="item"><enum>1.</enum><text>The gross proceeds of the vendor during the preceding month from sales that are subject to the tax;</text></sub-subparagraph><sub-subparagraph db-date="20120611" id=":g25b::13:::13H:f:2:ii:2:" role="item"><enum>2.</enum><text>The taxable price of sales for that month on which the tax is computed; and</text></sub-subparagraph><sub-subparagraph db-date="20120611" id=":g25b::13:::13H:f:2:ii:3:" role="item"><enum>3.</enum><text>The tax due.</text></sub-subparagraph></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection db-date="20120611" id=":g25b::13:::13H:g:"><enum>(g)</enum><paragraph db-date="20120611" id=":g25b::13:::13H:g:1:"><enum>(1)</enum><text>A vendor who makes a sale that is subject to a tax imposed under this section shall pay the tax that the vendor collects for that sale with the return that covers the period in which the vendor makes that sale.</text></paragraph><paragraph db-date="20120611" id=":g25b::13:::13H:g:2:"><enum>(2)</enum><text>For the expense of collection and remittance of a tax imposed under this section, a vendor who timely files a return and remits the tax may deduct an amount equal to 1.5&percnt; of the gross tax collected by the vendor.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection db-date="20120611" id=":g25b::13:::13H:h:"><enum>(h)</enum><text>The county commissioners may provide by law for:</text><paragraph db-date="20120611" id=":g25b::13:::13H:h:1:" role="item"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The imposition of interest and penalties for failure to pay the tax as required; and</text></paragraph><paragraph db-date="20120611" id=":g25b::13:::13H:h:2:" role="item"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Collection of unpaid tax, interest, or penalties.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection db-date="20120611" id=":g25b::13:::13H:i:"><enum>(i)</enum><paragraph db-date="20120611" id=":g25b::13:::13H:i:1:"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The State Comptroller shall provide a county that imposes a tax under this section with information to help the county verify liability for the tax.</text></paragraph><paragraph db-date="20120611" id=":g25b::13:::13H:i:2:"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The Comptroller may charge a county a reasonable fee for the cost of providing information.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection db-date="20120611" id=":g25b::13:::13H:j:"><enum>(j)</enum><text>From the total revenue derived from a tax imposed under this section, the county commissioners shall:</text><paragraph db-date="20120611" id=":g25b::13:::13H:j:1:" role="item"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Deduct a reasonable percentage not to exceed 5&percnt; for the cost of imposing and collecting the tax; and</text></paragraph><paragraph db-date="20120611" id=":g25b::13:::13H:j:2:" role="item"><enum>(2)</enum><text>After the deduction in item (1) of this subsection, distribute the revenue to the appropriate authority to be deposited in a sinking fund and used for the sole purpose of paying the principal and interest on bonds issued relating to a convention center facility in accordance with the provisions of subsection (b)(1) of this section.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection db-date="20120611" id=":g25b::13:::13H:k:"><enum>(k)</enum><paragraph db-date="20120611" id=":g25b::13:::13H:k:1:"><enum>(1)</enum><text>If any tax is imposed by a county governing body in accordance with the provisions of this section, the authority to impose the tax in that county shall terminate at the end of the month in which sufficient revenues have been generated to pay in full the maturing principal of and interest on any bonds issued relating to a convention center in accordance with the provisions of subsection (b)(1) of this section.</text></paragraph><paragraph db-date="20120611" id=":g25b::13:::13H:k:2:"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The county commissioners shall notify the Comptroller of the State as to the month in which the authority to impose the tax expires.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id=":g25b::14:::14:" db-date="20060801"><enum>14.</enum>
<text>Every code county has power under this subtitle to borrow money for any proper public purpose and to evidence the borrowing by the issue and sale of its general obligation bonds in the manner herein prescribed. Notwithstanding the other provisions of this subtitle, a code county also may issue bonds for sanitary facilities under the Environment Article and to issue such bonds as may be authorized by local law existing on the date this county acquires code home rule status; but in exercising the power to issue bonds described in this sentence, it shall not be necessary to enact a local law as provided in this subtitle; it shall only be required that the code county comply with the procedure set forth in the law conferring the borrowing power to be exercised.</text>
</section><section id=":g25b::14:::15:" db-date="20060801"><enum>15.</enum>
<text>Except as provided in &sect; 14 of this article, all bonds of a code county shall be authorized by public local law enacted by the board of county commissioners of the county in accordance with the provisions of &sect; 8 through &sect; 12 of this article. The public local law shall contain the following:</text>
<subsection id=":g25b::14:::15::" role="item" db-date="20060801"> 
<paragraph id=":g25b::14:::15::1:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(1)</enum>
<text>A statement of the aggregate amount of bonds authorized by the public local law; and</text>
</paragraph><paragraph id=":g25b::14:::15::2:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(2)</enum>
<text>A statement of the public purpose or purposes for which the proceeds of the bonds are to be expended; and</text>
</paragraph><paragraph id=":g25b::14:::15::3:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(3)</enum>
<text>A statement of the taxes or other revenues from which the principal of and interest on the bonds will be payable; and</text>
</paragraph><paragraph id=":g25b::14:::15::4:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(4)</enum>
<text>A requirement that the board of county commissioners of the code county, prior to issuing all or any part of the bonds authorized, shall adopt a resolution that contains the following:</text>
<subparagraph id=":g25b::14:::15::4:i:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(i)</enum>
<text>The amount of the bonds to be issued and a statement of the public purpose or purposes for which the proceeds of the bonds are to be expended; and</text>
</subparagraph><subparagraph id=":g25b::14:::15::4:ii:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(ii)</enum>
<text>The complete form of the bonds, which shall include the place or places and time or times of payment thereof, the rate or rates of interest payable thereon or space for the insertion of the rate or rates of interest upon the determination thereof, the titles of the officials whose signatures shall be affixed to or imprinted on such bonds, the authority for the issuance thereof, and the taxes and any special revenues from which the principal of and interest on said bonds will be payable; and</text>
</subparagraph><subparagraph id=":g25b::14:::15::4:iii:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(iii)</enum>
<text>If the public local law does not exempt the bonds from the provisions of &sect;&sect; 9 to 11, inclusive, of Article 31 of this Code, the form of the notice soliciting bids for the purchase of the bonds shall set forth the information required by &sect; 10 of Article 31 of this Code. This notice of sale may also require prospective purchasers to submit bids on specified forms, may make appropriate provisions for approval of the legality of the bonds, and may contain a financial statement of the code county. All or any of the foregoing provisions which may be included in any such notice of sale also may be separately set forth in a circular or official statement; and</text>
</subparagraph><subparagraph id=":g25b::14:::15::4:iv:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(iv)</enum>
<text>Specific provision for the appropriation and disposal of the proceeds of sale of the bonds and a specific provision for the payment of the principal thereof and the interest thereon, which provision shall specify the source or sources of payment and shall constitute a covenant binding the county to provide the funds from the source or sources as and when principal and interest are due and payable.</text>
</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id=":g25b::14:::15::5:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(5)</enum>
<text>Each resolution shall be adopted by the board of county commissioners of the code county in the manner followed in the usual course of considering resolutions in the government of the county, but it shall not be necessary to submit any resolution or the question of the issuance of bonds authorized thereby to a referendum of the registered voters of the county. Each resolution may contain such other provisions, not inconsistent with this subtitle, as the board of county commissioners of the county may deem appropriate. With respect to any bonds of a code county, the resolution authorizing them may provide:</text>
<subparagraph id=":g25b::14:::15::5:i:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(i)</enum>
<text>That the principal of and interest on the bonds shall be payable at one or more banks or trust companies, which may be either within or without the State; and</text>
</subparagraph><subparagraph id=":g25b::14:::15::5:ii:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(ii)</enum>
<text>That the official signatures and seals to be affixed to the bonds, or the coupons if any attached thereto, except the signature of the clerk or secretary of the code county which shall be manually affixed, shall be imprinted on the bonds or coupons in facsimile; and</text>
</subparagraph><subparagraph id=":g25b::14:::15::5:iii:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(iii)</enum>
<text>That the bonds shall be redeemable in whole or in part at the option of the code county at any time prior to the respective maturities thereof at a price, either at or above the par value of the bonds as the code county may prescribe in the resolution, provided that the bonds contain a statement of the redemption provisions and provided further that the resolution shall make provision for due and proper prior published notice of any redemption; and</text>
</subparagraph><subparagraph id=":g25b::14:::15::5:iv:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(iv)</enum>
<text>That this issue of bonds shall be in varying denominations and shall be in coupon form, registrable as to principal only, or in fully registered form, or both, provided that if both forms are authorized, they shall be interchangeable; and</text>
</subparagraph><subparagraph id=":g25b::14:::15::5:v:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(v)</enum>
<text>That, in the event any official whose signature appears on the bonds ceases to be an official prior to the delivery of the bonds, or, if the official whose signature appears on the bonds shall have become such after the date of issue thereof, the bonds nevertheless shall be valid and binding obligations of the county in accordance with their terms.</text>
</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id=":g25b::14:::16:" db-date="20060801"><enum>16.</enum>
<text>The authority conferred on code counties by this subtitle is subject to the following limitations:</text>
<subsection id=":g25b::14:::16::" role="item" db-date="20060801"> 
<paragraph id=":g25b::14:::16::1:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(1)</enum>
<text>No bonds shall be issued by any code county to mature later than forty years from their respective date of issue; and</text>
</paragraph><paragraph id=":g25b::14:::16::2:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(2)</enum>
<text>No bonds shall be issued by any code county except for cash or be sold at less than par value thereof; and</text>
</paragraph><paragraph id=":g25b::14:::16::3:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(3)</enum>
<text>If a valid petition for referendum is filed with the board of supervisors of elections in regard to a public local law enacted by the board of county commissioners of a code county and authorizing the issuance of bonds, the bonds authorized by the public local law shall be issued only if a majority of the registered voters voting on the public local law approve it; and</text>
</paragraph><paragraph id=":g25b::14:::16::4:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(4)</enum>
<text>All bonds sold by a code county shall be subject to the provisions of &sect;&sect; 9 to 11, inclusive, of Article 31 of this Code, as amended from time to time, unless the public local law authorizing the bonds specifically exempts them from the provisions of these sections.</text>
</paragraph></subsection></section><section id=":g25b::14:::17:" db-date="20060801"><enum>17.</enum>
<text>All bonds issued by any code county in accordance with this subtitle shall have and possess all the attributes of negotiable instruments as provided in &sect; 8 of Article 31 of this Code and in Title 8 of the Commercial Law Article. The principal of and interest on any bonds in the hands of the owner or owners thereof from time to time shall be and remain exempt from taxation of any kind or nature whatsoever by the State of Maryland and by any county, municipal corporation, or other political subdivision thereof.</text>
</section><section id=":g25b::14:::18:" db-date="20060801"><enum>18.</enum>
<text>A sinking fund established by any code county to provide for the payment of the principal of or interest on any bonds issued by the code county pursuant to the provisions of this subtitle shall not be invested by the fiscal officer of the county having custody of the sinking fund except in the manner prescribed by &sect;&sect; 6 and 7 of Article 31 of this Code. Any fiscal officer having custody of the proceeds of sale of the bonds may invest the proceeds, pending the expenditure thereof, in the manner and pursuant to the provisions of &sect; 22 of Article 95 of this Code.</text>
</section><section db-date="20110627" id=":g25b::14:::19:"><enum>19.</enum><subsection db-date="20110627" id=":g25b::14:::19:a:"><enum>(a)</enum><text>Except as provided in &sect; 20 of this subtitle, all bonds issued by any code county pursuant to this subtitle shall constitute pledges of the faith and credit of the issuing county to the prompt payment, from the taxes and other revenues described in the public local law authorizing such bonds, of the principal of and interest on the bonds when due.</text></subsection><subsection db-date="20110627" id=":g25b::14:::19:b:"><enum>(b)</enum><text>If at the time of the issuance of the bonds there is no statutory limit on the power of the code county to levy property taxes, this pledge constitutes a covenant on the part of the county issuing the bonds to levy upon all real and tangible personal property within its boundaries subject to assessment for unlimited county taxation, ad valorem taxes in rate and amount sufficient in each year in which any of the bonds are outstanding to provide for the payment of the principal of and the interest on the bonds.</text></subsection><subsection db-date="20110627" id=":g25b::14:::19:c:"><enum>(c)</enum><text>If at the time of issuance of the bonds there is a statutory limitation upon the power of the code county to levy property taxes, this pledge constitutes a covenant on the part of the county to levy ad valorem taxes as above described within the limitations so prescribed by law.</text></subsection><subsection db-date="20110627" id=":g25b::14:::19:d:"><enum>(d)</enum><text>No statute adopted or enacted after the date of issue of bonds of the types described in subsections (b) and (c) above, which places a maximum limit on the rate at which property taxes may be imposed by the county, or which removes any limit theretofore existing, shall be taken or construed as impairing or in any manner affecting the covenants of the county with respect to its bonds outstanding at the time the statute becomes effective.</text></subsection><subsection db-date="20110627" id=":g25b::14:::19:e:"><enum>(e)</enum><text>No bonds shall be issued by a county pursuant to the provisions of this subtitle, if, by the issuance thereof, existing maximum limits on the power of the county to incur indebtedness fixed by statute shall be exceeded, but no such maximum limitation imposed subsequent to the issue of the bonds shall be taken or construed as impairing or in any manner affecting the obligation thereof, nor shall the obligation of any outstanding bonds of a county be taken or construed as having been impaired or in any manner affected by the issuance of bonds pursuant to an increase in the maximum limitation on the power to incur indebtedness, or the elimination of the maximum limitation, enacted subsequent to the issue of the outstanding bonds.</text></subsection><subsection db-date="20110627" id=":g25b::14:::19:f:"><enum>(f)</enum><text>Any code county, in addition to the pledge of its faith and credit and taxing power for the payment of the principal of and interest on the bonds, may secure the payment by the additional pledge thereto of any other revenues of the county, including payments to the county from the State or federal governments and special benefit assessments, taxes, fees, or service charges which the county is authorized and empowered to impose, levy, or charge; and to the extent that the revenues are sufficient in any year to provide for the payment of the principal of and interest on the bonds to which they are pledged, the county shall not be obligated in that year to levy property taxes also pledged thereto; and the failure of the county to levy such property taxes, so long as the additional revenues are sufficient to satisfy the pledge, shall not be taken or construed as a breach of any of the above&ndash;described payments of the county.</text></subsection></section><section id=":g25b::14:::20:" db-date="20060801"><enum>20.</enum>
<text>Every code county by enactment of local law in the manner prescribed in this article may provide for the issuance by the county of bonds payable as to principal and interest solely from the revenues of one or more revenue-producing projects of the county, which bonds shall not constitute an indebtedness of the county to which its faith and credit or taxing power are pledged; and nothing contained in this subtitle shall be construed as a limitation on the power of a code county to issue revenue bonds under the provisions of any applicable general law or to make provision by local law for the issuance of revenue bonds.</text>
</section><section id=":g25b::14:::21:" db-date="20060801"><enum>21.</enum>
<text>Nothing contained in this subtitle shall be deemed or construed to impair the terms and conditions of any bonds, notes, or other obligations of any code county issued by the county or authorized to be issued by the county prior to the adoption of code home rule status.</text>
</section><section id=":g25b::22:::22:" db-date="20060801"><enum>22.</enum>
<text>Under the provisions of &sect; 8 of Article XI-F of the Constitution of Maryland the General Assembly has exclusive power, by local law, to limit the rate of property taxes which may be imposed by a code county or to regulate the maximum amount of indebtedness which may be incurred by a code county. It is the intent of the General Assembly that this authority should only be exercised when there is the possibility that the code county is imposing an excessive rate of property taxation or is incurring indebtedness in an excessive amount.</text>
</section></article></legisdoc>