<?xml version="1.0"?><!DOCTYPE legisdoc SYSTEM "c:\program files\epic\custom\doctypes\legisdoc\legisdoc.dtd"><legisdoc xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" doc-id="docID" public-private="private"><metadata><doc-state state="none"></doc-state></metadata><article id="dummy"><section id=":g26:::::1:" db-date="20060801"><enum>1.</enum>
<subsection id=":g26:::::1:a:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(a)</enum>
<text>For the purposes of this article the following words have the meanings indicated.</text>
</subsection><subsection id=":g26:::::1:b:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(b)</enum>
<text>&ldquo;Governmental entity&rdquo; means a special taxing district which:</text>
<paragraph id=":g26:::::1:b:1:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(1)</enum>
<text>Is a unit of government responsible for an area situated solely within a single county;</text>
</paragraph><paragraph id=":g26:::::1:b:2:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(2)</enum>
<text>Has a governing body elected independently of the county government;</text>
</paragraph><paragraph id=":g26:::::1:b:3:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(3)</enum>
<text>Is financed with revenues secured in whole or in part from special taxes or assessments levied on real property situated within the area;</text>
</paragraph><paragraph id=":g26:::::1:b:4:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(4)</enum>
<text>Performs municipal services for the residents of the area; and</text>
</paragraph><paragraph id=":g26:::::1:b:5:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(5)</enum>
<text>Was not created for a limited or special purpose or purposes.</text>
</paragraph></subsection><subsection id=":g26:::::1:c:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(c)</enum>
<text>&ldquo;Official of a governmental entity&rdquo; includes a member of the governing body of a governmental entity.</text>
</subsection></section><section id=":g26:::::2:" db-date="20060801"><enum>2.</enum>
<text>Officials of a governmental entity shall have the immunity from liability described under &sect; 5-511 of the Courts and Judicial Proceedings Article.</text>
</section><section id=":g26:::::3:" db-date="20060801"><enum>3.</enum>
<subsection id=":g26:::::3:a:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(a)</enum>
<text>A governmental entity shall provide a defense for an official for any act or omission undertaken without malice and arising within the scope of the official&rsquo;s authority.</text>
</subsection><subsection id=":g26:::::3:b:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(b)</enum>
<text>A governmental entity shall provide only a defense for its officials for negligence or any other tort arising from the operation of a motor vehicle as to any claim for damages in excess of the limits of any applicable policy of motor vehicle liability insurance.</text>
</subsection></section><section id=":g26:::::4:" db-date="20060801"><enum>4.</enum>
<text>A governmental entity may expend revenues for the purposes set forth in this article.</text>
</section><section id=":g26:::::5:" db-date="20060801"><enum>5.</enum>
<subsection id=":g26:::::5:a:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(a)</enum>
<paragraph id=":g26:::::5:a:1:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(1)</enum>
<text>There is a Crofton Police Department.</text>
</paragraph><paragraph id=":g26:::::5:a:2:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(2)</enum>
<text>The Department is:</text>
<subparagraph id=":g26:::::5:a:2:i:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(i)</enum>
<text>Established to provide protection for the Crofton Special Community Benefit District in Anne Arundel County; and</text>
</subparagraph><subparagraph id=":g26:::::5:a:2:ii:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(ii)</enum>
<text>Charged with the responsibility of enforcing the applicable laws, ordinances, and regulations of the State and Anne Arundel County.</text>
</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id=":g26:::::5:a:3:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(3)</enum>
<text>The Department is not an agency of Anne Arundel County, and its officers, employees, and agents are not officers, employees, or agents of the county. Anne Arundel County is not responsible for the acts or omissions of the Department, its officers, employees, or agents.</text>
</paragraph></subsection><subsection id=":g26:::::5:b:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(b)</enum>
<paragraph id=":g26:::::5:b:1:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(1)</enum>
<text>A member of the Crofton Police Department has all the powers granted to a peace officer and a police officer of this State. These powers may be exercised only on property within the Crofton Special Community Benefit District and not on any other property unless:</text>
<subparagraph id=":g26:::::5:b:1:i:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(i)</enum>
<text>Engaged in fresh pursuit of a suspected offender;</text>
</subparagraph><subparagraph id=":g26:::::5:b:1:ii:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(ii)</enum>
<text>Specially requested or permitted to do so in a political subdivision by its chief executive officer or its chief police officer; or</text>
</subparagraph><subparagraph id=":g26:::::5:b:1:iii:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(iii)</enum>
<text>Ordered to do so by the Governor.</text>
</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id=":g26:::::5:b:2:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(2)</enum>
<text>Members of the Crofton Police Department have concurrent jurisdiction in the performance of their duties with the law enforcement agencies of the State and of Anne Arundel County. Nothing contained in this section relieves the State or the county from a duty to provide police, fire, and other public safety service and protection or affects the jurisdiction of other police, fire, and public safety agencies.</text>
</paragraph></subsection><subsection id=":g26:::::5:c:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(c)</enum>
<text>The Maryland Police Training Commission shall adopt or may delegate to the Board of Directors of the Crofton Civic Association, Incorporated the authority to adopt standards, qualifications, and prerequisites of character, training, education, human and public relations, and experience for the Crofton Police Department, including standards for the performance of their duties.</text>
</subsection><subsection id=":g26:::::5:d:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(d)</enum>
<paragraph id=":g26:::::5:d:1:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(1)</enum>
<text>The Board of Directors of the Crofton Civic Association, Incorporated, acting as administrator of the Crofton Special Community Benefit District, shall adopt rules and regulations governing the operation and conduct of the Crofton Police Department, including the police officers.</text>
</paragraph><paragraph id=":g26:::::5:d:2:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(2)</enum>
<text>The rules and regulations of the Board of Directors concerning police officers shall supplement any rules or regulations of the Maryland Police Training Commission.</text>
</paragraph><paragraph id=":g26:::::5:d:3:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(3)</enum>
<text>Disobedience to the lawful commands, rules, or regulations of the Maryland Police Training Commission or the Board of Directors shall be grounds for disciplinary action, including removal.</text>
</paragraph></subsection><subsection id=":g26:::::5:e:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(e)</enum>
<paragraph id=":g26:::::5:e:1:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(1)</enum>
<text>There is a Chief of Police of the Crofton Police Department.</text>
</paragraph><paragraph id=":g26:::::5:e:2:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(2)</enum>
<subparagraph id=":g26:::::5:e:2:i:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(i)</enum>
<text>The Chief of Police shall be appointed by the Town Manager of the Crofton Special Community Benefit District, with the approval of the Board of Directors of the Crofton Civic Association, Incorporated, acting as administrator of the Crofton Special Community Benefit District.</text>
</subparagraph><subparagraph id=":g26:::::5:e:2:ii:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(ii)</enum>
<text>The Chief shall be experienced in the command of uniformed patrols and the detection and investigation of crime, and shall be selected solely on the basis of qualifications for the position.</text>
</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id=":g26:::::5:e:3:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(3)</enum>
<subparagraph id=":g26:::::5:e:3:i:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(i)</enum>
<text>The Chief of Police shall be responsible directly to the Town Manager.</text>
</subparagraph><subparagraph id=":g26:::::5:e:3:ii:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(ii)</enum>
<text>All orders to the Police Department from the Town Manager shall be directed through the Chief or the designee of the Chief.</text>
</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id=":g26:::::5:e:4:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(4)</enum>
<subparagraph id=":g26:::::5:e:4:i:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(i)</enum>
<text>The Chief of Police shall command and administer the Crofton Police Department.</text>
</subparagraph><subparagraph id=":g26:::::5:e:4:ii:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(ii)</enum>
<text>The duties of the Chief shall include:</text>
<sub-subparagraph id=":g26:::::5:e:4:ii:1:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>1.</enum>
<text>Being responsible for the efficiency and good conduct of the Department;</text>
</sub-subparagraph><sub-subparagraph id=":g26:::::5:e:4:ii:2:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>2.</enum>
<text>Overseeing the general operation of the Department;</text>
</sub-subparagraph><sub-subparagraph id=":g26:::::5:e:4:ii:3:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>3.</enum>
<text>Hiring employees and appointing officers; and</text>
</sub-subparagraph><sub-subparagraph id=":g26:::::5:e:4:ii:4:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>4.</enum>
<text>Disciplining employees and officers.</text>
</sub-subparagraph></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id=":g26:::::5:e:5:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(5)</enum>
<text>The Chief of Police shall serve at the pleasure of the Town Manager and, subject to the approval of the Board of Directors of the Crofton Civic Association, Incorporated, acting as administrator of the Crofton Special Community Benefit District, may be removed by the Town Manager.</text>
</paragraph></subsection><subsection id=":g26:::::5:f:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(f)</enum>
<paragraph id=":g26:::::5:f:1:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(1)</enum>
<text>Funding for the Crofton Police Department shall come from revenue derived from special taxes or assessments levied on real property located in the Crofton Special Community Benefit District.</text>
</paragraph><paragraph id=":g26:::::5:f:2:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(2)</enum>
<text>The Crofton Police Department, or the Board of Directors of the Crofton Civic Association, Incorporated, acting as administrator of the Crofton Special Community Benefit District, may apply for, accept, and spend any gift or grant for the benefit or use of the Crofton Police Department from the federal government, any State agency or office, any foundation, or any other person.</text>
</paragraph></subsection></section><section id=":g26:::::6:" db-date="20060801"><enum>6.</enum>
<subsection id=":g26:::::6:a:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(a)</enum>
<paragraph id=":g26:::::6:a:1:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(1)</enum>
<text>There is an Ocean Pines Police Department.</text>
</paragraph><paragraph id=":g26:::::6:a:2:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(2)</enum>
<text>The Department is:</text>
<subparagraph id=":g26:::::6:a:2:i:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(i)</enum>
<text>Established to provide protection for the Ocean Pines community in Worcester County; and</text>
</subparagraph><subparagraph id=":g26:::::6:a:2:ii:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(ii)</enum>
<text>Charged with the responsibility of enforcing the applicable laws, ordinances, and regulations of the State and Worcester County.</text>
</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id=":g26:::::6:a:3:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(3)</enum>
<text>The Department is not an agency of Worcester County, and its officers, employees, and agents are not officers, employees, or agents of the county. Worcester County is not responsible for the acts or omissions of the Department, its officers, employees, or agents.</text>
</paragraph></subsection><subsection id=":g26:::::6:b:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(b)</enum>
<paragraph id=":g26:::::6:b:1:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(1)</enum>
<text>A member of the Ocean Pines Police Department has all the powers granted to a peace officer and a police officer of this State. These powers may be exercised only on property within the Ocean Pines community and not on any other property unless:</text>
<subparagraph id=":g26:::::6:b:1:i:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(i)</enum>
<text>Engaged in fresh pursuit of a suspected offender;</text>
</subparagraph><subparagraph id=":g26:::::6:b:1:ii:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(ii)</enum>
<text>Specially requested or permitted to do so in a political subdivision by its chief executive officer or its chief police officer;</text>
</subparagraph><subparagraph id=":g26:::::6:b:1:iii:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(iii)</enum>
<text>By agreement with another law enforcement agency; or</text>
</subparagraph><subparagraph id=":g26:::::6:b:1:iv:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(iv)</enum>
<text>Ordered to do so by the Governor.</text>
</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id=":g26:::::6:b:2:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(2)</enum>
<subparagraph id=":g26:::::6:b:2:i:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(i)</enum>
<text>Members of the Ocean Pines Police Department have concurrent jurisdiction in the performance of their duties with the law enforcement agencies of the State and of Worcester County.</text>
</subparagraph><subparagraph id=":g26:::::6:b:2:ii:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(ii)</enum>
<text>Nothing contained in this section relieves the State or the county from a duty to provide police, fire, and other public safety service and protection or affects the jurisdiction of other police, fire, and public safety agencies.</text>
</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id=":g26:::::6:c:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(c)</enum>
<text>The Maryland Police Training Commission shall adopt or may delegate to the Board of Directors of the Ocean Pines Association the authority to adopt standards, qualifications, and prerequisites of character, training, education, human and public relations, and experience for the Ocean Pines Police Department, including standards for the performance of their duties.</text>
</subsection><subsection id=":g26:::::6:d:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(d)</enum>
<paragraph id=":g26:::::6:d:1:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(1)</enum>
<text>The Board of Directors of the Ocean Pines Association, Incorporated, shall adopt rules governing the operation and conduct of the Ocean Pines Police Department, including the police officers.</text>
</paragraph><paragraph id=":g26:::::6:d:2:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(2)</enum>
<text>The rules of the Board of Directors concerning police officers shall supplement any regulations of the Maryland Police Training Commission.</text>
</paragraph><paragraph id=":g26:::::6:d:3:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(3)</enum>
<text>Disobedience to the lawful commands, rules, or regulations of the Maryland Police Training Commission or the Board of Directors shall be grounds for disciplinary action, including removal.</text>
</paragraph></subsection><subsection id=":g26:::::6:e:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(e)</enum>
<paragraph id=":g26:::::6:e:1:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(1)</enum>
<text>There is a Chief of Police of the Ocean Pines Police Department.</text>
</paragraph><paragraph id=":g26:::::6:e:2:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(2)</enum>
<subparagraph id=":g26:::::6:e:2:i:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(i)</enum>
<text>The Chief of Police shall be appointed by the General Manager of the Ocean Pines Association.</text>
</subparagraph><subparagraph id=":g26:::::6:e:2:ii:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(ii)</enum>
<text>The Chief shall be experienced in the command of uniformed patrols and the detection and investigation of crime and shall be selected solely on the basis of qualifications for the position.</text>
</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id=":g26:::::6:e:3:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(3)</enum>
<subparagraph id=":g26:::::6:e:3:i:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(i)</enum>
<text>The Chief of Police shall be responsible directly to the General Manager.</text>
</subparagraph><subparagraph id=":g26:::::6:e:3:ii:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(ii)</enum>
<text>All orders to the Police Department from the General Manager shall be directed through the Chief or the designee of the Chief.</text>
</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id=":g26:::::6:e:4:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(4)</enum>
<subparagraph id=":g26:::::6:e:4:i:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(i)</enum>
<text>The Chief of Police shall command and administer the Ocean Pines Police Department.</text>
</subparagraph><subparagraph id=":g26:::::6:e:4:ii:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(ii)</enum>
<text>The duties of the Chief shall include:</text>
<sub-subparagraph id=":g26:::::6:e:4:ii:1:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>1.</enum>
<text>Being responsible for the efficiency and good conduct of the Department;</text>
</sub-subparagraph><sub-subparagraph id=":g26:::::6:e:4:ii:2:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>2.</enum>
<text>Overseeing the general operation of the Department;</text>
</sub-subparagraph><sub-subparagraph id=":g26:::::6:e:4:ii:3:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>3.</enum>
<text>Hiring employees and appointing officers, subject to the approval of the General Manager; and</text>
</sub-subparagraph><sub-subparagraph id=":g26:::::6:e:4:ii:4:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>4.</enum>
<text>Disciplining employees and officers.</text>
</sub-subparagraph></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id=":g26:::::6:e:5:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(5)</enum>
<text>The Chief of Police shall serve at the pleasure of the General Manager and may be removed by the General Manager.</text>
</paragraph></subsection><subsection id=":g26:::::6:f:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(f)</enum>
<paragraph id=":g26:::::6:f:1:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(1)</enum>
<text>Funding for the Ocean Pines Police Department shall come from revenue derived from assessments levied on real property located in the Ocean Pines Community and other sources, if available.</text>
</paragraph><paragraph id=":g26:::::6:f:2:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(2)</enum>
<text>The Ocean Pines Police Department, or the Board of Directors of the Ocean Pines Association, Incorporated, acting as administrator of the Ocean Pines Community, may apply for, accept, and spend any gift or grant for the benefit or use of the Ocean Pines Police Department from the federal government, any State agency or office, any foundation, or any other person.</text>
</paragraph></subsection></section></article></legisdoc>