<?xml version="1.0"?><!DOCTYPE legisdoc SYSTEM "c:\program files\epic\custom\doctypes\legisdoc\legisdoc.dtd"><legisdoc xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" doc-id="docID" public-private="private"><metadata><doc-state state="none"></doc-state></metadata><article id="dummy"><section id=":g41::1:2::1-205:" db-date="20060801"><enum>1&ndash;205.</enum>
<text>All meetings, regular and special, of the boards or commissions in control of any department, bureau or other agency of the Executive Department in the government of Maryland shall be public meetings and open to the public at all times. Nothing contained herein shall be construed to prevent any such board or commission from holding an executive session from which the public is excluded but no ordinance, resolution, rule or regulation shall be finally adopted at such an executive session.</text>
</section><section id=":g41::1:5::1-501:" db-date="20060801"><enum>1&ndash;501.</enum>
<subsection id=":g41::1:5::1-501:a:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(a)</enum>
<text>In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated.</text>
</subsection><subsection id=":g41::1:5::1-501:b:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(b)</enum>
<text>&ldquo;Drug crime&rdquo; means:</text>
<paragraph id=":g41::1:5::1-501:b:1:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(1)</enum>
<text>A violation of Title 5 of the Criminal Law Article;</text>
</paragraph><paragraph id=":g41::1:5::1-501:b:2:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(2)</enum>
<text>A violation of Title 12 of the Criminal Procedure Article; or</text>
</paragraph><paragraph id=":g41::1:5::1-501:b:3:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(3)</enum>
<text>A violation of the law of any other jurisdiction if the prohibited conduct would be a violation of Title 5 of the Criminal Law Article or Title 12 of the Criminal Procedure Article if committed in this State.</text>
</paragraph></subsection><subsection id=":g41::1:5::1-501:c:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(c)</enum>
<paragraph id=":g41::1:5::1-501:c:1:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(1)</enum>
<text>&ldquo;License&rdquo; means a license, permit, certification, registration, or other legal authorization:</text>
<subparagraph id=":g41::1:5::1-501:c:1:i:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(i)</enum>
<text>Issued to or granted to an individual by a licensing authority; and</text>
</subparagraph><subparagraph id=":g41::1:5::1-501:c:1:ii:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(ii)</enum>
<text>Required for engaging in employment or an occupation or profession.</text>
</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id=":g41::1:5::1-501:c:2:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(2)</enum>
<text>&ldquo;License&rdquo; includes a commercial driver&rsquo;s license issued under Title 16, Subtitle 8 of the Transportation Article.</text>
</paragraph><paragraph id=":g41::1:5::1-501:c:3:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(3)</enum>
<text>Except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, &ldquo;license&rdquo; does not include:</text>
<subparagraph id=":g41::1:5::1-501:c:3:i:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(i)</enum>
<text>A license to drive a motor vehicle issued by the Motor Vehicle Administration under Title 16 of the Transportation Article; or</text>
</subparagraph><subparagraph id=":g41::1:5::1-501:c:3:ii:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(ii)</enum>
<text>The registration of an agent, issuer agent, or investment advisor representative under the Maryland Securities Act (Title 11 of the Corporations and Associations Article) and regulations adopted under that Act.</text>
</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id=":g41::1:5::1-501:d:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(d)</enum>
<text>&ldquo;Licensee&rdquo; means a holder of a license issued by a licensing authority.</text>
</subsection><subsection id=":g41::1:5::1-501:e:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(e)</enum>
<paragraph id=":g41::1:5::1-501:e:1:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(1)</enum>
<text>&ldquo;Licensing authority&rdquo; means an agency of the State which issues a license.</text>
</paragraph><paragraph id=":g41::1:5::1-501:e:2:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(2)</enum>
<text>&ldquo;Licensing authority&rdquo; includes the Motor Vehicle Administration for purposes of issuing a commercial driver&rsquo;s license.</text>
</paragraph></subsection></section><section id=":g41::1:5::1-502:" db-date="20060801"><enum>1&ndash;502.</enum>
<subsection id=":g41::1:5::1-502:a:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(a)</enum>
<text>Except as provided in subsection (d) of this section, as a condition to issuance of a license or renewal of a license, a licensing authority may require an individual applying for a license to disclose whether the individual has ever been convicted of a drug crime committed on or after January 1, 1991.</text>
</subsection><subsection id=":g41::1:5::1-502:b:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(b)</enum>
<text>Subject to the provisions of &sect; 1-505 of this subtitle, if an individual applying for a license has been convicted of a drug crime committed on or after January 1, 1991, a licensing authority may:</text>
<paragraph id=":g41::1:5::1-502:b:1:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(1)</enum>
<text>Refuse to issue a license to the individual; or</text>
</paragraph><paragraph id=":g41::1:5::1-502:b:2:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(2)</enum>
<text>Issue a license subject to any terms and conditions that the licensing authority deems appropriate under &sect; 1-504 of this subtitle.</text>
</paragraph></subsection><subsection id=":g41::1:5::1-502:c:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(c)</enum>
<text>Unless a licensee shows good cause for a failure to disclose any information that a licensing authority may require under subsection (a) of this section, a licensing authority may suspend or revoke a licensee&rsquo;s license if a licensee fails to disclose the information that a licensing authority may require under subsection (a) of this section.</text>
</subsection><subsection id=":g41::1:5::1-502:d:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(d)</enum>
<text>This section may not be construed to prohibit a licensing authority which on or before January 1, 1990 required an applicant for an initial license or an applicant for a license renewal to disclose a criminal record or prior offense related to a controlled dangerous substance from:</text>
<paragraph id=":g41::1:5::1-502:d:1:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(1)</enum>
<text>Continuing to require an applicant to disclose a criminal record or prior offense related to a controlled dangerous substance, regardless of the date of the offense; and</text>
</paragraph><paragraph id=":g41::1:5::1-502:d:2:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(2)</enum>
<text>Taking any actions permitted by law, including refusing to issue a license, if the applicant:</text>
<subparagraph id=":g41::1:5::1-502:d:2:i:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(i)</enum>
<text>Discloses a criminal record or prior offense related to a controlled dangerous substance; or</text>
</subparagraph><subparagraph id=":g41::1:5::1-502:d:2:ii:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(ii)</enum>
<text>Wrongfully conceals a criminal record or prior offense related to a controlled dangerous substance.</text>
</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id=":g41::1:5::1-503:" db-date="20060801"><enum>1&ndash;503.</enum>
<text>Subject to the provisions of &sect; 1-505 of this subtitle, if a licensing authority receives notification under &sect; 5-810 of the Criminal Law Article that a licensee has been convicted of a drug crime committed on or after January 1, 1991, the licensing authority may:</text>
<subsection id=":g41::1:5::1-503::" role="item" db-date="20060801"> 
<paragraph id=":g41::1:5::1-503::1:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(1)</enum>
<subparagraph id=":g41::1:5::1-503::1:i:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(i)</enum>
<text>Place the licensee on probation for a reasonable period of time; or</text>
</subparagraph><subparagraph id=":g41::1:5::1-503::1:ii:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(ii)</enum>
<text>Suspend or revoke the license or reprimand the licensee;</text>
</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id=":g41::1:5::1-503::2:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(2)</enum>
<text>Assess the licensee, in accordance with applicable regulations, all or part of the cost of any disciplinary proceeding and sanction; or</text>
</paragraph><paragraph id=":g41::1:5::1-503::3:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(3)</enum>
<text>Impose any other sanction or take any other action authorized by law.</text>
</paragraph></subsection></section><section id=":g41::1:5::1-504:" db-date="20060801"><enum>1&ndash;504.</enum>
<subsection id=":g41::1:5::1-504:a:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(a)</enum>
<text>If a licensee is placed on probation under &sect; 1-502 or &sect; 1-503 of this subtitle, the licensing authority may:</text>
<paragraph id=":g41::1:5::1-504:a:1:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(1)</enum>
<text>Require the licensee to submit to periodic drug testing during the period of probation;</text>
</paragraph><paragraph id=":g41::1:5::1-504:a:2:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(2)</enum>
<text>Require the licensee to participate in appropriate counseling or treatment; and</text>
</paragraph><paragraph id=":g41::1:5::1-504:a:3:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(3)</enum>
<text>Impose any other reasonable term or condition of probation.</text>
</paragraph></subsection><subsection id=":g41::1:5::1-504:b:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(b)</enum>
<text>If a licensee who is on probation violates any condition of probation, the licensing authority may:</text>
<paragraph id=":g41::1:5::1-504:b:1:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(1)</enum>
<text>Revoke the probation;</text>
</paragraph><paragraph id=":g41::1:5::1-504:b:2:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(2)</enum>
<text>Suspend or revoke the licensee&rsquo;s license; or</text>
</paragraph><paragraph id=":g41::1:5::1-504:b:3:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(3)</enum>
<text>Impose additional terms of probation.</text>
</paragraph></subsection></section><section id=":g41::1:5::1-505:" db-date="20060801"><enum>1&ndash;505.</enum>
<subsection id=":g41::1:5::1-505:a:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(a)</enum>
<paragraph id=":g41::1:5::1-505:a:1:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(1)</enum>
<text>Except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, a licensing authority, before taking any action in regard to an initial license application, an application for a license renewal, or against a licensee under this subtitle, shall comply with the provisions of Title 10, Subtitle 2 of the State Government Article.</text>
</paragraph><paragraph id=":g41::1:5::1-505:a:2:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(2)</enum>
<text>The provisions of the Maryland Rules shall govern in the case of a lawyer or an applicant for admission to the bar.</text>
</paragraph></subsection><subsection id=":g41::1:5::1-505:b:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(b)</enum>
<text>In deciding whether to deny an applicant&rsquo;s application for a license or whether to impose license sanctions against a licensee and the nature of the sanctions, a licensing authority shall consider the following factors:</text>
<paragraph id=":g41::1:5::1-505:b:1:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(1)</enum>
<text>The relationship between the drug crime and the license, including:</text>
<subparagraph id=":g41::1:5::1-505:b:1:i:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(i)</enum>
<text>The licensee&rsquo;s ability to perform the tasks authorized by the license; and</text>
</subparagraph><subparagraph id=":g41::1:5::1-505:b:1:ii:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(ii)</enum>
<text>Whether the public will be protected if:</text>
<sub-subparagraph id=":g41::1:5::1-505:b:1:ii:1:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>1.</enum>
<text>In the case of an applicant, the license is issued; or</text>
</sub-subparagraph><sub-subparagraph id=":g41::1:5::1-505:b:1:ii:2:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>2.</enum>
<text>In the case of a licensee, the license is not suspended or revoked;</text>
</sub-subparagraph></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id=":g41::1:5::1-505:b:2:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(2)</enum>
<text>The nature and circumstances of the drug crime;</text>
</paragraph><paragraph id=":g41::1:5::1-505:b:3:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(3)</enum>
<text>If an individual is applying for a license or license renewal, the date of the drug crime; and</text>
</paragraph><paragraph id=":g41::1:5::1-505:b:4:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(4)</enum>
<text>Any other relevant information.</text>
</paragraph></subsection><subsection id=":g41::1:5::1-505:c:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(c)</enum>
<text>If a licensing authority decides that sanctions against a licensee may be appropriate, before imposing sanctions, the licensing authority:</text>
<paragraph id=":g41::1:5::1-505:c:1:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(1)</enum>
<text>Shall consider the impact any sanctions may have on third persons; and</text>
</paragraph><paragraph id=":g41::1:5::1-505:c:2:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(2)</enum>
<text>May take any action to protect the rights of innocent third persons which is in the interests of justice and which is not inconsistent with the provisions of this subtitle.</text>
</paragraph></subsection><subsection id=":g41::1:5::1-505:d:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(d)</enum>
<text>If a licensing authority decides to suspend or revoke a license, the licensing authority may grant the licensee a reasonable time period to complete any existing contracts.</text>
</subsection></section><section id=":g41::1:5::1-506:" db-date="20060801"><enum>1&ndash;506.</enum>
<subsection id=":g41::1:5::1-506:a:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(a)</enum>
<text>Subject to the provisions of this subtitle, if an individual who is convicted of a drug crime committed on or after January 1, 1991 holds a commercial driver&rsquo;s license, the Motor Vehicle Administration may disqualify the individual from driving a commercial motor vehicle or take any other action permitted under this subtitle.</text>
</subsection><subsection id=":g41::1:5::1-506:b:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(b)</enum>
<text>If the Motor Vehicle Administration disqualifies an individual from driving a commercial motor vehicle under this subtitle, the Motor Vehicle Administration shall issue a noncommercial driver&rsquo;s license to the individual if:</text>
<paragraph id=":g41::1:5::1-506:b:1:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(1)</enum>
<text>The individual surrenders the commercial driver&rsquo;s license; and</text>
</paragraph><paragraph id=":g41::1:5::1-506:b:2:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(2)</enum>
<text>The individual&rsquo;s driving privilege is not otherwise refused, suspended, revoked, or cancelled in this State or any other state.</text>
</paragraph></subsection><subsection id=":g41::1:5::1-506:c:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(c)</enum>
<text>This section may not be construed to limit the authority of the Motor Vehicle Administration to disqualify an individual from driving a commercial motor vehicle or taking any other action required or permitted under the Maryland Vehicle Law.</text>
</subsection></section><section id=":g41::1:5::1-507:" db-date="20060801"><enum>1&ndash;507.</enum>
<text>Each licensing authority may adopt regulations to carry out the provisions of this subtitle.</text>
</section><section id=":g41::4:3::4-301:" db-date="20060801"><enum>4&ndash;301.</enum>
<subsection id=":g41::4:3::4-301:a:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(a)</enum>
<paragraph id=":g41::4:3::4-301:a:1:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(1)</enum>
<text>In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</text>
</paragraph><paragraph id=":g41::4:3::4-301:a:2:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(2)</enum>
<text>&ldquo;DNA&rdquo; means deoxyribonucleic acid.</text>
</paragraph><paragraph id=":g41::4:3::4-301:a:3:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(3)</enum>
<text>&ldquo;DNA technology equipment&rdquo; means any equipment used for DNA testing purposes including those purposes listed under &sect; 2-505 of the Public Safety Article.</text>
</paragraph><paragraph id=":g41::4:3::4-301:a:4:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(4)</enum>
<text>&ldquo;Executive Director&rdquo; means the Executive Director of the Governor&rsquo;s Office of Crime Control and Prevention.</text>
</paragraph><paragraph id=":g41::4:3::4-301:a:5:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(5)</enum>
<text>&ldquo;Fund&rdquo; means the DNA Technology Fund established under this section.</text>
</paragraph><paragraph id=":g41::4:3::4-301:a:6:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(6)</enum>
<text>&ldquo;Local law enforcement agency&rdquo; means the agency of any county or municipal corporation, including Baltimore City, within the State that performs police protection functions.</text>
</paragraph></subsection><subsection id=":g41::4:3::4-301:b:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(b)</enum>
<text>A DNA Technology Fund is established to assist the Department of State Police and local law enforcement agencies in acquiring DNA technology equipment needed to test DNA samples.</text>
</subsection><subsection id=":g41::4:3::4-301:c:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(c)</enum>
<paragraph id=":g41::4:3::4-301:c:1:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(1)</enum>
<text>The Executive Director shall administer the Fund in accordance with this section and other applicable law.</text>
</paragraph><paragraph id=":g41::4:3::4-301:c:2:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(2)</enum>
<text>The Fund shall consist of money received from any private entity or federal agency for the purpose of collecting and testing DNA samples.</text>
</paragraph><paragraph id=":g41::4:3::4-301:c:3:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(3)</enum>
<text>Payments out of the Fund shall be made to the Department of State Police and a local law enforcement agency by the State Treasurer as authorized by the Executive Director.</text>
</paragraph><paragraph id=":g41::4:3::4-301:c:4:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(4)</enum>
<subparagraph id=":g41::4:3::4-301:c:4:i:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(i)</enum>
<text>The Fund is a continuing, nonlapsing fund which is not subject to &sect; 7-302 of the State Finance and Procurement Article.</text>
</subparagraph><subparagraph id=":g41::4:3::4-301:c:4:ii:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(ii)</enum>
<text>The Treasurer shall separately hold and the Comptroller shall account for the Fund in conjunction with the Executive Director.</text>
</subparagraph><subparagraph id=":g41::4:3::4-301:c:4:iii:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(iii)</enum>
<text>The Treasurer may invest moneys in the Fund in the same manner as other State money may be invested.</text>
</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id=":g41::4:3::4-301:d:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(d)</enum>
<paragraph id=":g41::4:3::4-301:d:1:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(1)</enum>
<text>The Executive Director shall establish application procedures for the Department of State Police and local law enforcement agencies to apply for aid from the Fund.</text>
</paragraph><paragraph id=":g41::4:3::4-301:d:2:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(2)</enum>
<text>The Department of State Police and a local law enforcement agency applying for aid from the Fund shall provide to the Executive Director any information that the Executive Director deems necessary in making awards for DNA technology equipment.</text>
</paragraph></subsection><subsection id=":g41::4:3::4-301:e:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(e)</enum>
<text>The Executive Director shall provide grants for the purchase or replacement of DNA technology equipment to the Department of State Police and local law enforcement agencies based upon the needs of the Department of State Police and the comparative needs of each local law enforcement agency as determined from the information provided under subsection (d)(2) of this section.</text>
</subsection><subsection id=":g41::4:3::4-301:f:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(f)</enum>
<text>After the Department of State Police or a local law enforcement agency receives notice of a grant award from the Executive Director, the Department of State Police or the local law enforcement agency shall submit proof of expenditures on DNA technology equipment to the Executive Director.</text>
</subsection><subsection id=":g41::4:3::4-301:g:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(g)</enum>
<text>The Executive Director shall report annually by September 1 to the Governor and, in accordance with &sect; 2-1246 of the State Government Article, to the General Assembly as to the distribution of aid provided under this section.</text>
</subsection></section><section id=":g41::4:4::4-401:" db-date="20060801"><enum>4&ndash;401.</enum>
<text>There is hereby created out of the general funds of the State a fund to be known as the State Aid for Police Protection Fund, to be used for the purpose and distributed in the manner hereinafter specified.</text>
</section><section id=":g41::4:4::4-402:" db-date="20060801"><enum>4&ndash;402.</enum>
<subsection id=":g41::4:4::4-402:a:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(a)</enum>
<text>The State Aid for Police Protection Fund is a continuing grant, intended for and to be used exclusively to provide adequate police protection in the subdivisions and qualifying municipalities of this State, by State and subdivision sharing of costs on an equitable basis within certain limits related to population factors.</text>
</subsection><subsection id=":g41::4:4::4-402:b:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(b)</enum>
<text>Provided, however, that nothing herein shall be construed as requiring a subdivision or qualifying municipality to expend more for police protection than the greater of:</text>
<paragraph id=":g41::4:4::4-402:b:1:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(1)</enum>
<text>The actual expenditures for police protection, as defined in &sect; 4-403 of this subtitle, except for capital expenditures; or</text>
</paragraph><paragraph id=":g41::4:4::4-402:b:2:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(2)</enum>
<text>The sum of the amount received in State aid under this program and local funds equal to that percentage of the local wealth used in calculating the State share in basic expenditures under the provisions of &sect; 4-403(b)(1) of this subtitle.</text>
</paragraph></subsection></section><section id=":g41::4:4::4-403:" db-date="20080625"><enum>4&ndash;403.</enum><subsection db-date="20080625" id=":g41::4:4::4-403:a:"><enum>(a)</enum><text>As used in this subtitle:</text><paragraph db-date="20080625" id=":g41::4:4::4-403:a:1:" role="item"><enum>(1)</enum><text>&ldquo;Subdivision&rdquo; means any county of Maryland but does not include Baltimore City; or where the context requires, the governing body thereof.</text></paragraph><paragraph db-date="20080625" id=":g41::4:4::4-403:a:2:" role="item"><enum>(2)</enum><text>&ldquo;Municipality&rdquo; means any incorporated city or town, except Baltimore City, within Maryland; or where the context requires, the governing body thereof.</text></paragraph><paragraph db-date="20080625" id=":g41::4:4::4-403:a:3:" role="item"><enum>(3)</enum><text>&ldquo;Expenditures for police protection&rdquo; shall be those for the fiscal year immediately preceding the fiscal year for which the calculation of State aid is to be made. Thus, State aid for the first year of this grant (1968&ndash;1969) shall be based on &ldquo;expenditures for police protection&rdquo; in the fiscal year ending June 30, 1968; State aid for the second year of this grant (1969&ndash;1970) shall be based on expenditures in the fiscal year ending June 30, 1969, and so forth. &ldquo;Expenditures for police protection&rdquo; means salaries and wages, other operating expenses, capital outlays from current operating funds, and properly identifiable debt service, paid for police protection. Expenditures for sheriffs and constables are included only to the extent that such officers perform police protection functions. Expenditures for traffic control, park police, and a share of the cost of a central alarm system proportionate to its police use, are included. No part of expenditures for collecting from or servicing parking meters, nor of constructing or operating jails, is included.</text></paragraph><paragraph db-date="20080625" id=":g41::4:4::4-403:a:4:" role="item"><enum>(4)</enum><text>&ldquo;Adjusted assessed valuation of real property&rdquo; means 100&percnt; of the assessed valuation of the operating real property of public utilities, plus 40&percnt; of the assessed valuation of all other real property for State purposes, as reported by the State Department of Assessments and Taxation as of July 1 of the second fiscal year preceding the fiscal year for which the calculation of State aid is to be made, plus 20&percnt; of new property assessed between July 1 and December 31 of the second preceding fiscal year. &ldquo;Real property&rdquo; means all property classified as real property under &sect; 8&ndash;101(b) of the Tax &ndash; Property Article.</text></paragraph><paragraph db-date="20080625" id=":g41::4:4::4-403:a:5:" role="item"><enum>(5)</enum><text>&ldquo;Net taxable income&rdquo; shall be the taxable income of individuals under Title 10 of the Tax &ndash; General Article, as certified by the Comptroller of the Treasury for the third completed calendar year preceding the fiscal year for which the calculation of State aid is to be made. Thus, State aid for the first year of this grant shall be based on taxable income in calendar year 1965, and State aid in succeeding years on taxable income in corresponding succeeding calendar years.</text></paragraph><paragraph db-date="20080625" id=":g41::4:4::4-403:a:6:" role="item"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Population figures for total number of people in a subdivision, i.e. figures used in per capita and density determinations, shall be those estimated by the State Department of Health and Mental Hygiene, as of July 1 of each year. Percentage of population residing in municipalities shall be determined from time to time by the most recently published federal decennial census data.</text></paragraph><paragraph db-date="20080625" id=":g41::4:4::4-403:a:7:" role="item"><enum>(7)</enum><text>&ldquo;Executive director&rdquo; means the executive director of the Governor&rsquo;s Office of Crime Control and Prevention.</text></paragraph><paragraph db-date="20080625" id=":g41::4:4::4-403:a:8:" role="item"><enum>(8)</enum><text>&ldquo;Qualifying municipality&rdquo; means a municipality:</text><subparagraph db-date="20080625" id=":g41::4:4::4-403:a:8:i:" role="item"><enum>(i)</enum><sub-subparagraph db-date="20080625" id=":g41::4:4::4-403:a:8:i:1:"><enum>1.</enum><text>Whose &ldquo;expenditures for police protection&rdquo;, as defined above, exceed $5,000; and</text></sub-subparagraph><sub-subparagraph db-date="20080625" id=":g41::4:4::4-403:a:8:i:2:"><enum>2.</enum><text>That employs at least one qualified full&ndash;time police officer, as determined by the executive director; or</text></sub-subparagraph></subparagraph><subparagraph db-date="20080625" id=":g41::4:4::4-403:a:8:ii:" role="item"><enum>(ii)</enum><sub-subparagraph db-date="20080625" id=":g41::4:4::4-403:a:8:ii:1:"><enum>1.</enum><text>Whose &ldquo;expenditures for police protection&rdquo;, as defined above, exceed $80,000; and</text></sub-subparagraph><sub-subparagraph db-date="20080625" id=":g41::4:4::4-403:a:8:ii:2:"><enum>2.</enum><text>That employs at least two qualified part&ndash;time police officers, as determined by the executive director, from a county police department or county sheriff&rsquo;s department.</text></sub-subparagraph></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph db-date="20080625" id=":g41::4:4::4-403:a:9:" role="item"><enum>(9)</enum><text>&ldquo;Wealth base&rdquo; of a subdivision means the sum of the &ldquo;adjusted assessed valuation of real property&rdquo; and &ldquo;net taxable income&rdquo;.</text></paragraph><paragraph db-date="20080625" id=":g41::4:4::4-403:a:10:" role="item"><enum>(10)</enum><text>&ldquo;Aggregate expenditures for police protection&rdquo; for a subdivision means the sum of &ldquo;expenditures for police protection&rdquo;, as defined above, of that subdivision and of every qualifying municipality in that subdivision.</text></paragraph><paragraph db-date="20080625" id=":g41::4:4::4-403:a:11:" role="item"><enum>(11)</enum><text>&ldquo;Equivalent of X dollars per capita&rdquo; means an amount of money equal to the product of X times the number of people in the particular subdivision.</text></paragraph><paragraph db-date="20080625" id=":g41::4:4::4-403:a:12:" role="item"><enum>(12)</enum><text>&ldquo;Sworn officer&rdquo; means:</text><subparagraph db-date="20080625" id=":g41::4:4::4-403:a:12:i:" role="item"><enum>(i)</enum><text>A law enforcement officer certified by the Police Training Commission; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph db-date="20080625" id=":g41::4:4::4-403:a:12:ii:" role="item"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>A full&ndash;time probationary employee of a local government who:</text><sub-subparagraph db-date="20080625" id=":g41::4:4::4-403:a:12:ii:1:" role="item"><enum>1.</enum><text>Is hired to attend a police training academy to become a certified law enforcement officer; and</text></sub-subparagraph><sub-subparagraph db-date="20080625" id=":g41::4:4::4-403:a:12:ii:2:" role="item"><enum>2.</enum><text>Is in training or is functioning as a law enforcement officer pending training.</text></sub-subparagraph></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection db-date="20080625" id=":g41::4:4::4-403:b:"><enum>(b)</enum><text>Subject to subsection (d) of this section, for the fiscal year beginning July 1, 2004, and thereafter, the State shall pay to each subdivision, and to each qualifying municipality, each year in the manner and subject to the limitations and requirements hereinafter provided, an amount determined as follows:</text><paragraph db-date="20080625" id=":g41::4:4::4-403:b:1:" role="item"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Share in Basic Expenditure. If the aggregate expenditures for police protection in a subdivision equal or exceed $6.00 per capita, the State shall pay to the subdivision the amount, if any, by which the equivalent of $6.00 per capita exceeds 0.09&percnt; of the wealth base. If the aggregate expenditures for police protection in a subdivision are less than $6.00 per capita, the State shall pay to the subdivision the amount, if any, by which aggregate expenditures for police protection exceed that proportion of 0.09 percent of the wealth base which aggregate expenditures for police protection bear to the equivalent of $6.00 per capita.</text></paragraph><paragraph db-date="20080625" id=":g41::4:4::4-403:b:2:" role="item"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Share Over the Basic Expenditure. In addition to the amount, if any, payable under paragraph (1) of this subsection, the State shall pay to each subdivision an amount equal to 25&percnt; of the amount, if any, by which aggregate expenditures for police protection exceed the equivalent of $6.00 per capita. Provided however:</text><subparagraph db-date="20080625" id=":g41::4:4::4-403:b:2:i:" role="item"><enum>(i)</enum><text>For subdivisions with a population density less than 100 per square mile, and less than 30&percnt; of total population residing in municipalities, there shall be no payment under this paragraph.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph db-date="20080625" id=":g41::4:4::4-403:b:2:ii:" role="item"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>For subdivisions with population density 100 or more but less than 500 per square mile, and for subdivisions with population density less than 100 per square mile but with 30&percnt; or more of total population residing in municipalities, payment under this paragraph shall not exceed the equivalent of $3.50 per capita.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph db-date="20080625" id=":g41::4:4::4-403:b:2:iii:" role="item"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>For subdivisions with population density 500 or more but less than 900 per square mile, payment under this paragraph shall not exceed the equivalent of $7.50 per capita.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph db-date="20080625" id=":g41::4:4::4-403:b:2:iv:" role="item"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>For subdivisions with population density 900 or more but less than 1,100 per square mile, payment under this paragraph shall not exceed the equivalent of $8.00 per capita.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph db-date="20080625" id=":g41::4:4::4-403:b:2:v:" role="item"><enum>(v)</enum><text>For subdivisions with population density 1,100 or more but less than 1,300 per square mile, payment under this paragraph shall not exceed the equivalent of $9.25 per capita.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph db-date="20080625" id=":g41::4:4::4-403:b:2:vi:" role="item"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>For subdivisions with population density 1,300 or more but less than 8,000 per square mile, payment under this paragraph shall be 25&percnt; of the amount by which aggregate expenditures for police protection exceed the equivalent of $6.00 per capita but do not exceed the equivalent of $36.00 per capita and 50&percnt; of the amount by which aggregate expenditures for police protection exceed the equivalent of $36.00 per capita but do not exceed the equivalent of $45.50 per capita.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph db-date="20080625" id=":g41::4:4::4-403:b:2:vii:" role="item"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>For subdivisions with population density 8,000 or more per square mile, payment under this paragraph shall be 25&percnt; of the amount by which aggregate expenditures for police protection exceed the equivalent of $6.00 per capita but do not exceed the equivalent of $36.00 per capita and 50&percnt; of the amount by which aggregate expenditures for police protection exceed the equivalent of $36.00 per capita but do not exceed the equivalent of $101.50 per capita.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph db-date="20080625" id=":g41::4:4::4-403:b:3:" role="item"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Minimum Grant. The State shall pay to each subdivision the amount, if any, by which the equivalent of $2.50 per capita exceeds the total payments determined under paragraphs (1) and (2) of this subsection. No subdivision for which the population estimate is less than the population estimated for the first year of this grant shall receive in any year a smaller amount of State aid for police protection than it received in any previous year, provided it has not reduced the level of expenditure for police protection which entitled it to the amount of that previous year&rsquo;s grant.</text></paragraph><paragraph db-date="20080625" id=":g41::4:4::4-403:b:4:" role="item"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Incentive Grant. In addition to the payments made under paragraphs (1), (2), and (3) of this subsection, the State shall pay to each subdivision with a population density of less than 500 per square mile, an amount the equivalent of $2.00 per capita.</text></paragraph><paragraph db-date="20080625" id=":g41::4:4::4-403:b:5:" role="item"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Supplemental Grant.</text><subparagraph db-date="20080625" id=":g41::4:4::4-403:b:5:i:"><enum>(i)</enum><text>In addition to the payments made under paragraphs (1), (2), (3), and (4) of this subsection, the State shall pay:</text><sub-subparagraph db-date="20080625" id=":g41::4:4::4-403:b:5:i:1:" role="item"><enum>1.</enum><text>To each subdivision, subject to subparagraph (ii) of this paragraph, an amount the equivalent of $2.50 per capita;</text></sub-subparagraph><sub-subparagraph db-date="20080625" id=":g41::4:4::4-403:b:5:i:2:" role="item"><enum>2.</enum><text>To Baltimore City, an amount the equivalent of fifty cents per capita; and</text></sub-subparagraph><sub-subparagraph db-date="20080625" id=":g41::4:4::4-403:b:5:i:3:" role="item"><enum>3.</enum><text>To each subdivision that borders the District of Columbia, in addition to the amount required under item 1 of this subparagraph, an amount the equivalent of fifty cents per capita living in this State within 1 mile of the border.</text></sub-subparagraph></subparagraph><subparagraph db-date="20080625" id=":g41::4:4::4-403:b:5:ii:"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>The State shall allocate and distribute the supplemental grant to each subdivision among the subdivisions and the qualifying municipalities in those subdivisions on a per capita basis.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph db-date="20080625" id=":g41::4:4::4-403:b:6:" role="item"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Additional Grant. For the fiscal year ending June 30, 1981, and for each fiscal year thereafter, an additional grant equal to 10 percent of the total of the payments determined under paragraphs (1), (2), (3) and (4) of this subsection, or an amount which shall not exceed the equivalent of $1 per capita, whichever is the larger, shall be paid to the subdivisions.</text></paragraph><paragraph db-date="20080625" id=":g41::4:4::4-403:b:7:" role="item"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Minimum Payment in Certain Years. Each subdivision shall be paid that amount, if any, by which the grant paid to the subdivision in the fiscal year ending June 30, 1984 exceeds the total payments determined under paragraphs (1), (2), (3), (4), (5) and (6) of this subsection.</text></paragraph><paragraph db-date="20080625" id=":g41::4:4::4-403:b:8:" role="item"><enum>(8)</enum><text>Municipal Sworn Officer Allocation. For fiscal year 2009 and each fiscal year thereafter, the State shall pay to each qualifying municipality, in addition to the payments made under paragraphs (1) through (7) of this subsection an amount equal to $1,950 for each sworn police officer actually employed on a full&ndash;time basis by the qualifying municipality, as determined by the executive director.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id=":g41::4:4::4-403:c:" db-date="20080625"><enum>(c)</enum><text>The payment received by each subdivision under subsection (b)(1), (2), (3), (4), (6) and (7) of this section shall be paid to each subdivision and qualifying municipality, in the exact proportion which the expenditures for police protection of the subdivision and of each qualifying municipality bear to aggregate expenditures for police protection.</text></subsection><subsection id=":g41::4:4::4-403:d:" db-date="20080625"><enum>(d)</enum><paragraph id=":g41::4:4::4-403:d:1:" db-date="20080625"><enum>(1)</enum><subparagraph id=":g41::4:4::4-403:d:1:i:" db-date="20080625"><enum>(i)</enum><text>In this subsection the following words have the meanings indicated.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id=":g41::4:4::4-403:d:1:ii:" db-date="20080625"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>&ldquo;Crime assessment&rdquo; means an amount obtained for each subdivision or Baltimore City by multiplying the percent of total Part I Crimes in the State that were committed in the subdivision or Baltimore City by 10&percnt; of the costs for the crime laboratory of the State Police as provided in the State budget for the fiscal year of the assessment.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id=":g41::4:4::4-403:d:1:iii:" db-date="20080625"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>&ldquo;Part I Crimes&rdquo; means the crimes reported by the State Police as Part I Crimes in the annual uniform crime report for the second completed calendar year preceding the fiscal year of the crime assessment.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id=":g41::4:4::4-403:d:1:iv:" db-date="20080625"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>&ldquo;Wealth assessment&rdquo; means an amount obtained for each subdivision or Baltimore City by multiplying the percent of the total wealth base of the State that is attributable to the wealth base of the subdivision or Baltimore City by 20&percnt; of the costs for the crime laboratory of the State Police as provided in the State budget for the fiscal year of the assessment.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id=":g41::4:4::4-403:d:2:" db-date="20080625"><enum>(2)</enum><text>For the fiscal year beginning July 1, 2004, and for each fiscal year thereafter, the amount determined under subsection (b) of this section for each subdivision or Baltimore City shall be reduced by the sum of the crime assessment and the wealth assessment for the subdivision or Baltimore City.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id=":g41::4:4::4-404:" db-date="20060801"><enum>4&ndash;404.</enum>
<text>Payments out of the State Aid for Police Protection Fund shall be made to each subdivision and qualifying municipality by the State Treasurer upon warrants of the State Comptroller. Payments shall be made at the end of each quarter of each fiscal year thereafter, and shall be paid in approximately equal amounts for each quarter to the appropriate qualifying municipality or subdivision.</text>
</section><section db-date="20080625" id=":g41::4:4::4-405:"><enum>4&ndash;405.</enum><subsection db-date="20080625" id=":g41::4:4::4-405:a:"><enum>(a)</enum><text>If the executive director finds that a county is not complying with the maintenance of effort provisions of &sect; 4&ndash;402 of this subtitle, the executive director shall notify the subdivision or qualifying municipality of such noncompliance.</text></subsection><subsection db-date="20080625" id=":g41::4:4::4-405:b:"><enum>(b)</enum><text>If a subdivision or qualifying municipality disputes the finding within 30 days of the issuance of such notice, the dispute shall be promptly referred to the Secretary of the Department of Budget and Management, who shall make a final determination.</text></subsection><subsection db-date="20080625" id=":g41::4:4::4-405:c:"><enum>(c)</enum><text>Upon receipt of certification of noncompliance by the executive director or the Secretary of the Department of Budget and Management, as the case may be, the Comptroller shall suspend, until notification of compliance is received, payment of any funds due the subdivision or qualifying municipality for the current fiscal year, as provided in &sect; 4&ndash;403 of this subtitle, to the extent that the State&rsquo;s aid due the subdivision or qualifying municipality in the current fiscal year under that section exceeds the amount which the subdivision or qualifying municipality received in the prior fiscal year.</text></subsection></section><section db-date="20080826" id=":g41::4:4::4-406:"><enum>4&ndash;406.</enum><subsection db-date="20080826" id=":g41::4:4::4-406:a:"><enum>(a)</enum><text>The executive director shall administer the State Aid for Police Protection Fund.</text></subsection><subsection db-date="20080826" id=":g41::4:4::4-406:b:"><enum>(b)</enum><text>The executive director shall:</text><paragraph db-date="20080826" id=":g41::4:4::4-406:b:1:" role="item"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Certify to the Comptroller and to the subdivisions and qualifying municipalities the amount of payments to the subdivisions and qualifying municipalities; and</text></paragraph><paragraph db-date="20080826" id=":g41::4:4::4-406:b:2:" role="item"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Make such regulations and require such reports as are necessary to certify the amounts.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection db-date="20080826" id=":g41::4:4::4-406:c:"><enum>(c)</enum><text>In administering the Fund, the executive director shall:</text><paragraph db-date="20080826" id=":g41::4:4::4-406:c:1:" role="item"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Make a continuing effort to establish standards of police protection adequate to the various local situations; and</text></paragraph><paragraph db-date="20080826" id=":g41::4:4::4-406:c:2:" role="item"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Subject to &sect; 2&ndash;1246 of the State Government Article, report periodically to the General Assembly on progress in establishing and meeting those standards, including the payment amounts certified under subsection (b) of this section and any other relevant fiscal information.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection db-date="20080826" id=":g41::4:4::4-406:d:"><enum>(d)</enum><text>In determining qualification under &sect; 4&ndash;403(a)(8) of this subtitle, the minimum standards determined by the Police Training Commission under authority of Title 3, Subtitle 2 of the Public Safety Article shall be applied.</text></subsection><subsection db-date="20080826" id=":g41::4:4::4-406:e:"><enum>(e)</enum><text>The Police Training Commission shall print and distribute to all municipalities its rules and regulations setting forth the minimum standards of police qualifications.</text></subsection><subsection db-date="20080826" id=":g41::4:4::4-406:f:"><enum>(f)</enum><paragraph db-date="20080826" id=":g41::4:4::4-406:f:1:"><enum>(1)</enum><text>In the event a municipality fails to meet the minimum standards for two successive years, the executive director shall withhold payments to the municipality with respect to the second year.</text></paragraph><paragraph db-date="20080826" id=":g41::4:4::4-406:f:2:"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Any payment withheld for noncompliance is forfeited, and a claim may not be made by the municipality for the funds.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id=":g41::14:3::14-301:" db-date="20060801"><enum>14&ndash;301.</enum>
<text>This subtitle may be known as the Parking Authorities Act.</text>
</section><section id=":g41::14:3::14-302:" db-date="20060801"><enum>14&ndash;302.</enum>
<text>In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated:</text>
<subsection id=":g41::14:3::14-302::" role="item" db-date="20060801"> 
<paragraph id=":g41::14:3::14-302::1:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(1)</enum>
<text>&ldquo;Authority&rdquo; means a parking authority established under &sect; 14-304 of this subtitle.</text>
</paragraph><paragraph id=":g41::14:3::14-302::2:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(2)</enum>
<text>&ldquo;Bond&rdquo; or &ldquo;bonds&rdquo; means any revenue bond issued by an authority pursuant to this subtitle.</text>
</paragraph><paragraph id=":g41::14:3::14-302::3:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(3)</enum>
<text>&ldquo;County&rdquo; means Prince George&rsquo;s County, Montgomery County, or Baltimore City.</text>
</paragraph><paragraph id=":g41::14:3::14-302::4:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(4)</enum>
<text>&ldquo;Local law&rdquo; means a legislative act of the county in which an authority is located.</text>
</paragraph><paragraph id=":g41::14:3::14-302::5:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(5)</enum>
<text>&ldquo;Property&rdquo; means any real or personal property or any interest in real or personal property, and includes any franchise or easement.</text>
</paragraph></subsection></section><section id=":g41::14:3::14-303:" db-date="20060801"><enum>14&ndash;303.</enum>
<subsection id=":g41::14:3::14-303:a:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(a)</enum>
<text>The General Assembly finds and determines that:</text>
<paragraph id=":g41::14:3::14-303:a:1:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(1)</enum>
<text>Conditions of unemployment exist in areas of the State;</text>
</paragraph><paragraph id=":g41::14:3::14-303:a:2:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(2)</enum>
<text>The development of vehicle parking facilities as provided in this subtitle is necessary to relieve this unemployment and establish a balanced economy in the counties; and</text>
</paragraph><paragraph id=":g41::14:3::14-303:a:3:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(3)</enum>
<text>The present and prospective health, happiness, safety, right of gainful employment, and general welfare of the citizens of the counties will be promoted by the establishment of vehicle parking facilities as provided herein.</text>
</paragraph></subsection><subsection id=":g41::14:3::14-303:b:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(b)</enum>
<text>The legislature recognizes that this subtitle is necessary to relieve conditions of unemployment in the counties, to encourage the increase of industry and a balanced economy in the counties, to assist in the retention of existing industries in the counties, to promote economic development of counties, and to promote the health, welfare, and safety of the residents of the counties through the provision of vehicle parking facilities by public parking authorities that are responsive to local needs.</text>
</subsection></section><section id=":g41::14:3::14-304:" db-date="20060801"><enum>14&ndash;304.</enum>
<subsection id=":g41::14:3::14-304:a:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(a)</enum>
<text>Each county may create a body politic and corporate known as the &ldquo;Parking Authority of (insert name of county or Baltimore City)&rdquo;. An authority shall be created when the county:</text>
<paragraph id=":g41::14:3::14-304:a:1:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(1)</enum>
<text>Passes local laws which provide and constitute the terms of the charter for this authority; and</text>
</paragraph><paragraph id=":g41::14:3::14-304:a:2:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(2)</enum>
<text>Files the charter with:</text>
<subparagraph id=":g41::14:3::14-304:a:2:i:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(i)</enum>
<text>The Department of Assessments and Taxation;</text>
</subparagraph><subparagraph id=":g41::14:3::14-304:a:2:ii:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(ii)</enum>
<text>The Department of Legislative Services; and</text>
</subparagraph><subparagraph id=":g41::14:3::14-304:a:2:iii:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(iii)</enum>
<text>The Secretary of State.</text>
</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id=":g41::14:3::14-304:b:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(b)</enum>
<text>Each county shall have the power to:</text>
<paragraph id=":g41::14:3::14-304:b:1:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(1)</enum>
<text>Amend the authority&rsquo;s charter through local legislation if the amendments are filed with the Department of Assessments and Taxation, State Department of Legislative Services, and Secretary of the State;</text>
</paragraph><paragraph id=":g41::14:3::14-304:b:2:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(2)</enum>
<text>Change the structure, organization, program, or activity of the authority unless the change would impair the authority&rsquo;s obligation under a contract the authority entered into before the change; and</text>
</paragraph><paragraph id=":g41::14:3::14-304:b:3:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(3)</enum>
<text>Terminate the authority unless the termination would impair the authority&rsquo;s obligation under a contract the authority entered into before the termination.</text>
</paragraph></subsection><subsection id=":g41::14:3::14-304:c:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(c)</enum>
<text>If a parking authority was created before July 1, 1984, a county may ratify the authority and all acts and contracts of the authority which were in accord with the authority&rsquo;s charter and the law by filing the authority&rsquo;s charter with the departments listed in subsection (a) of this section.</text>
</subsection></section><section id=":g41::14:3::14-305:" db-date="20060801"><enum>14&ndash;305.</enum>
<subsection id=":g41::14:3::14-305:a:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(a)</enum>
<text>An authority shall consist of five members.</text>
</subsection><subsection id=":g41::14:3::14-305:b:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(b)</enum>
<text>The residency requirements, means of appointment, qualifications and terms of office of these members shall be provided by local law.</text>
</subsection><subsection id=":g41::14:3::14-305:c:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(c)</enum>
<text>The officers and employees required by an authority shall be appointed as provided by local law.</text>
</subsection><subsection id=":g41::14:3::14-305:d:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(d)</enum>
<text>An act of the authority may not be challenged on the basis of the absence of qualifications of a member of the authority if the member:</text>
<paragraph id=":g41::14:3::14-305:d:1:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(1)</enum>
<text>Has been appointed by the appropriate authority designated by local law; and</text>
</paragraph><paragraph id=":g41::14:3::14-305:d:2:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(2)</enum>
<text>Has taken the oath of office.</text>
</paragraph></subsection></section><section id=":g41::14:3::14-306:" db-date="20060801"><enum>14&ndash;306.</enum>
<text>An authority has the powers granted to it by local law, not inconsistent with the provisions of this subtitle, to permit it to carry out its purposes under this subtitle, which are to acquire by purchase, lease, or other legal means, but not by eminent domain land and property of any kind in the county in which the authority is located; and to establish, construct, erect, alter, expand, enlarge, improve, equip, repair, maintain, operate, control, and regulate buildings, structures, and other facilities thereon, thereunder, or therein, or on, under, or in any land or property that is now or may hereafter be owned by the county in which the authority is located, or owned by the authority, for parking vehicles, and to establish and collect fees and charges for the use thereof. In addition, an authority may use the common seal, sue and be sued, and do any and all corporate acts necessary to carry out the provisions of this subtitle. The budgetary and financial procedures of an authority shall be set by local law.</text>
</section><section id=":g41::14:3::14-307:" db-date="20060801"><enum>14&ndash;307.</enum>
<text>An authority shall not be deemed a municipal corporation as defined in Article XI-E of the Constitution of Maryland.</text>
</section><section id=":g41::14:3::14-308:" db-date="20060801"><enum>14&ndash;308.</enum>
<subsection id=":g41::14:3::14-308:a:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(a)</enum>
<text>An authority may make rules and regulations for the operation and use of property and facilities under its jurisdiction in the manner provided by local law.</text>
</subsection><subsection id=":g41::14:3::14-308:b:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(b)</enum>
<text>Any violation of the rules and regulations adopted by an authority is a misdemeanor and is punishable by a fine not to exceed $1,000 or imprisonment for not more than 180 days, or both.</text>
</subsection></section><section id=":g41::14:3::14-309:" db-date="20060801"><enum>14&ndash;309.</enum>
<subsection id=":g41::14:3::14-309:a:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(a)</enum>
<text>An authority may from time to time issue its revenue bonds to finance the cost of acquiring property and of establishing, constructing, erecting, altering, expanding, and enlarging, improving, and equipping buildings, structures, and other facilities for the carrying out of its purposes under this subtitle. Every issue of bonds shall be pursuant to determination by the authority that the issuance is necessary to achieve one or more of its purposes, which determination shall be included in the resolution of the authority authorizing the issue of bonds.</text>
</subsection><subsection id=":g41::14:3::14-309:b:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(b)</enum>
<text>Each bond issue shall be authorized by a resolution approved by a vote of at least four of the five members of the authority, which shall provide that the vehicle parking facility or related project is to be acquired pursuant to the provisions of this subtitle and of local law, and shall contain the following:</text>
<paragraph id=":g41::14:3::14-309:b:1:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(1)</enum>
<text>A determination of the probable useful life of the project, or average probable useful life of the projects to be financed. In the case of bonds issued for projects having different probable useful lives, the authority shall consider the amount of the bonds to be issued on account of each project when it determines the average probable useful life of the projects. The determination of probable useful life of the project or average probable useful life of the projects by an authority under this section shall be conclusive.</text>
</paragraph><paragraph id=":g41::14:3::14-309:b:2:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(2)</enum>
<text>An estimate of the cost of the project or projects to be financed and the portion to be defrayed from sources, specifically named, other than the proposed bond issue.</text>
</paragraph><paragraph id=":g41::14:3::14-309:b:3:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(3)</enum>
<text>The procedure for the sale of the proposed issue of bonds.</text>
</paragraph><paragraph id=":g41::14:3::14-309:b:4:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(4)</enum>
<text>A description of each of the projects to be financed by the issue of bonds sufficient for purposes of identification.</text>
</paragraph><paragraph id=":g41::14:3::14-309:b:5:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(5)</enum>
<text>A finding that the amount of the proposed bond issue is sufficient to complete at least a useful portion of each project to be financed thereby.</text>
</paragraph></subsection><subsection id=":g41::14:3::14-309:c:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(c)</enum>
<text>All other matters with respect to the authorization, issuance, sale, delivery, and payment of the bonds, including, without limitation, the issue date or dates, maturity or maturities, interest rate or rates, terms, form or forms, denomination or denominations, manner of execution, place or places of payment, redemption, refunding, sale price, manner of sale, and security of bonds shall be as determined by local law consistent with the provisions of this subtitle.</text>
</subsection><subsection id=":g41::14:3::14-309:d:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(d)</enum>
<text>The bonds are negotiable instruments under Maryland law, notwithstanding any other provisions of the Code or any recitals in the bonds.</text>
</subsection><subsection id=":g41::14:3::14-309:e:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(e)</enum>
<text>The bonds are exempt from the provisions of &sect;&sect; 9, 10, and 11 of Article 31 of the Code.</text>
</subsection><subsection id=":g41::14:3::14-309:f:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(f)</enum>
<text>The bonds may be guaranteed as to payment of principal, interest and any redemption premium by and upon the full faith and credit of the county in which the authority is located as provided by local law.</text>
</subsection><subsection id=":g41::14:3::14-309:g:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(g)</enum>
<text>The bonds, the borrowing which they represent, the project being financed, or the guarantee of the county with respect to payment of the principal, interest and redemption premium thereon are not subject to any referendum requirements of the charter or other local law of the county in which the authority is located.</text>
</subsection></section><section id=":g41::14:3::14-310:" db-date="20060801"><enum>14&ndash;310.</enum>
<text>Any bonds issued under this subtitle, their transfer, the interest payable on them, and any income derived from them is exempt at all times from State, county, and municipal taxation of every kind and nature whatever in this State.</text>
</section><section id=":g41::14:3::14-311:" db-date="20060801"><enum>14&ndash;311.</enum>
<text>The property owned or controlled by the authority shall be exempt from taxation of every kind and nature whatsoever of the State or by any of its political subdivisions, municipal corporations, or public units of any kind.</text>
</section><section id=":g41::14:3::14-312:" db-date="20060801"><enum>14&ndash;312.</enum>
<text>The net earnings of an authority, aside from those necessary to pay debt service or to implement the public purposes of this subtitle, may not inure to the benefit of any person other than the county in which the authority is located. Upon termination of an authority, title to all its property shall vest in, and all obligations and assets of the authority shall be transferred to and assumed by, the county in which the authority is located.</text>
</section><section id=":g41::14:7::14-701:" db-date="20060801"><enum>14&ndash;701.</enum>
<subsection id=":g41::14:7::14-701:a:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(a)</enum>
<text>The Mayor and Council of Ocean City shall administer and operate the Ocean City Convention Hall.</text>
</subsection><subsection id=":g41::14:7::14-701:b:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(b)</enum>
<text>The Mayor and Council of Ocean City may:</text>
<paragraph id=":g41::14:7::14-701:b:1:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(1)</enum>
<text>Employ and set the salaries for a Convention Hall manager and other necessary personnel;</text>
</paragraph><paragraph id=":g41::14:7::14-701:b:2:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(2)</enum>
<text>Accept donations or grants for the maintenance and operation of the Convention Hall and receive any aid from the federal government, the State, or from local governments;</text>
</paragraph><paragraph id=":g41::14:7::14-701:b:3:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(3)</enum>
<text>Set reasonable charges for the use and rental of the facilities of the Convention Hall;</text>
</paragraph><paragraph id=":g41::14:7::14-701:b:4:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(4)</enum>
<text>Grant, upon the basis of competitive bidding, concessions on the premises of the Convention Hall to concessionaires for the sale of food or beverages, including alcoholic beverages subject to the provisions of Article 2B of this Code; and</text>
</paragraph><paragraph id=":g41::14:7::14-701:b:5:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(5)</enum>
<text>Perform any acts necessary and proper for the administration and operation of the Convention Hall.</text>
</paragraph></subsection><subsection id=":g41::14:7::14-701:c:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(c)</enum>
<text>The Mayor and Council of Ocean City shall:</text>
<paragraph id=":g41::14:7::14-701:c:1:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(1)</enum>
<text>Keep records as are consistent with sound business practice;</text>
</paragraph><paragraph id=":g41::14:7::14-701:c:2:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(2)</enum>
<text>Cause an audit to be made of its accounting at the conclusion of each calendar or fiscal year; and</text>
</paragraph><paragraph id=":g41::14:7::14-701:c:3:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(3)</enum>
<text>Submit a detailed annual report of the activities and financial standing of the Convention Hall to the Board of Public Works.</text>
</paragraph></subsection><subsection id=":g41::14:7::14-701:d:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(d)</enum>
<text>The Convention Hall is exempt from taxation by the State and local governments.</text>
</subsection><subsection id=":g41::14:7::14-701:e:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(e)</enum>
<text>As a condition for the administration and management of the Convention Hall, the Mayor and Council of Ocean City shall enter into a contract with the State of Maryland accepting title to the Convention Hall as of July 1, 1985.</text>
</subsection></section><section db-date="20060801" id=":g41::14:7::14-702:"><enum>14&ndash;702.</enum><subsection db-date="20060801" id=":g41::14:7::14-702:a:"><enum>(a)</enum><text>The Board of Public Works shall pay the following sums to the Mayor and Council of Ocean City for the Ocean City Convention Hall:</text><table frame="none" line-rules="no-gen"><tgroup cols="3"><?PubTbl tgroup clmarg="30.00pt"?><colspec coldef="align-on-char" colname="col1" colwidth="2.00in" min-data-value="0"/><colspec align="center" coldef="align-on-char" colname="col2" colwidth="1.52in" min-data-value="0"/><colspec align="right" coldef="align-on-char" colname="col3" colwidth="2.00in" min-data-value="0"/><tbody><row><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0">(1)&emsp;Fiscal year </entry><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0">1981 <?Pub Caret?></entry><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0">$224,000; </entry></row><row><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0">(2)&emsp;Fiscal year </entry><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0">1982 </entry><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0">$199,200; </entry></row><row><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0">(3)&emsp;Fiscal year </entry><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0">1983 </entry><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0">$174,400; </entry></row><row><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0">(4)&emsp;Fiscal year </entry><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0">1984 </entry><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0">$149,600; </entry></row><row><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0">(5)&emsp;Fiscal year </entry><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0">1985 </entry><entry colsep="0" rowsep="0">$124,800.</entry></row></tbody></tgroup></table></subsection><subsection db-date="20060801" id=":g41::14:7::14-702:b:"><enum>(b)</enum><text>The Board of Public Works shall approve expending funds for capital improvements and capital repairs to the Convention Hall to the extent authorized in the operating or capital budget of the State. However, after December 31, 1985 no funds shall be expended by the State for capital improvements or capital repairs to the Ocean City Convention Hall.</text></subsection><subsection db-date="20060801" id=":g41::14:7::14-702:c:"><enum>(c)</enum><text>Any name given to any section of the Convention Hall by official action of the Board of Public Works may be changed subsequently only by action of the Board.</text></subsection></section><section id=":g41::18:2::18-201:" db-date="20060801"><enum>18&ndash;201.</enum>
<subsection id=":g41::18:2::18-201:a:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(a)</enum>
<text>Subject to the initial approval of the Secretary of General Services, the services of the Purchasing Bureau of the Department of General Services may be used to purchase materials, supplies, and equipment by the county commissioners or the appropriate purchasing entity for:</text>
<paragraph id=":g41::18:2::18-201:a:1:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(1)</enum>
<text>A county or Baltimore City;</text>
</paragraph><paragraph id=":g41::18:2::18-201:a:2:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(2)</enum>
<text>A municipal corporation;</text>
</paragraph><paragraph id=":g41::18:2::18-201:a:3:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(3)</enum>
<text>A governmental agency in the State;</text>
</paragraph><paragraph id=":g41::18:2::18-201:a:4:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(4)</enum>
<text>A public or quasi-public agency that:</text>
<subparagraph id=":g41::18:2::18-201:a:4:i:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(i)</enum>
<text>Receives State money; and</text>
</subparagraph><subparagraph id=":g41::18:2::18-201:a:4:ii:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(ii)</enum>
<text>Is exempt from taxation under &sect; 501(c)(3) of the Internal Revenue Code;</text>
</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id=":g41::18:2::18-201:a:5:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(5)</enum>
<text>A private elementary or secondary school that:</text>
<subparagraph id=":g41::18:2::18-201:a:5:i:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(i)</enum>
<text>Either has been issued a certificate of approval from the State Board of Education or is accredited by the Association of Independent Schools; and</text>
</subparagraph><subparagraph id=":g41::18:2::18-201:a:5:ii:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(ii)</enum>
<text>Is exempt from taxation under &sect; 501(c)(3) of the Internal Revenue Code; or</text>
</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id=":g41::18:2::18-201:a:6:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(6)</enum>
<text>A nonpublic institution of higher education under &sect; 17-106 of the Education Article.</text>
</paragraph></subsection><subsection id=":g41::18:2::18-201:b:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(b)</enum>
<text>The right to purchase through the Department of General Services under subsection (a) of this section shall be in addition to, but not in substitution for, the applicable purchasing power granted to any county, municipal corporation, the Mayor and City Council of Baltimore, any other governmental agency in this State, or any public or quasi-public agency pursuant to any statutory or charter provision.</text>
</subsection><subsection id=":g41::18:2::18-201:c:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(c)</enum>
<text>Notwithstanding subsection (a)(5) and (6) of this section, the Department of General Services may not purchase religious materials on behalf of a private elementary or secondary school or a nonpublic institution of higher education.</text>
</subsection></section><section id=":g41::18:2::18-202:" db-date="20060801"><enum>18&ndash;202.</enum>
<subsection id=":g41::18:2::18-202:a:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(a)</enum>
<text>The Secretary of Agriculture shall study the effectiveness of an ethanol and gasoline mixture, known as gasohol, as an alternative fuel for motor vehicles. The Secretary of Agriculture shall initiate a 1-year program of tests using gasohol for fuel in eight presently owned State motor vehicles according to the provisions of this section. The purposes of the gasohol testing program are:</text>
<paragraph id=":g41::18:2::18-202:a:1:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(1)</enum>
<text>To evaluate the cost-effectiveness of gasohol as an alternative fuel for motor vehicles;</text>
</paragraph><paragraph id=":g41::18:2::18-202:a:2:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(2)</enum>
<text>To evaluate the performance of gasohol as an alternative fuel for motor vehicles;</text>
</paragraph><paragraph id=":g41::18:2::18-202:a:3:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(3)</enum>
<text>To compare the performance of gasohol in a new motor vehicle with its performance in a used motor vehicle;</text>
</paragraph><paragraph id=":g41::18:2::18-202:a:4:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(4)</enum>
<text>To determine the negative effects, if any, from using gasohol in a motor vehicle for an extended period of time; and</text>
</paragraph><paragraph id=":g41::18:2::18-202:a:5:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(5)</enum>
<text>To investigate and review the feasibility of establishing a local source of supply for methanol or ethanol utilizing State agricultural produce.</text>
</paragraph></subsection><subsection id=":g41::18:2::18-202:b:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(b)</enum>
<text>The motor vehicles used in the gasohol testing program shall consist of the following:</text>
<paragraph id=":g41::18:2::18-202:b:1:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(1)</enum>
<text>Four motor vehicles currently in use with the Department of General Services which have been in use for 1 year before the tests begin; and</text>
</paragraph><paragraph id=":g41::18:2::18-202:b:2:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(2)</enum>
<text>Four new motor vehicles of the Department of General Services may be used for the test.</text>
</paragraph></subsection><subsection id=":g41::18:2::18-202:c:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(c)</enum>
<text>The costs of the gasohol testing program shall be paid from funds appropriated in the State budget.</text>
</subsection><subsection id=":g41::18:2::18-202:d:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(d)</enum>
<text>The gasohol testing program shall include, but is not limited to, at least one member from each of the following:</text>
<paragraph id=":g41::18:2::18-202:d:1:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(1)</enum>
<text>The Department of Agriculture;</text>
</paragraph><paragraph id=":g41::18:2::18-202:d:2:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(2)</enum>
<text>The Department of General Services;</text>
</paragraph><paragraph id=":g41::18:2::18-202:d:3:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(3)</enum>
<text>The Department of the Environment; and</text>
</paragraph><paragraph id=":g41::18:2::18-202:d:4:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(4)</enum>
<text>The Department of Natural Resources.</text>
</paragraph></subsection><subsection id=":g41::18:2::18-202:e:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(e)</enum>
<text>The gasohol testing program shall conduct the testing program according to the following procedures:</text>
<paragraph id=":g41::18:2::18-202:e:1:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(1)</enum>
<text>Locate gasohol suppliers and contract with a supplier, according to the procurement procedures of this subtitle, to provide a sufficient amount of gasohol for the testing program;</text>
</paragraph><paragraph id=":g41::18:2::18-202:e:2:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(2)</enum>
<text>The test motor vehicles shall be operated by Department of General Services personnel in the Department&rsquo;s routine operations;</text>
</paragraph><paragraph id=":g41::18:2::18-202:e:3:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(3)</enum>
<text>It shall provide for regular evaluation of the test vehicles during the course of the testing program;</text>
</paragraph><paragraph id=":g41::18:2::18-202:e:4:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(4)</enum>
<text>The test vehicles shall be operated throughout the State to provide as many diverse operating conditions as are practicable;</text>
</paragraph><paragraph id=":g41::18:2::18-202:e:5:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(5)</enum>
<text>It shall prepare a final report of the testing program which includes:</text>
<subparagraph id=":g41::18:2::18-202:e:5:i:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(i)</enum>
<text>A critical evaluation of the performance of gasohol;</text>
</subparagraph><subparagraph id=":g41::18:2::18-202:e:5:ii:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(ii)</enum>
<text>A breakdown of the costs incurred in the operation of the test vehicles using gasohol; and</text>
</subparagraph><subparagraph id=":g41::18:2::18-202:e:5:iii:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(iii)</enum>
<text>Recommendations for future use of gasohol in State motor vehicles; and</text>
</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id=":g41::18:2::18-202:e:6:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(6)</enum>
<text>The gasohol testing program shall be submitted no later than January 1, 1980 to the Legislative Policy Committee.</text>
</paragraph></subsection><subsection id=":g41::18:2::18-202:f:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(f)</enum>
<text>The Legislative Policy Committee shall make a report of its recommendations to the Governor and to the General Assembly no later than January 31, 1980.</text>
</subsection></section></article></legisdoc>