<?xml version="1.0"?><!DOCTYPE legisdoc SYSTEM "c:\program files\epic\custom\doctypes\legisdoc\legisdoc.dtd"><legisdoc xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" doc-id="docID" public-private="private"><metadata><doc-state state="none"></doc-state></metadata><article id="dummy"><section id=":g49b::44:::44:" db-date="20060801"><enum>44.</enum>
<subsection id=":g49b::44:::44:a:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(a)</enum>
<text>In this subtitle the following words and phrases have the meanings indicated.</text>
</subsection><subsection id=":g49b::44:::44:b:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(b)</enum>
<text>&ldquo;Alternative dispute resolution&rdquo; includes mediation.</text>
</subsection><subsection id=":g49b::44:::44:c:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(c)</enum>
<text>&ldquo;Board&rdquo; means the Board of County Commissioners of St. Mary&rsquo;s County.</text>
</subsection><subsection id=":g49b::44:::44:d:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(d)</enum>
<text>&ldquo;Commission&rdquo; means the St. Mary&rsquo;s County Human Relations Commission.</text>
</subsection><subsection id=":g49b::44:::44:e:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(e)</enum>
<text>&ldquo;County&rdquo; means St. Mary&rsquo;s County.</text>
</subsection></section><section id=":g49b::44:::45:" db-date="20060801"><enum>45.</enum>
<subsection id=":g49b::44:::45:a:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(a)</enum>
<text>The Board may, by ordinance or resolution, establish a Human Relations Commission for the County.</text>
</subsection><subsection id=":g49b::44:::45:b:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(b)</enum>
<text>The purpose of the Commission is to:</text>
<paragraph id=":g49b::44:::45:b:1:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(1)</enum>
<text>Promote understanding and harmony of relationship between the people of the County through the study of the nature and causes of social friction and prejudice;</text>
</paragraph><paragraph id=":g49b::44:::45:b:2:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(2)</enum>
<text>Advance the means for the alleviation of social friction and prejudice; and</text>
</paragraph><paragraph id=":g49b::44:::45:b:3:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(3)</enum>
<text>Otherwise further the American ideal of equality and justice.</text>
</paragraph></subsection><subsection id=":g49b::44:::45:c:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(c)</enum>
<text>The Commission shall use its influence and persuasion to direct the community&rsquo;s efforts to the solution of all those problems which many times are the basic reasons for racial tensions.</text>
</subsection><subsection id=":g49b::44:::45:d:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(d)</enum>
<text>The Commission shall encourage and ensure equal treatment of all persons, without regard to race, color, religion, ancestry, national origin, sex, age, marital status, or physical or mental handicap, in compliance with federal, State, and local laws and regulations related to housing, employment, and public accommodations.</text>
</subsection></section><section id=":g49b::44:::46:" db-date="20060801"><enum>46.</enum>
<text>To accomplish the obligations imposed under &sect; 45 of this subtitle, the Commission may:</text>
<subsection id=":g49b::44:::46::" role="item" db-date="20060801"> 
<paragraph id=":g49b::44:::46::1:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(1)</enum>
<text>Provide advice and assistance related to the filing and processing of grievances and complaints of discrimination with the appropriate federal and State agencies;</text>
</paragraph><paragraph id=":g49b::44:::46::2:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(2)</enum>
<text>Educate the community to the rights and responsibilities of individuals in housing, employment, and public accommodations;</text>
</paragraph><paragraph id=":g49b::44:::46::3:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(3)</enum>
<text>Advocate the removal of all vestiges of discrimination; and</text>
</paragraph><paragraph id=":g49b::44:::46::4:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(4)</enum>
<text>Assist in nonbinding alternative dispute resolution.</text>
</paragraph></subsection></section><section id=":g49b::44:::47:" db-date="20060801"><enum>47.</enum>
<subsection id=":g49b::44:::47:a:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(a)</enum>
<text>The Board shall:</text>
<paragraph id=":g49b::44:::47:a:1:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(1)</enum>
<text>Determine the size of the Commission.</text>
</paragraph><paragraph id=":g49b::44:::47:a:2:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(2)</enum>
<text>Appoint the members of the Commission.</text>
</paragraph><paragraph id=":g49b::44:::47:a:3:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(3)</enum>
<text>Ensure that the membership of the Commission reflects the diversity of the County&rsquo;s population.</text>
</paragraph></subsection><subsection id=":g49b::44:::47:b:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(b)</enum>
<paragraph id=":g49b::44:::47:b:1:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(1)</enum>
<text>The term of a member of the Commission is 4 years.</text>
</paragraph><paragraph id=":g49b::44:::47:b:2:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(2)</enum>
<text>The terms of the members shall be staggered in a manner to be determined by the Board.</text>
</paragraph><paragraph id=":g49b::44:::47:b:3:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(3)</enum>
<text>A person may not serve more than two consecutive terms.</text>
</paragraph></subsection><subsection id=":g49b::44:::47:c:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(c)</enum>
<paragraph id=":g49b::44:::47:c:1:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(1)</enum>
<text>The Commission shall select a chairperson and a vice chairperson to be the officers of the Commission.</text>
</paragraph><paragraph id=":g49b::44:::47:c:2:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(2)</enum>
<text>The term of an officer of the Commission is 1 year.</text>
</paragraph><paragraph id=":g49b::44:::47:c:3:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(3)</enum>
<text>A person may not serve as an officer of the Commission for more than two consecutive terms.</text>
</paragraph></subsection><subsection id=":g49b::44:::47:d:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(d)</enum>
<text>Each member of the Commission shall serve without compensation.</text>
</subsection></section><section id=":g49b::44:::48:" db-date="20060801"><enum>48.</enum>
<subsection id=":g49b::44:::48:a:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(a)</enum>
<text>This section supersedes any contrary provisions of the St. Mary&rsquo;s County Open Meetings Act and the Maryland Public Information Act.</text>
</subsection><subsection id=":g49b::44:::48:b:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(b)</enum>
<paragraph id=":g49b::44:::48:b:1:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(1)</enum>
<text>Subject to paragraph (2) of this subsection:</text>
<subparagraph id=":g49b::44:::48:b:1:i:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(i)</enum>
<text>All activities of the Commission that relate to an alternative dispute resolution, grievance, or complaint of discrimination shall be conducted in confidence and without publicity; and</text>
</subparagraph><subparagraph id=":g49b::44:::48:b:1:ii:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(ii)</enum>
<text>The Commission may meet in closed or executive sessions when dealing with an alternative dispute resolution, grievance, or complaint of discrimination.</text>
</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id=":g49b::44:::48:b:2:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(2)</enum>
<text>If all parties involved in an alternative dispute resolution, grievance, or complaint of discrimination consent in writing, the Commission&rsquo;s activities related to that alternative dispute resolution, grievance, or complaint of discrimination may be conducted publicly.</text>
</paragraph><paragraph id=":g49b::44:::48:b:3:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(3)</enum>
<text>Except as provided under &sect; 51 of this subtitle, the Commission shall hold confidential all information concerning an alternative dispute resolution, grievance, or complaint of discrimination, including the identities of the parties involved.</text>
</paragraph></subsection><subsection id=":g49b::44:::48:c:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(c)</enum>
<paragraph id=":g49b::44:::48:c:1:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(1)</enum>
<text>Information related to the activities or involvement of the Commission in an alternative dispute resolution, grievance, or complaint of discrimination may not be admitted as evidence in any administrative proceeding or litigation.</text>
</paragraph><paragraph id=":g49b::44:::48:c:2:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(2)</enum>
<text>The records of the Commission may not be discovered in any administrative proceeding or litigation.</text>
</paragraph></subsection><subsection id=":g49b::44:::48:d:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(d)</enum>
<paragraph id=":g49b::44:::48:d:1:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(1)</enum>
<text>Except as provided under &sect; 51 of this subtitle and paragraph (2) of this subsection, information or records related to the activities of the Commission or the involvement of the Commission in an alternative dispute resolution, grievance, or complaint of discrimination are not subject to public inspection under the Maryland Public Information Act.</text>
</paragraph><paragraph id=":g49b::44:::48:d:2:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(2)</enum>
<text>Statistical information may be made available for public inspection under &sect; 10-624(e) of the State Government Article.</text>
</paragraph></subsection><subsection id=":g49b::44:::48:e:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(e)</enum>
<text>The Commission shall hold confidential any information and records obtained by a predecessor County body that was authorized to perform a function similar to that of the Commission before the effective date of this subtitle.</text>
</subsection></section><section id=":g49b::44:::49:" db-date="20060801"><enum>49.</enum>
<subsection id=":g49b::44:::49:a:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(a)</enum>
<text>Subject to subsection (b) of this section, the Commission shall file with the Board a comprehensive report of its activities at least once every 12 months.</text>
</subsection><subsection id=":g49b::44:::49:b:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(b)</enum>
<text>The Commission may not reveal any confidential information in its report to the Board.</text>
</subsection></section><section id=":g49b::44:::50:" db-date="20060801"><enum>50.</enum>
<text>The Board may appropriate funds for the administrative support of the Commission.</text>
</section><section db-date="20110707" id=":g49b::44:::51:"><enum>51.</enum><subsection db-date="20110707" id=":g49b::44:::51:a:"><enum>(a)</enum><text>A person seeking the involvement of the Commission in an alternative dispute resolution related to an incident within the Commission&rsquo;s jurisdiction shall file a written request for alternative dispute resolution within 6 months after the date of the relevant incident.</text></subsection><subsection db-date="20110707" id=":g49b::44:::51:b:"><enum>(b)</enum><paragraph db-date="20110707" id=":g49b::44:::51:b:1:"><enum>(1)</enum><text>A person satisfying the time requirements under subsection (a) of this section shall be deemed to have complied with the requirements of &sect; 20&ndash;1004 of the State Government Article.</text></paragraph><paragraph db-date="20110707" id=":g49b::44:::51:b:2:"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The Commission may provide a copy of a written request filed under subsection (a) of this section to the Maryland Commission on Civil Rights to verify a party&rsquo;s compliance with the requirements of &sect; 20&ndash;1004 of the State Government Article.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></article></legisdoc>