<?xml version="1.0"?><!DOCTYPE legisdoc SYSTEM "c:\program files\epic\custom\doctypes\legisdoc\legisdoc.dtd"><legisdoc xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" doc-id="docID" public-private="private"><metadata><doc-state state="none"></doc-state></metadata><article id="dummy"><section id=":g75::81:::81:" db-date="20060801"><enum>81.</enum>
<text>Every county lying on any navigable river in this State shall extend its jurisdiction from the shore to the channel of the river that divides the counties except where a dividing line has been fixed in such river by law, and, where any ship or other vessel shall be in said river, process may be served on board the said ship or vessel by the officers of either county that can first serve it; but if she is moored or fastened to the land on either side of said river, then she shall be considered as in the county to whose shore she is fastened.</text>
</section><section id=":g75::81:::82:" db-date="20060801"><enum>82.</enum>
<text>The jurisdiction of every county bounded at any point by navigable waters shall extend from the shore to the inside of the channel, which shall be regarded to be the center of said waters, except where said waters adjoin neighboring states, in which case the jurisdiction of said counties shall continue to the ultimate limits of the State at the place in question; provided, however, that nothing in this section or &sect;&sect; 83 and 84 shall be construed as changing such rights as the State of Maryland may have on or under such waters.</text>
</section><section id=":g75::81:::83:" db-date="20060801"><enum>83.</enum>
<text>The center of the waters aforesaid shall be deemed to be as represented on the county maps issued under authority of the Laws of Maryland, 1896, Chapter 51, and the Laws of Maryland, 1898, Chapter 129, and said maps shall be admissible as evidence as to the location of the boundary or boundaries aforesaid.</text>
</section><section id=":g75::81:::84:" db-date="20060801"><enum>84.</enum>
<text>Certified copies of said county maps shall be filed with the clerks of the several courts for all the several counties of Maryland, and also with the board of county commissioners of said counties; said maps to be regarded as official and authoritative.</text>
</section></article></legisdoc>