<?xml version="1.0"?><!DOCTYPE legisdoc SYSTEM "c:\program files\epic\custom\doctypes\legisdoc\legisdoc.dtd"><legisdoc xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" doc-id="docID" public-private="private"><metadata><doc-state state="none"></doc-state></metadata><article id="dummy"><section id=":g95::1:::22:" db-date="20080625"><enum>22.</enum><subsection id=":g95::1:::22:a:" db-date="20080625"><enum>(a)</enum><text>Except as provided in subsection (b) of this section or &sect; 22-O of this article, and subject to &sect; 22F of this article, and notwithstanding any provision of a local law or ordinance, the governing body of each county and municipal corporation, each county board of education, and the governing body of each road, drainage, improvement, construction or soil conservation district or commission in the State, the Upper Potomac River Commission, and any other political subdivision or body politic of the State, or their authorized acknowledged agent, are directed, authorized, and empowered to invest, redeem, sell, exchange and reinvest all unexpended or surplus money in any fund or account of which they have custody or control in obligations or repurchase agreements in accordance with &sect; 6-222 of the State Finance and Procurement Article, or deposit unexpended or surplus money in any federally insured bank in the State of Maryland or in any federally insured savings and loan association in the State of Maryland in interest-bearing time deposit or savings accounts, or in the local government investment pool created in this article. Except as provided in &sect; 22-O of this article, deposits in banks or in savings and loan associations shall only be made if the bank or savings and loan association has given as security for these deposits any of the types of collateral set forth in &sect; 6-202 of the State Finance and Procurement Article. The interest or income from any such investment or deposit shall become a part of the fund from which the investment or deposit was made and may itself be so invested or deposited. If the fund so invested or deposited constitutes the proceeds of the issue of bonds or other obligations, the principal of or interest on which the issuer is obligated to repay to the holders thereof, the interest or income from the investments may be used to pay the principal or interest by the issuer. Investments or deposits made pursuant to this section may be withdrawn or altered from time to time by the investing or depositing officer or governing body either to meet the requirements for which such funds are held or for reinvestment pursuant to this subsection.</text></subsection><subsection db-date="20080625" id=":g95::1:::22:b:"><enum>(b)</enum><paragraph db-date="20080625" id=":g95::1:::22:b:1:"><enum>(1)</enum><text>In this subsection, &ldquo;other postemployment benefits&rdquo; means postemployment health care benefits, regardless of the type of plan that provides them, and all postemployment benefits provided separately from a pension plan.</text></paragraph><paragraph db-date="20080625" id=":g95::1:::22:b:2:"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The trustees or other officers in charge of any pension or retirement system or fund or other postemployment benefits fund of any political subdivision of the State or any agency or department of the political subdivision may invest, redeem, sell, exchange, and reinvest moneys under their custody or control as provided by law by the governing body of the political subdivision and shall comply with fiduciary standards that at least meet the standards set forth in Title 21, Subtitle 2 of the State Personnel and Pensions Article in connection with funds under their custody or control.</text></paragraph><paragraph db-date="20080625" id=":g95::1:::22:b:3:"><enum>(3)</enum><subparagraph db-date="20080625" id=":g95::1:::22:b:3:i:"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, a political subdivision of the State or a unit of a political subdivision of the State may enter into an agreement with a third party contractor or vendor for the management or investment of money intended for other postemployment benefits.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph db-date="20080625" id=":g95::1:::22:b:3:ii:"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>An agreement entered into under this paragraph includes the authority to:</text><sub-subparagraph db-date="20080625" id=":g95::1:::22:b:3:ii:1:" role="item"><enum>1.</enum><text>Create pooled investments under the stewardship of:</text><sub-sub-subparagraph db-date="20080625" id=":g95::1:::22:b:3:ii:1:A:" role="item"><enum>A.</enum><text>A political subdivision of the State or unit of a political subdivision of the State; or</text></sub-sub-subparagraph><sub-sub-subparagraph db-date="20080625" id=":g95::1:::22:b:3:ii:1:B:" role="item"><enum>B.</enum><text>A separate body under an agreement with a political subdivision of the State;</text></sub-sub-subparagraph></sub-subparagraph><sub-subparagraph db-date="20080625" id=":g95::1:::22:b:3:ii:2:" role="item"><enum>2.</enum><text>Create one or more accounts to be managed in coordination with other funds or investments by a third party under an agreement with a political subdivision of the State; and</text></sub-subparagraph><sub-subparagraph db-date="20080625" id=":g95::1:::22:b:3:ii:3:" role="item"><enum>3.</enum><text>Create distinct funding accounts for payment on behalf of employees of a unit of a political subdivision of the State under an agreement with the political subdivision.</text></sub-subparagraph></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section db-date="20120611" id=":g95::1:::22F:"><enum>22F.</enum><subsection db-date="20120611" id=":g95::1:::22F:a:"><enum>(a)</enum><paragraph db-date="20120611" id=":g95::1:::22F:a:1:"><enum>(1)</enum><text>In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</text></paragraph><paragraph db-date="20120611" id=":g95::1:::22F:a:2:"><enum>(2)</enum><text>&ldquo;Chief executive&rdquo; means:</text><subparagraph db-date="20120611" id=":g95::1:::22F:a:2:i:" role="item"><enum>(i)</enum><text>For Baltimore City, the Mayor;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph db-date="20120611" id=":g95::1:::22F:a:2:ii:" role="item"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>For a nonhome rule county, the chairman or president of the board of county commissioners;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph db-date="20120611" id=":g95::1:::22F:a:2:iii:" role="item"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>For a charter county, the elected county executive or, if the county does not have an elected executive, the chairman or president of the county council;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph db-date="20120611" id=":g95::1:::22F:a:2:iv:" role="item"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>For a code home rule county, the chairman or president of the board of county commissioners;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph db-date="20120611" id=":g95::1:::22F:a:2:v:" role="item"><enum>(v)</enum><text>For a community college, a designee of the board of trustees;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph db-date="20120611" id=":g95::1:::22F:a:2:vi:" role="item"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>For a municipal corporation, the mayor or, if the municipal corporation does not have a mayor, the chairman or president of the municipal governing body;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph db-date="20120611" id=":g95::1:::22F:a:2:vii:" role="item"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>For the Washington Suburban Sanitary Commission, the Chairman of the Commission;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph db-date="20120611" id=":g95::1:::22F:a:2:viii:" role="item"><enum>(viii)</enum><text>For a public corporation, the chief executive officer; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph db-date="20120611" id=":g95::1:::22F:a:2:ix:" role="item"><enum>(ix)</enum><text>For an authority, the executive director or executive secretary.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph db-date="20120611" id=":g95::1:::22F:a:3:"><enum>(3)</enum><subparagraph db-date="20120611" id=":g95::1:::22F:a:3:i:"><enum>(i)</enum><text>&ldquo;Community college&rdquo; includes a regional community college established under Title 16, Subtitle 2 of the Education Article.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph db-date="20120611" id=":g95::1:::22F:a:3:ii:"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>&ldquo;Community college&rdquo; does not include the Baltimore City Community College.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph db-date="20120611" id=":g95::1:::22F:a:4:"><enum>(4)</enum><text>&ldquo;Financial officer&rdquo; means the treasurer or other financial officer of a local government unit who is responsible for the investment of public funds or the issuance and management of debt of the local government unit.</text></paragraph><paragraph db-date="20120611" id=":g95::1:::22F:a:5:"><enum>(5)</enum><text>&ldquo;Governing body&rdquo; means:</text><subparagraph db-date="20120611" id=":g95::1:::22F:a:5:i:" role="item"><enum>(i)</enum><text>For Baltimore City, the Baltimore City Board of Estimates;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph db-date="20120611" id=":g95::1:::22F:a:5:ii:" role="item"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>For a nonhome rule county, the county commissioners;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph db-date="20120611" id=":g95::1:::22F:a:5:iii:" role="item"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>For a charter county, as provided by local law, the county council or the county executive and the county council;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph db-date="20120611" id=":g95::1:::22F:a:5:iv:" role="item"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>For a code county, the county commissioners;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph db-date="20120611" id=":g95::1:::22F:a:5:v:" role="item"><enum>(v)</enum><text>For a community college, the board of trustees;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph db-date="20120611" id=":g95::1:::22F:a:5:vi:" role="item"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>For a municipal corporation, the body provided by the municipal charter;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph db-date="20120611" id=":g95::1:::22F:a:5:vii:" role="item"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>For the Washington Suburban Sanitary Commission, the Commission;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph db-date="20120611" id=":g95::1:::22F:a:5:viii:" role="item"><enum>(viii)</enum><text>For a public corporation, the board of directors; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph db-date="20120611" id=":g95::1:::22F:a:5:ix:" role="item"><enum>(ix)</enum><text>For an authority, the board of the authority.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph db-date="20120611" id=":g95::1:::22F:a:6:"><enum>(6)</enum><text>&ldquo;Local government unit&rdquo; means:</text><subparagraph db-date="20120611" id=":g95::1:::22F:a:6:i:" role="item"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Baltimore City;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph db-date="20120611" id=":g95::1:::22F:a:6:ii:" role="item"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>A community college;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph db-date="20120611" id=":g95::1:::22F:a:6:iii:" role="item"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>A county;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph db-date="20120611" id=":g95::1:::22F:a:6:iv:" role="item"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>A municipal corporation;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph db-date="20120611" id=":g95::1:::22F:a:6:v:" role="item"><enum>(v)</enum><text>The Washington Suburban Sanitary Commission;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph db-date="20120611" id=":g95::1:::22F:a:6:vi:" role="item"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>A public corporation authorized to issue debt; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph db-date="20120611" id=":g95::1:::22F:a:6:vii:" role="item"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>An authority of the State authorized to issue debt.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph db-date="20120611" id=":g95::1:::22F:a:7:"><enum>(7)</enum><subparagraph db-date="20120611" id=":g95::1:::22F:a:7:i:"><enum>(i)</enum><text>&ldquo;Public funds&rdquo; means any revenue held by a local government unit as part of:</text><sub-subparagraph db-date="20120611" id=":g95::1:::22F:a:7:i:1:" role="item"><enum>1.</enum><text>A general fund;</text></sub-subparagraph><sub-subparagraph db-date="20120611" id=":g95::1:::22F:a:7:i:2:" role="item"><enum>2.</enum><text>A special fund;</text></sub-subparagraph><sub-subparagraph db-date="20120611" id=":g95::1:::22F:a:7:i:3:" role="item"><enum>3.</enum><text>A capital improvement fund;</text></sub-subparagraph><sub-subparagraph db-date="20120611" id=":g95::1:::22F:a:7:i:4:" role="item"><enum>4.</enum><text>A debt service fund;</text></sub-subparagraph><sub-subparagraph db-date="20120611" id=":g95::1:::22F:a:7:i:5:" role="item"><enum>5.</enum><text>An enterprise fund;</text></sub-subparagraph><sub-subparagraph db-date="20120611" id=":g95::1:::22F:a:7:i:6:" role="item"><enum>6.</enum><text>An internal service fund; or</text></sub-subparagraph><sub-subparagraph db-date="20120611" id=":g95::1:::22F:a:7:i:7:" role="item"><enum>7.</enum><text>Except as otherwise provided in subparagraph (ii) of this paragraph, any other account of the local government unit.</text></sub-subparagraph></subparagraph><subparagraph db-date="20120611" id=":g95::1:::22F:a:7:ii:"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>&ldquo;Public funds&rdquo; does not include revenues held as part of a pension fund, other postemployment benefits fund, trust fund account, or for self&ndash;insurance purposes.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection db-date="20120611" id=":g95::1:::22F:b:"><enum>(b)</enum><text>This section and the local government investment guidelines adopted by the State Treasurer under this section supersede any local law, including any charter provision, or any other public general law to the extent of any conflict.</text></subsection><subsection db-date="20120611" id=":g95::1:::22F:c:"><enum>(c)</enum><paragraph db-date="20120611" id=":g95::1:::22F:c:1:"><enum>(1)</enum><subparagraph db-date="20120611" id=":g95::1:::22F:c:1:i:"><enum>(i)</enum><text>After consulting with local government officials, the State Treasurer shall adopt by regulation local government investment guidelines to govern the investment of public funds by local government units in a manner that will facilitate sound cash management while protecting the public and assuring that a local government unit has access to its public funds as required.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph db-date="20120611" id=":g95::1:::22F:c:1:ii:"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>The State Treasurer&rsquo;s local government investment guidelines shall:</text><sub-subparagraph db-date="20120611" id=":g95::1:::22F:c:1:ii:1:" role="item"><enum>1.</enum><text>State the types of investments in which public funds may be invested;</text></sub-subparagraph><sub-subparagraph db-date="20120611" id=":g95::1:::22F:c:1:ii:2:" role="item"><enum>2.</enum><text>Include guidance for the prudent investment of public funds based on cash flow projections, income, liquidity, investment ratings, and risk;</text></sub-subparagraph><sub-subparagraph db-date="20120611" id=":g95::1:::22F:c:1:ii:3:" role="item"><enum>3.</enum><text>Require that investments by a board of education and a board of library trustees are in compliance with the local investment policy of the respective county; and</text></sub-subparagraph><sub-subparagraph db-date="20120611" id=":g95::1:::22F:c:1:ii:4:" role="item"><enum>4.</enum><text>Prohibit borrowing of funds for the express purpose of investing those funds.</text></sub-subparagraph></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph db-date="20120611" id=":g95::1:::22F:c:2:"><enum>(2)</enum><subparagraph db-date="20120611" id=":g95::1:::22F:c:2:i:"><enum>(i)</enum><text>The governing body of each local government unit shall adopt by resolution a local investment policy that:</text><sub-subparagraph db-date="20120611" id=":g95::1:::22F:c:2:i:1:" role="item"><enum>1.</enum><text>Is consistent with the local government investment guidelines adopted by the State Treasurer; and</text></sub-subparagraph><sub-subparagraph db-date="20120611" id=":g95::1:::22F:c:2:i:2:" role="item"><enum>2.</enum><text>Meets the individual needs of the local government unit.</text></sub-subparagraph></subparagraph><subparagraph db-date="20120611" id=":g95::1:::22F:c:2:ii:"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Promptly after the adoption of a local investment policy, the local government unit shall mail a certified copy to the State Treasurer.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph db-date="20120611" id=":g95::1:::22F:c:2:iii:"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>If the State Treasurer determines that the local investment policy is not consistent with the local government investment guidelines adopted by the State Treasurer, the State Treasurer shall notify the local government unit and the governing body of the local government unit shall prepare and submit a revised local investment policy that is consistent with the State Treasurer&rsquo;s guidelines.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph db-date="20120611" id=":g95::1:::22F:c:3:"><enum>(3)</enum><text>If the governing body of a local government unit amends its local investment policy, the local government shall submit its new policy to the State Treasurer consistent with the provisions of paragraph (2) of this subsection.</text></paragraph><paragraph db-date="20120611" id=":g95::1:::22F:c:4:"><enum>(4)</enum><text>A financial official may not invest public funds of the local government unit in a manner inconsistent with the local investment policy.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection db-date="20120611" id=":g95::1:::22F:d:"><enum>(d)</enum><paragraph db-date="20120611" id=":g95::1:::22F:d:1:"><enum>(1)</enum><subparagraph db-date="20120611" id=":g95::1:::22F:d:1:i:"><enum>(i)</enum><text>On or before September 1, 2009, each local government unit shall adopt by resolution, motion, or ordinance a local debt policy that:</text><sub-subparagraph db-date="20120611" id=":g95::1:::22F:d:1:i:1:" role="item"><enum>1.</enum><text>Is consistent with the Maryland Constitution, Articles 23A, 24, and 31 of the Code, and all other applicable statutes, charters, and local laws; and</text></sub-subparagraph><sub-subparagraph db-date="20120611" id=":g95::1:::22F:d:1:i:2:" role="item"><enum>2.</enum><text>Meets the individual needs of the local government unit.</text></sub-subparagraph></subparagraph><subparagraph db-date="20120611" id=":g95::1:::22F:d:1:ii:"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Promptly after the adoption of a local debt policy, the local government unit shall mail a certified copy to the State Treasurer.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph db-date="20120611" id=":g95::1:::22F:d:1:iii:"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>If the State Treasurer determines that the local debt policy is not consistent with the Maryland Constitution, Articles 23A, 24, and 31 of the Code, or other applicable statutes, charters, or local law:</text><sub-subparagraph db-date="20120611" id=":g95::1:::22F:d:1:iii:1:" role="item"><enum>1.</enum><text>The State Treasurer shall notify the local government unit; and</text></sub-subparagraph><sub-subparagraph db-date="20120611" id=":g95::1:::22F:d:1:iii:2:" role="item"><enum>2.</enum><text>The local government unit shall prepare and submit a revised local debt policy.</text></sub-subparagraph></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph db-date="20120611" id=":g95::1:::22F:d:2:"><enum>(2)</enum><text>If the local government unit amends its local debt policy, the local government shall submit its revised policy to the State Treasurer consistent with the provisions of paragraph (1) of this subsection.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection db-date="20120611" id=":g95::1:::22F:e:"><enum>(e)</enum><paragraph db-date="20120611" id=":g95::1:::22F:e:1:"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The State Treasurer shall contact the local government unit to seek compliance if a local government unit fails to:</text><subparagraph db-date="20120611" id=":g95::1:::22F:e:1:i:" role="item"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Adopt a local investment policy that is consistent with the local government investment guidelines adopted by the State Treasurer; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph db-date="20120611" id=":g95::1:::22F:e:1:ii:" role="item"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Adopt a local debt policy in accordance with (d)(1)(i) of this section.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph db-date="20120611" id=":g95::1:::22F:e:2:"><enum>(2)</enum><text>On request of the State Treasurer, a financial officer shall provide to the State Treasurer, in the format and time frame requested:</text><subparagraph db-date="20120611" id=":g95::1:::22F:e:2:i:" role="item"><enum>(i)</enum><text>A report of the local government investment portfolio; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph db-date="20120611" id=":g95::1:::22F:e:2:ii:" role="item"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>A report of the local government debt portfolio in the format required under Article 24, &sect; 2&ndash;101 of the Code.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph db-date="20120611" id=":g95::1:::22F:e:3:"><enum>(3)</enum><text>If the local government unit fails to comply with this subsection, the State Treasurer shall notify in writing the Joint Committee on the Management of Public Funds.</text></paragraph><paragraph db-date="20120611" id=":g95::1:::22F:e:4:"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The Joint Committee on the Management of Public Funds may request the Attorney General to seek judicial enforcement against the local government unit.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section db-date="20120611" id=":g95::1:::22G:"><enum>22G.</enum><subsection db-date="20120611" id=":g95::1:::22G:a:"><enum>(a)</enum><paragraph db-date="20120611" id=":g95::1:::22G:a:1:"><enum>(1)</enum><subparagraph db-date="20120611" id=":g95::1:::22G:a:1:i:"><enum>(i)</enum><text>In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph db-date="20120611" id=":g95::1:::22G:a:1:ii:"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>&ldquo;Authorized participant&rdquo; means:</text><sub-subparagraph db-date="20120611" id=":g95::1:::22G:a:1:ii:1:" role="item"><enum>1.</enum><text>The governing body of each county or municipality;</text></sub-subparagraph><sub-subparagraph db-date="20120611" id=":g95::1:::22G:a:1:ii:2:" role="item"><enum>2.</enum><text>A county board of education;</text></sub-subparagraph><sub-subparagraph db-date="20120611" id=":g95::1:::22G:a:1:ii:3:" role="item"><enum>3.</enum><text>The governing body of each road, drainage, improvement, construction, or soil conservation district or commission in the State;</text></sub-subparagraph><sub-subparagraph db-date="20120611" id=":g95::1:::22G:a:1:ii:4:" role="item"><enum>4.</enum><text>The Upper Potomac River Commission;</text></sub-subparagraph><sub-subparagraph db-date="20120611" id=":g95::1:::22G:a:1:ii:5:" role="item"><enum>5.</enum><text>Any other political subdivision or body politic of the State;</text></sub-subparagraph><sub-subparagraph db-date="20120611" id=":g95::1:::22G:a:1:ii:6:" role="item"><enum>6.</enum><text>A local government insurance pool formed under Title 19, Subtitle 6 of the Insurance Article; or</text></sub-subparagraph><sub-subparagraph db-date="20120611" id=":g95::1:::22G:a:1:ii:7:" role="item"><enum>7.</enum><text>On approval of the Treasurer, a unit of State government or an entity created by the State if the funds of the unit or entity are not State money over which the Treasurer has investment authority.</text></sub-subparagraph></subparagraph><subparagraph db-date="20120611" id=":g95::1:::22G:a:1:iii:"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>&ldquo;Pool&rdquo; means the Local Government Investment Pool.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph db-date="20120611" id=":g95::1:::22G:a:2:"><enum>(2)</enum><text>There is a Local Government Investment Pool.</text></paragraph><paragraph db-date="20120611" id=":g95::1:::22G:a:3:"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The Pool consists of:</text><subparagraph db-date="20120611" id=":g95::1:::22G:a:3:i:" role="item"><enum>(i)</enum><text>All funds from authorized participants that are placed in the custody of the State; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph db-date="20120611" id=":g95::1:::22G:a:3:ii:" role="item"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Any funds of the State that are placed in the Pool by the Treasurer.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph db-date="20120611" id=":g95::1:::22G:a:4:"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The investment policies for the Pool shall be established by the Treasurer.</text></paragraph><paragraph db-date="20120611" id=":g95::1:::22G:a:5:"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The Treasurer shall administer the Pool on behalf of the authorized participants and, to the extent that State money is included, on behalf of the State.</text></paragraph><paragraph db-date="20120611" id=":g95::1:::22G:a:6:"><enum>(6)</enum><text>The Treasurer shall develop such procedures necessary for the efficient administration of the Pool, including:</text><subparagraph db-date="20120611" id=":g95::1:::22G:a:6:i:" role="item"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Specification of minimum and maximum amounts that may be deposited by any authorized participant in the Pool and minimum periods of time for which deposits shall be retained in the Pool;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph db-date="20120611" id=":g95::1:::22G:a:6:ii:" role="item"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Payment of amounts equivalent to administrative expenses from the earnings of the Pool; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph db-date="20120611" id=":g95::1:::22G:a:6:iii:" role="item"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>Distribution of the earnings in excess of expenses, or allocation of losses, to the authorized participants in a manner that equitably reflects the differing amount of their respective investments and the differing periods of time for which the amounts were in the custody of the Pool.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection db-date="20120611" id=":g95::1:::22G:b:"><enum>(b)</enum><paragraph db-date="20120611" id=":g95::1:::22G:b:1:"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The Treasurer shall invest moneys in the Pool in accordance with the provisions set forth in &sect;&sect; 6&ndash;222 and 6&ndash;223 of the State Finance and Procurement Article.</text></paragraph><paragraph db-date="20120611" id=":g95::1:::22G:b:2:"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Notwithstanding any provisions of law to the contrary or any limitation or restriction contained in any other law, the Treasurer may invest, redeem, sell, exchange, and reinvest moneys in the Pool in bankers&rsquo; acceptances guaranteed by banking institutions.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection db-date="20120611" id=":g95::1:::22G:c:"><enum>(c)</enum><paragraph db-date="20120611" id=":g95::1:::22G:c:1:"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The governing authority of any authorized participant having funds which are available for investment and which are not required by law or by any covenant or agreement with bondholders or others to be segregated and invested in a different manner may direct its financial officer to remit funds to the Treasurer for investment as part of the Pool.</text></paragraph><paragraph db-date="20120611" id=":g95::1:::22G:c:2:"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The governing authority of any authorized participant having funds intended for other postemployment benefits that are available for investment, as authorized under &sect; 22 of this article, may direct its financial officer to remit those funds to the Treasurer for investment as part of the Pool.</text></paragraph><paragraph db-date="20120611" id=":g95::1:::22G:c:3:"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Upon determination by the governing authority of an authorized participant that it is in the best interest of the authorized participant to deposit funds in the Pool, it shall adopt and file with the Treasurer a certified copy of a resolution or ordinance authorizing investment of its funds in the Pool. The resolution or ordinance shall name the official or officials of the authorized participant who are responsible for deposit and withdrawal of such funds.</text></paragraph><paragraph db-date="20120611" id=":g95::1:::22G:c:4:"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The resolution or ordinance filed with the Treasurer shall be accompanied by a statement as to the approximate cash flow requirements of the authorized participant for the invested funds. Subsequent deposits into the Pool shall be accompanied by a statement as to the intended duration of the investment or the anticipated date of withdrawal of the funds from the Pool.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection db-date="20120611" id=":g95::1:::22G:d:"><enum>(d)</enum><text>A separate account designated by name or number for each authorized participant in the Pool, including the State, shall be kept to record individual transactions and totals of all investments belonging to each authorized participant. A monthly report showing the changes in investments made during the preceding month shall be furnished to each authorized participant in the Pool. Details of any investment transaction shall be furnished to any authorized participant upon request.</text></subsection><subsection db-date="20120611" id=":g95::1:::22G:e:"><enum>(e)</enum><text>The principal and credited income of each account maintained for an authorized participant in the Pool shall be subject to payment from the Pool upon request, provided that the request for payment is made in accordance with the terms of the deposit. Accumulated income shall be credited to each authorized participant account at least monthly.</text></subsection><subsection db-date="20120611" id=":g95::1:::22G:f:"><enum>(f)</enum><text>Except as provided in this section, all instruments of title of all investments of the Pool shall remain in the custody of the Treasurer. The Treasurer may deposit with one or more fiscal agents or banks those instruments of title the Treasurer considers advisable, to be held in safekeeping by the agents or banks for collection of the principal and interest or other income, or of the proceeds of sale. The Treasurer shall collect the principal and interest or other income from investments of the Pool, the instruments of title to which are in the Treasurer&rsquo;s custody, when due and payable.</text></subsection><subsection db-date="20120611" id=":g95::1:::22G:g:"><enum>(g)</enum><text>A payment may not be issued upon any account in an amount greater than the sum total of the particular account to which it applies. If such payment is issued, it shall be refunded by the distributee.</text></subsection><subsection db-date="20120611" id=":g95::1:::22G:h:"><enum>(h)</enum><paragraph db-date="20120611" id=":g95::1:::22G:h:1:"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Subject to the objectives and requirements of this section, the Treasurer shall formulate procedures for the investment and reinvestment of funds in the Pool and the acquisition, retention, management, and disposition of investments of the Pool.</text></paragraph><paragraph db-date="20120611" id=":g95::1:::22G:h:2:"><enum>(2)</enum><subparagraph db-date="20120611" id=":g95::1:::22G:h:2:i:"><enum>(i)</enum><text>The Treasurer may enter into a contractual agreement with a qualified Maryland fiscal agent and may compensate the agent for services rendered.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph db-date="20120611" id=":g95::1:::22G:h:2:ii:"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>The agent may perform investment and administrative services which the Treasurer is authorized by this section to perform.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection db-date="20120611" id=":g95::1:::22G:i:"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Funds placed in the Pool, other than funds of the State, may not be considered to be money of the State.</text></subsection></section><section id=":g95::1:::22H:" db-date="20060801"><enum>22H.</enum>
<subsection id=":g95::1:::22H:a:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(a)</enum>
<text>There is a Montgomery County Investment Pool that consists of money of Montgomery County, other local governments, and public and nonprofit entities that have placed money in the Pool for investment purposes.</text>
</subsection><subsection id=":g95::1:::22H:b:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(b)</enum>
<text>The Montgomery County Investment Pool:</text>
<paragraph id=":g95::1:::22H:b:1:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(1)</enum>
<text>Shall be administered by the Montgomery County Director of Finance; and</text>
</paragraph><paragraph id=":g95::1:::22H:b:2:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(2)</enum>
<text>Shall be managed in accordance with the investment policy adopted by Montgomery County under &sect; 22F of this article.</text>
</paragraph></subsection><subsection id=":g95::1:::22H:c:" db-date="20060801"><enum>(c)</enum>
<text>The Montgomery County Investment Pool may not accept funds from any entity that is not participating in the Pool on July 1, 1996.</text>
</subsection></section><section id=":g95::1:::22M:" db-date="20060801"><enum>22M.</enum>
<text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law and in addition to any other authority provided by law, the controller, director of finance, or similar official of a chartered county or Baltimore City may invest, redeem, sell, exchange, and reinvest unexpended bond sale proceeds and other funds which are subject to arbitrage, rebate, or similar limitations under federal tax law, of which the controller, director of finance, or similar official has custody or control in bonds, notes, or other obligations of investment grade quality, as established by a nationally recognized rating agency, issued by or on behalf of this State or any other state or any agency, department, county, municipal or public corporation, special district, authority, or political subdivision of this State or any other state, either directly or through a trust or fund that restricts investments of the trust or fund to obligations of investment grade quality.</text>
</section><section id=":g95::1:::22N:" db-date="20060801"><enum>22N.</enum>
<text>Notwithstanding any provision of law to the contrary or any limitation or restriction contained in any other law, whenever the county commissioners of any county of the State, or the chief fiscal or administrative officer or officers or governing body of any municipality, town, body politic, public body corporate, school, road, drainage, improvement, construction, or soil conservation district or commission in the State, including, by way of enumeration and not in limitation, the Upper Potomac River Commission, or any county school board or other political subdivision or bodies politic of the State, or any agency of any political subdivision of the State, or the trustees or other officers in charge of any pension or retirement system or fund of the State or any political subdivision thereof or any agency or department of either are directed, authorized, empowered, or permitted to invest in, purchase, or take as collateral a bond, obligation, or other evidence of indebtedness of the United States of America, they are directed, authorized, empowered, and permitted to invest in, purchase, or take as collateral an obligation or security of, or other interest in, any open-end or closed-end management type investment company or investment trust registered under the provisions of the federal Investment Company Act of 1940, 15 U.S.C. &sect; 80A-1 et seq., if:</text>
<subsection id=":g95::1:::22N::" role="item" db-date="20060801"> 
<paragraph id=":g95::1:::22N::1:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(1)</enum>
<text>The portfolio of the open-end or closed-end management type investment company or investment trust is limited to direct obligations of the United States government and to repurchased agreements fully collateralized by United States government obligations; and</text>
</paragraph><paragraph id=":g95::1:::22N::2:" role="item" db-date="20060801"><enum>(2)</enum>
<text>The open-end or closed-end management type investment company or investment trust takes delivery of that collateral, either directly or through an authorized custodian.</text>
</paragraph></subsection></section><section db-date="20100618" id=":g95::1:::22-O:"><enum>22&ndash;O.</enum><subsection db-date="20100618" id=":g95::1:::22-O:a:"><enum>(a)</enum><paragraph db-date="20100618" id=":g95::1:::22-O:a:1:"><enum>(1)</enum><text>In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</text></paragraph><paragraph db-date="20100618" id=":g95::1:::22-O:a:2:"><enum>(2)</enum><text>&ldquo;Depositor&rdquo; means a local government or its authorized acknowledged agent making a deposit of unexpended or surplus money as provided in this section.</text></paragraph><paragraph db-date="20100618" id=":g95::1:::22-O:a:3:"><enum>(3)</enum><text>&ldquo;Local government&rdquo; means:</text><subparagraph db-date="20100618" id=":g95::1:::22-O:a:3:i:" role="item"><enum>(i)</enum><text>The governing body of a county or municipal corporation;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph db-date="20100618" id=":g95::1:::22-O:a:3:ii:" role="item"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>A county board of education;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph db-date="20100618" id=":g95::1:::22-O:a:3:iii:" role="item"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>The governing body of a road, drainage, improvement, construction, or soil conservation district or commission in the State;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph db-date="20100618" id=":g95::1:::22-O:a:3:iv:" role="item"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>The Upper Potomac River Commission; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph db-date="20100618" id=":g95::1:::22-O:a:3:v:" role="item"><enum>(v)</enum><text>Any other political subdivision or body politic of the State.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph db-date="20100618" id=":g95::1:::22-O:a:4:"><enum>(4)</enum><text>&ldquo;State financial institution&rdquo; means any of the following institutions that have a branch in the State that takes deposits:</text><subparagraph db-date="20100618" id=":g95::1:::22-O:a:4:i:" role="item"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Bank, trust company, or savings bank incorporated under the laws of the State;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph db-date="20100618" id=":g95::1:::22-O:a:4:ii:" role="item"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Bank incorporated under federal law;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph db-date="20100618" id=":g95::1:::22-O:a:4:iii:" role="item"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>Bank incorporated under the laws of any other state; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph db-date="20100618" id=":g95::1:::22-O:a:4:iv:" role="item"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>Savings and loan association incorporated under the laws of the State or of the United States.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection db-date="20100618" id=":g95::1:::22-O:b:"><enum>(b)</enum><text>Notwithstanding the provisions of &sect; 22 of this article, a local government may deposit unexpended or surplus money in any federally insured bank or savings and loan association without the security required in &sect; 22(a) of this article if:</text><paragraph db-date="20100618" id=":g95::1:::22-O:b:1:" role="item"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The unexpended or surplus money is initially placed for deposit with a State financial institution selected by the depositor;</text></paragraph><paragraph db-date="20100618" id=":g95::1:::22-O:b:2:" role="item"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The State financial institution selected by the depositor arranges for the further deposit of the money into one or more certificates of deposit, each in an amount of not more than the applicable Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation maximum insurance coverage limit, in one or more federally insured banks or savings and loan associations for the account of the depositor;</text></paragraph><paragraph db-date="20100618" id=":g95::1:::22-O:b:3:" role="item"><enum>(3)</enum><text>At the same time the money is deposited and the certificates of deposit are issued for the benefit of the depositor by other banks or savings and loan associations, the State financial institution selected by the depositor receives an amount of deposits from customers of other banks or savings and loan associations equal to the amount of money initially deposited by the depositor;</text></paragraph><paragraph db-date="20100618" id=":g95::1:::22-O:b:4:" role="item"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Each certificate of deposit issued for the depositor&rsquo;s account is insured by the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation for 100&percnt; of the principal and accrued interest of the certificate of deposit; and</text></paragraph><paragraph db-date="20100618" id=":g95::1:::22-O:b:5:" role="item"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The State financial institution selected by the depositor acts as custodian for the depositor with respect to the certificates of deposit issued for the depositor&rsquo;s account.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection db-date="20100618" id=":g95::1:::22-O:c:"><enum>(c)</enum><text>Notwithstanding the provisions of &sect; 22 of this article, a local government may deposit unexpended or surplus money in any federally insured bank or savings and loan association without the security required in &sect; 22(a) of this article if:</text><paragraph db-date="20100618" id=":g95::1:::22-O:c:1:" role="item"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The unexpended or surplus money is initially placed for deposit with a State financial institution that is selected by the depositor to arrange for the redeposit of the money through a deposit placement program that meets the requirements under this subsection;</text></paragraph><paragraph db-date="20100618" id=":g95::1:::22-O:c:2:" role="item"><enum>(2)</enum><text>On or after the date that the local government money is received, the State financial institution selected by the depositor:</text><subparagraph db-date="20100618" id=":g95::1:::22-O:c:2:i:" role="item"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Arranges for the redeposit of the money into one or more deposit accounts, each in an amount of not more than the applicable Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation maximum insurance coverage limit, in one or more federally insured banks or savings and loan associations for the account of the depositor; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph db-date="20100618" id=":g95::1:::22-O:c:2:ii:" role="item"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Acts as custodian for the depositor with respect to the money deposited into the accounts;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph db-date="20100618" id=":g95::1:::22-O:c:3:" role="item"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Any local government money deposited into a State financial institution in accordance with this subsection and held by that State financial institution at the close of a business day that is in excess of the amount insured by the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation is secured in accordance with this article;</text></paragraph><paragraph db-date="20100618" id=":g95::1:::22-O:c:4:" role="item"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The full amount of the local government money redeposited by the State financial institution into deposit accounts in federally insured banks or savings and loan associations under this subsection is insured by the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation; and</text></paragraph><paragraph db-date="20100618" id=":g95::1:::22-O:c:5:" role="item"><enum>(5)</enum><text>On the same date that the money of the local government is redeposited under this subsection, the State financial institution selected by the depositor receives an amount of deposits from customers of other banks or savings and loans in accordance with the deposit placement program that is equal to the amount of the local government money redeposited by the selected State financial institution.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></article></legisdoc>