<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="c11g" order_by="11" level="1">XI-G - City of Baltimore - Resid. Rehab. &amp; Comm. Financing Loans</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>c11g-1</section_number>
  <catch_line>The General Assembly of Maryland, by public local law, may authorize the Mayor and City Council of B...</catch_line>
  <order_by>1</order_by>
  <text>The General Assembly of Maryland, by public local law, may authorize the Mayor and City Council of Baltimore:<section prefix="(a)">To make or contract to make financial loans to any person or other legal entity to be used for or in connection with the rehabilitation, renovation, redevelopment or improvement of buildings or structures located within the boundaries of Baltimore City, which buildings or structures are to be used or occupied for residential purposes.</section><section prefix="(b)">To guarantee or insure financial loans made by third parties to any person or other legal entity to be used for or in connection with the rehabilitation, renovation, redevelopment or improvement of buildings or structures located within the boundaries of Baltimore City, which buildings or structures are to be used or occupied for residential purposes.</section><section prefix="(c)">To make or contract to make financial loans to any person or other legal entity to be used for or in connection with the purchase or acquisition of leasehold or fee simple interests in buildings or structures, and for construction, reconstruction, erection, development, rehabilitation, renovation, redevelopment or improvement of buildings or structures, located within the boundaries of Baltimore City, which buildings or structures are to be used or occupied for commercial purposes.</section><section prefix="(d)">To guarantee or insure financial loans made by third parties to any person or other legal entity to be used for or in connection with the purchase or acquisition of leasehold or fee simple interests in buildings or structures, and for construction, reconstruction, erection, development, rehabilitation, renovation, redevelopment or improvement of buildings or structures, located within the boundaries of Baltimore City, which buildings or structures are to be used or occupied for commercial purposes.</section><section prefix="(e)">Any and all financial loans made by the Mayor and City Council of Baltimore; any and all guarantees or insurance commitments made by the Mayor and City Council of Baltimore in connection with any of said loans; and any and all money used or expended by the Mayor and City Council of Baltimore in connection with said loans, guarantees, or insurance commitments, pursuant to the power and authority hereinabove vested in the municipality, and any and all acts performed by the Mayor and City Council of Baltimore in connection with any powers which may be granted to the Mayor and City Council of Baltimore pursuant to this Article, are all hereby declared to be needed, contracted for, expended or exercised for a public use.</section><section prefix="(f)">In the event of any conflict between the provisions of this Article and those of Article XI, Section 7, of the Constitution of Maryland, or any other provisions of said Constitution, then the provisions of this Article shall control.</section></text>
</law>
