<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="c18" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="5" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>c18-5</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">For the purpose of implementing the amendments proposed by House Bill 916 of 1995 concerning the membership of the Commission on Judicial Disabilities, this section temporarily is part of Article IV - Judiciary Department, Section 4A of the Constitution. This section shall expire, in accordance with Article XIV, Section 1A of the Constitution, when the terms of the members initially appointed to fill the five new memberships added to the Commission under House Bill 916 of 1995 have expired in accordance with subsection (b) of this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The initial terms of the four members of the public added to the Commission under House Bill 916 of 1995 shall expire as follows:<section prefix="(i)">Two members in 1999, and each of those members may be appointed to two full terms; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Two members in 2000, and each of those members may be appointed to one full term.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The initial term of the member of the Bar added to the Commission under House Bill 916 of 1995 shall expire in 1998.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">For the purpose of implementing the elimination of one of the four judicial memberships, the following provisions apply:<section prefix="(1)">If a vacancy exists in a judicial membership at the time the Governor issues the proclamation under Article XIV, Section 1 of the Constitution, declaring the amendments proposed by House Bill 916 of 1995 to have been adopted, a successor may not be appointed and that membership shall be terminated.</section><section prefix="(2)">If no vacancy exists in a judicial membership at the time the Governor issues the proclamation under Article XIV, Section 1 of the Constitution, declaring the amendments proposed by House Bill 916 of 1995 to have been adopted, the four judges serving on the Commission may continue to serve. When the first vacancy in a judicial membership occurs, a successor may not be appointed and that membership shall be terminated.</section><section prefix="(3)">If no vacancy in a judicial membership occurs before January 1, 1999, one of the two judges whose terms expire on January 1, 1999 may not be reappointed and the membership held by that judge shall be terminated.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
