<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="c19" order_by="" level="1">XIX - Video Lottery Terminals</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>c19-1</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>1</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">This article does not apply to:<section prefix="(1)">Lotteries conducted under Title 9, Subtitle 1 of the State Government Article of the Annotated Code of Maryland;</section><section prefix="(2)">Wagering on horse racing conducted under Title 11 of the Business Regulation Article of the Annotated Code of Maryland; or</section><section prefix="(3)">Gaming conducted under Title 12 or Title 13 of the Criminal Law Article of the Annotated Code of Maryland.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">In this article, "video lottery operation license" means a license issued to a person that allows players to operate video lottery terminals.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in subsection (e) of this section, the State may issue up to five video lottery operation licenses throughout the State for the primary purpose of raising revenue for:<section prefix="(i)">Education for the children of the State in public schools, prekindergarten through grade 12;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Public school construction and public school capital improvements; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Construction of capital projects at community colleges and public senior higher education institutions.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Except as provided in subsection (e) of this section, the State may not authorize the operation of more than 15,000 video lottery terminals in the State.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Except as provided in subsection (e) of this section, a video lottery operation license only may be awarded for a video lottery facility in the following locations:<section prefix="(i)">Anne Arundel County, within 2 miles of MD Route 295;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Cecil County, within 2 miles of Interstate 95;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Worcester County, within 1 mile of the intersection of Route 50 and Route 589;</section><section prefix="(iv)">On State property located within Rocky Gap State Park in Allegany County; or</section><section prefix="(v)">Baltimore City, if the video lottery facility is:<section prefix="1.">Located:</section><section prefix="2.">Not adjacent to or within one-quarter mile of property that is:</section></section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">Except as provided in subsection (e) of this section, the State may not award more than one video lottery operation license in a single county or Baltimore City.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">A video lottery facility shall comply with all applicable planning and zoning laws of the local jurisdiction.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Except as provided in subsection (e) of this section, on or after November 15, 2008, the General Assembly may not authorize any additional forms or expansion of commercial gaming.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The General Assembly may only authorize additional forms or expansion of commercial gaming if approval is granted through a referendum, authorized by an act of the General Assembly, in a general election by a majority of the qualified voters in the State.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The General Assembly may, from time to time, enact such laws not inconsistent with this section, as may be necessary and proper to carry out its provisions.</section>
  </text>
</law>
