<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="c4" order_by="" level="1">IV - Judiciary Department</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>c4-18</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>18</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Court of Appeals from time to time shall adopt rules and regulations concerning the practice and procedure in and the administration of the appellate courts and in the other courts of this State, which shall have the force of law until rescinded, changed or modified by the Court of Appeals or otherwise by law. The power of courts other than the Court of Appeals to make rules of practice and procedure, or administrative rules, shall be subject to the rules and regulations adopted by the Court of Appeals or otherwise by law.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Chief Judge of the Court of Appeals shall be the administrative head of the Judicial system of the State. The Chief Judge of the Court of Appeals shall from time to time require, from each of the judges of the Circuit Courts, of the District Court and of any intermediate courts of appeal, reports as to the judicial work and business of each of the judges and their respective courts.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Subject to paragraphs (3) and (4) of this subsection, the Chief Judge of the Court of Appeals may, in case of a vacancy, or of the illness, disqualification or other absence of a judge or for the purpose of relieving an accumulation of business in any court assign any judge except a judge of the Orphans' Court to sit temporarily in any court except an Orphans' Court.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A retired judge of the Circuit Court for Montgomery County that sits as the Orphans' Court for Montgomery County may be assigned by the Chief Judge of the Court of Appeals, upon approval of a majority of the Court of Appeals, to do an act that a judge of the Orphans' Court for Montgomery County is authorized to perform.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">A retired judge of the Circuit Court for Harford County that sits as the Orphans' Court for Harford County may be assigned by the Chief Judge of the Court of Appeals, upon approval of a majority of the Court of Appeals, to do an act that a judge of the Orphans' Court for Harford County is authorized to perform.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">Any judge assigned by the Chief Judge of the Court of Appeals pursuant to this section has all the power and authority pertaining to a judge of the court to which the judge is so assigned; and the judge's power and authority shall continue with respect to all cases (including any motion, or other matters incidental thereto) which may come before the judge by virtue of such assignment until the judge's action thereon shall be completed. In the absence of the Chief Judge of the Court of Appeals, the provisions of this section shall be applicable to the senior judge present in the Court of Appeals. The powers of the Chief Judge set forth in this section shall be subject to any rule or regulation adopted by the Court of Appeals.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
