<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="c5" order_by="" level="1">V - Attorney-General and State's Attorneys</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>c5-3</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>3</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Attorney General shall:<section prefix="(1)">Prosecute and defend on the part of the State all cases pending in the appellate courts of the State, in the Supreme Court of the United States or the inferior Federal Courts, by or against the State, or in which the State may be interested, except those criminal appeals otherwise prescribed by the General Assembly.</section><section prefix="(2)">Investigate, commence, and prosecute or defend any civil or criminal suit or action or category of such suits or actions in any of the Federal Courts or in any Court of this State, or before administrative agencies and quasi legislative bodies, on the part of the State or in which the State may be interested, which the General Assembly by law or joint resolution, or the Governor, shall have directed or shall direct to be investigated, commenced and prosecuted or defended.</section><section prefix="(3)">When required by the General Assembly by law or joint resolution, or by the Governor, aid any State's Attorney or other authorized prosecuting officer in investigating, commencing, and prosecuting any criminal suit or action or category of such suits or actions brought by the State in any Court of this State.</section><section prefix="(4)">Give his opinion in writing whenever required by the General Assembly or either branch thereof, the Governor, the Comptroller, the Treasurer or any State's Attorney on any legal matter or subject.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Attorney General shall have and perform any other duties and possess any other powers, and appoint the number of deputies or assistants, as the General Assembly from time to time may prescribe by law.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Attorney General shall receive for his services the annual salary as the General Assembly from time to time may prescribe by law, but he may not receive any fees, perquisites or rewards whatever, in addition to his salary, for the performance of any official duty.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Governor may not employ any additional counsel, in any case whatever, unless authorized by the General Assembly.</section>
  </text>
</law>
