<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="g1" order_by="1" level="1">Rules of Interpretation</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>g1-27</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this Code and any rule, regulation, or directive adopted under it, "legal holiday" means:...</catch_line>
  <order_by>27</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this Code and any rule, regulation, or directive adopted under it, "legal holiday" means:<section prefix="(1)">January 1, for New Year's Day;</section><section prefix="(2)">January 15, for Dr. Martin Luther King, Jr.'s birthday, unless the United States Congress designates another day for observance of that legal holiday, in which case, the day designated by the United States Congress;</section><section prefix="(3)">February 12, for Lincoln's birthday;</section><section prefix="(4)">The third Monday in February, for Washington's birthday;</section><section prefix="(5)">March 25, for Maryland Day;</section><section prefix="(6)">Good Friday;</section><section prefix="(7)">May 30, for Memorial Day, unless the United States Congress designates another day for observance of that legal holiday, in which case, the day designated by the United States Congress;</section><section prefix="(8)">July 4, for Independence Day;</section><section prefix="(9)">The first Monday in September, for Labor Day;</section><section prefix="(10)">September 12, for Defenders' Day;</section><section prefix="(11)">October 12, for Columbus Day, unless the United States Congress designates another day for observance of that legal holiday, in which case, the day designated by the United States Congress;</section><section prefix="(12)">November 11, for Veterans' Day;</section><section prefix="(13)">The fourth Thursday in November, for Thanksgiving Day;</section><section prefix="(14)">The Friday after Thanksgiving Day, for American Indian Heritage Day;</section><section prefix="(15)">December 25, for Christmas Day;</section><section prefix="(16)">Each statewide general election day in this State; and</section><section prefix="(17)">Each other day that the President of the United States or the Governor designates for general cessation of business.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Except as otherwise expressly provided in this Code, a legal holiday shall be observed on:<section prefix="(1)">The date specified in subsection (a) of this section for the legal holiday; and</section><section prefix="(2)">If that date falls on a Sunday, on the next Monday after that date.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
