<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="g1" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="25" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>g1-25</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Unnumbered revised articles of the Annotated Code of Maryland may be cited as stated in this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A section of the Agriculture Article may be cited as: "&#xA7;___ of the Agriculture Article".</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A section of the Business Occupations and Professions Article may be cited as: "&#xA7;___ of the Business Occupations and Professions Article".</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A section of the Business Regulation Article may be cited as: "&#xA7;___ of the Business Regulation Article".</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">A section of the Commercial Law Article may be cited as: "&#xA7;___ of the Commercial Law Article".</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">A section of the Corporations and Associations Article may be cited as: "&#xA7;___ of the Corporations and Associations Article".</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">A section of the Correctional Services Article may be cited as: "&#xA7;___ of the Correctional Services Article".</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">A section of the Courts and Judicial Proceedings Article may be cited as: "&#xA7;___ of the Courts Article".</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">A section of the Criminal Law Article may be cited as: "&#xA7;___ of the Criminal Law Article".</section>
    <section prefix="(j)">A section of the Criminal Procedure Article may be cited as: "&#xA7;___ of the Criminal Procedure Article".</section>
    <section prefix="(k)">A section of the Economic Development Article may be cited as: "&#xA7;___ of the Economic Development Article".</section>
    <section prefix="(l)">A section of the Education Article may be cited as: "&#xA7;___ of the Education Article".</section>
    <section prefix="(m)">A section of the Election Law Article may be cited as: "&#xA7;___ of the Election Law Article".</section>
    <section prefix="(n)">A section of the Environment Article may be cited as: "&#xA7;___ of the Environment Article".</section>
    <section prefix="(o)">A section of the Estates and Trusts Article may be cited as: "&#xA7;___ of the Estates and Trusts Article".</section>
    <section prefix="(p)">A section of the Family Law Article may be cited as: "&#xA7;___ of the Family Law Article".</section>
    <section prefix="(q)">A section of the Financial Institutions Article may be cited as: "&#xA7;___ of the Financial Institutions Article".</section>
    <section prefix="(r)">A section of the Health - General Article may be cited as: "&#xA7;___ of the Health - General Article".</section>
    <section prefix="(s)">A section of the Health Occupations Article may be cited as: "&#xA7;___ of the Health Occupations Article".</section>
    <section prefix="(t)">A section of the Housing and Community Development Article may be cited as: "&#xA7;___ of the Housing and Community Development Article".</section>
    <section prefix="(u)">A section of the Human Services Article may be cited as: "&#xA7;___ of the Human Services Article".</section>
    <section prefix="(v)">A section of the Insurance Article may be cited as: "&#xA7;___ of the Insurance Article".</section>
    <section prefix="(w)">A section of the Labor and Employment Article may be cited as: "&#xA7;___ of the Labor and Employment Article".</section>
    <section prefix="(x)">A section of the Land Use Article may be cited as: "&#xA7;___ of the Land Use Article".</section>
    <section prefix="(y)">A section of the Natural Resources Article may be cited as: "&#xA7;___ of the Natural Resources Article".</section>
    <section prefix="(z)">A section of the Public Safety Article may be cited as: "&#xA7;___ of the Public Safety Article".</section>
    <section prefix="(aa)">A section of the Public Utilities Article may be cited as: "&#xA7; ___ of the Public Utilities Article".</section>
    <section prefix="(bb)">A section of the Real Property Article may be cited as: "&#xA7;___ of the Real Property Article".</section>
    <section prefix="(cc)">A section of the State Finance and Procurement Article may be cited as: "&#xA7;___ of the State Finance and Procurement Article".</section>
    <section prefix="(dd)">A section of the State Government Article may be cited as: "&#xA7;___ of the State Government Article".</section>
    <section prefix="(ee)">A section of the State Personnel and Pensions Article may be cited as: "&#xA7;___ of the State Personnel and Pensions Article".</section>
    <section prefix="(ff)">A section of the Tax - General Article may be cited as: "&#xA7;___ of the Tax - General Article".</section>
    <section prefix="(gg)">A section of the Tax - Property Article may be cited as: "&#xA7;___ of the Tax - Property Article".</section>
    <section prefix="(hh)">A section of the Transportation Article may be cited as: "&#xA7;___ of the Transportation Article".</section>
  </text>
</law>
