<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="g19" order_by="19" level="1">Comptroller</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>g19-37</section_number>
  <catch_line>Except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, each county, municipal corporation, and taxi...</catch_line>
  <order_by>37</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, each county, municipal corporation, and taxing district in the State shall by the first day of November after the close of the fiscal year file with the Department of Legislative Services its financial report covering the full period of that fiscal year.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Each county, municipal corporation, or taxing district with a population of more than 400,000 may by the first day of January after the close of the fiscal year file with the Department of Legislative Services its financial report covering the full period of that fiscal year.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">Unless subparagraph (i) of this paragraph applies, Howard County may by the first day of December after the close of the fiscal year file with the Department of Legislative Services its financial report covering the full period of that fiscal year.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">Calvert County may by the first day of January after the close of the fiscal year file with the Department of Legislative Services its financial report covering the full period of that fiscal year.</section>
        <section prefix="(iv)">Frederick County may by the first day of January after the close of the fiscal year file with the Department of Legislative Services its financial report covering the full period of that fiscal year.</section>
        <section prefix="(v)">Queen Anne's County may by the first day of January after the close of the fiscal year file with the Department of Legislative Services its financial report covering the full period of that fiscal year.</section>
        <section prefix="(vi)">St. Mary's County may by the first day of January after the close of the fiscal year file with the Department of Legislative Services its financial report covering the full period of that fiscal year.</section>
        <section prefix="(vii)">Wicomico County may by the first day of January after the close of the fiscal year file with the Department of Legislative Services its financial report covering the full period of that fiscal year.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The reports required by subsection (a) of this section shall be:<section prefix="(1)">Properly filled in on the form or forms established by the Department as provided in this subtitle; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Verified by the chief executive officer of each county, municipal corporation, and taxing district.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
