<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="g23a" order_by="" level="1">Corporations - Municipal</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>g23a-54</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>54</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">By ordinance, the legislative body of a municipal corporation may establish a land bank authority in accordance with this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">An ordinance adopted under subsection (a) of this section shall include proposed articles of incorporation of an authority that state:<section prefix="(1)">The name of the authority, which shall be "Land Bank Authority of (name of the incorporating municipal corporation)";</section><section prefix="(2)">That the authority is formed under this subtitle;</section><section prefix="(3)">The names, addresses, and terms of office of the initial members of the board of directors of the authority;</section><section prefix="(4)">The address of the principal office of the authority;</section><section prefix="(5)">The purposes for which the authority is formed; and</section><section prefix="(6)">The powers of the authority subject to the limitations on the powers of an authority under this subtitle.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The chief executive of the incorporating municipal corporation, or any other official designated in the ordinance establishing an authority, shall execute and file the articles of incorporation of the authority for recordation with the State Department of Assessments and Taxation.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">When the State Department of Assessments and Taxation accepts the articles of incorporation for recordation, the authority becomes a body politic and corporate and an instrumentality of the incorporating municipal corporation.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Acceptance of the articles of incorporation for recordation by the State Department of Assessments and Taxation is conclusive evidence of the formation of the authority.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">By ordinance, the legislative body of the incorporating municipal corporation may adopt an amendment to the articles of incorporation of an authority.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Articles of amendment may contain any provision that lawfully could be contained in articles of incorporation at the time of the amendment.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The articles of amendment shall be filed for recordation with the State Department of Assessments and Taxation.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The articles of amendment are effective as of the time the State Department of Assessments and Taxation accepts the articles for recordation.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">Acceptance of the articles of amendment for recordation by the State Department of Assessments and Taxation is conclusive evidence that the articles have been lawfully and properly adopted.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Subject to the provisions of this section and any limitations imposed by law on the impairment of contracts, the incorporating municipal corporation, in its sole discretion, by ordinance may:<section prefix="(i)">Set or change the structure, organization, procedures, programs, or activities of an authority; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">Terminate the authority.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">On termination of the authority:<section prefix="(i)">Title to all property of the authority shall be transferred to and shall vest in the incorporating municipal corporation; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">All obligations of the authority shall be transferred to and assumed by the incorporating municipal corporation.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
