<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="g23a" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="64" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>g23a-64</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Following an unsuccessful attempt on the part of the municipal corporation to collect outstanding liens at tax sale and subject to the approval of the local tax collecting unit of the jurisdiction where the property is located, an authority may accept from a person with an interest in a parcel of tax delinquent property or tax sale property a deed or assignment conveying that person's interest in the property instead of:<section prefix="(1)">The foreclosure or sale of the property for delinquent taxes, penalties, and interest, as defined by &#xA7; 14-801(c) of the Tax - Property Article; or</section><section prefix="(2)">Delinquent specific taxes imposed by a local taxing jurisdiction.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Except as otherwise provided by law, conveyance of property by deed instead of foreclosure under this section may not affect or impair any other lien against the property or any existing recorded or unrecorded interest in the property, including:<section prefix="(1)">Future installments of special assessments;</section><section prefix="(2)">Liens recorded by the State;</section><section prefix="(3)">Easements or rights-of-way;</section><section prefix="(4)">Private deed restrictions;</section><section prefix="(5)">Security interests and mortgages; or</section><section prefix="(6)">Tax liens of other taxing jurisdictions that do not consent to a release of their liens.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A tax lien against property held by or under the control of an authority may be released or abated at any time by one or more of the following:<section prefix="(1)">A county or municipal corporation with respect to a lien held by the county or municipal corporation;</section><section prefix="(2)">The governing body of any taxing jurisdiction other than the State, county, or municipal corporation with respect to a lien held by the taxing jurisdiction;</section><section prefix="(3)">A public water or sewer authority with respect to a tax lien or right to collect a tax held by the public water or sewer authority; or</section><section prefix="(4)">The State Comptroller with respect to a State tax lien.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
