<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="g23a" order_by="23" level="1">Corporations - Municipal</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>g23a-17</section_number>
  <catch_line>In any proposal to amend an existing charter of a municipal corporation, the new matter, if any, to ...</catch_line>
  <order_by>17</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In any proposal to amend an existing charter of a municipal corporation, the new matter, if any, to be added to the charter shall be indicated by being underscored or in italics or typed or printed completely in capital letters and all matter to be eliminated from the existing charter, if any, shall be indicated in its proper place by enclosing such matter in double parentheses or in boldface brackets. Where the subject matter consists of an entirely new section or sections the words of such new section or sections shall also be underscored or in italics or typed or printed completely in capital letters or contain some marginal or other notation to that effect. When the purpose of any proposal is to repeal in entirety any section or sections of the existing charter, the matter intended to be repealed need not be written out in full and enclosed in either double parentheses or boldface brackets.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The resolution to amend a charter shall identify the source of the existing section or sections, citing the code or other publication or amendment in which appears the most recent text of the section or sections to be amended.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Amendments to the charter of any municipal corporation shall be in a consecutively numbered series.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The resolution to amend a charter shall provide specifically (and not simply by implication) for the repeal of any section or sections of the existing charter which are inconsistent with the amended section or sections.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">A proposal to amend a charter, whether initiated by the legislative body of the municipal corporation or by a petition of qualified voters of the municipal corporation, may not be rescinded after its adoption by the legislative body or after its formal submission in a petition, in any manner other than that of another charter amendment.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">At the time a charter amendment or amendments become effective by reason of having been ordained or passed by the legislative body of the municipal corporation, or at the time of making public proclamation as to the vote on any question containing a proposed charter amendment or amendments which have been adopted, the mayor or other chief executive officer of the municipal corporation shall send the information concerning the charter amendment or amendments to the Department of Legislative Services as provided in &#xA7; 9A of this article.</section>
  </text>
</law>
