<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="g23a" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="17A" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>g23a-17A</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">At the end of each calendar or fiscal year, each municipal corporation shall furnish in a convenient and legible compilation a complete set of the measures dealt with during that year which enact, amend, or repeal sections in its municipal charter. The measures in the compilation shall be in a numerical sequence, beginning with No. 1, and in a separate series for each year.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Copies of this compilation shall be made available for inspection at the office of the mayor and town council, by whatever name known, during normal business hours; and copies shall be kept on permanent record in the same office. The foregoing copies shall be furnished without charge, and the county also may make other copies available at a reasonable cost to any person.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Not later than March 1 of the next succeeding year, the municipal corporation, without charge, shall furnish copies of the compilation to the Department of Legislative Services as provided in &#xA7; 9A of this article.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">In addition to furnishing copies of the compilation, the municipal corporation shall provide to the Department of Legislative Services as provided in &#xA7; 9A of this article, a statement concerning any referendum on any proposed charter amendment.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">At the end of each calendar year the Department of Legislative Services shall address an inquiry to each municipal corporation inquiring whether or not during that calendar year or its latest fiscal year it has enacted, amended or repealed any portion of its municipal charter. The municipal corporation shall promptly answer the inquiry and shall verify, by a signed and notarized statement, that copies of all such enactments, amendments, or repeals have already been sent to the Department.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">If the municipal corporation fails or refuses to supply copies of this compilation and of the results of any referenda thereon to the Department of Legislative Services by March 1 of the next succeeding year, or fails or refuses to certify that there have been no such enactments, amendments, or repeals, or referenda, during the last calendar or fiscal year, the Department shall promptly certify that fact to the State Comptroller, who then may order the discontinuance of all funds, grants or State aid which the municipal corporation is entitled to receive under State law. The section refers specifically to all funds, grants or State aid which the municipal corporation is entitled to receive under applicable provisions of State law relating to the income tax, the tax on racing, the recordation tax, the admissions and amusement tax, and the license tax.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">The Department of Legislative Services shall receive the several compilations and statements thus delivered to it. The titles of the laws of the several municipal corporations which amend their charters shall be arranged in a logical and convenient order and shall be delivered to the State printer for inclusion in the Session Laws of the General Assembly for its regular session in that year. The titles of the laws of the municipal corporations which amend their charters shall be printed and identified as such, and they shall be indexed with or in a supplemental volume to the laws enacted by the General Assembly.</section>
  </text>
</law>
