<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="g23a" order_by="23" level="1">Corporations - Municipal</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>g23a-14</section_number>
  <catch_line>Twenty per centum or more of the persons who are qualified to vote in municipal general elections in...</catch_line>
  <order_by>14</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Twenty per centum or more of the persons who are qualified to vote in municipal general elections in the particular municipal corporation may initiate a proposed amendment or amendments to the municipal charter, by a petition presented to the legislative body of the municipal corporation, by whatever name known. The petition shall contain the complete and exact wording of the proposed amendment or amendments, and the proposed amendment or amendments shall be prepared in conformity with the several requirements contained in subsections (b) and (c) of &#xA7; 13 of this subtitle. Each person signing it shall indicate thereon both his name and residence address. Upon receiving the petition, the legislative body is directed to verify that any person who signed it is qualified to vote in municipal general elections, and shall consider the petition as of no effect if it is signed by fewer than twenty per centum of the persons who are qualified to vote in municipal general elections. If the petition complies with the requirements of this section, the legislative body shall by resolution, passed as in its normal legislative procedure, and not later than sixty days after the petition shall have been presented to it, specify the day and the hours for the election at which the question shall be submitted to the voters of the municipal corporation. This may be at either the next regular municipal general election or at a special election, in the discretion of the legislative body. In the event a special election is designated, it shall be within a period of not less than forty days nor more than sixty days after the final passage of the resolution. In the resolution, the exact wording shall be specified which is to be placed on the ballots or voting machines when the question is submitted to the voters of the municipal corporation.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Provided, however, that if the legislative body shall approve of the amendment or amendments provided for in the petition presented to it under subsection (a) above, it shall have the right by resolution to adopt the amendment or amendments thereby proposed and to proceed thereafter in the same manner as if the amendment or amendments had been initiated by such legislative body and in compliance with the provisions of &#xA7; 13 of this article.</section>
  </text>
</law>
