<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="g23a" order_by="" level="1">Corporations - Municipal</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>g23a-52</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>52</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Authority" means a nonprofit or quasi-governmental entity created by a municipal corporation under &#xA7; 54 of this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Board" means the board of directors of an authority.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Bond" means a bond issued by an authority under this subtitle.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Bond" includes a bond, a refunding bond, a note, and any other obligation.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"Cost" includes:<section prefix="(1)">The purchase price of property;</section><section prefix="(2)">The cost to acquire any right, title, or interest in property;</section><section prefix="(3)">The cost of any improvements made to property;</section><section prefix="(4)">The amount to be paid to discharge each obligation necessary or desirable to vest title to any part of property in an authority or other owner;</section><section prefix="(5)">The cost of any property, right, easement, franchise, and permit associated with a project;</section><section prefix="(6)">The cost of labor, machinery, and equipment necessary to implement a project;</section><section prefix="(7)">Financing charges;</section><section prefix="(8)">Interest and reserves for principal and interest and for improvements;</section><section prefix="(9)">The cost of revenue and cost estimates, engineering and legal services, plans, specifications, studies, surveys, and other expenses necessary or incident to determining the feasibility or practicability of a project;</section><section prefix="(10)">Administrative expenses; and</section><section prefix="(11)">Other expenses as necessary or incident to:<section prefix="(i)">Financing a project;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Acquiring and improving a project;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Placing a project in operation, including reasonable provisions for working capital; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">Operating and maintaining a project.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">"Finance" includes refinance.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Project" means any organized plan carried out by an authority in relation to:<section prefix="(i)">Acquiring and rehabilitating abandoned and dilapidated properties; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Marketing and leasing or selling the rehabilitated properties.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Project" includes:<section prefix="(i)">Acquiring land or an interest in land;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Acquiring structures, equipment, and furnishings located on a property;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Acquiring property that is functionally related and subordinate to a project; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">Obtaining or contracting for any services necessary for the rehabilitation of a property.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(h)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Revenues" means the income, revenue, and other money an authority receives from or in connection with a project and all other income of an authority.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Revenues" includes grants, rentals, rates, fees, and charges.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(i)">"Tax sale property" means property or an interest in property sold by the tax collector of the county in accordance with Title 14, Subtitle 8, Part III of the Tax - Property Article.</section>
    <section prefix="(j)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Trust agreement" means an agreement entered into by an authority to secure a bond.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Trust agreement" may include a bond contract, bond resolution, or other contract with or for the benefit of a bondholder.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
