<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="g23a" order_by="" level="1">Corporations - Municipal</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>g23a-9A</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>9A</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Whenever the mayor and city council, by whatever name known, of any municipal corporation in this State (as defined in &#xA7; 9(a) of this article) causes, or is required to cause any of the following documents to be created, implemented or otherwise established, the respective documents shall be deposited with the Department of Legislative Services, and in the manner, as prescribed by this section.<section prefix="(1)">A code or compilation containing all or a portion of the municipal charter, published or issued in printed, mimeographed or similar duplicated form; as provided for in &#xA7; 9(e) of this article.</section><section prefix="(2)">A charter amendment or amendments ordained or passed by the legislative body of the municipal corporation, or as adopted by the vote on the question at a public referendum; including (i) the complete text of it, (ii) the date of the referendum election, if any, (iii) the number of votes cast for or against each question containing the charter amendment or amendments, whether in the legislative body or in a referendum, and (iv) the effective date of the charter amendment or amendments; as provided for in &#xA7; 17(f) of this article.</section><section prefix="(3)">A complete list of the measures which enact, amend, or repeal sections in the municipal charter, identifying each charter section affected by number and title; as provided for in &#xA7; 17A(a), (b), and (c) of this article.</section><section prefix="(4)">A charter amendment, ordinance, referendum or any other device by which the corporate boundaries of the municipality are enlarged or otherwise changed; including (i) a copy of the complete text of it with a statement of the new boundaries, (ii) the date of the referendum election, if any, (iii) the number of votes cast for or against the annexation, whether in the legislative body or in a referendum, and (iv) the effective date of the annexation; as provided for in &#xA7; 19(p) of this article.</section><section prefix="(5)">A unified charter providing for the merger of two or more municipal corporations; including (i) the complete text of it, (ii) the date of the referendum election, if any, (iii) the number of votes cast for or against the adoption of the unified charter, whether in the legislative bodies or in a referendum, and (iv) the effective date of the unified charter; as provided for in &#xA7; 19A(j) of this article.</section><section prefix="(6)">A charter providing for the creation of a new municipal corporation; including (i) the complete text of it, (ii) the date of the referendum election, (iii) the number of votes cast for and against the question of incorporation, under the charter, and (iv) the effective date of the charter; as provided for in &#xA7; 27(a) of this article.</section><section prefix="(7)">A charter amendment providing for the entire repeal of the charter of a municipal corporation, ordained or passed by the legislative body of the municipal corporation, or as adopted by the vote on the question at a public referendum; including (i) the complete text of it, (ii) the date of the referendum election, if any, (iii) the number of votes cast for or against the charter amendment, whether in the legislative body or in a referendum, and (iv) the effective date of the charter amendment; as provided for in &#xA7; 41 of this article.</section><section prefix="(8)">In addition to the document and referenda enumerated elsewhere in this subsection, a statement on the results of any referendum on any proposed charter amendment held during the year, and any referendum pending, actually or potentially, but not yet held, at the end of the year; as provided for in &#xA7; 17A(d) of this article.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The mayor or other chief executive officer, by whatever name known, of each municipal corporation shall send, or cause to be sent, separately by mail, bearing a postmark from the United States Postal Service, one copy of each of the documents, as appropriate, enumerated in subsection (a) of this section to the Department of Legislative Services.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The mayor or other chief executive officer, by whatever name known, of each municipal corporation shall send to the Department of Legislative Services:<section prefix="(1)">A charter amendment resolution within 10 days after the resolution becomes effective under &#xA7; 13(f) or &#xA7; 16(c) of this article; or</section><section prefix="(2)">An annexation resolution within 10 days after the resolution becomes effective under &#xA7; 19(e) or (l) of this article.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
