<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="g23a" order_by="" level="1">Corporations - Municipal</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>g23a-16</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>16</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">On the day and during the hours specified for any referendum, the proposed charter amendment or amendments shall be submitted to the qualified voters of the municipal corporation. The official or officials thereof whose duty it is to arrange for and conduct the regular municipal elections shall perform the same duties so far as relevant to the referendum election on the proposed charter amendment or amendments. It is the intent of this section that the referendum election shall be conducted generally according to the procedures and practices observed for regular municipal elections, except as specifically or necessarily modified by the provisions of this subheading. The wording specified by the legislative body of the municipal corporation, in the resolution providing for a referendum on the charter amendment or amendments, shall be placed on the ballots or voting machines used at the referendum election. The expenses of the referendum election shall be defrayed by the municipal corporation.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The official or officials charged with the duty to arrange for and conduct the referendum, promptly following the closing of the polls, shall tally the results thereof, and shall forthwith certify the results of the referendum to the mayor or other chief executive officer of the municipal corporation.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">If a majority of those who vote on any question so submitted to the voters of the municipal corporation shall cast their votes in favor of the proposed charter amendment or amendments, the mayor or other chief executive officer of the municipal corporation shall so proclaim publicly within ten days after receiving a certification of the votes from the officials conducting the referendum; and on the thirtieth day following the public proclamation the proposed charter amendment or amendments shall become a part of the charter of the municipal corporation, according to its terms, in all respects to be effective and observed as such. If less than a majority of those who vote on any such question shall cast their votes in favor of the proposed charter amendment or amendments, the mayor or other chief executive officer likewise shall so proclaim, adding to his proclamation the statement that the proposed charter amendment or amendments contained in said question are null and void and of no effect whatsoever.</section>
  </text>
</law>
