<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="g24" order_by="" level="1">Political Subdivisions - Miscellaneous Provisions</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>g24-11-507</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>507</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">For the purposes of this section and &#xA7; 11-508 of this subtitle, "person" means an individual, receiver, trustee, guardian, personal representative, fiduciary, or representative of any kind and any partnership, firm, association, corporation, or other entity.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Money arising from the dog licenses or taxes shall be kept in a separate fund by the treasurer of the county, or tax collecting office or credited to the county's general fund, and may be used for the payment of damages for the injury and killing of sheep, poultry or other livestock in the respective counties, according to the procedures set out in a local law or ordinance adopted under &#xA7; 11-508 of this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">If a county adopts a local law or ordinance under &#xA7; 11-508 of this subtitle and there are insufficient funds for the payment of all damages the damages shall be paid in the order the claims are presented. Any person whose claim is not paid in any one year by reason of the lack of money available to satisfy claims shall be paid out of the first money that becomes available after the claim is reached. Claims shall be paid in the order in which the claims are proved and filed. Any claims now filed and passed upon, but remaining unpaid, shall have preference over any new claims in the order of payment.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The governing body of each county may expend any funds in excess of $1,000 remaining in a dog license fund after the payment of the claims for any public purpose which, in the governing body's judgment may seem right and proper. The county governing body may enter into a contract or agreement with any person considered suitable, for the removal, care, and disposition of unlicensed dogs, or licensed dogs which may create a menace to the safety, security, and property of the residents of the county, on the terms and conditions and for the compensation that may be agreed to by the county governing body and the person.</section>
  </text>
</law>
