<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="g24" order_by="" level="1">Political Subdivisions - Miscellaneous Provisions</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>g24-2-101</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>101</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Department" means the Department of Legislative Services.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Financial officer" means the treasurer or other financial officer of a political subdivision.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">"Political subdivision" includes:<section prefix="(i)">A county;</section><section prefix="(ii)">A municipal corporation in the State;</section><section prefix="(iii)">A special taxing district in the State; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">A public corporation of the State.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If a political subdivision is authorized to incur debt to be redeemed from a fee, charge, or the proceeds of a levy, the financial officer of the political subdivision shall submit to the State Treasurer and, subject to &#xA7; 2-1246 of the State Government Article, to the Department a comprehensive report on the financial condition of the political subdivision as of the end of that fiscal year.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A political subdivision shall submit the report required under paragraph (1) of this subsection in accordance with the timeframes required under Article 19, &#xA7; 37 of the Code for the submission to the Department of annual financial reports of counties, municipal corporations, and special taxing districts.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A report under this section shall be on the form that the Department provides.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A report under this section shall include the affidavit of the financial officer and all of the following information that applies to the political subdivision:<section prefix="(1)">The assessed valuation of taxable and tangible property in the political subdivision;</section><section prefix="(2)">The total indebtedness of the political subdivision;</section><section prefix="(3)">The following categories of the total indebtedness:<section prefix="(i)">Bond indebtedness that is redeemable from the proceeds of general and ad valorem taxes;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Temporary or floating indebtedness;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Obligations that are incurred in anticipation of tax collection;</section><section prefix="(iv)">Current bills payable;</section><section prefix="(v)">Contingent liability that results from the guaranty of an obligation of another political subdivision; and</section><section prefix="(vi)">Self-liquidating bond indebtedness;</section></section><section prefix="(4)">As to self-liquidating bond indebtedness:<section prefix="(i)">The amount of indebtedness for each project; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">The source of the revenue for its liquidation;</section></section><section prefix="(5)">As to each sinking fund for retirement of obligations:<section prefix="(i)">Each obligation for which the fund is established;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The amount of the fund; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">The manner in which money in the fund is invested;</section></section><section prefix="(6)">As to the tax levy for the fiscal year for which the report is made:<section prefix="(i)">The amount of the levy imposed;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The amount of the levy collected; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Separate items for:<section prefix="1.">The amount of any special assessment levied; and</section><section prefix="2.">The amount of that assessment collected;</section></section></section><section prefix="(7)">As to the tax levy for each of the 3 fiscal years immediately preceding the fiscal year for which the report is made:<section prefix="(i)">The amount of the levy imposed; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">The amount of uncollected taxes;</section></section><section prefix="(8)">As to the population of the political subdivision:<section prefix="(i)">The population in the most recent federal census; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Any official or unofficial population estimates for the fiscal year for which the report is made;</section></section><section prefix="(9)">A copy of the most recent actuarial report on the pension system of the political subdivision, unless it is a county or municipal corporation and a member of the State pension system;</section><section prefix="(10)">As to all categories of indebtedness:<section prefix="(i)">Variable interest rate debt instruments;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Interest rate exchange agreements or swaps; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Other derivatives, including futures and options; and</section></section><section prefix="(11)">Any other information about the financial affairs of the political subdivision that the Department finds pertinent or appropriate and necessary to show accurately the financial condition of the political subdivision.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">On request of the State Treasurer, a financial officer shall submit an updated report on the indebtedness of the political subdivision as required in subsection (d) of this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A financial officer may not fail to:<section prefix="(i)">Submit a report under this section; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">Resubmit a report that meets the requirements of this section within 15 days after receiving notice that the Department finds the report inadequate.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If a financial officer violates any provision of this subsection, the political subdivision employing the financial officer is liable to the State for a penalty of $10 for each day or part of a day for which the report is overdue.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
