<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="g24" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="9-318" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>g24-9-318</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Except for Talbot County, Washington County, Dorchester County, Frederick County, and Carroll County, an authorized county shall distribute the hotel rental tax revenue as follows:<section prefix="(1)">From the total revenue, a reasonable sum for hotel rental tax administrative costs to the general fund of the county;</section><section prefix="(2)">In a code county and Calvert, Cecil, Garrett, and St. Mary's counties, after the distribution in item (1) of this subsection, the revenue attributable to a hotel located in a municipal corporation to the municipal corporation; and</section><section prefix="(3)">The remaining balance to the general fund of the county.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Cecil County may not deduct more than 5% of the revenue for administrative costs under subsection (a)(1) of this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Garrett County shall designate a part of the balance under subsection (a)(3) of this section for the promotion of the county.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Wicomico County may not deduct more than 5% of the revenue for administrative costs under subsection (a)(1) of this section.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">If Wicomico County authorizes a hotel rental tax rate of 6%, the county shall distribute:</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">Wicomico County shall deposit all remaining revenues, after the distributions under subsection (a)(1) of this section and subparagraphs (ii) and (iii) of this paragraph in the general funds of Wicomico County to underwrite the Wicomico County Convention and Visitors Bureau.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(4)">
        <section prefix="(i)">For purposes of this paragraph, actual administrative costs mean costs incurred for wages, postage, and supplies.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">Washington County:</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">A municipal corporation in Washington County may apply to the Board of County Commissioners of Washington County for funding from the special fund established under subparagraph (ii)2 of this paragraph for an eligible project within the municipal corporation.</section>
        <section prefix="(iv)">Each year before adoption of its annual budget, the Hagerstown/Washington County Convention and Visitors Bureau shall hold a public hearing on the proposed annual budget.</section>
        <section prefix="(v)">On or before September 1 of each year beginning in 2001:</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(5)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Frederick County shall distribute the hotel rental tax revenue as follows:</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The internal auditor of the county shall conduct an audit of the financial records of the Tourism Council and report the findings to the County Commissioners.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(6)">Dorchester County shall distribute:<section prefix="(i)">80% of the revenues attributable to a hotel located in a municipal corporation to that municipal corporation; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">The remaining revenues to the general fund of the county.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(7)">Carroll County shall distribute the hotel rental tax revenue as follows:<section prefix="(i)">A reasonable sum for hotel rental tax administrative costs to the general fund of the county; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">The remaining balance to the tourism and general promotion of Carroll County.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(8)">Notwithstanding subsection (a)(2) of this section, if a code county in the Western Maryland class imposes a tax rate greater than 5%, the revenue attributable to the rate greater than 5% and attributable to a hotel located in a municipal corporation shall be distributed to the general fund of the county instead of to the municipal corporation.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">An authorized county shall make the distributions required under this section between the 15th day and the 30th day of each calendar month.</section>
  </text>
</law>
