<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="g24" order_by="" level="1">Political Subdivisions - Miscellaneous Provisions</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>g24-11-301</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>301</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">This section applies only to Carroll and Washington counties.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Transient or temporary vendors" means all persons, partnerships, corporations, or other legal entities, and their principals and agents, who:<section prefix="(i)">Engage in a business for the purpose of selling or soliciting orders for the sale of goods, wares, or merchandise;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Are located in 1 location or travel from place to place;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Have the intent to continue this business in Washington County or in Carroll County for a period of a year or less; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">For the purpose of conducting this business, rent, use, or occupy the following:<section prefix="1.">Buildings, including:</section><section prefix="2.">Any lots or parcels of land including:</section><section prefix="3.">Motor or nonmotorized vehicles of any type including:</section></section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Date of issuance" means the date on which the license is actually obtained by the vendor and the date the vendor may legally proceed with business.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">"Nonenclosed shopping center" means a nonenclosed commercial complex:<section prefix="(i)">Located on one parcel of ground and containing at least 450,000 square feet of floor space; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Containing at least 100 retail establishments.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This subsection applies only to Carroll County.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">In a proceeding to prosecute a violation of this section or to enforce the provisions of this section, there is a presumption that a person conducting a business intends to continue the business for 1 year or less if the business is not open for business at least 5 days during each week and at least 50 weeks during the year.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The county commissioners of each county may:<section prefix="(1)">License and regulate persons who conduct a transient or temporary business; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Require a license to be obtained before conducting business within the county.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">This section does not apply to the following:<section prefix="(1)">Travelers or selling agents, including auctioneers, in the usual course of business;</section><section prefix="(2)">The mere solicitation of orders for the future delivery of goods, wares, or merchandise in interstate commerce;</section><section prefix="(3)">Sales of goods, wares, or merchandise exhibited on the grounds used by any agricultural society for the purpose of holding that agricultural society's annual fair;</section><section prefix="(4)">Sales by any other nonprofit organization or society for charitable, religious, or other public purpose;</section><section prefix="(5)">Conventions of religious, civic, or charitable groups or nonprofit trade associations, concerts, cultural events, art and craft shows, sales, exhibitions, or fairs and the exhibitor is the sole producer of the products;</section><section prefix="(6)">Sales by a farmer or his agent of produce from a truck or stand owned or leased by the farmer;</section><section prefix="(7)">Shows, sales, exhibitions, or fairs conducted within the central pedestrian areas of enclosed shopping malls;</section><section prefix="(8)">Sales by a seller at a residential premises pursuant to an invitation by the owner or legal occupant of the residential premises; or</section><section prefix="(9)">In Washington County, shows, sales, exhibitions, or fairs conducted within the central pedestrian areas of nonenclosed shopping centers, provided that the event complies with all applicable codes and ordinances and that all applicable permits are secured.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The promoter, sponsor, or other person organizing a convention, show, or sale that includes at least 10 participants shall pay a license fee and obtain a license in accordance with the provisions of this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Transient vendors participating in a convention, show, or sale licensed according to this subsection may not be required to obtain a separate transient vendor's license.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">At least 30 days prior to the date of intended sale, each transient vendor shall furnish to the county commissioners of the county in which the vendor intends to do business a verified, written application that contains the following:<section prefix="(1)">The name and address of the applicant and the true owner, if not the applicant, of the goods, wares, or merchandise to be sold or exhibited for sale;</section><section prefix="(2)">The name and address of the employer of the applicant or the persons with whom the applicant is associated and the length of this employment or association;</section><section prefix="(3)">The nature and place of employment of the applicant during the preceding 12 months;</section><section prefix="(4)">An estimate of the length of time and exact location in which the applicant will pursue the activities contained in this section; if a fixed site is occupied, then the address of the property owner;</section><section prefix="(5)">The names and addresses of at least 3 individuals who have known that applicant for at least 1 year and who will verify the facts contained in the application;</section><section prefix="(6)">The applicant's Maryland State sales and use tax number;</section><section prefix="(7)">The address of any permanent place of business in the State, or a copy of the certificate from the State Department of Assessments and Taxation stating that the applicant has qualified to do business in the State, and the name and address of the applicant's agent;</section><section prefix="(8)">If the applicant is an individual, partnership, or corporation, proof that the individual or partnership is qualified to do business in and has obtained all necessary permits and licenses from the State and county for the operation of the business;</section><section prefix="(9)">A description of the nature of the business and goods, wares, or merchandise intended for sale or the catalog from which they can be ordered;</section><section prefix="(10)">A description and motor vehicle tag number of any vehicle used in connection with the applicant's activities;</section><section prefix="(11)">A statement as to whether the applicant has ever been convicted of a felony or misdemeanor and, if so, the nature of the offense, when and where convicted, and the penalty or punishment imposed;</section><section prefix="(12)">The place where the goods, wares, or merchandise are manufactured, their location at the time of the filing of this application, and the proposed method of delivery; and</section><section prefix="(13)">Any additional information which the county commissioners may require.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(h)">
      <section prefix="(1)">An applicant for a transient vendor's license shall execute and file a bond in the amount of $10,000 with the county commissioners of the county in which the vendor intends to do business along with a surety qualified to do business in the State and approved by the county commissioners of that county.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The bond shall be payable to the extent of any taxes, fees, or fines.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The surety shall indemnify a purchaser who suffers a loss by reason of defective merchandise or misrepresentation.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The bond shall provide that the county commissioners of the county in which the vendor intends to do business may file suit in their own name against the licensee or surety on the bond for taxes, fees, or fines due from the licensee that are not paid within 30 days of the termination of the sale or license.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">The bond shall provide that a purchaser at a sale may maintain an action against a licensee or surety for claims arising from the sale.</section>
      <section prefix="(6)">The bond shall continue in effect for 1 year after the termination of the transient vendor's license, and until all actions are concluded and judgments have been satisfied or until the amount of bond has been exhausted by these payments.</section>
      <section prefix="(7)">The bond shall be in addition to all deposits, license fees, permit fees, or other requirements under the law of the county in which the vendor intends to do business.</section>
      <section prefix="(8)">The applicant shall deposit a sum of cash which is equivalent to the full amount that would be due for the license based on the estimated time that the license will be required.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(i)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The county commissioners of the county in which the vendor intends to do business shall verify the statements made by the applicant contained in the application for the license.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If a false statement is contained in the application, the license may be denied and if denied, a refund shall be made, less administrative costs.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(j)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If the county commissioners of the county in which the vendor intends to do business approve the application and the surety bond, and the license fee is paid, the county commissioners of that county shall issue the license within 20 days of the application date.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The license shall be for the duration and term applied for in the application, and shall terminate automatically.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(k)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A transient vendor shall pay the following license fee to each county in which the vendor intends to do business before commencing business:<section prefix="(i)">A minimum of $1,000, which shall cover a period of 1 month or less from the date of issuance; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">The sum of $500 for each additional month or portion of a month.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The maximum amount payable for a license shall be $3,500.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The license shall be issued for 1 year or less.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(l)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A transient vendor may not engage in business without first obtaining the necessary license required under this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">This section does not exempt a vendor from obtaining any other license or permit of the United States, the State, the county in which the vendor intends to do business, or the City of Hagerstown if the vendor intends to do business in Hagerstown, or from being subjected to liability, tax liability, or any other regulations that may be applicable in the United States, the State, the county in which the vendor intends to do business, or the City of Hagerstown if the vendor intends to do business in Hagerstown.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Unless otherwise permitted by law, a licensed transient vendor may not sell goods, wares, or merchandise on Sunday.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(m)">A person who engages in a transient business in violation of this section is guilty of a misdemeanor and on conviction, shall be subject to a fine not to exceed $2,500 or imprisonment for not more than 1 year, or both.</section>
    <section prefix="(n)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In Washington County, law enforcement personnel from the City of Hagerstown if the vendor intends to do business in Hagerstown, Washington County, and the State may enforce compliance with the provisions of this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">In Carroll County, law enforcement personnel from the State, Carroll County, or any municipal corporation in Carroll County may enforce compliance with the provisions of this section within their respective jurisdictions.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(o)">The County Commissioners of Carroll County may adopt regulations to:<section prefix="(1)">Implement the provisions of this section;</section><section prefix="(2)">Protect against persons who attempt to avoid the requirements of this section or any other law or regulation relating to transient vendors;</section><section prefix="(3)">Require persons engaging in business to prove that they are not transient vendors; and</section><section prefix="(4)">Require a person engaging in business to post the bond or other security required by this section until the person has engaged in business for 1 year and has paid all taxes due as a result of engaging in that business.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
