<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="g24" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="16-103" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>g24-16-103</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The amount of benefit payable on account of the death of an officer or a civilian employee whose death is proximately caused by injuries sustained or by harm inflicted upon the body in the course of the performance of their duty shall be $10,000 or such greater amount as may be prospectively and uniformly established by resolution adopted by the board. The amount of benefit payable on account of the death of an officer or a civilian employee whose death is not proximately caused by injuries sustained or by harm inflicted upon the body in the course of the performance of their duty shall be $500 or such greater amount as may be prospectively and uniformly established by resolution adopted by the board. The benefits under this title shall be in addition to all other benefits provided by law or by voluntary action of any person or persons.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The said benefit shall be paid only to the following, and in the following order: to the decedent's widow or widower, if any, and if there is no widow or widower, to the decedent's children under 18 years of age, if any, in equal shares; and if there is no widow or widower or minor children, to the decedent's dependent parents, if any, in equal shares; and if there is no widow, widower, minor children, or dependent parents, then to any other dependents or the estate of the decedent (and in such amounts up to the maximum benefit, and in such proportions) as the trustees in their discretion determine. Payments due a minor shall be made to the minor's legal guardian, if any, in this State, and if none, to such person or persons on behalf of the minor at such times and amounts, and subject to such conditions, as the board of trustees may determine. Eligibility shall not be affected by whether the decedent has paid into the Fund.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The benefits provided hereunder shall not be subject to execution, garnishment, attachment, or any other process whatever; and they shall not be subject to assignment until actually paid over into the hands of the beneficiary.</section>
  </text>
</law>
