<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="g24" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="12-103" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>g24-12-103</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Commission consists of 7 members.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Subject to subsection (d) of this section, the Commission shall be comprised of:<section prefix="(1)">One member from the Democratic Central Committee of Allegany County;</section><section prefix="(2)">One member from the Republican Central Committee of Allegany County;</section><section prefix="(3)">One member of the Allegany County Chamber of Commerce;</section><section prefix="(4)">One member of the Allegany County Fire and Rescue Association;</section><section prefix="(5)">One member of the Farm Bureau of Allegany County;</section><section prefix="(6)">One member of the League of Women Voters of Allegany County; and</section><section prefix="(7)">One member of the Western Maryland Central Labor Council.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The County Commissioners shall solicit each organization listed in subsection (b) of this section before July 15, 1992, and before July 15 every 4th year thereafter, requesting that the organization recommend an appointee to the County Commissioners by August 1.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The County Commissioners shall appoint the Commission members recommended by each organization.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If any organization fails to recommend an appointee to the County Commissioners by August 1, the County Commissioners shall appoint a substitute citizen member to the Commission to serve through the following January 30.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A member of the Commission appointed under paragraph (1) or (2) of this subsection may not be:<section prefix="(i)">An Allegany County official or an employee of Allegany County; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">An official or employee of any office studied by the Commission.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The County Commissioners shall make their appointments to the Commission final before September 30, 1992, and before September 30 every 4th year thereafter.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">A member of the Commission may not receive compensation but is entitled to reimbursement for expenses as authorized by the County Commissioners.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">From among its members, the Commission shall elect a chairman.</section>
  </text>
</law>
