<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="g24" order_by="24" level="1">Political Subdivisions - Miscellaneous Provisions</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>g24-11-510</section_number>
  <catch_line>The provisions of this section are applicable only in Calvert County....</catch_line>
  <order_by>510</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The provisions of this section are applicable only in Calvert County.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Any dog found running at large without the proper license tag attached in accordance with the provisions of this subtitle is a nuisance and is subject to seizure, detention and destruction. The dog warden or his duly authorized deputies, whenever possible, shall seize and impound any dog found running at large without the proper license tag attached. When the dog warden or his duly authorized deputies are not able to catch a dog running at large without a license tag, they may shoot or otherwise kill the dog.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The County Commissioners may provide by ordinance that owners of dogs may not permit the dog, whether licensed or unlicensed, to run at large within the confines of any platted subdivision or district zoned residential, except when the dog is under the control of the owner or an authorized agent of the owner by leash, cord or chain. However, a petition requesting such an ordinance shall be submitted to the County Commissioners and signed by a majority of the residents of the platted subdivision or district zoned residential, with a designation of the boundary limits of the specific area. Further, the County Commissioners, after advertising the proposed ordinance and a public hearing on that ordinance for 2 consecutive weeks in 2 newspapers of general circulation in Calvert County, shall designate the boundary limits of each area as part of any enacted ordinance.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Any dog seized and impounded shall be held for its owner for a period of 72 hours. During this period any dog seized shall be released to the owner, or his duly authorized representative, upon satisfactory proof of ownership, tender of a fee in whatever amount the County Commissioners determine for the costs of seizure and impounding, and upon presentation of the license for the dog.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">Any owner who does not redeem his dog within 72 hours forfeits all rights of ownership and the dog shall be the property of Calvert County. The dog shall remain impounded for an additional 48 hours, during which time any person desiring may obtain ownership of the dog by tendering the fee for the costs of seizure and impounding and by purchasing a license.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">Any dog seized and not redeemed within 120 hours from time of its seizure may be killed by the dog warden or one of his duly authorized deputies. If it is killed, it shall be killed in the most humane manner possible.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">Whenever the County Commissioners are of the opinion that the health, welfare and safety of the citizens of Calvert County require, the Commissioners by resolution may provide for the quarantine of all dogs, and they may make whatever further rules and regulations concerning dogs they deem necessary.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">The County Commissioners may make from time to time all necessary rules and regulations for the sale of dog licenses, the keeping of records of those licenses, and the convenient and effective enforcement of these provisions.</section>
  </text>
</law>
