<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="g24" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="9-609" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>g24-9-609</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Gross receipts shortage" means the amount by which the property tax calculated under subsection (d)(2) of this section that would have been due exceeds the total gross receipts tax remitted under subsection (c) of this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Gross receipts surplus" means the amount by which the total gross receipts tax remitted under subsection (c) of this section exceeds the amount of property tax calculated under subsection (d)(2) of this section that would have been due.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">
        <section prefix="(i)">"Heavy equipment property" means construction, earthmoving, or industrial equipment that is mobile including any attachment for the heavy equipment.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">"Heavy equipment property" includes:</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(5)">"Short-term lease or rental" means the lease or rental of heavy equipment property for a period of 365 days or less.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">There is a tax at a rate of 2% on the gross receipts from the short-term lease or rental of heavy equipment property by a person whose principal business is the short-term lease or rental of heavy equipment property at retail.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The tax imposed under paragraph (1) of this subsection does not apply to a business located in a county or municipal corporation that does not impose a personal property tax.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A person is in the principal business of short-term lease or rental of heavy equipment property if:<section prefix="(i)">The largest segment of total rental receipts of the business is from the short-term lease or rental of heavy equipment property; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">The business is described under Code 532412 of the North American Industry Classification System as published by the United States Census Bureau.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A person who owns a business with gross receipts subject to the tax under subsection (b) of this section shall collect the tax from the rental customer and remit the tax as provided in this subsection.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The tax is payable quarterly and due by the last day of the month after the end of the quarter.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A person who owns a business with gross receipts subject to the tax under subsection (b) of this section shall remit the tax collected to:<section prefix="(i)">The county in which the business is located, if that location is not within a municipal corporation; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">The county and municipal corporation in which the business is located in proportion to the personal property tax rate of the county and municipal corporation, if that location is within a municipal corporation.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">Notwithstanding any other provision of law and except as otherwise provided in this section, the gross receipts tax imposed under this section shall be administered and collectible according to the laws otherwise applicable to the personal property tax under the Tax - Property Article.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A person who owns a business with gross receipts subject to the tax under subsection (b) of this section shall submit:<section prefix="(i)">To the Department of Assessments and Taxation a report on personal property as required under &#xA7; 11-101 of the Tax - Property Article; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">To the county or municipal corporation where the heavy equipment rental business is located a list of all personal property, including the original cost and date of acquisition of the property, that:</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">For each person that submits a list under paragraph (1)(ii) of this subsection, a county or municipal corporation shall calculate the amount of property tax that would have been due for all property that is exempt under &#xA7; 7-243 of the Tax - Property Article.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A county or municipal corporation shall calculate the difference between:<section prefix="(i)">The total gross receipts tax remitted under subsection (c) of this section by the person during the previous calendar year; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">The amount of property tax calculated under paragraph (2) of this subsection that would have been due.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">
        <section prefix="(i)">On or before February 28th of each year, a county or municipal corporation shall provide a statement to each person who owns a business with gross receipts subject to the tax under subsection (b) of this section, that includes:</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">If the statement includes a gross receipts shortage, the county or municipal corporation shall include with the statement a bill for the amount of the gross receipts shortage payable on or before March 31 of each year.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(5)">The list required under paragraph (1)(ii) of this subsection shall be submitted with the second quarterly payment required under subsection (c)(2) of this section.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
