<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="g24" order_by="" level="1">Political Subdivisions - Miscellaneous Provisions</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>g24-9-1401</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>1401</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, "governmental charge" means:<section prefix="(1)">Property taxes, any other tax, or any fee or charge collected by a county or municipal corporation; or</section><section prefix="(2)">Any additional charge collected by a county or municipal corporation in connection with property taxes, any other tax, or any fee or charge collected.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The governing body of a county or municipal corporation may allow a governmental charge to be paid by credit card or debit card.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The governing body of a county or municipal corporation shall determine:<section prefix="(i)">The types of governmental charges that may be paid by credit card or debit card; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">The types of credit cards or debit cards that will be accepted.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If a governmental charge is paid by use of a credit card or debit card, the governing body of the county or municipal corporation may provide that a service charge is to be added to the amount of governmental charge to be paid.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The amount of the service charge assessed under this subsection:<section prefix="(i)">May not exceed the amount of any fee that may be charged to the county or municipal government in connection with use of the card; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Shall be determined at the time the governmental charge is paid.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">In those counties and municipal corporations that elect to allow governmental charges to be paid by credit card or debit card, the governing body shall specify on or include notice with each property tax bill and other invoices for which payment by credit card or debit card is authorized:<section prefix="(1)">That a credit card or debit card may be used to pay the governmental charge;</section><section prefix="(2)">The types of credit and debit cards that may be used; and</section><section prefix="(3)">Whether a service charge will be added to the governmental charge if a credit or debit card is used.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
