<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="g24" order_by="24" level="1">Political Subdivisions - Miscellaneous Provisions</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>g24-9-10A-01</section_number>
  <catch_line>The County Council of Harford County, by ordinance, may fix, impose, and provide for the collection ...</catch_line>
  <order_by>01</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The County Council of Harford County, by ordinance, may fix, impose, and provide for the collection of a development impact fee not to exceed $10,000 for new construction or development.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The County Treasurer shall deposit the revenues from the development impact fee into a special fund.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The revenues from the special fund may be used only for:<section prefix="(1)">School site acquisition;</section><section prefix="(2)">School construction;</section><section prefix="(3)">School renovation;</section><section prefix="(4)">School debt reduction; or</section><section prefix="(5)">School capital expenses.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A municipal corporation within Harford County shall assist the County Council in the collection of the development impact fee within the municipal corporation by:<section prefix="(1)">Collecting and remitting the fee to the county; or</section><section prefix="(2)">Requiring the fee to be paid to the county in accordance with the terms of the county ordinance.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">If a development impact fee is enacted under the authority granted to the County Council by subsection (a) of this section, the county shall:<section prefix="(1)">Cause an annual report to be prepared on the revenues generated by the development impact fee and how those revenues were spent; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Submit the report to the Harford County Delegation of the General Assembly on or before May 31 of each year.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
