<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="g24" order_by="24" level="1">Political Subdivisions - Miscellaneous Provisions</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>g24-9-608</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this section the following words have the meanings indicated....</catch_line>
  <order_by>608</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Hotel" has the meaning stated in &#xA7; 9-301 of this title.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Hotel rental tax" means the tax authorized under this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">
        <section prefix="(i)">"Transient charge" means a hotel charge for sleeping accommodations for a period not exceeding 4 consecutive months.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">"Transient charge" does not include any hotel charge for services or for accommodations other than sleeping accommodations.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Subject to paragraphs (2) and (3) of this subsection, a municipal corporation may impose, by ordinance or resolution, a tax on a transient charge paid to a hotel located in that municipal corporation.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">In this paragraph, "hotel rental tax revenue sharing arrangement" includes:<section prefix="1.">A requirement under the provisions of &#xA7; 9-318 of this title that a county distribute revenue from a county hotel rental tax to a municipal corporation; or</section><section prefix="2.">Any other hotel rental tax revenue sharing requirement, agreement, or arrangement between a county and a municipal corporation.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">A municipal corporation in a county that has a hotel rental tax revenue sharing arrangement between the municipal corporation and the county may not impose a hotel rental tax under this section.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A municipal corporation may not impose a tax on a transient charge paid to a hotel if:<section prefix="(i)">The hotel has 10 or fewer sleeping rooms; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">The municipal corporation is located within a county that:<section prefix="1.">Distributes at least 50% of total hotel tax revenues to promote tourism within the county; or</section><section prefix="2.">Does not impose a tax on a transient charge paid to a hotel.</section></section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Subject to paragraph (2) of this subsection, a municipal corporation shall set the rate of the hotel rental tax.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The hotel rental tax for a municipal corporation may not exceed 2%.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A municipal corporation that imposes a hotel rental tax may:<section prefix="(1)">Provide for the administration and collection of the tax;</section><section prefix="(2)">Provide for additional exemptions from the tax; and</section><section prefix="(3)">Impose penalties for failure to collect, report, or pay the tax.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">A municipal corporation that imposes a hotel rental tax under this section shall distribute to a convention and visitors bureau in the county where the municipal corporation is located at least the same percentage of the hotel rental tax collected that the county distributes to the convention and visitors bureau from any county hotel rental tax.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">If a county has the authority under Subtitle 3 of this title or any other provision of law to impose a tax on transient charges paid to hotels, to accommodate a tax imposed under this section by a municipal corporation the county may impose a tax rate on transient charges paid to hotels located within the municipal corporation that is lower than the tax rate imposed on transient charges paid to hotels outside the municipal corporation.</section>
  </text>
</law>
