<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="g24" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="9-1101" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>g24-9-1101</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Subject to subsection (d) of this section, for each fiscal year, the Comptroller shall distribute to a county the amount determined for each county under this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The amount a county shall receive under this section in any fiscal year shall be based on the county income tax collected from individuals for the taxable year that ended in the second prior fiscal year, from returns filed through November 1 immediately preceding the applicable fiscal year, as determined by the Comptroller.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">For each fiscal year, the Comptroller shall determine as rounded to the nearest cent:<section prefix="(i)">The per capita yield of the county income tax for each county, based on:</section><section prefix="(ii)">The per capita statewide yield of the county income tax, based on:</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Subject to subparagraph (ii) of this paragraph, if the per capita yield of the county income tax for a county determined under paragraph (1)(i) of this subsection is less than 75% of the per capita statewide yield of the county income tax determined under paragraph (1)(ii) of this subsection, the Comptroller shall determine the amount that would increase the county per capita yield to equal 75% of the statewide per capita yield, as rounded to the nearest dollar.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">For fiscal year 2012 only, if the per capita yield of the county income tax for a county determined under paragraph (1)(i) of this subsection is less than 77% of the per capita statewide yield of the county income tax determined under paragraph (1)(ii) of this subsection, the Comptroller shall determine the amount that would increase the county per capita yield to equal 77% of the statewide per capita yield, as rounded to the nearest dollar.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A county may not receive a distribution under this subsection if the county tax rate in that county was less than 2.4%:<section prefix="(i)">For the taxable year that ended in the second prior fiscal year; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">For any subsequent taxable year through the taxable year that ends in the current fiscal year.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Comptroller shall make payments of the additional amounts provided under this section quarterly during the fiscal year for which the payment is made.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">For fiscal year 2011 and each subsequent fiscal year, the distribution provided to any county or Baltimore City under this section may not exceed the amount distributed to the county or Baltimore City for fiscal year 2010.</section>
  </text>
</law>
