<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="g24" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="16-105" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>g24-16-105</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The board of trustees shall consist of nine members; one member of the rank of major or higher, one deputy major, one lieutenant, one sergeant, three patrolmen, one civilian employee of the Department, and the Director of Fiscal Affairs Division. With the exception of the Director of Fiscal Affairs, members of the board of trustees shall be elected at large, and shall serve a term of 4 years. Elections will be held biannually with the terms of the major or higher rank, sergeant and two patrolmen terminating at alternate 2-year periods with those of the deputy major, lieutenant, one patrolman and civilian representative. The first election will be held during the year of enactment of this title, at which time the deputy major, lieutenant, and one patrolman (the patrolman member of the board of trustees having held office the longest period of time will stand for election) and the civilian member will be elected.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">In years when elections are to be held, nominations will be submitted to the secretary of the board of trustees in writing and signed by not less than 20 members of the Department; and no more than half of the persons signing the nomination may be from the same district or unit. Nominations must be received by the secretary not less than 15 days prior to the date established for such election. The nominees corresponding with the number of members to be elected who receive the highest number of votes shall be declared elected. Persons so elected shall serve a term of 4 years and until their respective successors are elected and qualified. Election of members to the board of trustees of the Death Relief Fund may be held concurrent with the election of members to the Personnel Service Board as provided in the Code of Public Local Laws of Baltimore City, 1979 Edition, &#xA7; 16-12.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">In the event an elected member dies, resigns, retires, or ceases to be a member of the Department, the member's vacated position will be filled from those nominees of comparable rank or status who received the next highest number of votes in descending order from those nominees actually elected during the preceding election, and this member will serve the uncompleted term of the member whom he replaces. In the event there is no such nominee available, the board of trustees shall elect from the Department at large a member of the same rank to serve instead until the next scheduled election at which time a replacement shall be elected in accordance with the foregoing procedure.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The trustees shall serve without compensation, but they shall be reimbursed from the Fund for all necessary expenses they may incur through service on the board.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Each trustee, within 10 days after the commencement of the trustee's term, shall take an oath of office that the trustee will diligently and faithfully perform the duties of trustee in accordance with law. Such oath shall be administered by the Clerk of the Circuit Court for Baltimore City, subscribed by the member making it, and filed in said Clerk's office.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The board of trustees shall act by majority vote. Five members shall constitute a quorum for all purposes. Each member of the board shall be entitled to one vote. The board shall elect its own officers.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The board of trustees shall keep a record of all its proceedings which shall be open to public inspection. It shall provide, if requested, an opportunity for a full hearing, including the right to counsel and cross-examination for all interested parties in any proceeding as to any benefit, or any part thereof, provided herein. The board, through its member presiding at any hearing, shall have the power to administer oaths and may apply to the circuit court of any county for a subpoena for any witness, which shall be granted by the court upon finding that the evidence of said witness is necessary to provide a fair hearing, and that requiring attendance by the witness would not be oppressive. The board may expend from the Fund such amounts as may be necessary for the conduct of its proceedings, including but not limited to expenses for investigation, medical or other advice, stenographic service, and the like. The legal adviser to the Baltimore City Police Department shall be the legal adviser to the board, and shall upon request by the board, assist and advise the board during the conduct of any hearing.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">The board of trustees may establish rules and regulations, consistent with this title with respect to the amount of benefits, the administration of the Fund created by this title, and the transaction of its business.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">The board of trustees shall have the power to sue and be sued as an entity in any court of this State or any other state or federal jurisdiction. The board shall adopt an official seal.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">No trustee shall be liable for the conduct of any predecessor, cotrustee, or any agent, representative, custodian, or depository selected with reasonable care, but only for his own negligence or default.</section>
  </text>
</law>
