<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="g24" order_by="24" level="1">Political Subdivisions - Miscellaneous Provisions</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>g24-24-405</section_number>
  <catch_line>Except as otherwise provided in this title, the City of Takoma Park may impose an ad valorem tax on ...</catch_line>
  <order_by>405</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Except as otherwise provided in this title, the City of Takoma Park may impose an ad valorem tax on all property assessed for tax purposes within the city at a rate required to produce the amount needed to pay for:<section prefix="(1)">Maintenance of stormwater management systems in the city that were maintained by the Commission before July 1, 1990, and systems established by the city on or after July 1, 1990;</section><section prefix="(2)">The principal and interest that becomes due and owing to:<section prefix="(i)">The bondholders during the following year and the proportionate part of the principal of all outstanding sinking fund bonds, as determined by the table of redemption of bonds for bonds issued by or on behalf of the city on or after July 1, 1990, for stormwater management under this title; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Prince George's County with respect to the repayment of any loan made by the county to the City of Takoma Park under &#xA7; 24-302(b) of this title; and</section></section><section prefix="(3)">The cost of stormwater management activities and practices in the city, as approved in the city's annual stormwater management budget and appropriations resolution for the following fiscal year.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">In lieu of the ad valorem taxes authorized by subsection (a) of this section, the City of Takoma Park may adopt a stormwater management utility fee system or user charges to pay the costs of stormwater management activities and projects based on factors such as land use, amount of runoff, conservation, and environmental and other considerations.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, the taxes authorized by this section shall be imposed and collected in the same manner, have the same priority, bear the same interest, and be treated in all respects as other taxes imposed by the City of Takoma Park.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Notwithstanding any provision of the charter, laws, or ordinances of the City of Takoma Park, the taxes may not be subject to a limitation on the tax rate or tax revenues of the city.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The tax revenues, user charges, and utility fees shall be deposited and maintained in a separate stormwater management fund established under &#xA7; 24-408 of this subtitle.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
