<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="g24" order_by="" level="1">Political Subdivisions - Miscellaneous Provisions</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>g24-24-402</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>402</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In the stormwater management district, Prince George's County may require an owner or developer of a subdivision or tract of land on which buildings are to be erected to contribute what the county determines to be a fair share of the cost of a stormwater management project before the county approves or constructs the project.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">In the City of Bowie, the city may require an owner or developer of a subdivision or tract of land on which buildings are to be erected to contribute what the city determines to be a fair share of the cost of a stormwater management project before the city approves or constructs the project.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">In the City of Takoma Park, the city may require an owner or developer of a subdivision or tract of land on which buildings are to be erected to contribute what the City Council determines to be a fair share of the cost of a stormwater management project in the city's jurisdiction before the City Council approves the project for construction.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">In Montgomery County, except for property within the City of Takoma Park, the Montgomery County Council may require an owner or developer of a subdivision or tract of land on which buildings are to be erected to contribute what the County Council determines to be a fair share of the cost of a stormwater management project in the county's jurisdiction before the County Council approves the project for construction.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">Before construction begins, the contribution shall be paid in cash or secured to the satisfaction of the approving authority.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Montgomery County, Prince George's County, the City of Bowie, and the City of Takoma Park each may construct within its boundaries any part of an approved stormwater management project if the owner or developer contributes a share of the cost of the project considered appropriate by the approving authority.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Montgomery County, Prince George's County, the City of Bowie, and the City of Takoma Park each shall include in its annual capital budget for stormwater management capital projects an amount representing anticipated contributions to stormwater management.</section>
  </text>
</law>
