<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="g24" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="5-101" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>g24-5-101</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, "electric company" has the meaning stated in &#xA7; 1-101 of the Public Utilities Article.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">On written request by a local government, an electric company shall sell to the local government some or all of the electric company's existing street lighting equipment that is located within the local jurisdiction.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">If the local government purchases street lighting equipment from an electric company, the local government shall pay to the electric company the fair market value of the street lighting equipment.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A local government that purchases the street lighting equipment in accordance with subsection (b) of this section shall be responsible for the maintenance of the street lighting equipment and may contract with an outside entity for the maintenance of the street lighting equipment.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Any person who controls the right to use space on any pole, lamppost, or other mounting surface previously used in the local jurisdiction by the electric company for street lighting equipment shall allow a local government that has purchased the street lighting equipment to assume the rights and obligations of the electric company with respect to the space for the unexpired term of any lease or other agreement under which the electric company used the space.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Notwithstanding paragraph (1) of this subsection, the local government may not restrict or prohibit universal access for electricity or any other service by assuming the rights and obligations of an electric company as to space on any pole, lamppost, or other mounting surface used for street lighting equipment.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Any dispute between an electric company and a local government arising under this subsection shall be submitted to the Public Service Commission for resolution.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
