<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="g24" order_by="24" level="1">Political Subdivisions - Miscellaneous Provisions</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>g24-9-1301</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this section the following words have the meanings indicated....</catch_line>
  <order_by>1301</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">"Bond" means a special obligation bond, revenue bond, note, or other similar instrument issued by the county in accordance with this section.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">"Bond" includes a special obligation bond, revenue bond, note, or similar instrument issued by the revenue authority of Prince George's County.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Cost" includes the cost of:<section prefix="(i)">Construction, reconstruction, and renovation, and acquisition of all lands, structures, real or personal property, rights, rights-of-way, franchises, easements, and interests acquired or to be acquired by the Maryland Economic Development Corporation, or the State, any unit or department or political subdivision of the State, or any other governmental unit having jurisdiction of the infrastructure improvement;</section><section prefix="(ii)">All machinery and equipment including machinery and equipment needed to expand or enhance county services to the special taxing district;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Financing charges and interest prior to and during construction, and, if deemed advisable by the county, for a limited period after completion of the construction, interest and reserves for principal and interest, including costs of municipal bond insurance and any other type of financial guaranty and costs of issuance;</section><section prefix="(iv)">Extensions, enlargements, additions, and improvements;</section><section prefix="(v)">Architectural, engineering, financial, and legal services;</section><section prefix="(vi)">Plans, specifications, studies, surveys, and estimates of cost and of revenues;</section><section prefix="(vii)">Administrative expenses necessary or incident to determining to proceed with the infrastructure improvements; and</section><section prefix="(viii)">Other expenses as may be necessary or incident to the construction, acquisition, and financing of the infrastructure improvements.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">In Prince George's County, "cost" includes the cost of renovation, rehabilitation, and repair of existing buildings, internal and external structural systems, elevators, facades, mechanical systems and components, and security systems.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">"MEDCO obligation" means any bond, note, or other similar instrument that the Maryland Economic Development Corporation issues under authority other than this section to finance the purposes specified in subsection (c)(2) or (e)(3) of this section only with respect to infrastructure improvements located in or supporting a transit-oriented development or a State hospital redevelopment.</section>
      <section prefix="(6)">"State hospital redevelopment" means any combination of private or public commercial, residential, or recreational uses, improvements, and facilities that:<section prefix="(i)">Is part of a comprehensive coordinated development plan or strategy involving:<section prefix="1.">Property that was occupied formerly by a State facility, as defined in &#xA7; 10-101 of the Health - General Article, or a State residential center, as defined in &#xA7; 7-101 of the Health - General Article; or</section><section prefix="2.">Property that is adjacent or reasonably proximate to property that was occupied formerly by a State facility, as defined in &#xA7; 10-101 of the Health - General Article, or a State residential center, as defined in &#xA7; 7-101 of the Health - General Article;</section></section><section prefix="(ii)">In accordance with design development principles, maximizes use of the property by those constituencies it is intended to serve; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Is designated as a State hospital redevelopment by:<section prefix="1.">The Smart Growth Subcabinet established under &#xA7; 9-1406 of the State Government Article; and</section><section prefix="2.">The local government or multicounty agency with land use and planning responsibility for the relevant area.</section></section></section>
      <section prefix="(7)">"Transit-oriented development" has the meaning stated in &#xA7; 7-101 of the Transportation Article.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">This section applies only to Anne Arundel County, Baltimore County, Calvert County, Cecil County, Charles County, Garrett County, Harford County, Howard County, Prince George's County, St. Mary's County, Washington County, and Wicomico County.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Subject to the provisions of this section, and for the purpose stated in paragraph (2) of this subsection, the county may:<section prefix="(i)">Create a special taxing district;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Levy ad valorem or special taxes; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Issue bonds and other obligations.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The purpose of the authority granted under paragraph (1) of this subsection is to provide financing, refinancing, or reimbursement for the cost of the design, construction, establishment, extension, alteration, or acquisition of adequate storm drainage systems, sewers, water systems, roads, bridges, culverts, tunnels, streets, sidewalks, lighting, parking, parks and recreation facilities, libraries, schools, transit facilities, solid waste facilities, and other infrastructure improvements as necessary, whether situated within the special taxing district or outside the special taxing district if the infrastructure improvement is reasonably related to other infrastructure improvements within the special taxing district, for the development and utilization of the land, each with respect to any defined geographic region within the county.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The authority granted under paragraph (1)(i) and (ii) of this subsection also makes available a source of funding for payment of costs of:<section prefix="1.">Infrastructure improvements located in or supporting a transit-oriented development or a State hospital redevelopment; and</section><section prefix="2.">Operation and maintenance of infrastructure improvements located in or supporting a transit-oriented development or a State hospital redevelopment.</section></section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A law enacted by Anne Arundel County under the authority of this section:<section prefix="(i)">Shall specify the types of infrastructure and related costs that may be financed;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Shall require:<section prefix="1.">Reasonable disclosure in the real estate contract to buyers of real property within a special taxing district of any special assessment, special tax, or other fee or charge for which the buyer would be liable due to the special taxing district;</section><section prefix="2.">That a seller's failure to provide the disclosure required under subitem 1 of this item renders the contract voidable at the option of the buyer before the date of settlement; and</section><section prefix="3.">That adequate debt service reserve funds be maintained;</section></section><section prefix="(iii)">May not allow:<section prefix="1.">Acceleration of assessments or taxes by reason of bond default; or</section><section prefix="2.">An increase in the maximum special assessments, special taxes, or other fees or charges applicable to any individual property in the event that other property owners become delinquent in the payment of a special assessment, special tax, or other fee or charge securing special obligation debt issued under this section; and</section></section><section prefix="(iv)">May provide:<section prefix="1.">For exemptions, deferrals, and credits; and</section><section prefix="2.">That a lien attaches to property within a special taxing district to the extent of that property owner's obligation under any special taxing district financing.</section></section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Charles County may exercise the authority granted under this section only in commercial or light industrial zones.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">Charles County may exercise the authority granted under this section to:<section prefix="1.">Impose hotel rental taxes; and</section><section prefix="2.">Provide financing, refinancing, or reimbursement of costs for the purposes under paragraph (2) of this subsection relating to the development of resort hotels and conference centers within a waterfront planned community.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">Charles County may not impose a hotel rental tax under this paragraph outside a special taxing district established under this section.</section>
        <section prefix="(iv)">
          <section prefix="1.">The hotel rental tax authorized under this paragraph is in addition to the hotel rental tax authorized under Subtitle 3 of this title.</section>
          <section prefix="2.">The rate of the hotel rental tax authorized under this paragraph may not exceed the rate of the hotel rental tax imposed under Subtitle 3 of this title in effect on the date the governing body of Charles County creates a special taxing district under this section.</section>
        </section>
        <section prefix="(v)">The proceeds from the hotel rental tax authorized under this paragraph may be used only for the purposes authorized under this section.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(5)">Prince George's County may exercise the authority granted in this subsection to:<section prefix="(i)">Levy hotel rental taxes; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Provide financing, refinancing, or reimbursement for the costs of:<section prefix="1.">Convention centers, conference centers, and visitors' centers;</section><section prefix="2.">Maintenance of infrastructure improvements, convention centers, conference centers, and visitors' centers;</section><section prefix="3.">Marketing the special taxing district facilities and other improvements; and</section><section prefix="4.">Renovation, rehabilitation, and repair of existing buildings, building systems, and components for existing residential condominiums designated as workforce housing as defined in &#xA7; 4-1801 of the Housing and Community Development Article.</section></section></section>
      <section prefix="(6)">
        <section prefix="(i)">This paragraph applies only to Harford County.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">
          <section prefix="1.">Except as provided in subsubparagraph 2 of this subparagraph, the county may exercise the authority granted under this section only in designated growth areas as defined in the county Master Plan and Land Use Element Plan.</section>
          <section prefix="2.">The county may not exercise the authority granted under this section in any of the county's rural villages.</section>
        </section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">A law creating a special taxing district shall be enacted by a bill adopted by the county governing body.</section>
        <section prefix="(iv)">At the public hearing on a bill creating a special taxing district, the county governing body may consider, among other things, the following elements of a proposed development that would receive the proceeds of a proposed bond under this section:<section prefix="1.">Development design standards;</section><section prefix="2.">The use of transfer of development rights or other methods of achieving density of development;</section><section prefix="3.">Design and usage of open space; and</section><section prefix="4.">Availability and design of recreational and educational facilities.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(v)">A law enacted by the county creating a special taxing district shall require that adequate debt service reserve funds be maintained.</section>
        <section prefix="(vi)">Notwithstanding subsection (d) of this section, before the county may establish a special taxing district, all of the owners of real property within the proposed special taxing district must petition the county for the creation of the special taxing district.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(7)">
        <section prefix="(i)">This paragraph applies only to Cecil County.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The county may exercise the authority granted under this section only in designated growth areas as defined in the county comprehensive plan.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">The county shall hold at least one public hearing on a bill creating a special taxing district.</section>
        <section prefix="(iv)">At a public hearing on a bill creating a special taxing district, the county governing body may consider the following elements of a proposed development that would receive the proceeds of a proposed bond under this section:<section prefix="1.">Development design standards;</section><section prefix="2.">The use of transfer of development rights or other methods of increasing the density of development;</section><section prefix="3.">Design and usage of open space; and</section><section prefix="4.">Availability and design of recreational and educational facilities.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(v)">A law enacted by the county under the authority of this section shall require that adequate debt service reserve funds be maintained.</section>
        <section prefix="(vi)">Notwithstanding subsection (d) of this section, before the county may establish a special taxing district, all of the owners of real property within the proposed special taxing district must petition the county for the creation of the special taxing district.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In addition to other powers the county may have, and notwithstanding the provisions of any other public local law, public general law, or the county charter of a county that has adopted home rule powers under Article XI-A of the Maryland Constitution, the county may borrow money by issuing and selling bonds for the purpose stated in subsection (c)(2) of this section if a request to the county is made by both:<section prefix="(i)">The owners of at least two-thirds of the assessed valuation of the real property located within the special taxing district; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">At least two-thirds of the owners of the real property located within the special taxing district, provided that:<section prefix="1.">Multiple owners of a single parcel are treated as a single owner; and</section><section prefix="2.">A single owner of multiple parcels is treated as one owner.</section></section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">This section is self-executing and does not require the county to enact legislation or, if applicable, to amend its charter to exercise the powers granted under this section.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Bonds shall be payable from the special fund required under subsection (f) of this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If the governing body of the county issues bonds under this section, the governing body may also:<section prefix="(i)">Establish sinking funds;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Establish debt service reserve funds;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Pledge other assets and revenues towards the payments of the principal and interest; or</section><section prefix="(iv)">Provide for municipal bond insurance or any other type of financial guaranty of the bonds.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">All proceeds received from any bonds issued and sold shall be applied solely to pay the cost of infrastructure improvements, including:<section prefix="(i)">Costs of design, construction, establishment, extension, alteration, or acquisition of infrastructure improvements;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Costs of issuing bonds;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Payment of the principal and interest on loans, money advances, or indebtedness incurred by the county for any of the purposes stated in subsection (c)(2) of this section, including the refunding of bonds previously issued under this section; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">Funding of a debt service reserve fund or payment of interest prior to, during, or for a limited period of time after construction.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The governing body of the county may:<section prefix="1.">Designate by resolution an area or areas as a special taxing district;</section><section prefix="2.">Subject to paragraph (2) of this subsection, adopt a resolution creating a special fund with respect to the special taxing district; and</section><section prefix="3.">Provide for the levy of an ad valorem or special tax on all real and personal property within the special taxing district at a rate or amount designed to provide adequate revenues to pay the principal of, interest on, and redemption premium, if any, on the bonds, to replenish any debt service reserve fund, and for any other purpose related to the ongoing expenses of or security for the bonds, and, as the governing body of the county determines, to:</section></section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">Ad valorem taxes shall be levied in the same manner, upon the same assessments, for the same period or periods, and as of the same date or dates of finality as are now or may hereafter be prescribed for general ad valorem tax purposes within the district.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">Special taxes shall be levied pursuant to subsection (o) of this section.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The resolution creating a special fund under paragraph (1)(i)2 of this subsection shall:<section prefix="(i)">Pledge to the special fund the proceeds of the ad valorem or special tax to be levied as provided under paragraph (1)(i)3 of this subsection; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Require that the proceeds from the tax be paid into the special fund.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">In Charles County, the taxes provided under this subsection for payment of the bonds and pledged to the special fund may include the hotel rental tax authorized under subsection (c)(4) of this section.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, when no bonds authorized by this section and no MEDCO obligations described in paragraph (3) of this subsection are outstanding with respect to a special taxing district and the governing body of the county determines not to use moneys in the special fund for payment of costs of infrastructure improvements located in or supporting a transit-oriented development or a State hospital redevelopment, or the payment of costs of operation and maintenance of infrastructure improvements located in or supporting a transit-oriented development or a State hospital redevelopment:<section prefix="(i)">The special taxing district shall be terminated; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Any moneys remaining in the special fund on the date of termination of the special taxing district shall be paid to the general fund of the county.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">When no bonds authorized by this section are outstanding with respect to a special taxing district and the governing body of the county so determines, moneys in the special fund may be:<section prefix="(i)">Used for any of the purposes described in this section;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Accumulated for payment of debt service on bonds subsequently issued under this section;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Used to pay or reimburse the county for debt service that the county is obligated to pay or has paid, either as a general or limited obligation on MEDCO obligations or any bond, note, or other similar instrument issued by the State, by any unit, department, or political subdivision of the State, or by the Revenue Authority of Prince George's County, the proceeds of which have been used for any of the purposes specified in this section; or</section><section prefix="(iv)">Paid to the county to provide funds to be used for any legal purpose as the governing body of the county may determine.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">A county that has created a special fund for a special taxing district may pledge, under an agreement, that amounts deposited to the special fund shall, as the governing body of the county may determine, be paid over to:<section prefix="1.">Secure payment on MEDCO obligations;</section><section prefix="2.">Provide for the payment of costs of infrastructure improvements located in or supporting a transit-oriented development or a State hospital redevelopment; and</section><section prefix="3.">Provide for the payment of costs of operation and maintenance of infrastructure improvements located in or supporting a transit-oriented development or a State hospital redevelopment.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The agreement shall:<section prefix="1.">Be authorized by ordinance or resolution of the county;</section><section prefix="2.">Be in writing;</section><section prefix="3.">Be executed on behalf of the county making the pledge, the Maryland Economic Development Corporation, and the other persons or entities that the governing body of the county determines; and</section><section prefix="4.">Run to the benefit of and be enforceable on behalf of the holders of any MEDCO obligations secured by the agreement.</section></section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(h)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In order to implement the authority conferred upon it by this section to issue bonds, the governing body of the county shall adopt an ordinance or resolution that:<section prefix="(i)">Specifies and describes the proposed undertaking and states that it has complied with subsection (f) of this section;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Specifies the maximum principal amount of bonds to be issued;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Specifies the maximum rate or rates of interest for the bonds; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">Agrees to a covenant to levy upon all real and personal property within the special taxing district ad valorem taxes or special taxes in rate and amount at least sufficient in each year in which any of the bonds are outstanding to provide for the payment of the principal of and the interest on the bonds.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The ordinance or resolution may specify or may authorize its finance board or other appropriate financial officer, by resolution or ordinance, or its chief executive officer, by executive order, to specify any of the following as it deems appropriate to effect the financing of the proposed undertaking:<section prefix="(i)">The actual principal amount of the bonds to be issued;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The actual rate or rates of interest for the bonds;</section><section prefix="(iii)">The manner in which and the terms upon which the bonds are to be sold;</section><section prefix="(iv)">The manner in which and the times and places that the interest on the bonds is to be paid;</section><section prefix="(v)">The time or times that the bonds may be executed, issued, and delivered;</section><section prefix="(vi)">The form and tenor of the bonds and the denominations in which the bonds may be issued;</section><section prefix="(vii)">The manner in which and the times and places that the principal of the bonds is to be paid, within the limitations set forth in this section;</section><section prefix="(viii)">Provisions pursuant to which any or all of the bonds may be called for redemption prior to their stated maturity dates; or</section><section prefix="(ix)">Any other provisions not inconsistent with this section as shall be determined by the governing body of the county to be necessary or desirable to effect the financing of the proposed undertaking.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Except as may be required by the Maryland Constitution, an ordinance or resolution authorizing the bonds required under this subsection, an ordinance, resolution, or executive order passed or adopted in furtherance of the required ordinance or resolution, the bonds, the designation of a special taxing district, or the levy of a special ad valorem tax or special tax may not be subject to any referendum by reason of any other State or local law.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The ordinance or resolution authorizing the bonds required under this subsection, any ordinance, resolution, or executive order passed or adopted in furtherance of the required ordinance or resolution, the bonds, the designation of a special taxing district, or the levy of a special ad valorem tax or special tax shall be subject to the request of the landowners as specified under subsection (d)(1) of this section.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The special fund and any sinking fund established by the county to provide for the payment of the principal of or interest on any bonds issued by the county under the provisions of this section may not be invested by the fiscal officer of the county having custody of the special fund and any sinking fund except in the manner prescribed by Article 31, &#xA7;&#xA7; 6 and 7 of the Code. Any such fiscal officer having custody of the proceeds of sale of any such bonds may invest the proceeds, pending the expenditure thereof, as prescribed under the provisions of Article 95, &#xA7; 22 of the Code.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(i)">The principal amount of the bonds, the interest payable on the bonds, their transfer, and any income derived from the transfer, including any profit made in the sale or transfer of the bonds, shall be exempt from taxation by the State and by the counties and municipal corporations of the State but shall be included, to the extent required under Title 8, Subtitle 2 of the Tax - General Article, in computing the net earnings of financial institutions.</section>
    <section prefix="(j)">
      <section prefix="(1)">All bonds may be in bearer form or in coupon form or may be registrable as to principal alone or as to both principal and interest. Each of the bonds shall be deemed to be a security as defined in &#xA7; 8-102 of the Commercial Law Article, whether or not it is either one of a class or series or by its terms is divisible into a class or series of instruments.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">All bonds shall be signed manually or in facsimile by the chief executive officer of the county, and the seal of the county shall be affixed to the bonds and attested by the clerk or other similar administrative officer of the county. If any officer whose signature or countersignature appears on the coupons ceases to be such officer before delivery of the bonds, the officer's signature or countersignature shall nevertheless be valid and sufficient for all purposes the same as if the officer had remained in office until delivery.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">All bonds shall mature not later than 30 years from their date of issuance.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">All bonds shall be sold in the manner, either at public or private sale, and upon the terms as the governing body of the county deems best. Any contract for the acquisition of property may provide that payment shall be made in bonds. Bonds issued under this section are not subject to Article 31, &#xA7;&#xA7; 9, 10, and 11 of the Code.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(k)">Bonds issued under this section are securities:<section prefix="(1)">In which all public officers and public bodies of the State and its political subdivisions, all insurance companies, State banks and trust companies, national banking associations, savings banks, savings and loan associations, investment companies, executors, administrators, trustees and other fiduciaries may properly and legally invest funds, including capital in their control or belonging to them; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Which may properly and legally be deposited with and received by any State or county officer or any agency or political subdivision of the State for any purpose for which the deposit of bonds or obligations of the State is now or may hereafter be authorized by law.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(l)">The powers granted under this section shall be regarded as supplemental and additional to powers conferred by other laws, and may not be regarded as in derogation of any powers now existing, including powers provided in Article 25, Article 25A, or Article 25B of the Code.</section>
    <section prefix="(m)">This section, being necessary for the welfare of the State and its residents, shall be liberally construed to effect the purpose stated in subsection (c)(2) of this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(n)">Unless otherwise provided in the charter, if any, bylaws, or code of the county, before adopting an ordinance or resolution that designates a special taxing district, authorizes the issuance of bonds, or levies ad valorem taxes or special taxes under the provisions of this section may be finally enacted, the county governing body shall hold a public hearing after giving not less than 10-days' notice in a newspaper of general circulation in the county.</section>
    <section prefix="(o)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">As an alternative to levying ad valorem taxes under this section, the governing body of the county may levy special taxes on property in a special taxing district to cover the cost of infrastructure improvements.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">In addition to levying ad valorem taxes or special taxes under this section, Charles County may impose a hotel rental tax in a special taxing district to provide financing, refinancing, or reimbursement of costs for the purposes under subsection (c)(2) of this section relating to the development of resort hotels and conference centers within a waterfront planned community.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">In determining the basis for and amount of a tax imposed under paragraph (1)(i) of this subsection, the cost of an improvement may be calculated and levied:<section prefix="(i)">Equally per front foot, lot, parcel, dwelling unit, or square foot;</section><section prefix="(ii)">According to the value of the property as determined by the governing body, with or without regard to improvements on the property; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">In any other reasonable manner that results in fairly allocating the cost of the infrastructure improvements.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The governing body of the county may provide by ordinance or resolution for:<section prefix="(i)">A maximum amount to be assessed with respect to any parcel of property located within a special taxing district;</section><section prefix="(ii)">A tax year or other date after which no further special taxes under this section shall be levied or collected on a parcel; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">The circumstances under which the special tax levied against any parcel may be increased, if at all, as a consequence of delinquency or default by the owner of that parcel or any other parcel within the special taxing district.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The governing body by ordinance or resolution may establish procedures allowing for the prepayment of special taxes under this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">Special taxes levied under this subsection shall be collected and secured in the same manner as general ad valorem taxes unless otherwise provided in the ordinance or resolution and shall be subject to the same penalties and the same procedure, sale, and lien priority in case of delinquency as is provided for general ad valorem taxes.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(p)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Before the county may designate an area wholly or partly within a municipal corporation as a special taxing district, the governing body of the municipal corporation must give its consent to the designation.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Before the county may designate an area wholly or partly within another county specified in subsection (b) of this section, the governing body of the other county must give its consent to the designation.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(q)">Bonds issued under this section are a special obligation of the county and may not constitute a general obligation debt of the county or a pledge of the county's full faith and credit or taxing power.</section>
  </text>
</law>
