<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="g24" order_by="" level="1">Political Subdivisions - Miscellaneous Provisions</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>g24-9-1103</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>1103</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">If on or before January 1, 2020, the Federal Nuclear Regulatory Commission license for the Calvert Cliffs Nuclear Power Plant expires and is not extended or renewed, for each of the 5 property tax years following the expiration and nonrenewal, the State shall pay as a grant to Calvert County an amount equal to the applicable percentage, determined under subsection (b) of this section, of the difference between:<section prefix="(1)">The product of multiplying $14,554,000 times the percentage specified for the taxable year under &#xA7; 7-237(b) of the Tax - Property Article; and</section><section prefix="(2)">The sum of:<section prefix="(i)">$2,000,000; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">The county's property tax revenue for the taxable year derived from personal property that is machinery or equipment used to generate electricity for sale.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">For each property tax year following the expiration and nonrenewal of the Federal Nuclear Regulatory Commission license for the Calvert Cliffs Nuclear Power Plant, the applicable percentage for purposes of determining the grants under this section is:<section prefix="(1)">100% for the first taxable year;</section><section prefix="(2)">80% for the second taxable year;</section><section prefix="(3)">60% for the third taxable year;</section><section prefix="(4)">40% for the fourth taxable year;</section><section prefix="(5)">20% for the fifth taxable year; and</section><section prefix="(6)">0% for each subsequent taxable year.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">For each taxable year for which a grant is to be provided under this section, the Department of Assessments and Taxation shall determine and certify to the Comptroller Calvert County's property tax revenue for the taxable year derived from personal property that is machinery or equipment used to generate electricity for sale.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Comptroller shall pay the amounts provided under this section to Calvert County in equal amounts for each quarter at the end of each quarter of the taxable year for which the payments are made.</section>
  </text>
</law>
