<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="g24" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="9-1302" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>g24-9-1302</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Cost" has the meaning stated in &#xA7; 9-1301 of this subtitle.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"County tax limitation" means a provision of a county charter that limits:<section prefix="(i)">The maximum property tax rate that a county may impose; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">The rate of growth of county property tax revenues.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">"County transportation improvements" includes:<section prefix="(i)">For county roads and highways:</section><section prefix="(ii)">For county transit facilities, any one or more or combination of tracks, rights-of-way, bridges, tunnels, subways, rolling stock, stations, terminals, ports, parking areas, equipment, fixtures, building structures, other real or personal property, and services incidental to or useful or designed for use in connection with the rendering of transit service by any means, including rail, bus, motor vehicle, or other mode of transportation but does not include any railroad facility.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(5)">"Highway facility" has the meaning stated in &#xA7; 3-101(f) of the Transportation Article.</section>
      <section prefix="(6)">"Special taxing district" means a defined geographic area designated by a county within which ad valorem or special taxes are imposed for the purpose of financing the cost of infrastructure improvements.</section>
      <section prefix="(7)">"State transportation improvements" includes highway facilities, transit facilities, and related infrastructure.</section>
      <section prefix="(8)">"Transit facility" has the meaning stated in &#xA7; 3-101(k) of the Transportation Article.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A county tax limitation that would otherwise apply to ad valorem or special taxes imposed only within a special taxing district does not apply for the purpose of financing the cost of State transportation improvements and county transportation improvements.</section>
  </text>
</law>
