<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="g24" order_by="24" level="1">Political Subdivisions - Miscellaneous Provisions</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>g24-1-112</section_number>
  <catch_line>Subject to paragraph (2) of this subsection, a county or municipal corporation may:...</catch_line>
  <order_by>112</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Subject to paragraph (2) of this subsection, a county or municipal corporation may:<section prefix="(i)">Pay the wage of an employee by direct deposit as provided in subsection (b) of this section; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Require an employee to receive the payment of wages by direct deposit as a condition of employment.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A county or municipal corporation may not require the payment of wages by direct deposit for an employee:<section prefix="(i)">Who was hired before October 1, 2011, unless the county or municipal corporation, before October 1, 2011, required by local law, regulation, or collective bargaining agreement, the payment of wages by direct deposit;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Whose employment is not conditioned on the employee receiving the payment of wages by direct deposit; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">Who:<section prefix="1.">Does not have a personal bank account; and</section><section prefix="2.">Informs the employee's employer that the employee wishes to opt out of direct deposit.</section></section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">If a county or municipal corporation elects to pay wages by direct deposit, an employee who is not required to receive the payment of wages by direct deposit may elect to receive the payment of wages by direct deposit in accordance with subsection (c) of this section.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">If a county or municipal corporation elects to pay the wages of its employees by direct deposit, the county or municipal corporation shall:<section prefix="(1)">Provide an employee who is required or elects to receive the payment of wages by direct deposit with an electronic fund transfer authorization form;</section><section prefix="(2)">Deposit the wage of an employee into a personal bank account selected by the employee on the electronic fund transfer authorization form; and</section><section prefix="(3)">Each time the county or municipal corporation pays the wage of an employee by direct deposit, provide the employee with a direct deposit statement that includes:<section prefix="(i)">The total amount of the wage;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Any amount deducted from the wage; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">The amount of the wage directly deposited into the personal bank account selected by the employee.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">An employee who is required or elects to receive the payment of wages by direct deposit shall complete and submit to the county or municipal corporation the electronic fund transfer authorization form provided to the employee under subsection (b) of this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">An employee who is required or elects to receive the payment of wages by direct deposit shall select a personal bank account for the direct deposit of the employee's wages that is at a financial institution that participates in the automated clearinghouse network.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Subject to paragraph (2) of this subsection, an employee may change the personal bank account or the financial institution designated on an electronic fund transfer authorization form by completing and submitting a new electronic fund transfer authorization form to the county or municipal corporation.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
