<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="g24" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="12-203" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>g24-12-203</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Commission consists of nine members.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Each member shall be a registered voter of Washington County who in the previous 4 years has voted in at least two elections, at least one of which shall have been in the gubernatorial election year.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Commission shall be comprised as follows:<section prefix="(1)">One member from the Democratic Party Central Committee of Washington County;</section><section prefix="(2)">One member from the Republican Party Central Committee of Washington County;</section><section prefix="(3)">One member from the Washington County Chamber of Commerce;</section><section prefix="(4)">One member from the Washington County Farm Bureau;</section><section prefix="(5)">One member from the League of Women Voters of Washington County;</section><section prefix="(6)">One member from the Western Maryland Central Labor Council;</section><section prefix="(7)">One member from the Cumberland Valley Associated Builders and Contractors, Inc.;</section><section prefix="(8)">One member from the Joint Veterans Council of Washington County; and</section><section prefix="(9)">One member at large selected by the Washington County Retired Teachers Association.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The County Commissioners shall solicit each organization listed in subsection (b) of this section before April 1, 1996, and before April 1 each fourth year thereafter, requesting that the organization recommend an appointee to the County Commissioners by May 15.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The County Commissioners shall appoint the individual recommended by each organization to the Commission.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The County Commissioners shall provide professional staff to the Commission as necessary for the Commission to issue its report.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The County Commissioners shall provide funds necessary for the Commission to advertise its hearings so that the public will receive sufficient notice and an opportunity to attend and present testimony at the hearings.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">If an organization fails to make a recommendation to the County Commissioners by June 1, the members who have been appointed to the Commission shall meet, solicit prospective members from the public, and select by majority vote a qualified substitute citizen member to the Commission to serve through the following December 1.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A member of the Commission may not be an elected official or an employee of an official whose salary the Commission studies.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">A member of the Commission may not receive compensation.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">From among its members, the Commission shall elect a chairman.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Commission shall hold at least one public hearing every 4 years.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Commission shall publish notice of each hearing in a newspaper of general circulation.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
