<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="g24" order_by="24" level="1">Political Subdivisions - Miscellaneous Provisions</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>g24-4-202</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated....</catch_line>
  <order_by>202</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Meeting" means the convening of a quorum of the constituent membership of a public agency to deliberate or act upon a matter over which the public agency has supervision, control, jurisdiction or advisory power.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Official action" means the phases of the process in which a decision or recommendation is reached including receipt of information, deliberation and decision of a public agency.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">"Public agency" includes:<section prefix="(1)">Any agency, assembly, authority, board, bureau, commission, committee, council, or department of St. Mary's County, except as provided in &#xA7; 4-209 of this subtitle, including advisory and quasi-judicial agencies, supported in whole or in part by public funds or authorized to expend public funds;</section><section prefix="(2)">The St. Mary's County Board of Education; and</section><section prefix="(3)">Subcommittees and other subordinate units of the agencies above.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"Public business" means all matters within the jurisdiction of a public agency which are before an agency for official action or which reasonably, foreseeably may come before that agency in the future.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">"Quorum" unless otherwise defined by applicable law, means a simple majority of the constituent membership of a public body.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">"Staff meeting" means a meeting of three or more staff members or a combination of three or more staff members of a public agency.</section>
  </text>
</law>
