<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="g24" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="9-326" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>g24-9-326</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">To protect hotel rental tax revenue, an authorized county may require a hotel to file security with that county in an amount that the county determines.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Cecil, Talbot, and Wicomico counties may require security under this section only if a hotel has been in default.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Security under this section shall be:<section prefix="(1)">A bond issued by a surety company that is:<section prefix="(i)">Authorized to do business in the State; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Approved by the Insurance Commissioner as to solvency and responsibility;</section></section><section prefix="(2)">Cash; or</section><section prefix="(3)">Securities approved by the county.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">If security is required under this section, the county shall give the hotel notice of the amount of security.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Within 5 days after a hotel receives notice that security is required, the hotel shall:<section prefix="(1)">File the security; or</section><section prefix="(2)">Submit a written request for a hearing on the security requirement.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If a hearing is requested, the county shall hold a hearing to determine the necessity, propriety, and amount of the security.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The determination at the hearing is final, and the hotel shall comply within 15 days after the hotel receives notice of the determination.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">Without notice to the hotel that files security under subsection (b)(2) or (3) of this section, the county at any time may:<section prefix="(1)">Apply the cash to the hotel rental tax due; or</section><section prefix="(2)">Sell the security and apply the proceeds of the sale to the hotel rental tax due.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
