<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="g24" order_by="" level="1">Political Subdivisions - Miscellaneous Provisions</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>g24-15-102.1</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>102.1</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, "distribute" means to:<section prefix="(1)">Give, sell, deliver, dispense, or issue;</section><section prefix="(2)">Offer to give, sell, deliver, dispense, or issue; or</section><section prefix="(3)">Cause or hire any person to give, sell, deliver, dispense, or issue or offer to give, sell, deliver, dispense, or issue.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">This section applies only in Garrett County, St. Mary's County, Carroll County, and Cecil County.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A person may not:<section prefix="(1)">Distribute any tobacco product to a minor, unless the minor is acting solely as the agent of the minor's employer who is engaged in the business of distributing tobacco products;</section><section prefix="(2)">Distribute cigarette rolling papers to a minor; or</section><section prefix="(3)">Subject to subsection (d) of this section, distribute to a minor a coupon redeemable for a tobacco product.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Subsection (c)(3) of this section does not apply to the distribution of a coupon that is redeemable for a tobacco product if the coupon:<section prefix="(1)">Is contained in a newspaper, magazine, or other type of publication and the coupon is incidental to the primary purpose of the publication; or</section><section prefix="(2)">Is sent through the mail.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">A person has not violated this section if:<section prefix="(1)">The person examined the driver's license or other valid government-issued identification presented by the recipient of a tobacco product, cigarette rolling paper, or coupon redeemable for a tobacco product; and</section><section prefix="(2)">The license or other identification positively identified the recipient as being at least 18 years old.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In Carroll County and St. Mary's County, a person who violates this section is committing a civil infraction and is subject to a civil penalty of:<section prefix="(i)">$300 for the first violation; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">$500 for any subsequent violation within a 24-month period from the previous citation.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">In Garrett County, a person who violates this section is committing a civil infraction and is subject to a civil penalty not exceeding $300.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">In Cecil County, a person who violates this section is committing a civil infraction and is subject to a civil penalty of:<section prefix="(i)">$300 for the first violation;</section><section prefix="(ii)">$500 for a second violation; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">$750 for each subsequent violation.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
