<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="g24" order_by="" level="1">Political Subdivisions - Miscellaneous Provisions</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>g24-9-1502</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>1502</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">A political subdivision may enact an ordinance or a resolution establishing a Clean Energy Loan Program.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The purpose of the Program is to provide loans to:<section prefix="(1)">Residential property owners, including low income residential property owners, for the financing of energy efficiency and renewable energy projects; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Commercial property owners for the financing of:<section prefix="(i)">Energy efficiency projects; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Renewable energy projects with an electric generating capacity of not more than 100 kilowatts.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Program shall require a property owner to repay a loan provided under the Program through a surcharge on the owner's property tax bill.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A surcharge shall be limited to an amount that allows the political subdivision to recover the costs associated with issuing bonds to finance the loan and costs associated with administering the Program.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A person who acquires property subject to a surcharge under this section, whether by purchase or other means, assumes the obligation to pay the surcharge.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">An ordinance or resolution enacted under subsection (a) of this section shall provide for:<section prefix="(i)">Eligibility requirements for participation in the Program, including eligibility requirements for:<section prefix="1.">Energy efficiency improvements and renewable energy devices; and</section><section prefix="2.">Property and property owners; and</section></section><section prefix="(ii)">Loan terms and conditions.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Eligibility requirements under paragraph (1) of this subsection shall include a requirement that the political subdivision, in a manner substantially similar to that required for a mortgage loan under &#xA7;&#xA7; 12-127, 12-311, 12-409.1, 12-925, and 12-1029 of the Commercial Law Article, give due regard to the property owner's ability to repay a loan provided under the Program.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
