<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="g24" order_by="" level="1">Political Subdivisions - Miscellaneous Provisions</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>g24-9-602</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>602</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Anne Arundel County may impose, by ordinance, and collect a sales or use tax on:<section prefix="(1)">Fuels and utilities used by commercial and industrial businesses;</section><section prefix="(2)">Residential, commercial, and industrial telephone service; and</section><section prefix="(3)">Space rentals.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Any revenues collected under the authority of subsection (a)(1) and (2) of this section within the boundaries of the City of Annapolis shall be allocated and distributed in equal amounts to the City of Annapolis and to Anne Arundel County.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Except as otherwise provided in this subsection, any revenue generated within the boundaries of the City of Annapolis from the tax on space rentals shall be collected and retained by the City of Annapolis.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Any revenue generated within the boundaries of the City of Annapolis from the hotel tax shall be collected by Anne Arundel County.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">From any revenue generated within the boundaries of the City of Annapolis from the hotel tax, Anne Arundel County shall distribute:<section prefix="(i)">In fiscal year 2012:<section prefix="1.">2% to the Arts Council of Anne Arundel County, Inc.; and</section><section prefix="2.">8% to the Annapolis and Anne Arundel County Conference and Visitors Bureau;</section></section><section prefix="(ii)">In fiscal year 2013:<section prefix="1.">2.5% to the Arts Council of Anne Arundel County, Inc.; and</section><section prefix="2.">12.5% to the Annapolis and Anne Arundel County Conference and Visitors Bureau; and</section></section><section prefix="(iii)">In fiscal year 2014 and each fiscal year thereafter:<section prefix="1.">3% to the Arts Council of Anne Arundel County, Inc.; and</section><section prefix="2.">17% to the Annapolis and Anne Arundel County Conference and Visitors Bureau.</section></section></section>
      <section prefix="(5)">After making the distributions required under paragraph (4) of this subsection, the balance of the revenue generated within the boundaries of the City of Annapolis from the hotel tax shall be distributed to the City of Annapolis.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Anne Arundel County may not impose a sales and use tax on space rentals for the docking or storage of boats.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Anne Arundel County, from the county's share of any revenue from the hotel tax, shall distribute:<section prefix="(i)">In fiscal years 2010 and 2011, 7% to the Annapolis and Anne Arundel County Conference and Visitors Bureau;</section><section prefix="(ii)">In fiscal year 2012:<section prefix="1.">2% to the Arts Council of Anne Arundel County, Inc.; and</section><section prefix="2.">8% to the Annapolis and Anne Arundel County Conference and Visitors Bureau;</section></section><section prefix="(iii)">In fiscal year 2013:<section prefix="1.">2.5% to the Arts Council of Anne Arundel County, Inc.; and</section><section prefix="2.">12.5% to the Annapolis and Anne Arundel County Conference and Visitors Bureau; and</section></section><section prefix="(iv)">In fiscal year 2014 and each fiscal year thereafter:<section prefix="1.">3% to the Arts Council of Anne Arundel County, Inc.; and</section><section prefix="2.">17% to the Annapolis and Anne Arundel County Conference and Visitors Bureau.</section></section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">After the distributions required under paragraph (1) of this subsection, the balance of the county's share of revenue from a hotel tax shall be credited to the general fund of the county.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The Arts Council of Anne Arundel County, Inc. and the Annapolis and Anne Arundel County Conference and Visitors Bureau shall report to the Anne Arundel County Executive and the members of the General Assembly representing Anne Arundel County on their use of hotel tax revenue during the preceding fiscal year.</section>
  </text>
</law>
