<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="g24" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="15-104" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>g24-15-104</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as otherwise provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, a person who receives a citation under this title may elect to stand trial for the offense by filing with the county health officer a notice of intention to stand trial.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">In Cecil County, a person who receives a citation under this title may elect to stand trial for the offense by filing a notice of intention to stand trial with a copy of the citation with the District Court having venue at least 5 days before the date set forth in the citation for payment of the civil penalty.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The person electing to stand trial under subsection (a)(1) of this section, shall give notice at least 5 days before the date set forth in the citation for the payment of the civil penalty.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">After receiving a notice of intention to stand trial from a person providing notice under subsection (a)(1) of this section, the county health officer shall forward the notice to the District Court having venue, with a copy of the citation.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">After receiving the citation and notice, the District Court shall schedule the case for trial and notify the defendant of the trial date.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">All penalties and forfeitures collected by the District Court for violations of this title shall be remitted to the county in which the violation occurred.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">In a proceeding before the District Court, a violation shall be prosecuted in the same manner and to the same extent as a municipal infraction under Article 23A, &#xA7; 3(b)(7) through (15) of the Code.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">The county commissioners of the county in which the violation occurred may authorize the county attorney to prosecute a civil infraction under this title.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">If the District Court finds that a person has committed a civil infraction under this title, the person shall be liable for the costs of the court proceedings.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">The finding by the District Court of a violation under this title is not a criminal conviction and does not impose any of the civil disabilities ordinarily imposed by a criminal conviction.</section>
  </text>
</law>
