<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="g24" order_by="" level="1">Political Subdivisions - Miscellaneous Provisions</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>g24-11-501</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>501</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Except in Calvert County, Carroll County, Cecil County, Montgomery County, Howard County, Talbot County, and Washington County, on or before the first day of July of each year, the owner of any dog, six months old or over, shall apply either orally or in writing, to the county treasurer or to the tax collecting officer in said county for a license for each such dog owned or kept by him, and such application shall be accompanied by a fee of one dollar ($1.00) for each male dog or each spayed female dog, and a fee of two dollars ($2.00) for each unspayed female dog, and provided that kennel license shall be issued for ten dollars ($10.00) to persons owning or keeping not in excess of twenty-five dogs and that a kennel license fee of twenty dollars ($20.00) shall be issued to persons keeping more than twenty-five dogs. Except as provided in subsection (a-1) of this section, the said license or fee shall be the only license or tax required for the ownership or keeping of said dog or dogs. Such license shall be issued on a form prepared and supplied by the county commissioners. Such license shall be dated and numbered, and shall contain a description of the dog licensed. Except in Calvert County, Carroll County, Cecil County, Montgomery County, Howard County, Talbot County, and Washington County, all licenses shall be void upon the first day of July of the following year. The county commissioners shall also furnish, and the county treasurer, or tax collecting officer issuing the license, shall issue, with each license, a metal tag. Such tag shall be affixed to a substantial collar. The collar shall be furnished by the owner, and with the tag attached shall at all times be kept on the dog for which the license is issued, except when confined in the kennel or when hunting in charge of an attendant.</section>
    <section prefix="(a-1)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This subsection applies in all counties.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Notwithstanding any other provisions of this section, a person shall obtain a kennel license from the local licensing agency if the person:<section prefix="(i)">Owns or has custody of 15 or more unspayed female dogs over the age of 6 months kept for the purpose of breeding the dogs and selling their offspring; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Sells dogs from six or more litters in a year.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Each county shall collect and maintain a record of the following information for each kennel license issued in the county:<section prefix="(i)">Name of the licensee;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Address of the licensee;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Number of dogs maintained by the licensee; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">Number of puppies sold by the licensee in the preceding year.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">On or before January 15 of each year, each county shall report to the Department of Labor, Licensing, and Regulation the information collected under paragraph (3) of this subsection for the preceding year.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">A county may establish additional kennel license fees to cover the cost of collecting, maintaining, and submitting the records and reports required by paragraphs (3) and (4) of this subsection.</section>
      <section prefix="(6)">This section may not be construed to prohibit a county from enacting more stringent kennel licensing ordinances.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">In Calvert County the fees for dog licenses shall be determined by the County Commissioners. However, before establishing or altering any license fee, the Calvert County Commissioners shall advertise the proposed fee for 2 consecutive weeks in at least 2 newspapers of general circulation in Calvert County. All dog licenses will expire 1, 2, or 3 years after the date of issue, as specified by county law.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">In Harford County all applications for licenses under the provisions of this section shall be made on or before the thirty-first day of December of each year and all licenses issued shall be void upon the thirty-first day of December of the following year. Any license issued under the provisions of this section as of July 1, 1950, shall be valid until December 31, 1951. The license fee for each unspayed female dog shall be three dollars ($3.00).</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">In Montgomery County:<section prefix="(1)">The fees for dogs shall be determined by the County Executive of the county; and</section><section prefix="(2)">A dog license shall expire when a rabies vaccination certification issued under &#xA7; 18-319(a)(3) of the Health - General Article expires.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">In St. Mary's County the license fees for dogs, including the fee for any kennel license, shall be determined by the County Commissioners of the county and shall be payable on or before the thirtieth day of June of each year, and all such licenses issued shall be void upon the thirtieth day of June the following year. The County Commissioners of St. Mary's County are authorized and directed to appoint the necessary agents to collect said license fees from owners of dogs who have not paid the required license fees by the first day of August in each year, and there shall be added to the fee of such delinquent owner a penalty of one dollar ($1.00) per license. Every dog warden appointed in St. Mary's County shall have all the powers of a constable or other peace officer.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">In Talbot County:<section prefix="(1)">The fees, the term, and the form of dog and kennel licenses shall be determined by the County Council of Talbot County;</section><section prefix="(2)">A dog license shall expire as specified by county law; and</section><section prefix="(3)">A dog tag may be either a metal tag or a surgically implanted microchip.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(g)">In Charles County the fee for dogs shall be determined by the County Commissioners of the county.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">In Howard County:<section prefix="(1)">The fee for dog and kennel licenses is determined by the County Executive with the approval of the County Council; and</section><section prefix="(2)">A dog license shall expire as specified by county law.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(i)">Repealed.</section>
    <section prefix="(j)">In Worcester, Kent, and Caroline counties the fee for dog and kennel licenses shall be determined by the county commissioners.</section>
    <section prefix="(k)">In Frederick County, the license fees for dogs, including the fee for any kennel license, shall be determined by the County Commissioners of the county.</section>
    <section prefix="(l)">In Wicomico County:<section prefix="(1)">The fees for dog and kennel licenses shall be determined by the County Council of Wicomico County; and</section><section prefix="(2)">A dog license shall expire as specified by county law.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(m)">In Anne Arundel County, the fees for dog and kennel licenses shall be determined by the County Council of Anne Arundel County. A dog license shall expire when a rabies vaccination certificate issued under &#xA7; 18-319(a)(3) of the Health - General Article expires.</section>
    <section prefix="(n)">In Garrett County, the license fee for dogs, including the fee for any kennel license, shall be determined by the County Commissioners of the county.</section>
    <section prefix="(o)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This subsection applies only to Carroll County.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Carroll County Commissioners shall set the fees, the term, and the form for dog licenses and kennel licenses pursuant to the authority under &#xA7; 11-511 of this subtitle.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(p)">In Cecil County, the fees, the terms, and the forms for dog and kennel licenses shall be determined by the County Commissioners of Cecil County.</section>
  </text>
</law>
