<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="g24" order_by="24" level="1">Political Subdivisions - Miscellaneous Provisions</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>g24-9-1001</section_number>
  <catch_line>The County Council of Talbot County, by ordinance, may fix, impose, and provide for the collection o...</catch_line>
  <order_by>1001</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The County Council of Talbot County, by ordinance, may fix, impose, and provide for the collection of a building excise tax on any building construction within Talbot County.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The County Council shall specify in the ordinance the:<section prefix="(1)">Types of building construction subject to the building excise tax;</section><section prefix="(2)">Criteria and formulas used to assess the tax; and</section><section prefix="(3)">Tax rates.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The County Council may impose different rates of the building excise tax on different types of building construction subject to the building excise tax.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The tax rates:<section prefix="(i)">Shall relate to the development or growth-related infrastructure needs in the county; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">May not exceed $2,000 per lot or parcel where building construction is to occur.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The revenues from the building excise tax shall be deposited in a special fund.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The special fund may only be used for the capital costs of additional or expanded public works, improvements, and facilities required to accommodate new construction or development including:<section prefix="(i)">Bridges;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Streets and roads;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Parks and recreational facilities;</section><section prefix="(iv)">Schools; and</section><section prefix="(v)">Storm drainage facilities.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The building excise tax may be imposed throughout the county, including within municipal corporations.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">If the building excise tax is imposed within a municipal corporation, the municipal corporation shall assist the county in the collection of the building excise tax by:<section prefix="(1)">Collecting and remitting the tax to the county; or</section><section prefix="(2)">Requiring the tax be paid to the county in accordance with the terms of the county ordinance.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(g)">The county shall adopt a revenue sharing mechanism to apportion an appropriate share of revenues from the building excise tax to the municipal corporations within the county.</section>
  </text>
</law>
