<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="g24" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="16-106" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>g24-16-106</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Fund provided by this title shall consist of the assets turned over to the board of trustees by the Police Commissioner of Baltimore City from the Relief Fund, and any increments from gifts or contributions from any source, less benefit payments and expenses. The board of trustees may receive and accept gifts, devises, and bequests to be administered in accordance with this title from any person, governmental agency, or public or private corporation or association. The board may make such expenditures, for the purpose of carrying out this title, as in their judgment may be necessary, including but not limited to organization, clerical, and office expenses.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">When the Fund falls below $75,000, the board of trustees may require the collection, by means of payroll deductions, from each officer and civilian employee of the Police Department of Baltimore City, of an amount not exceeding 10 cents per week, for payment to the Fund, for such time or times as the board may require, except that all such assessments shall cease whenever the Fund reaches $200,000, and may not again be required until the Fund again falls below $75,000. Upon written request of at least 10 percent of the total number of personnel of the Department, the action of the board in requiring an assessment shall be submitted to a secret ballot vote of the officers and civilian employees of the Department, and if a majority of the votes cast are opposed to assessment, the assessment shall not be imposed. If not replenished by assessment, the Fund shall be used until exhausted to pay the benefits herein, whereupon the Fund shall cease.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The board of trustees may invest the assets of the Fund in such investments as in their discretion they deem prudent, but at least sufficient cash shall be deposited in federally insured savings accounts to meet the anticipated benefit payments for each year.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The accounts of the Fund shall be regularly audited by the Legislative Auditor, and from time to time by such independent certified public accountant that the board of trustees may engage. On or before May 1 in each year, the board of trustees shall publish annually a report including the fiscal transactions of the Fund for the year ending the preceding December 31, and a detailed balance sheet as of the said preceding December 31. The board shall provide copies of the report to all members of the board by electronic mail, post copies of the report on the Baltimore City Police Department's Intranet, and file with its own records one or more copies, which shall be made available to any officer or civilian employee of the Department or potential beneficiary of any deceased officer or civilian employee wishing to inspect the same.</section>
  </text>
</law>
