<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="g24" order_by="" level="1">Political Subdivisions - Miscellaneous Provisions</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>g24-9-1503</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>1503</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">A political subdivision may issue bonds for the purpose of financing loans made through the Program.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">To issue a bond, a political subdivision shall adopt an ordinance or a resolution that specifies the maximum principal amount of the bond.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">As the political subdivision considers appropriate to effect the Program, the ordinance or resolution may:<section prefix="(1)">Specify the items listed in subsection (d) of this section;</section><section prefix="(2)">Authorize the finance board of the political subdivision to specify those items by resolution or ordinance; or</section><section prefix="(3)">Authorize the chief executive of the political subdivision to specify those items by executive order.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">For each issuance of a bond, the political subdivision may specify:<section prefix="(1)">The principal amount;</section><section prefix="(2)">The interest rate or, for floating or variable rates of interest, the method to determine the interest rate;</section><section prefix="(3)">The manner and terms of sale, including whether by competitive or negotiated sale;</section><section prefix="(4)">The time of execution, issuance, and delivery;</section><section prefix="(5)">The form and denomination;</section><section prefix="(6)">The source, manner, times, and places to pay principal or interest;</section><section prefix="(7)">Conditions for redemption before maturity;</section><section prefix="(8)">The purposes for which proceeds may be spent;</section><section prefix="(9)">The source of security; and</section><section prefix="(10)">Other provisions that the governing body of the political subdivision determines are necessary or desirable to effect the Program.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
