<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="g24" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="24-403" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>g24-24-403</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Except as otherwise provided in this title, Montgomery County and Prince George's County each may impose an ad valorem tax on all property assessed for tax purposes within the stormwater management district at a rate required to produce the amount needed to pay for:<section prefix="(1)">Maintenance of stormwater management systems in the stormwater management district that were maintained by the Commission before July 1, 1987, and systems established by each county on or after July 1, 1987;</section><section prefix="(2)">The principal and interest that becomes due and owing to the bondholders during the following year and the proportionate part of the principal of all outstanding sinking fund bonds, as determined by the table of redemption of bonds for bonds issued by:<section prefix="(i)">The Commission for stormwater management; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">The county for stormwater management under this title; and</section></section><section prefix="(3)">The cost of stormwater management activities and practices in the stormwater management district, as approved in the county's annual stormwater management budget and appropriations resolution for the following fiscal year.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Commission shall certify annually to each county the amount necessary to produce the sum required to pay the principal, interest, and other obligations for the current year on the outstanding bonds issued by the Commission to pay for stormwater management projects within the county's stormwater management district.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The county shall pay the amount certified under paragraph (1) of this subsection.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, the taxes authorized by this section shall be imposed and collected in the same manner, have the same priority, bear the same interest, and be treated in all respects as other county taxes.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Notwithstanding any provision of charter or other law, the taxes may not be subject to a limitation on the tax rate or tax revenues of the county.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The tax revenues shall be deposited and maintained in a separate stormwater management fund established under &#xA7; 24-407 of this subtitle.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">The tax revenues deposited in the fund shall be in addition to all other county taxes and may not be considered county taxes for the purpose of applying the limitations in Article VIII, &#xA7; 812 of the Prince George's County Charter.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
