<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="g24" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="1-107" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>g24-1-107</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Administrator" means the chief administrative officer of a county or municipal corporation.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Department head" means the head of a separate unit of a county or municipal corporation who reports directly to an elected executive or administrator or directly to the governing body of the county or municipal corporation.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">"Employee" does not include an elected official, a department head, or an administrator.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">"Regional agency" means an agency created under State law that provides governmental services to more than one political subdivision.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A county or municipal corporation may not require an employee to reside within the State, county, or municipal corporation or within a required distance of the State, county, or municipal corporation as a condition of employment.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Subject to subsection (c) of this section, a county or municipal corporation may not discriminate between residents and other citizens of the State or any other state in employment, promotion, demotion, layoff, and discharge decisions.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A county or municipal corporation may grant a resident of the State, county, or municipal corporation additional points or credits in employment or promotion decisions if the points or credits are provided under provisions of a merit system established by the county or municipal corporation by local law or ordinance.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A regional agency may not require an employee as a condition of employment to reside within the State or a political subdivision for which the regional agency provides governmental services or within a required distance of the State or a political subdivision for which the agency provides governmental services.</section>
  </text>
</law>
