<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="g24" order_by="24" level="1">Political Subdivisions - Miscellaneous Provisions</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>g24-9-712</section_number>
  <catch_line>The tax collector shall:...</catch_line>
  <order_by>712</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The tax collector shall:<section prefix="(1)">Investigate each claim for refund; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Conduct a hearing at the request of the claimant prior to a final determination on the claim.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If the tax collector determines that a claim for refund should be allowed, either in whole or in part, the tax collector shall forward the claim to the chief fiscal officer for approval.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If the chief fiscal officer does not approve the claim, the chief fiscal officer shall give the tax collector notice of the disapproval.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A claim for refund may not be approved unless all other State, county, or municipal corporation taxes, fees, and charges due by the person entitled to the refund have been paid.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The tax collector shall give the claimant notice of:<section prefix="(1)">The determination of the claim for refund; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Any delay in paying an allowed claim.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, within 30 days after the date on which a notice is mailed, a person who is aggrieved by the action in the notice may appeal to the Maryland Tax Court in the manner allowed in Title 13, Subtitle 5, Parts IV and V of the Tax - General Article.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If a tax collector does not make a determination on a claim for refund within 6 months after the claim is filed, the claimant may:<section prefix="(i)">Consider the claim as being disallowed; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Appeal the disallowance to the Tax Court.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
