<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="g25" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="217.1" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>g25-217.1</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">This section applies only in Washington County.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">In this section, "inactive association" means a public watershed association established under this subtitle that for at least 5 years has not substantially complied with the majority of ordinary operating procedures required under this subtitle, including:<section prefix="(1)">The maintenance of ongoing and current information in the watershed file at the Office of the Clerk of the Board of County Commissioners;</section><section prefix="(2)">Elections of a board of directors and officers of the Board;</section><section prefix="(3)">An annual meeting of owners of land within the association;</section><section prefix="(4)">The submission of an annual report by the board of directors to the Clerk of the Board of County Commissioners;</section><section prefix="(5)">The development, approval, appropriate filing, execution, or maintenance of a work plan applicable to property owned by the association; and</section><section prefix="(6)">The submission and regular updating of the association's easement record in the office of the Clerk of the Circuit Court in the applicable county.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Notwithstanding the requirements of &#xA7; 217 of this subtitle, upon a written petition for dissolution by any member of the most recently elected or appointed board of directors of an association considered currently inactive, the Board of County Commissioners of Washington County shall promptly:<section prefix="(1)">Consider all available information to determine the current operating status and foreseeable operating potential of the association; and</section><section prefix="(2)">By majority vote, approve or deny the petition for dissolution.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">If the Board of County Commissioners approves a petition for dissolution under this section, the Board shall:<section prefix="(1)">With any balance remaining in the county treasury to the credit of the dissolved association:<section prefix="(i)">Satisfy all outstanding debts of the association; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Distribute any remainder to the Board of County Commissioners; and</section></section><section prefix="(2)">Provide for the transfer of any interest in real property held by the inactive association to the county or counties in which the property is located.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
