<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="g25" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="10D-1" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>g25-10D-1</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The County Commissioners of St. Mary's County may raise the building permit fees up to two percent of the cost of any new construction of any living units built in St. Mary's County, or prebuilt and brought into St. Mary's County; the building permit fees shall be set by the County Commissioners in December of each year.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Subject to paragraphs (2) and (3) of this subsection, the County Commissioners of St. Mary's County may require every person, firm, partnership, corporation, or other legal entity which submits its property plans for approval to the planning commission of St. Mary's County (or the appropriate approving authority) to pay a fixed sum as set by the County Commissioners to defray the additional cost for additional public facilities as required by local ordinance or resolution.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">By ordinance, the County Commissioners of St. Mary's County may enact an exemption to the building impact fee imposed under paragraph (1) of this subsection for the first 3 lots, in a minor subdivision, that:<section prefix="(i)">Were recorded after June 1, 2000 and created from a parcel of record or a lot of record; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Transferred to a natural, direct lineal descendant, or a legally adopted son, daughter, grandson, or granddaughter.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Subject to subparagraphs (ii) and (iii) of this paragraph for each fiscal year, the County Commissioners of St. Mary's County may:</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The County Commissioners may waive, defer, or amortize the building impact fee only for newly constructed living units that are deemed to be affordable for individuals whose family income in the previous fiscal year was less than 60 percent of the county median family income as reported by the U.S. Department of Housing and Urban Development.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">A waiver, deferral, or amortization shall be limited to new construction of living units not exceeding a certain square footage as determined by the County Commissioners of St. Mary's County.</section>
        <section prefix="(iv)">The total amount of building impact fees waived, deferred, or amortized shall be reflected in the St. Mary's County annual capital budget for the fiscal year in which the waiver, deferral, or amortization is granted.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The income derived from subsections (a) and (b) of this section shall be used to defray the additional cost to St. Mary's County for additional educational, water, sewerage, road, sanitation, solid waste, park, or similar facilities.</section>
  </text>
</law>
