<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="g25" order_by="" level="1">County Commisioners</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>g25-122D</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>122D</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In Harford County, no person, firm, or corporation may lease, rent, use, or permit the use of property for the purpose of erecting thereon any outdoor advertising signs of any kind adjacent to any State or county highway which are visible from the traveled way of the highway, except as hereinafter provided. As used in this section "visible from the traveled way" means capable of being seen, whether or not legible, without visual aid by a person of normal visual acuity. This prohibition does not apply to the following:<section prefix="(1)">Outdoor advertising signs promoting a business or other activity being conducted on the same property as the sign, known as "on-premise signs".</section><section prefix="(2)">Outdoor advertising signs located under the authority of zoning permits in commercial or industrial zones.</section><section prefix="(3)">Outdoor advertising signs authorized in districts zoned commercial and industrial by municipal corporations within their boundaries.</section><section prefix="(4)">Temporary real estate signs.</section><section prefix="(5)">Official directional signs installed by the State Highway Administration or Harford County.</section><section prefix="(6)">Signs denoting places of religious worship or a historic monument on location. However, these signs shall be located in accordance with the rules and regulations of the State Highway Administration.</section><section prefix="(7)">Outdoor advertising signs erected prior to June 1, 1972.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Either the State Highway Administration or Harford County may acquire by purchase, gift or condemnation, and pay just compensation upon the removal of, outdoor advertising signs which are visible from the traveled way of State or county highways if the outdoor advertising signs were erected prior to June 1, 1972. No compensation may be paid for any such signs erected subsequent to June 1, 1972. Compensation is authorized to be paid only for the following:<section prefix="(1)">The taking from the owner of the sign, display, or device of all right, title, leasehold and interest in the sign, display or device.</section><section prefix="(2)">The taking from the owner of the land on which the sign, display, or device is located of the right to erect and maintain the sign, display or device thereon.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Nothing herein may be construed to permit the erection of outdoor advertising signs otherwise prohibited by State or local law or by local zoning ordinance.</section>
  </text>
</law>
