<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="g25" order_by="" level="1">County Commisioners</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>g25-107</section_number>
  <catch_line>The engineer and viewers shall have power to employ such assistants as may be necessary to make a co...</catch_line>
  <order_by>107</order_by>
  <text>The engineer and viewers shall have power to employ such assistants as may be necessary to make a complete survey of the drainage district, and shall enter upon the ground and make a survey of the main drain or drains and all their laterals. The line of each ditch, drain or levee shall be plainly and substantially marked on the ground. The course and distance of each ditch shall be carefully noted and sufficient notes made, so that it may be accurately platted and mapped. A line of levels shall be run for the entire work and sufficient data secured from which accurate profiles and plans may be made for each of the proposed drains or levees. Frequent bench marks shall be established along the line, on permanent objects, and their elevation and full description recorded in the field books and their location shown on the map. If it is deemed expedient by the engineer and viewers, other levels may be run to determine the fall from one part of the district to another. If an old watercourse, ditch or channel is being widened, deepened or straightened, it shall be accurately cross-sectioned, so as to compute the amount of cubic yards saved by the use of such old channel. A drainage map of the district shall then be completed, showing the location of the ditch or ditches and other improvements, and the boundary, as closely as may be determined by the records, of the lands owned by such individual landowner within the district. The location of any railroads or public highways and the boundary of any incorporated towns or villages within the district shall be shown on the map. There shall also be prepared to accompany this map a profile of each levee, drain or watercourse, showing the surface of the ground, the bottom or grade of the proposed improvement and the number of cubic yards of excavation or fill in each mile or fraction thereof, and the total yards in the proposed improvement and the number of cubic yards of excavation or fill in each mile or fraction thereof, and the total yards in the proposed improvement and the estimated cost thereof, and plans and specifications and the cost of any other work required to be done.</text>
</law>
