<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="g25" order_by="" level="1">County Commisioners</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>g25-27</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>27</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">This section only applies in the following counties:<section prefix="(1)">Caroline;</section><section prefix="(2)">Carroll;</section><section prefix="(3)">Cecil;</section><section prefix="(4)">Charles;</section><section prefix="(5)">Frederick;</section><section prefix="(6)">Howard;</section><section prefix="(7)">Somerset;</section><section prefix="(8)">Talbot;</section><section prefix="(9)">Wicomico; and</section><section prefix="(10)">Worcester.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A person, firm or corporation may not establish, maintain or operate any public dance hall, boxing or wrestling arena, amusement park, or tourist camp with cabins for hire outside the limits of any municipal corporation of any county without first obtaining a permit from the county commissioners of the county.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The county commissioners of the several counties shall have authority to grant or refuse such permission or to grant the same for such time and under such rules and regulations as they may deem proper for the public welfare, and shall also have the right to revoke any such permit for cause after notice and a hearing.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In Worcester County, the provisions of this section shall also apply to any tourist cabin, motel, apartment house, rooming house or other structure or building to be rented to 4 or more persons at any one time.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">In Charles County, except for a facility that qualifies under subparagraph (ii) of this paragraph, the County Commissioners shall charge:<section prefix="1.">$50 for issuing the initial permit; and</section><section prefix="2.">$50 annually for the renewal of the permit.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">A facility in Charles County provided for under subsection (b) of this section is exempt from the provisions of subparagraph (i) of this paragraph if:<section prefix="1.">The facility is established, maintained, or operated for the purposes of a religious, educational, or fraternal organization; and</section><section prefix="2.">No other person or corporation shares the profits and gains from events held in the facility.</section></section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">Any person, firm or corporation establishing, maintaining or operating any establishment or place in violation of the provisions of this section is guilty of a misdemeanor and upon conviction shall be subject to a fine of not less than $100 or more than $500 for each such offense. The place or establishment shall also be subject to abatement as a nuisance.</section>
  </text>
</law>
