<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="g25" order_by="" level="1">County Commisioners</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>g25-26A</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>26A</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The governing bodies of any county, city, town or any combination thereof by resolution may establish, organize and participate in a council of governments, which may include counties, cities, and towns outside the State of Maryland, for the purpose of studying area governmental problems of mutual interest and concern, including such matters as facility studies on sewers and sewage disposal, water, storm drainage, roads, rubbish and garbage disposal, recreation, zoning, parks and ports, and to formulate recommendations for review and action thereon by the participating governing bodies.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Membership of the council shall consist of at least one representative from each participating county, city or town. The representative or representatives from each participating county, city or town shall be the elected chief executive of a participating government and/or a member or members of its governing body chosen by such body to be its representatives. Any county, city or town which has become a member may withdraw upon 60 days notice subsequent to formal action by the governing body.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The council shall have the power to (i) study such area governmental problems common to two or more members of the council as it deems appropriate, including but not limited to matters affecting health, environment, safety, welfare, education, economic conditions, and regional development; (ii) promote cooperative arrangements and coordinate action among its members; and (iii) make recommendations for review and action to the members and other public agencies that perform functions within the region.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The council shall adopt bylaws designating the officers of the council and providing for the conduct of its business.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The council may employ such staff, and consult and retain such experts, as it deems necessary.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The governing bodies of the participating governments may appropriate funds to meet the expenses of the council. Services of personnel, use of equipment and office space, and other necessary services may be accepted from participating governments as part of their financial support.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The council may accept funds, grants, gifts, and services from the government of the United States or its agencies, from the State of Maryland or its departments, agencies or instrumentalities, or from any governmental unit whether participating in the council or not, and from private and civic sources.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">It shall make an annual report of its activities to the participating governments.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">The Metropolitan Washington Council of Governments operating under the provisions of this section shall be entitled to receive State financial support to assist it in carrying out its activities on the basis of fifty per centum of the per capita contributions of the participating Maryland governments in the council; provided, however, that the State contribution shall not exceed an amount equal to the sum computed on the basis of three thousand two hundred dollars ($3,200) for each fifty thousand (50,000) persons residing in the participating Maryland governments in the council. This amount shall be included in the annual State budget and shall be subject to review by the General Assembly.</section>
  </text>
</law>
