<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="g25" order_by="" level="1">County Commisioners</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>g25-10-I</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>I</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The County Commissioners of St. Mary's County may regulate any public road, street, avenue, lane, alley or bridge, sidewalk, curb, gutter, and storm drainage facilities within St. Mary's County which is not within the corporate limits of any incorporated city or town and which has not been designated or maintained as a part of the State or federal highway system or any extension with respect to:<section prefix="(1)">The weight of vehicles;</section><section prefix="(2)">The parking of vehicles;</section><section prefix="(3)">The abandonment of vehicles;</section><section prefix="(4)">Use by private and public utilities in the construction and maintenance necessitated by the performance of their purpose;</section><section prefix="(5)">The construction and maintenance of driveway connections where those connections are provided; and</section><section prefix="(6)">The speed of vehicles.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The County Commissioners of St. Mary's County shall enact by ordinance rules and regulations governing the grading, constructing, improving, maintaining, and repairing of roads, now used by the public or intended for public use, including roads proposed for subdivisions, whether now recorded or hereafter proposed, including sidewalks, curbs and gutters, driveway entrances and storm drainage facilities and appurtenances to be located within the subdivision.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The County Commissioners of St. Mary's County shall provide appropriate traffic control devices when mandated by the ordinance adopted pursuant to subsection (a) of this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The County Commissioners of St. Mary's County may regulate the engineering, constructing, and accepting of any new public road, street, avenue, lane, alley, bridge, sidewalk, curb, gutter, and storm drainage facilities into the county roads system.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">In St. Mary's County, except as provided in subsection (f) of this section, any violations of this subtitle shall be a misdemeanor punishable by a fine of not more than $1,000 or six months imprisonment for each and every violation, or both fine and imprisonment, in the discretion of the judge. Every day that said violation continues shall be a separate offense.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The County Commissioners may provide for a civil penalty for violation of any ordinance, rule, or regulation enacted under this section. In a proceeding before the District Court, the violation shall be enforced in the same manner and to the same extent as set forth for municipal infractions in Article 23A, &#xA7; 3(b) of the Code.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">In addition to all other remedies provided by law, St. Mary's County shall have the right of ex parte injunctive relief against a violator requiring correction or elimination of any violation.</section>
  </text>
</law>
