<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="g25" order_by="25" level="1">County Commisioners</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>g25-121H</section_number>
  <catch_line>The provisions of &#xA7;&#xA7; 103 through 121G of this article shall be liberally construed to promote the ...</catch_line>
  <order_by>121H</order_by>
  <text>The provisions of &#xA7;&#xA7; 103 through 121G of this article shall be liberally construed to promote the ditching, draining, leveeing and reclamation of wet and overflowed lands which may be made available for agriculture, and to encourage the starting of such enterprises there is hereby established a fund to be known as the "Drainage District Fund", and the sum of ten thousand dollars is hereby appropriated out of any money that may be in the State Treasury and not otherwise appropriated, to be placed to the credit of that fund, from which loans can be made in sums not to exceed a total of more than two thousand dollars to any one drainage project for the payment of the expenses of the surveys, engineer, viewers, advertising and all other incidental fees and expenses connected with the project up to time of the establishment of the drainage district, and the turning over of the work to the board of drainage commissioners. The money thus loaned shall be paid out by the Treasurer, when there is money to the credit of this fund, on warrant of the State Comptroller upon the receipt of an itemized statement or statements so requesting endorsed by the president and clerk of the board of county commissioners of the county in which the original petition of the particular district was filed. The funds loaned by the State shall be returned to the treasury again through the board of county commissioners, who shall collect the amount loaned under a petition filed with them from the petitioner or their bondsmen in case the petition is not allowed, but should the drainage district be established, then from the board of drainage commissioners out of the first proceeds of the sale of the bonds of that district charged with the loan.</text>
</law>
