<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="g25" order_by="" level="1">County Commisioners</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>g25-254</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>254</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The board of county commissioners or county council of every county in this State may establish a citizens nursing home board.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, the board shall consist of ten members; and the initial members shall be appointed by the county commissioners or county council; three members to be appointed for three years, three for two years, three for one year.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">In St. Mary's County, the board shall consist of at least 10, but no more than 15, members.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">New positions, as approved by the county commissioners, shall be initially filled by appointment by the county commissioners for terms to ensure balanced staggering of the expiration of terms of all members, but not to exceed three years.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Members shall be chosen from among the residents of the county.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">One member of the board of county commissioners or county council shall be a member of the board, ex officio, as chosen by the board of county commissioners or county council from time to time.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Except as provided in subparagraphs (ii) and (iii) of this paragraph, as the terms of the initial appointees expire or as vacancies occur, their successors shall be elected by a majority vote or quorum of the board for terms of three years or the remainder thereof; and hereafter, these positions shall be so filled.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">In St. Mary's County, as the terms of the initial appointees expire or as vacancies occur, their successors shall be appointed by the County Commissioners of St. Mary's County for a term of 3 years if a term expires, or the rest of the term if a term is vacated.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">In Frederick County, as the terms of the initial appointees expire or as vacancies occur, their successors shall be appointed by the County Commissioners of Frederick County for a term of 3 years if a term expires, or the rest of the term if a term is vacated.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The members of the board shall serve without compensation.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The board shall establish, maintain, and operate a nursing or convalescent home or homes and any other facilities and services necessary for the proper care and treatment of aged, convalescent, and chronically ill residents of the county and shall have the following powers and duties:<section prefix="(1)">To accept gifts, legacies, bequests or endowments for purposes of the board. Unless otherwise specified by the donor making such gift, legacy, bequest or endowment, the board, in its discretion, may expend both principal and income of any such gift, bequest, legacy or endowment to support the board's nursing home program;</section><section prefix="(2)">To acquire and hold real and personal property in the name of the county commissioners by any means, to sell or otherwise dispose of such property so acquired, and to preserve and administer such properties;</section><section prefix="(3)">To provide adequate facilities and services for the care and treatment of the aged, convalescent, and chronically ill citizens of the county. These facilities and services will or may include physical care, medical, nursing, recreational, rehabilitative, special education, and other similar activities, and, in addition, dissemination of information relative to causes and prevention of chronic and debilitating illnesses;</section><section prefix="(4)">To charge such fees for admission to and maintenance in such facilities and for use of such services as may support the facilities and services subject, however, to the provision that where aged, convalescent, and chronically ill residents of the county are in need of such facilities and services and are sufficiently impecunious as to be unable to pay the full cost of such care, then the charges to such residents shall be in direct proportion to their ability to pay for the services;</section><section prefix="(5)">To apply all moneys, assets, property or other things of value it may receive to the general purposes of the board;</section><section prefix="(6)">To adopt, subject to the terms of this section, such rules and regulations of any facilities or services that it establishes as may be necessary for their proper operation;</section><section prefix="(7)">To cooperate with and assist, insofar as practicable, any agency of the State of Maryland, the United States of America, any subdivision of either, or any private agency or person in furtherance of any of the purposes of this section;</section><section prefix="(8)">To hire a director of any facility or service that it establishes and to provide for such additional employees, their qualifications and wages as are necessary to properly operate such facilities;</section><section prefix="(9)">To require that all facilities and services that it establishes maintain such standards that they may qualify for licenses as hospitals under Title 19, Subtitle 3, Part III of the Health - General Article; and</section><section prefix="(10)">To integrate its facilities with, accept funds from, and cooperate with the Secretary of Health and Mental Hygiene in any facet or facets of its operations insofar as deemed advisable by this board.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The board shall elect one of its members to serve as chairman for any period it may designate. It shall hold such meetings as may be necessary for the proper conduct of its business, not, however, less frequently than once per month. It shall adopt, subject to the terms of this section, such rules as are necessary for the internal regulation of the board.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The activities of the board shall be supported insofar as possible by citizen support, voluntary contributions, fees and charges, payments from the State and federal government. The county commissioners or county council are authorized to make annual appropriations in support of the operations of the citizens nursing home board of the county for the objective of maintaining an adequate level of medical and nursing care for the aged, convalescent, and chronically ill citizens of the county. In further support of the objectives of this section the county commissioners or county council may make appropriations for land acquisition and capital improvements or borrow funds for these purposes and issue individual notes, bonds or other evidences of indebtedness.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">The board shall annually report their activities to the county commissioners or county council during the preceding year, together with recommendations or requests they deem appropriate to achieve the objectives and purposes of this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">In Frederick County, in addition to the authority provided in this section, the Frederick County Commissioners may establish, maintain, and operate a nursing or convalescent home or homes and any other facilities and services for the proper care and treatment of the aged, convalescent, and chronically ill.</section>
  </text>
</law>
