<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="g25" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="168" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>g25-168</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Whenever a request to restrict the use of water furnished or supplied by the Mayor and City Council of Baltimore in any of the counties hereinafter mentioned is made by the water engineer of the Mayor and City Council of Baltimore, then the county commissioners of Anne Arundel, Baltimore and Howard counties and the Anne Arundel County Sanitary Commission, acting for and within the boundaries of their respective counties, are hereby authorized, empowered and directed to restrict the use of water furnished or supplied by the Mayor and City Council of Baltimore to any person or property located in the said respective counties: (1) to the same extent as restrictions are imposed upon the water consumers in Baltimore City when restrictions are required by a shortage of raw water, or (2) over or within limited areas when required because of deficiencies in the water distribution system or appurtenances serving any particular areas on such conditions as may be approved by the county commissioners of the aforementioned respective counties or their duly authorized representative.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Before restrictions are imposed as aforesaid in any limited area in any of the aforesaid counties, the water engineer of the Mayor and City Council of Baltimore shall determine that the unrestricted use of water in all other areas of any of said counties will have no detrimental effect on the particular limited area where the use of water is to be restricted.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The county commissioners of said counties and the Anne Arundel County Sanitary Commission are hereby authorized and empowered to pass any and all ordinances, resolutions, rules or regulations that may be necessary for the imposition of such restrictions and the enforcement thereof, and to provide penalties for the violation of such restrictions.</section>
  </text>
</law>
