<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="g25" order_by="" level="1">County Commisioners</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>g25-170</section_number>
  <catch_line>A petition signed by not less than one third of the landowners or by the owners of not less than one...</catch_line>
  <order_by>170</order_by>
  <text>A petition signed by not less than one third of the landowners or by the owners of not less than one third of the land in a watershed or subwatershed area, may be filed with the clerk of the board of county commissioners of the county in which all or a greater part of such land is located, describing the area in such a way as to convey an intelligent idea of its location and boundaries, and its problems of watershed protection, flood prevention, recreation, soil conservation, drainage, and/or the conservation, development, storage, utilization, and disposal of water, for all beneficial purposes and that the public benefit, or the public health, safety or welfare would be promoted by establishing works of improvement for watershed protection, flood prevention, recreation, soil conservation, drainage, and/or the conservation, development, storage, utilization and disposal of water for all beneficial purposes and asking for the establishment of a public watershed association for such purposes. Said petition shall be accompanied by a report from the local soil conservation district or districts lying in whole or in part within the proposed association, which shall show the following:<section prefix=""><section prefix="1.">The size and location of the proposed public watershed association.</section><section prefix="2.">The nature of the problems.</section><section prefix="3.">The types of treatment believed needed and the benefits anticipated.</section><section prefix="4.">Whether the proposed public watershed association is practicable and feasible and is generally supported by the landowners in the area.</section><section prefix="5.">Whether it will promote the public benefit, and be conducive to the public health, safety and welfare.</section><section prefix="6.">The name of the proposed organization which shall be styled the "............ Public Watershed Association".</section><section prefix="7.">The number of directors (not less than 3) to serve as the governing body.</section></section></text>
</law>
