<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="g25" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="236E" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>g25-236E</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Alarm system contractor" means:<section prefix="(i)">A person engaged in installing, maintaining, monitoring, altering, or servicing alarm systems; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">An agency that furnishes the services of a person engaged in installing, maintaining, monitoring, altering, or servicing alarm systems.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">"Alarm user" means a person in control of an alarm system within, on, or around any building, structure, facility, or site.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">"Alarm user" includes the owner or lessee of an alarm system.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(4)">
        <section prefix="(i)">"False alarm" means any request for immediate assistance by a law enforcement agency, fire department, or emergency services agency, regardless of cause, that is not in response to an actual emergency situation or threatened suggested criminal activity.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">"False alarm" includes:</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">"False alarm" does not include:</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">An alarm system that is activated a second time within a 12-hour period when the premises are unoccupied shall be deemed a false alarm under this section if:<section prefix="(i)">Access to the building is provided to the alarm system contractor; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">An alarm system contractor or an employee of an alarm system contractor responds.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If access to the building is not provided to the alarm system contractor, and the contractor does not respond to an alarm system that is activated a second time within a 12-hour period when the premises are unoccupied, each subsequent alarm shall be counted as a false alarm.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Board of County Commissioners of Washington County may adopt regulations for:<section prefix="(1)">Registering alarm system contractors operating in the county;</section><section prefix="(2)">Registering alarm users in the county;</section><section prefix="(3)">Providing penalties for failure to register as an alarm system contractor or alarm user;</section><section prefix="(4)">Providing civil citations and penalties for false alarms, notwithstanding Title 9, Subtitle 6, Part II of the Criminal Law Article;</section><section prefix="(5)">Providing exemptions from the issuance of civil citations and penalties for false alarms;</section><section prefix="(6)">Authorizing the designated county enforcement agency to maintain a record of the alarm system contractor, monitoring service, and manufacturer of each security system in operation in the county;</section><section prefix="(7)">Authorizing the designated county enforcement agency, if it finds a pattern of false alarms attributed to a particular manufacturer's model or to installation by a particular alarm system contractor, to inform:<section prefix="(i)">The manufacturer of the model or the alarm system contractor that installed the alarm system; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">The appropriate State or national licensing agency or the certification standards entity; and</section></section><section prefix="(8)">Establishing fees for registering an alarm system contractor or alarm user.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
