<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="g25" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="164" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>g25-164</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Whenever the plans and specifications for the construction of erosion prevention works, or any part thereof, for any of said assessment districts shall have been completed, the county commissioners, acting as the district council for such assessment district, shall notify the owners of real property in such district that the plans and specifications for erosion prevention works in said district have been completed, can be inspected at its office and the probable cost of such erosion prevention work, and that upon a day certain to be named therein a hearing will be granted such owners at a place designated therein. Said notice, as far as practicable, shall be mailed to each property owner in such assessment district by placing the same in an envelope addressed to his last known address and depositing the same, postpaid, in a United States post office, and by publication thereof once a week for two successive weeks in a newspaper of general circulation published in the county.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">After affording such hearing, the commissioners, acting as district council for such district, shall determine whether or not to proceed with such erosion prevention works. In the event it shall determine to proceed therewith, it shall advertise, once a week for two successive weeks, in such newspaper, newspapers and technical press as it may deem proper, for bids for the construction of such erosion prevention works, in part or as a whole as in its judgment may appear advisable. The contract shall be let to the lowest responsible bidder, the commissioners reserving the right to reject any and all bids, and to readvertise for bids in accordance with and subject to the provisions of this subtitle. Before letting any such contract, said commissioners shall require a bond, approved by it, from the successful bidder in such penalty as said commissioners shall determine, conditioned for the completion of said work in accordance with said contract plans and specifications, within the time limited in said contract and for the payment for all supplies and labor furnished the contractor in the construction of said erosion prevention works. Said bond shall be enforceable in any court having jurisdiction.</section>
  </text>
</law>
