<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="g25" order_by="25" level="1">County Commisioners</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>g25-232</section_number>
  <catch_line>Subject to subsection (b) of this section, the governing body of a county may adopt an ordinance, re...</catch_line>
  <order_by>232</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Subject to subsection (b) of this section, the governing body of a county may adopt an ordinance, resolution, or regulation or take any other action that the governing body considers necessary to authorize a person to:<section prefix="(1)">Use the person's personal property or real estate to operate a seafood business;</section><section prefix="(2)">Buy or sell seafood;</section><section prefix="(3)">Store equipment used in the person's seafood business;</section><section prefix="(4)">Enjoy the quiet conduct of the person's seafood business in conformance with county and State requirements; and</section><section prefix="(5)">Harvest seafood.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Before adopting an ordinance, resolution, or regulation under subsection (a) of this section, the governing body of the county in which the ordinance, resolution, or regulation will apply shall:<section prefix="(i)">Hold a public hearing and provide reasonable notice of the hearing; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Obtain the written consent of the Secretary of Natural Resources.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">An ordinance, resolution, or regulation adopted without the written consent of the Secretary of Natural Resources is void and without legal effect.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">In the event of a conflict, federal law, State law, or written program guidance issued by a federal or State agency shall preempt any ordinance, resolution, or regulation adopted or any other action taken by the governing body of a county under this section.</section>
  </text>
</law>
