<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="g25" order_by="" level="1">County Commisioners</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>g25-162</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>162</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The county commissioners of the county are hereby authorized and empowered to act as the district council for each of said taxing and assessment districts, and, in carrying out the provisions of this subtitle, to use all the applicable power and authority vested in them by existing law and by this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Whenever it shall be deemed necessary by said county commissioners, acting as a district council for any said taxing and assessment districts, to take or acquire any land, structures or buildings, as an easement, for the construction, extension or maintenance of any erosion prevention works to prevent erosion by Chesapeake Bay and tributaries, or by any other stream or body of water in this State, in any of said taxing and assessment districts, it may purchase the same from the owner or owners, or, failing to agree with the owner or owners thereof, may condemn the same and any interest of any tenant, lessee or other person therein, by proceedings in the circuit court for the county as provided by Title 12 of the Real Property Article. At any time after ten days after the return and recordation of the verdict or award in said proceedings, the county commissioners, acting as the district council for the taxing and assessment district, may enter and take possession of the property so condemned, upon first paying to the clerk of the court the amount of said award and all costs taxed to date notwithstanding any appeal or further proceedings upon the part of the defendant or defendants; at the time of the payment, however, it shall give its corporate undertaking, acting as district council for the district proposed to be protected by said erosion prevention works, to abide by and fulfill any judgment on appeal or on further proceedings.</section>
  </text>
</law>
