<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="g25" order_by="" level="1">County Commisioners</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>g25-155A</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>155A</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The County Commissioners of Calvert County, by ordinance, may provide for the establishment of road construction districts. Two thirds of the property owners along the road route may present a written petition to the County Commissioners requesting the creation of a road construction district and requesting a road construction or repair project.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The County Commissioners shall set up a public hearing, shall notify the owners of real property in the proposed district of the time and place of the hearing by mailing a notice of the hearing addressed to each owner at his or her address as shown on the assessment records, and by giving notice of the time and place of the hearing in two newspapers of general circulation in the county for two consecutive weeks. At such hearing, the Commissioners shall determine the scope of the project and shall advise the property owners of the approximate cost and estimated individual levies. The Commissioners shall determine whether it is feasible to take the road into the county road system and to undertake the road construction or repair project; and whether upon completion of the project the road can be taken into the county road system in accordance with subsection (e). The Commissioners shall also determine whether to proceed with plans and specifications and shall set a date for final hearing which date may only be changed provided notice is given in accordance with this subsection.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">At the final hearing, the Commissioners shall establish the district and designate the area included within the district. The project scope, cost estimate, and estimated individual levies shall be provided. The estimated individual levies shall be based on the benefits accruing to each of the lots or parcels of land in the road construction district to the extent it is benefitted by the said road construction. The costs shall be paid back to the county by the property owners within a period of time to be determined by the County Commissioners. The County Commissioners shall determine whether interest is to be charged and, if so, the rate of interest. If the County Commissioners determine to proceed, they shall advertise for bids in the proper manner and let the contract to the lowest responsible bidder. Upon completion of the project, the Commissioners are empowered and directed to fix and levy a benefit charge upon all real property in the district. The benefit charge shall be sufficient to meet the costs of the project, including interest paid if a debt is created by the County Commissioners and administrative costs including notices to property owners and advertisements. The benefit charge shall be a lien upon the real property against which it is assessed and shall be paid annually as county taxes are required to be paid, by all the owners of lots or parcels of land in the district for the period of time previously established by the County Commissioners.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The County Commissioners have full power to agree and contract with owners for the purchase of land required for use in connection with the road construction district.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">Upon completion of the road construction project to county specifications the road shall be taken into the county road system.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The minimum right-of-way which may be purchased under this section is 30 feet.</section>
  </text>
</law>
