<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="g25" order_by="" level="1">County Commisioners</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>g25-16</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>16</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">This section applies only to commission counties and, unless otherwise provided by a local law enacted by a code county, code counties.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In case any office of county commissioner shall become vacant in any county by death, resignation or otherwise, the Governor, if such vacancy shall occur during the session of the Senate, shall, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate, appoint, and if such vacancy shall occur during the recess of the Senate, the Governor shall appoint a proper person or proper persons to fill such vacancy or vacancies; and the nomination of the person or persons thus appointed during such recess, or of some other person in his or their place, shall be made to the Senate within thirty days after the next meeting of the legislature.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Subject to subparagraph (ii) of this paragraph the Governor shall nominate or appoint the person to fill such vacancy whose name shall be submitted to the Governor in writing by the central committee of the political party with which the county commissioner, so vacating, has been affiliated in the particular county, provided that the nominee or appointee shall be of the same political party as the person whose office is to be filled; and it shall be the duty of the Governor to make the nomination or appointment within fifteen days after the submission of the name of the nominee or appointee to the Governor.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">In Garrett County, the nominee or appointee shall be a resident of the same commissioner district in which the former county commissioner resided.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">In the event there is no central committee in the county in which the vacancy occurs, the Governor shall appoint to fill the vacancy a person who has all the qualifications required for the office of county commissioner in the particular county.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">As to Allegany County, if there is no resident Senator from Allegany County in the Senate of Maryland at the time of the appointment, it shall be by and with the advice and consent of the House of Delegates of Maryland.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
