<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="g25" order_by="25" level="1">County Commisioners</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>g25-237</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this section the following words have the meanings indicated....</catch_line>
  <order_by>237</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Advisory Board" means the Garrett County Agricultural Preservation Advisory Board.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Commissioners" means the Garrett County Board of County Commissioners.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">This section applies only to Garrett County.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Commissioners shall adopt rules, regulations, and procedures for:<section prefix="(1)">The establishment and monitoring of agricultural districts; and</section><section prefix="(2)">The evaluation of land to be included in agricultural districts.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The rules, regulations, and procedures adopted by the Commissioners in accordance with this section shall provide that:<section prefix="(1)">One or more landowners actively devoted to agricultural use may file a petition with the Commissioners requesting the establishment of an agricultural district on the land owned by the petitioners;</section><section prefix="(2)">The petition filed in accordance with item (1) of this subsection includes maps and descriptions of the current use of land in the proposed district;</section><section prefix="(3)">On receipt of a petition to establish an agricultural district, the Commissioners shall refer the petition and accompanying materials to the Advisory Board and the county planning commission;</section><section prefix="(4)">Within 60 days after the referral of a petition, the Advisory Board shall advise the Commissioners:<section prefix="(i)">Whether the land in the proposed district meets the requirements established by the county under subsection (f) of this section; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Whether the Advisory Board recommends establishment of the district;</section></section><section prefix="(5)">Within 60 days after the referral of a petition, the county planning commission shall advise the Commissioners:<section prefix="(i)">Whether establishment of the district is compatible with existing or approved county plans and policy; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Whether the county planning commission recommends establishment of the district.</section></section><section prefix="(6)">If either the Advisory Board or the county planning commission recommends approval, the Commissioners shall hold a public hearing on the petition;</section><section prefix="(7)">Adequate notice of a hearing under item (6) of this subsection shall be made to:<section prefix="(i)">All landowners in the proposed district; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">The Maryland Agricultural Land Preservation Foundation;</section></section><section prefix="(8)">Within 120 days after the receipt of the petition or application, the Commissioners shall decide whether the proposed agricultural district will be established;</section><section prefix="(9)">The establishment of an agricultural district does not take effect until all landowners in the proposed district have executed an agreement with the Commissioners that:<section prefix="(i)">Is recorded in the county land records;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Requires a landowner to keep the landowner's land in agricultural use for a minimum of 3 years from the establishment of the agricultural district; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Maintains the right of a landowner to sell an easement for development rights on the land to the Maryland Agricultural Land Preservation Foundation;</section></section><section prefix="(10)">In the event of severe economic hardship, the Commissioners may release the landowner's property from the agricultural district;</section><section prefix="(11)">After meeting the minimum 3-year requirement in the agricultural district agreement under item (9) of this subsection, a landowner may terminate the property's designation as an agricultural district by notifying the Commissioners in writing 1 year before the desired date of termination;</section><section prefix="(12)">After the establishment of an agricultural district, the Commissioners may review the use of the land within the agricultural district; and</section><section prefix="(13)">The Commissioners may approve the alteration or termination of an agricultural district only if the use of the land within the agricultural district has changed so that the land within the district fails to meet the county requirements under subsection (f) of this section.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">Rules, regulations, or procedures adopted by the Commissioners under this section may not require a natural gas rights owner or lessee to subordinate its interest to the Commissioners' interest if the Commissioners determine that the exercise of the natural gas rights will not interfere with an agricultural operation conducted on land in the agricultural district or on land subject to an easement.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">Rules, regulations, or procedures adopted by the Commissioners relating to land that may be included in an agricultural district shall provide that:<section prefix="(1)">The land shall meet productivity, acreage, and locational criteria determined by the Commissioners to be necessary for the continuation of farming;</section><section prefix="(2)">The Commissioners shall attempt to preserve the minimum number of acres in a given agricultural district that may reasonably be expected to promote the continued availability of agricultural suppliers and markets for agricultural goods; and</section><section prefix="(3)">Land within the boundaries of a 10-year water and sewer service district may be included in an agricultural district only if, in the discretion of the Commissioners, that land is outstanding in productivity and is of significant size.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Land may be included in an agricultural district only if the county's rules, regulations, and procedures governing the land allow the activities listed under &#xA7; 2-513 of the Agriculture Article.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Agricultural districts may be established on any land in agricultural use, but only if the landowner agrees to the conditions, restrictions, and limitations under &#xA7; 2-513 of the Agriculture Article.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(h)">The Maryland Agricultural Land Preservation Foundation may not purchase an easement on land that is located in the county but that is outside of an agricultural district established under this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">This section may not be construed to preclude a landowner from selling the landowner's property.</section>
  </text>
</law>
