<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="g25" order_by="25" level="1">County Commisioners</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>g25-9B</section_number>
  <catch_line>The County Commissioners of Calvert County, in addition to but not in substitution for, the powers w...</catch_line>
  <order_by>9B</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The County Commissioners of Calvert County, in addition to but not in substitution for, the powers which may have been or may hereafter be granted to them, shall have the full power to secure an option upon, or to acquire by lease, purchase, condemnation, gift or devise, real or leasehold property needed for any public purpose, and to erect buildings thereon for the benefit of the county.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Immediately following the execution of any option to lease or purchase any real or leasehold property, the County Commissioners shall advertise:<section prefix="(i)">The optionee's name;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The purpose for which the option has been secured; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">The price and terms of the option.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The advertisement shall be published for at least three consecutive weeks in one or more newspapers of general circulation published in the county.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The County Commissioners are further authorized to lease or sell any real or leasehold property owned by the county when in their discretion it is no longer needed for public use.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">In case of a decision to sell any real or leasehold property on which is located any facility to or for which the county has made an appropriation in any year of $1,000 or more, the sale shall be made pursuant to sealed bids.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The offer to bid shall be advertised for at least three consecutive weeks in one or more newspapers published in the county, accurately describing the property and stating the time and place for opening the bids, and reserving the right to reject any and all bids.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The proposals shall be publicly opened at the time specified in the advertisement, and the property sold to the highest bidder, unless in the discretion of the County Commissioners the interests of the county would be better served by selling the property to some other bidder.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">In case of the rejection of all bids or if no bids are submitted, the County Commissioners may dispose of the property as they may deem desirable.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The County Commissioners of Calvert County may transfer, convey, or lease to the Calvert County Historical Society, Incorporated, the land and improvement known as Solomons Elementary School property, or any part thereof, for use as a public maritime museum without complying with the requirements of this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The property immediately shall revert to the county should it no longer be used as a museum open to the public.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The County Commissioners of Calvert County are authorized to:<section prefix="(i)">Provide funds for financing, in whole or in part, the purchase, construction, rehabilitation, or development of housing or a housing project in Calvert County; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Record a deed of trust, mortgage, or other instrument on the property upon which the housing or housing project is situated to ensure repayment of funds provided under subparagraph (i) of this paragraph.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The County Commissioners may implement the provisions of this subsection only by adoption of a resolution each time funds are provided under paragraph (1) of this subsection.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The County Commissioners shall hold a public hearing at least 10 days prior to any action on the proposed resolution required by subparagraph (i) of this paragraph.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">The County Commissioners shall publish notice of the public hearing, together with a synopsis of the proposed resolution, in at least 1 newspaper of general circulation in Calvert County once each week for 2 successive weeks prior to the public hearing.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The County Commissioners of Calvert County are authorized to convey any interest in real property to the United States of America, the State, or any other political subdivision or public instrumentality without consideration, if the property will be used for a public purpose.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The instrument of conveyance shall include a provision that if the property ever ceases to be used for a public purpose, the property shall revert to the county, unless the County Commissioners expressly waive receipt of the reversionary interest at the time the property ceases to be used for a public purpose.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Prior to conveying the property, the County Commissioners shall:<section prefix="(i)">Hold a public hearing at least 10 days prior to any action on the resolution required under this subsection;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Publish notice of the public hearing, together with a synopsis of the proposed resolution, in at least one newspaper of general circulation in the county once each week for 2 successive weeks prior to the public hearing; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Have an appraisal made of the real property for discussion at the public hearing.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
