<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="g25" order_by="25" level="1">County Commisioners</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>g25-9</section_number>
  <catch_line>This section applies only in Dorchester County....</catch_line>
  <order_by>9</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">This section applies only in Dorchester County.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The County Commissioners, in addition to, but not in substitution of, the powers which may have been or may hereafter be granted them, may acquire by lease, purchase, or condemnation, real or leasehold property needed for any public purpose, may erect buildings on the property for the benefit of the county, may sell at public sale any real or leasehold property belonging to the county when in their discretion it is no longer needed for public use, and may execute and acknowledge any and all deeds and other instruments necessary to effect and complete the lease, purchase, or sale of real or leasehold property.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, the County Commissioners may sell real or leasehold property without public sale to any municipality or other governmental agency within Dorchester County upon terms and conditions and for consideration, if any, which they consider proper, when in their discretion the property is no longer needed for public use by the county, and may execute and acknowledge any and all deeds and other instruments necessary to effect and complete the sale of the real or leasehold property.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The County Commissioners may not sell or lease the riparian rights adjacent to any real or leasehold property that belongs to Dorchester County and is located in the City of Cambridge unless the County Commissioners provide for the public sale or lease under a process that includes the following elements:<section prefix="(i)">A public advertisement, in at least one newspaper of general circulation in the county, soliciting sealed bids or proposals;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The public opening of sealed bids or proposals;</section><section prefix="(iii)">The rejection of unresponsive or unacceptable bids or proposals; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">The selection of the bidder or offeror who offers the terms most favorable to the county.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The County Commissioners may take any and all actions necessary to effectuate and complete the process of competitive bidding under paragraph (2) of this subsection.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The County Commissioners may lease real or leasehold property belonging to the county, in lieu of sale, to nonprofit organizations upon terms and conditions they deem proper, when in their discretion the real or leasehold property is no longer needed for public use, and to execute and acknowledge any instruments necessary to effect and complete the lease of the property.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The County Commissioners may sell real or leasehold property or any reversionary interest in that property without a public sale to any volunteer fire company located in the county for use in providing fire, emergency, and supporting services or facilities, upon the terms and conditions and for whatever consideration, if any, which they consider proper when in their discretion the property is no longer needed for public use by the county, and may execute and acknowledge any and all deeds and other instruments necessary to effect and complete the sale of real or leasehold property.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The County Commissioners may sell to the Dorchester County Family YMCA, Inc. all of the County Commissioners' right, title, and interest in and to that certain parcel of real property located at 201 Talbot Avenue, Cambridge, Maryland, and more particularly described in paragraph (2) of this subsection, upon the terms and conditions and for whatever consideration, if any, which they consider proper when in their discretion the property is no longer needed for public use by the county, and may execute and acknowledge any and all deeds and other instruments necessary to effect and complete the sale of the property.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The description of 201 Talbot Avenue is as follows:</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
