<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="g25" order_by="25" level="1">County Commisioners</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>g25-102</section_number>
  <catch_line>A majority of the landowners or the owners of a majority of the land in a public drainage associatio...</catch_line>
  <order_by>102</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">A majority of the landowners or the owners of a majority of the land in a public drainage association established under this subtitle may petition the board of county commissioners of the county in which such association was organized for the dissolution of the association. Such petition must be accompanied by a complete list of the creditors of the association, sworn to by the board of managers.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">In this section, "inactive association" means a public drainage association established under this subtitle that for at least 5 years has not substantially complied with the majority of ordinary operating procedures required under this subtitle including:<section prefix="(1)">The maintenance of ongoing and current information in the watershed file at the office of the clerk of the board of county commissioners;</section><section prefix="(2)">Elections of a board of managers and officers of the board;</section><section prefix="(3)">An annual meeting of owners of land within the association;</section><section prefix="(4)">The submission of an annual report by the board of managers to the clerk of the board of county commissioners;</section><section prefix="(5)">The development, approval, appropriate filing, execution, or maintenance of a work plan applicable to property owned by the association; and</section><section prefix="(6)">The submission and regular updating of the association's easement record in the office of the clerk of the circuit court in the applicable county.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Notwithstanding the requirements of this section, upon a written petition for dissolution by any member of the most recently elected or appointed board of managers of an association considered currently inactive, the board of county commissioners of the county in which the association was organized shall promptly:<section prefix="(1)">Provide public notice that the commissioners have received and are considering a petition for dissolution of an association and hold a public hearing to accept public comment before taking any action on the petition;</section><section prefix="(2)">Consider all available information to determine the current operating status and foreseeable operating potential of the association; and</section><section prefix="(3)">By majority vote, approve or deny the petition for dissolution.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">If the board of county commissioners approves a petition for dissolution under this section, the board shall:<section prefix="(1)">With any balance remaining in the county treasury to the credit of the dissolved association:<section prefix="(i)">Satisfy all outstanding debts of the association; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Distribute any remainder to the board of county commissioners; and</section></section><section prefix="(2)">Provide for the transfer of any interest in real property held by the inactive association to the county or counties in which the property is located.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
