<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="g25" order_by="" level="1">County Commisioners</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>g25-109</section_number>
  <catch_line>It shall be the further duty of the engineer and viewers to personally examine the land in the distr...</catch_line>
  <order_by>109</order_by>
  <text>It shall be the further duty of the engineer and viewers to personally examine the land in the district and classify it with reference to the benefit it will receive from the construction of the levee, ditch, drain or watercourse or other improvement. In the case of drainage, the degree of wetness of the land, its proximity to the ditch or a natural outlet and the fertility of the soil shall be considered in determining the amount of benefit it will receive by the construction of the ditch. The land benefited shall be separated into five classes: The land receiving the highest benefit shall be marked "Class A"; that receiving the next highest benefit "Class B"; that receiving the next highest benefit "Class C"; that receiving the next highest benefit "Class D"; and that receiving the smallest benefit "Class E". The holdings of any one landowner need not necessarily be all in one class, but the number of acres in each class shall be ascertained, though its boundary need not be marked on the ground or shown on the map. The total number of acres owned by one person in each class and the total number of acres benefited shall be determined. The total number of acres of each class in the entire district shall be ascertained and presented in tabulated form. The scale of assessment upon the several classes of land returned by the engineer and viewers shall be in the ratio of five, four, three, two and one; that is to say, as often as five mills per acre is assessed against the land in "Class A", four mills per acre shall be assessed against the land in "Class B", three mills per acre in "Class C", two mills per acre in "Class D", and one mill per acre in "Class E". This shall form the basis of the assessment of benefits to the lands for drainage purposes, and the basis of all future assessments, taxes, levies and costs connected with the drainage district, except as the same may be modified or changed under order of the board of county commissioners at the time of the final hearing or to conform to any decree of the courts.</text>
</law>
