<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="g25" order_by="" level="1">County Commisioners</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>g25-25</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>25</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">They shall have power to open, alter or close any public road or roads in their respective counties.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The county commissioners of the several counties may promulgate and enforce rules and regulations as to the maximum size and weight of motor vehicles, trucks, tractors and trailers that may be operated or used on their respective county roads. These rules and regulations shall have a reasonable relationship to the construction, use and character of the road or roads concerned, and shall be designed to assure the continued safety and good condition of any such road or roads. Any violation of any such rule and regulation is a misdemeanor, subject to a fine of not more than $1,000 or to imprisonment for not more than 60 days. The provisions of this subsection apply only to Allegany, Baltimore, Calvert, Carroll, Cecil, Frederick, Garrett, Harford, Howard, Montgomery, Prince George's, St. Mary's and Washington counties. A rule or regulation concerning maximum weight laws on county roads may not be greater than the maximum set by the public general laws of Maryland.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In accordance with the provisions of paragraph (2) of this subsection, the Board of County Commissioners of Charles County shall select county roads, or portions of county roads, under its jurisdiction that are not accessible for through traffic by trucks, tractors, or trailers that are over 26,000 pounds.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The selection of county roads, or portions of county roads, shall have a reasonable relationship to the construction, use, and character of the roads, and shall be designed to assure the continued safety and good condition of the roads.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Commissioners shall provide for the installation of traffic control devices that give notice of the restricted access to the selected roads on or at the entrances to the roads or the portions of the roads.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">Any violation of this subsection, or any ordinance or regulation adopted by the Commissioners under this subsection, is a misdemeanor, subject to a fine of not more than $1,000 or imprisonment for not more than 60 days or both.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
