<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="g25" order_by="25" level="1">County Commisioners</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>g25-236A</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this section, "animal control officer" means a county employee or a contract employee hired by th...</catch_line>
  <order_by>236A</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, "animal control officer" means a county employee or a contract employee hired by the county commissioners who is authorized:<section prefix="(1)">To provide animal control services; and</section><section prefix="(2)">To issue citations for violations of animal control ordinances in the county.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">This section applies only to Garrett County and Washington County.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The county commissioners may adopt an animal control ordinance to:<section prefix="(1)">Create a quasi-judicial deliberative animal control authority for the county to:<section prefix="(i)">Hold public hearings to decide citations, complaints, and other controversies arising under the animal control ordinance, other than those filed with the District Court, subject to the right of a party to file a petition for judicial review in the circuit court; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Adopt rules and regulations for the governance of its hearings;</section></section><section prefix="(2)">Designate an appropriate private agency or department of county government to:<section prefix="(i)">Enforce the provisions of the ordinance;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Maintain records regarding the licensing, impoundment, and disposition of animals coming into the custody of the private agency or department of county government; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Enter into contracts or agreements to provide for the disposal of animals;</section></section><section prefix="(3)">Provide for the designation of animal control shelters in the county;</section><section prefix="(4)">Specify rules and regulations that may include:<section prefix="(i)">The licensing of dogs, kennels, and pet shops;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The control of rabid animals; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">The disposition of uncontrolled, vicious, and sick animals; and</section></section><section prefix="(5)">Provide that a violation of the animal control ordinance is a misdemeanor punishable by imprisonment of up to 30 days or a fine of $1,000, or both for each offense.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">An animal control officer may deliver a citation to a person believed to be committing a violation of an animal control ordinance.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The animal control officer shall keep a copy of the citation.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The citation shall bear a certification attesting to the truth of the matters set forth in the citation.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The citation shall contain:<section prefix="(1)">The name and address of the person charged;</section><section prefix="(2)">The nature of the violation;</section><section prefix="(3)">The location and time of the violation;</section><section prefix="(4)">The amount of the fine;</section><section prefix="(5)">The manner, location, and time in which the fine may be paid; and</section><section prefix="(6)">The cited person's right to elect to stand trial for the violation.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A fine not exceeding $1,000 may be imposed for each violation.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The county commissioners also may:<section prefix="(i)">Establish a schedule of additional fines for each violation; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Adopt procedures for the collection of the fines.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A person who receives a citation may elect to stand trial for the offense by filing with the animal control officer a notice of intention to stand trial.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The person electing to stand trial shall give notice at least 5 days before the date set forth in the citation for the payment of fines.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">After receiving a notice of intention to stand trial, the animal control officer shall forward the notice to the District Court having venue, with a copy of the citation.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">After receiving the citation and notice, the District Court shall schedule the case for trial and notify the defendant of the trial date.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">All fines, penalties, or forfeitures collected by the District Court for violations of this title shall be remitted to the county in which the violation occurred.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(h)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If a person who receives a citation for a violation fails to pay the fine by the date of payment set forth on the citation and fails to file a notice of intention to stand trial, a formal notice of the violation shall be sent to the owner's last known address.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If the citation is not satisfied within 15 days after the date the formal notice of violation is mailed, the person shall be subject to an additional fine not exceeding twice the amount of the original fine.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">If the person who receives the citation does not pay the citation by the 36th day after the formal notice of violation is mailed, the animal control officer may request the District Court to adjudicate the violation.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">After the animal control officer requests adjudication, the District Court shall schedule the case for trial and summon the defendant to appear.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(i)">In a proceeding before the District Court, a violation of this title shall be prosecuted in the same manner and to the same extent as a municipal infraction under Article 23A, &#xA7; 3(b)(7) through (15) of the Annotated Code of Maryland.</section>
    <section prefix="(j)">The county commissioners may authorize the County Attorney, the State's Attorney, or another attorney to prosecute a violation of this title.</section>
    <section prefix="(k)">If the District Court finds that a person has committed a violation of this title, the person shall be liable for the costs of the court proceedings.</section>
  </text>
</law>
