<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="g25" order_by="" level="1">County Commisioners</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>g25-10B</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>10B</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Notwithstanding any other provisions of this article, the County Commissioners of Carroll County are authorized and empowered to regulate any public road, street, avenue, lane, alley or bridge within Carroll County which is not within the corporate limits of any incorporated city or town and which has not been designated or maintained as a part of the State or federal highway system or any extension thereof with respect to:<section prefix="(1)">The weight of vehicles thereon;</section><section prefix="(2)">The parking of vehicles thereon;</section><section prefix="(3)">The abandonment of vehicles thereon;</section><section prefix="(4)">The use thereof by private and public utilities in the construction and maintenance necessitated in the performance of their corporate purpose;</section><section prefix="(5)">The construction and maintenance of driveway connections where driveway connections to such road, street, avenue, lane, or alley are or are to be provided; and</section><section prefix="(6)">The speed of any vehicle on any road defined herein as being under the jurisdiction of the County Commissioners of Carroll County, provided, however, that any speed regulation adopted by the County Commissioners of Carroll County would not be legal without first having been recommended by the Department of State Police.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Where rules and regulations with respect to the weight of vehicles, the parking of vehicles and the speed of vehicles are adopted pursuant to subsection (a) of this section, the County Commissioners of Carroll County are directed to provide the appropriate traffic-control devices deemed necessary to indicate and carry out the rules and regulations so adopted. All such traffic-control devices shall conform to the State manual and specification.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The County Commissioners of Carroll County are authorized to promulgate and adopt, amend, revise, or rescind rules and regulations relative to the engineering, construction and acceptance of any new road, street, avenue, lane, alley, bridge or drainage system by the County Commissioners into the county roads system for maintenance by Carroll County.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The County Commissioners of Carroll County are authorized to provide that any person, firm, or corporation violating any regulation adopted pursuant to the authority conferred by this section shall be guilty of a misdemeanor and, upon conviction thereof, shall be fined a sum not to exceed twenty-five dollars ($25.00) exclusive of costs. In the event the fine so prescribed is in conflict with any other penalty provision of the public general laws of Maryland such other provision shall prevail.</section>
  </text>
</law>
