<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="g25" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="155B" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>g25-155B</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The County Commissioners of Calvert County, by ordinance, may provide for the establishment of stormwater management districts. Prior to the adoption of an ordinance establishing stormwater management districts, the County Commissioners shall adopt by ordinance, a comprehensive stormwater management plan. Two thirds of the property owners, or the owners of two thirds of the property within the area affected (defined for this section as the critical area generating the run-off water and all of the area flooded) may present a written petition to the County Commissioners requesting the creation of a stormwater management district and a stormwater management project.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Upon receipt of a valid petition, the County Commissioners shall set up a public hearing, shall notify the owners of real property in the proposed district of the time and place of the hearing by mailing a notice of the hearing addressed to each owner at his address as shown on the assessment records, and by giving notice of the time and place of the hearing in at least one newspaper of general circulation in the county for 2 consecutive weeks. At such hearing, the Commissioners, with the advice of the Calvert Soil Conservation District, shall determine the scope of the project and shall advise the property owners of the approximate cost and estimated levies. The Commissioners, with the advice of the Calvert Soil Conservation District, shall determine the extent to which the county shall assume responsibility for design, construction, and maintenance of the project, and fix responsibility for design, construction, and maintenance which is not to be assumed by the county. The Commissioners shall also determine whether to proceed with plans and specifications and shall set a date for final hearing which date may only be changed provided notice is given in accordance with this subsection.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">At the final hearing, the Commissioners may establish the district and designate the area included within the district. If established, the project scope, cost estimate, and estimated cost to be borne by the county, cost to be borne by other persons and parties, and estimated individual levies shall be provided. The estimated individual levies shall be based on the benefits accruing to each of the lots or parcels of land in the stormwater management district to the extent it is benefitted by the project, as determined by the Board of County Commissioners. The total cost of the project may be funded by the County Commissioners, with individual costs paid back to the county by property owners within a period of time and with an interest rate determined by the County Commissioners.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If the County Commissioners determine to proceed, they shall advertise for bids in the proper manner and let the contract to the lowest responsible bidder. Upon completion of the project, the Commissioners are empowered and directed to fix and levy a benefit charge upon all real property in the district. The benefit charge shall be sufficient to meet the costs of the project assessed to persons and parties. The benefit charge shall be a lien upon the real property against which it is assessed and shall be paid annually as county taxes are required to be paid, by all the owners of lots or parcels of land in the district for the period of time previously established by the County Commissioners.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The County Commissioners have full power to accept as gifts, and to agree and contract with owners for the purchase of land and easements required for use in connection with the stormwater management district.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">Upon completion of the project to county specifications, the county shall maintain those portions of the system located on county owned rights-of-way and drainage ways, and on drainage ways for which the county has accepted a permanent easement. All other portions of the system shall be maintained by a person or party owning the property. If such person or party fails to maintain his portion of the drainage system, the county, after due notice, may enter on that property and correct the drainage problems, with all costs for such actions to be charged as a lien upon the real property against which assessed.</section>
  </text>
</law>
