<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="g25" order_by="25" level="1">County Commisioners</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>g25-82A</section_number>
  <catch_line>The board of drainage viewers shall make out and return to the board of county commissioners and to ...</catch_line>
  <order_by>82A</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The board of drainage viewers shall make out and return to the board of county commissioners and to the State Soil Conservation Committee, at the earliest practical date, a written report, in triplicate, which shall set forth:<section prefix="(1)">Whether the proposed drainage is practical.</section><section prefix="(2)">Whether it will promote the public benefit or utility, or the public health, convenience or welfare.</section><section prefix="(3)">Whether the improvements proposed will benefit the lands in question sufficiently to warrant the probable expenditure.</section><section prefix="(4)">The names of all persons entitled to damages, and the amounts of same.</section><section prefix="(5)">The names of all persons entitled to compensation for adopted improvements previously constructed, and the amount of the same.</section><section prefix="(6)">The total estimated cost of the improvements, including damages, compensations, and organization expenses.</section><section prefix="(7)">The sum or amount which each owner or possessor or person benefited shall be assessed as his share of the total cost of the drainage improvements, and its proportion of the whole.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">They shall file with their report maps and profiles, likewise in triplicate, which shall show:<section prefix="(1)">The location of the proposed ditches or drains or other improvements on a map, drawings or aerial photograph to a suitable scale.</section><section prefix="(2)">A general delineation of the boundary of the area affected, with the general location in the county indicated.</section><section prefix="(3)">A general delineation of the boundaries of the lands within the area owned by each individual assessed, with an estimate of the acreage which each contains.</section><section prefix="(4)">The dimensions and profiles of the proposed ditches or drains or other improvements.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
