<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="g25" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="255" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>g25-255</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Board of County Commissioners of Somerset County shall cooperate within the terms of this section and subtitle for the construction of a nursing home hospital and related hospital facilities by contributions up to two hundred thousand dollars ($200,000.00) of the cost of this nursing home hospital and hospital facilities. The nursing home hospital so constructed shall be provided in the Town of Crisfield as a sixty-bed nursing home hospital adjoining McCready Hospital in that town, to be known as the Alice Byrd Tawes Nursing Home and to be on the same grounds as McCready Hospital, and to have a corridor connecting therewith. For this purpose the County Commissioners of Somerset County shall levy or appropriate from the general funds of the county up to a maximum of two hundred thousand dollars ($200,000.00); or they may (within the limits of any restriction upon their borrowing power) secure the payment of this sum by the issue of bonds or other certificates of indebtedness, pledging the full faith and credit of the county to the payment of interest and principal thereon.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The board of county commissioners or county council of every county in this State may cooperate within the terms of this section and subtitle for the construction and reconstruction of hospitals and related facilities, by contributions up to one third of the cost of any hospital or facility. For this purpose, the county commissioners or county council may levy or appropriate from the general funds of the county; or they may (within the limits of any restrictions upon their borrowing power) secure the necessary moneys or any portion thereof by the issue of bonds or other certificates of indebtedness, pledging the full faith and credit of the county to the payment of interest and principal thereon. For the purposes of this subsection, the Secretary of Health and Mental Hygiene as the sole agency to represent the State shall represent and cooperate with the county.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Board of County Commissioners of Kent County may cooperate within the terms of this section and subtitle for the construction of a nursing home and related facilities by contributions up to one third of the cost of this nursing home and facilities. The nursing home so constructed shall be at least a 25-bed nursing home. For this purpose the County Commissioners of Kent County may levy or appropriate from the general funds of the county; or they may (within the limits of any restriction upon their borrowing power) secure the necessary moneys or any portion thereof by the issue of bonds or other certificates of indebtedness, pledging the full faith and credit of the county to the payment of interest and principal thereon. For the purposes of this subsection, the Secretary of Health and Mental Hygiene, as the sole agency to represent the State, shall represent and cooperate with the Board of County Commissioners of Kent County.</section>
  </text>
</law>
