<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="g25" order_by="25" level="1">County Commisioners</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>g25-10K</section_number>
  <catch_line>The Board of County Commissioners of Calvert County may provide for:...</catch_line>
  <order_by>10K</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Board of County Commissioners of Calvert County may provide for:<section prefix="(1)">The enforcement and correction of violations of the Erosion and Sediment Control Ordinance of Calvert County, including the designation of the County Attorney or the State's Attorney to represent the interests of the county;</section><section prefix="(2)">The collection of the cost of these enforcement and corrective actions; and</section><section prefix="(3)">The enforcement of this section and of the Erosion and Sediment Control Ordinance by means of civil penalties as provided in this section.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If erosion and sediment control work does not comply with or conform to a permit or approved plans, and if Calvert County desires to obtain any performance bond that was required for the work, a written notice of noncompliance shall be sent by certified mail or be delivered by hand personally to the permittee and the surety.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The notice shall set forth the nature of the corrections required and the time within which the corrections shall be made. If the permittee does not act on the notice within the time set forth, or if the situation is deemed to be of a critical environmental nature, a stop-work notice shall be posted on the site and, except as permitted by the county engineer or a designee of the county engineer, no further work shall be permitted on the site.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">If the corrections are not commenced and diligently pursued within five days of notice:<section prefix="(i)">The permittee shall be considered in default of the obligations imposed by this section; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">The county engineer may take immediate action to obtain the security posted.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If in the discretion of the county engineer or a designee of the county engineer there is imminent and substantial environmental harm because of the instability of the site, the county may perform sufficient work at the site to eliminate public safety problems and to provide environmental stabilization and protection.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">It is a condition of each grading permit that the employees of the county engineering department or their approved designees may enter the site to undertake work in accordance with paragraph (1) of this subsection.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The cost of work performed by the county or its contractors under the provisions of this section shall:<section prefix="(i)">Be levied and collected from the owner of the property in the same manner as county real property taxes; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Have the same priority rights, bear the same interest and penalties, and in every respect be treated as county real property taxes.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The interest rate charged to the property owner shall be at the maximum legal rate.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Any person or contractor who violates any provision of the Erosion and Sediment Control Ordinance of Calvert County and who is issued a citation under this section shall:<section prefix="(i)">Be deemed to have committed a civil violation; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Pay to the county a civil fine in the amount prescribed under this subsection.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Each separate day of violation that remains uncorrected is a distinct civil violation subject to an additional citation and fine in the amount prescribed in this subsection.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The fine for each civil violation of the Erosion and Sediment Control Ordinance of Calvert County is:<section prefix="(i)">$250 for the first violation;</section><section prefix="(ii)">$500 for the second violation;</section><section prefix="(iii)">$750 for the third violation; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">$1,000 for each violation in excess of three.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Any erosion and sediment control work that is undertaken without first obtaining a permit shall be deemed to be a violation of the Erosion and Sediment Control Ordinance of Calvert County.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">In addition to the civil penalties provided under subsection (d) of this section, where work is undertaken without a permit, the county may enforce this section and take the same actions as those provided in this section for permit violations, including issuance of stop-work orders and performing work on site to eliminate public safety problems and to provide environmental stabilization and protection. The cost of this work shall be levied as provided under the provisions of subsection (c) of this section.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">On verification of a violation of the Erosion and Sediment Control Ordinance of Calvert County, an inspector from the engineering department may deliver or mail a citation to the person deemed responsible for committing the violation.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The citation shall serve as a notification to the person concerned that the person has been assessed a civil fine that is due and payable to the county, subject to the person's right to stand trial in District Court.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">The citation shall be on a form adopted by the Board of County Commissioners of Calvert County, which shall include:<section prefix="(1)">The date of issuance of the citation;</section><section prefix="(2)">The name and address of the person charged;</section><section prefix="(3)">The section number of the Erosion and Sediment Control Ordinance that has been violated;</section><section prefix="(4)">The nature of the violation;</section><section prefix="(5)">The place where and time when the violation occurred;</section><section prefix="(6)">The amount of the civil fine assessed;</section><section prefix="(7)">The manner, location, and time period in which the fine is to be paid;</section><section prefix="(8)">Where applicable, the notice that each day of continued violation thereafter shall be deemed a separate violation subject to additional citation;</section><section prefix="(9)">The name, business address, and telephone number of the county official cognizant of the case; and</section><section prefix="(10)">The person's right to elect to stand trial for the violation, and instructions and timing necessary for this right to stand trial.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(h)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A person who receives a citation may elect to stand trial for the offense by filing with the county office concerned a notice of intention to stand trial.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The notice shall be given at least five days before the date of payment as set forth in the citation.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">On receipt of the notice of intention to stand trial, the county shall forward to the District Court a copy of the citation and the notice of intention to stand trial.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">On receipt of the citation, the District Court shall schedule the case for trial and notify the defendant of the trial date.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(i)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If a person who receives a citation for a violation fails to pay the fine by the date of payment set forth in the citation and fails to file a timely notice of intention to stand trial, a formal notice of the violation shall be sent to the person's last address, if known. If the citation is not satisfied within 15 days from the date of the notice, the person is liable for an additional fine not to exceed twice the original fine. If, after 35 days, the citation is not satisfied, the county may request adjudication of the case through the District Court.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The District Court shall schedule the case for trial and summon the defendant to appear.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(j)">The County Attorney or the State's Attorney, whichever is designated by the Board of County Commissioners under subsection (a) of this section, shall prosecute a civil violation under this section before the District Court.</section>
  </text>
</law>
