<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="g25a" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="5" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>g25a-5</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>The following enumerated express powers are granted to and conferred upon any county or counties which hereafter form a charter under the provisions of Article XI-A of the Constitution, that is to say:<section prefix=""><section prefix="(1)">To enact local laws for the county, including the power to repeal or amend local laws of the county enacted by the General Assembly upon the matters covered by the express powers in this article.</section><section prefix="(2)">To provide for the enforcement of all ordinances, resolutions, bylaws and regulations adopted under the authority of this article by fines, penalties and imprisonment, enforceable according to law as may be prescribed. A penalty may not exceed $1,000 for any offense, unless otherwise authorized in this subsection, or provide for imprisonment for more than six months.</section><section prefix="(3)">To provide for the enforcement of local fair housing laws by fines or penalties that do not exceed the fines or penalties provided in the federal Fair Housing Act Amendments of 1988 for enforcement of similar federal fair housing laws.</section><section prefix="(4)">To provide for the enforcement of local employment discrimination laws or public accommodations discrimination laws by fines or penalties that do not exceed $5,000 for any offense.</section><section prefix="(5)">To provide for enforcement of all ordinances, resolutions, bylaws, and regulations adopted under the authority of this article by civil fines and penalties.</section></section><section prefix="(1)">To provide, as far as necessary, for the draining of swamp and lowlands.</section><section prefix="(2)">With regard to a redetermination as to which lands continue to benefit from a prior drainage improvement project:<section prefix="(i)">At the request of the board of managers of a drainage association, the county council shall appoint a board of viewers to determine if the original determination as to which lands have benefited from the improvements has changed;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The board of viewers shall have the same qualifications, rights, powers, privileges, and duties as the original board of viewers;</section><section prefix="(iii)">The board of viewers shall report its findings to the county council. The report shall be considered in the same manner as the original report, including the same right to a public hearing and the right to judicial review; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">Any revision in the original determination as to which lands benefit from the improvements shall become the basis for all future assessments for paying for the improvements, including related expenses such as damages, and the maintenance of the improvements.</section></section><section prefix="(1)">To provide for the borrowing of moneys on the faith and credit of the county and for the issuance of bonds or other evidences of indebtedness therefor in such sums, for such purposes, on such terms and payable at such times, and from such taxes or other sources as may have been or may be provided by or pursuant to local law, subject to any limitations imposed by the charter adopted by the county and to the following limitations:<section prefix="(i)">The aggregate amount of bonds and other evidences of indebtedness outstanding at any one time shall not exceed a total of 6 percent of the assessable basis of real property of the county and 15 percent of the county's assessable basis of personal property and operating real property described in &#xA7; 8-109(c) of the Tax - Property Article of the county, except that (a) tax anticipation notes or other evidences of indebtedness having a maturity not in excess of 12 months, (b) bonds or other evidences of indebtedness issued or guaranteed by the county payable primarily or exclusively from taxes levied in or on, or other revenues of, special taxing areas or districts heretofore or hereafter established by law, and (c) bonds or other evidences of indebtedness issued for self-liquidating and other projects payable primarily or exclusively from the proceeds of assessments or charges for special benefits or services, shall not be subject to, or be included as bonds or evidences of indebtedness in computing or applying, the limitations established in this section.</section><section prefix="(ii)">Any local law authorizing the borrowing of money or issuance of bonds or other evidences of indebtedness shall be submitted to the registered voters of the county for approval or rejection, if a petition for such submission is filed pursuant to the provisions of the charter and local laws of the county. If the charter contains no such provisions, any local law authorizing the borrowing of money or issuance of bonds or other evidences of indebtedness shall be submitted to the registered voters of the county for approval or rejection, if a petition for such submission, bearing the signatures of 10 per centum or more of such voters, is filed with the board of supervisors of elections of the county within 75 days after the enactment of such local law.</section></section><section prefix="(2)">To provide for the issuance of bonds or other obligations payable as to principal and interest and premium, if any, solely from the funds or revenues received from or in connection with any system, project, or undertaking, all or part of which is financed from the proceeds of such bonds or obligations. Bonds or obligations issued under this paragraph do not constitute an indebtedness of the county or a pledge of its faith and credit or taxing power, may be sold at private (negotiated) sale, and are not subject to the limitations of paragraph (1) of this subsection, Article 31, &#xA7;&#xA7; 10 and 11 of the Code, or any provision of the issuing county's charter. Nothing in this paragraph shall be construed as a limitation on the power of a county to issue revenue bonds under the provision of any other applicable law.</section><section prefix="(3)">The bonds, notes, and any other evidences of obligation issued under this section, their transfer, the interest payable on them, and any income derived from them, including any profit realized in their sale or exchange, shall be exempt at all times from every kind and nature of taxation by this State, or by any of its political subdivisions, municipal corporations or public agencies of any kind.</section><section prefix="(1)">To provide for the appointment and removal of all county officers except those whose appointment or election is provided for by the Constitution or public general law, and to establish a merit system, if deemed desirable, in connection with the appointment of all county officials and employees not elected or appointed under the Constitution and the public general laws; to fix the qualifications and term of office of such county executive authority as may be established, and to fix its compensation; provided that the county council may enact local laws designed to prevent conflicts between the private interests and public duties of any county officers, including members of the county council, and to govern the conduct and actions of all such county officers in the performance of their public duties, and to provide for penalties, including removal from office, for violation of any such laws or the regulations adopted thereunder.</section><section prefix="(2)">To provide for the conduct of a special election to fill a vacancy in the county council that occurs upon the death or resignation of a member of the county council or on forfeiture of office by a member of the county council.</section><section prefix="(1)"><section prefix="(i)">To enact local laws, for the protection and promotion of public safety, health, morals, and welfare, relating to zoning and planning, including:<section prefix="1.">The power to provide for the right of appeal of any matter arising under such planning and zoning laws to the circuit court, except as is provided in &#xA7; 5(U) of this article. Any decision of the circuit court may be appealed to the Court of Special Appeals; and</section><section prefix="2.">The power to establish a program for the transfer of development rights.</section></section><section prefix="(ii)">To provide by ordinance that a violation of a zoning law or regulation enacted under this section may be a civil zoning violation. The violation shall be enforced as provided in Title 11, Subtitle 2 of the Land Use Article.</section></section><section prefix="(2)"><section prefix="(i)">It has been and shall continue to be the policy of this State that the orderly development and use of land and structures requires comprehensive regulation through implementation of planning and zoning controls.</section><section prefix="(ii)">It has been and shall continue to be the policy of this State that planning and zoning controls shall be implemented by local government.</section><section prefix="(iii)">To achieve the public purposes of this regulatory scheme, the General Assembly recognizes that local government action will displace or limit economic competition by owners and users of property.</section><section prefix="(iv)">It is the policy of the General Assembly and of this State that competition and enterprise shall be so displaced or limited for the attainment of the purposes of the State policy for implementing planning and zoning controls as set forth in this article and elsewhere in the public local and public general law.</section><section prefix="(v)">The powers granted to the county pursuant to this paragraph shall not be construed:<section prefix="1.">To grant to the county powers in any substantive area not otherwise granted to the county by other public general or public local law;</section><section prefix="2.">To restrict the county from exercising any power granted to the county by other public general or public local law or otherwise;</section><section prefix="3.">To authorize the county or its officers to engage in any activity which is beyond their power under other public general law, public local law, or otherwise; or</section><section prefix="4.">To preempt or supersede the regulatory authority of any State department or agency under any public general law.</section></section></section><section prefix="(1)">As to each authority it establishes, the county governing body:<section prefix="(i)">Shall specify the membership, organization, jurisdiction, and geographical limits of the authority;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Shall specify one or more of the following as the purposes of the authority:<section prefix="1.">Promotion;</section><section prefix="2.">Marketing; and</section><section prefix="3.">The provision of security, maintenance, or amenities within the district;</section></section><section prefix="(iii)">May specify the provisions of the county charter or local law relating to personnel, procurement, or similar operational matters that apply or do not apply to the authority, except that minority business enterprise procurement and equal employment opportunity laws may not be waived;</section><section prefix="(iv)">May approve the annual budget of the authority if the county governing body levies an ad valorem tax to support the authority; and</section><section prefix="(v)">May provide such financing as it deems appropriate for the authority through fees which may be charged to, or taxes which may be levied against, businesses subject to the authority's jurisdiction.</section></section><section prefix="(2)">An authority established pursuant to this subsection may not:<section prefix="(i)">Exercise the power of eminent domain;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Purchase, sell, construct, or, as a landlord, lease office or retail space; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">Except as otherwise authorized by law, otherwise engage in competition with the private sector.</section></section><section prefix="(3)">Any fees or taxes imposed under this subsection shall be used only for the purposes stated in this subsection and may not revert to the general fund of the county.</section><section prefix="(4)">The county governing body may establish an authority pursuant to this subsection as a special taxing district.</section></text>
</law>
