<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="g25a" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="7" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>g25a-7</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">At the end of each calendar or fiscal year, each charter county shall furnish in a convenient and legible compilation a complete set of all laws enacted during that year under the "Express Powers Act" in &#xA7; 5 of this article, whether to enact, amend, or repeal a local law.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The laws in the compilation shall be in numerical sequence, beginning with No. 1, and in a separate series for each year.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Copies of this compilation shall be:<section prefix="(i)">Made available for inspection at the office of the county council, county executive, or county manager, during normal business hours; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Kept on permanent record in the same office.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Each charter county shall:<section prefix="(i)">Furnish printed copies of the compilation to the State Archives and the State Law Library; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Once each year:</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Copies under paragraph (2) of this subsection shall be furnished without charge, and the county also may make other copies available at a reasonable cost to any person.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Not later than March 1 of the next succeeding year, the charter county, without charge, shall furnish 4 printed copies of the compilation to the State Department of Legislative Services.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Each charter county shall provide to the State Department of Legislative Services a statement concerning any referendum on any proposed local law.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The statement shall include information on the results of any referendum held during the year, and it shall include information as to any referendum pending actually or potentially, but not yet held, at the end of the year.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">At the end of each calendar year the State Department of Legislative Services shall address an inquiry to each charter county inquiring whether or not during that calendar year or its latest fiscal year it has enacted, amended or repealed any portion of its laws under the "Express Powers Act".</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The charter county shall promptly answer the inquiry and shall verify that printed copies of all such enactments, amendments, or repeals have already been sent to the Department.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If the charter county fails or refuses to supply printed copies of this compilation and of the results of any referenda thereon to the State Department of Legislative Services by March 1 of the next succeeding year, or fails or refuses to certify that there have been no such enactments, amendments, or repeals, or referenda, during the last calendar or fiscal year, the Department shall promptly certify that fact to the State Comptroller, who then may order the discontinuance of all funds, grants or State aid which the charter county is entitled to receive under State law.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">This section refers specifically to all funds, grants or State aid which the charter county is entitled to receive under applicable provisions of State law relating to the income tax, the tax on racing, the recordation tax, the admissions and amusement tax, and the license tax.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The State Department of Legislative Services shall receive the compilations and statements delivered to it.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The titles of the laws of the several charter counties which amend their codes of public local laws shall be arranged in a logical and convenient order and shall be delivered to the State printer for inclusion in the Session Laws of the General Assembly for its regular session in that year.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The titles of the laws of the charter counties which amend their codes of public local laws shall be printed and identified as such, and they shall be indexed with or in a supplemental volume to the laws enacted by the General Assembly.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(h)">Whenever the county council of any county in this State publishes or issues in printed, mimeographed, or similar duplicated form a code or compilation containing all or a portion of the public local laws of the county, the council shall deposit printed copies free of charge with the following State agencies: State Archives, 1 copy; State Law Library, 1 copy; State Department of Legislative Services, 5 copies.</section>
  </text>
</law>
