<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="g25b" order_by="" level="1">Home Rule for Code Counties</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>g25b-13C-1</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>1</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Curfew hours" means 12:00 a.m. until 5:00 a.m.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Emergency" means a sudden or unexpected happening or an unforeseen combination of circumstances that calls for immediate action to protect the health, safety, welfare, or property of an individual from actual or threatened harm or from an unlawful act.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">"Establishment" means a privately owned place of business operated for a profit to which the public is invited.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">"Guardian" means a person who is appointed by a court as a guardian of a minor.</section>
      <section prefix="(6)">
        <section prefix="(i)">"Public place" means a place to which the general public has access and a right to resort for business, entertainment, or other lawful purpose.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">"Public place" includes:<section prefix="1.">A public street, sidewalk, alley, highway, and right-of-way of a public street or highway; and</section><section prefix="2.">The common areas of a transport facility, school, hospital, apartment building, office building, shopping center, park, playground, parking lot, theater, restaurant, bowling alley, tavern, cafe, arcade, and shops.</section></section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(7)">"Remain" means to:<section prefix="(i)">Linger or stay unnecessarily in a public place; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">Fail to leave the premises of an establishment or public place when asked by a local law enforcement officer or employee of the establishment or public place.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The provisions of this section apply to code counties in the Eastern Shore class as established by Article 25B, &#xA7; 2.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">After making independent factual findings demonstrating a local need for a juvenile curfew, the county commissioners in their respective jurisdictions may adopt a juvenile curfew ordinance which may be adopted by a municipal corporation in the county.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A juvenile curfew ordinance shall state that:<section prefix="(1)">A minor may not remain in a public place or on the premises of an establishment within the local jurisdiction during curfew hours;</section><section prefix="(2)">A parent or guardian of a minor may not knowingly allow the minor to remain in a public place or on the premises of an establishment within the local jurisdiction during curfew hours; and</section><section prefix="(3)">The owner, operator, or employee of an establishment may not knowingly allow a minor to remain on the premises of the establishment within the local jurisdiction during curfew hours.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">A juvenile curfew ordinance adopted under this section does not apply to a minor who is:<section prefix="(1)">Accompanied by the minor's parent or guardian;</section><section prefix="(2)">Performing an errand at the direction of the minor's parent or guardian, without a detour or stop, until 12:30 a.m.;</section><section prefix="(3)">Accompanied by a person at least 18 years of age and authorized by the minor's parent or guardian to have temporary care or custody of the minor for a designated period of time within a specified area;</section><section prefix="(4)">With consent of the minor's parent or guardian, involved in interstate travel through the local jurisdiction or beginning or ending in the local jurisdiction;</section><section prefix="(5)">Engaged in legal employment activity or is going to or returning home from a legal employment activity;</section><section prefix="(6)">Involved in an emergency;</section><section prefix="(7)">On the property where the minor resides or on the sidewalk abutting the minor's residence or abutting the residence of a next-door neighbor, if the adult resident of that property has given permission for the minor's presence;</section><section prefix="(8)">Attending or returning directly home from:<section prefix="(i)">A school, religious, or recreational activity supervised by adults and sponsored by the local jurisdiction, a civic organization, or a voluntary association that takes responsibility for the minor; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">A place of public entertainment, including a movie, play, or sporting event;</section></section><section prefix="(9)">Exercising First Amendment rights under the United States Constitution, if the minor has first submitted to the chief of the local law enforcement agency a written communication that:<section prefix="(i)">Is signed by the minor and countersigned, if practicable, by the parent or guardian of the minor;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Includes the parent's or guardian's home address and telephone number; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Specifies when, where, and in what manner the minor will be in a public place during curfew hours; or</section></section><section prefix="(10)">Remaining in a public place in a case of reasonable necessity if the minor's parent or guardian has communicated to the chief of the local law enforcement agency facts:<section prefix="(i)">Establishing the reasonable necessity; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Designating:<section prefix="1.">The specific public place and the points of origin and destination for the minor's travel; and</section><section prefix="2.">The times the minor will be in the public place or traveling to or from the public place.</section></section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If a law enforcement officer reasonably believes that a minor is in a public place or on the premises of an establishment in violation of the juvenile curfew ordinance, the officer shall:<section prefix="(i)">Notify the minor that the minor is in violation of the juvenile curfew ordinance;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Require the minor to tell the officer the minor's name, address, telephone number, and where to contact the minor's parent or guardian;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Issue the minor a written warning that the minor is in violation of the juvenile curfew ordinance; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">Order the minor to promptly go home.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The chief of the local law enforcement agency shall send written notice of the violation of the juvenile curfew ordinance to the minor's parent or guardian.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">The local law enforcement agency may take the minor:<section prefix="(1)">To the minor's home, if appropriate; or</section><section prefix="(2)">Into custody and transport the minor to a local law enforcement station or designated curfew center when:<section prefix="(i)">The minor has received one previous written warning for a violation of the juvenile curfew ordinance;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The local law enforcement officer has reasonable grounds to believe that the minor has committed a delinquent act; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">Taking the minor into custody is authorized under &#xA7; 3-8A-14 of the Courts Article.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(h)">When a minor is taken into custody for a violation of the juvenile curfew ordinance, the local law enforcement officer shall:<section prefix="(1)">Immediately notify the parent or guardian of the minor to come to the local law enforcement station to take custody of the minor; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Determine whether, consistent with constitutional safeguards, the minor or the parent or guardian, or both, are in violation of the juvenile curfew ordinance.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(i)">
      <section prefix="(1)">When a parent or guardian arrives at the local law enforcement station as a result of subsection (h) of this section, and the appropriate information is recorded, the minor shall be released to the custody of the parent or guardian.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If the parent or guardian cannot be located or fails to take charge of the minor, then the minor shall be released to the local Department of Social Services, the Department of Juvenile Services, or to another adult who will, on behalf of the parent or guardian, assume the responsibility of caring for the minor pending the availability or arrival of the parent or guardian.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(j)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A law enforcement officer may issue a civil citation for a violation of a juvenile curfew ordinance to:<section prefix="(i)">A minor;</section><section prefix="(ii)">A parent or guardian of a minor; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">An owner, operator, or employee of an establishment.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The civil citation shall include a fine of:<section prefix="(i)">Not more than $500 for a first offense; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">Not more than $1,000 for a second or subsequent offense.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
