<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="g25b" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="13A" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>g25b-13A</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Unless otherwise specifically provided by the laws of Maryland, a code county, and every officer, department, agency, board, commission, or other unit of county government may not raise the defense of sovereign immunity in the courts of this State in an action in contract based upon a written contract executed on behalf of the county, or its department, agency, board, commission, or unit by an official or employee acting within the scope of his authority.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">In any action in contract described under subsection (a) of this section, the county, or its officer, department, agency, board, commission, or other unit of government shall have the immunity from liability described under &#xA7; 5-510 of the Courts and Judicial Proceedings Article.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A claim is barred unless the claimant files suit within one year from the date on which the claim arose or within one year after the completion of the contract giving rise to the claim, whichever is later.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">In order to provide for the implementation of this section, the governing body of every code county shall make available adequate funds for the satisfaction of any final judgment, after the exhaustion of any right of appeal, which has been rendered against the county, or any officer, department, agency, board, commission, or other unit of government in an action in contract as provided in this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">Except as provided in subsections (f) and (g) of this section, a code county may not require in a construction contract, or otherwise provide with regard to a construction contract, to which it is a party, that a dispute between the parties involving $10,000 or more regarding the terms of the contract or performance under the contract, be subject to final binding or conclusive determination by an officer or official body of a code county.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">A code county may require or provide, with regard to a construction contract, to which it is a party, that if there is a dispute regarding the terms of the contract or performance under the contract, the question or questions involved in the dispute shall be subject to a determination which is final and conclusive on all parties, made either by:<section prefix="(1)">A neutral person or entity selected by or in accordance with a procedure established by the highest executive authority of a code county, or</section><section prefix="(2)">In the event that the other party does not accept as neutral a person or entity selected under paragraph (1) of this subsection, by an arbitration panel composed of the following:<section prefix="(i)">One member designated by the highest executive authority of a code county;</section><section prefix="(ii)">One member designated by the other party to the dispute; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">One member to be selected by mutual agreement of the two designated members from lists to be submitted by the parties to the dispute.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(g)">Notwithstanding the provisions of subsections (e) and (f) of this section, a code county may provide or require, with regard to a construction contract to which it is a party, that a dispute between the parties involving $10,000 or more regarding the terms of the contract or performance under the contract, be subject to a determination of questions of fact by an officer or official body of a code county, provided that the decision of the officer or official body of a code county is subject to review on the record by a court of competent jurisdiction.</section>
  </text>
</law>
