<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="g25b" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="13H" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>g25b-13H</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Food", "premises", and "substantial grocery or market business" have the meanings stated in &#xA7; 11-206 of the Tax - General Article.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Beverage" does not include an alcoholic beverage, as defined in &#xA7; 5-101 of the Tax - General Article, if the alcoholic beverage is sold for consumption off the premises.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">"Convention center facility" means a convention center of at least 150,000 net square feet, that is used for the holding of conventions, trade shows, meetings, displays, entertainment shows, or similar events but does not have lodging facilities.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">"Resort area" means any portion or portions of a county, as specified by the county commissioners of the county, that:<section prefix="(i)">By reason of natural, scenic, or man-made attractions or development, has or have an unusual influx of visitors, sojourners, and temporary residents; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">By reason of the influx requires municipal services in unusual number or magnitude.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(6)">"Taxable price" has the meaning stated in &#xA7; 11-101 of the Tax - General Article.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as otherwise provided in this section, the county commissioners of a code county, by public local law, may impose a tax on the sale of food and beverages in a resort area in the county for the sole purpose of providing revenues to pay the principal and interest on bonds issued relating to the construction, reconstruction, repair, renovation, or equipping of a convention center facility in the resort area. The total outstanding principal amount of the bonds issued by the local governing body for this purpose may not exceed $20,000,000.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Before passing a public local law imposing a tax under this section or altering the amount of the tax, the county commissioners shall hold a public hearing.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">Notice of the hearing shall be published in at least one newspaper of general circulation in the county not less than 3 or more than 14 days before the hearing.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">The notice shall state the subject of the hearing and the time and place that the hearing will occur.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A tax imposed under this section does not apply to:<section prefix="(1)">A sale of food that is exempt from the State sales and use tax under &#xA7; 11-206 of the Tax - General Article;</section><section prefix="(2)">A sale of food or beverages for consumption off the premises if sold by a vendor that operates a substantial grocery or market business at the same location where the food is sold, even if the sale is subject to the State sales and use tax under Title 11 of the Tax - General Article; or</section><section prefix="(3)">A sale of food or beverages in vending machines.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A tax imposed under this section may not exceed 1% of the taxable price of a sale of food and beverages that are subject to the tax.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">A tax imposed under this section shall be:<section prefix="(1)">Collected from the buyer on behalf of the county by the vendor who makes a sale that is subject to the tax; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Held in trust by the vendor for the county.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A vendor required to collect a tax imposed under this section shall file a return with the county on or before the 21st day of each month.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A return required under this section:<section prefix="(i)">Shall be made on the form that the county requires; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Shall contain the information that the county requires, including:</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A vendor who makes a sale that is subject to a tax imposed under this section shall pay the tax that the vendor collects for that sale with the return that covers the period in which the vendor makes that sale.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">For the expense of collection and remittance of a tax imposed under this section, a vendor who timely files a return and remits the tax may deduct an amount equal to 1.5% of the gross tax collected by the vendor.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(h)">The county commissioners may provide by law for:<section prefix="(1)">The imposition of interest and penalties for failure to pay the tax as required; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Collection of unpaid tax, interest, or penalties.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(i)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The State Comptroller shall provide a county that imposes a tax under this section with information to help the county verify liability for the tax.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Comptroller may charge a county a reasonable fee for the cost of providing information.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(j)">From the total revenue derived from a tax imposed under this section, the county commissioners shall:<section prefix="(1)">Deduct a reasonable percentage not to exceed 5% for the cost of imposing and collecting the tax; and</section><section prefix="(2)">After the deduction in item (1) of this subsection, distribute the revenue to the appropriate authority to be deposited in a sinking fund and used for the sole purpose of paying the principal and interest on bonds issued relating to a convention center facility in accordance with the provisions of subsection (b)(1) of this section.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(k)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If any tax is imposed by a county governing body in accordance with the provisions of this section, the authority to impose the tax in that county shall terminate at the end of the month in which sufficient revenues have been generated to pay in full the maturing principal of and interest on any bonds issued relating to a convention center in accordance with the provisions of subsection (b)(1) of this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The county commissioners shall notify the Comptroller of the State as to the month in which the authority to impose the tax expires.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
