<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="g25b" order_by="" level="1">Home Rule for Code Counties</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>g25b-13E-1</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>1</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section, "local community" means an incorporated or unincorporated community, other than a municipal corporation, with a governing body or governing board that is elected by the property owners or residents of the community.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Local community" may include a community association or similar association or a special taxing district if the association or district has a governing body or governing board elected by the property owners or residents of the community.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">This section only applies if a code county establishes a Department of Public Facilities and Services and assumes the responsibilities of a sanitary district or commission or a water or sewer authority under &#xA7; 13E of this article.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Subject to subsections (d) and (e) of this section, the county commissioners of a code county may enter into an agreement with the governing body of a municipal corporation or of a local community that transfers responsibility for water or sewerage services to the municipal corporation or local community.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">An agreement made under this section shall be in writing and shall require that:<section prefix="(1)">The municipal corporation or local community continues to serve any area, within or outside its boundaries, that is served by the facilities transferred when the transfer occurs;</section><section prefix="(2)">Any increase in fees or taxes for water or sewerage services following the transfer be applied uniformly within and outside the boundaries of the municipal corporation or local community;</section><section prefix="(3)">The municipal corporation or local community, in accordance with the agreement, assumes legal responsibility for the payment of principal and interest on any applicable outstanding bonds issued by the county or by a water or sewer authority or a sanitary district or commission with respect to facilities being transferred to the municipal corporation or local community;</section><section prefix="(4)">The disposal of sewage sludge by the municipal corporation or local community be conducted in accordance with county regulations;</section><section prefix="(5)">The municipal corporation or local community honors, in accordance with the agreement, any obligation that exists when the transfer occurs, for the treatment at a treatment facility of leachate generated at a landfill in the county;</section><section prefix="(6)">The municipal corporation or local community complies with the terms of any grant or requirement involving a federal or State agency concerning facilities or operations transferred to the municipal corporation under the agreement; and</section><section prefix="(7)">Any revenues from an entity abolished under &#xA7; 13E of this article and transferred under the agreement remain dedicated for the purpose collected and are not transferred into the municipal corporation or local community's general fund.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The agreement made under this section shall specify:<section prefix="(1)">The obligation of the parties to cooperate in the operation of any laboratory, the sharing of equipment, and other related matters in which the county and municipal corporation or local community might mutually benefit;</section><section prefix="(2)">The obligation of the parties to satisfy any vested retirement rights for employees who transfer from the county to the municipal corporation or local community under the agreement;</section><section prefix="(3)">The obligation of the parties to assure the maintenance of salary levels, retirement benefits, insurance benefits, vacation benefits, leave time, seniority levels, and other employee benefits, which are in effect for county employees who transfer to the municipal corporation or local community under the agreement; and</section><section prefix="(4)">Any other matter relating to water or sewerage services on which the county and municipal corporation or local community agree that are consistent with this section.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
