<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="g25b" order_by="25" level="1">Home Rule for Code Counties</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>g25b-13E</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this section, "Department" means a Department of Public Facilities and Services....</catch_line>
  <order_by>13E</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, "Department" means a Department of Public Facilities and Services.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The county commissioners of a code county, by public local law, may:<section prefix="(1)">Establish a Department of Public Facilities and Services; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Provide for the organization and functions of the Department.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The county commissioners may assign to the Department:<section prefix="(1)">Responsibility for construction, maintenance, repair, service, and management of:<section prefix="(i)">Public works, public buildings, publicly owned water and sewerage facilities and projects, and capital projects;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Water supply facilities and projects;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Wastewater collection, treatment, and disposal facilities and projects;</section><section prefix="(iv)">Solid waste collection, recycling, and disposal facilities and projects;</section><section prefix="(v)">Storm drainage, erosion, and sediment control facilities and projects;</section><section prefix="(vi)">Lighting for roads, highways, alleys, and other public places; or</section><section prefix="(vii)">Mosquito control facilities and programs; and</section></section><section prefix="(2)">Any other function or duty that is not inconsistent with this section.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If the county commissioners assign to a Department the responsibility for water and sewerage functions, in accordance with paragraph (3) and subject to paragraph (4) of this subsection, the county commissioners shall abolish by public local law:<section prefix="(i)">Any water or sewer authority established for the county under Title 9, Subtitle 9 of the Environment Article; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Any sanitary district or commission established for the county under Title 9, Subtitle 6 of the Environment Article.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Before abolishing a water or sewer authority or sanitary district or commission, the county commissioners may request that the entity provide to the county appropriate information to assist the county commissioners in complying with paragraph (3) of this subsection.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The public local law shall provide:<section prefix="(i)">For the retiring, refunding, refinancing, transfer, or assumption of any applicable outstanding bonds of the abolished entity;</section><section prefix="(ii)">For the assumption of all existing assets and liabilities of the abolished entity by the county, subject to an audit of the assets and liabilities by a certified public accountant;</section><section prefix="(iii)">For the transfer of all real and personal property of the abolished entity to the county;</section><section prefix="(iv)">For the transfer of responsibility and administration of any legally enforceable agreement between the abolished entity and another party to the county;</section><section prefix="(v)">For the continued effect of orders, rules, and regulations of the abolished entity, until revoked or modified by the county commissioners;</section><section prefix="(vi)">That any revenues of an abolished entity remain dedicated for the purpose collected and are not transferred into the county's general fund; and</section><section prefix="(vii)">That all matters pending before the abolished entity may continue and shall be completed by the Department.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">Any employee of a water or sewer authority or of a sanitary commission employed on the date that the authority or commission is abolished who transfers to the Department or to a municipal corporation or local community under &#xA7; 13E-1 of this article shall transfer without any loss of salary, retirement benefits, insurance benefits, leave time, seniority level, or other employee benefits.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If the county commissioners abolish a water or sewer authority or sanitary district or commission, the county commissioners then shall exercise the powers of a water or sewer authority or sanitary district or commission.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The county commissioners may:<section prefix="(i)">Adopt regulations for water and sewerage management;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Acquire, construct, operate, or maintain water and sewerage systems as the county commissioners consider to be in the public interest and necessary to protect the general health and welfare; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Set rates, fees, and assessments for water and sewerage services and benefits.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The powers granted code counties under this section may be exercised notwithstanding any other law in effect when the county commissioners exercise the power granted under this section.</section>
  </text>
</law>
