<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="g2b" order_by="" level="1">Alcoholic Beverages</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>g2b-11-507</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>507</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">This section applies only in Carroll County.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The following restrictions, limitations, and regulations apply.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Holders of "on-sale" licenses authorized under this article may sell, offer for sale, or dispense alcoholic beverages between 8 a.m. and 1 a.m. the following day and no other hours. Holders of these licenses may not sell, offer to sell or dispense any alcoholic beverages on Sunday except:<section prefix="1.">When the holder of that license is open for business on Saturday at midnight the licensee may remain open until 1 a.m. the Sunday immediately following;</section><section prefix="2.">Holders of Class C and H beer, wine and liquor licenses may reopen and may sell alcoholic beverages on Sundays between 11 a.m. and 1 a.m. the following Monday;</section><section prefix="3.">Holders of Class B beer, wine and liquor licenses may reopen and may sell alcoholic beverages on Sundays between 11 a.m. and 1 a.m. the following Monday; and</section><section prefix="4.">Holders of Class B beer and light wine, 7-day licenses may conduct "on-sales" of alcoholic beverages on Sundays between 11 a.m. and 1 a.m. the following Monday.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">In all cases in which a closing time is indicated in this subsection a licensee may not permit the drinking of any alcoholic beverage on the premises 15 minutes following the closing time indicated.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Holders of "off-sale" licenses under this article may sell, offer for sale, or dispense the beverages defined in this article between 8 a.m. and 11 p.m. on Monday through Saturday, and between 11 a.m. and 11 p.m. on Sunday.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">Holders of Class B beer and light wine, 7-day licenses may conduct "off-sales" of alcoholic beverages only between 8 a.m. and 11 p.m. on Monday through Saturday, and between 11 a.m. and 11 p.m. on Sunday.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(4)">A Class A wine licensee may sell wine on Sundays.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">The hours established in this subtitle for the sale of alcoholic beverages in Carroll County are hereby declared to be in accordance with Eastern Standard Time when such time is effective and the hours are declared to be in accordance with daylight time when such time is effective.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
