<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="g2b" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="2-207" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>g2b-2-207</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">A Class 6 pub-brewery license shall be issued:<section prefix="(1)">By the State Comptroller;</section><section prefix="(2)">Only to a holder of a Class B beer, wine and liquor (on-sale) license that is issued for use on the premises of a restaurant located in the jurisdictions permitted by this subsection;</section><section prefix="(3)">In the City of Annapolis; and</section><section prefix="(4)">Throughout the State, but not in the following subdivisions:<section prefix="(i)">Allegany County;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Caroline County;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Howard County;</section><section prefix="(iv)">St. Mary's County; and</section><section prefix="(v)">Somerset County.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A holder of a Class 6 pub-brewery license:<section prefix="(1)">May brew malt beverages at a single location for consumption on the restaurant premises; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Is limited to the brewing of 2,000 barrels of malt beverage each calendar year.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The pub-brewery premises shall be located immediately adjacent to the restaurant where the brewed beverage is to be sold to the public.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Class 6 pub-brewery license is void if:<section prefix="(1)">The restaurant ceases to be operated as a restaurant; or</section><section prefix="(2)">The holder's Class B beer, wine and liquor (on-sale) license is revoked or transferred to a different location.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">If the holder's Class B beer, wine and liquor (on-sale) license is suspended, the Class 6 pub-brewery license shall be suspended for the same period of time.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">Except for a license transferred to a new location, a Class 6 pub-brewery license may be transferred under &#xA7; 10-503 of this article if an application for transfer is filed with the local licensing board and simultaneously filed with the Office of the Comptroller.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This subsection applies only in the following jurisdictions:<section prefix="(i)">City of Annapolis;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Anne Arundel County;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Baltimore City;</section><section prefix="(iv)">Baltimore County;</section><section prefix="(v)">Calvert County;</section><section prefix="(vi)">Cecil County;</section><section prefix="(vii)">Charles County;</section><section prefix="(viii)">Harford County;</section><section prefix="(ix)">Prince George's County;</section><section prefix="(x)">Talbot County;</section><section prefix="(xi)">Wicomico County; and</section><section prefix="(xii)">Worcester County.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The holder of a Class 6 pub-brewery license may sell malt beverages for off-premises consumption in sealed refillable containers.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The containers may be returned and at the time of refill shall be sealed by the pub-brewery licensee.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">A holder of a Class 6 pub-brewery license may not sell malt beverages to any retail alcoholic beverages licensee in this State for the purpose of a subsequent sale or distribution of that malt beverage under the retail license.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(h)">In Montgomery County, a holder of a Class 6 pub-brewery license shall enter into a written agreement with the Department of Liquor Control for Montgomery County for the sale and resale of all malt beverages brewed under this license in accordance with this article.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This subsection applies only in Wicomico County.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Before the Office of the Comptroller of this State may issue a pub-brewery license, it shall forward a copy of the application to the Board of License Commissioners. The Board shall review the application, hold a public hearing on the application, and recommend to the Office whether or not to grant the license.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(j)">For Talbot County, the Office of the Comptroller of Maryland shall specify which local license is the equivalent of the Class B beer, wine and liquor license specified in subsection (a)(2) of this section.</section>
  </text>
</law>
