<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="g2b" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="8-202" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>g2b-8-202</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">This section applies only in Anne Arundel County.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Board" means the Board of License Commissioners.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"License" means a license for the sale of alcoholic beverages that is issued by the Board.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">In the City of Annapolis the Mayor, Counselor, and Aldermen have the power to:<section prefix="(1)">Fix the fees for all licenses authorized to be issued in the city; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Determine a periodic basis on which payments for the renewal of a license may be made.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">There is a special Sunday license.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Notwithstanding any other provision of this article and except for "special licenses" provided for in &#xA7; 6-501 of this article, a licensee may not sell any alcoholic beverages after 2 a.m. on Sundays except as provided in this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Upon application made in the same manner as for new licenses and approved by the Board as provided for by &#xA7;&#xA7; 10-202(d) and 10-208(b) of this article, a licensee shall be issued an additional license known as a "special Sunday license" upon payment of the required fee.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The holder of a "special Sunday license" may sell alcoholic beverages on Sundays. The licenses shall be of the same kind as the ongoing license and are subject to the same limitations as to hours, restrictions, and other provisions found in licenses issued by the Board. The alcoholic beverages shall contain the same alcoholic content as is found in other alcoholic beverages.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">A "special Sunday license" may not be issued to any person:</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(5)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The annual fee for each beer and light wine "special Sunday license" is $60.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The annual fee for each beer, wine and liquor "special Sunday license" is $120.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(6)">"Special Sunday licenses" may be renewed in the same manner as other licenses. "Special Sunday licenses" are not "special licenses" under the provisions of &#xA7; 10-301 of this article.</section>
      <section prefix="(7)">The granting of a "special Sunday license" in addition to a license of any other class, to the same licensee, shall not be deemed to be in conflict with the provisions of &#xA7; 9-102 of this article.</section>
      <section prefix="(8)">If any other license held by the holder of a "special Sunday license" is suspended or revoked, the "special Sunday license" is suspended or revoked by operation of law.</section>
      <section prefix="(9)">Section 9-203(c) of this article does not prohibit any person who holds any other class of alcoholic beverages license from obtaining a "special Sunday license".</section>
      <section prefix="(10)">This subsection does not apply in the sixth district, which is the City of Annapolis.</section>
      <section prefix="(11)">This section does not apply to beach and amusement park licenses.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">There is a racetrack license.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The owner of any regularly licensed racing establishment, whether individual, association of individuals, or a corporation, without further residential, voting or locative qualifications, may procure a license for the sale of any and all alcoholic beverages within the confines of its racing park.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The license fee is $60 per day to be paid on January 1 for the racing of the preceding year, payable to the Board. It entitles the holder to sell at one or more locations within its park.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">Licenses and licensees are subject to all laws and regulations applicable to the sale of alcoholic beverages not inconsistent with the provisions of this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">This subsection does not apply to the sixth district, which is the City of Annapolis.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The Board may permit the sale of any alcoholic beverages permitted by law to be sold in any district other than the sixth, which is the City of Annapolis, on or in any parking lot, picnic grounds, building or terrace which forms an integral part of the licensed premises.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">There is an airport concessionaire license.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">An individual, association of individuals, or a corporation which is a lessee, sublessee, or a concessionaire at any airport, without further residential, voting or locative qualifications, may obtain an airport concessionaire license for the sale of any and all alcoholic beverages within the airport terminal buildings.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)"/>
        <section prefix="(iii)"/>
        <section prefix="(iv)">On receipt of an application for an airport concessionaire license under subparagraph (ii) or (iii) of this paragraph, the Board shall:</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The annual fee for the airport concessionaire license and one location from which alcoholic beverages may be sold is $5,000.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The annual fee for each additional location from which alcoholic beverages may be sold is $5,000.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">Each fee shall be paid on May 1 to the Board.</section>
        <section prefix="(iv)">The licensee may sell alcoholic beverages every day from each location within the airport terminal buildings.</section>
        <section prefix="(v)">The license permits the playing of music and dancing.</section>
        <section prefix="(vi)">The provisions of subsection (d) of this section relating to special Sunday licenses do not apply to the holder of a license issued under this subsection.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(4)">Licenses and licensees are subject to all laws and regulations applicable to the sale of alcoholic beverages not inconsistent with the provisions of this section.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(h)">
      <section prefix="(1)">There is a resort complex license.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Resort complex" means a recreational area of 10 or more acres with beach facilities and facilities to serve and accommodate 500 or more persons at one time.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Board may issue a resort complex license covering "on-sales" of beer, wine and liquor to any person, for the sale of any and all alcoholic beverages within the confines of the resort complex. This license shall be issued only to the person, firm, or corporation owning or leasing a resort complex.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The annual license fee is $1,800.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">It shall be paid on May 1 to the Board and entitles the holder to sell daily at one or more locations within the resort complex.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">The license permits playing of music and dancing.</section>
        <section prefix="(iv)">The provisions of subsection (d) of this section relating to special Sunday licenses do not apply to the holder of a license issued under this subsection.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(5)">The licenses and licensees are subject to all laws and regulations applicable to the sale of alcoholic beverages not inconsistent with the provisions of this subsection.</section>
      <section prefix="(6)">This license permits the sale of alcoholic beverages at bars or counters, but not for consumption off the premises.</section>
      <section prefix="(7)">Licensees may serve alcoholic beverages at one or more outside locations within the resort complex from 8 a.m. to midnight for each outing and from 6 a.m. to 2 a.m. in main, permanent areas.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(i)">
      <section prefix="(1)">There is a motel/hotel-restaurant license.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The license covers "on-sales" of beer, wine and liquor to any person, without further residential, voting or locative qualifications being required of the applicant, for the sale of any and all alcoholic beverages within the confines of the motel-restaurant complex or hotel-restaurant complex.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">These licenses shall be issued only to the person, firm, or corporation owning or leasing motel-restaurant complexes or hotel-restaurant complexes that have:</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">If the food concession is leased to a concessionaire, the concessionaire is exempt from having a capital investment of not less than $500,000.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">Any motel-restaurant complex or hotel-restaurant complex with 100 or more rooms shall have a motel-restaurant or hotel-restaurant complex license by October 1, 1977.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(4)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The annual license fee for each separate establishment is $3,600.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The fee shall be paid on May 1 to the Board and entitles the holder to sell alcoholic beverages every day at one or more locations within the hotel-restaurant or motel-restaurant complex.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">The license permits the playing of music and dancing.</section>
        <section prefix="(iv)">The provisions of subsection (d) of this section relating to special Sunday licenses do not apply to the holder of a license issued under this subsection.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(5)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The licenses and licensees are subject to all laws and regulations applicable to the sale of alcoholic beverages, not inconsistent with the provisions of this subsection.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">This license permits the sale of alcoholic beverages at bars or counters, but not for consumption off the premises.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(j)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">There is a beer and wine (hotel-limited service) (on-sale) license.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">There is a beer, wine and liquor (hotel-limited service) (on-sale) license.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Board may issue a license under paragraph (1)(i) or (ii) of this subsection only to a person who owns or leases a hotel that contains at least 50 rooms and operates a kitchen licensed at least as a food service facility.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A license issued under this subsection entitles the holder to sell alcoholic beverages every day at one or more locations within the hotel.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The annual license fee is:<section prefix="(i)">$2,400 for a beer and wine (hotel-limited service) license; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">$2,800 for a beer, wine and liquor (hotel-limited service) license.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(5)">The annual license fee shall be paid on May 1 to the Board.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(k)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">In this subsection the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">"Concessionaire" means a lessee, sublessee, or any other operator of an establishment that:</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">"Entertainment facility" means a facility that holds a license under Title 9, Subtitle 1A of the State Government Article.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">There is an entertainment facility license.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The Board may issue an entertainment facility license for an entertainment facility that contains one or more food service facilities, bars, or lounges that are part of the operation of the entertainment facility.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">The entertainment facility license shall be issued to an individual, entity, or subsidiary of an entity that owns an entertainment facility and holds a license under Title 9, Subtitle 1A of the State Government Article.</section>
        <section prefix="(iv)">An applicant for an entertainment facility license need not meet any location, voting, or residency requirements.</section>
        <section prefix="(v)">An entertainment facility license authorizes the holder to sell beer, wine, and liquor on any premises of the entertainment facility that is not covered by an entertainment concessionaire license for consumption anywhere in the entertainment facility.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">There is an entertainment concessionaire license.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The Board may issue an entertainment concessionaire license to a concessionaire operating in conjunction with an entertainment facility.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">The entertainment concessionaire license authorizes the holder to sell beer, wine, and liquor on the premises of the concessionaire for consumption anywhere in the entertainment facility.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(4)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The annual fee for an entertainment facility license is $15,000.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The annual fee for an entertainment concessionaire license is $5,000.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">The annual license fees shall be paid on May 1 to the Board.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(5)">
        <section prefix="(i)">An off-sale privilege is not conferred by an entertainment facility license or an entertainment concessionaire license.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">Beer, wine, and liquor purchased under an entertainment facility license or an entertainment concessionaire license may be taken into and consumed anywhere in an entertainment facility.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">The hours for the sale and consumption of alcoholic beverages under an entertainment facility license or an entertainment concessionaire license are the same as the hours of operation for a video lottery facility established under &#xA7; 9-1A-23 of the State Government Article.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(6)">An entertainment facility license and an entertainment concessionaire license authorize the playing of music and dancing in their respective licensed premises.</section>
      <section prefix="(7)">Subsection (d) of this section, relating to special Sunday licenses, does not apply to a license issued under this subsection.</section>
      <section prefix="(8)">An entertainment facility license or an entertainment concessionaire license may not be counted as a Class B or Class H license for purposes of &#xA7; 9-102(h-1) of this article.</section>
      <section prefix="(9)">The licenses and holders are subject to all laws and regulations applicable to the sale of alcoholic beverages not inconsistent with this subsection.</section>
      <section prefix="(10)">Any penalty or other sanction that is imposed for a violation of a regulation of the Board on the licensed premises of the holder of an entertainment concessionaire license shall apply to the concessionaire that the Board determines to be responsible for the violation.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
