<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="g2b" order_by="" level="1">Alcoholic Beverages</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>g2b-8-405.2</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>405.2</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">This section applies only in Dorchester County.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Subject to paragraph (2) of this subsection, the Board of License Commissioners may issue a beer and wine sampling or tasting (BWST) license to a holder of a Class A license to hold tastings or samplings of beer or wine.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A holder of a Class A beer license may use a BWST license to hold tastings or samplings of beer only.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A BWST license authorizes sampling or tasting of alcoholic beverages only on the licensed premises of  the holder of a Class A license.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The alcoholic beverages shall be offered to consumers at no charge.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A person may consume alcoholic beverages covered by a BWST license in a quantity not exceeding:<section prefix="(1)"><section prefix="(i)">1 ounce from a single brand of wine; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">4 ounces from all brands of wine in a single day; and</section></section><section prefix="(2)"><section prefix="(i)">3 ounces from a single brand of beer; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">8 ounces from all brands of beer in a single day.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">An application for a BWST license shall be made on a form supplied by the Board of License Commissioners.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A BWST license may be issued without a public hearing.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">If an initial application for a BWST license is denied:<section prefix="(i)">The applicant may resubmit the application; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">On request from the applicant, the Board shall hold a public hearing on the application before determining whether to issue the license.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">A renewal of a BWST license may be made at the time the holder's Class A license is renewed.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The fee for a BWST license is:<section prefix="(1)">$150 for not more than 15 beer or wine tastings per year; or</section><section prefix="(2)">$250 for not more than 30 beer or wine tastings per year.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Board of License Commissioners may not require the publication of an application for a BWST license before issuing the license.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The holder of a BWST license shall notify the Board in writing at least 7 days before the event at which the license is to be used.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(h)">At the end of the day for which a BWST license is valid, the holder of the license shall properly dispose of alcoholic beverages that remain in a container opened for tasting or sampling.</section>
  </text>
</law>
