<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="g2b" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="4-201" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>g2b-4-201</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">A Class A light wine license may be issued only in:<section prefix="(1)">Anne Arundel County;</section><section prefix="(2)">Baltimore County;</section><section prefix="(3)">Calvert County;</section><section prefix="(4)">Caroline County;</section><section prefix="(5)">Carroll County;</section><section prefix="(6)">Cecil County;</section><section prefix="(7)">Dorchester County;</section><section prefix="(8)">Frederick County;</section><section prefix="(9)">Garrett County;</section><section prefix="(10)">Harford County;</section><section prefix="(11)">Howard County;</section><section prefix="(12)">Kent County;</section><section prefix="(13)">Montgomery County;</section><section prefix="(14)">Prince George's County;</section><section prefix="(15)">Queen Anne's County;</section><section prefix="(16)">St. Mary's County;</section><section prefix="(17)">Somerset County;</section><section prefix="(18)">Talbot County;</section><section prefix="(19)">Washington County;</section><section prefix="(20)">Wicomico County; and</section><section prefix="(21)">Worcester County.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as otherwise provided in this subsection, the annual fee for this license is $50.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">In Montgomery County the annual license fee is $100.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">In Garrett County, the issuing fee for this license is $50.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">In Harford County, the annual fee for this license is $100.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">In Caroline County, the annual fee for this license shall be set by the Board of License Commissioners with the approval of the Board of County Commissioners.</section>
      <section prefix="(6)">In Somerset County, the annual fee for this license is $63.</section>
      <section prefix="(7)">In Anne Arundel County the annual fee for this license is $60.</section>
      <section prefix="(8)">In Baltimore County, the fee for this license is $100.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A Class A light wine license may be issued by the license issuing authority of the county in which the place of business is located to any holder of a Class 4 manufacturer's license.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A winery in Cecil County that applies for a Class A/Class 4 license is exempt from any quotas established by the Cecil County Board of License Commissioners as to the number of licenses in the election district where the winery is located.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A winery in Baltimore County that applies for a Class A/Class 4 license is exempt from any quotas established by the Baltimore County Board of License Commissioners as to the number of licenses in the election district where the winery is located.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">A winery in Prince George's County that applies for a Class A/Class 4 license is exempt from any quotas established by the Prince George's County Board of License Commissioners as to the number of licenses in the election district where the winery is located.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The license authorizes the holder to keep for sale and to sell light wines produced at the winery in any quantity to any consumer at retail at the place described in the license. The light wine shall be delivered in a sealed package or container which may not be opened or the contents consumed on the licensed premises.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">In Montgomery County the licensee may not make more than 20,000 gallons of on-premises sales per year.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">In Frederick County and Baltimore County, the licensee may keep for sale and sell light wines and ports that contain not in excess of 21 percent of alcohol by volume produced at the winery in any quantity to any consumer at retail at the place described in the license.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Notwithstanding any other provision of law to the contrary, in Harford County, the licensee may keep for sale and sell light wines and port wines produced at the winery in accordance with the provisions of subparagraph (ii) of this paragraph.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The light wines and port wines under the provisions of subparagraph (i) of this paragraph:</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This subsection applies only in the following counties:<section prefix="(i)">Anne Arundel County;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Baltimore County;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Frederick County;</section><section prefix="(iv)">Garrett County;</section><section prefix="(v)">Harford County;</section><section prefix="(vi)">Kent County;</section><section prefix="(vii)">Somerset County;</section><section prefix="(viii)">Talbot County; and</section><section prefix="(ix)">Washington County.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A Class A light wine license may be issued to a holder of a Class 3 manufacturer's license, who makes wine from agricultural products grown in Maryland.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
