<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="g2b" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="10-301" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>g2b-10-301</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Except in Prince George's County, the holder of any expiring license, other than special licenses issued under the provisions of this article, shall, not less than 30 nor more than 60 days before the first day of May of each and every year, file a written application, duly verified by oath, for the renewal of the license with the official authorized to approve the same.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)"/>
        <section prefix="(iii)"/>
        <section prefix="(iv)">This protest shall be:</section>
        <section prefix="(v)">If the protest has been filed it shall be heard and determined as in the case of original applications, except in Baltimore City it shall be heard and determined not as in the case of original application in regard to zoning but only on a specific complaint as to the operation of the licensee's establishments.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">For all statewide licenses issued to a corporation by the State Comptroller and in each county and Baltimore City, notwithstanding any other provision of this article to the contrary, a corporation or club holding an alcoholic beverages license may, during the license year, substitute any or all names of its officers on the license if the deleted officer:</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The corporation or club shall file with the license issuing authority an affidavit that gives:</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">Upon receipt of the affidavit and after making a determination that the applicant qualifies under the provisions of this article, the license issuing authority shall:</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(a-1)">In Prince George's County, the procedures for the renewal of applications, protests, and hearings are provided in &#xA7; 10-302 of this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">If the licensing official finds that the license holder is not qualified to obtain a renewal of the expiring license said official shall not renew said expiring license but shall issue to him by way of renewal the class or type of license for which they find him qualified. If an expiring license is subject to any order of restriction or suspension the new license shall be issued subject to said order. All applications for renewal received otherwise than as herein stated shall be treated as original applications.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">No renewal of any license shall be granted any person who during the license year has been convicted of any offense against the laws of the State or of the United States which in the judgment of the local licensing officials is of such a nature as to render such person unfit or disqualified to obtain said renewal; provided that in such a case a public hearing shall be held by such local licensing officials prior to renewal at which all relevant facts and circumstances of such offense may be inquired into.</section>
    <section prefix="(c-1)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This section applies only in Prince George's and St. Mary's counties.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">In this section, "Board" means:<section prefix="(i)">In Prince George's County, the Prince George's County Board of License Commissioners; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">In St. Mary's County, the Alcohol Beverage Board of St. Mary's County.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A renewal of a license may not be granted, at the discretion of the Board, if the licensee or any of the stockholders of the corporation having the use of a license has been convicted of a felony. A public hearing shall be held by the Board prior to the renewal of that license. All relevant facts and circumstances of the offense may be inquired into at that hearing.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A license issuing authority may issue such new licenses for the ensuing year as hereinabove provided, at any time between April 15th and May 1st, of each and every year, but all such licenses shall be dated May 1st.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Notwithstanding paragraph (1) of this subsection, in St. Mary's County new licenses may be issued at any time between April 1st and May 1st.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d-1)">The Garrett County Liquor Control Board may issue new licenses for the ensuing year as provided in this section at any time between June 15 and July 1 of each and every year, but all licenses shall be dated July 1. During the first calendar year, the Board shall prorate all class licenses for a period of 14 months. Thereafter, licenses shall be prorated on a 12-month basis.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">In Harford County applications for a renewal of license shall be in such form as the Liquor Control Board may prescribe by rules and regulations duly adopted. Renewal applications received after April 1st may be considered by the Board for a period of thirty days before final action on the application is taken.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">In Prince George's County and in Montgomery County, any licensee may obtain a renewal license without obtaining a certificate of approval of the owner of the building in which the business is conducted, provided the licensee is the holder of a lease upon the entire building for not less than the term of the renewal license.</section>
    <section prefix="(f-1)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This subsection applies only in Prince George's County.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Subject to paragraph (4) of this subsection, before a license may be renewed, the Board of License Commissioners shall verify:<section prefix="(i)"/><section prefix="(ii)">That the current license holder has provided for payment of the taxes described in item (i) of this paragraph in a manner satisfactory to the governmental unit responsible for the collection.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">If the information provided to the Board of License Commissioners states that the current license holder owes undisputed taxes and has not provided for payment in a manner satisfactory to the governmental unit responsible for collection, the Board of License Commissioners may not renew the license.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">If the license was issued on behalf of a corporation, club, or other entity, the verification requirements specified in paragraph (2) of this subsection apply to undisputed taxes payable by each owner or principal of the entity.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">In Prince George's County notwithstanding any other provision of this article, any corporation or club holding a Class C beer, wine and liquor license may, during any license year, substitute the name of one of its officers for the name of any other officer on the license when the deleted officer has died, retired, been removed from office, or no longer holds an office in said corporation. Said corporation shall file an affidavit with the Board of License Commissioners showing the substitution of an officer or officers with an explanation for said substitution. Upon receipt of said affidavit the Board shall amend its record and issue a new license with the corrected names thereon.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In Worcester, Wicomico, Dorchester, Somerset, and Howard counties, notwithstanding any other provision of this article, any corporation or club holding any class of alcoholic beverage license may, during any license year, substitute the name of one of its officers for the name of any other officer on the license when the deleted officer has died, retired, been removed from office, or no longer holds an office in the corporation or club if the substitute is a fit person approved by the Board and can meet all the requirements the substitute would have to meet if the substitute were named in the original application. The corporation or club shall file an affidavit with the Board of License Commissioners showing the substitution of the officer or officers with an explanation of the substitution. Upon receipt of the affidavit the Board shall amend its records and issue a new license with the corrected names on it. The corporation or club shall pay a fee of $5 to the Board of License Commissioners for this service. In Somerset and Wicomico counties, the fee is $50 and is payable to the local collecting agent. In Worcester County, this section applies only to Class C (clubs) establishments for which the fee is $5. In Wicomico County, an application for renewal of a restaurant license is subject to requirements specified in &#xA7; 6-201(x) of this article, as amended from time to time.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">In Howard County, failure to file renewal applications for alcoholic beverages licenses by April 1 of each year shall result in nonrenewal of the license or a penalty of $50 per day for each day the application is late.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(i)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In Charles County, the Board of License Commissioners may not renew any license as authorized in subsection (a) of this section unless there is presented to the Board a certification from the:<section prefix="(i)">Office of the County Supervisor of Assessments showing the value of the merchandise, fixtures, and stock-in-trade for the business for which the application is made for the calendar year next preceding the year the license is to be issued;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Treasurer of the county showing that there are no unpaid taxes due from the applicant to the county, incorporated city, or town where the licensed premises is to be located; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Treasurer of the county showing there are no unpaid taxes due from the applicant to the county or the State of Maryland on the merchandise, fixtures and stock-in-trade where the licensed premises is to be located.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">A renewal application for an alcoholic beverages license is due on or before March 31 of each year.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">Subject to subparagraph (iii) of this paragraph, a person who files a renewal application after March 31 is subject to a penalty of $50 for each day that the application is late.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">The maximum amount that the Board of License Commissioners may charge a person under this paragraph is $500 per renewal application.</section>
        <section prefix="(iv)">A renewal application may not be submitted later than the date of the next meeting of the Board of License Commissioners following March 31.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(j)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In Baltimore City, unless a licensee presents to the Board of Liquor License Commissioners by June 30 of the respective year, a certificate issued by the Director of Finance, showing that there are no unpaid taxes on the merchandise, fixtures and stock of the applicant due to the City of Baltimore or the State of Maryland, the renewal license shall be immediately suspended without a hearing but thereafter shall be immediately returned without a hearing upon presentation of such a certificate.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Each year, between March 1 and March 31, both inclusive, each licensee shall file an application for license renewal with the Board.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">An applicant for a renewal of a license issued by the Board shall pay a renewal application fee of $50 to the Director of Finance.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">A license renewal application received by the Board after March 31 may be subject to:</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">This paragraph applies only to a license that is issued in, transferred into, or transferred to a different location within the following areas of the 46th alcoholic beverages district if the application for the issuance or transfer was received by the Board of License Commissioners after December 31, 1995:</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">A licensee shall file with each license renewal application a copy of a valid capacity rating issued by the Baltimore City Fire Department for the licensed establishment.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)"/>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(4)">Notwithstanding any other provision of this article, and except where extenuating circumstances exist, before a licensed premises in Baltimore City that has been closed for at least 3 consecutive months may be reopened:<section prefix="(i)">The Board of Liquor License Commissioners shall hold a public hearing; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">The licensee shall obtain approval from the Board of Liquor License Commissioners to reopen.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(k)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This subsection applies only in Wicomico County.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">In this subsection "Board" means the Board of License Commissioners.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">An applicant for a renewal of a license issued by the Board shall pay an additional renewal application fee of $50 to the local collecting agent.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The Board may not renew an alcoholic beverages license until the licensee has presented the Board with a certificate of receipt from the County Finance Office that shows that there are not unpaid taxes on the merchandise, fixtures, and stock of the applicant due to the county or State.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(l)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In Montgomery County a licensee shall annually, between February 1 and March 31, file an application for renewal in accordance with subsection (a) of this section. The Board of License Commissioners may receive late applications during April, and may fine the licensee an amount not to exceed $50 for each day the application is late.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Each renewal application shall satisfy the requirements of &#xA7; 10-104(q) of this article, as the Board may prescribe.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(m)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In Baltimore County, the Board of License Commissioners may not renew an alcoholic beverages license until the applicant has presented to the Board a receipt or certificate from the office of finance showing that there are no unpaid taxes on the merchandise, fixtures, and stock of the applicant due to Baltimore County or the State of Maryland.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A licensee shall annually, between February 1 and March 31, file an application for renewal in accordance with provisions of this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Board of License Commissioners may receive late applications during April, and may fine the licensee an amount not to exceed $50 for each day the application is late up to a maximum cumulative amount of $500.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(n)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This subsection applies only in Calvert County.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The term of a license is 1 year.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">To renew a license, a licensee shall file an application for license renewal with the Board of License Commissioners at any time beginning on April 1 and ending on May 1.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">A license renewal application received by the Board on or after July 1 is subject to a late fine of $50 for each day the application is late.</section>
        <section prefix="(iv)">A late fine may not exceed $500.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">An application for a license renewal shall be accompanied by:<section prefix="(i)">A statement of the hours of operation of the licensed premises;</section><section prefix="(ii)">A statement of the name of the manager; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">A copy of the current statement for the licensed business that shows that all applicable taxes are paid.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">In addition to the requirements of paragraph (3) of this subsection, an application for a Class B license renewal shall be accompanied by a statement that shows the average monthly sales of food and alcoholic beverages for the licensed premises.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(o)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This subsection applies only in Washington County.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Board of License Commissioners may not renew an alcoholic beverages license until the licensee has paid all county taxes that are due and owing under the license and has certified by affidavit to the Board that no county taxes are due and owing.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A holder of an alcoholic beverages license who files a completed application for renewal of the license:<section prefix="(i)">After April 1, but on or before April 11, is subject to a penalty of $100; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">On or after April 12, is subject to a penalty of $400.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(p)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In Queen Anne's County, notwithstanding any other provision of this article to the contrary, a corporation or club holding a Class C alcoholic beverages license may, during the license year, substitute any or all names of its officers on the license if the deleted officer:<section prefix="(i)">Is dead;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Is retired;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Has been removed from office; or</section><section prefix="(iv)">No longer holds an office in the corporation or club.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The corporation or club shall file an affidavit with the Board of License Commissioners that gives:<section prefix="(i)">The substitution of the officer or officers; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">An explanation for the substitution.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Upon receipt of the affidavit the Queen Anne's County Board of License Commissioners shall:<section prefix="(i)">Amend its records; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Issue a new license in corrected form.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(q)">In Carroll County the Board of License Commissioners may impose a late fee of $50 per day for each day a licensee fails to renew the license after the application is due. The total amount of the fees may not exceed $500.</section>
    <section prefix="(r)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This subsection applies only in St. Mary's County.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Unless an alcoholic beverages license is renewed for a 1-year term as provided in this subsection, the license expires on the first April 30 that comes after its effective date.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Before a license expires, the licensee may renew it for an additional term if the licensee applies for renewal to the Administrator of the Alcohol Beverage Board of St. Mary's County from February 1 through March 3, both inclusive.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">A holder of an expired license may apply to the Board for a new license.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(s)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This subsection applies only in Somerset County.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">In this subsection, "Board" means the Board of License Commissioners.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">An applicant for a renewal of a license issued by the Board shall pay a renewal application fee of $50 to the local collecting agent.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The Board may not renew an alcoholic beverages license until the licensee has presented the Board with a certificate of receipt from the County Finance Office that shows that there are not unpaid taxes on the merchandise, fixtures, and stock of the applicant due to the county or State.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">If an applicant fails to renew an alcoholic beverages license in a timely manner as determined by the Board, the applicant shall pay a late renewal fee of $100 in addition to the renewal application fee of $50 required by paragraph (3) of this subsection.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(t)">In Worcester County, the Board of License Commissioners may receive late applications during April and fine the licensee an amount not exceeding $50 for each day the application is late.</section>
    <section prefix="(u)">In Anne Arundel County, an applicant for a renewal of a license shall pay to the local collecting agent a nonrefundable renewal fee of $50 in addition to the annual license fee.</section>
  </text>
</law>
