<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="g2b" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="15-109" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>g2b-15-109</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The salaries of the members of the boards of license commissioners are specified in this section. Where no salary is specified for those boards which serve ex officio, the members may not receive additional compensation under the provisions of this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">In Allegany County the annual salary of the members of the Board of License Commissioners shall be set by the County Commissioners in accordance with Article 24, Title 12, Subtitle 1 of the Code.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">In Anne Arundel County the chairman of the Board of License Commissioners shall receive annually as salary not more than $18,000; each other member of the Board shall receive annually as salaries not more than $15,000, plus reimbursement for expenses reasonably incurred by them.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">In Baltimore City:<section prefix="(1)">The chairman of the Board shall receive an annual salary of $28,500, and the other members of the Board shall receive an annual salary of $28,000.</section><section prefix="(2)">The chairman and the other members of the Board are eligible to receive the same health benefits that full-time liquor inspectors of the Board receive.</section><section prefix="(3)">The Board shall appoint an executive secretary and a deputy executive secretary whose salaries shall be fixed by the Board, subject to approval by the State Comptroller.</section><section prefix="(4)">The executive secretary and the deputy executive secretary shall be residents of Baltimore City and of high character and integrity.</section><section prefix="(5)">The executive secretary and the deputy executive secretary shall be appointed upon the basis of their executive skill and ability and once appointed shall hold office during good behavior regardless of changes in members constituting the Board. They shall be removed only for incompetency or immorality upon charges furnished in writing by the Board setting forth the grounds for dismissal and after opportunity for hearing.</section><section prefix="(6)">Either the executive secretary or the deputy executive secretary shall be a member of the Bar of this State.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">In Baltimore County:<section prefix="(1)">The salaries of the members of the Board of License Commissioners shall be as determined from time to time by "Baltimore County, Maryland", in such amounts as are deemed reasonable and proper, but the annual salary of the chairman shall be not less than $11,500 and the annual salary of each of the associate members shall be not less than $10,500.</section><section prefix="(2)">The Board of License Commissioners may appoint an executive secretary. The salary of the executive secretary shall be paid from the liquor license appropriation in the Baltimore County budget in an amount set forth under grade 27, step 3, and such longevity benefits as the executive secretary to the Board may be entitled.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">In Calvert County:<section prefix="(1)">The chairman of the Board shall receive $4,200 annually for expenses incurred while carrying on the duties of the office;</section><section prefix="(2)">The regular members of the Board shall receive $3,600 annually for expenses incurred while carrying on the duties of the office; and</section><section prefix="(3)">The alternate Board member shall receive $200 compensation for each meeting of the Board attended as an acting regular member to compensate for expenses incurred while carrying on the duties of the office.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(g)">In Caroline County:<section prefix="(1)">The members of the Board of License Commissioners shall receive annual salaries as determined by the County Commissioners, but not less than:<section prefix="(i)">$3,000 for the chairman; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">$2,500 for a regular Board member.</section></section><section prefix="(2)">The alternate member of the Board shall receive $100 per meeting but not more than $2,000 in any 1-year period.</section><section prefix="(3)">The chairman, associate members and substitute member shall be reimbursed for expenses incurred in the performance of their duties in accordance with the Standard State Travel Regulations.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(h)">In Carroll County, the annual salaries for the members of the Board of License Commissioners are set by the Carroll County Commissioners.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In Cecil County, the Chairman of the Board of License Commissioners shall receive an annual salary of $3,000.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Each of the other members shall receive an annual salary in the amount of $2,500.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Chairman and each member shall be reimbursed for expenses in accordance with the Standard State Travel Regulations.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The expenses shall be paid by the Commissioners.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(j)">In Charles County:<section prefix="(1)">The County Commissioners shall set the salaries of the chairman and the associate members of the Board of License Commissioners.</section><section prefix="(2)">The County Commissioners also shall provide a clerk, counsel, and supplies to the Board as the County Commissioners consider appropriate. The County Commissioners may set salaries for the clerk and counsel as the County Commissioners consider appropriate.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(k)">In Dorchester County, the annual compensation for the members of theBoard of License Commissioners is:<section prefix="(1)">$3,000 for the Chairman; and</section><section prefix="(2)">$2,500 for each regular member.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(l)">In Frederick County, the salary of the Board of License Commissioners is provided for in &#xA7; 15-103 of this article.</section>
    <section prefix="(m)">In Garrett County the members of the Board of County Commissioners may not receive additional compensation for their services in acting as members of the Board of License Commissioners.</section>
    <section prefix="(n)">In Harford County the provisions of subsection (a) of this section apply.</section>
    <section prefix="(o)">Repealed.</section>
    <section prefix="(p)">In Kent County each member of the Board of County Commissioners shall receive, in addition to their salaries as County Commissioners, $300 per year for their services in acting as members of the Board of License Commissioners.</section>
    <section prefix="(q)">In Montgomery County, each member of the Board of License Commissioners shall receive $9,000 per year, except the chairman who shall receive $10,000 per year.</section>
    <section prefix="(r)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This subsection applies only in Prince George's County.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Each of the members of the Board shall receive an annual salary of $17,000.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The chairman shall receive an annual salary of $18,000.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Board shall meet at least two times per month.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The administrator of the Board shall be appointed by and serve at the will of the Board and shall devote full time and attention to the duties of the Board.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The administrator may receive an annual salary of $40,705 as determined by the Board of License Commissioners after a performance evaluation.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(5)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The attorney for the Board shall be appointed by, and serve at the will of, the Board.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The attorney shall receive an annual salary of $15,500.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">In addition to the annual salary designated in subparagraph (ii) of this paragraph, the County Council shall pay to the attorney for the Board:</section>
        <section prefix="(iv)">The Board shall establish the fee rate for representing the Board in court.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(6)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The County Council shall pay for all expenses of the Board of License Commissioners upon the submission of an annual budget.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">In that budget, the salary of the members of the Board, the salary of the attorney for the Board, and any additional compensation for legal fees for the attorney for the Board, shall be approved as hereinbefore set forth.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">Except as provided in subparagraph (iv) of this paragraph, all other expenses, including, but not restricted to, the salary of the administrator as limited herein, compensation of other personnel, who shall be qualified and employed under the county merit system, printing, supplies, and office space, shall be at the discretion of the County Council.</section>
        <section prefix="(iv)">Each inspector shall receive an annual salary of $10,900.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(7)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Members of the Board of Alcoholic Beverages License Commissioners and the attorney for the Board are eligible for:</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The health benefits under this paragraph include:</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">The administrator of the Board of License Commissioners is eligible to participate in the County's supplemental retirement plan.</section>
        <section prefix="(iv)">The County Executive and the County Council may not adopt, either through public local law or personnel law, any policy contrary to the provisions of subparagraph (i) or (iii) of this paragraph.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(s)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In Queen Anne's County, the compensation for the Board of License Commissioners shall be at the rate to be determined by the County Commissioners.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The rate may not be less than:<section prefix="(i)">$65 per meeting for the chairman; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">$60 per meeting for each regular member.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(t)">In St. Mary's County the provisions of subsection (a) of this section apply.</section>
    <section prefix="(u)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In Somerset County each of the members of the Board, except the chairman, shall receive an annual salary of $3,000, and the chairman shall receive an annual salary of $3,500.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The County Commissioners shall provide a sum sufficient to pay for the salaries of the members of the Board.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The County Commissioners may provide a sum sufficient to pay for all expenses of the Board, including:<section prefix="(i)">Salaries of personnel other than members of the Board; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Costs of printing, supplies, and other expenses related to the operation of the Board.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(v)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In Talbot County each member of the Board shall receive as compensation a salary of $500 per year.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">In addition, the chairman of the Board shall receive a salary of $250 per year.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(w)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This subsection applies only in Washington County.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The annual salaries for the Board of License Commissioners are:<section prefix="(i)">Chairman - $9,850; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Members - $9,600.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The salaries specified in this subsection are payable monthly from the license fees derived from the issuance of licenses authorized by this article.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">A member or employee of the Board may not have any pecuniary or other interest in any phase of the manufacture, sale or distribution of any alcoholic beverages.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(x)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This subsection applies only in Wicomico County.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The annual compensation for the Board of License Commissioners is:<section prefix="(i)">Chairman - $5,000.</section><section prefix="(ii)">Members - $4,000.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(y)">In Worcester County:<section prefix="(1)">The regular members of the Board of License Commissioners shall receive an annual salary as determined by the County Commissioners but no less than:<section prefix="(i)">Chairman - $2,500 per year; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Each regular member - $2,100 per year; and</section></section><section prefix="(2)">The alternate member of the Board shall receive compensation, as determined by the County Commissioners, for services when acting on the Board.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
