<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="g2b" order_by="2" level="1">Alcoholic Beverages</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>g2b-2-101</section_number>
  <catch_line>The Office of the Comptroller shall provide application forms for the permits listed in this section...</catch_line>
  <order_by>101</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Office of the Comptroller shall provide application forms for the permits listed in this section and applicants shall make application to the Office of the Comptroller. The procedure in issuing permits, the purchase of alcoholic beverages, and the exercise of the privileges granted under the various permits shall be subject to regulations promulgated by the Office of the Comptroller. The Office of the Comptroller may cancel, restrict, suspend, or revoke any permit.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The Office of the Comptroller shall collect a fee for the issuance or renewal of the following permits:<section prefix="1.">$50 for a solicitor's permit, an individual storage permit, a nonresident winery permit, or a commercial nonbeverage permit;</section><section prefix="2.">$75 for a public storage permit, a public transportation permit, or an import and export permit;</section><section prefix="3.">$200 for a public storage and transportation permit, a nonresident dealer's permit, a resident dealer's permit, or a bulk transfer permit;</section><section prefix="4.">$400 for a family beer and wine facility permit;</section><section prefix="5.">$200 for issuance or renewal of a direct wine shipper's permit; and</section><section prefix="6.">$100 for a common carrier permit.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The Office of the Comptroller shall issue a nonbeverage permit without the payment of any fee for an eleemosynary or a fuel-alcohol permittee.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The permits issued pursuant to this section expire on October 31 following the date of their issue unless otherwise provided.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">All nonbeverage permits do not expire until canceled or revoked.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The fee for a change of domicile permit is $5, and when issued shall cover only a specific transaction.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The fee for an individual transportation permit is $10.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">A bulk transfer permit shall cover only a specific transaction and shall expire 10 days from the date of its issue. If the time restriction of this permit would be an undue burden, the Office of the Comptroller may grant a reasonable extension of time.</section>
      <section prefix="(6)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The Office of the Comptroller shall prescribe a means of identification for each vehicle authorized under an individual transportation permit or a transportation or public storage and transportation permit. The identification shall be kept in or on the vehicle at all times when alcoholic beverages are being transported.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The fee for the identification is $10 for each vehicle.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(7)">The fee for a national family beer and wine exhibition permit is $50.</section>
      <section prefix="(8)">The fee for the nonresident storage permit is $500.</section>
      <section prefix="(9)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The fee for an alcohol awareness program instructor's permit is $5.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The fee for an alcohol awareness program permit is $15.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(10)">The fee for a private bulk sale permit is $25 and shall cover the sale of a specific inventory of alcoholic beverages. The permit shall expire 60 days from the date of issuance. An individual or entity may be issued not more than two private bulk sale permits in any calendar year.</section>
      <section prefix="(11)">The fee for a winery special event permit is $25 per event.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The holder of a nonbeverage permit may purchase alcohol and alcoholic beverages for use in compounding or manufacturing flavoring extracts; medicinal, antiseptic or toilet preparations, or for other similar purposes; for scientific or laboratory purposes; or flavoring food products; or for sale by druggists or apothecaries upon the written prescription of a qualified physician.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The holder of a nonbeverage permit may not use, sell or deliver alcoholic beverages for beverage purposes or use, sell or deliver any product produced with alcoholic beverages which is fit for beverage purposes.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The holder of a change of domicile permit may transport into this State the holder's private stock of alcoholic beverages, for personal consumption only, when the permit holder is changing his domicile into this State, provided the taxes levied by &#xA7; 5-102 of the Tax - General Article have been paid to the Office of the Comptroller.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The holder of a permit may transport the holder's private stock of alcoholic beverages from or en route through this State without the payment of the excise taxes levied under &#xA7; 5-102 of the Tax - General Article, provided that the alcoholic beverages are not for use or delivery within this State.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">A person whose license has expired or otherwise has been discontinued, within 60 days subsequent to the last day the license was effective, may apply to the Comptroller for a permit to authorize transfer with or without consideration whether by sale, gift, inheritance, assignment or otherwise of the stock of alcoholic beverages on hand as of that day. The permit authorizes the transfer only to a license holder, which shall be consummated within the period covered by the permit.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The permit authorizes the operation of a warehouse for the storage of alcoholic beverages for the accounts of other persons and for the transportation for the accounts of other persons of alcoholic beverages into, within, or out of this State.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A permit may be issued for transportation or storage, or both.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A license or permit holder need not have a transportation permit to deliver alcoholic beverages which under this article the licensee or permit holder is authorized to acquire, store, sell, or use.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(h)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The holder of an individual storage permit may establish a warehouse for the storage of alcoholic beverages in which title to the stored alcoholic beverages is vested in the permit holder.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">In Anne Arundel County all retailers shall have written approval from the Board of License Commissioners for the county before making application with the Office of the Comptroller for the permit.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(i)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A nonresident dealer's permit, for the purpose of selling beer, wine, or distilled spirits to Maryland licensees authorized to receive those beverages, may be issued only to:<section prefix="(i)">A brewer, distiller, rectifier, bottler, manufacturer, vintner, or winery;</section><section prefix="(ii)">A sales agent of one of those under subparagraph (i) of this paragraph, provided proof of that agency is presented to the Office of the Comptroller;</section><section prefix="(iii)">An importer of beer, wine, or distilled beverages produced outside the United States who purchases directly from the brand owner or from a sales agent of a brewer, distiller, rectifier, bottler, manufacturer, vintner, or winery, who is authorized by the brand owner to sell in Maryland, and who has provided proof of this sales agency relationship to the Office of the Comptroller; or</section><section prefix="(iv)">An American sales agent of an importer under subparagraph (iii) of this paragraph, provided proof of that agency is presented to the Office of the Comptroller.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A nonresident dealer's permit may not be issued to a person who:<section prefix="(i)">Holds a wholesaler or retailer license of any class issued under this article;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Has an interest in a wholesaler licensed under this article, other than a disclosed legal, equity, or security interest of a malt beverage wholesaler; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">Has an interest in a retailer licensed under this article.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A holder of a nonresident dealer's permit may sell, consign, or deliver, from a location outside Maryland, to persons in Maryland who are authorized to receive them, only those beers, wines, or distilled spirits which it distills, rectifies, bottles, manufactures, produces, imports from outside the United States, or represents as the designated sales agent. The brewer, distiller, rectifier, bottler, manufacturer, vintner, winery, importer and their designated agent may not discriminate directly or indirectly in price between Maryland licensees.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">Notwithstanding any other provision of this section, any brand of beer presently being sold, consigned, or delivered in Maryland by the holder of a nonresident dealer's permit from a location outside Maryland to persons in Maryland who are authorized to receive it under this article may continue to be sold, consigned, or delivered until such time as the brewer, the importer, or designated sales agent of the brewer or the importer of that brand of beer preempts the sales territory by appointing a franchisee as provided in &#xA7;&#xA7; 17-101 through 17-107, inclusive, the Beer Franchise Fair Dealing Act, of this article.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">Notwithstanding any other provision of this section, a nonresident dealer's permit is not required to make direct sales and shipments to a wholesaler within this State from a location outside the continental limits and possessions of the United States.</section>
      <section prefix="(6)">Notwithstanding any other provision of this section, in Montgomery County the alcohol beverage purchasing power shall be as described in &#xA7;&#xA7; 15-204(b) and 15-205(k) of this article.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(j)">The holder of a permit may import into this State alcoholic beverages for storage in public warehouses, for subsequent shipment outside this State and not for sale, consignment or delivery to any person within this State.</section>
    <section prefix="(k)">A solicitor's permit may be issued in the discretion of the Office of the Comptroller and, if issued, shall grant a resident or nonresident holder the privilege of promoting, selling, or offering for sale, beer, wines or distilled spirits to manufacturers, wholesalers or retailers in this State. A permit holder may not contact consumers, and if the person holding the permit is employed by a nonresident dealer or resident dealer, the person holding the permit is not permitted to sell, promote or offer for sale alcoholic beverages to retail dealers, except for the account of a Maryland wholesaler or manufacturer who is a distributor for the products of the employer of the nonresident person or resident person holding such a permit.</section>
    <section prefix="(l)">The holder of a permit may establish a distilled spirits plant solely for the purpose of manufacturing, processing, storing, using, or distributing distilled spirits to be used exclusively for fuel purposes and not for beverage purposes.</section>
    <section prefix="(m)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A national family beer and wine exhibition permit may be issued at the discretion of the Office of the Comptroller to a bona fide national family wine association, national family beer association, or national family beer and wine association.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The permit holder may conduct a national family beer and wine exhibition and competition.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The permit holder may receive for use, exhibition, and tastings at a national family beer and wine exhibit:<section prefix="(i)">Tax free family-produced beer and wine;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Tax paid commercially-produced beers and wines from licensed nonresident dealers or manufacturers through licensed Maryland wholesalers or wines through licensed Class 4 wineries; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Commercially-produced beer and wine from non-Maryland licensed manufacturers or suppliers subject to the tax imposed in &#xA7; 5-102 of the Tax - General Article.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">A nonresident dealer's permit is not required of a non-Maryland licensed supplier for shipment of beer and wine to a national family beer and wine exhibition permittee.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">The permit holder may not sell but may exhibit, judge, and taste beer and wine acquired pursuant to this section at the place designated in the application for a period not exceeding 5 days.</section>
      <section prefix="(6)">Manufacturers, nonresident dealers, suppliers, and wholesalers or their representatives may act as judges or participate at a national family beer and wine exhibition.</section>
      <section prefix="(7)">The permit may be granted for:<section prefix="(i)">An unlicensed premises;</section><section prefix="(ii)">A Class B or Class C alcoholic beverages licensed premises; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">A Baltimore City Class B-D-7 alcoholic beverages licensed premises.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(8)">The permit authorizes the possession and consumption of beer and wine on the named premises with the permission of the licensee as provided in this section, notwithstanding contrary provisions of &#xA7; 12-107 of this article.</section>
      <section prefix="(9)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The permit holder shall file a report on forms provided by the Office of the Comptroller of the number of gallons of commercially-produced beer and wine received from nonlicensed suppliers, and pay the tax provided by &#xA7; 5-102 of the Tax - General Article within 30 days following the close of the exhibition.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">Instead of a bond, the Office of the Comptroller may require prepayment of a satisfactory sum to cover the anticipated tax.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(n)">A license or permit holder may not accept or deliver alcoholic beverages except as provided in this article and the Tax - General Article.</section>
    <section prefix="(o)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this subsection the following words have the meanings indicated.<section prefix="(i)">"Charitable organization" means an organization that is a benevolent, educational, philanthropic, humane, patriotic, religious, or eleemosynary organization that solicits or obtains contributions solicited from the public for charitable or benevolent purposes, and that is registered with the Secretary of State as required by law.</section><section prefix="(ii)">"Charitable organization" includes a chapter, branch, area office, or similar affiliate which has its principal place of business outside the State.</section><section prefix="(iii)">"Charitable organization" does not include a political party, political committee, political club, an agency of the State government or political subdivision, a fraternal organization, fire fighters, rescue or ambulance squads, or police or other law enforcement organization.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A wine auction permit, provided for under this subsection, may not be issued for use within Montgomery County.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Office of the Comptroller may issue a 1-day wine auction permit to a charitable organization.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The permit authorizes the holder to sell wine at public or private auction to any consumer through the solicitation and acceptance of bids.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">The permit may be granted for:<section prefix="(i)">An unlicensed premises;</section><section prefix="(ii)">A Class B or C licensed premises; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">In Baltimore City, a Class B-D-7 licensed premises.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(6)">The permit fee is $10.</section>
      <section prefix="(7)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The permit authorizes the holder to conduct 1 auction of wine during a calendar year.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">Only 1 permit shall be issued to each charity during a calendar year.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(8)">
        <section prefix="(i)">A permit holder may receive wine for the auction from:<section prefix="1.">A wholesaler licensed under this article;</section><section prefix="2.">A Class 3 or Class 4 winery licensed under this article;</section><section prefix="3.">A retail dealer licensed under this article;</section><section prefix="4.">A private individual residing in the State; or</section><section prefix="5.">A business entity that is located in the State and not licensed under this article.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">A permit holder may receive commercially-produced wine that is not authorized for distribution and sale in the State from:<section prefix="1.">A nonresident private individual; or</section><section prefix="2.">A business entity that is located outside of this State.</section></section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(9)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Wine that is received from the following sources is subject to Maryland tax as provided under &#xA7; 5-102 of the Tax - General Article:<section prefix="1.">Wholesalers licensed under this article;</section><section prefix="2.">Class 3 and 4 wineries licensed under this article; and</section><section prefix="3.">Any other source outside of this State.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">Wine that is received from the following sources is presumed to have been tax-paid:<section prefix="1.">Retail dealers licensed under this article;</section><section prefix="2.">Private individuals residing in this State; and</section><section prefix="3.">Business entities that are located in this State and not licensed under this article.</section></section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(10)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Within 30 days from the close of the auction, the permit holder shall file a report and pay all taxes that are due and owing on the wine that is received for the auction.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The report shall be filed with the Office of the Comptroller and shall include the total number of gallons of wine that was received for the auction and the sources from which it was received.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">The Office of the Comptroller shall provide the forms for the report.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(11)">The Office of the Comptroller may require that, within 7 days from the date of the auction, the permit holder prepay a satisfactory sum to cover the anticipated wine tax that is due and owing.</section>
      <section prefix="(12)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Wines that have been purchased at auction shall be delivered to the purchaser at the event or from a licensed warehouse or retail premises or other premises that is approved by the Office of the Comptroller.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">All wines delivered are subject to the applicable State sales taxes.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(13)">Notwithstanding any other provision of this article, any person authorized to sell wine at retail may purchase any wine offered at a wine auction, provided for under this section, in an amount not exceeding 5 gallons (18 liters) and may resell it in accordance with the terms of their license.</section>
      <section prefix="(14)">The Office of the Comptroller may adopt regulations to implement the provisions of this subsection.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(p)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Office of the Comptroller may issue a nonresident storage permit to a holder of a nonresident dealer permit.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The permit holder may store alcoholic beverages in a licensed public storage warehouse in this State for subsequent shipment to:<section prefix="(i)">Maryland licensed wholesalers;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Maryland licensed manufacturers; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">Persons outside of this State.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A nonresident storage permit holder may not ship any alcoholic beverages as provided under this section unless:<section prefix="(i)">The invoice for the shipment originates from the out-of-state permit address of the nonresident dealer; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">The holder ships the alcoholic beverages from the public storage warehouse in Maryland to the purchaser concurrently with the invoice being sent to the purchaser.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The permit holder shall file a monthly storage and shipping activities report with the Office of the Comptroller on forms and in the manner prescribed by the Office of the Comptroller.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(q)">An alcohol awareness program permit shall authorize the holder to conduct an alcohol awareness program which has been certified by the Comptroller under &#xA7; 13-101 of this article.</section>
    <section prefix="(r)">An alcohol awareness instructor's permit shall authorize the holder to conduct alcohol awareness training as an employee or agent of an alcohol awareness program permit holder.</section>
    <section prefix="(s)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this subsection, "permit" means a family beer and wine facility permit.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A permit authorizes the holder to establish a facility for the production of family beer or wine by nonlicensed State consumers who are of legal drinking age.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The permit holder may provide equipment, raw materials, and instructions to the consumer. Except for beer or wine produced for testing equipment or recipes and samples described in paragraph (5) of this subsection, the permit holder may not engage in the actual production or manufacture of beer or wine.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">All family beer and wine produced at a family beer and wine facility shall be removed from the premises by the consumer. It may only be used for home consumption and the personal use of the consumer.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The permit includes a sampling privilege.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">Patrons may have a maximum of five samples and the samples may not exceed 2 ounces per sample.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">Samples may only be consumed on the premises by a person who has a nonrefundable contract to brew or ferment at that facility.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(6)">The Office of the Comptroller may restrict a family beer and wine facility permit to the production of either family produced beer or family produced wine.</section>
      <section prefix="(7)">The holder of a permit may not simultaneously hold any other license issued pursuant to this article.</section>
      <section prefix="(8)">The Office of the Comptroller may promulgate regulations regarding limits on the quantities produced, requirements for record keeping, and any other activities that relate to the operation of a family beer and wine facility.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(t)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A private bulk sale permit authorizes the holder to sell the holder's private alcoholic beverages inventory to an individual or entity in accordance with this subsection.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">In order to qualify for a private bulk sale permit, an applicant must:<section prefix="(i)">Be an individual at least 21 years of age or older;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Be a current Maryland resident;</section><section prefix="(iii)">File an inventory with the Comptroller of all alcoholic beverages to be sold; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">Certify that all alcoholic beverages to be sold:<section prefix="1.">Have been legally acquired and transported into Maryland in accordance with this article; and</section><section prefix="2.">Are owned by the permit holder at the time of application.</section></section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Sales under a private bulk sale permit shall be made by:<section prefix="(i)">The permit holder; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">An unlicensed agent or auction company acting on behalf of the permit holder.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">Sales transactions may take place on:<section prefix="(i)">A premises not licensed under the provisions of this article; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">A private room of an on-premise retail licensee.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(5)">Sales may only be made under this permit to one or more of the following:<section prefix="(i)">A Maryland resident who is at least 21 years of age;</section><section prefix="(ii)">A Maryland alcoholic beverages retailer who holds the proper class of license; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">An individual or entity located outside of this State if the individual or entity is authorized to ship alcoholic beverages purchased under the permit to their home state or state of ultimate destination.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(6)">The Comptroller may promulgate regulations regarding record keeping, reporting requirements, and any other activities related to a private bulk sale permit.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(u)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Office of the Comptroller may issue a winery special event permit to a licensed Class 4 Maryland limited winery, provided that:<section prefix="(i)">Except as provided in paragraphs (6), (7), (8), (9), (10), (11), (12), (13), and (14) of this subsection, no more than 12 winery special event permits are issued to the Class 4 Maryland limited winery in any given calendar year;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The permit does not exceed 3 consecutive days; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Except as provided in paragraphs (6), (7), (8), (9), (10), (11), (12), (13), and (14) of this subsection, no more than three winery special event permits are issued in any calendar year to any given limited winery for use in the same political subdivision.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">In addition to the winery special event permit under paragraph (1) of this subsection, the Office of the Comptroller may issue a  winery special event permit to a licensed Class 4 Maryland limited winery for use during the entire length of the Montgomery County Agricultural Fair.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The winery special event permit may only be issued for an event which:<section prefix="(i)">Has as its major purpose an activity other than the sale and promotion of alcoholic beverages and for which the participation of the winery is a subordinate activity;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Is approved by the Department of Agriculture and the Office of the Comptroller; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Is held on a nonlicensed premises or a premises on which a person may obtain a temporary alcoholic beverages license.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">A winery special event permit shall authorize the holder to:<section prefix="(i)">Provide samples not to exceed 1 fluid ounce per brand to consumers;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Sell not more than four 750 ml bottles of wine to a consumer at any given event or festival for off-premises consumption; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Sell by the glass wine produced by the licensee to persons participating in any event or festival and for on-premises consumption.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(5)">The winery special event permit application shall be filed with the Office of the Comptroller not less than 15 days prior to any event.</section>
      <section prefix="(6)">A Class 4 Maryland limited winery in Calvert County may be issued a winery special event permit for unlimited use for one night each week from June through November at the North Beach Friday Night Farmers' Market.</section>
      <section prefix="(7)">
        <section prefix="(i)">In addition to the winery special event permits that may be issued under paragraph (1)(i) and (iii) of this subsection, a Class 4 Maryland limited winery may be issued not more than 12 winery special event permits for use at farmers' markets in Prince George's County that are listed on the Farmers' Market Directory of the Maryland Department of Agriculture.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">If a winery special event permit is issued under this paragraph:<section prefix="1.">The holder of the permit may not sell wine by the glass; and</section><section prefix="2.">The farmers' market administrator or the administrator's designee and the holder of the permit or the holder's designee shall be:</section></section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(8)">
        <section prefix="(i)">In addition to the winery special event permits that may be issued under paragraph (1)(i) and (iii) of this subsection, a Class 4 Maryland limited winery may be issued not more than 12 winery special event permits for use at farmers' markets in Montgomery County that are listed on the Farmers' Market Directory of the Maryland Department of Agriculture.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">If a winery special event permit is issued under this paragraph:<section prefix="1.">The holder of the permit may not sell wine by the glass; and</section><section prefix="2.">The farmers' market administrator or the administrator's designee and the holder of the permit or the holder's designee shall be:</section></section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(9)">
        <section prefix="(i)">In addition to the winery special event permits that may be issued under paragraph (1)(i) and (iii) of this subsection, a Class 4 Maryland limited winery may be issued not more than 12 winery special event permits for use at farmers' markets in Frederick County that are listed on the Farmers' Market Directory of the Maryland Department of Agriculture.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">If a winery special event permit is issued under this paragraph:<section prefix="1.">The holder of the permit may not sell wine by the glass; and</section><section prefix="2.">The farmers' market administrator or the administrator's designee and the holder of the permit or the holder's designee shall be:</section></section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(10)">
        <section prefix="(i)">
          <section prefix="1.">In addition to the winery special event permits that may be issued under paragraph (1)(i) and (iii) of this subsection and subject to subsubparagraph 2 of this subparagraph, a Class 4 Maryland limited winery may be issued not more than 12 winery special event permits for use at farmers' markets in Baltimore County that are listed on the Farmers' Market Directory of the Maryland Department of Agriculture.</section>
          <section prefix="2.">A Class 4 Maryland limited winery may use not more than six winery special event permits at the same farmers' market in Baltimore County in a year.</section>
        </section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">If a winery special event permit is issued under this paragraph:<section prefix="1.">The holder of the permit may not sell wine by the glass; and</section><section prefix="2.">The farmers' market administrator or the administrator's designee and the holder of the permit or the holder's designee shall be:</section></section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(11)">
        <section prefix="(i)">In addition to the winery special event permits that may be issued under paragraph (1)(i) and (iii) of this subsection, a Class 4 Maryland limited winery may be issued not more than 12 winery special event permits for use at farmers' markets in Carroll County that are listed on the Farmers' Market Directory of the Maryland Department of Agriculture.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">If a winery special event permit is issued under this paragraph:<section prefix="1.">The holder of the permit may not sell wine by the glass; and</section><section prefix="2.">The farmers' market administrator or the administrator's designee and the holder of the permit or the holder's designee shall be:</section></section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(12)">In addition to the winery special event permits that may be issued under paragraph (1)(i) and (iii) of this subsection, a Class 4 Maryland limited winery may be issued a winery special event permit for unlimited use for 1 day each week at a farmers' market in St. Mary's County that is listed on the Farmers' Market Directory of the Maryland Department of Agriculture.</section>
      <section prefix="(13)">In addition to the winery special event permits that may be issued under paragraph (1)(i) and (iii) of this subsection, a Class 4 Maryland limited winery may be issued a winery special event permit for unlimited use for 1 day each week at a farmers' market in Dorchester County that is listed on the Farmers' Market Directory of the Maryland Department of Agriculture.</section>
      <section prefix="(14)">In addition to the winery special event permits that may be issued under paragraph (1)(i) and (iii) of this subsection, a Class 4 Maryland limited winery may be issued a winery special event permit for unlimited use for 1 day each week at a farmers' market in Charles County that is listed on the Farmers' Market Directory of the Maryland Department of Agriculture.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(v)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Office of the Comptroller may issue a nonresident winery permit to a person that:<section prefix="(i)">Is licensed outside of the State to engage in the manufacture of wine;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Produces not more than 27,500 gallons of its own wine annually; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Does not hold a nonresident dealer's permit.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A holder of a nonresident winery permit may sell and deliver its own wine from a location outside of the State to a retail licensee or permit holder in the State authorized to acquire the wine.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A nonresident winery permit holder shall comply with all of the requirements of this article, the Tax - General Article, and the regulations of the Office of the Comptroller that apply to a holder of a Class 6 limited wine wholesaler's license.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(w)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Subject to paragraph (2) of this subsection, the Comptroller may issue a resident dealer's permit to:<section prefix="(i)">An importer of beer, wine, or distilled spirits produced outside the United States who purchases directly from the brand owner or from a sales agent of a brewer, distiller, rectifier, bottler, manufacturer, vintner, or winery, who is authorized by the brand owner to sell in the State, and who has provided proof of this sales agency relationship to the Comptroller; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">An American sales agent of an importer under subparagraph (i) of this paragraph, providing proof of that agency is presented to the Comptroller.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">To be issued a resident dealer's permit, an individual applicant, an applicant qualifying as a resident applicant for a corporation, or each applicant for a partnership shall have been a resident of the State for at least 2 years immediately before applying for the permit.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A resident dealer's permit may not be issued to a person who:<section prefix="(i)">Holds a wholesaler or retailer license of any class issued under this article;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Has an interest in a wholesaler licensed under this article, other than a disclosed legal, equity, or security interest of a malt beverage wholesaler; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">Has an interest in a retailer licensed under this article.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">A resident dealer's permit authorizes the holder to sell alcoholic beverages to a wholesaler licensed under this article in the State or to a person outside of the State who the Comptroller authorizes to acquire the alcoholic beverages.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">A holder of a resident dealer's permit may not own or operate a warehouse in the State.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(x)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this subsection, "permit" means a farmer's market permit.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">There is a farmer's market permit.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Comptroller may issue the permit to a holder of a license:<section prefix="(i)">Other than a Class 4 limited winery license, that allows the holder to sell alcoholic beverages to the public for consumption off the licensed premises; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">That was issued by the local licensing board of the jurisdiction in which the farmer's market will be held.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The holder of a permit shall notify the local licensing board of the jurisdiction in which the farmer's market will be held that the permit has been issued.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">
        <section prefix="(i)">A permit may be used only:<section prefix="1.">At a farmer's market that is listed in the farmer's market directory of the Maryland Department of Agriculture;</section><section prefix="2.">At the farmer's market named in the permit; and</section><section prefix="3.">During the hours of operation of the farmer's market for which it is obtained.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The Comptroller may issue not more than one permit for use at each farmer's market.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(6)">A permit authorizes the holder to:<section prefix="(i)">Occupy stall space at a farmer's market; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Subject to paragraph (7) of this subsection:<section prefix="1.">Offer and sell sealed containers of wine to consumers for consumption off the licensed premises of the farmer's market; and</section><section prefix="2.">Provide at no charge samples of wine not to exceed 1 fluid ounce per brand to consumers for consumption on the licensed premises of the farmer's market.</section></section></section>
      <section prefix="(7)">All wine offered for sale or samplings by the permit holder shall be the product of a Class 4 limited winery.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(y)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Office of the Comptroller may issue a common carrier permit to a person who meets the definition of a "common carrier" under &#xA7; 7.5-101 of this article.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The holder of a common carrier permit may deliver wine from a location inside or outside the State to a consumer in the State for the consumer's personal use under Title 7.5 of this article.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The holder of a common carrier permit that delivers wine solely under Title 7.5 of this article may not be required to obtain a transportation permit issued under subsection (g) of this section in addition to the common carrier permit.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
