<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="g2b" order_by="2" level="1">Alcoholic Beverages</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>g2b-11-102</section_number>
  <catch_line>Except as otherwise provided in this section, the hours during which alcoholic beverages may be sold...</catch_line>
  <order_by>102</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Except as otherwise provided in this section, the hours during which alcoholic beverages may be sold or delivered to retail license holders by holders of wholesalers' licenses are from 6 a.m. to midnight, on every day except Sundays.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Notwithstanding the provisions of subsections (a), (c), and (d) of this section, in each county of the State and in Baltimore City, the holder of a wholesale license may enter into an agreement with the holder of a special 1-day license issued pursuant to &#xA7; 7-101 of this article to deliver beer on the effective day of the license and accept returns on the same day of delivery.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The parties shall agree upon the type of equipment, services, personnel, and supplies that shall be required for the dispensing of draft beer.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Notwithstanding subsection (a) of this section, in Allegany County, a holder of a beer wholesaler's license may deliver draft beer to a retail license holder on Sundays and the beer wholesaler may provide equipment for the dispensing of draft beer at a rental price not less than the fair market cost for the rental. The provisions of this subsection do not violate any of the provisions of &#xA7; 12-104 of this article.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">In Anne Arundel County, whenever a special Class C license is issued under the provisions of &#xA7; 7-101 of this article, the holders of wholesale licenses may agree with the holder of a special Class C license to deliver beer on the effective date of the license and accept returns on the same day. The holder of a special Class C license shall pay for any equipment, services, personnel, and supplies required for dispensing draft beer, prior to the expiration of the license.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">In Montgomery County, the hours during which alcoholic beverages may be sold or delivered to retail license holders by the department of liquor control are from 6 a.m. to midnight on every day except Sundays.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This subsection applies only in Talbot County.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The hours during which alcoholic beverages may be sold or delivered to retail license holders by holders of wholesalers' licenses are from 6 a.m. to midnight, on every day except Sundays and election days.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">In Worcester County, the hours during which the Liquor Control Board may sell or deliver alcoholic beverages, except beer and light wine, to retail license holders are from 6 a.m. to midnight Monday through Saturday and from 9 a.m. to 5 p.m. on Sunday.</section>
  </text>
</law>
