<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="g2b" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="20-104" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>g2b-20-104</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">It shall be unlawful in Cecil County for any "bottle club" as herein defined or other public club, room, or premises which is to be used or is used as a "bottle club" so as to evade the alcoholic beverage license laws or hours of operation, to sell, give, serve, dispense, keep, or allow to be consumed on its premises or on premises under its control or possession any alcoholic beverage, setups, or other component parts of mixed alcoholic drinks.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">As used in this subsection, the term "bottle club" shall mean any club which serves, sells, gives, or dispenses alcoholic beverages to its members or guests, or which keeps for its members or guests any alcoholic beverages, or which allows to be consumed on its premises any alcoholic beverages, by its members or guests, which beverages have been reserved or purchased by the members or guests; or any club at which patrons are served, given, or allowed to consume alcoholic beverages after legal closing hours from the supplies that the patrons have previously purchased or reserved; or any club that sells, dispenses, serves, keeps, or allows to be consumed any setups or other component parts of mixed alcoholic drinks to its members or guests.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In Cecil County, any person who operates a business establishment for profit that is not licensed under this article may not knowingly permit customers to bring alcoholic beverages for consumption into an unlicensed building.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A person who violates any provision of this subsection is guilty of a misdemeanor and on conviction is subject to a fine not exceeding $1,000.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
