<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="g2b" order_by="" level="1">Alcoholic Beverages</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>g2b-2-208</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>208</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">There is a Class 7 micro-brewery (on- and off-sale) license.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The license shall be issued:<section prefix="(1)">By the State Comptroller;</section><section prefix="(2)">Only in the following jurisdictions:<section prefix="(i)">Allegany County;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Baltimore City;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Baltimore County;</section><section prefix="(iv)">The City of Annapolis;</section><section prefix="(v)">Anne Arundel County;</section><section prefix="(vi)">Calvert County;</section><section prefix="(vii)">Carroll County;</section><section prefix="(viii)">Charles County;</section><section prefix="(ix)">Dorchester County;</section><section prefix="(x)">Frederick County;</section><section prefix="(xi)">Garrett County;</section><section prefix="(xii)">Harford County;</section><section prefix="(xiii)">Howard County;</section><section prefix="(xiv)">Kent County;</section><section prefix="(xv)">Montgomery County;</section><section prefix="(xvi)">Prince George's County;</section><section prefix="(xvii)">Talbot County;</section><section prefix="(xviii)">Washington County;</section><section prefix="(xix)">Wicomico County; and</section><section prefix="(xx)">Worcester County;</section></section><section prefix="(3)"><section prefix="(i)">Only to a holder of a Class B beer, wine and liquor (on-sale) license that is issued for use on the premises of a restaurant located in a jurisdiction listed in paragraph (2) of this subsection;</section><section prefix="(ii)">To a holder of a Class D beer (off-sale) license that is issued for use on the premises of the existing Class D license if the premises are located in Kent County or the Town of Berlin in Worcester County; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">To a holder of a Class D alcoholic beverages license that is issued for use on the premises of the existing Class D license if the premises are located in:<section prefix="1.">The 22nd Alcoholic Beverages District of Prince George's County; or</section><section prefix="2.">Washington County; and</section></section></section><section prefix="(4)">In addition to item (3) of this subsection, in Montgomery County only to a holder of a Class H beer and light wine license that is issued for use on the premises of a restaurant located in the County.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A holder of a Class 7 micro-brewery license:<section prefix="(i)">May brew and bottle malt beverages at the license location;</section><section prefix="(ii)">May obtain a Class 2 rectifying license for a premises located within 1 mile of the existing Class 7 micro-brewery location to bottle malt beverages brewed at the micro-brewery location only;</section><section prefix="(iii)">May contract with the holder of a Class 5 brewery license, a Class 7 micro-brewery license, or a Class 2 rectifying license held under &#xA7; 2-203 of this subtitle or the holder of a nonresident dealer's permit to brew and bottle malt beverages on their behalf;</section><section prefix="(iv)">May store the finished product under an individual storage permit or at a licensed public storage facility for subsequent sale and delivery to a licensed wholesaler, an authorized person outside this State, and for shipment back to the micro-brewery location for sale on the retail premises;</section><section prefix="(v)">May not collectively brew, bottle, or contract for more than 22,500 barrels of malt beverages each calendar year; and</section><section prefix="(vi)">May enter into a temporary delivery agreement with a distributor only for delivery of beer to a beer festival or wine and beer festival and the return of any unused beer if:<section prefix="1.">The beer festival or wine and beer festival is in a sales territory for which the holder does not have a franchise with a distributor under the Beer Franchise Fair Dealing Act; and</section><section prefix="2.">The temporary delivery agreement is in writing.</section></section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A Class 7 licensee who wishes to produce more than the barrelage authorized under paragraph (1)(v) of this subsection shall divest of any Class B, D, or any other retail license and obtain a Class 5 manufacturer's license.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">For the purposes of determining the barrelage limitation under paragraph (1)(v) of this subsection, any salable beer produced under contractual arrangements accrues only to the Class 7 micro-brewery licensee who is the brand owner.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">In Allegany County only, the holder of a Class 7 license:<section prefix="(i)">May brew in one location and may contract for the bottling of the malt beverage in another location; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Need not meet the hotel/motel requirements for a Class B beer, wine and liquor licensee but shall meet the requirements for those Class B restaurants.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The on-sale privilege authorizes the holder, each calendar year, to sell at retail up to 4,000 barrels of beer brewed under this license to customers for consumption on the licensed premises.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The off-sale privilege authorizes the holder to sell and deliver beer brewed under this license to:<section prefix="(i)">Any wholesaler licensed under this article to sell beer in this State; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">Any person who is located in a state other than Maryland who is authorized under the laws of that state to receive brewed beverages.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">This paragraph applies only in:<section prefix="1.">Allegany County;</section><section prefix="2.">The City of Annapolis;</section><section prefix="3.">Anne Arundel County;</section><section prefix="4.">Baltimore City;</section><section prefix="5.">Baltimore County;</section><section prefix="6.">Calvert County;</section><section prefix="7.">Carroll County;</section><section prefix="8.">Charles County;</section><section prefix="9.">Dorchester County;</section><section prefix="10.">Frederick County;</section><section prefix="11.">Garrett County;</section><section prefix="12.">Harford County;</section><section prefix="13.">Howard County;</section><section prefix="14.">Kent County;</section><section prefix="15.">Montgomery County;</section><section prefix="16.">Prince George's County;</section><section prefix="17.">Talbot County;</section><section prefix="18.">Washington County;</section><section prefix="19.">Wicomico County; and</section><section prefix="20.">Worcester County.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The holder may sell at retail beer brewed under this license to customers for consumption off the licensed premises in refillable containers that are sealed by the micro-brewery licensee at the time of each refill.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">A holder of a Class 7 micro-brewery license:<section prefix="(1)">May not own, operate or be affiliated with any other manufacturer of beer except for a Class 2 rectifying license authorized by subsection (c)(1)(ii) of this section; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Notwithstanding &#xA7; 2-201(b) of this subtitle, may not be granted a wholesale alcoholic beverages license.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, the hours and days for consumer sales under a Class 7 micro-brewery license are as established for:<section prefix="(i)">A Class B license in the respective jurisdictions listed in subsection (b)(2) of this section, for a holder of a Class B beer, wine and liquor license;</section><section prefix="(ii)">A Class D beer license in Worcester County, for a holder of a Class D beer license in the Town of Berlin in Worcester County; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">A Class D license in Kent County.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">For Class D licensees in the 22nd Alcoholic Beverages District in Prince George's County only, the hours and days for consumer sales under this license are as established for a Class D license in Prince George's County.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">For Class D licensees in Washington County, the hours and days for consumer sales under this license are as established for a Class D license in Washington County.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">In Montgomery County, a holder of a Class 7 micro-brewery license shall enter into a written agreement with the Department of Liquor Control for Montgomery County for the sale and resale of malt beverages brewed under this license in accordance with this article.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">For Talbot County, the Office of the Comptroller of Maryland shall specify which local license is the equivalent of the Class B beer, wine and liquor license specified in subsection (b)(3) of this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">In Carroll County, the distance restriction requirement for micro-breweries is found in &#xA7; 9-207 of this article.</section>
    <section prefix="(j)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This subsection applies only in Washington County.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Comptroller may not issue a Class 7 micro-brewery license for a premises on property that has been leased unless the landlord of the property presents to the Comptroller a receipt or certificate showing that there are no unpaid taxes due to the State, a county, or any local government from the landlord or any entity in which the landlord has a direct or indirect interest that:<section prefix="(i)">Is proprietary; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">Has been obtained by a loan, mortgage, or lien, or in any other manner.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
