<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="g2b" order_by="" level="1">Alcoholic Beverages</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>g2b-8-313.2</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>313.2</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Board" means the Wicomico County Board of License Commissioners.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Festival" means the Wicomico County Wine Festival.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">This section applies only in Wicomico County.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Board may issue a special WCWF license.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Notwithstanding any other provision of this article, to be eligible for a special WCWF license an applicant must be a holder of an existing State retail alcoholic beverages license, a State Class 3 winery license, or a State Class 4 limited winery license.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">A holder of a special WCWF license shall:<section prefix="(1)">Display and sell wine that is:<section prefix="(i)">Manufactured and processed in any state;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Price filed in accordance with regulations adopted by the Comptroller; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Distributed in the State at the time the application is filed; and</section></section><section prefix="(2)">Display and sell wine at retail for consumption on or off the licensed premises on the days and for the hours designated for the Festival.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">This section does not prohibit the holder of a special WCWF license from holding another alcoholic beverages license of a different class or nature.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">The special WCWF license fee is $50 per day.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Board shall choose:<section prefix="(i)">One weekend, Friday through Sunday inclusive, annually for the Festival; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">A location for the Festival that is in the county but that is not licensed currently under this article.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Board shall assure that the primary focus of the Festival is the promotion of Maryland wine.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(i)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Products displayed and sold at the Festival shall be:<section prefix="(i)">Invoiced to the holder of the special WCWF license by a licensed State wholesaler, winery, or limited winery; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Delivered to the Festival from the licensed premises of the wholesaler, winery, or limited winery.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Whenever a special WCWF license is issued, a holder of a wholesale, winery, or limited winery license may enter into an agreement with the holder of a special WCWF license to deliver wine 2 days before the effective date of the special WCWF license and to accept returns 2 days after the expiration date of the special WCWF license.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(j)">The Board shall adopt regulations to carry out this section.</section>
  </text>
</law>
