<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="g2b" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="10-204" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>g2b-10-204</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as otherwise provided in this section, the local collecting agent shall remit all license fees collected under this article to the board of county commissioners or county fiscal officer for the county, or to the Mayor and City Council of Baltimore, as the case may be.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The board of county commissioners or Mayor and City Council of Baltimore shall use the portion of the receipts as may be necessary to pay refunds as provided in this section, and devote the balance to the general purposes of the county or city, as the case may be.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Comptroller's office may retain from the license and permit fees collected by the office for the use of the State of Maryland sums necessary to pay refunds on licenses issued by the office and the expenses incurred by the office in the discharge of the duties imposed by this article.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This subsection applies only in Allegany County.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Director of Finance is the local collecting agent. The Director of Finance shall:<section prefix="(i)">Credit 5 percent of the license fees received for licenses that are issued to a place of business located in a municipal corporation to the general fund of the county to cover administrative costs; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Pay 50 percent of the remaining license fees received for licenses that are issued to a place of business located in a municipal corporation in the county to the municipal corporation.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The chairman of the Board of License Commissioners shall submit to the Director of Finance the total amount of the Board's budget, including:</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">From the receipts, the County Commissioners shall pay:</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">The salaries and expenses of the employees of the Board shall be subject to the approval of the County Commissioners.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except for licenses granted to places of business located in the City of Annapolis, the Anne Arundel County Board of License Commissioners shall:<section prefix="(i)">Collect all alcoholic beverages license fees; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Issue all alcoholic beverages licenses authorized under this article for Anne Arundel County.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The Anne Arundel County Board of License Commissioners shall remit to the county all fees collected by the Board.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The county shall pay from the receipts the salaries and expenses of the Board and of its employees, as approved by the State Comptroller, and shall devote the balance of the receipts to the general purposes of the county.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The City Clerk of the City of Annapolis shall:<section prefix="(i)">Collect all alcoholic beverages license fees for licenses granted to places of business located in the City of Annapolis; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Issue all alcoholic beverages licenses authorized under this article for the City of Annapolis.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The City Clerk of the City of Annapolis shall remit to the City of Annapolis all fees collected by the City Clerk.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The City of Annapolis shall devote the receipts to the general purposes of the City.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">In Baltimore City the Mayor and City Council of Baltimore shall pay from the receipts the salaries and expenses of the Board of License Commissioners of Baltimore City and its employees, as approved by the State Comptroller.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">Baltimore County shall pay from the license fees all salaries and expenses of the Board of License Commissioners as determined by the county, and shall devote the balance of the license fees to the general purposes of the county. The phrase "the general purposes of the county" in Baltimore County includes the general purposes of the highways and the general purposes of the metropolitan district department of the county.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">Calvert County Board of County Commissioners shall pay the salaries and expenses of the Board of License Commissioners for Calvert County. Where the licensed place of business is located in an incorporated town 50 percent of the net license fee shall be payable to the incorporated town and the remaining 50 percent and all the net license fees for places of business located outside an incorporated town shall be used by the County Commissioners for the purposes of the county.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">In Caroline County, the provisions of subsection (a) of this section apply.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">In Carroll County, the County Commissioners shall forthwith pay 25 percent of the sum to the incorporated town in which the place of business is located.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">Repealed.</section>
    <section prefix="(j)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In Charles County, the Board of License Commissioners shall remit promptly to the Board of County Commissioners:<section prefix="(i)">All license fees collected under this article; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Any refunds paid under this article.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Any amount paid to the Board of County Commissioners under paragraph (1) of this subsection shall be applied to the general fund of the county.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Any person violating any of the provisions of paragraph (1) of this subsection shall be punished by a fine not exceeding $500.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(k)">In Dorchester County, the provisions of subsection (a) of this section apply.</section>
    <section prefix="(l)">In Frederick County, where the licensed place of business is located in an incorporated town, 50 percent of the license fee shall be paid to the incorporated town, and the remaining 50 percent, and all license fees for places of business located outside an incorporated town, shall be turned over by the Board of County Commissioners to the County Treasurer. The salary and expenses of the license commissioner shall be paid by the County Commissioners from the license fees received under this article.</section>
    <section prefix="(m)">The Board of License Commissioners of Garrett County shall pay 50 percent of the license fee or $500, whichever is less, to the mayor and council of the incorporated town in which the licensed premises are located.</section>
    <section prefix="(n)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The provisions of this subsection apply only in Harford County.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The net proceeds of all funds received by the Board from the sale of licenses under the provisions of this article, outside of the corporate limits of the municipalities of Aberdeen, Bel Air and Havre de Grace, shall be paid to the Treasurer and credited to the general funds of the county.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The net proceeds of the funds derived from the sale of licenses within the corporate limits of the municipalities of Aberdeen, Bel Air and Havre de Grace, after the deduction of a proportionate part of the expenses incident to the proper administration and enforcement of this article, shall be paid by the Board to the treasurers of the respective towns, to be applied to the payment of the interest and the redemption of the principal of any bonded indebtedness.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">All expenses incident to the proper administration and enforcement of this article, including the salaries of the members of the Board, and the proper proportion of the salaries of any employees of the Board, whose duties include the handling of licenses, including the salaries of officers, inspectors, etc., shall be deducted proportionately from the shares of the license fees payable as set forth in this subsection, to the general funds of the county and the governing bodies of the three municipalities.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Prior to the beginning of each fiscal year, the Board shall submit an annual budget to the County Council and County Executive for review.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">Except as provided under &#xA7; 15-205(i)(3) of this article, the budget is not subject to approval by the County Council or County Executive.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">The expenditure of license fees collected by the Board for the administration and enforcement of county liquor laws is a matter entirely within the sound discretion of the Board and the provisions of this subsection.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(o)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In Howard County:<section prefix="(i)">The Board of License Commissioners shall issue the license; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">The Director of Finance shall collect the license fees.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The county shall:<section prefix="(i)">Pay from the receipts the salaries and expenses of the Board of License Commissioners; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Devote the balance of the receipts to the general purposes of Howard County.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(p)">In Kent County, the provisions of subsection (a) of this section apply.</section>
    <section prefix="(q)">In Montgomery County, the provisions of subsection (a) of this section apply.</section>
    <section prefix="(r)">In Prince George's County, the Prince George's County Director of Finance shall collect fees for the County Executive and County Council, which shall use a portion of the receipts to pay the salaries and expenses of the Board of License Commissioners.</section>
    <section prefix="(s)">Repealed.</section>
    <section prefix="(t)">In St. Mary's County the County Treasurer shall collect the alcoholic beverages license fees and shall pay to the Commissioners of Leonardtown, for general corporate purposes, the funds received from licenses issued to premises within the limits of town.</section>
    <section prefix="(u)">In Somerset County, the provisions of subsection (a) of this section apply.</section>
    <section prefix="(v)">In Talbot County the salaries of the Board of License Commissioners and the necessary office, clerical, and investigational expenses of the Board shall be paid by the County Council out of receipts from licenses for the sale of alcoholic beverages. However, the Board may expend in its discretion not more than $3,500 in any year for salaries and expenses.</section>
    <section prefix="(w)">In Washington County the Board of License Commissioners shall deduct funds necessary to pay its salaries and its employees' salaries, and such other expenses as the Board may deem necessary. The Board shall pay over the net proceeds of the license fees ratably to the incorporated town in which the place of business is located or to the County Commissioners for the use of the county, if the place of business is not located in an incorporated town.</section>
    <section prefix="(x)">In Wicomico County the County Council shall pay the salaries and expenses of the Board of License Commissioners.</section>
    <section prefix="(y)">In Worcester County the Board of County Commissioners shall pay the salaries and expenses of the Board of License Commissioners.</section>
  </text>
</law>
