<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="g2b" order_by="2" level="1">Alcoholic Beverages</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>g2b-9-217</section_number>
  <catch_line>This section applies only in Prince George's County....</catch_line>
  <order_by>217</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">This section applies only in Prince George's County.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Subject to subsection (b-1) of this section, the number of licenses of each class of alcoholic beverage licenses may not exceed the following maximum amounts:<section prefix="(1)">Beer license, Class A19</section><section prefix="(2)">Beer license, Class B23</section><section prefix="(3)">Beer license, Class C3</section><section prefix="(4)">Beer license, Class D76</section><section prefix="(5)">Beer and light wine license, Class A26</section><section prefix="(6)">Beer and light wine license, Class B45</section><section prefix="(7)">Beer and light wine license, Class B-GC4</section><section prefix="(8)">Beer and light wine license, Class B-Stadium1</section><section prefix="(9)">Beer and light wine license, Class C8</section><section prefix="(10)">Beer and light wine license, Class D55</section><section prefix="(11)">Beer, wine and liquor license, Class A142</section><section prefix="(12)">Beer, wine and liquor license, Class B185</section><section prefix="(13)">Beer, wine and liquor license, Class B-AE5</section><section prefix="(14)">Beer, wine and liquor license, Class BCE8</section><section prefix="(15)">Beer, wine and liquor license, Class B-CI2</section><section prefix="(16)">Reserved.</section><section prefix="(17)">Beer, wine and liquor license, Class B/ECF1</section><section prefix="(18)">Beer, wine and liquor license, Class B-ECF/DS1</section><section prefix="(19)">Beer, wine and liquor license, Class B-ECR1</section><section prefix="(20)">Beer, wine and liquor license, Class B-Stadium1</section><section prefix="(21)">Beer, wine and liquor license, Class C<section prefix="(i)">Under &#xA7; 6-301(r)(2) 30</section><section prefix="(ii)">Under &#xA7; 6-301(r)(3) 25</section><section prefix="(iii)">Under &#xA7; 6-301(r)(4) 4</section><section prefix="(iv)">Under &#xA7; 6-301(r)(5) 12</section><section prefix="(v)">Under &#xA7; 6-301(r)(7) 1</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(b-1)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A person may obtain a Class A license of any kind for the purpose of having the Board of License Commissioners declare the license to be extinguished.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The person shall inform the Board of License Commissioners of the purpose for obtaining the license.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The Board of License Commissioners shall declare the license to be extinguished when the person comes into possession of the license.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Within 10 days after having come into possession of the license, the person shall:<section prefix="(i)">Surrender the license to the Board of License Commissioners; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Provide evidence to satisfy the Board that all taxes or obligations to wholesalers or other persons have been paid.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">A person that obtains a license under this subsection may not exercise the privileges of, sell, assign, or apply for transfer of the license.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">The Board of License Commissioners may impose on a person who violates this subsection a penalty not exceeding $1,000.</section>
      <section prefix="(6)">A license that is extinguished under this subsection:<section prefix="(i)">May not be replaced by the Board; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Counts as one of the number of licenses in the appropriate class listed in subsection (b) of this section.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">This section does not invalidate any license in any class which exceeds the maximum number of that class at the time of effective date of this provision, but when any licenses in excess of the number provided in this section expire by virtue of revocation, cessation of business, or nonrenewal, then a new license may not be issued to replace it.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">This section does not apply to a license issued under the provisions of &#xA7; 6-201(r)(2), (5), (15), or (17), or &#xA7; 7-101 of this article.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Except as provided in item (ii) of this paragraph, a license may not be granted to sell alcoholic beverages in any building located within 1,000 feet of a school building, or within 500 feet of a place of worship. The 1,000 feet, or the 500 feet, as the case may be, is to be measured from the front door or main entrance, whichever is nearest the street abutting the premises, of the proposed licensed establishment along the nearest usual pedestrian route to the door closest to the licensed premises which is used as an entrance or exit to any school, or to the main entrance of the place of worship.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">In the part of the Gateway Arts and Entertainment District located in the City of Hyattsville, as designated by the Secretary of Business and Economic Development, the front door or main entrance of an establishment for which a Class D beer and wine license is issued may be used if the door or entrance is at least 350 feet from a place of worship.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">This restriction does not apply in the case of a church if the governing body of the church concerned consents in writing to the granting of the license. The consent shall be filed with the application. The license of any person or persons or for the use of a corporation or unincorporated association issued for any building located within the requisite distance from a church or school building may be renewed or extended for the same building.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">This restriction does not apply to any transfer or assignment of a license located within the distance of 1,000 feet to another place of business within the specified distance and/or to an assignee of the license within the distance of the same church or school building.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">This does not apply to the issuance of a license for a place of business, not having an alcoholic beverage license, to which an alcoholic beverage license had been issued and was in force and effect on June 1, 1965, as to a license of the same class which was in force and effect as of that date, applied for in the place of business nor to a renewal of a license of any establishment where, subsequent to the original granting of the license a school or church building was erected within 1,000 feet.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">This subsection does not apply to any license issued under &#xA7; 6-201(r)(2), (4), (5), (15), (16), or (18) or &#xA7; 7-101 of this article.</section>
      <section prefix="(6)">This restriction does not apply in the case of a private kindergarten or nursery school.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Except as provided in &#xA7; 6-201(r)(15) of this article, a person, whether acting on that person's behalf or on the behalf of another person or entity, corporation, association, partnership, limited partnership or other combination of persons (natural or otherwise) for whatever reason formed, may not have an interest in more than one license authorizing the retail or wholesale sale of alcoholic beverages.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">An interest shall be conclusively presumed to exist between 2 licensees or a licensee and an applicant for a license if any of the following conditions exist between them:<section prefix="1.">A franchise agreement;</section><section prefix="2.">A licensing agreement;</section><section prefix="3.">A concession agreement;</section><section prefix="4.">Where both are part of a chain of businesses commonly owned and operated and so portrayed to the public;</section><section prefix="5.">Any sharing of directors or stockholders or any sharing of directors or stockholders of parents or subsidiaries;</section><section prefix="6.">Common direct or indirect sharing of profit from the sale of alcoholic beverages; or</section><section prefix="7.">Sharing of a common trade name, trademark, logo or theme, or mode of operation identifiable by the public, except hotels and motels.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">The Board of License Commissioners shall make determinations under this subsection without regard to whether a particular licensee or proposed licensee is or may be an independent contractor for purposes other than the application of this subsection.</section>
        <section prefix="(iv)">A holder of a wholesale alcoholic beverages license is considered a licensee for purposes of this subsection and may not hold or have an interest, directly or indirectly, in an alcoholic beverages license of any class that authorizes retail sale of alcoholic beverages in Prince George's County.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">This subsection does not apply to licenses issued under the provisions of &#xA7; 6-201(r)(2), (3), (5), (10), or (15), &#xA7; 7-101, or &#xA7; 8-505 of this article or to club licenses.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Notwithstanding other provisions of this subsection or other provisions of this article, the Board of License Commissioners may permit an individual, partnership, or corporation to hold or have an interest in not more than four BH licenses.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">If the Board of License Commissioners determines after a hearing that an interest exists in more than one license, the Board shall refuse to issue a new license or shall revoke an existing license, unless the license is operational and complied with law applicable at the time of its issuance.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">
        <section prefix="(i)">This paragraph does not apply to a restaurant located within a chain store, supermarket, discount house, drug store, or convenience store.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">Notwithstanding any other provision of this article, the Board of License Commissioners may allow an individual, partnership, corporation, unincorporated association, or limited liability company to hold or have an interest in more than one Class B beer, wine and liquor license, if the restaurant for which the license is sought is located within:<section prefix="1.">Any of the following areas that are underserved by restaurants:</section><section prefix="2."/></section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">
          <section prefix="1.">Except as provided in sub-subparagraph 2 and 3 of this subparagraph, a license holder may not hold more than 4 Class B beer, wine and liquor licenses within all of the underserved areas described in subparagraph (ii)1 of this paragraph.</section>
          <section prefix="2."/>
          <section prefix="3."/>
        </section>
        <section prefix="(iv)">An individual, partnership, corporation, unincorporated association, or limited liability company that holds or has an interest in a license located in an underserved area described in subparagraph (ii)1 of this paragraph may not hold or have an interest in more than one license located outside of all the underserved areas.</section>
        <section prefix="(v)">An individual, partnership, corporation, unincorporated association, or limited liability company may not hold or have an interest in more than one license in a commercial establishment described in subparagraph (ii)2 of this paragraph.</section>
        <section prefix="(vi)">The annual license fee for a Class B license obtained under this paragraph is $2,500.</section>
        <section prefix="(vii)">A Class B license obtained under this paragraph does not confer off-sale privileges.</section>
        <section prefix="(viii)">The residency requirements under &#xA7; 9-101 of this title apply to an applicant for a Class B license under this paragraph.</section>
        <section prefix="(ix)">The limit on the maximum number of Class B beer, wine and liquor licenses in the county under subsection (b) of this section applies to the issuance of licenses under this paragraph.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(6)">
        <section prefix="(i)">In this paragraph, "business licensing agreement" means an agreement that authorizes a person, in the operation of a restaurant, to use a trademark, trade name, or other identifying symbol owned by a licensor.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">This paragraph does not apply to a restaurant located in a chain store, supermarket, discount house, drug store, or convenience store.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">In accordance with the alcoholic beverages license quota limitations under subsection (b) of this section, the Board of License Commissioners may issue or transfer a Class B beer (on-sale) license or a Class B beer and wine (on-sale) license for use by:<section prefix="1.">A franchisee who operates a restaurant under a franchise agreement with a franchisor; or</section><section prefix="2.">A person who operates a restaurant under a business licensing agreement with a licensor.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(iv)">Notwithstanding paragraph (1) of this subsection or other provisions of this article, the Board may issue or transfer a license under subparagraph (iii) of this paragraph regardless of whether a Class B beer (on-sale) license or Class B beer and wine (on-sale) license has been issued or transferred for use by:<section prefix="1.">Another franchisee operating a restaurant under a franchise agreement with the same franchisor; or</section><section prefix="2.">Another person operating a restaurant under a business licensing agreement with the same licensor.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(v)">A person that receives a Class B beer (on-sale) or Class B beer and wine (on-sale) license under this paragraph may not hold another Class B beer (on-sale) or Class B beer and wine (on-sale) license unless authorized under another provision of law.</section>
        <section prefix="(vi)">For the purposes of this paragraph:<section prefix="1.">A licensor or franchisor may not have an ownership interest in a person that receives a Class B beer (on-sale) or Class B beer and wine (on-sale) license under this paragraph; and</section><section prefix="2.">Notwithstanding item 1 of this subparagraph, a business licensing agreement or franchise agreement may require a person that receives a Class B beer (on-sale) or Class B beer and wine (on-sale) license under this paragraph to pay the licensor or franchisor a fee that is based on a percentage of revenue.</section></section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(7)">Subject to &#xA7; 6-201(r)(15) of this article, the Board of License Commissioners may issue:<section prefix="(i)">Up to four Class B-DD (Development District) licenses for restaurants located within the Capital Plaza commercial area, consisting of commercial properties within the area bounded by the Baltimore-Washington Parkway on the west and northwest, Maryland Route 450 on the south, and Cooper Lane on the east and northeast;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Up to four Class B-DD (Development District) licenses for restaurants located within the area of Greenbelt Station, located inside the Capital Beltway and adjacent to the Greenbelt Metro Station; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Up to six Class B-DD (Development District) licenses may be issued to restaurants located within the area of Ritchie Station Marketplace.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">If an existing license has been issued to individuals for the use of a corporation or club and thereafter the licensee desires to substitute one or more of the officers of such corporation or club, the substitution may be requested by filing with the Board of License Commissioners for the county a petition setting forth the necessary information for the substitution or substitutions without the necessity of filing a formal application for transfer of license as otherwise provided in this article. The petition for substitution of officers shall be approved by the Board upon a proper showing that the licensee would still meet the requirements of the law as set forth elsewhere in this article.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, an alcoholic beverage license with an off-sale privilege of any class, except by way of renewal, may not be transferred or issued to any business establishment of the type commonly known as chain stores, supermarkets, discount houses or their franchisors and franchisees or concessionaires. However, those establishments holding an alcoholic beverage license at the time of enactment of this section may continue to hold such license, and may, at the discretion of the Board of License Commissioners, change the classification of their license.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Notwithstanding any other provision of this article, the Board of License Commissioners may approve the transfer from the 47th alcoholic beverages district to the 21st alcoholic beverages district of one Class D beer and light wine license with an off-sale privilege for use by a supermarket or similar type of premises.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(i)">An application for an alcoholic beverage license may not be considered prima facie evidence that the applicant or applicants are entitled to the license. Because of the limitation on licenses as set forth in subsection (b) of this section the burden of proof is upon the applicant or applicants to show to the Board of License Commissioners that the issuance of a license to the applicant or applicants is necessary for the accommodation of the public at the premises applied for. The limitations on licenses enumerated in subsection (b) of this section may not be construed as the number of licenses the Board is obligated to issue.</section>
    <section prefix="(j)">The residency requirement provided for in &#xA7; 9-101 of this article applies to any issuance, renewal, or transfer of a license.</section>
    <section prefix="(k)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This subsection does not prohibit the issuance of a Class B-DH (drafthouse) license for use on the premises of a drafthouse as defined in &#xA7; 8-702(a) of this article.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Prince George's County Board of License Commissioners may not issue an alcoholic beverages license for use on the premises of a motion picture theater.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(l)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Board of License Commissioners may not issue any new beer, wine or liquor licenses that have an off-sale privilege within, or transfer any additional beer, wine or liquor licenses that have an off-sale privilege into the boundaries of the 21st (that part located within the county), 22nd, 23rd, 24th, 25th, 26th, 27th (that part located within the county), or 47th alcoholic beverages district as follows:<section prefix="(i)">The 21st alcoholic beverages district at all times shall be coterminous with the Prince George's County part of the 21st legislative district. As ordered by the Maryland Court of Appeals on June 21, 2002, the Prince George's County part of the 21st alcoholic beverages district consists of:<section prefix="1.">Prince George's County election district 1;</section><section prefix="2.">Prince George's County election district 10, precincts 1 through 5, 9, 12, and 13;</section><section prefix="3.">Prince George's County election district 21, precincts 1, 2, 4, 14, 15, and 17;</section><section prefix="4.">That part of Prince George's County election district 21, precinct 5 consisting of census tract 8073.05, block 1014; and</section><section prefix="5.">That part of Prince George's County election district 21, precinct 10 consisting of the following census tracts and blocks:</section></section><section prefix="(ii)">The 22nd alcoholic beverages district at all times shall be coterminous with the 22nd legislative district in Prince George's County. As ordered by the Maryland Court of Appeals on June 21, 2002, the 22nd alcoholic beverages district consists of:<section prefix="1.">Prince George's County election district 19;</section><section prefix="2.">Prince George's County election district 2, precincts 6 and 10;</section><section prefix="3.">Prince George's County election district 14, precinct 8;</section><section prefix="4.">Prince George's County election district 16, precincts 2 through 5;</section><section prefix="5.">Prince George's County election district 17, precincts 9 and 12;</section><section prefix="6.">Prince George's County election district 20, precincts 1, 2, 6, 7, and 11;</section><section prefix="7.">Prince George's County election district 21, precincts 3, 6 through 9, 11 through 13, and 16;</section><section prefix="8.">That part of Prince George's County election district 2, precinct 5 consisting of the following census tracts and blocks:</section><section prefix="9.">That part of Prince George's County election district 2, precinct 8 consisting of census tract 8063.00, block 2016;</section><section prefix="10.">That part of Prince George's County election district 16, precinct 1 consisting of the following census tracts and blocks:</section><section prefix="11.">That part of Prince George's County election district 21, precinct 10 consisting of the following census tracts and blocks:</section></section><section prefix="(iii)">The 23rd alcoholic beverages district at all times shall be coterminous with the 23rd legislative district in Prince George's County. As ordered by the Maryland Court of Appeals on June 21, 2002, the 23rd alcoholic beverages district consists of:<section prefix="1.">Delegate district 23A (two member delegate district):</section><section prefix="2.">Delegate district 23B (single member delegate district):</section></section><section prefix="(iv)">The 24th alcoholic beverages district at all times shall be coterminous with the 24th legislative district in Prince George's County. As ordered by the Maryland Court of Appeals on June 21, 2002, the 24th alcoholic beverages district consists of:<section prefix="1.">Prince George's County election district 6, precincts 3, 6, 9, 12, 15, and 19;</section><section prefix="2.">Prince George's County election district 13, precincts 1, 3, 5, 7, 8, 10, and 14 through 17;</section><section prefix="3.">Prince George's County election district 18, precincts 1 through 4 and 7 through 11;</section><section prefix="4.">Prince George's County election district 20, precincts 4 and 8;</section><section prefix="5.">That part of Prince George's County election district 18, precinct 5 consisting of the following census tracts and blocks:</section><section prefix="6.">That part of Prince George's County election district 18, precinct 6 consisting of census tract 8028.04, blocks 4005 and 4006;</section></section><section prefix="(v)">The 25th alcoholic beverages district at all times shall be coterminous with the 25th legislative district in Prince George's County. As ordered by the Maryland Court of Appeals on June 21, 2002, the 25th alcoholic beverages district consists of:<section prefix="1.">Prince George's County election district 3, precinct 4;</section><section prefix="2.">Prince George's County election district 6, precincts 1, 4, 5, 7, 10, 11, 14, 16, 18, and 20 through 23;</section><section prefix="3.">Prince George's County election district 7, precinct 12;</section><section prefix="4.">Prince George's County election district 9, precincts 1, 3, 10, and 11;</section><section prefix="5.">Prince George's County election district 13, precincts 4, 6, 9, and 11 through 13;</section><section prefix="6.">Prince George's County election district 15, precinct 2; and</section><section prefix="7.">That part of Prince George's County election district 18, precinct 6 consisting of census tract 8028.04, blocks 1006 through 1009, 2000 through 2003, 3000 through 3021, 4000, and 4002 through 4004;</section></section><section prefix="(vi)">The 26th alcoholic beverages district at all times shall be coterminous with the 26th legislative district in Prince George's County. As ordered by the Maryland Court of Appeals on June 21, 2002, the 26th alcoholic beverages district consists of:<section prefix="1.">Prince George's County election district 12;</section><section prefix="2.">Prince George's County election district 5, precincts 2, 3, and 5 through 7;</section><section prefix="3.">Prince George's County election district 6, precincts 2, 8, 13, and 17; and</section><section prefix="4.">Prince George's County election district 9, precincts 2 and 5;</section></section><section prefix="(vii)">The 27th alcoholic beverages district at all times shall be coterminous with the Prince George's County part of the 27th legislative district. As ordered by the Maryland Court of Appeals on June 21, 2002, the Prince George's County part of the 21st alcoholic beverages district was in delegate district 27A (two member delegate district) and consists of:<section prefix="1.">Prince George's County election districts 4, 8, and 11;</section><section prefix="2.">Prince George's County election district 3, precinct 1;</section><section prefix="3.">Prince George's County election district 5, precincts 1, 4, and 8;</section><section prefix="4.">Prince George's County election district 9, precincts 4 and 6 through 9; and</section><section prefix="5.">Prince George's County election district 15, precincts 1, 3, and 4; and</section></section><section prefix="(viii)">The 47th alcoholic beverages district at all times shall be coterminous with the 47th legislative district in Prince George's County. As ordered by the Maryland Court of Appeals on June 21, 2002, the 47th alcoholic beverages district consists of:<section prefix="1.">Prince George's County election district 2, precincts 1 through 4, 7, and 9;</section><section prefix="2.">Prince George's County election district 13, precinct 2;</section><section prefix="3.">Prince George's County election district 17, precincts 1 through 8, 10, 11, 13, and 14;</section><section prefix="4.">Prince George's County election district 20, precinct 3;</section><section prefix="5.">That part of Prince George's County election district 2, precinct 5 consisting of the following census tracts and blocks:</section><section prefix="6.">That part of Prince George's County election district 2, precinct 8 consisting of the following census tracts and blocks:</section></section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Prince George's County Board of License Commissioners may approve the issuance or transfer of a license into the boundaries of the 21st (that part located within the county), 22nd, 23rd, 24th, 25th, 26th, 27th (that part located within the county), or 47th alcoholic beverages district provided any off-sale privileges of the license are permanently waived as long as the license remains within the boundaries of the district.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(m)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">In this subsection the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">"Board" means the Board of License Commissioners.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">"Food stores" includes supermarkets.</section>
        <section prefix="(iv)">"Off-sale" means the sale of alcoholic beverages that are to be consumed off the licensed premises.</section>
        <section prefix="(v)">"On-sale" means the sale of alcoholic beverages that are to be consumed only on the licensed premises.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Without regard to its class of license, a licensee may not devote more than 10,000 square feet of floor space to off-sale use.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Except as to food stores that had an alcoholic beverages license on or before January 1, 1995, floor space shall be considered the space devoted to the retail sale of alcoholic beverages for off-sale consumption which, in the case of all licenses without on-premises consumption privileges, is located within the four walls of the building from which the licensed business operates or, in the case of licenses with on-sale and off-sale privileges, is actually used for the sale, display or storage of those beverages. In all cases, floor space includes:<section prefix="(i)">Basements on licensed premises; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Whatever other area off the licensed premises upon which the beverages are at any time lawfully stored.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">
        <section prefix="(i)">This subsection does not prohibit the renewal or transfer of ownership or location of a license issued in conjunction with any business that on or before January 1, 1995, has in excess of 10,000 square feet devoted to off-sale use.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The square footage of floor space used for the sale, display, or storage of the beverages may not be expanded beyond 10,000 square feet.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">Food stores having an alcoholic beverages license on or before January 1, 1995, may not expand the actual square footage of their alcoholic beverages departments, including sales, display, and storage areas, beyond a total of 10,000 square feet. This size shall be determined without regard to the total area available within the four walls of the business premises.</section>
        <section prefix="(iv)">There is no presumption in favor of or which otherwise requires the Board to approve requests by licensees to expand the amount of space devoted to the retail sale of beverages for off-sale consumption up to 10,000 square feet unless the Board finds, based upon the evidence presented to them, that:<section prefix="1.">The expansion is necessary to accommodate the public; and</section><section prefix="2.">The licensee otherwise continues to meet the criteria for issuance or transfer of a license and whatever other conditions are imposed by the Board.</section></section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(n)">A holder of a license issued by the Board may not impose a cover charge, offer facilities for patron dancing, or provide entertainment unless the holder is specifically authorized under this article and meets all requirements under County law.</section>
  </text>
</law>
