<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="g2b" order_by="" level="1">Alcoholic Beverages</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>g2b-12-222</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>222</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">This section applies only in Washington County.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A holder of any license authorizing the sale of alcoholic beverages at retail shall sell any alcoholic beverages except for cash unless such alcoholic beverages are delivered to the purchaser at a place designated by the purchaser other than the premises of the licensee.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Cash deposits for returnable containers shall be required at the time of delivery or sale.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">For the purposes of this section and of &#xA7; 12-112 of this article which relate to this county, in addition to currency, checks accepted for payment which are not postdated and are promptly deposited for collection by the licensee shall also be deemed to be cash. Any check given in payment for alcoholic beverages to any licensee, which is returned uncollected, is prima facie evidence in any civil case of a violation of this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">A suit or action ex contractu to enforce or collect any claim for credit extended, or to enforce payment of any check given for payment for alcoholic beverages in violation of this section, may not be maintained in this State.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">This section and &#xA7; 12-112 of this article which relate to this county do not apply to any:<section prefix="(1)">"Hotel", as defined by &#xA7; 1-102(a)(10) of this article, which is the holder of a Class B beer, wine and liquor license; and</section><section prefix="(2)">"Club", as defined by &#xA7; 1-102(a)(4) of this article which is the holder of a Class C beer, wine and liquor license.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(g)">A holder of any license authorizing the sale of alcoholic beverages at retail may not pledge any business or business property, real or personal, which pertains to or is related to the business so licensed as collateral for any loan or loans exceeding $1,000 in the aggregate, to which any person or persons, business or corporation dealing in, manufacturing or distributing vending machines, vending devices, pinball machines or music boxes is a party.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">Any person violating the provisions of this section is guilty of a misdemeanor and upon conviction shall be subject to a fine of not more than $500 or to imprisonment for not more than six months, or both fined and imprisoned.</section>
  </text>
</law>
