<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="g2b" order_by="2" level="1">Alcoholic Beverages</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>g2b-16-407</section_number>
  <catch_line>There is a Field Enforcement Bureau under the Comptroller, with such officers and employees as may b...</catch_line>
  <order_by>407</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">There is a Field Enforcement Bureau under the Comptroller, with such officers and employees as may be provided for in the budget from time to time.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The officers and employees of the Field Enforcement Bureau shall be sworn police officers and shall have all the powers, duties and responsibilities of peace officers for the enforcement of the provisions of this article having to do generally with (1) the illegal importation of alcoholic beverages into this State; (2) the illegal manufacture of alcoholic beverages in this State; (3) the transportation and/or distribution throughout this State of alcoholic beverages which were manufactured illegally and/or on which any alcoholic beverages taxes imposed by this State are due and illegally unpaid; and (4) the manufacture, sale, barter, transportation, distribution or other form of owning, handling or dispersing alcoholic beverages by any person, persons, associations or corporation not licensed or authorized therefor under the provisions of this article. They are authorized and empowered, from time to time to make cooperative arrangements for and to work and cooperate with the various State's Attorneys, sheriffs, constables, bailiffs, police and other prosecuting and peace officers of every sort, in order to enforce the provisions of this article and as provided in this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Field Enforcement Bureau shall consult and advise with the several State's Attorneys and other law enforcement officials and police officers as to enforcement problems in their respective jurisdictions, and may make suggestions and recommendations for changes to improve the execution and administration of the provisions of this article.</section>
  </text>
</law>
