<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="g2b" order_by="" level="1">Alcoholic Beverages</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>g2b-2-203</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>203</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">A Class 2 manufacturer's license:<section prefix="(1)">Is a rectifying license;</section><section prefix="(2)">Authorizes the holder to:<section prefix="(i)">Establish and operate in this State a plant for rectifying, blending and bottling alcoholic beverages; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Sell and deliver alcoholic beverages to a holder of a distillery, rectifying, or wholesaler's license, or to permit holders authorized to acquire those alcoholic beverages and to persons outside this State;</section></section><section prefix="(3)">Authorizes the holder to acquire alcoholic beverages from the holder of a:<section prefix="(i)">Distillery, rectifying, winery, or wholesaler's license in this State; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">Nonresident dealer's permit;</section></section><section prefix="(4)">Authorizes the holder to rectify, blend, bottle and store alcoholic beverages for another person or under another trade name if a rectifying license has been issued in the name of that person or under that trade name, as the case may be; and</section><section prefix="(5)">Authorizes the holder to:<section prefix="(i)">Conduct guided tours of the licensed premises; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Serve not more than three samples of products manufactured at the licensed premises, with each sample consisting of not more than one-half ounce from a single product, to persons who have attained the legal drinking age and participated in a guided tour of the licensed premises.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A holder of a Class 2 manufacturer's (rectifying) license or entity in which a holder has a pecuniary interest may not act as a caterer of food.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Subject to subsection (d) of this section, a license holder may conduct the activities specified in subsection (a)(5) of this section:<section prefix="(1)">For consumption off the licensed premises of products manufactured at the licensed premises and for sampling, each day from 10 a.m. to 10 p.m.; and</section><section prefix="(2)">For consumption on the licensed premises of products manufactured at the licensed premises:<section prefix="(i)">From 10 a.m. to 6 p.m. each day; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">If guests are attending a planned promotional event or other organized activity on the licensed premises, from 10 a.m. to 10 p.m. each day.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, a Class 2 manufacturer's (rectifying) license allows the holder to operate 7 days a week.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">In Garrett County, a license holder may open on Sundays to engage in the activities listed in subsection (a)(5) of this section only in an election district where the voters, in a referendum authorized by law, have approved Sunday sales at a rectifying facility.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">At least 14 days before holding a planned promotional event after 6 p.m., a license holder shall file a notice of the promotional event with the Comptroller on the form that the Comptroller provides.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, a license holder may not sell or allow to be consumed at the licensed premises any product other than products produced by the license holder under the authority of this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A holder of a caterer's license or privilege under Title 6, Subtitle 7 of this article may exercise the privileges of the license or privilege on the licensed premises of the license holder.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">Nothing in this section limits the application of relevant provisions of Title 21 of the Health - General Article, and regulations adopted under that title, to a license holder.</section>
  </text>
</law>
