<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="g2b" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="6-706.1" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>g2b-6-706.1</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">This section applies only in Montgomery County.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">There is a caterer's (CAT) license.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The annual license fee is $1,250.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The hours and days during which the holder of a CAT license may exercise the privileges of the license are the same as for the holder of a Class B beer, wine and liquor license.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The holder of a CAT license shall meet all the requirements of this article.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The holder of a CAT license shall have the facilities to prepare food and deliver food to the site of the catered affair. The county health department shall approve those facilities before the license may be issued, reissued, or renewed.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">The holder of a CAT license shall contract for and provide food as well as alcoholic beverages for consumption at catered events. The holder may not provide only alcoholic beverages at a catered event. The holder shall meet the same ratio of gross receipts between food sales and alcoholic beverage sales as a holder of a Class B beer, wine and liquor license.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">An applicant for a CAT license need not have a banquet hall. Persons holding existing licenses are not eligible for a CAT license. A CAT license is a separate alcoholic beverages license.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">The holder of a CAT license may not hold any self-sponsored events and may only hold off-sale events.</section>
    <section prefix="(j)">The holder of a CAT license shall purchase all alcoholic beverages from the Department of Liquor Control.</section>
    <section prefix="(k)">The holder of a CAT license who violates the requirements of this section is subject to the provisions of Title 16, Subtitle 5 (Penalties) of this article.</section>
  </text>
</law>
