<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="g2b" order_by="2" level="1">Alcoholic Beverages</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>g2b-15-208</section_number>
  <catch_line>No member or employee of a liquor control board shall have any financial interest, directly or indir...</catch_line>
  <order_by>208</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">No member or employee of a liquor control board shall have any financial interest, directly or indirectly, in the manufacture of any alcoholic beverage, or in any alcoholic beverage purchased or sold under the provisions of this article or derive any profit or remuneration from the purchase or sale of any such beverage other than the salary or wages payable for the discharge of the duties of the office or position, as herein prescribed or authorized.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Any member of the board, or any employee of said board, violating the provisions of this subsection shall, upon conviction, be subject to a fine not exceeding two thousand dollars ($2,000.00) or to imprisonment, not exceeding three years, or both fine and imprisonment, in the discretion of the court.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In Montgomery County, an employee of the Department of Liquor Control for Montgomery County, a member of the Montgomery County Council, or the Montgomery County Executive may not have any financial interest, directly or indirectly, in the sale, manufacture, blending, brewing, distilling, rectifying or wholesaling of any alcoholic beverage purchased or sold under the provisions of this article. An employee of the Department of Liquor Control may not have any interest in any license issued under the provisions of this article. An employee of the Department of Liquor Control may not solicit or receive directly or indirectly, any fee, commission, gratuity, emolument, remuneration, reward, present or sample of any alcoholic beverage, from any person, partnership, firm or corporation, agents, servants or employees, engaged in the sale, manufacture, blending, brewing, distilling, rectifying, wholesaling or distribution of alcoholic beverages, or any licensee licensed under the provisions of this article, or to derive any profit or remuneration from the purchase or sale of any such beverage other than the salary or wages payable by the county for the discharge of the duties as herein prescribed or authorized.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">In Montgomery County, a person, firm, association or corporation, engaged in the manufacture, sale, blending, brewing, distilling, rectifying, wholesaling or distribution of alcoholic beverages (or any agent, servant, or employee thereof), and a licensee (or employee thereof) licensed under the provisions of this article, may not directly or indirectly offer, pay or give any fee, emolument, remuneration, reward, present, commission, gratuity, or sample of any alcoholic beverages or make any gift of any value whatever to any employee of the Department of Liquor Control for Montgomery County, or any member of the Montgomery County Council, or the Montgomery County Executive.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">This subsection does not prevent any manufacturer, brewer, wholesaler or dealer in alcoholic beverages now selling or in the future attempting to sell or selling alcoholic beverages to the Department of Liquor Control from giving and delivering samples of alcoholic beverages to the Department. Any person, firm or corporation delivering samples of alcoholic beverages to the Department shall obtain an official receipt, signed by the director of the Department of Liquor Control, stating in detail the amount and description of the sample, which samples, when so received, shall be inventoried and sold as are other beverages purchased by the Department.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">Subject to the provisions of the Montgomery County Public Ethics Law, the Department of Liquor Control may grant exceptions to the restrictions of this subsection relating to dual employment by employees of the Department of Liquor Control whose employment by an alcoholic beverages licensee directly relates to the performing arts.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">Any person, firm, association, corporation or licensee violating the provisions of this subsection shall be fined not more than $5,000 or imprisoned not more than 12 years, or both.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
