<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="g2b" order_by="2" level="1">Alcoholic Beverages</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>g2b-15-107.1</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this section the following words have the meanings indicated....</catch_line>
  <order_by>107.1</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"County" means Howard County.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"County Council" means the County Council for Howard County.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">"Hearing Board" means the Appointed Alcoholic Beverage Hearing Board in Howard County.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">"Hearing Board member" means a member of the Appointed Alcoholic Beverage Hearing Board in Howard County.</section>
      <section prefix="(6)">"Liquor Board" means the Board of License Commissioners for Howard County.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The County Council for Howard County shall ex officio constitute on a permanent basis the Board of License Commissioners for Howard County.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">There is an Appointed Alcoholic Beverage Hearing Board in Howard County.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Except as otherwise provided in this section, the Liquor Board shall delegate to the Hearing Board its authority to conduct hearings and render decisions on cases involving alcoholic beverage licensees in the county.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Hearing Board consists of five members, one from each councilmanic district.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Not more than three members shall be registered with the same political party.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">Each political party that polled at least 25% of the total vote cast for all candidates for the office of County Executive in the most recent general election shall have at least one representative on the Hearing Board.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">If a political party that polled at least 25% of the total vote cast for all candidates for the office of County Executive in the most recent general election does not have at least one representative on the Hearing Board, the next vacancy on the Hearing Board shall be filled with an individual registered with that party.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(5)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Each member of the County Council shall nominate to the County Executive three qualified individuals who live in the district of the member of the County Council.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The County Executive shall appoint to the Hearing Board one individual from the list of nominees that each member of the County Council submits.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">The County Council by resolution shall confirm the appointment of Hearing Board members.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(6)">To qualify for appointment as a Hearing Board member, an individual shall be:<section prefix="(i)">Of good moral character and integrity;</section><section prefix="(ii)">A registered voter of the county immediately prior to the appointment; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">At least 21 years of age.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A Hearing Board member may not hold another public office or be employed by the Howard County government.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Except as provided in subparagraph (ii) of this paragraph, a Hearing Board member may not have a direct or indirect interest in any premises where alcoholic beverages are manufactured or sold, or in any business wholly or partially devoted to the manufacture or sale of alcoholic beverages.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">A Hearing Board member may be a holder of a 1-day or 2-day alcoholic beverage license.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A Hearing Board member is required to be a registered voter of the county during the Hearing Board member's term of office.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Except for the terms of some of the initial Hearing Board members, the term of a Hearing Board member is 5 years.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The terms of Hearing Board members are staggered as required by the terms provided for Hearing Board members on October 1, 1998.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(5)">A Hearing Board member who is appointed to fill a vacancy shall serve the remainder of the unexpired term.</section>
      <section prefix="(6)">A Hearing Board member whose term has expired and who has served 8 or more consecutive years on the Hearing Board is not eligible for immediate reappointment to the Hearing Board.</section>
      <section prefix="(7)">The County Council may remove a Hearing Board member for incompetence, misconduct, neglect of a duty required by law, unprofessional conduct, dishonorable conduct, a violation of any of the provisions of paragraph (2)(i) of this subsection or failure to meet the qualifications of subsection (c)(6)(i), (ii), or (iii) of this section.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">From among its members, the Hearing Board shall elect a chairperson.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">A majority of the members then serving on the Hearing Board is a quorum.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">A majority of the authorized membership of the Hearing Board is needed to take action.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Hearing Board shall meet at least once each month and may meet more often if needed.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The compensation of the Hearing Board members for the performance of their duties shall be:<section prefix="(i)">For the chairperson, $55 per meeting attended, not to exceed $1,300 in a fiscal year regardless of the number of meetings attended; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">For other Hearing Board members, $50 per meeting attended, not to exceed $1,200 in a fiscal year regardless of the number of meetings attended; and</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The compensation of the Liquor Board members for the performance of their duties shall be:<section prefix="(i)">For the chairperson, $55 per meeting attended, not to exceed $1,300 in a fiscal year regardless of the number of meetings attended; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">For other Liquor Board members, $50 per meeting attended, not to exceed $1,200 in a fiscal year regardless of the number of meetings attended.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Personnel needed to carry out the duties of the Hearing Board and the Liquor Board shall be:<section prefix="(i)">Included in the staff of the County Council; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Supervised by the County Council Administrator.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Chief of the County Police Department shall provide a sworn member of the County Police Department as an inspector to assist the Hearing Board and the Liquor Board in carrying out their responsibilities and in enforcing the law.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(h)">The Hearing Board shall propose reasonable regulations to enable it to discharge its duties, including the issuance of alcoholic beverage licenses, and shall submit proposed regulations to the Liquor Board for approval.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Hearing Board and the Liquor Board shall submit an annual budget request to the County Council not later than January 15 in each year for the ensuing fiscal year.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A budget request shall include:<section prefix="(i)">Salaries of the chairperson and Hearing Board members;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Compensation of personnel assigned to the Hearing Board; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Expenses for office supplies, equipment, and services necessary for carrying out the responsibilities of the Hearing Board.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The County Council shall review the budget requests and shall submit budgets for the Hearing Board and the Liquor Board to the County Executive in the amounts that the County Council determines are adequate to support the duties and responsibilities of the Hearing Board and the Liquor Board.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The County Executive shall include the budget for the Hearing Board and the Liquor Board as submitted by the County Council in the county budget that is prepared in accordance with Article VI of the Howard County Charter.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(j)">A member or employee of the Hearing Board and the Liquor Board is subject to the public ethics laws of the county.</section>
    <section prefix="(k)">
      <section prefix="(1)">After the Hearing Board proposes a decision regarding any case before it, a party or other participant in the case or other person who would be aggrieved by the decision may request the Liquor Board to conduct a hearing and make a final decision on the case.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A person that makes a request to the Liquor Board must:<section prefix="(i)">Make the request in writing;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Include a copy of the proposed decision and order;</section><section prefix="(iii)">State the reasons why the person believes that the proposed decision is wrong; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">Send a copy of the request and accompanying materials to all other parties in the case.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">If a request is submitted to the Liquor Board, the proposed decision of the Hearing Board is stayed.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">After a request for a hearing is submitted to the Liquor Board, any other party to the proceeding may submit to the Liquor Board a response stating why the proposed decision by the Hearing Board should be upheld.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(l)">After the period to file a response ends, the Liquor Board shall:<section prefix="(1)">Schedule a public meeting to decide whether to hear the case; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Notify the parties of the meeting date.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(m)">The proposed decision of the Hearing Board becomes final if:<section prefix="(1)">No request for a hearing is submitted to the Liquor Board within the time allotted for a request; or</section><section prefix="(2)">The Liquor Board decides not to hear the case.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(n)">
      <section prefix="(1)">After deciding to hear a case, the Liquor Board shall:<section prefix="(i)">Schedule a hearing de novo at which the Liquor Board may hear witnesses; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Notify the parties of the hearing date.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">After the close of the hearing record, the Liquor Board shall issue to the parties a final decision.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(o)">The Hearing Board shall give the Liquor Board regular and prompt notice of the filing of:<section prefix="(1)">Each application for an alcoholic beverage license or change in license; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Each petition alleging that a violation of an alcoholic beverage law or regulation has occurred.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(p)">By giving notice to the Hearing Board and the applicant or the affected licensee, the Liquor Board may:<section prefix="(1)">Assume initial jurisdiction of any matter before the Hearing Board; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Hear the case in the first instance when the Liquor Board determines that exercising initial jurisdiction is desirable and in the public interest.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(q)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A holder of a license, a person applying for an alcoholic beverage license, or a person engaged in the manufacture or sale of alcoholic beverages may not directly or indirectly offer to pay a commission, profit, or remuneration or make a gift of more than nominal value to:<section prefix="(i)">A member of the Hearing Board or of the Liquor Board;</section><section prefix="(ii)">An employee of the member of the Hearing Board or of the Liquor Board; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">An agent acting on behalf of a member of the Hearing Board or of the Liquor Board or employee assigned to the Hearing Board or the Liquor Board.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A person who violates this subsection is guilty of a misdemeanor and subject to a fine of not more than $1,000.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
