<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="g2b" order_by="2" level="1">Alcoholic Beverages</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>g2b-9-207</section_number>
  <catch_line>This section applies only in Carroll County....</catch_line>
  <order_by>207</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">This section applies only in Carroll County.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The restrictions imposed by subsections (c) through (g) of this section apply only to micro-brewery licenses, as set forth in &#xA7; 2-208 of this article.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">In this section, "protected building" means any elementary or secondary school and church or other place of worship.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The distance restriction requirement between a licensed premises and a protected building is 300 feet.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">This distance shall be measured from the nearest point of the building in which the licensed premises is located to the nearest point of the property line on which the protected building is located.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">If a licensed premises preceded the location of the protected building but the protected building is located within 300 feet of a licensed premises, the Office of the Comptroller may renew the license.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">Distance restriction requirements do not apply to any licensed premises in existence on July 1, 1997.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The aggregate number of all Class A beer, beer and light wine, and beer, wine and liquor licenses in each election district may not total more than one for every 5,000 individuals.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Board of License Commissioners shall determine the population of each election district by using the most recently published population report of the Carroll County Planning Commission.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Except as provided in paragraph (5) of this subsection, a new Class A license, regardless of kind, may not be issued if in the election district in which the license would be located:<section prefix="(i)">The ratio already exceeds one Class A license for every 5,000 individuals; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">The issuance of the license would cause the ratio to exceed one Class A license for every 5,000 individuals.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">For the purposes of this section, the renewal or transfer of a license issued by the Board of License Commissioners is not a new license.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">A winery that applies for a Class A light wine license under &#xA7; 4-201 of this article is exempt from the quota limitations established under paragraph (3) of this subsection.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
