<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="g2b" order_by="2" level="1">Alcoholic Beverages</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>g2b-8-216.3</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this section, "Board" means the Montgomery County Board of License Commissioners....</catch_line>
  <order_by>216.3</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, "Board" means the Montgomery County Board of License Commissioners.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">This section applies only in Montgomery County.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">There is a special culinary school license.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Board, by unanimous vote, may issue the license for use on the premises of a private culinary educational institution that:<section prefix="(1)">Is accredited by a nationally recognized accrediting association;</section><section prefix="(2)">Is approved by the Maryland Higher Education Commission; and</section><section prefix="(3)">Holds a private educational institution license issued by Montgomery County.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The annual license fee is $400.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The license authorizes the holder to:<section prefix="(i)">In connection with a wine tasting course offered by the license holder, allow the consumption of wine by individuals who are at least 21 years old and registered in the wine tasting course; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">In connection with a culinary or confectionary course offered by the license holder, allow the consumption of beer and wine by individuals who are at least 21 years old and registered in the culinary or confectionary course.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">An individual may consume beer or wine covered by a special culinary school license only on the licensed premises.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A license holder may conduct the activities specified in paragraph (1) of this subsection during the following hours:<section prefix="(i)">On Monday through Thursday, from 9 a.m. to 1 a.m. the following day;</section><section prefix="(ii)">	On Friday and Saturday, from 9 a.m. to 2 a.m. the following day; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">On Sunday, from 10 a.m. to 1 a.m. the following day.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">A license holder shall provide food during the hours alcoholic beverages are served.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">A license holder may not simultaneously hold any other license issued under this article.</section>
  </text>
</law>
