<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="g2b" order_by="" level="1">Alcoholic Beverages</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>g2b-11-302</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>302</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as otherwise provided in this subsection, the hours during which the privileges conferred by a Class A beer and light wine license may be exercised are from 6 a.m. to midnight on every day except Sunday.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">In the Park Heights Redevelopment Area that is specified in the Park Heights Master Plan adopted by Baltimore City in 2006, the hours of sale begin at 9 a.m. each day.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">In Caroline County, the hours of operation are from 6 a.m. to 2 a.m. the following day, on Monday through Sunday.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">In Frederick County, the hours of operation are:<section prefix="(i)">On Monday through Saturday, from 6 a.m. to 2 a.m. the following day; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">On Sunday, from 11 a.m. to 2 a.m. the following day.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(5)">In Montgomery County the hours are as provided in &#xA7; 11-516(d)(1) of this title.</section>
      <section prefix="(6)">In Prince George's County the hours are from 6 a.m. to 2 a.m. on the following day except on Sunday when sales are not permitted after 2 a.m.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The hours during which the privileges conferred by a Class B beer and light wine license may be exercised are from 6 a.m. to midnight.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Except as otherwise provided in subsections (h), (i), and (j) of this section, in Baltimore City the hours are from 6 a.m. to 2 a.m. on the following day.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">In Baltimore County the hours are from 6 a.m. to 2 a.m. on the following day.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">In Montgomery County, except as provided in &#xA7; 11-516 of this article, the hours for on-sale are from 9 a.m. on any day to 1 a.m. on the following day.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">In Prince George's County the hours are from 6 a.m. to 2 a.m. on the following day.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The hours during which the privileges conferred by a Class C beer and light wine license may be exercised are from 6 a.m. to midnight.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Except as otherwise provided in subsections (h) and (i) of this section, in Baltimore City the hours are from 6 a.m. to 2 a.m. on the following day.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">In Baltimore County the hours are from 6 a.m. to 2 a.m. on the following day.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">In Caroline County, the hours of operation are from 6 a.m. to 2 a.m. the following day, on Monday through Sunday.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">In Montgomery County, except as provided in &#xA7; 11-516 of this article, sales may not be made before 11 a.m.</section>
      <section prefix="(6)">In Prince George's County the hours are from 6 a.m. to 2 a.m. on the following day.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The hours during which the privileges conferred by a Class D beer and light wine license may be exercised are from 6 a.m. to midnight.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Except as otherwise provided in subsections (h), (i), and (j) of this section, in Baltimore City the hours are from 6 a.m. to 1 a.m. on the following day.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">In Baltimore County the hours are from 6 a.m. to 2 a.m. Monday through Sunday.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">In Caroline County, the hours of operation are from 6 a.m. to 2 a.m. the following day, on Monday through Sunday.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">In Montgomery County, except as provided in &#xA7; 11-516 of this article, the hours for on-sale are from 9 a.m. on any day to 1 a.m. on the following day.</section>
      <section prefix="(6)">In Prince George's County the hours are from 6 a.m. to 2 a.m. on the following day.</section>
      <section prefix="(7)">In Wicomico County, notwithstanding the provisions of paragraph (1) of this subsection, the hours on Sunday are from noon to midnight only by bowling alleys as defined in &#xA7; 1-102(b)(4) of this article.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The hours during which the privileges conferred by a Class H beer and light wine license may be exercised are from 9 a.m. to midnight.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">In Caroline County the hours are from 6 a.m. to 2 a.m. on the following day.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">In Montgomery County the hours are from 9 a.m. on any day to 1 a.m. on the following day.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">In Wicomico County, the hours for exercising on a Sunday the privileges conferred by a seven day, Class A (off-sale) beer and light wine license shall be the same as for the other days of the week.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">In Kent County, the hours for exercising the privileges conferred by a seven day, Class A (off-sale) beer and light wine license are as provided under &#xA7; 11-515 of this article.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This subsection applies only in Baltimore City on the inner perimeter of a rectangle bounded by 31st Street on the south, Greenmount Avenue on the east, 32nd Street on the north, and Barclay Street on the west.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">By regulation, the Board of License Commissioners may restrict the hours and days for the sale and consumption of beer and light wine.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(i)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In Baltimore City, in response to a complaint, the Board of License Commissioners may petition the circuit court for an order that limits the hours and days for the sale and consumption of beer and light wine on a licensee's premises.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The circuit court may issue a temporary order that limits the hours and days for the sale and consumption of beer and light wine on the licensed premises if the court finds by clear and convincing evidence that:<section prefix="(i)">The activities arising from sale and consumption of beer and light wine on the licensed premises result in an extreme and continuing disturbance to a residential community;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The licensee has failed to exercise good faith in attempting to remedy the disturbance at the request or order of the Board of License Commissioners; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">The Board has been unable to provide relief to the residential community by exercising its authority to suspend the license or reprimand the licensee.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The duration of the order of the court may not exceed the duration of the license term.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">Pending an appeal from the order of the circuit court, the order shall be stayed.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">This section may not be construed to limit any other powers of the Board of License Commissioners.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(j)">In the Park Heights Redevelopment Area that is specified in the Park Heights Master Plan adopted by Baltimore City in 2006, the hours of sale begin at 9 a.m. each day.</section>
    <section prefix="(k)">In Carroll County, the privileges conferred by a Class A beer and light wine license may be exercised from 11 a.m. to 6 p.m. on Sundays.</section>
  </text>
</law>
