<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="g2b" order_by="2" level="1">Alcoholic Beverages</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>g2b-8-806</section_number>
  <catch_line>The Alcoholic Beverage Board of St. Mary's County may issue a special beer festival (BF) license....</catch_line>
  <order_by>806</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Alcoholic Beverage Board of St. Mary's County may issue a special beer festival (BF) license.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Notwithstanding any other law, an applicant for a special BF license shall be a holder of an existing retail alcoholic beverages license issued in the State authorizing the sale of beer, a State Class 5 brewery license, a State Class 6 pub-brewery license, or a State Class 7 micro-brewery license.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A holder of a special BF license shall display and sell only beer that is:<section prefix="(1)">Manufactured and processed in any state;</section><section prefix="(2)">Price filed in accordance with regulations adopted by the Comptroller;</section><section prefix="(3)">Distributed in the State at the time the application is filed; and</section><section prefix="(4)">Sold at retail on the days and for the hours designated for the festival for consumption on or off the licensed premises.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The license fee is $15.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">This section does not prohibit the holder of a special BF license from holding another alcoholic beverages license of a different class or nature.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The Alcoholic Beverage Board of St. Mary's County shall:<section prefix="(1)">Approve one weekend annually for the beer festival that does not fall on the dates chosen for the Sotterley Wine Festival;</section><section prefix="(2)">Approve a location in Historic St. Mary's City for this festival; and</section><section prefix="(3)">Ensure that the primary focuses of the festival are both the promotion of Maryland beer and tourism in Historic St. Mary's City.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(g)">The Alcoholic Beverage Board of St. Mary's County shall adopt regulations for carrying out this section.</section>
  </text>
</law>
