<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="g2b" order_by="2" level="1">Alcoholic Beverages</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>g2b-8-204.6</section_number>
  <catch_line>This section applies only in Baltimore County....</catch_line>
  <order_by>204.6</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">This section applies only in Baltimore County.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Board of License Commissioners may accept an application for an alcoholic beverages license from:<section prefix="(1)">A contract purchaser of a property that becomes the owner of record of the premises to be licensed before the license is issued;</section><section prefix="(2)">An owner of a premises that is proposed to be licensed; or</section><section prefix="(3)">A developer of a property with the consent and authority of the owner of the property.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">An application filed under this section need not contain a specific street address or description of the premises to be licensed other than a general description of the site on which the premises will be built, including a property map number, parcel number, property tax identification number, or plat number.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">If the Board of License Commissioners approves the application, the applicant may apply to transfer the license to an operator of the type of business for which the license was approved if:<section prefix="(1)">The license is for a location in the site for which the license was approved; and</section><section prefix="(2)">The application for transfer occurs within 3 years after the original application for the site is approved or construction at the location is completed, whichever is later.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">Unless otherwise prohibited by law, the Board of License Commissioners may approve a change of location of a license issued under this section if the licensee has engaged in an active alcoholic beverages business under the license for at least 1 year before applying for the change.</section>
  </text>
</law>
