<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="g2b" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="8-312.1" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>g2b-8-312.1</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Alcoholic Beverages Board of St. Mary's County may issue a special wine festival (WF) license.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Notwithstanding any other provision to the contrary, an applicant for a special WF license shall be a holder of an existing retail alcoholic beverages license issued in the State authorizing the sale of wine, a State Class 3 winery license, or a State Class 4 winery license issued under this article.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A holder of a special WF license shall only display and sell wine:<section prefix="(1)">That is:<section prefix="(i)">Manufactured and processed in any state;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Price filed in accordance with regulations adopted by the Comptroller; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Distributed in the State at the time the application is filed;</section></section><section prefix="(2)">At retail for consumption on or off the licensed premises on the days and for the hours designated for the festival; and</section><section prefix="(3)">That is manufactured and processed in any state at retail for consumption off the licensed premises on the days and hours designated for the festival.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The license fee is $15.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">This section does not prohibit the holder of a special WF license from holding another alcoholic beverages license of a different class or nature.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The Alcoholic Beverages Board of St. Mary's County:<section prefix="(1)">Shall approve one weekend annually for the wine festival;</section><section prefix="(2)">Shall approve a location in St. Mary's County for this festival that is not licensed under this article; and</section><section prefix="(3)">Shall ensure that the primary focus of the festival is the promotion of Maryland wine.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(g)">The Alcoholic Beverages Board of St. Mary's County shall adopt regulations for carrying out this section.</section>
  </text>
</law>
