<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="g2b" order_by="2" level="1">Alcoholic Beverages</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>g2b-8-505</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this section the following words have the meanings indicated....</catch_line>
  <order_by>505</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Board" means the Prince George's County Board of License Commissioners.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Commission" means the Maryland-National Capital Park and Planning Commission.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Board may issue special 7-day Class B-GC (golf course) on-sale beer and wine licenses for the exclusive use on the premises of the Commission's golf courses located within Prince George's County.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The special 7-day Class B-GC on-sale beer and wine license authorizes the holder to sell beer and wine from 1 or more outlets for consumption on the premises of the golf course.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">A separate license is required for each applicable golf course.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">A special 7-day Class B-GC on-sale beer and wine license shall be issued to each of the managers of the Commission's golf courses upon making application and qualifying as a license holder under this article.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(4)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Except as provided in this subsection, the hours of sale for beer and wine under this license are from 11 a.m. to 10 p.m. daily, Monday through Sunday.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The Commission may:<section prefix="1.">Reduce the hours of sale of beer and wine under this license; and</section><section prefix="2.">Discontinue the sale of beer and wine under this license from Labor Day through Memorial Day.</section></section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(5)">The annual fee for a special 7-day Class B-GC on-sale beer and wine license is $365.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
