<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="g2b" order_by="" level="1">Alcoholic Beverages</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>g2b-9-102.2</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>102.2</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Director or Deputy Director of the Montgomery County Parks Department of the Maryland-National Capital Park and Planning Commission may hold more than one of the following alcoholic beverages licenses for the limited use of public golf courses that are under the Commission's jurisdiction in Montgomery County:<section prefix="(i)">A Class H beer (on-sale) license; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">A Class H beer and light wine (on-sale) license.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Executive Director of the Montgomery County Revenue Authority or the Executive Director's designee may hold more than one of the following alcoholic beverages licenses for the limited use of public golf courses that are under the jurisdiction of the Revenue Authority:<section prefix="(i)">A Class H beer (on-sale) license; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">A Class H beer and light wine (on-sale) license.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A license issued under paragraph (2) of this subsection shall be signed by the Revenue Authority's Executive Director or the Executive Director's designee.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">As a condition to holding any license under this section, the Director or Deputy Director of the Montgomery County Parks Department of the Maryland-National Capital Park and Planning Commission or the Executive Director of the Montgomery County Revenue Authority or the Executive Director's designee, respectively, shall designate an individual with respect to each golf course to complete training in an alcohol awareness program approved under &#xA7; 13-101 of this article.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The individual designated to complete training in an alcohol awareness program under paragraph (1) of this subsection shall:<section prefix="(i)">Represent the concessionaire; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Be involved with the management of the sale of beer or light wine by the concessionaire at the golf course.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
