<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="g2b" order_by="2" level="1">Alcoholic Beverages</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>g2b-8-802</section_number>
  <catch_line>The Baltimore County Board of License Commissioners may issue a special beer festival license....</catch_line>
  <order_by>802</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Baltimore County Board of License Commissioners may issue a special beer festival license.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Notwithstanding any other provision to the contrary, an applicant for a special beer festival license shall be a holder of an existing retail alcoholic beverages license issued in the State, Class 5 brewery license, or Class 7 micro-brewery license, issued in accordance with this article.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A special beer festival license entitles the holder to display and sell at retail beer for consumption on or off the licensed premises on the days and for the hours designated for the special beer festival in Baltimore County.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The license fee is $50.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The provisions of this section may not prohibit the licensee from holding another alcoholic beverages license of a different class or nature.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The Baltimore County Board of License Commissioners:<section prefix="(1)">Except for the dates chosen for the Cumberland and Shenandoah Valley Wine Festival in Washington County, the Maryland Wine Festival in Carroll County, and the Anne Arundel County Beer and Wine Festival, shall approve one weekend annually for the special beer festival;</section><section prefix="(2)">Shall approve a location in Baltimore County for the special beer festival which does not hold an alcoholic beverages license; and</section><section prefix="(3)">Shall ensure that the primary focus of the special beer festival is the promotion of Maryland beer.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(g)">The Baltimore County Board of License Commissioners shall adopt regulations for implementing this section.</section>
  </text>
</law>
