<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="g2b" order_by="2" level="1">Alcoholic Beverages</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>g2b-9-102.1</section_number>
  <catch_line>This section applies only in Montgomery County....</catch_line>
  <order_by>102.1</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">This section applies only in Montgomery County.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Board" means the Board of License Commissioners.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Enterprise zone" has the meaning stated in &#xA7; 5-701 of the Economic Development Article.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">"License" means a Class B beer, wine and liquor on-sale only license.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">"Original license" means a Class B license as set forth in &#xA7; 6-201(q) of this article.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">After making an application and paying the fees, the holder of an original license may obtain the additional license or licenses authorized by this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A licensee may obtain additional licenses for premises operated as a public hotel.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">An applicant for this additional license shall:<section prefix="(i)">Meet the minimum requirements set forth in &#xA7; 6-201(a)(3) of this article. If the capital investment in the hotel exceeds $3,000,000, the building height and elevator requirements required by that section do not apply; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Have a minimum restaurant seating capacity, as specified in &#xA7; 6-201(a)(3) of this article, of 100 persons.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A licensee may obtain one additional license for premises which meet the qualifications specified in this subsection. For identification purposes, the additional license may be referred to as a "1-year" license.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">An applicant for this additional license shall:<section prefix="(i)">Have the applicant's place of business located in this State;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Have been the holder of a license for at least 1 year; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Operate a restaurant, as defined by regulations of the Board.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">This is an on-sale license only.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A licensee may obtain not more than two additional licenses for premises which meet the qualifications specified in this subsection. For identification purposes, this additional license may be referred to as an enterprise zone license.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Each restaurant shall be located within one of two designated enterprise zones, with not more than one restaurant in each enterprise zone.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The requirement that the holder have been a licensee for 1 year does not apply to this subsection.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">A licensee may obtain an additional license for a premises in a designated enterprise zone, even after the incentives and initiatives for a business entity in the designated enterprise zone are eliminated or reduced.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A licensee may obtain one additional license for premises which meet the qualifications specified in this subsection. For identification purposes, this additional license may be referred to as a "Rockville" license.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The restaurant shall be located within the Rockville Town Center zoned property.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The requirement that the holder have been a licensee for 1 year does not apply to this subsection.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(h)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A licensee may obtain one additional license for premises that meet the qualifications specified in this subsection. For identification purposes, each additional license may be referred to as a "Germantown" license.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The restaurant shall be located within the Germantown Town Center district.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The requirement that the holder have been a licensee for 1 year does not apply to this subsection.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(i)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A licensee may obtain up to one additional license for premises that meet the qualifications specified in this subsection. For identification purposes, each additional license may be referred to as a "Gaithersburg" license.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The restaurant shall be located within the City of Gaithersburg.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The requirement that the holder have been a licensee for 1 year does not apply to this subsection.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(j)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A licensee may obtain up to one additional license for premises that meet the qualifications specified in this subsection. For identification purposes, each additional license may be referred to as a "Montgomery Village" license.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The restaurant shall be located within the town sector zoned area called Montgomery Village.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The requirement that the holder have been a licensee for 1 year does not apply to this subsection.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(k)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A licensee may obtain one additional license for premises that meet the qualifications specified in this subsection. For identification purposes, each additional license may be referred to as an "East County" license.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The restaurant shall be located in an area bounded by the Howard County-Montgomery County line on the north, the Prince George's County-Montgomery County line on the east, the Capital Beltway (I-495) on the south, and a line 3,000 feet west of the center of Columbia Pike on the west.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The requirement that the holder have been a licensee for 1 year does not apply to this subsection.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(l)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A licensee may obtain a maximum of two additional licenses for premises which meet the qualifications specified in this subsection. For identification purposes, each additional license may be referred to as an "incentive" license.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">An applicant for an additional license shall:<section prefix="(i)">Have the applicant's place of business located in this State;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Operate a restaurant, as defined by regulations of the Board; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Hold an enterprise zone license, a Rockville license, a Germantown license, a Gaithersburg license, a Montgomery Village license, or an East County license.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A maximum of one incentive license may be issued for each enterprise zone license, Rockville license, Germantown license, Gaithersburg license, Montgomery Village license, or East County license.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The requirement that the holder have been a licensee for 1 year does not apply to this subsection.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">This is an on-sale license only.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(m)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A licensee may obtain one additional license for premises which meet the qualifications specified in this subsection. For identification purposes, the additional license may be referred to as a "5-year" license.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">An applicant for an additional license shall:<section prefix="(i)">Have the applicant's place of business located in this State;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Have been for at least 5 years the holder of two licenses under this section that are not restricted by location; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Operate a restaurant, as defined by regulations of the Board.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">This is an on-sale license only.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(n)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Subsection (o) of this section excludes additional licenses issued pursuant to subsection (d) of this section, which relates to public hotels.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">This section does not permit the issuance to a person or for the use of any partnership, corporation, unincorporated association, or limited liability company of more than the number of licenses specified.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(o)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A licensee that holds an original license, may obtain a maximum of 9 additional licenses and may not hold more than 10 licenses altogether.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Subject to the requirements of subsections (e) through (m) of this section, a licensee may hold any combination of the following licenses:<section prefix="(i)">One 1-year license under subsection (e) of this section;</section><section prefix="(ii)">One 5-year license under subsection (m) of this section;</section><section prefix="(iii)">One enterprise zone license in each of two enterprise zones under subsection (f) of this section;</section><section prefix="(iv)">One Rockville license under subsection (g) of this section;</section><section prefix="(v)">One Germantown license under subsection (h) of this section;</section><section prefix="(vi)">One Gaithersburg license under subsection (i) of this section;</section><section prefix="(vii)">One Montgomery Village license under subsection (j) of this section;</section><section prefix="(viii)">One East County license under subsection (k) of this section; and</section><section prefix="(ix)">Two incentive licenses under subsection (l) of this section.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
