<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="g2b" order_by="2" level="1">Alcoholic Beverages</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>g2b-21-105</section_number>
  <catch_line>This section applies only in Baltimore City....</catch_line>
  <order_by>105</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">This section applies only in Baltimore City.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">In this section, "publicly visible locations" include outdoor billboards, sides of buildings, and freestanding signboards.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Mayor and City Council of Baltimore may adopt an ordinance restricting the placement of signs, posters, placards, devices, graphic displays, or any other forms of advertising or on the sides of the building of the licensed premises that advertise alcoholic beverages in publicly visible locations if:<section prefix="(i)">The ordinance is necessary for the promotion of the welfare and temperance of minors exposed to advertisements for alcoholic beverages placed in publicly visible locations; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">The restrictions do not unduly burden legitimate business activities of persons licensed under this article to sell alcoholic beverages on a retail basis.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The ordinance adopted by the Mayor and City Council of Baltimore City may not restrict:<section prefix="(i)">The placement of signs, including advertisements:<section prefix="1.">Inside licensed premises;</section><section prefix="2.">On commercial vehicles used for transporting alcoholic beverages; or</section><section prefix="3.">In conjunction with a 1-day alcoholic beverages license or a temporary license granted by the Board of License Commissioners;</section></section><section prefix="(ii)">Any sign that contains the name or slogan of the licensed premises that has been placed for the purpose of identifying the licensed premises;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Except for billboards and freestanding signboards, any sign for which zoning board approval or a minor privilege permit is required;</section><section prefix="(iv)">Any sign that contains a generic description of beer, wine, liquor, or spirits, or any other generic description of alcoholic beverages;</section><section prefix="(v)">Any neon or electrically charged sign on licensed premises that is provided as part of a promotion of a particular brand of alcoholic beverage;</section><section prefix="(vi)">Any sign on an MTA vehicle or a taxicab;</section><section prefix="(vii)">Any sign on property owned, leased, or operated by the Maryland Stadium Authority;</section><section prefix="(viii)">Any sign at Memorial Stadium;</section><section prefix="(ix)">Any sign at a facility that operates in accordance with a license issued under &#xA7; 11-304 of the Business Regulation Article; or</section><section prefix="(x)">Any sign on property adjacent to an interstate highway.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">In this subsection, "advertise falsely" means to use any advertisement that is untrue, deceptive, or misleading in a material respect.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">"Advertise falsely" includes the use and placement of an advertisement by a person on the Internet that contains an affirmative representation that an alcoholic beverages licensee may offer for sale a container of alcoholic beverages that the licensee is not authorized to sell.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">An alcoholic beverages licensee may not advertise falsely in the conduct of any business.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Board of License Commissioners shall enforce this subsection.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">A person who violates the provisions of this section is guilty of a misdemeanor and may be fined no more than $1,000.</section>
  </text>
</law>
