<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="g2b" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="11-515.1" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>g2b-11-515.1</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In Kent County, the Board of License Commissioners may grant a special Sunday (on-sale) beer, wine and liquor license privilege.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">This license privilege may be granted only to a holder of a Class B (on-sale) beer, wine and liquor license for use on the premises that qualify as a restaurant under &#xA7; 6-201(p) of this article.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">This license privilege authorizes the holder to serve beer, wine and liquor on the restaurant premises on Sundays from 12 noon to 12 midnight without being subject to the meal and seating restrictions provided under &#xA7; 6-201(p) of this article.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The annual fee for this license privilege is $100 in addition to the annual fee for the Class B (on-sale) beer, wine and liquor restaurant license.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">This license privilege is not considered a separate class of license, and if it is granted, the privilege will be incorporated in the existing Class B (on-sale) beer, wine and liquor restaurant license.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Kent County Board of License Commissioners may grant 5 special Sunday (on-sale) beer, wine and liquor licenses to each holder of a Class C beer, wine and liquor license who applies.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">No more than 5 special Sunday licenses shall be issued to a holder during the Class C license year.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">This license authorizes the holder to serve beer, wine and liquor on the Class C premises from 7 a.m. to 12 midnight for consumption on the premises.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The fee for each license is $15.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">The provisions of law under &#xA7; 9-102 of this article prohibiting the issuance of 2 licenses for the same premises do not apply to this license.</section>
      <section prefix="(6)">The Board of License Commissioners shall adopt regulations to implement this subsection.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
