<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="g2b" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="11-512" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>g2b-11-512</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">This section applies only in Garrett County.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Notwithstanding any other provisions of this subtitle and except on Sundays and New Year's Day, holders of any class of on- or off-sale licenses issued under this article may sell the alcoholic beverages authorized under their respective license from 6 a.m. to 2 a.m. the following day, but may not sell alcoholic beverages between the hours of 2 a.m. and 6 a.m. on any day of the week or, unless authorized under subsection (c) of this section, at any time on Sunday after 2 a.m.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The provisions of this subsection apply to a holder of a Class E steamboat license issued by the State Comptroller's Office for use on all State waters located within the county.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">However, this section is subject to the provisions of &#xA7; 11-402(m) of this title regarding sales on New Year's Eve or New Year's Day regardless of the day of the week on which December 31 and January 1 fall.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The provisions of this subsection apply in:<section prefix="(i)">Election districts 11 and 15, in which the voters approved Sunday sales in the referendum authorized by law in November 1996; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Any other election district in which the voters in a referendum authorized by law approve Sunday sales as specified in this subsection.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">This subsection only applies to on-premises sales by holders of Class C service club licenses and, subject to paragraph (4) of this subsection, holders of Class B licenses, special 2-day Class C licenses, special 6-day Class C licenses, and special 12-day Class C licenses.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Sunday sales may begin, where permitted, at 1 p.m. and continue until 10 p.m.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">
        <section prefix="(i)">This paragraph does not apply to a holder of a Class C service club license.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">Sunday sales may be made only when the consumer places an order for a meal simultaneously or prior to placing an order for an alcoholic beverage or the consumer is otherwise entitled to a meal on the premises as part of a prearranged event, such as a banquet, where the alcoholic beverage is served. Bar or counter sales may be made as long as the consumer complies with the requirement of this paragraph.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(5)">In addition to the usual license fee, the holder of a Class C service club license or Class B license who wants to provide Sunday sales and who is otherwise eligible to provide Sunday sales under this subsection shall pay an additional $250 for the privilege of Sunday sales.</section>
      <section prefix="(6)">At the time the Class C service club license or Class B license is issued, the Board shall charge a $250 issuing fee.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
