<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="g2b" order_by="2" level="1">Alcoholic Beverages</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>g2b-12-302</section_number>
  <catch_line>Unless provision is made elsewhere, the following provisions apply statewide to persons who are empl...</catch_line>
  <order_by>302</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Unless provision is made elsewhere, the following provisions apply statewide to persons who are employed in licensed establishments:<section prefix="(1)">A person under age 18 may not be engaged in the sale of alcoholic beverages.</section><section prefix="(2)">Except for Class D beer, wine and liquor licensees as provided in paragraph (3) of this subsection, a person between ages 18 and 21 may be employed in the sale of beer and light wine.</section><section prefix="(3)">A person under age 21 may not be employed by any holder of a Class D beer, wine and liquor license in the sale of alcoholic beverages.</section><section prefix="(4)">A person 18 years old and older may be employed by a Class A licensee to operate a lottery ticket terminal.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">In the following jurisdictions the specified exceptions to subsection (a) of this section apply:<section prefix="(1)">In Anne Arundel County a Class A (off-sale) licensee may employ a person age 16 years or older to stock alcoholic beverages.</section><section prefix="(2)">In Baltimore City a licensee:<section prefix="(i)">May employ a person 18 years of age or older to sell, serve, deliver, or otherwise deal with alcoholic beverages;</section><section prefix="(ii)">May not employ or allow a person under the age of 18 years to sell, serve, or deliver alcoholic beverages; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">May not employ or allow a person under the age of 18 years to provide entertainment on the licensed premises.</section></section><section prefix="(3)">In Baltimore County a member of an alcoholic beverages licensee's immediate family who is under 18 years old may not be employed to sell, deliver, or otherwise deal with alcoholic beverages by the holder of an alcoholic beverages license.</section><section prefix="(4)"><section prefix="(i)">The provisions of this paragraph apply only in Carroll County.</section><section prefix="(ii)">Class B licensees may employ a person 15 years or older to perform any task other than those involving selling, serving, or delivering alcoholic beverages.</section><section prefix="(iii)">A person 18 years old or older may serve, sell, or deliver alcoholic beverages in restaurants.</section><section prefix="(iv)">Class A licensees may employ a person 18 years old and older to stock alcoholic beverages and to operate a lottery ticket terminal.</section><section prefix="(v)">A person under 21 years of age may not act as a bartender or barmaid or in any solely bar-related capacity.</section></section><section prefix="(5)">In Cecil County a licensee may employ a person 18 years old or older to sell, serve, deliver, or otherwise deal with alcoholic beverages.</section><section prefix="(6)">In Dorchester County the holder of a Class A (off-sale) beer license may employ a person 16 years old or older to stock beer at the licensee's place of business.</section><section prefix="(7)">Notwithstanding the other provisions of this section, in Frederick County a licensee may employ a person 18 years of age or older to sell, serve, deliver, or otherwise deal with alcoholic beverages and may employ a person 14 years of age or older to perform any other task other than to sell, serve, or deliver alcoholic beverages.</section><section prefix="(8)"><section prefix="(i)">The provisions of this paragraph apply only in Garrett County.</section><section prefix="(ii)">Except as provided in subparagraph (iii) of this paragraph, a licensee may not employ a person under the age of 21 years to sell or deliver alcoholic beverages.</section><section prefix="(iii)">A licensee may employ a person at least 18 years old to:<section prefix="1.">Serve and sell alcoholic beverages in a restaurant in connection with the serving or selling of a meal;</section><section prefix="2.">Serve alcoholic beverages from a service bar to a seated customer; or</section><section prefix="3.">Operate a lottery ticket terminal in a Class A establishment.</section></section><section prefix="(iv)">A licensee may not employ a person under the age of 18 years to handle alcoholic beverages.</section></section><section prefix="(9)">In Kent County the provisions of subsection (c) of this section apply.</section><section prefix="(10)">In Prince George's County a person under age 18 years may not be employed to sell, deliver, or otherwise deal with alcoholic beverages.</section><section prefix="(11)">In Queen Anne's County the provisions of subsection (c) of this section apply.</section><section prefix="(12)">In Washington County a licensee may employ a person 18 years of age or older to sell, serve, deliver, or otherwise deal with alcoholic beverages and may employ a person 16 years of age or older to perform any other task other than to sell, serve, or deliver alcoholic beverages.</section><section prefix="(13)">In Wicomico County, an individual who is at least 16 years old and has a work permit may be employed at a licensed premises to stock alcoholic beverages or clear tables and bar areas.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, and except as provided by paragraph (2) of this subsection, a person under the age of 21 may not be employed to sell, deliver, or otherwise deal with alcoholic beverages by any of the holders of the licenses listed by county in paragraph (3) of this subsection.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A person at least 18 years of age may be employed:<section prefix="(i)">To stock alcoholic beverages in a Class A establishment;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Except for Class A licenses, to serve alcoholic beverages while acting in the capacity of a waiter or waitress on the licensed premises; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">To operate a lottery ticket terminal in a Class A establishment.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The provisions of this subsection apply within Kent and Queen Anne's counties to the holder of any:<section prefix="(i)">Class A (off-sale) license;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Class B (on-sale) license; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Class C (on-sale) beer, wine and liquor license.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
