<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="g2b" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="6-701.1" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>g2b-6-701.1</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">This section applies only in Baltimore City.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">In this section, "caterer" means any beer and wine or beer, wine and liquor licensee who contracts to provide food and alcoholic beverages to sponsors of public or private events held off the licensed premises.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Board of License Commissioners may add a special off-sale caterer privilege for the sole purpose of authorizing a licensee to be a caterer.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A licensee who holds the special off-sale caterer privilege may contract to provide food and alcoholic beverages for consumption at a catered event.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The licensee may exercise the special off-sale caterer privilege only during the hours and days that are permitted under this article for the existing beer and wine or beer, wine and liquor license.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A licensee who holds a special off-sale caterer privilege shall have the facilities to prepare and deliver food to the site of the catered event.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Baltimore City Health Department shall approve the food preparation facilities and issue a caterer's license before the Board adds or renews a special off-sale caterer privilege.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">A special off-sale caterer privilege is not a separate class of license and, if it is granted, the privilege is incorporated within the existing on-sale beer, wine and liquor license.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">The annual fee for the special off-sale caterer privilege is $500 in addition to the annual fee for the existing beer and wine or beer, wine and liquor license.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">A special off-sale caterer privilege may be renewed.</section>
  </text>
</law>
