<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="g2b" order_by="2" level="1">Alcoholic Beverages</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>g2b-11-401</section_number>
  <catch_line>It is unlawful for the keeper of any hotel, tavern, store, drinking establishment or any other place...</catch_line>
  <order_by>401</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">It is unlawful for the keeper of any hotel, tavern, store, drinking establishment or any other place where liquors are sold, or for any person or persons, directly or indirectly, to sell, barter, give or dispose of any spirituous or fermented liquors, ale or beer, or intoxicating drinks of any kind within any election district or precinct of this State on the day of any general, special or primary election to be held in any district or precinct during the hours when the polls are open. Any person violating the provisions of this section is liable for indictment, and upon conviction is fined not less than $50 nor more than $100 for each offense.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">On the day of any election any restaurant holding any license issued under the provisions of this article may dispense those alcoholic beverages that are in accordance with that license for consumption on the premises only.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">In the enumerated subdivisions below the holder of any license issued under the provisions of this article is permitted to exercise all of the privileges conferred by that license on the day of any election in that subdivision:<section prefix="(1)">Allegany County, but an alcoholic beverage licensee whose premises are also used as a polling place may not exercise any privilege conferred by that license on the day of any election during those hours the polls are open;</section><section prefix="(2)">Anne Arundel County;</section><section prefix="(3)">Baltimore City;</section><section prefix="(4)">Baltimore County;</section><section prefix="(5)">Calvert County;</section><section prefix="(6)">Caroline County;</section><section prefix="(7)">Carroll County;</section><section prefix="(8)">Cecil County;</section><section prefix="(9)">Charles County;</section><section prefix="(10)">Dorchester County;</section><section prefix="(11)">Frederick County;</section><section prefix="(12)">Garrett County;</section><section prefix="(13)">Harford County;</section><section prefix="(14)">Howard County;</section><section prefix="(15)">Kent County;</section><section prefix="(16)">Montgomery County;</section><section prefix="(17)">Prince George's County;</section><section prefix="(18)">Queen Anne's County;</section><section prefix="(19)">St. Mary's County;</section><section prefix="(20)">Somerset County;</section><section prefix="(21)">Washington County;</section><section prefix="(22)">Wicomico County; and</section><section prefix="(23)">Worcester County.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
