<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="g2b" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="12-112" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>g2b-12-112</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">This section applies only in the following jurisdictions:<section prefix="(1)">Baltimore City;</section><section prefix="(2)">Caroline;</section><section prefix="(3)">Cecil;</section><section prefix="(4)">Charles;</section><section prefix="(5)">Dorchester;</section><section prefix="(6)">Frederick;</section><section prefix="(7)">Garrett;</section><section prefix="(8)">Harford;</section><section prefix="(9)">Kent;</section><section prefix="(10)">Prince George's;</section><section prefix="(11)">Queen Anne's;</section><section prefix="(12)">St. Mary's;</section><section prefix="(13)">Somerset;</section><section prefix="(14)">Talbot;</section><section prefix="(15)">Washington;</section><section prefix="(16)">Wicomico; and</section><section prefix="(17)">Worcester.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Except as provided in subsection (c) of this section, a manufacturer or wholesaler may not sell any beer to any retail dealer except for cash on delivery.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This subsection applies only in Worcester County.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Subject to the conditions and restrictions provided under paragraphs (3), (4), and (5) of this subsection, a wholesaler may sell beer on credit to a retail dealer who has been doing business for at least 2 years.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A wholesaler who extends credit under this subsection may establish different prices for cash and credit transactions.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">A term of credit extended under this subsection may not exceed 10 days, with no grace period.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">
        <section prefix="(i)">A wholesaler may not intentionally deliver beer to a retail dealer to whom any wholesaler has extended credit under this subsection if the retail dealer:</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">A wholesaler who violates this paragraph is subject to a fine not exceeding $1,000 for each such delivery.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(6)">The Board of License Commissioners may not transfer or renew the alcoholic beverages license of a retail dealer who has been extended credit under this subsection and who owes a balance on the debt at the time of the transfer or renewal.</section>
      <section prefix="(7)">A retail dealer who fails to satisfy a debt on credit extended under this subsection on three separate occasions within a single calendar year may not obtain beer on credit for a period of 2 years from the time of the third occurrence.</section>
      <section prefix="(8)">
        <section prefix="(i)">A retail dealer may request a hearing with the State Comptroller within 10 days after being listed on the Worcester County beer credit control list for failure to comply with the provisions of this subsection.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The State Comptroller shall remove immediately from the Worcester County beer credit control list a retail dealer who requests a hearing, pending the disposition of the hearing.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(9)">The State Comptroller shall enforce the provisions of this subsection and shall adopt regulations to carry out this subsection.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A suit or action ex contractu to enforce or collect any claim for credit extended in violation of this section may not be maintained in this State.</section>
  </text>
</law>
