<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="g2b" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="15-204" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>g2b-15-204</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Subject to &#xA7; 16-407.1 of this article and except as otherwise provided in this section, the liquor control board in each county shall have an absolute monopoly of the sale and distribution of the particular alcoholic beverages which elsewhere in this subtitle it is empowered to sell.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Provided, that in Montgomery County no person, firm, or corporation shall keep for sale any alcoholic beverage not purchased from the Department of Liquor Control for Montgomery County, provided, however, that nothing in this subsection shall apply to a holder of a Class F license or a holder of a Class 1 beer, wine and liquor, Class 2 wine and liquor, Class 3 beer and wine, Class 4 beer, or Class 5 wine wholesaler's license, who may not sell or deliver any alcoholic beverage in Montgomery County for resale except to a county liquor dispensary.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Notwithstanding paragraph (1) of this subsection:<section prefix="(i)"/><section prefix="(ii)">A holder of a direct wine shipper's permit may ship wine directly to a consumer in Montgomery County.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">This section does not apply to the sale and distribution of light wine in Somerset County.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">In Wicomico County, the county dispensaries shall make wholesale sales of all liquors at a markup of not more than 15 percent above the operating cost to the dispensary to any licensee of a Class A, B, or C beer, wine and liquor license.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this subsection, "Department" means the Worcester County Department of Liquor Control.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">This subsection applies only in Worcester County.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Beginning on May 1, 2016, a licensee in the county may elect to purchase wine or liquor from a licensed wholesaler by providing written notice of the licensee's intent to the Department at least 60 days before the date the purchasing activity is to start.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The notice shall contain:</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(4)">A licensee that meets the requirements of this subsection may purchase wine or liquor from a licensed wholesaler in addition to or instead of the Department.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The Department shall issue a letter of confirmation to a licensee that meets the requirements of this subsection.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The licensee shall display the letter conspicuously on the licensed premises.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
