<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="g2b" order_by="2" level="1">Alcoholic Beverages</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>g2b-10-404</section_number>
  <catch_line>Except as otherwise provided in this section, when the license issued under the provisions of this a...</catch_line>
  <order_by>404</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Except as otherwise provided in this section, when the license issued under the provisions of this article has been revoked, such licensee shall not at any time thereafter be entitled to obtain any other license under the provisions of this article, and no other person shall be entitled to obtain such a license for the same premises until after the expiration of six months from the date of such revocation and not at all in the discretion of said Comptroller, board of license commissioners for the city or county, court or State Appeal Board as the case may be. If the license was held on behalf of a corporation, partnership, or unincorporated association, no person until after the expiration of said six-month period shall be entitled to obtain another license on behalf of such corporation, partnership, or unincorporated association, for the sale of alcoholic beverages upon the same premises.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">In Allegany County if a license is revoked by reason of the licensee being convicted of violating any provisions of the Tax - General Article that relate to the alcoholic beverage tax or any provision of this article, no license under this article may be issued to the same person or for the same premises within a period of one year thereafter.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">In Garrett County if a license is revoked by reason of the licensee being convicted of violating any provisions of the Tax - General Article that relate to the alcoholic beverage tax or any provision of this article, no license under this article may be issued to the same person or for the same premises within a period of two years thereafter.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">In Montgomery County if a license is revoked, the Board of License Commissioners may issue a license for the same premises to a person other than the former licensee in the same manner as the Board considers an application for a new license.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">In Wicomico County if a license is revoked by reason of the licensee being convicted of violating any provisions of the Tax - General Article that relate to the alcoholic beverage tax or any provision of this article, no license under this article may be issued to the same person within a period of 1 year thereafter. No other persons shall be entitled to obtain such a license for the same premises until after expiration of 6 months from the date of such revocation.</section>
  </text>
</law>
