<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="g2b" order_by="2" level="1">Alcoholic Beverages</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>g2b-6-201</section_number>
  <catch_line>A Class B beer, wine and liquor license shall be issued by the license issuing authority of the coun...</catch_line>
  <order_by>201</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A Class B beer, wine and liquor license shall be issued by the license issuing authority of the county in which the place of business is located, and the license authorizes its holder to keep for sale and sell all alcoholic beverages at retail at any hotel or restaurant at the place described, for consumption on the premises or elsewhere, or as provided in this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The annual fee for this license is payable to the local collecting agent before any license is issued, for distribution as provided in this article.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Except in Montgomery County or in the case of a contrary provision in this subtitle, this license shall be issued, on approval of the application by the board of license commissioners in any county in which a license may be issued for the sale of beer, wine, and liquor, to the owner of any hotel which meets the following minimum provisions:<section prefix="1.">The hotel building shall be originally constructed for hotel purposes; be at least three stories in height; and contain at least one passenger elevator;</section><section prefix="2.">The hotel shall contain no less than 100 rooms for the accommodation of the public;</section><section prefix="3.">The hotel shall contain a dining room with facilities for preparing and serving regular meals for at least 125 persons at one seating; and</section><section prefix="4.">The capital investment in the hotel facility may not be less than $500,000.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The annual fee for this license is $2,000.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The provisions of this subsection apply only in Allegany County.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The Board of License Commissioners may issue Class B beer, wine and liquor (on-sale) licenses.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">This license shall be issued for the exclusive use:<section prefix="1.">On the premises of a restaurant that is located within a hotel or motel establishment; or</section><section prefix="2.">If used in conjunction with a Class 7 micro-brewery license, on the premises of a restaurant only.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">In addition to other county requirements provided for in this article:<section prefix="1.">The hotel or motel shall be an establishment having at least 100 bedrooms for public accommodation; and</section><section prefix="2.">The restaurant shall be an establishment:</section></section>
        <section prefix="(iv)">This license authorizes the holder to sell beer, wine and liquor by the drink for consumption on the licensed premises only.</section>
        <section prefix="(v)">This license does not have off-sale privileges.</section>
        <section prefix="(vi)">The requirements for hours and days of sale are as provided under &#xA7; 11-501(a) and (b) of this article.</section>
        <section prefix="(vii)">The annual license fee is $800.</section>
        <section prefix="(viii)">This license is exempt from any license population quota limitation.</section>
        <section prefix="(ix)">Notwithstanding any law to the contrary, this license may not be transferred to a location other than the premises for which it was issued.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The Board of License Commissioners may issue a special Class B-BT (Buffet Theater) on-sale beer, light wine and liquor license for the use of an establishment that:<section prefix="1.">Is operated as a nonprofit professional theater;</section><section prefix="2.">Provides to its customers live Broadway-style musicals, comedy, drama, live acoustic-style music, or feature films; and</section><section prefix="3.">Is open to the public by reservation.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The holder of a Class B-BT license may sell at retail beer and light wine by the drink or by the bottle and liquor by the drink only for on-premises consumption beginning 2 hours before the performance, during the performance, and for 2 hours after the end of the performance on:<section prefix="1.">Monday through Saturday; and</section><section prefix="2.">Sunday no earlier than 1 p.m.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">The license does not authorize the holder to sell alcoholic beverages:<section prefix="1.">For off-premises consumption by the drink or by the bottle; or</section><section prefix="2.">At any time except in conjunction with the buffet theater.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(iv)">The annual fee for a Class B-BT license is $350.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The provisions of this subsection apply only in Anne Arundel County and do not apply to the City of Annapolis.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The annual fee for a Class B license is $1,080.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">A Class H beer, wine and liquor license authorizes the holder to keep for sale and sell beer, wine and liquor at retail at any restaurant for consumption on the premises.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The annual fee for this license is $960.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">This subsection applies only in Baltimore City.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">Except as otherwise provided by this subsection, the annual license fee is:<section prefix="1.">$1,320 for a licensed establishment with a seating capacity of 200 or fewer; and</section><section prefix="2.">$1,800 for a licensed establishment with a seating capacity of more than 200.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">In this paragraph "46th Alcoholic Beverages District" means an area that at all times shall be coterminous with the 46th Legislative District in the Legislative Districting Plan of 2002 as ordered by the Maryland Court of Appeals on June 21, 2002.</section>
        <section prefix="(iv)">Except for the 46th Alcoholic Beverages District, this license shall be issued in accordance with the provisions of subsection (a) of this section.</section>
        <section prefix="(v)">
          <section prefix="1.">Except as provided in subsubparagraph 2 of this subparagraph, in an area coterminous with the 47th Alcoholic Beverages District as that district existed before the Legislative Districting Plan was ordered by the Maryland Court of Appeals on June 21, 2002, a Class B beer, wine and liquor license issued for use in a restaurant:</section>
          <section prefix="2.">A license specified under subsubparagraph 1 of this subparagraph may include an off-sale privilege for sales of refillable containers under a refillable container license issued in accordance with &#xA7; 8-203(e) of this article.</section>
        </section>
        <section prefix="(vi)">The sales prohibition in subparagraph (v)1D of this paragraph does not apply to a Class B beer, wine and liquor licensee:<section prefix="1.">Whose license was issued before July 1, 1991; and</section><section prefix="2.">Who prior to July 1, 1991 operated the premises and exercised the sales privileges under the license on Sundays.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(vii)">In addition to the other requirements provided for in this subsection, in the 46th Alcoholic Beverages District the restaurant shall have a minimum:<section prefix="1.">Except as provided in subparagraph (ix) of this paragraph, capital investment of $500,000 for restaurant facilities not including the cost of the land, the building, or improvements that are not to the interior of a building on the licensed premises; and</section><section prefix="2.">Seating capacity of 75 persons, and, except as provided in subparagraph (ix) of this paragraph, a maximum seating capacity of 150 persons.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(viii)">
          <section prefix="1.">Notwithstanding &#xA7; 1-102(a)(22)(i)3 of this article and, except as provided in subparagraph (ix) of this paragraph, for a licensee who is issued a Class B beer, wine and liquor license for use in a restaurant in the 46th Alcoholic Beverages District, the average daily receipts from the sale of food must be at least 51% of the total daily receipts of the restaurant.</section>
          <section prefix="2.">A licensee annually, at the time the license is renewed, shall file with the Board of Liquor License Commissioners for Baltimore City a statement of average daily receipts and an affidavit of a licensed certified public accountant that verify that the licensee has met the requirement of sub-subparagraph 1 of this subparagraph or subparagraph (ix) of this paragraph.</section>
          <section prefix="3.">A license may not be transferred from the location of its first issuance.</section>
          <section prefix="4.">A license may not be issued for use in an establishment that is a fast food style restaurant.</section>
        </section>
        <section prefix="(ix)">The Board of Liquor License Commissioners for Baltimore City may issue a Class B beer, wine and liquor license for use in a restaurant that has a seating capacity exceeding 150 persons if the restaurant:<section prefix="1.">Is located in ward 26, precinct 8, ward 4, precinct 1, or ward 3, precinct 3 of the 46th Alcoholic Beverages District, which at all times shall be coterminous with the 46th Legislative District in the Legislative Districting Plan of 2002 as ordered by the Maryland Court of Appeals on June 21, 2002;</section><section prefix="2.">Has a minimum capital investment of $700,000; and</section><section prefix="3.">Has average daily receipts from the sale of food that are at least 65% of the total daily receipts.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(x)">Until July 1, 2005, the Board of Liquor License Commissioners for Baltimore City may issue a Class B beer, wine and liquor license for use in a restaurant that has a seating capacity exceeding 150 persons if the restaurant:<section prefix="1.">Is an establishment located in an area identified in &#xA7; 9-204(e)(1) of this article;</section><section prefix="2.">Has a minimum capital investment of $1,000,000; and</section><section prefix="3.">Has average daily receipts from the sale of food that are at least 70% of the total daily receipts.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(xi)">Notwithstanding any restriction or requirement in this article regarding the issuance of Class B beer, wine and liquor licenses, a not for profit arts center in the Highlandtown arts and entertainment district that holds a Class C license on June 1, 2004, may apply to the Board of Liquor License Commissioners for Baltimore City to convert that license into a Class B beer, wine and liquor license.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">There is a Class B-BWL (H-M) license.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The Class B-BWL (H-M) license shall be issued to any hotel or motel meeting the minimum criteria of subparagraph (iv) of this paragraph.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">The annual license fee is $6,500.</section>
        <section prefix="(iv)">The minimum criteria for the issuance of a Class B-BWL (H-M) license are as follows:<section prefix="1.">The hotel or motel shall contain no less than 100 rooms for the accommodation of the public;</section><section prefix="2.">The hotel or motel shall contain a dining room with facilities for preparing and serving regular meals for at least 125 persons at one seating; and</section><section prefix="3.">The capital investment in the hotel or motel facility may not be less than $500,000.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(v)">A Class B-BWL (H-M) license may not be required of any restaurant that is not located in a hotel or motel or of any catering establishment.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">
          <section prefix="1.">In this paragraph the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
          <section prefix="2.">"Arena" means a facility that is a:</section>
          <section prefix="3.">"Board" means the Board of License Commissioners.</section>
          <section prefix="4.">"Person" means a natural person, an association, a firm, a partnership, a corporation, or the Mayor and City Council of Baltimore.</section>
        </section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">There is an arena license.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">
          <section prefix="1.">A licensee may sell beer, wine and liquor by the drink and by the bottle within the arena, from one or more outlets, for consumption on the licensed premises.</section>
          <section prefix="2.">An arena license may not be issued in the Second and Third Wards after October 1, 1994. Licenses issued prior to that date are valid and may be treated like any other license.</section>
        </section>
        <section prefix="(iv)">The Board may issue an arena license only if the applicant has:<section prefix="1.">A minimum capital investment, not including any real property, of $1,000,000; and</section><section prefix="2.">A minimum capacity of 1,000 people, as determined by the Baltimore City Fire Department.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(v)">This license shall be issued only to the person, firm, or corporation owning or leasing an arena, one of whom must be a resident of the State of Maryland, or to a concessionaire designated by the person, firm or corporation owning or leasing the arena. The concessionaire need not be a resident of the State of Maryland.</section>
        <section prefix="(vi)">The Board shall prescribe regulations pertaining to the manner of dispensing alcoholic beverages, the number of outlets authorized to dispense alcoholic beverages, and the hours and days of sale.</section>
        <section prefix="(vii)">The licensee is subject to all of the provisions of this article and to the regulations of the Board of License Commissioners.</section>
        <section prefix="(viii)">The annual license fee for the arena license is $12,000.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(4)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The owner or owners of any regularly licensed racing establishment, or the concessionaire or catering organization at such place, whether an individual, association or corporation, without additional residential, voting or locative qualifications may procure a license for the sale of beer, wine and liquor within the confines of its racing park.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The license fee is $55 per day.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">The holder may sell at one or more locations within its park.</section>
        <section prefix="(iv)">The licenses and the licensees are subject to all laws and regulations applicable in Baltimore City to the sale of alcoholic beverages that are not inconsistent with the provisions of this subsection.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(5)">A licensee that is issued a license for room service for an establishment with fewer than 100 rooms shall pay an annual room service fee of $1,000 in addition to the license fee.</section>
      <section prefix="(6)">Except as provided under subsection (d-1) of this section, in addition to the annual license fee, a licensee issued a license under  this subsection shall pay annually:<section prefix="(i)">$500, if the licensee provides live entertainment; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">$200, if the licensee provides outdoor table or cafe service.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d-1)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">In this subsection the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">"Concessionaire" means a lessee, sublessee, or any other operator of an establishment that:<section prefix="1.">Engages in the daily sale of beer, wine, and liquor by the drink or by the bottle on its premises for consumption anywhere in a video lottery facility; and</section><section prefix="2.">Is operated as a concession independent of the  Class BWL-VLF licensee.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">"Video lottery facility" means a facility that holds a license under Title 9, Subtitle 1A of the State Government Article.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">There is a Class BWL-VLF (video lottery facility) beer, wine and liquor license.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The Board may issue a Class BWL-VLF license for a video lottery facility that contains one or more food service facilities, bars, or lounges.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">The Class BWL-VLF license may be issued to an individual or entity that owns a video lottery facility and holds a license under Title 9, Subtitle 1A of the State Government Article.</section>
        <section prefix="(iv)">An applicant for a Class BWL-VLF license need not meet any location, voting, or residency requirement.</section>
        <section prefix="(v)">A Class BWL-VLF license authorizes the licensee to sell beer, wine, and liquor by the drink and by the bottle on the premises of the video lottery facility, for consumption anywhere in the video lottery facility or on grounds controlled by the licensee, as defined in the Class BWL-VLF license.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">There is a video lottery concessionaire (Class BWL-VLC) license.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The Board may issue a Class BWL-VLC license to one or more concessionaires operating in the video lottery facility.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">Notwithstanding any other provision in this article, a Class BWL-VLC license authorizes the licensee to sell beer, wine, and liquor on the premises of the concessionaire for consumption anywhere in the video lottery facility or on grounds controlled by the Class BWL-VLF licensee, as defined in the Class BWL-VLF license.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(4)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The annual fee for a Class BWL-VLF license is $15,000.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The annual fee for a Class BWL-VLC license is $5,000.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">The annual license fees shall be paid on May 1 to the Board.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(5)">
        <section prefix="(i)">An off-sale privilege is not conferred by a Class BWL-VLF license or a Class BWL-VLC license.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">Beer, wine, and liquor purchased under a Class BWL-VLF license or a Class BWL-VLC license may be taken anywhere in a video lottery facility or on grounds controlled by the Class BWL-VLF licensee, as defined in the Class BWL-VLF license.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(6)">A Class BWL-VLF license and a Class BWL-VLC license authorize:<section prefix="(i)">The playing of music and dancing; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">The sale and providing of beer, wine, and liquor throughout the video lottery facility and grounds controlled by the Class BWL-VLF licensee during those days and hours that the video lottery facility is open for business.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(7)">Class BWL-VLF and Class BWL-VLC licenses and licensees are subject to all laws and regulations applicable to the sale of alcoholic beverages not inconsistent with this subsection.</section>
      <section prefix="(8)">Any penalty or other sanction that is imposed for a violation of a regulation of the Board on the licensed premises of a Class BWL-VLC licensee shall apply to the concessionaire that the Board determines to be responsible for the violation.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This subsection applies only in Baltimore County.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The annual fee for a license is $1,500.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The area of the licensed premises normally used as a restaurant for the preparation and consumption of food and beverage on the premises may occupy no less than 80 percent of the square foot area. These occupancy requirements do not apply to or affect any present licensee having this license prior to December 31, 1966.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This subsection applies only in Calvert County.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The annual fee for a Class B license is:<section prefix="(i)">$1,250, if the place of business remains open until midnight; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">$2,250, if the place of business remains open until 2 a.m.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">There is a Class BR beer, wine and liquor license which authorizes licensees to sell beer, wine, and liquor in restaurants for on-sale consumption with meals only.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The annual license fee for each license is $500.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">Hours and days for sale are those for other Calvert County Class B licensees.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(4)">
        <section prefix="(i)">In the 27th Legislative District of Calvert County, there is a Class BLX license for luxury-type restaurants.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The Class BLX license shall be applied for in the same manner as are other classes of licenses.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">The license fee is $2,400.</section>
        <section prefix="(iv)">A luxury-type restaurant shall be defined by the County Liquor Board.</section>
        <section prefix="(v)">To qualify for a Class BLX license, a restaurant shall have:<section prefix="1.">A minimum capital investment of $500,000 for the dining room facilities and kitchen equipment, not including the cost of land, buildings, or leases; and</section><section prefix="2.">A seating capacity of at least 150 persons.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(vi)">Notwithstanding any other provision of this article, an individual, corporation, limited liability company, partnership, limited partnership, joint venture, association, or other person or combination of persons may not have a direct or indirect interest in any combination in more than 4 Class B and Class BLX licenses.</section>
        <section prefix="(vii)">An indirect interest is presumed to exist between any combination of individuals, corporations, limited liability companies, partnerships, limited partnerships, joint ventures, associations, or other persons if any of the following conditions exist between them:<section prefix="1.">A common parent company;</section><section prefix="2.">A franchise agreement;</section><section prefix="3.">A licensing agreement;</section><section prefix="4.">A concession agreement;</section><section prefix="5.">Dual membership in a chain of businesses commonly owned and operated;</section><section prefix="6.">A sharing of directors, stockholders, partners, or members, or a sharing of directors, stockholders, partners, or members of parents or subsidiaries;</section><section prefix="7.">Common direct or indirect sharing of profit from the sale of alcoholic beverages; or</section><section prefix="8.">A sharing of a common trade name, trademark, logo or theme, or mode of operation identifiable by the public.</section></section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This subsection applies only in Caroline County.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Bona fide hotels and restaurants, as defined by the Board of License Commissioners, may serve liquors, wines, and beers by the drink only and only upon the premises.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The annual license fee for a:<section prefix="(i)">6-day license is $1,000; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">7-day license is $1,250.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(h)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">This subsection applies only in Carroll County.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">In this subsection "Board" means the Board of License Commissioners.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The annual license fee is $1,500 for a restaurant and $1,500 for a hotel.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">This license may be issued to a bona fide hotel which:<section prefix="1.">Is an establishment for the accommodation of the public providing service ordinarily found in hotels;</section><section prefix="2.">Is equipped with not fewer than 25 rooms, a lobby with registration and mail desk, seating facilities and a dining room which serves full-course meals at least twice daily and which has a regular seating capacity at tables (not including seats at bars or counters) for 50 or more persons; and</section><section prefix="3.">Is operated in facilities which are valued for purposes of State and local assessment and taxation at not less than $50,000.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">
          <section prefix="1.">This license may be issued to a restaurant which meets the following requirements and conditions:</section>
          <section prefix="2."/>
          <section prefix="3."/>
        </section>
        <section prefix="(iv)">Whenever application is made for licensing under this subsection for any new or improved building, the supervisor of assessments, at the request of the Board, shall assess the building and advise the Board of the valuation of the building for assessment and taxation purposes.</section>
        <section prefix="(v)">The valuation of the building for assessment and taxation purposes as set out in subparagraphs (ii) and (iii) of this paragraph does not affect or prohibit in any manner the renewal or transfer of any Class B license issued prior to May 1, 1979.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">There is a Class BC license.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The Board may issue a Class BC restaurant or hotel and caterer's (on- and limited off-sale) beer, wine and liquor license to an applicant:<section prefix="1.">Who has a restaurant or hotel which meets the licensure requirements and conditions provided under this section; or</section><section prefix="2.">Who is a holder of a Class B hotel or restaurant (on- and off-sale) beer, wine and liquor license issued in Carroll County, if the holder surrenders the license to the Board before being issued a new license under this paragraph.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">The Class BC restaurant or hotel and caterer's license issued under this section authorizes the holder to sell:<section prefix="1.">Beer, wine and liquor, 7 days a week, on the restaurant or hotel premises for on-premises consumption;</section><section prefix="2.">Beer, 7 days a week, on the restaurant or hotel premises for off-premises consumption; and</section><section prefix="3.">Beer, wine and liquor, 7 days a week, at catered events held in Carroll County off the restaurant or hotel premises for on-premises consumption.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(iv)">The holder of a license issued under this paragraph shall provide food as well as alcoholic beverages for consumption at the catered event.</section>
        <section prefix="(v)">The annual fee for a license issued under this paragraph is $250 more than the annual fee for a Class B hotel or restaurant (on- and off-sale) beer, wine and liquor license issued in Carroll County.</section>
        <section prefix="(vi)">The holder of a license issued under this section may exercise the license privileges only during the hours and days that are permitted under this article for a Class B hotel or restaurant (on- and off-sale) beer, wine and liquor license issued in Carroll County.</section>
        <section prefix="(vii)">Upon payment of an additional annual license fee of $250, the holder of a Class BR license has the privileges of the holder of a Class BC license specified in subparagraph (3)(iii)3 of this subsection, subject to the restrictions set forth in subparagraph (iv) of this subsection.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(4)">
        <section prefix="(i)">
          <section prefix="1.">There is a Class BR license.</section>
          <section prefix="2.">In this paragraph, "premises" means an area inside the restaurant building where meals are prepared and served and an area on the outside of the restaurant building that is approved in writing by the Board.</section>
        </section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The annual license fee is $2,000.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">The Board may issue a Class BR beer, wine and liquor license to an applicant who owns or operates a restaurant that:<section prefix="1.">Serves at least one full-course evening dinner meal at least 5 days a week;</section><section prefix="2.">Is only open during the time meals are served;</section><section prefix="3.">Has a regular seating capacity at tables (not including seating at bars and counters) for 50 or more people; and</section><section prefix="4.">Is operated in facilities which are valued for purposes of State and local assessment and taxation at not less than $50,000.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(iv)">Whenever an application is made for a Class BR license for a new or improved building, the Supervisor of Assessments, at the request of the Board, shall assess the building and advise the Board of the valuation of the building for assessment and taxation purposes.</section>
        <section prefix="(v)">A Class BR license authorizes the licensee to sell beer, wine and liquor, 7 days a week, on the premises of the restaurant for consumption with meals on the premises or for consumption on the premises pursuant to regulations adopted by the Board.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(i)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This subsection applies only in Cecil County.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The annual license fee is $750.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Notwithstanding the license quota provisions of &#xA7; 8-208 of this article, the Board of License Commissioners may issue special Class B licenses known as Class BLX beer, wine and liquor on-sale restaurant licenses.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">To qualify for a Class BLX on-sale license the restaurant shall have:<section prefix="1.">A minimum capital investment of $450,000 for dining room facilities and kitchen equipment, which sum may not include the cost of land, buildings, or a lease; and</section><section prefix="2.">A minimum seating capacity of 100 persons.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">The holder of a Class BLX license:<section prefix="1.">Is authorized to sell alcoholic beverages for consumption on the licensed premises only;</section><section prefix="2.">May not sell alcoholic beverages for off-premises consumption; and</section><section prefix="3.">May serve alcoholic beverages:</section></section>
        <section prefix="(iv)">The annual fee for a Class BLX license is $2,500.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(4)">
        <section prefix="(i)">There is a Class EF (entertainment facility) beer, wine and liquor license.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">A Class EF license authorizes the holder to sell beer, wine, and liquor by the drink and by the bottle, from one or more outlets in the entertainment facility, for consumption anywhere within the entertainment facility.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">A holder of a Class EF license may not sell alcoholic beverages for off-sale consumption.</section>
        <section prefix="(iv)">Notwithstanding &#xA7; 8-208(b) of this article, the Board of License Commissioners may issue a Class EF license if the applicant has a capital investment in the facility for which the license is sought, not including any real property, of at least $35,000,000.</section>
        <section prefix="(v)">The Board may issue one or more Class EF licenses for the same facility.</section>
        <section prefix="(vi)">A Class EF license authorizes the playing of music and dancing.</section>
        <section prefix="(vii)">A Class EF license authorizes the sales and serving of beer, wine, and liquor throughout the entertainment facility during those days and hours that the entertainment facility is open for business.</section>
        <section prefix="(viii)">The annual license fee is $7,500.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(j)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This subsection applies only in Charles County.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The annual license fee is $360.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">This license shall provide for the consumption of beer, wine and liquor on the premises only.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">
        <section prefix="(i)">There is in addition to the classes provided for, a special Class B license known as a Class BLX, which is issued only to luxury-type restaurants.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The Class BLX license shall be applied for in the same manner as are other classes of licenses.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">The license fee is $2,400.</section>
        <section prefix="(iv)">A luxury-type restaurant shall be defined by the Board of License Commissioners.</section>
        <section prefix="(v)">To qualify for a Class BLX license a restaurant shall have:<section prefix="1.">A minimum capital investment of $550,000 for the dining room facilities and kitchen equipment, not including the cost of land, buildings, or leases; and</section><section prefix="2.">A seating capacity of at least 150 persons.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(vi)">Notwithstanding any other provision of this article, an individual, corporation, limited liability company, partnership, limited partnership, joint venture, association, or other person or combination of persons may not have a direct or indirect interest in any combination in more than 6 Class B-BLX licenses.</section>
        <section prefix="(vii)">An indirect interest is presumed to exist between any combination of individuals, corporations, limited liability companies, partnerships, limited partnerships, joint ventures, associations, or other persons if any of the following conditions exist between them:<section prefix="1.">A common parent company;</section><section prefix="2.">A franchise agreement;</section><section prefix="3.">A licensing agreement;</section><section prefix="4.">A concession agreement;</section><section prefix="5.">Dual membership in a chain of businesses commonly owned and operated;</section><section prefix="6.">A sharing of directors, stockholders, partners, or members, or a sharing of directors, stockholders, partners, or members of parents or subsidiaries;</section><section prefix="7.">Common direct or indirect sharing of profit from the sale of alcoholic beverages; or</section><section prefix="8.">A sharing of a common trade name, trademark, logo or theme, or mode of operation identifiable by the public.</section></section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(5)">
        <section prefix="(i)">
          <section prefix="1.">In this paragraph, "guest" means a person whose name and address appear on the registry that is maintained by the establishment and who is an occupant of a sleeping room in the establishment.</section>
          <section prefix="2.">"Guest" does not include a person who is registered only for the purpose of obtaining alcoholic beverages.</section>
        </section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">There is a special Class B-B&amp;B (bed and breakfast) on-sale beer, wine, and liquor license.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">The Board may issue a Class B-B&amp;B license.</section>
        <section prefix="(iv)">To qualify for a Class B-B&amp;B license, the applicant's establishment:<section prefix="1.">Shall have rooms, excluding the resident management quarters, that the public, for consideration, may use for sleeping accommodations for a specified period of time; and</section><section prefix="2.">May not have dining facilities that are open to the general public.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(v)">A Class B-B&amp;B licensee may sell beer, wine, and liquor only to guests for consumption on the licensed premises.</section>
        <section prefix="(vi)">The annual license fees are:<section prefix="1.">$25 for an establishment with one to five bedrooms; or</section><section prefix="2.">$50 for an establishment with six or more bedrooms.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(vii)">The hours and days for sale under the license shall be in accordance with &#xA7; 11-509 of this article.</section>
        <section prefix="(viii)">An applicant for a Class B-B&amp;B license shall meet all other qualifications to hold an alcoholic beverages license in the county.</section>
        <section prefix="(ix)">The Board may adopt additional regulations consistent with this paragraph.</section>
        <section prefix="(x)">If the licensed premises ceases to be operated as a bed and breakfast establishment, the license is void.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(6)">
        <section prefix="(i)">There is a Class B-Stadium (baseball stadium) on-sale beer, wine and liquor license.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The Board of License Commissioners may issue a 7-day Class B-Stadium license to:<section prefix="1.">The owner of any professional team franchise, whether the franchise is a partnership, corporation, or limited liability company; or</section><section prefix="2.">A private concessionaire that is under contract with the County or a professional baseball team franchise.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">A Class B-Stadium license authorizes the holder to sell beer, wine, and liquor on the premises of a baseball stadium owned or operated by the County to individuals present at baseball games or other events held at the stadium.</section>
        <section prefix="(iv)">Except as provided in subparagraph (v) of this paragraph, beer, wine, and liquor shall be served in plastic, styrofoam, or paper containers on the stadium premises.</section>
        <section prefix="(v)">Beer, wine, and liquor may be served in glass containers in an enclosed stadium dining area in which patrons are seated.</section>
        <section prefix="(vi)">A patron:<section prefix="1.">May consume and carry beer and wine anywhere on the stadium premises; but</section><section prefix="2.">May consume liquor only in the enclosed stadium dining area or bar; and</section><section prefix="3.">May not carry liquor out of the enclosed stadium dining area or bar.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(vii)">The annual fee for the Class B-Stadium license is $2,200.</section>
        <section prefix="(viii)">Except for a distributor of beer who is conducting business with a holder of a Class B-Stadium license for the purposes of this paragraph, the holder may not allow any individual to carry alcoholic beverages onto or from the licensed premises.</section>
        <section prefix="(ix)">The Board of License Commissioners may adopt additional regulations consistent with this paragraph relating to:<section prefix="1.">The manner of dispensing alcoholic beverages;</section><section prefix="2.">The number of outlets authorized to dispense alcoholic beverages; and</section><section prefix="3.">The hours and days of sale of alcoholic beverages.</section></section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(k)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This subsection applies only in Dorchester County.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Bona fide restaurants, motels and hotels having restaurant facilities for serving full-course meals at least twice daily and seating capacity at tables for 50 or more persons, not including seats at bars or counters, may obtain a license from the Board of License Commissioners. This license entitles the licensee to sell beer, wines, and liquors.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The annual license fee is $1,000.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">This license provides for the consumption of beer, wine, and liquor on the premises only.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(l)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This subsection applies only in Frederick County.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The annual license fee is $1,500 for a restaurant and $2,000 for a hotel.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">Any hotel meeting the minimum requirements of subsection (a)(3) of this section may elect to be issued a license under that subsection, or any bona fide hotel may elect to be issued a license under this subsection if it:<section prefix="1.">Is an establishment for the accommodation of the public providing service ordinarily found in hotels;</section><section prefix="2.">Is equipped with not fewer than 25 rooms, a lobby with registration and mail desk, seating facilities and a dining room which serves full-course meals at least twice daily and which has a regular seating capacity at tables (not including seats at bars or counters) for 50 or more persons; and</section><section prefix="3.">Is operated in a physical plant which has a valuation for purposes of State and local assessment and taxation of not less than $20,000 and which has a valuation of personal property for purposes of State and local assessment and taxation of not less than $3,000. This license in a hotel does not permit sales at bars or counters, or sales for consumption anywhere except on the premises on which the meals are prepared and served.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">This license may be issued to a restaurant which:<section prefix="1.">Serves full-course meals at least twice daily;</section><section prefix="2.">Has a regular seating capacity at tables (not including seats at bars or counters) for 50 or more persons;</section><section prefix="3.">Is operated in a physical plant which has a valuation for purposes of State and local assessment and taxation of not less than $40,000 and which has a valuation of personal property for purposes of State and local assessment and taxation of not less than $5,000. This license in a restaurant permits sales for consumption on the premises on which meals are prepared and served, except in the case of beverages with an alcoholic content of not more than 14.5 percent by volume, which may be sold for off-premises consumption; and</section><section prefix="4."/></section>
        <section prefix="(iv)">
          <section prefix="1.">A restaurant issued a license under this subsection may remove its tables and chairs to accommodate additional patrons at not more than four special events held in the restaurant in a calendar year.</section>
          <section prefix="2.">A restaurant that removes its tables and chairs for a special event:</section>
        </section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Any bona fide hotel or motel may obtain a special Class B (on-sale) beer, wine and liquor license issued by the Board of License Commissioners providing:<section prefix="1.">It is an establishment for the accommodation of the public providing services ordinarily found in bona fide hotels and motels;</section><section prefix="2.">It contains no less than 15 rooms;</section><section prefix="3.">It contains a dining room with facilities for preparing and serving full-course meals for at least 50 persons at one seating; and</section><section prefix="4.">The capital investment in the hotel or motel facility is not less than $400,000.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">
          <section prefix="1.">Subject to this special Class B license, sales of all alcoholic beverages may be by the individual drink at any place on the hotel or motel premises.</section>
          <section prefix="2.">Sales of all alcoholic beverages may be by the bottle at any place on the premises for banquets, parties, hospitality rooms, meetings, and similar functions, and for dinners in the restaurant portion of the premises. However, the customer is not permitted to remove the unused portion of any such bottle from the premises.</section>
          <section prefix="3.">Alcoholic beverages by the bottle may be sold through room service to bona fide registered patrons in the hotel or motel rooms. However, no more than two bottles may be sold through room service to any one patron in any 24-hour period. Bottles sold through room service may be removed from the premises by the patron upon checking out from the hotel or motel.</section>
        </section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">The annual fee for this special Class B license is $2,000.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(4)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The Board of License Commissioners may issue a Class B-B.F. (Banquet Facility) beer, light wine and liquor on-sale license for a banquet facility that:<section prefix="1.">Accommodates the public for banquets, parties, meetings, and similar functions;</section><section prefix="2.">Contains a dining room with adequate facilities for preparing and serving full-course meals for at least 100 persons at one seating;</section><section prefix="3.">Is eligible for inclusion on the National Register of Historic Places; and</section><section prefix="4.">Has a capital investment of not less than $500,000, excluding the cost of the land, buildings, and leases.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The Class B-B.F. beer, light wine and liquor license authorizes the holder to keep for sale, and sell at retail, beer, light wine, and liquor by the drink or by the bottle for on-premises consumption only; provided that:<section prefix="1.">The beer, light wine, and liquor are only sold during the function;</section><section prefix="2.">The licensee may not sell alcoholic beverages for off-premises consumption;</section><section prefix="3.">The licensee may not permit alcoholic beverages to be carried off the premises; and</section><section prefix="4.">Food is furnished at the function where the alcoholic beverages are provided.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">The days and hours of sale under this license are as provided in &#xA7; 11-511 of this article.</section>
        <section prefix="(iv)">The annual license fee for a Class B-B.F. license is $1,500.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(5)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The Board of License Commissioners may issue a special Class B-DT (Dinner Theater) on-sale beer, light wine and liquor license for the use of an establishment that:<section prefix="1.">Is operated as a dinner theater;</section><section prefix="2.">Provides live Broadway-style musicals, comedy, or drama to its customers;</section><section prefix="3.">Is open to the public by reservation only; and</section><section prefix="4.">Contains a dining room with facilities for preparing and serving full-course meals for at least 120 persons at one seating.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The holder of a Class B-DT license is authorized to sell at retail beer and light wine by the drink or by the bottle and liquor by the drink only for on-premises consumption beginning 2 hours before the live performance through the end of the performance on:<section prefix="1.">Monday through Saturday; and</section><section prefix="2.">Sunday no sooner than 1 p.m.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">The license does not authorize the holder to sell alcoholic beverages:<section prefix="1.">For off-premises consumption by the drink or by the bottle; or</section><section prefix="2.">At any time except in conjunction with the dinner theater.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(iv)">The annual fee for a Class B-DT license is $1,500.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(6)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The Board of License Commissioners may issue a Class B-BB (bed and breakfast) on-sale beer, wine and liquor license for the use of an establishment that:<section prefix="1.">Provides services ordinarily found in a bed and breakfast establishment; and</section><section prefix="2.">Contains at least one room with sleeping accommodations, excluding resident management quarters, that the public for consideration may use for a specified time.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The holder of a Class B-BB license may sell alcoholic beverages only:<section prefix="1.">For consumption on the premises during the hours and days that are permitted for a Class B on-sale beer, wine and liquor license issued in the county; and</section><section prefix="2.">To a guest whose name and address appears on the registry that is maintained by the establishment and who is an occupant of a sleeping room in the establishment.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">The holder of a Class B-BB license may not sell alcoholic beverages to a person who is registered at the establishment only to obtain alcoholic beverages.</section>
        <section prefix="(iv)">The annual license fee is $500.</section>
        <section prefix="(v)">If an establishment ends operations as a bed and breakfast establishment:<section prefix="1.">The Class B-BB license is voided; and</section><section prefix="2.">The holder shall return the Class B-BB license to the Board of License Commissioners.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(vi)">The Board of License Commissioners may adopt regulations to carry out this paragraph.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(7)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The Board of License Commissioners may issue a Class B-CI (country inn) on-sale beer, wine and liquor license for the use of an establishment that:<section prefix="1.">Provides services ordinarily found in a country inn establishment;</section><section prefix="2.">Contains at least eight rooms with sleeping accommodations, excluding resident management quarters, that the public for consideration may use for a specified time; and</section><section prefix="3.">Has a kitchen facility for guests that is separate from the kitchen facility of the resident management quarters.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The holder of a Class B-CI license may sell alcoholic beverages only:<section prefix="1.">For consumption on the premises during the hours and days that are permitted for a Class B on-sale beer, wine and liquor license issued in the county; and</section><section prefix="2.">When accommodating the public for banquets, parties, meetings, and similar functions.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">The annual license fee is $2,500.</section>
        <section prefix="(iv)">If an establishment ends operations as a country inn facility:<section prefix="1.">The Class B-CI license is voided; and</section><section prefix="2.">The holder shall return the Class B-CI license to the Board of License Commissioners.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(v)">The Board of License Commissioners may adopt regulations to carry out this paragraph.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(m)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This subsection applies only in Garrett County.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">A Class B beer, wine and liquor license may be issued for use in a bona fide hotel or motel that:<section prefix="1.">Is an establishment for the accommodation of the public;</section><section prefix="2.">Provides services ordinarily found in hotels or motels;</section><section prefix="3.">Is equipped with not less than 25 rooms; and</section><section prefix="4.">Has a lobby with a registration and mail desk and seating facilities.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">A Class B beer, wine and liquor license may be issued to a restaurant that:<section prefix="1.">Has a seating capacity at tables, not including seats at bars or counters, for 20 or more persons; and</section><section prefix="2.">Is capable of preparing and serving full-course meals for 20 or more persons at one seating.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">Except at catered events, if the holder has the catering option, the holder is authorized to sell brewed beverages, as defined in this article, for off-premises consumption.</section>
        <section prefix="(iv)">
          <section prefix="1.">If the holder has the catering option, this license also authorizes the holder to keep for sale and sell beer, wine, and liquor for consumption at events catered in the county by the licensee off the licensed premises.</section>
          <section prefix="2.">If the licensee provides alcoholic beverages at a catered event off the licensed premises the holder shall also provide food.</section>
          <section prefix="3.">The licensee may exercise the catering privileges only during the hours and days that are permitted under the Class B license.</section>
        </section>
        <section prefix="(v)">
          <section prefix="1.">The annual fee for a license with the catering option is $2,000 and the issuing fee for a new license is $2,000, in addition to the annual fee.</section>
          <section prefix="2.">The annual fee for a license without the catering option is $1,500. The issuing fee for a new license is $1,500, in addition to the annual fee.</section>
        </section>
        <section prefix="(vi)">An application for a license under this subsection shall be denied if the Liquor Control Board determines that the business to be operated under this license will not enhance the recreational, business, and economical development within the county.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">In this paragraph, "guest" means a person whose name and address appears on the registry that is maintained by the establishment and who is an occupant of a sleeping room in the establishment. "Guest" does not include a person who is registered solely for the purpose of obtaining alcoholic beverages.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">
          <section prefix="1.">There is a Class B-B&amp;B license. The Board may issue a 7-day special Class B (bed and breakfast) on-sale beer, wine and liquor license.</section>
          <section prefix="2.">To qualify for a license under sub-subparagraph 1 of this subparagraph:</section>
          <section prefix="3.">A holder of a Class B-B&amp;B license may sell beer, wine, and liquor only to guests for consumption on the premises.</section>
        </section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">The annual license fees are:<section prefix="1.">One to five bedrooms: $25;</section><section prefix="2.">Six to ten bedrooms: $50; and</section><section prefix="3.">Eleven or more bedrooms: $75.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(iv)">The Board shall charge an issuing fee in an amount equal to the annual license fee.</section>
        <section prefix="(v)">A Class B-B&amp;B license is an on-sale only license.</section>
        <section prefix="(vi)">The days and hours of sale under this license shall be in accordance with &#xA7; 11-512(b)(1) of this article.</section>
        <section prefix="(vii)">An applicant shall meet all other qualifications to hold a license within the county. The Board may adopt additional regulations consistent with this paragraph.</section>
        <section prefix="(viii)">If the establishment ceases to be operated as a bed and breakfast, the license is void.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(4)">
        <section prefix="(i)">In this paragraph, "resort" means a complex that has two or more facilities that are:<section prefix="1.">Located on the same contiguous property;</section><section prefix="2.">Separated by at least 150 feet from the main area of the licensed premises; and</section><section prefix="3.">Determined by the Board of License Commissioners to be recreational, hotel, motel, or restaurant facilities.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The Board may issue a Class B-resort license.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">A Class B-resort license authorizes the licensee to exercise the same privileges as a licensee of a regular Class B (on-sale) hotels and restaurants beer, wine and liquor license.</section>
        <section prefix="(iv)">The annual license fees are:<section prefix="1.">Two facilities, $3,000; and</section><section prefix="2.">Each additional facility, $1,500.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(v)">The Board of License Commissioners shall charge an issuing fee for new licenses in an amount equal to the annual license fee.</section>
        <section prefix="(vi)">The days and hours of sale under a Class B-resort license shall be in accordance with &#xA7; 11-512 of this article.</section>
        <section prefix="(vii)">An applicant shall meet all other qualifications to hold a license within the county.</section>
        <section prefix="(viii)">The Board of License Commissioners may adopt regulations consistent with this paragraph.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(5)">
        <section prefix="(i)">There is a Class BDR (deluxe restaurant) beer, wine and liquor license, which is a Special Class B license.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">A Class BDR license may be issued for a deluxe restaurant, as defined by the Board of License Commissioners.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">Notwithstanding &#xA7; 9-102(a) of this article, a Class BDR license may be issued to an applicant who already holds a Class B (on-sale) beer, wine and liquor license or a Class B Resort (on-sale) beer, wine and liquor license.</section>
        <section prefix="(iv)">A Class BDR license may be issued only for the use of a restaurant with:<section prefix="1.">A minimum seating capacity for 85 persons; and</section><section prefix="2.">A minimum capital investment of $250,000 for the restaurant facilities, not including the cost of land or buildings.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(v)">If an applicant purchases or leases an existing building, the capital investment attributable to the cost of the land and improvements shall be based on the assessed value of the land and improvements in accordance with the records of the Department of Assessments and Taxation at the time of purchase.</section>
        <section prefix="(vi)">The annual license fee is $2,250.</section>
        <section prefix="(vii)">The Board of License Commissioners shall charge a one-time issuing fee for a new license in an amount equal to the annual fee.</section>
        <section prefix="(viii)">
          <section prefix="1.">A holder of a Class BDR license may acquire the same catering option that is described under paragraph (2)(iii) and (iv) of this subsection for Class B beer, wine and liquor licenses.</section>
          <section prefix="2.">The annual catering option fee is $500.</section>
        </section>
        <section prefix="(ix)">The days and hours of sale under a Class BDR license are in accordance with &#xA7; 11-512(b)(1) of this article.</section>
        <section prefix="(x)">The Board of License Commissioners may adopt rules and regulations to carry out this paragraph.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(n)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This subsection applies only in Harford County.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The annual license fee is:<section prefix="1.">For a 6-day, Monday through Saturday, license:</section><section prefix="2.">For a 7-day license:</section></section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">
          <section prefix="1.">The license permits the sale of liquor for consumption inside the premises only.</section>
          <section prefix="2.">As to any 6- or 7-day restaurant or hotel license issued prior to July 1, 1984, beer and wine may be sold for consumption on- and off-sale pursuant to &#xA7; 5-201(n) of this article.</section>
          <section prefix="3.">As to any 6- or 7-day restaurant license issued on or after July 1, 1984, beer and wine may be sold for consumption on the premises only.</section>
          <section prefix="4.">These licenses shall be issued by the Liquor Control Board.</section>
        </section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">This license may be issued to an applicant for a bona fide hotel which:<section prefix="1.">Is an establishment for the accommodation of the public, providing services ordinarily found in hotels; and</section><section prefix="2.">Is equipped with no fewer than 25 rooms, a lobby with a registration and mail desk and seating facilities, and a dining room which serves full-course meals at least twice daily.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(iv)">
          <section prefix="1.">This license in a hotel permits sales at bars or counters, but not liquor, beer, or wine for consumption off the premises.</section>
          <section prefix="2.">As to any such license issued prior to July 1, 1984, beer and wine may be sold for consumption on- and off-sale pursuant to &#xA7; 5-201(n) of this article.</section>
        </section>
        <section prefix="(v)">This license may be issued to an applicant for a restaurant which meets the following requirements and conditions:<section prefix="1.">Serves full-course meals at least twice daily;</section><section prefix="2.">Has a regular seating capacity of tables, not including seats at bars or counters for 60 or more persons;</section><section prefix="3.">Has been in full-time operation as a restaurant for not less than 6 months immediately preceding the time the application is made for the license. However, the 6-month time period requirement does not apply to a licensee whose business has been disrupted or interrupted as a result of fire or other disaster; and</section><section prefix="4.">Has had daily average receipts from the sale of food in excess of sales of alcoholic beverages during the 6-month period immediately preceding the application for license.</section></section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">
          <section prefix="1.">There is a "Class B-3 restaurant/hotel license", which may be issued by the Liquor Control Board to a licensee who has been operating his business establishment under the Class B beer, wine and liquor license for 1 year prior to the application for this license and who is, in the judgment of the Board, equipped and stocked for the continued regular sale of food to customers and guests and does at least 25 percent of his business in the sale of food.</section>
          <section prefix="2.">The annual license fee:</section>
        </section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">
          <section prefix="1.">The restaurant or hotel may purchase liquor or spirituous beverages from licensed suppliers.</section>
          <section prefix="2.">This subsection may not be construed to limit the powers of the Liquor Control Board to control the number of licensees under &#xA7;&#xA7; 9-201 and 16-301 of this article.</section>
          <section prefix="3.">This subsection may not contravene the provisions of &#xA7;&#xA7; 10-103, 10-104, and 11-513 of this article, as the several sections may be amended from time to time.</section>
        </section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(4)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Any Class B licensee who was granted an option that authorizes the sale of liquor off-sale as provided for in &#xA7; 6-101(n) of this article shall pay the following additional fees:<section prefix="1.">Six-day restaurant - $350; and</section><section prefix="2.">Seven-day restaurant - $450.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">Any licensee who has been previously granted an option under the provision of &#xA7; 6-101(n)(5) of this article shall apply that option only to the area described in the application and that area may not exceed 20 percent of the area normally used in the operation of the restaurant business. This area shall be separate and distinct from the restaurant seating area, unless sales are merely from behind the bar. The 20 percent area limitation does not apply to additions or extensions. If the application indicates that off-sale of liquor will be more extensive than from behind the bar, a separate outside entrance for the use of off-sale customers shall be provided.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">Class B licensees who utilize this option shall meet all of the appropriate operating requirements stipulated in this subsection and &#xA7; 5-201(n) of this article. However, for the purposes of meeting food sale requirements, off-sale liquor receipts may not be included in the calculation of sales.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(5)">
        <section prefix="(i)">There is a special Class B on-sale license known as Class BNR which may be issued only to newly opened restaurants that:<section prefix="1.">Have a minimum capital investment of $250,000 for new dining room facilities and newly installed kitchen equipment, which sum may not include the cost of land, buildings, or a lease;</section><section prefix="2.">Comply with paragraph (2)(v)1 and 2 of this subsection; and</section><section prefix="3.">Are as further defined by the regulations of the Liquor Control Board.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The annual license fee is $3,000.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">The licensee may serve alcoholic beverages on Monday through Sunday and only between 8 a.m. and 2 a.m. the following morning.</section>
        <section prefix="(iv)">The Liquor Control Board has complete discretion as to:<section prefix="1.">The number of licenses to be issued; and</section><section prefix="2.">To whom these licenses shall be issued.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(v)">A BNR license is restricted to the purpose of providing alcoholic beverages for consumption on the licensed premises only and provides no off-sale privileges.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(6)">Repealed.</section>
      <section prefix="(7)">
        <section prefix="(i)">In this paragraph, "guest" means an individual whose name and address appear on the registry that is maintained by the establishment.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The Liquor Control Board may issue a 7-day special Class B (inn) on-sale beer, wine and liquor license.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">To qualify for the issuance or reissuance of a special Class B (inn) license, the establishment of the applicant or the special Class B (inn) license holder shall:<section prefix="1.">Be approved by the appropriate governing authority to operate as an inn;</section><section prefix="2.">Have a minimum of 11 rooms or suites, excluding the resident management quarters, which the public, for consideration, may use as guests for sleeping accommodations for a specified period of time;</section><section prefix="3.">Have a seated dining capacity of a sufficient size to accommodate overnight guests and dinner patrons who are participating in regular meals and special dinner events on the premises of the establishment as allowed under subparagraph (vi) of this paragraph; and</section><section prefix="4.">Have a kitchen facility that has been approved by the local governing authority.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(iv)">
          <section prefix="1.">The holder of a 7-day special Class B (inn) license may sell, only in conjunction with a meal, alcoholic beverages to guests for consumption on the premises during the days and hours established for a Class B on-sale beer, wine and liquor license for Harford County under this article.</section>
          <section prefix="2.">The holder of a Class B (inn) license issued after March 6, 2006, may sell beer and wine from the dining room to guests for consumption off the premises, if the holder previously held a Class B (restaurant) license permitting sales of beer and wine for consumption off the premises.</section>
        </section>
        <section prefix="(v)">The annual fee for a 7-day special Class B (inn) license is:<section prefix="1.">For an establishment that has 11 through 24 rooms or suites, $2,500; and</section><section prefix="2.">For an establishment that has 25 or more rooms or suites, $3,295.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(vi)">
          <section prefix="1.">The special Class B (inn) license authorizes the holder of the license to:</section>
          <section prefix="2.">For purposes of subsubparagraph 1C of this subparagraph, a building that is within a reasonable distance from the inn establishment means a building that is located within the same mail unit number as the inn establishment or is not more than one-eighth of a mile from the inn establishment.</section>
        </section>
        <section prefix="(vii)">At no time may alcoholic beverages in open containers be transferred, carried, taken, or delivered to, from, or between the inn establishment and other buildings that are considered part of the inn establishment operations.</section>
        <section prefix="(viii)">The holder of a special Class B (inn) license may not sell alcoholic beverages to a person who:<section prefix="1.">Is not a guest or a patron of the dining facility of the establishment; or</section><section prefix="2.">Is a guest registered at the establishment only for the purpose of obtaining alcoholic beverages.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(ix)">The holder of a special Class B (inn) license may serve alcoholic beverages to guests and dinner patrons on a patio, deck, terrace, or the grounds or other outdoor area that is an integral part of the premises of the inn establishment only with the prior approval of the Liquor Control Board.</section>
        <section prefix="(x)">
          <section prefix="1.">Subject to the requirement of subsubparagraph 2 of this subparagraph, the special Class B (inn) license authorizes the holder of the license to keep for sale and sell beer, wine, and liquor for on-premises consumption during catered events that are catered by the license holder at the inn establishment if the license holder is under contract to cater the event.</section>
          <section prefix="2.">Food must be served at all catered events at the inn establishment at which alcoholic beverages are provided or sold.</section>
        </section>
        <section prefix="(xi)">
          <section prefix="1.">At no time may an inn be operated solely for the purpose of selling or providing alcoholic beverages.</section>
          <section prefix="2.">If an establishment ceases to be operated as an inn:</section>
        </section>
        <section prefix="(xii)">The Liquor Control Board shall adopt regulations to:<section prefix="1.">Implement the provisions of this paragraph; and</section><section prefix="2.">Ensure that the primary purpose of the special Class B (inn) license is to allow the holder of the license to operate an establishment as an inn.</section></section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(8)">
        <section prefix="(i)">There is a 7-day Class B-BB (bed and breakfast) on-sale beer, wine and liquor license that may be issued by the Liquor Control Board.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">To qualify for the issuance or reissuance of a Class B-BB license, the applicant's or the Class B-BB license holder's establishment, as appropriate, shall:<section prefix="1.">Provide services ordinarily provided by a bed and breakfast establishment;</section><section prefix="2.">Contain at least one room but not more than 10 rooms, each with sleeping accommodations, excluding resident management quarters, that the public for consideration may use for a specified time;</section><section prefix="3.">Be approved by the appropriate local government authority to operate as a bed and breakfast establishment; and</section><section prefix="4.">Have a kitchen facility that has been approved by the appropriate local government authority.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">The holder of a Class B-BB license may sell alcoholic beverages only:<section prefix="1.">For consumption on the premises during the hours and days that are allowed for a Class B on-sale beer, wine and liquor license issued in the county; and</section><section prefix="2.">To a guest whose name and address appears on the registry that is maintained by the establishment and who is an occupant of a sleeping room in the establishment.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(iv)">The holder of a Class B-BB license may not sell alcoholic beverages to a person who:<section prefix="1.">Is not a guest of the establishment; or</section><section prefix="2.">Is registered as a guest at the establishment only for the purpose of obtaining alcoholic beverages.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(v)">
          <section prefix="1.">Subject to the requirement of subsubparagraph 2 of this subparagraph, the Class B-BB license authorizes the holder of the license to keep for sale and sell beer, wine and liquor for on-premises consumption during catered events that are catered by the license holder at the bed and breakfast establishment if the license holder is under contract to cater the event.</section>
          <section prefix="2.">Food must be served at all catered events at the bed and breakfast establishment at which alcoholic beverages are provided or sold.</section>
        </section>
        <section prefix="(vi)">The annual license fee for a Class B-BB license is $1,000.</section>
        <section prefix="(vii)">
          <section prefix="1.">At no time may a bed and breakfast establishment be operated solely for the purpose of selling or providing alcoholic beverages.</section>
          <section prefix="2.">If an establishment ends operations as a bed and breakfast establishment:</section>
        </section>
        <section prefix="(viii)">The Liquor Control Board shall adopt regulations to:<section prefix="1.">Implement this paragraph; and</section><section prefix="2.">Ensure that the primary purpose of the Class B-BB license is to allow the holder of the license to operate an establishment as a bed and breakfast establishment.</section></section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(9)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The Liquor Control Board may issue a special Class BFD (fine dining) on-sale beer, wine and liquor license.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The license authorizes the licensee to serve only full-course dinners at least 5 days a week.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">A restaurant with a Class BFD license must open for business not later than 5 p.m. and comply with the requirements of &#xA7; 1-102(a)(22)(iii) of this article.</section>
        <section prefix="(iv)">The annual fees are:<section prefix="1.">$2,500 for a 6-day license, Monday through Saturday; and</section><section prefix="2.">$2,900 for a 7-day license.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(v)">The Liquor Control Board shall adopt rules to carry out this subsection.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(o)">In Howard County the annual fee is $1,000.</section>
    <section prefix="(p)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">This subsection applies only in Kent County.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">In this subsection, "Board" means the Board of License Commissioners.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The Board may issue a Class B beer, wine and liquor license for use in a restaurant.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">To qualify for licensure under this subsection, the restaurant shall:<section prefix="1.">Be fully equipped with a proper and adequate dining room;</section><section prefix="2.">Have sufficient facilities for preparing and serving meals to the public; and</section><section prefix="3.">Be approved by the Board.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">When operating under this license, a holder's average daily receipts from the sale of food shall comprise at least 60 percent of the average daily receipts of the business.</section>
        <section prefix="(iv)">The annual license fee under this subsection is $2,000.</section>
        <section prefix="(v)">On Sunday, the holder is authorized under the license to sell:<section prefix="1.">Beer, wine and liquor for consumption on-premises to a customer:</section><section prefix="2.">Only beer and light wine for consumption off the premises.</section></section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">In this subsection, "guest" means a person whose name and address appears on the registry that is maintained by the establishment and who is an occupant of a sleeping room in the establishment. "Guest" does not include a person who is registered solely for the purpose of obtaining alcoholic beverages.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">
          <section prefix="1.">The Board may issue a 7-day special Class B (bed and breakfast) on-sale beer, wine and liquor license.</section>
          <section prefix="2.">To qualify for a license under sub-subparagraph 1 of this paragraph, the applicant's establishment shall:</section>
          <section prefix="3.">A holder of a 7-day special Class B (bed and breakfast) license may sell beer, wine, and liquor to guests for consumption on the premises during the days and hours established for a Class B on-sale restaurant beer, wine and liquor license for Kent County under this article.</section>
          <section prefix="4.">The annual license fee is $350.</section>
          <section prefix="5.">The Board may adopt additional regulations consistent with this subsection.</section>
          <section prefix="6.">If the establishment ceases to be operated as a bed and breakfast, the license is void.</section>
        </section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">
          <section prefix="1.">The Board may issue a 7-day special Class B (country inn) on-sale beer, wine and liquor license.</section>
          <section prefix="2.">To qualify for a license under sub-subparagraph 1 of this paragraph, the applicant's establishment shall:</section>
          <section prefix="3.">The holder of a 7-day special Class B (country inn) license may sell beer, wine, and liquor to guests for consumption on the premises during the days and hours established for a Class B on-sale restaurant beer, wine and liquor license for Kent County under this article.</section>
          <section prefix="4.">The annual license fee is $550.</section>
          <section prefix="5.">The Board may adopt additional regulations consistent with this subsection.</section>
          <section prefix="6.">If the establishment ceases to be operated as a country inn, the license is void.</section>
        </section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(4)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The Board may issue a special Maryland Wine License Privilege.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">To qualify for a special Maryland Wine License Privilege, an applicant shall be a holder of a Class B (on-sale) beer and wine license or beer, wine and liquor license for use on a premises that qualifies as a restaurant under paragraph (2)(ii) of this subsection.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">A special Maryland Wine License Privilege authorizes the holder to sell wine by the bottle for off-sale without the cost of the wine counting as a part of the average daily receipts of the business required to meet the minimum 60 percent food sales requirement under paragraph (2)(iii) of this subsection.</section>
        <section prefix="(iv)">The annual fee for the special Maryland Wine License Privilege is $100.</section>
        <section prefix="(v)">The special Maryland Wine License Privilege is not a separate class of license but shall be considered part of the existing Class B (on-sale) beer and wine license or beer, wine and liquor license of the holder of the special Maryland Wine License Privilege.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(q)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">This subsection applies only in Montgomery County.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">
          <section prefix="1.">In this subsection the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
          <section prefix="2.">"Board" means the Board of License Commissioners.</section>
          <section prefix="3.">"Dining area" means the area occupied by patrons for the consumption of food and includes a cocktail area where food need not be served if there is no separate outdoor entrance to the cocktail area.</section>
        </section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">
          <section prefix="1.">The Board may issue this license only to the owner of any restaurant or hotel.</section>
          <section prefix="2.">The restaurant shall be located in the second, third, fourth, sixth, seventh, eighth, ninth, tenth, or thirteenth election districts.</section>
          <section prefix="3.">The licensee may not be located in the Towns of Poolesville, Takoma Park, and Kensington.</section>
        </section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">
          <section prefix="1.">As a prerequisite for the initial issuance of a license under this subsection, the owner shall attest in a sworn statement that gross receipts from food sales in the restaurant or hotel will be at least equal to the gross receipts from the sale of alcoholic beverages.</section>
          <section prefix="2.">As a prerequisite for each renewal of a license issued under this subsection, the owner shall attest in a sworn statement that the gross receipts from food sales in the restaurant or hotel for the 12-month period immediately preceding the application for renewal have been at least equal to the gross receipts from the sale of alcoholic beverages.</section>
          <section prefix="3.">The Board by regulation shall provide for periodic inspection of the premises and for audits to determine the ratio of gross receipts from the sale of food to gross receipts from the sale of alcoholic beverages.</section>
          <section prefix="4.">Any regulations adopted by the Board shall include a requirement of at least monthly physical inspections of the premises during the initial license year of any licensee and the submission by the licensee to the Board, during the initial license year, of monthly statements showing gross receipts from the sale of food and gross receipts from the sale of alcoholic beverages for the immediately preceding month.</section>
          <section prefix="5.">In the event that a licensee, during the initial license year, fails to maintain the sales ratio requirement provided in this paragraph for a period of three consecutive months or after the initial license year for each license or calendar year, the Board, in its discretion, may revoke the license. The Board may require any licensee to provide supporting data as it, in its discretion, deems necessary, in order to establish that the requirements of this section relating to the ratio of gross receipts from the sale of food to those from the sale of alcoholic beverages have been met.</section>
        </section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">A license issued under this subsection authorizes its holder to keep for sale and sell alcoholic beverages for consumption on the premises only, and alcoholic beverages may not be served to patrons or consumed at any bar, counter without seats, or other room but in the dining area. However, the seats in the cocktail area may not exceed 25 percent of the seats normally available for the general public in the dining area, including the cocktail area portion, but excluding special banquet and private party facilities.</section>
        <section prefix="(iv)">Signs visible from the exterior of the building, advertising the sale of alcoholic beverages, are not permitted in connection with any restaurant or hotel holding a license issued under the provisions of this section except for the display of the menu then in use by the licensee.</section>
        <section prefix="(v)">
          <section prefix="1.">The annual license fee is $2,500.</section>
          <section prefix="2.">For the third license that is not restricted by location and is obtained by a licensee under &#xA7; 9-102.1 of this article, the annual fee is $5,000.</section>
        </section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">There is a special Class B license known as Class B-BWL (H-M) which shall be issued only for hotels and motels that meet the minimum requirements set forth in subsection (a)(3) of this section. All of the privileges and restrictions provided for in paragraph (2) of this subsection are applicable to this special Class B license except that the gross receipts from the sale of alcoholic beverages may not exceed the gross receipts from the sale of food, and registered guests may be served in their rooms. In any instance where there is more than one licensed establishment within the hotel or motel, the foregoing sales ratio shall be applicable only to one license and that shall be the one that provides the food and beverage service to the conventions, banquets and other groups that utilize facilities within the hotel or motel.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The annual license fee is $2,500.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(4)">
        <section prefix="(i)">In this paragraph, "performing arts facility" means a facility that is used for artistic, corporate, and community related activities.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">There is a special Class B-BWL (performing arts facility) license.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">The Board of License Commissioners may issue a special Class B-BWL (performing arts facility) license to apply only to a performing arts facility that has:<section prefix="1.">A minimum capital investment, not including real property, of $1,000,000;</section><section prefix="2.">A minimum capacity of 1,500 persons; and</section><section prefix="3.">A food service facility permit and 40 seats in a food service area.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(iv)">The Board may issue a special Class B-BWL (performing arts facility) license for use by a not-for-profit partnership, limited liability company, corporation, or other entity that leases the performing arts facility to host artistic, corporate, and community related activities.</section>
        <section prefix="(v)">
          <section prefix="1.">A special Class B-BWL (performing arts facility) license authorizes the holder to sell beer, wine, and liquor by the drink from one or more outlets on the licensed premises for consumption on the licensed premises.</section>
          <section prefix="2.">A holder of a special Class B-BWL (performing arts facility) license may only exercise the privileges under the license from 10:00 a.m. on any day until 2:00 a.m. the following day.</section>
          <section prefix="3.">A holder of a special Class B-BWL (performing arts facility) license may not sell alcoholic beverages at:</section>
        </section>
        <section prefix="(vi)">The Board may impose conditions on the issuance or renewal of a special Class B-BWL (performing arts facility) license that establish the areas in the performing arts facility where beer, wine, and liquor may be sold, served, possessed, or consumed.</section>
        <section prefix="(vii)">The Board may not approve the transfer of a special Class B-BWL (performing arts facility) license to another location.</section>
        <section prefix="(viii)">The annual license fee for a special Class B-BWL (performing arts facility) license is $1,000.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(r)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">This subsection applies only in Prince George's County.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">
          <section prefix="1.">In this subsection the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
          <section prefix="2.">"Board" means the Board of License Commissioners.</section>
          <section prefix="3.">"Restaurant" means any establishment:</section>
        </section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">
          <section prefix="1.">The annual license fee is $1,455.</section>
          <section prefix="2.">The licensee may not make any sale of alcoholic beverages for consumption off the licensed premises except from the main bar and within the main portion of the dining room facilities.</section>
        </section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">
          <section prefix="1.">A separate license fee may be charged whenever the applicant for or holder of a Class B (on-sale) beer, wine and liquor license proposes to or in fact establishes and conducts on the licensed premises, an area or portion of these licensed premises, where there are maintained "off-sale" shelves or counters not contained within and an integral part of the main bar and in the main dining facilities where the majority of the meals are served and consumed in the licensed premises (whether enclosed or opened, partitioned or otherwise partly separated from the main bar or the usual serving area within these premises for the sale of alcoholic beverages for consumption on the premises and not part of the premises where the major portion of meals are served and consumed in these licensed premises) for the sale of alcoholic beverages for consumption off the licensed premises.</section>
          <section prefix="2.">The annual license fee is $2,420.</section>
        </section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">
          <section prefix="1.">The license holder under this subsection may sell alcoholic beverages for consumption off the premises from any portion of these premises other than from the main bar, or the usual place maintained for sale of alcoholic beverages for consumption on the premises and where the major portion of the meals are consumed in these premises.</section>
          <section prefix="2.">The annual license fee for this privilege is $2,420.</section>
        </section>
        <section prefix="(iv)">The number of licenses which are permitted to have any off-sale privileges referred to in this subsection are limited to those licenses having the permit and facilities on May 28, 1969.</section>
        <section prefix="(v)">Any interruption of restaurant facilities for any reason shall be reported to the Board promptly.</section>
        <section prefix="(vi)">Any drug, candy or confectionery store may not be construed to be a restaurant.</section>
        <section prefix="(vii)">On and after May 1, 1966, any new application for a beer, wine and liquor license, Class B may not be granted by the Board, and any transfer from one location to another location by the same license holder, and any transfer from one license holder to another at the same location, or from one license holder to another at a different location, may not be approved unless the establishment where it is proposed to locate or transfer the license meets the standards contained in this section.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">This license may be issued to any agricultural association, agricultural fair association or any other association duly authorized to conduct racing under the provisions of the Maryland Horse Racing Act where restaurant facilities are available or to duly authorized concessionaires of any association, or to any organization on any other day, exclusive of racing days, where the premises and facilities of this association are used for a limited period of time for legitimate theatrical productions, social receptions, and any bona fide entertainment conducted by any club, society or association, or for any bona fide religious, fraternal, civic, war veterans, hospital or charitable organizations upon payment of a license fee of $60 per day for the period of this license.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">At least one officer of the corporation or the concessionaire, whichever applies for the license, shall be a resident of the State of Maryland. The residency requirements specified in &#xA7; 9-101 of this article as it pertains to Prince George's County do not apply to an issuance, renewal or transfer of this license.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(4)">
        <section prefix="(i)">There is a special Class B license known as Class BH, which may be issued only to hotels.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The annual license fee is $5,000.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">In this paragraph "hotel" means an establishment:<section prefix="1.">Which is recognized as a hotel for the accommodation of the public providing services ordinarily found in hotels;</section><section prefix="2.">Which is equipped with:</section><section prefix="3.">Where the average daily receipts from the hire of rooms and the sale of food exceeds the average daily receipts from the sale of alcoholic beverages; and</section><section prefix="4.">Where the capital investment in the facility, including the building or buildings and all fixtures and systems contained therein and components thereof, parking compound, swimming pool and other recreational areas, landscaping, site preparation and improvements and infrastructure, engineering, architectural and other similar costs but excluding the cost of land furnishings and removable equipment and personal property, is not less than $30,000 per bedroom.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(iv)">Class BH licenses are subject to all other provisions pertaining to Class B beer, wine and liquor licenses, except that any restrictions against the sale of alcoholic beverages on Sunday appearing in &#xA7; 11-517 of this article and elsewhere in this article do not apply; and any alcoholic beverages may not be sold, served or consumed on the licensed premises on Sunday after 2 a.m. and before 10 a.m.</section>
        <section prefix="(v)">
          <section prefix="1.">In addition to the other privileges granted under this paragraph, a holder of a Class BH beer, wine and liquor (on-sale) license for hotel use may sell alcoholic beverages in sealed containers to hotel guests who are 21 years of age or older if:</section>
          <section prefix="2.">If a room is rented to a guest under 21 years of age, the hotel management is responsible for removing the bar key from the room.</section>
        </section>
        <section prefix="(vi)">The Board shall adopt regulations to establish compliance with the provisions of this paragraph.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(5)">
        <section prefix="(i)">There is a special Sunday "on-sale" permit.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The annual fee for a special Sunday "on-sale" permit is $850, which is in addition to the annual fee for the Class B beer, wine and liquor license to which it is attached.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">
          <section prefix="1.">The Board may issue to the holders of a Class B beer, wine and liquor license who meet the qualifications specified in paragraph (2) of this subsection a special Sunday "on-sale" permit to allow the holder to keep for sale and to sell at retail beer, wine and liquor on Sunday for consumption on the licensed premises.</section>
          <section prefix="2.">Sales may be made between the hours of 12 noon and 2 a.m. the following day.</section>
          <section prefix="3.">The average daily receipts from the sale of food shall equal 40 percent of the total daily receipts from the sale of "on-sale" food and alcoholic beverages in the establishments where it is proposed to locate this permit, and the ratio of food sales to the sale of alcoholic beverages has been maintained for at least 6 months prior to the application for this permit. For a newly licensed establishment the Board may immediately authorize the issuance of a special Sunday "on-sale" permit if in the opinion of the Board and upon good cause shown the newly licensed establishment meets the specifications of paragraph (2) of this subsection pertaining to the preparation, serving and sale of food and if the holder of the license complies with the provisions of this paragraph. Applicants for a special Sunday "on-sale" permit shall furnish the Board with any proof it considers necessary indicating the qualifications of the establishment to be issued this permit.</section>
        </section>
        <section prefix="(iv)">The holder of a special Sunday "on-sale" permit is subject to all other provisions of this article pertaining to Class B beer, wine and liquor licenses, except that any restrictions on the sale of alcoholic beverages on Sunday appearing in &#xA7; 11-517 of this article and elsewhere may not apply. Holders of this permit shall submit to the Board, from time to time at regular intervals to be established by the Board, a statement indicating in detail the ratio of food sales to the sales of alcoholic beverages. If the average daily receipts from the sale of food fail for 3 successive months to equal 40 percent of the total daily receipts from the sale of food and alcoholic beverages, the Board shall cancel this permit. Class B beer, wine and liquor licensees with a special Sunday "on-sale" permit and Class BH licensees may sell beer, wine and liquor by the drink from the bar or a cocktail lounge to persons on the licensed premises.</section>
        <section prefix="(v)">The Board may adopt regulations it considers necessary relating to the issuance, suspension, and cancellation of these permits in furtherance of this subsection.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(6)">
        <section prefix="(i)">There is a Class BLX license, which is a special Class B license.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The annual license fee is $3,025.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">
          <section prefix="1.">Class BLX licenses may be issued only to luxury type restaurants, a term which shall be defined by the regulations of the Board.</section>
          <section prefix="2.">The restaurant shall have a minimum capital investment of $1,000,000 for dining room facilities and kitchen equipment, which sum may not include the cost of land, buildings or a lease.</section>
          <section prefix="3.">The restaurant shall have a minimum seating capacity of 100 persons.</section>
          <section prefix="4.">The Board has complete discretion as to whom these licenses may be issued, the number to be issued, and whether an existing license holder of an alcoholic beverages license may also have an interest in one Class BLX license.</section>
          <section prefix="5.">Subject to sub-subparagraphs 6, 7, and 8 of this subparagraph, an individual or corporation may hold not more than 10 Class BLX licenses.</section>
          <section prefix="6.">A license holder may be issued a fifth BLX license only if the date of application for a fifth license is at least 1 year after the date the license holder was issued the fourth license.</section>
          <section prefix="7.">A license holder may be issued a sixth BLX license only if the date of application for a sixth license is at least 1 year after the date the license holder was issued the fifth license.</section>
          <section prefix="8.">In determining whether to issue a fifth, sixth, seventh, eighth, ninth, or tenth BLX license to a single license holder, the Board of License Commissioners for Prince George's County:</section>
          <section prefix="9.">This license is limited and restricted to the purpose of providing alcoholic beverages for consumption on the licensed premises only, with no off-sale privileges to be exercised.</section>
          <section prefix="10.">The residency requirements specified in &#xA7; 9-101 of this article as it pertains to Prince George's County do not apply to Class BLX licenses.</section>
        </section>
        <section prefix="(iv)">If the requirements under subparagraph (iii) of this paragraph are satisfied, the Board of License Commissioners may issue or transfer one Class BLX license on behalf of any of the following:<section prefix="1.">Prince George's County;</section><section prefix="2.">The Maryland-National Capital Park and Planning Commission; or</section><section prefix="3.">A private concessionaire under contract with either:</section></section>
        <section prefix="(v)">If a license is issued under subparagraph (iv) of this paragraph, the profit realized from the sale of alcoholic beverages under this license may be for the use and benefit of Prince George's County, the Maryland-National Capital Park and Planning Commission, or a concessionaire under contract as provided under subparagraph (iv) of this paragraph.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(7)">Repealed.</section>
      <section prefix="(8)">
        <section prefix="(i)">There is a Class BCE license.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The annual license fee is $3,630.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">The Board may issue a special Class B on-sale beer, wine and liquor license to be known as Class BCE which shall be issued only to catering establishments.</section>
        <section prefix="(iv)">A catering establishment shall be defined by the regulations of the Board which shall require that:<section prefix="1.">The catering establishment have a minimum capital investment of $500,000 for dining room facilities and kitchen equipment. This sum may not include the cost of land, buildings, or a lease; and</section><section prefix="2.">A minimum seating capacity of 150 persons.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(v)">The Board shall prescribe regulations pertaining to the hours and days of sale.</section>
        <section prefix="(vi)">Food shall be served with alcoholic beverages.</section>
        <section prefix="(vii)">A Class BCE license is limited and restricted to the purpose of providing alcoholic beverages for consumption on the licensed premises by participants of catered events only, and off-sale privileges may not be exercised.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(9)">
        <section prefix="(i)">There is a Class B/ECF license.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The annual fee is $4,325.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">
          <section prefix="1.">Notwithstanding the provisions of &#xA7; 9-217(e)(1) of this article, the Board may issue a Class B/ECF beer, wine and liquor license, to be known as an "educational conference facility" license, to the University of Maryland, University College Center of Adult Education.</section>
          <section prefix="2.">The licensee may sell beer, wine, and liquor by the drink within the Center, from one or more outlets, for consumption on the licensed premises to any person or persons authorized by the proper authority to use the Center. The application for this license shall be filed and processed in the normal manner.</section>
        </section>
        <section prefix="(iv)">The policies of the Center that pertain to the sponsorship of events where alcoholic beverages may be sold shall be filed with the application.</section>
        <section prefix="(v)">
          <section prefix="1.">The license shall be issued to the individual authorized by the University College Center of Adult Education of the University of Maryland to act for it, assume all responsibility, and be subject to all the penalties, conditions, and restrictions imposed upon licenses under this article. The individual shall be a resident and registered voter of Prince George's County.</section>
          <section prefix="2.">All profits from the sale of alcoholic beverages shall be deposited into the food services income fund.</section>
          <section prefix="3.">The residency requirements specified in &#xA7; 9-101 of this article as it pertains to Prince George's County do not apply to Class B/ECF licenses.</section>
        </section>
        <section prefix="(vi)">The Board shall prescribe regulations pertaining to the manner of dispensing alcoholic beverages, and the hours and days of sale authorized in &#xA7; 11-517 of this article. The licensee is subject to all the provisions of this article and to the regulations of the Board.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(10)">
        <section prefix="(i)">There is a special Class B license known as Class B-CI.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The annual license fee is $1,515.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">The Class B-CI license shall be issued only to country inns.</section>
        <section prefix="(iv)">A "country inn" means:<section prefix="1.">An establishment for the accommodation of the public equipped with a dining room with facilities for preparing and serving regular meals, wherein the average daily receipts from the sale of foods exceed the average daily receipts from the sale of alcoholic beverages, and which is located within:</section><section prefix="2.">In addition to the criteria in sub-subparagraph 1 of this subparagraph, a country inn must meet all the following criteria:</section><section prefix="3.">The Board may adopt regulations that specify additional standards and criteria not inconsistent with this section.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(v)">The Board may determine to whom these licenses shall be issued, the number to be issued, and whether an existing license holder of an alcoholic beverages license in Prince George's County may also have an interest in one Class B-CI license.</section>
        <section prefix="(vi)">A licensee may not hold more than two Class B-CI licenses.</section>
        <section prefix="(vii)">Class B-CI licenses are limited and restricted to the purpose of providing alcoholic beverages for consumption on the licensed premises only, with no off-sale privileges to be exercised therewith.</section>
        <section prefix="(viii)">The Board may not issue more than two Class B-CI licenses.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(11)">
        <section prefix="(i)">There is a Class B-ECR license.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The annual license fee is $2,420.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">In this paragraph "Commission" means the Maryland-National Capital Park and Planning Commission.</section>
        <section prefix="(iv)">
          <section prefix="1.">The Board may issue a special 7-day Class B-ECR (Equestrian Center restaurant) on-sale beer, wine and liquor license for the exclusive use on the premises of the Commission's Equestrian Center restaurant located within Prince George's County.</section>
          <section prefix="2.">The special 7-day Class B-ECR on-sale beer, wine and liquor license authorizes the sale of beer, wine, and liquor by the drink for consumption on the restaurant premises by the holder or a private concessionaire under contract with the holder to operate the licensed premises.</section>
        </section>
        <section prefix="(v)">
          <section prefix="1.">A special 7-day Class B-ECR on-sale beer, wine and liquor license shall be issued to the Commission for use in the Commission's Equestrian Center restaurant upon the Commission's making application and qualifying as a license holder under this article.</section>
          <section prefix="2.">The residency requirement under &#xA7; 9-101 of this article does not apply to an applicant for this license under this paragraph.</section>
        </section>
        <section prefix="(vi)">Any profit made from the sale of beer, wine, and liquor by the holder of a license issued pursuant to this paragraph may be for the use and benefit of the Commission.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(12)">
        <section prefix="(i)">There is a Class B-ECF/DS license.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The annual license fee is $7,425.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">The Board may issue a special Class B beer, wine and liquor (on-sale) license known as a Class B-Education Conference Facility/Dining Service license (Class B-ECF/DS license).</section>
        <section prefix="(iv)">A Class B-ECF/DS license may only be issued to an individual who is:<section prefix="1.">Authorized by the University of Maryland, College Park to act on its behalf under this license and be subject to the conditions, restrictions, and penalties under this article; and</section><section prefix="2.">A resident and registered voter of Prince George's County.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(v)">The residency requirement under &#xA7; 9-101 of this article does not apply to a license applicant under this paragraph.</section>
        <section prefix="(vi)">A Class B-ECF/DS license authorizes the holder to sell beer, wine, and liquor from multiple designated outlets on the University's campus only at University-related functions catered by the Department of Dining Services.</section>
        <section prefix="(vii)">
          <section prefix="1.">A Class B-ECF/DS license is restricted to on-sale privileges only.</section>
          <section prefix="2.">Any alcoholic beverages purchased at a designated outlet shall be consumed within the confines of that outlet and may not be transported to another outlet.</section>
        </section>
        <section prefix="(viii)">All profits from the retail sale of alcoholic beverages under this paragraph shall be deposited in the Dining Services Income Fund of the University of Maryland.</section>
        <section prefix="(ix)">The Board:<section prefix="1.">May regulate the manner in which alcoholic beverages are dispensed under a Class B-ECF/DS license;</section><section prefix="2.">Prior to the issuance of this license, shall designate the exact campus locations for the outlets for the sale of alcoholic beverages under this license;</section><section prefix="3.">Shall maintain a map and description of the designated outlets for verification upon the renewal of this license;</section><section prefix="4.">Shall require the Department of Dining Services of the University of Maryland, College Park to report to the Board at least 5 days in advance of all University-related catered functions at which beer, wine, or liquor is intended to be sold or served; and</section><section prefix="5.">Shall process this license in the same manner as any other license issued by the Board.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(x)">The hours and days of sale under this license are as provided under &#xA7; 11-517 of this article.</section>
        <section prefix="(xi)">The restriction on the distance between the location of a school and an alcoholic beverages licensed premises does not apply to a Class B-ECF/DS license.</section>
        <section prefix="(xii)">The general prohibition on the number of alcoholic beverages licenses for the same person or premises does not apply to a Class B-ECF/DS license.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(13)">
        <section prefix="(i)">There is a Class B beer, wine and liquor stadium license.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The annual license fee is $21,780.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">This license entitles the holder to sell beer, wine and liquor by the drink and by the bottle, from one or more outlets, for consumption on the licensed premises only.</section>
        <section prefix="(iv)">This is a 7-day license.</section>
        <section prefix="(v)">This license may be exercised only at the Redskins Stadium in Landover.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(14)">
        <section prefix="(i)">There is a Class B-MB/22 license, which may be issued only to a holder of a Class 7 micro-brewery license in the 22nd legislative district.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The annual license fee is $1,090.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">A Class B-MB/22 license entitles the holder to sell liquor by the drink for consumption on the premises only.</section>
        <section prefix="(iv)">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the holder of a Class B-MB/22 license may also hold a Class D license.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(15)">
        <section prefix="(i)">There is a Class B-DD (Development District) 7-day beer, wine and liquor license.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">Only on-sale consumption is permitted.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">The annual license fee is $3,025.</section>
        <section prefix="(iv)">A Class B-DD license may be issued only for a restaurant within any single area designated in &#xA7; 9-217(f)(7) of this article.</section>
        <section prefix="(v)">Ownership of a Class B-DD license may be transferred from one license holder to another if the license is to be used at the same location but may not be transferred for use at a different location.</section>
        <section prefix="(vi)">
          <section prefix="1.">The Board of License Commissioners shall determine the number of Class B-DD licenses to be issued, the persons to whom Class B-DD licenses are to be issued, and the number of licenses each recipient may hold.</section>
          <section prefix="2.">Notwithstanding subsubparagraph 1 of this subparagraph, the Board of License Commissioners may not issue a Class B-DD license to any restaurant located within a single area described in &#xA7; 9-217(f)(7) of this article, if, at the time of issuance:</section>
        </section>
        <section prefix="(vii)">
          <section prefix="1.">Notwithstanding any other provision of this article:</section>
          <section prefix="2.">Except as provided in subsubparagraph 3 of this subparagraph, the Class B license issued to a holder of a Class B-DD license for a restaurant in a development district under &#xA7; 9-217(f)(7) of this article remains in effect only as long as the restaurant in the development district remains open for business as a restaurant.</section>
          <section prefix="3.">If the restaurant in the development district is closed for not more than 6 months, the Class B license shall remain in effect.</section>
        </section>
        <section prefix="(viii)">A Class B-DD license may not be issued to a restaurant located within a chain store, supermarket, discount house, drug store, or convenience store.</section>
        <section prefix="(ix)">
          <section prefix="1.">A restaurant in a single area described in &#xA7; 9-217(f)(7) of this article is not eligible for a Class B-DD license unless:</section>
          <section prefix="2.">The Board of License Commissioners may revoke a license in order to enforce the provisions of this subparagraph.</section>
          <section prefix="3.">A license holder for a restaurant described in subsubparagraph 1 of this subparagraph shall submit a monthly report to the Board of License Commissioners of the restaurant's average daily receipts from the sale of food and nonalcoholic beverages and the restaurant's average daily receipts from the sale of alcoholic beverages to verify that the restaurant has met the requirements of subsubparagraph 1 of this subparagraph.</section>
        </section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(16)">
        <section prefix="(i)">In this paragraph, "theme park" means an entertainment complex that includes roller coasters and other rides, shows, a water park, restaurants, and shops.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">There is a Class B (TP) beer, wine and liquor theme park license.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">The annual license fee is $4,290.</section>
        <section prefix="(iv)">The license privileges may be exercised only at a theme park in Mitchellville.</section>
        <section prefix="(v)">The license entitles the holder to sell beer, wine, and liquor by the drink within the theme park, from one or more outlets, for consumption on the licensed premises only.</section>
        <section prefix="(vi)">The license is a 7-day license.</section>
        <section prefix="(vii)">To receive the license, the applicant shall file:<section prefix="1.">An application on a form that the Board of License Commissioners provides; and</section><section prefix="2.">The policies of the theme park for the sponsorship of special events held when the theme park is closed to the public and alcoholic beverages are sold.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(viii)">The Board shall adopt regulations relating to the dispensing of alcoholic beverages and the days and hours of sale.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(17)">
        <section prefix="(i)">There is a Class B-CC (convention center) beer, wine and liquor license.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">A Class B-CC license may be issued only to an establishment  that is recognized as a hotel for the accommodation of the public that provides services ordinarily provided in hotels and that is equipped with:<section prefix="1.">At least 1,500 bedrooms;</section><section prefix="2.">At least three dining areas with facilities for preparing and serving regular meals;</section><section prefix="3.">Rooms for meetings, displays, banquets, balls, dancing, and live entertainment; and</section><section prefix="4.">A bar and entertainment or dancing area commonly recognized as a nightclub.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">The annual license fee is $22,000.</section>
        <section prefix="(iv)">The total average daily receipts from the hire of meeting rooms, bedrooms, and the sale of food of a Class B-CC licensed establishment shall exceed the average daily receipts from the sale of alcoholic beverages.</section>
        <section prefix="(v)">The hours during which alcoholic beverages may be served at a Class B-CC licensed establishment are from 6 a.m. until 3 a.m. the next morning, 7 days a week.</section>
        <section prefix="(vi)">
          <section prefix="1.">Except as provided in subsubparagraph 2 of this subparagraph, alcoholic beverages may be sold from a locked, prestocked private bar in an individual guest room if the charges for the alcoholic beverages sold are indicated on the guest room bill.</section>
          <section prefix="2.">The management of the establishment shall remove the bar key from any room that is rented to a guest under the age of 21 years.</section>
        </section>
        <section prefix="(vii)">Alcoholic beverages may be sold for consumption on the premises throughout the licensed establishment, both indoors and outdoors, including meeting and banquet rooms, patios, verandas, quays, and green spaces.</section>
        <section prefix="(viii)">Dancing and live entertainment are authorized throughout the licensed establishment.</section>
        <section prefix="(ix)">This paragraph does not preclude a holder of a Class B-CC license from having an interest in other alcoholic beverages licenses in the county.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(18)">
        <section prefix="(i)">There is a Class B-AE (arts and entertainment) beer, wine and liquor license.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">A Class B-AE license may be issued only to an establishment in the Prince George's County arts and entertainment district as approved by the County Council in Council Resolution CR-83-2001.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">The license authorizes the holder to sell beer, wine, and liquor for consumption on the licensed premises only.</section>
        <section prefix="(iv)">A person may not hold more than 2 Class B-AE licenses.</section>
        <section prefix="(v)">The annual license fee is $2,750.</section>
        <section prefix="(vi)">The Board of License Commissioners shall adopt regulations to carry out this paragraph, including regulations specifying hours and days of sale.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(19)">
        <section prefix="(i)">A license holder that seeks to provide entertainment is not required to obtain a permit under this paragraph if:<section prefix="1.">The license is issued under paragraph (3), (9), (10), (11), (12), (13), (16), or (17) of this subsection or &#xA7; 5-201(r)(4) of this article;</section><section prefix="2.">The Board of License Commissioners determines that the holder's principal business is to provide family entertainment;</section><section prefix="3.">The license is a Class B (on-sale) license issued for a restaurant, and the license holder provides entertainment for adults and children that:</section><section prefix="4.">The license is a veterans or fraternal Class C license, and the license holder provides entertainment that:</section></section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">There is a special entertainment permit that the Board may issue to a holder of any Class B (on-sale) license in accordance with this paragraph.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">The Board shall determine the number of days in a week that a permit holder may exercise the privileges of the permit.</section>
        <section prefix="(iv)">
          <section prefix="1.">Before approving an application for and issuing a permit under this paragraph, the Board shall hold a public hearing in accordance with the requirements for a public hearing on an application for a license under &#xA7; 10-202(i) of this article.</section>
          <section prefix="2.">At the public hearing, the Board shall give the applicant, supporters of the applicant, and opponents of the applicant an opportunity to be heard.</section>
          <section prefix="3.">In making its determination whether to approve the application and issue the permit, the Board shall consider whether:</section>
          <section prefix="4.">The Board shall hold a similar public hearing on receipt of a petition to:</section>
        </section>
        <section prefix="(v)">
          <section prefix="1.">The permit authorizes the holder that complies with all requirements under county law, including zoning and use and occupancy laws and regulations, to impose a cover charge, offer facilities for patron dancing, and provide entertainment.</section>
          <section prefix="2.">The permit is valid after 9 p.m. until 2 a.m. the following day.</section>
        </section>
        <section prefix="(vi)">Before being issued a permit, an applicant shall:<section prefix="1.">Submit evidence to the satisfaction of the Board that:</section><section prefix="2."/></section>
        <section prefix="(vii)">
          <section prefix="1.">The Chief of the Prince George's County Police Department may submit comments to the Board on the adequacy of the security plan within 30 days after receipt of the plan.</section>
          <section prefix="2.">The Board shall consider the comments, if any, of the Chief of Police and subsequently issue the permit, refuse to issue the permit, or condition the issuance of the permit on changes to the security plan.</section>
          <section prefix="3.">If the Board issues the permit with a security plan that the Chief of the Prince George's County Police Department does not support, the Board shall specify in writing to the Chief the reasons why the Board has determined that the security plan is adequate.</section>
          <section prefix="4.">Each permit holder shall follow the approved security plan at all times when the permit holder exercises the privileges of the permit.</section>
        </section>
        <section prefix="(viii)">A holder of the permit:<section prefix="1.">Shall implement the security plan; and</section><section prefix="2.">When the privileges authorized by the permit are being exercised, may not allow an individual who is under the age of 21 years on the premises for which the permit is issued, unless the individual is employed by or is an immediate family member of the holder.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(ix)">The Board at any time may prohibit, condition, or restrict the type of entertainment offered by a holder of the permit, including lewd, exotic, loud, or raucous entertainment, if after a hearing the Board determines that the entertainment adversely impacts or unduly disturbs the community and is not conducive to the peace, health, welfare, or safety of the residents of the County.</section>
        <section prefix="(x)">The annual fee for the permit is $1,500, which is in addition to the annual fee for the Class B license.</section>
        <section prefix="(xi)">A permit holder may employ sworn security personnel as part of the security plan if the sworn security personnel have full police powers in the jurisdiction where the premises of the permit holder is located.</section>
        <section prefix="(xii)">
          <section prefix="1.">The circuit court may issue a temporary restraining order to immediately close to the public the entire operation of the premises if the County establishes that the security plan has not been implemented and that the public health, safety, or welfare requires emergency action.</section>
          <section prefix="2.">On issuance of a temporary restraining order under subsubparagraph 1 of this subparagraph, the County shall give the permit holder written notice of and reasons for the closure.</section>
          <section prefix="3.">The permit holder promptly shall be given an opportunity for a hearing in circuit court on the granting of the temporary restraining order in accordance with Title 15, Chapter 500 of the Maryland Rules.</section>
        </section>
        <section prefix="(xiii)">Subject to subparagraph (xiv) of this paragraph, the Board may immediately suspend a permit if the Board reasonably believes that the permit holder:<section prefix="1.">Violated this paragraph; or</section><section prefix="2.">Is not in compliance with a county zoning property standard or use and occupancy requirement.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(xiv)">If the Board immediately suspends a permit, the Board shall:<section prefix="1.">Give the permit holder notice of the suspension and a hearing on the suspension at which the permit holder may be heard and present evidence; and</section><section prefix="2.">Hold the hearing within 30 days after the suspension is imposed.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(xv)">At the hearing, the Board shall determine:<section prefix="1.">Whether the permit holder violated this paragraph or other law; and</section><section prefix="2.">If a violation occurred, what penalty to impose among those listed in subparagraphs (xvi) and (xvii) of this paragraph.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(xvi)">Subject to subparagraph (xvii) of this paragraph, if the Board finds that a person has violated this paragraph, the Board:<section prefix="1.">May revoke or continue the suspension of the permit; and</section><section prefix="2.">Shall impose on the person a penalty of:</section></section>
        <section prefix="(xvii)">The Board:<section prefix="1.">Shall revoke the permit of a person who the Boarddetermines violated this paragraph twice within a 24-month period; and</section><section prefix="2.">Until at least 12 months after the order of revocation was issued, may not consider an application from the person for a new permit or an application for a new permit for the premises that was the subject of the revocation.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(xviii)">If the Board determines that the permit holder did not violate this paragraph, the Board shall immediately reinstate the permit.</section>
        <section prefix="(xix)">The Board of License Commissioners shall adopt regulations to carry out this paragraph.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(s)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This subsection applies only in Queen Anne's County.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The annual license fee is $1,000.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">This license provides for the consumption of wine and liquor on the premises only.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The Board of License Commissioners may issue a Class B beer, wine and liquor on-sale license for use in a conference center.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The annual fee is $1,500.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">To qualify for a license under this paragraph, the conference center shall have the following facilities to accommodate at least 100 persons:<section prefix="1.">A kitchen facility;</section><section prefix="2.">A dining facility; and</section><section prefix="3.">Overnight facilities.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(iv)">The holder may sell beer, wine, and liquor for on-premises consumption to persons attending an event at the conference center.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(t)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This subsection applies only to hotel/restaurant and restaurant licenses in St. Mary's County.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">There is a Class B beer, wine and liquor hotel/restaurant license.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The annual license fee is $1,000.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">This license may be issued to a bona fide hotel that:<section prefix="1.">Is an establishment for the accommodation of the public providing services ordinarily found in hotels; and</section><section prefix="2.">Is equipped with not fewer than 25 rooms, a lobby with a registration and mail desk and seating facilities, and a dining room that serves full-course meals at least twice daily.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(iv)">A hotel/restaurant license does not permit sales of alcoholic beverages for consumption off the premises.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">There is a Class B beer, wine and liquor restaurant license.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The annual license fee is $650.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(u)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This subsection applies only in Somerset County.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The annual license fee is $1,265 for a restaurant or for a hotel.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">This license may be issued to any bona fide hotel or motel which:<section prefix="(i)">Is an establishment for the accommodation of the public providing services ordinarily found in hotels or motels;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Has a lobby with registration and mail desk and seating facilities;</section><section prefix="(iii)">In the case of a hotel or motel in existence and operated as such on June 1, 1967, maintains not fewer than ten rooms for occupancy by guests; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">In the case of a hotel or motel not in existence and operated as such on June 1, 1967, maintains not fewer than 20 rooms for occupancy by guests and is operated in facilities which are assessed for State and county taxation at not less than $45,000.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">This license may be issued to a restaurant which meets the following requirements and conditions:<section prefix="(i)">Serves full-course meals at least twice daily;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Has a regular seating capacity at tables (not including seats at bars or counters) for 50 or more persons; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Has had daily average receipts from the sale of food in excess of those for the sale of alcoholic beverages, during the 12-month period immediately preceding the application for the license.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(5)">Every hotel or restaurant shall purchase all wines and liquor sold by them from the Somerset County Liquor Control Board and shall be charged the invoice price of it to the Liquor Control Board, plus freight charges on it and plus a sum not to exceed 20 percent of the aggregate invoice price and freight charges.</section>
      <section prefix="(6)">This license provides for the consumption of wine and liquor on the premises only.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(v)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This subsection applies only in Talbot County.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The annual license fee is $1,000.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">A license may be issued to bona fide hotels having 25 or more bedrooms located under one roof regularly serving meals or any restaurant seating at least 50 persons and which restaurant can show that at least 60 percent of the gross income is derived from the sale of food, notwithstanding the other requirements of this article, and otherwise complying with the provisions of this article.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">Any sale of liquor as provided for may not exceed one quart and sales may not be made at bars or counters. This license for a restaurant does not cover "package sales" or any other form of "off-sale" alcoholic beverages.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The hours and days for sale are from 7 a.m. to 1 a.m. the following day, Monday through Saturday.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(w)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This subsection applies only in Washington County.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The annual license fee is $1,000.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">There is a Class B-theater license.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The annual license fee is $200.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">The Board of License Commissioners may issue a Class B beer, wine and liquor on-sale license for use in a theater.</section>
        <section prefix="(iv)">To qualify for a license under this paragraph the theater shall:<section prefix="1.">Be operated by a nonprofit organization;</section><section prefix="2.">Appear on the National Register of Historic Places;</section><section prefix="3.">Accommodate at least 1,400 persons; and</section><section prefix="4.">Be located on the south side of Hagerstown.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(v)">The holder of a license issued under this paragraph is authorized to sell beer, wine, and liquor for on-premises consumption only to persons who are attending a performance or an event that is held at the theater.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(x)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This subsection applies only in Wicomico County.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">This paragraph applies solely to hotel and restaurant licenses.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The annual license fee is:<section prefix="1.">For a restaurant - $1,320; and</section><section prefix="2.">For a hotel - $1,980.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">
          <section prefix="1.">This license may be issued to a bona fide hotel which:</section>
          <section prefix="2.">A hotel license does not permit sales for consumption off the premises.</section>
        </section>
        <section prefix="(iv)">
          <section prefix="1.">This license may be issued only to a restaurant that:</section>
          <section prefix="2.">The seating does not affect present Class B beer, wine and liquor licensees.</section>
          <section prefix="3.">This license requires the sale of alcoholic beverages for consumption only on the inside of the restaurant premises. A person may not enter or egress the premises while in possession of any alcoholic beverages.</section>
        </section>
        <section prefix="(v)">
          <section prefix="1.">Except for the purchase of beer and light wine, the holder shall purchase all of the alcoholic beverages that are sold for consumption on the premises from the county dispensary.</section>
          <section prefix="2.">The county dispensary may not charge the holder more than 15 percent above the wholesale operation cost to the dispensary for each item that the holder purchases.</section>
        </section>
        <section prefix="(vi)">
          <section prefix="1.">"Lounge area" means a room or area that includes:</section>
          <section prefix="2.">The holder of this license may prohibit a person under the legal drinking age in the State from entering the lounge area on the licensed premises after 9:00 p.m., unless this person is accompanied by a parent or legal guardian who is of the legal drinking age in the State.</section>
          <section prefix="3.">The holder of this license may charge an entertainment fee for each person who enters or who is present during the time live entertainment is in progress in the lounge area.</section>
        </section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">There is a Class B-Conference Center license.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The annual license fee is $1,500.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">The conference center shall have a minimum capacity of 500 persons and the following facilities:<section prefix="1.">Kitchen;</section><section prefix="2.">Dining; and</section><section prefix="3.">Meeting space.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(iv)">Licensees may sell beer, wine and liquor for on-premises consumption to persons attending an event at the conference center.</section>
        <section prefix="(v)">An existing Class B license may be amended to one for conference center use.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(4)">
        <section prefix="(i)">There is a Class B special wine (B-SWL) (off-sale) license.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">A holder of a license under this paragraph may sell wine for consumption off the licensed premises.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">
          <section prefix="1.">The Board of License Commissioners may issue a license under this paragraph only to a holder of a Class B beer, wine and liquor (7-day) (on-sale) license that is issued for a restaurant.</section>
          <section prefix="2.">The term of a license under this paragraph that is issued to a successful applicant shall be the same as that of the Class B beer, wine and liquor license held by the applicant.</section>
        </section>
        <section prefix="(iv)">A holder of a license under this paragraph at a minimum shall offer for sale 5 days per week:<section prefix="1.">Breakfast and lunch;</section><section prefix="2.">Breakfast and dinner; or</section><section prefix="3.">Lunch and dinner.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(v)">The meals shall be described in a printed menu.</section>
        <section prefix="(vi)">The area used for the preparation and consumption of food and beverages shall occupy at least 80% of the total square foot area of the licensed premises.</section>
        <section prefix="(vii)">An applicant for a license under this paragraph shall complete the form that the Board of License Commissioners provides.</section>
        <section prefix="(viii)">Advertising, posting of notice, and public hearing requirements for a license under this paragraph are the same as those for other Class B licenses.</section>
        <section prefix="(ix)">The annual license fee is $1,500.</section>
        <section prefix="(x)">Off-sale alcoholic beverages receipts shall be included in the calculation of average daily receipts from the sale of alcoholic beverages under paragraph (2)(iv)1D of this subsection.</section>
        <section prefix="(xi)">Subject to subparagraph (xii) of this paragraph, the hours for sale for a license under this paragraph are:<section prefix="1.">10 a.m. to midnight, Monday through Saturday; and</section><section prefix="2.">12:30 p.m. to midnight on Sunday.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(xii)">A license holder may exercise the privileges of a license under this paragraph only if the licensed premises is open for business as a restaurant.</section>
        <section prefix="(xiii)">Wine sold under a license under this paragraph shall have a maximum alcohol content of 15.5%.</section>
        <section prefix="(xiv)">The Board of License Commissioners may adopt regulations to carry out this subsection, including a limit on the number of licenses to be issued.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(y)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This subsection applies only in Worcester County.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The annual license fees for the following types of licenses are:<section prefix="(i)">Six-day licenses - $1,750; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Seven-day licenses - $2,500.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Hotels and restaurants are defined to be:<section prefix="(i)">For six-day license holders:<section prefix="1.">Bona fide hotels having at least 20 rooms and serving meals regularly; or</section><section prefix="2.">Restaurants having a seating capacity at tables of at least 70 people.</section></section><section prefix="(ii)">For seven-day license holders:<section prefix="1.">As required for six-day license holders, which are incorporated by reference; and</section><section prefix="2."/></section><section prefix="(iii)">A license may not be issued unless the hotel or restaurant is operated in a clean and sanitary manner and is equipped with the proper restroom facilities.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">Seven-day license holders may sell beer, wine and liquor (on-sale) and beer and light wine (off-sale).</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">If the premises to be licensed by the provisions of this subsection are within a municipal corporation, the license application may be subject to approval by its mayor and town council and shall be approved by the licensing authority.</section>
      <section prefix="(6)">All license fees shall go to the general funds of the county. However, if the licensed premises are in a municipal corporation, 75 percent of the fees shall go to that municipal corporation.</section>
      <section prefix="(7)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Except as provided in subparagraph (ii) of this paragraph, all licensees shall purchase all wines and liquors, except light wine and beer, from the Worcester County Department of Liquor Control. They shall be charged not more than 85 percent of the retail price or any special sale price or discount price, whichever is lower, set by the Department for wines and liquors. All licensees may purchase beer and light wine from licensed wholesalers.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">Beginning on May 1, 2016, a licensee may elect to purchase wine and liquor from a licensed wholesaler under &#xA7; 15-204(e) of this article.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(8)">The hours for sale are as provided in &#xA7; 11-524 of this article.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
