<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="g2b" order_by="2" level="1">Alcoholic Beverages</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>g2b-6-703</section_number>
  <catch_line>This section only applies in Carroll County....</catch_line>
  <order_by>703</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">This section only applies in Carroll County.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Board" means the Carroll County Board of License Commissioners.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Caterer" means an establishment containing one or more banquet rooms suitable for public gatherings, with food preparation facilities on the premises, which contracts to provide food and alcoholic beverages to sponsors of public or private events.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A Class H beer, wine and liquor license shall be issued by the Board which authorizes the owner or operator of a catering establishment to keep for sale and sell all alcoholic beverages at retail at the premises described in the license for consumption on the premises.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The annual license fee is the amount set for a Class B beer, wine and liquor license in &#xA7; 6-201 of this article.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The fee shall be paid to the Board before any license is issued. The fee shall be distributed as provided in this article.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A caterer licensed under this section also may contract with patrons to permit them to bring personal alcoholic beverages onto the premises of the caterer for consumption at catered events.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">A hotel or restaurant which holds a Class B beer, wine and liquor license need not obtain a Class H license if catering is, or has been, a part of the service provided by the hotel or restaurant. Any caterer holding a Class B beer, wine and liquor license shall automatically be issued a Class H liquor license, without any additional charge to the caterer for the license so issued, and the Class B license held by the caterer shall be surrendered upon receipt of the Class H license.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">There is a Class HC license.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Board may issue a Class HC caterer's (on- and limited off-sale) beer, wine and liquor license to an applicant who holds a Class H caterer's beer, wine and liquor license.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A Class HC caterer's licensee may sell:<section prefix="(i)">Beer, wine, and liquor, 7 days a week, on the premises for on-premises consumption; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Beer, wine, and liquor, 7 days a week, at catered events held off the premises for consumption on-premises at the event.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">A Class HC licensee shall provide food in addition to alcoholic beverages for consumption at the catered event.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">The annual license fee is $250 more than the annual fee for a Class B hotel or restaurant (on- and off-sale) beer, wine and liquor license.</section>
      <section prefix="(6)">The hours and days for sale for a Class HC licensee are the same as for a Class B hotel and restaurant (on- and off-sale) beer, wine and liquor licensee.</section>
      <section prefix="(7)">A Class HC licensee may hold only eight events in any calendar year that are self-sponsored. Pursuant to regulations adopted by the Board, these events may be held only at a location approved by the Board and on dates approved by the Board.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
