<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="g2b" order_by="2" level="1">Alcoholic Beverages</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>g2b-6-713</section_number>
  <catch_line>This section applies only in Dorchester County....</catch_line>
  <order_by>713</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">This section applies only in Dorchester County.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Dorchester County Board of License Commissioners may issue a Class B caterer's license to a licensee who:<section prefix="(1)">Holds a Class B restaurant or hotel (on-sale) beer and light wine license or Class B restaurant or hotel (on-sale) beer, wine and liquor license;</section><section prefix="(2)">Holds a caterer's license issued by the county health department; and</section><section prefix="(3)">Contracts to provide food and alcoholic beverages to sponsors of public or private events.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The annual license fee is $150.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A Class B caterer's license authorizes the holder to provide alcoholic beverages at events that are held off the premises covered by the Class B beer and light wine license or Class B beer, wine and liquor license.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A holder of a Class B beer and light wine license or a Class B beer, wine and liquor license need not have a Class B caterer's license for catering on the premises that is covered by the holder's license.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The Board of License Commissioners need not publish an application for a Class B caterer's license before issuing the license.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The holder of a Class B caterer's license:<section prefix="(1)">Shall notify the Board in writing at least 7 days before the event for which the license is to be used;</section><section prefix="(2)">Shall provide food as well as alcoholic beverages for consumption at the catered event; and</section><section prefix="(3)">May exercise the privileges of the license only during the hours and days that are authorized for the holder's Class B beer and light wine license or Class B beer, wine and liquor license.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(g)">When catering a public event, a holder of a Class B caterer's license:<section prefix="(1)">Shall distribute a wristband to each individual at least 21 years old at the catered event; and</section><section prefix="(2)">May not serve an alcoholic beverage to an individual at the catered event who does not wear the wristband.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
