<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="g2b" order_by="2" level="1">Alcoholic Beverages</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>g2b-5-202</section_number>
  <catch_line>This section applies only in the following counties:...</catch_line>
  <order_by>202</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">This section applies only in the following counties:<section prefix="(1)">Anne Arundel County;</section><section prefix="(2)">Caroline County;</section><section prefix="(3)">Charles County; and</section><section prefix="(4)">Montgomery County.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A Class H beer and light wine license shall be issued by the license issuing authority of the county in which the place of business is located. The license authorizes the holder to keep for sale and sell beer and light wines at retail at any hotel or restaurant, at the place described in the license, for consumption on the premises.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The annual fee shall be paid to the local collecting agent before any license is issued, for distribution as provided in this article.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">This paragraph applies only in Anne Arundel County.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">A license may not be issued to, or for use in conjunction with, or upon the premises of any restaurant located within a bowling alley, drugstore or billiard hall or for use upon any premises which has a door, archway, opening or other passageway providing direct public access to any bowling alley, billiard hall or drugstore.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">This paragraph applies only in Montgomery County.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">A license may not be issued to, or for use in conjunction with, or upon the premises of any restaurant located within a drugstore or for use upon any premises which has a door, archway, opening or other passageway providing direct public access to any drugstore.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">A license may be issued to, or for use in conjunction with or on the premises of, a restaurant located within a bowling alley if the gross receipts from the sale of alcoholic beverages do not exceed the gross receipts from the sale of food.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">In Anne Arundel County the annual license fee is $360.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">In Caroline County the annual license fee is $500.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">In Charles County the annual license fee is $240.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">In Montgomery County the annual license fee is $400.</section>
  </text>
</law>
