<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="g2b" order_by="" level="1">Alcoholic Beverages</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>g2b-10-207</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>207</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The fee for every license issued for a period of less than one year (except temporary or special licenses) shall be subject to the annual fee if issued during the first three months of the license year, three fourths of the annual fee if issued during the second quarter of the license year, one half of the annual fee if issued during the third quarter of the license year and one fourth of the annual license fee if issued during the fourth quarter of the license year.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">In Queen Anne's County all licenses shall be issued for twelve or six months only, and for no other periods of time; all twelve months licenses shall be granted to begin from the first day of May in the year of their issue, and all six months licenses shall be granted to begin from the first day of November in the year of their issue; provided, however, that when such licenses are issued for a period of six months, one half only of the annual fee herein provided for shall be charged. In cases of undue hardship, the Board of License Commissioners may refund a portion of any license it has granted.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">In Kent County all licenses shall be issued only for six or twelve month periods, to begin from the first day of May in the year of their issue, and shall be claimed by the applicant within 30 days after renewal or issue. If the license is not claimed by the applicant within 30 days after issue or renewal of the license, the license is null and void. When a six month license is issued, only one half of the annual fee shall be charged. Nothing in this subsection may be construed to prevent a holder of a six month license from applying for a renewal of that license pursuant to the procedure set forth in &#xA7; 10-301 of this title.</section>
  </text>
</law>
