<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="g2b" order_by="" level="1">Alcoholic Beverages</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>g2b-8-216.1</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>216.1</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">There is a special theater license.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Board" means the Montgomery County Board of License Commissioners.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Movie theater" means a building designed or used primarily for the exhibition of motion pictures to the general public.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">
        <section prefix="(i)">"Performing arts theater" means those areas, buildings, or structures designed and used for plays, acts, dramas, or histrionics by actors or actresses performing on a stage.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">"Performing arts theater" does not include either the showing or exhibition of motion pictures or a building or amphitheater that is part of a sports complex regularly used by minors.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Board may issue a special theater (on-sale) beer and wine license for use on the premises of:<section prefix="(1)">A performing arts theater; or</section><section prefix="(2)">A movie theater operated by a bona fide nonprofit organization.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Notwithstanding any other provision of this article to the contrary, a holder of a special theater license is authorized to sell beer and wine at retail for on-premises consumption when snacks are served:<section prefix="(1)">1 hour before and after a performance;</section><section prefix="(2)">During intermissions; and</section><section prefix="(3)">During cast parties and receptions before and after a performance.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The annual license fee is $100.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">A special theater (on-sale) beer and wine license may not be transferred from the location of original issuance to another location.</section>
  </text>
</law>
