<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="g2b" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="6-709" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>g2b-6-709</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This section applies only in Washington County.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">In this section, "Board" means the Board of License Commissioners.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Board may issue a caterer's license to a holder of a pouring license or a Class B restaurant or hotel (on and off-sale) beer, wine and liquor license.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The annual license fee is $1,500.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A caterer's license issued under this section authorizes the holder to provide alcoholic beverages at events that are held off the premises covered by the pouring license or the Class B restaurant or hotel license.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The holder shall prepare, deliver, and provide food as well as alcoholic beverages for consumption at the catered event.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">Before a caterer's license may be issued, reissued, or renewed, the county health department shall approve the facilities that prepare the food.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">A holder may exercise the privileges under this license only during the hours and days that are allowed under this article for the underlying pouring license or Class B restaurant or hotel license.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">This section does not require a holder of an existing pouring license or Class B restaurant or hotel license to have a caterer's license for catering on the premises that is covered by the existing license.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">The holder of a caterer's license shall:<section prefix="(1)">Provide all the service employees to serve the alcoholic beverages at the catered event; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Ensure that at least one of those employees is   certified by an alcohol awareness program and  on the premises at all times during the catered event.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
