<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="g2b" order_by="" level="1">Alcoholic Beverages</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>g2b-5-301</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>301</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in subsection (n) of this section, a Class C beer and light wine license shall be issued by the license issuing authority of the county in which the place of business is located. The holder of the license may keep for sale and sell beer and light wines at retail to bona fide members and their guests, at any club, at the place described in the license, for consumption on the premises only.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The annual fee for the license shall be paid to the local collecting agent before any license is issued, for distribution as provided.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This subsection applies only in Allegany County.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The annual license fee is $150.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Beer and light wines may be sold for consumption on the premises or elsewhere.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">In Anne Arundel County the annual license fee is $120.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">In Baltimore City the annual license fee is $82.50.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">In Baltimore County the annual license fee is $150.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">This section does not apply in Calvert County.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">This section does not apply in Caroline County.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">In Carroll County the annual license fee is $70.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">In Cecil County the annual license fee is $100.</section>
    <section prefix="(j)">This section does not apply in Charles County.</section>
    <section prefix="(k)">In Dorchester County the annual license fee is $150.</section>
    <section prefix="(l)">In Frederick County the annual license fee is $70.</section>
    <section prefix="(m)">This section does not apply in Garrett County.</section>
    <section prefix="(n)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This subsection applies only in Harford County.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The Liquor Control Board may issue a 6-day, Monday through Saturday, or a 7-day Class C-1 beer and light wine license for the sale of beer and light wine for consumption on the premises only to a bona fide not for profit association or corporation that:<section prefix="1.">Is organized for patriotic or war veterans purposes; and</section><section prefix="2.">Has held regular meetings at an established headquarters for a period of 1 year prior to the application for the license.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">
          <section prefix="1.">The annual fee for a 6-day license under this paragraph is $150.</section>
          <section prefix="2.">The annual fee for a 7-day license under this paragraph is $225.</section>
        </section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The Liquor Control Board may issue a 6-day, Monday through Saturday, or a 7-day Class C-2 beer and light wine license for the sale of beer and light wine for consumption on the premises only to a bona fide not for profit association or corporation that:<section prefix="1.">Is organized for fraternal purposes; and</section><section prefix="2.">Has held regular meetings at an established headquarters for a period of 1 year prior to the application for the license.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">
          <section prefix="1.">The annual fee for a 6-day license under this paragraph is $350.</section>
          <section prefix="2.">The annual fee for a 7-day license under this paragraph is $425.</section>
        </section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(4)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The Liquor Control Board may issue a 6-day, Monday through Saturday, or a 7-day Class C-3 beer and light wine license for the sale of beer and light wine for consumption on the premises only to a bona fide not for profit association or corporation that:<section prefix="1.">Is organized for social, educational, or athletic purposes; and</section><section prefix="2.">Has held regular meetings at an established headquarters for a period of 1 year prior to the application for the license.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">
          <section prefix="1.">The annual fee for a 6-day license under this paragraph is $450.</section>
          <section prefix="2.">The annual fee for a 7-day license under this paragraph is $525.</section>
        </section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(o)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This subsection applies only in Howard County.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The annual license fee is $150.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Board of License Commissioners may issue a club license for the sale of beer and light wine for consumption on the premises only to bona fide clubs as defined by &#xA7; 1-102(a)(4) of this article, which have held regular meetings at an established headquarters for a period of one year prior to the application for the license.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The licensee may sell for consumption on the premises brewed beverages with an alcoholic content of no more than 6 percent by volume and fermented beverages containing no more than 23 percent by volume.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">The holder of a club license may purchase also a special Sunday on-sale only license upon the payment of an additional fee of $75.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(p)">This section does not apply in Kent County.</section>
    <section prefix="(q)">In Montgomery County the annual license fee is $120.</section>
    <section prefix="(r)">In Prince George's County the annual license fee is $245.</section>
    <section prefix="(s)">This section does not apply in Queen Anne's County.</section>
    <section prefix="(t)">This section does not apply in St. Mary's County.</section>
    <section prefix="(u)">In Somerset County the annual license fee is $45.</section>
    <section prefix="(v)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This section does not apply in Talbot County.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Section 18-101 of this article permits the Talbot County Council to provide for the retail alcoholic beverage laws for the county which, if enacted, supersede the provisions of this article.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(w)">In Washington County the annual license fee is $200.</section>
    <section prefix="(x)">In Wicomico County the annual license fee is $125.</section>
    <section prefix="(y)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In Worcester County the annual license fee is $200.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The hours for sale shall be as provided in &#xA7; 11-524 of this article.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
