<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="g2b" order_by="" level="1">Alcoholic Beverages</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>g2b-20-102</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>102</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">This section applies only in Baltimore City.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Except as provided in subsection (c) of this section, an establishment that is not licensed by the Board of License Commissioners may not give, serve, dispense, keep, or allow to be consumed on its premises, or on premises under its control or possession, any alcoholic beverages.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A restaurant as defined in &#xA7; 1-102(a)(22)(i) and (ii) of this article that is not licensed by the Board of License Commissioners may allow a patron to consume alcoholic beverages from 6 a.m. to 2 a.m. the following day if:<section prefix="(1)">The alcoholic beverages are brought to the restaurant by the patron;</section><section prefix="(2)">The alcoholic beverages are consumed with a meal;</section><section prefix="(3)">There is no charge for admission to the restaurant; and</section><section prefix="(4)">The Baltimore City Fire Department determines that the maximum seating capacity of the restaurant is 50.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Baltimore City Police Department may immediately close all operations of an establishment if the Department determines that the establishment is in violation of this section and that the public health, safety, or welfare requires emergency action.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The establishment shall be closed until the Baltimore City Police Department determines that the public health, safety, or welfare has been restored.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The owner or operator of the establishment shall be given an opportunity to request a prompt hearing in circuit court on when the establishment may reopen.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">A violation of this section is a misdemeanor, and upon conviction, the court shall impose a fine of up to $10,000 or imprisonment for up to 2 years, or both.</section>
  </text>
</law>
