<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="g2b" order_by="" level="1">Alcoholic Beverages</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>g2b-6-703.1</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>703.1</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">This section applies only in Frederick County.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Board of License Commissioners may issue a caterer's license to a holder of a Class B restaurant or hotel (on-sale) beer, wine and liquor license.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The annual license fee is $1,500.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A caterer's license issued under this section authorizes the holder to provide alcoholic beverages at publicly or privately sponsored events that are held off the premises that is covered by the Class B restaurant or hotel (on-sale) license.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The holder of a caterer's license shall prepare, deliver, and provide food as well as provide alcoholic beverages for consumption at the catered event.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The county health department shall approve the facilities that prepare the food before the license may be issued, reissued, or renewed.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The holder of a caterer's license shall provide all service employees to serve the alcoholic beverages at the catered event.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">At least one employee shall have been certified by an alcohol awareness program and shall be on the premises at all times during the catered event.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">After the event, all alcoholic beverages shall remain in possession of the holder of the caterer's license and be returned to the premises covered by the Class B restaurant or hotel license.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">The holder of a caterer's license may exercise the privileges under the license only during the hours and days that are permitted in this article for a Class B restaurant or hotel (on-sale) beer, wine and liquor license.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">This section does not require a holder of an existing Class B (on-sale) beer, wine and liquor license to hold a caterer's license for catering on the premises that is covered by the existing license.</section>
  </text>
</law>
