<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="g2b" order_by="" level="1">Alcoholic Beverages</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>g2b-8-403.2</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>403.2</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">This section applies only in:<section prefix="(1)">Ward 27, precincts 42 and 44 of the 41st Legislative District of Baltimore City;</section><section prefix="(2)">Ward 27, precincts 41 and 48 of the 43rd Legislative District of Baltimore City; and</section><section prefix="(3)">Ward 11, precinct 5 of the 44th Legislative District of Baltimore City.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Board of Liquor License Commissioners for Baltimore City may issue a Class BWLT beer, wine, and liquor (on-premises) tasting license to a holder of a Class A beer, wine and liquor license.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The fees for a Class BWLT license are as follows:<section prefix="(i)">$20 for a daily tasting license, which may be issued not more than 12 times in any annual license year;</section><section prefix="(ii)">$200 annually for a 26-day tasting license, which may be used consecutively or nonconsecutively;</section><section prefix="(iii)">$300 annually for a 52-day tasting license, which may be used consecutively or nonconsecutively; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">$750 annually for a tasting license that may be used daily throughout the year.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The fees for a Class BWLT license are in addition to the Class A annual license fee.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A Class BWLT license authorizes the holder to allow the on-premises consumption of beer, light wine, and liquor for tasting or sampling.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A person may consume beer, light wine, or liquor covered by a Class BWLT license in a quantity not exceeding:<section prefix="(i)">1 ounce of light wine from a given brand in a single day;</section><section prefix="(ii)">3 ounces of beer from a given brand in a single day; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">One-half ounce of liquor from a given brand in a single day.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">At the end of each day for which a Class BWLT license is valid, the holder of the license shall dispose of any unconsumed alcoholic beverage remaining in a container that was opened for tasting or sampling.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Each Class A license holder that seeks issuance of a Class BWLT license for which the holder is eligible shall apply for the license on forms provided by the Board of Liquor License Commissioners for Baltimore City.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The forms provided by the Board of Liquor License Commissioners for Baltimore City under paragraph (1) of this subsection for licenses issued under subsection (c)(1)(i) through (iii) of this section shall specify the date or dates on which the tasting is requested to occur.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The application and payment for the daily license under subsection (c)(1)(i) of this section shall be submitted at least 7 days in advance of the tasting event or 7 days in advance of the first day of consecutive day tasting events.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The application and payment for the 26-day tasting license and the 52-day tasting license shall be made at least 7 days in advance of the first proposed tasting event.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">The holder of a 26-day tasting license and a 52-day tasting license shall notify the Board of Liquor License Commissioners for Baltimore City, on forms approved by the Board of Liquor License Commissioners for Baltimore City, of additional tasting events authorized by the licenses.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">The provisions of this section are not restricted by:<section prefix="(1)">&#xA7; 12-107(b) of this article; and</section><section prefix="(2)">The provisions in &#xA7; 9-102 of this article that prohibit the issuance of two licenses for the same premises.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(h)">The holder of a Class BWLT license may exercise the privileges of this section during the hours and days provided for under the holder's respective Class A license.</section>
  </text>
</law>
