<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="g2b" order_by="2" level="1">Alcoholic Beverages</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>g2b-16-301</section_number>
  <catch_line>In addition to the powers otherwise provided by this article, the Comptroller and the board of licen...</catch_line>
  <order_by>301</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In addition to the powers otherwise provided by this article, the Comptroller and the board of license commissioners from any county or Baltimore City, respectively, have full power and authority to adopt such reasonable rules and regulations as they may deem necessary to enable them effectively to discharge the duties imposed upon them by this article.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Baltimore City Board of License Commissioners shall not require: That protests against the issuance or transfer of any license must be accompanied by an abstract of title from the land records of Baltimore City substantiating the protestants' ownership of the real or leasehold property, but it may require that a qualified person familiar with the land records of Baltimore City appear at the hearing and testify as to who is the holder of full legal title as shown by the land records of Baltimore City. In case of property owned jointly, if one owner appears in person at the hearing as a protestant, the other owner's protest may be recorded by an affidavit. The Board shall supply a form of acceptable affidavit upon request to any person representing himself to be a protestant.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Baltimore County Board of License Commissioners shall publish notice of any intended action to change or promulgate rules and regulations not less than 30 days in advance of the effective date of the proposed rules and regulations in a newspaper of general publication in Baltimore County and shall afford all interested persons a reasonable opportunity to submit data or views orally or in writing prior to the effective date of the proposed rules and regulations.</section>
  </text>
</law>
