<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="g2b" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="20-105.1" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>g2b-20-105.1</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Bottle club" means a club, room, or premises:<section prefix="(i)">That serves, sells, gives, or dispenses alcoholic beverages to its members or guests;</section><section prefix="(ii)">That keeps for its members or guests any alcoholic beverages;</section><section prefix="(iii)">That allows to be consumed by its members or guests on its premises any alcoholic beverages that have been reserved or purchased by the members or guests;</section><section prefix="(iv)">At which patrons are served, given, or allowed to consume alcoholic beverages after legal closing hours from the supplies that the patrons have previously purchased or reserved; or</section><section prefix="(v)">That sells, dispenses, or serves to, keeps for, or allows to be consumed any setups or other component parts of mixed alcoholic drinks by its members or guests.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Place of public entertainment" means a business establishment that does not hold a license under this article and that allows on its premises any form of attire or sexual display prohibited under &#xA7; 10-405 of this article.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">"Setups" includes drinking containers and ice.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">This section applies only in Dorchester County.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A bottle club may not evade the alcoholic beverage license laws, including those laws relating to hours of operation and the sale, giving, serving, dispensing, keeping, and allowing to be consumed on the premises of the club or on premises under its control or in its possession any alcoholic beverage, setups, or other component parts of mixed alcoholic drinks.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A person who operates a business establishment for profit that is not licensed under this article may not knowingly allow customers to bring alcoholic beverages for consumption into an unlicensed building.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A person may not serve or dispense setups or serve, dispense, keep, or allow to be consumed any alcoholic beverages or other component parts of mixed alcoholic drinks in a place of public entertainment.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">On the filing of an application for a waiver of this section, the Board of License Commissioners may grant the waiver.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The Board of License Commissioners shall adopt regulations to implement this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">A person who violates this section is guilty of a misdemeanor and on conviction is subject to imprisonment not exceeding 2 years or a fine not exceeding $10,000 or both.</section>
  </text>
</law>
