<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="g2b" order_by="" level="1">Alcoholic Beverages</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>g2b-8-202.1</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>202.1</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">This section applies only in Anne Arundel County.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Board" means the Board of License Commissioners of Anne Arundel County.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Capital investment" means amounts paid for the acquisition of property:<section prefix="(i)">For a useful life greater than 1 year; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">For a permanent improvement or betterment of the property that has a useful life greater than 1 year.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">"Cost of land" includes:<section prefix="(i)">The purchase price, plus taxes and fees incidental to the purchase, including costs related to obtaining appropriate zoning and licensing;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The cost of site grading, preparation, paving, sidewalks, gutters, curbs, and landscaping; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">The cost of the construction and installation of all utilities to the exterior of the building shell.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(5)">"Cost of the building shell" includes the cost attributable to a structure with a roof, sidewalls, doors, and windows completely enclosed and weatherproofed on a slab or other subflooring.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">There is a 7-day Class BLX (deluxe restaurant) (on-sale) beer, wine and liquor license.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A BLX license may be issued only for the use of an establishment that:<section prefix="(i)">Qualifies as a restaurant under the regulations of the Board;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Has a minimum seating capacity of 100 persons for dining;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Has a cocktail lounge or bar area seating capacity not exceeding 25% of the seating capacity for dining;</section><section prefix="(iv)">Has parking facilities to accommodate a minimum of 75 vehicles; and</section><section prefix="(v)">Has a minimum capital investment by the applicant of $800,000, exclusive of the cost of the land and buildings.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If an applicant for a BLX license purchases an existing building, the capital investment attributable to the cost of the building shell shall be based on the fair market value of the structures for which the cost of the building shell was incurred, determined at the time of purchase.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The capital investment, excluding land and building shell, shall also be evaluated at the fair market value at the time of purchase.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">If the premises are leased, the rent paid for the land shall be considered a cost of land and any rent paid for a building shall be considered a cost of a building shell.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">A BLX license may not be issued for use in an establishment that is a fast-food style restaurant.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The annual license fee is $1,200.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A licensee may hold not more than 10 licenses of any class in accordance with this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Of the licenses held by a licensee:<section prefix="(i)">Not more than four licenses may be ones in which the licensee holds a direct interest; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">The remaining licenses shall be ones in which the licensee holds an indirect interest, as evidenced by any of the following relationships involving the licensee and another licensee or the licensee and an applicant for a license:<section prefix="1.">A common parent company;</section><section prefix="2.">A franchise agreement;</section><section prefix="3.">A licensing agreement;</section><section prefix="4.">A concession agreement;</section><section prefix="5.">Membership by the licensee and the other person in a chain of businesses commonly owned and operated and so portrayed to the public;</section><section prefix="6.">Sharing of directors or stockholders or sharing of directors or stockholders of parent companies or subsidiaries;</section><section prefix="7.">Common direct or indirect sharing of profit from the sale of alcoholic beverages; or</section><section prefix="8.">Sharing of a common trade name, trademark, logo or theme, or mode of operation identifiable by the public, except hotels and motels.</section></section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(h)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, a license that was issued on or before June 30, 2006, and in which a licensee holds a direct interest or an indirect interest:<section prefix="(i)">Shall be counted against the maximum number of 10 licenses that the licensee may hold under this section; but</section><section prefix="(ii)">Is exempt from subsections (i) through (l) of this section.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A Class H license that was issued in the period beginning on March 14, 2005, and ending on December 1, 2005, may not be counted against the maximum number of 10 licenses that the licensee may hold under this section.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(i)">A person may be issued one Class B license, Class H license, or Class BLX alcoholic beverages license for a restaurant located anywhere in the county.</section>
    <section prefix="(j)">A licensee may be issued a second license if:<section prefix="(1)">The licensee holds a Class B license that has a restriction prohibiting off-sales, a Class H license, or a Class BLX license;</section><section prefix="(2)">The license sought is a Class H license or a Class BLX license; and</section><section prefix="(3)">The restaurant for which the license is sought is located in:<section prefix="(i)">The Glen Burnie Urban Renewal Area;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The Parole Town Center Growth Management Area;</section><section prefix="(iii)">The Odenton Town Center Growth Management Area;</section><section prefix="(iv)">The Baltimore-Washington International Thurgood Marshall Airport State Priority Funding Area, as designated by Anne Arundel County in accordance with &#xA7; 6-301(f)(8) of the Economic Development Article;</section><section prefix="(v)">A shopping center with a gross area of at least 1,000,000 square feet that is zoned C3 General Commercial by the zoning article of the Anne Arundel County Code;</section><section prefix="(vi)">The Route 198 corridor, consisting of properties located within 500 feet of the right-of-way of Maryland Route 198, from Maryland Route 32 on the east to the Prince George's County-Anne Arundel County line on the west;</section><section prefix="(vii)">A community revitalization zone with a designation in the series "A" through "P", inclusive, as shown on the map adopted by the Anne Arundel County Council by Bill 97-01;</section><section prefix="(viii)">The Severn Commercial District, consisting of properties designated as "commercial zoning" by the comprehensive rezoning maps adopted by the Anne Arundel County Council and located on that portion of Maryland Route 174 west of Maryland Route 100 and east of the railroad right-of-way owned by the National Railroad Passenger Corporation (Parcel 117, Anne Arundel County Tax Map 29);</section><section prefix="(ix)">The Edgewater/Mayo Commercial District, consisting of those properties that are designated "commercial zoning districts" on the comprehensive rezoning maps adopted by the Anne Arundel County Council for the Edgewater/Mayo Small Area Planning District;</section><section prefix="(x)">The Pasadena Commercial District, consisting of those properties that are designated "commercial zoning areas", including Lake Shore Crossing, Lake Shore Plaza, and the Mountain Marketplace Shopping Center on the comprehensive zoning maps adopted by the Anne Arundel County Council for the Pasadena Small Area Planning District; or</section><section prefix="(xi)">The area in Pasadena known as the Brumwell Property.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(k)">A licensee may be issued a third license if:<section prefix="(1)">The license sought is a Class BLX license; and</section><section prefix="(2)">The restaurant for which the license is sought is located in:<section prefix="(i)">The Glen Burnie Urban Renewal Area;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The Parole Town Center Growth Management Area;</section><section prefix="(iii)">The Odenton Town Center Growth Management Area;</section><section prefix="(iv)">The Baltimore-Washington International Thurgood Marshall Airport State Priority Funding Area, as designated by Anne Arundel County in accordance with &#xA7; 6-301(f)(8) of the Economic Development Article;</section><section prefix="(v)">A shopping center with a gross area of at least 1,000,000 square feet that is zoned C3 General Commercial by the zoning article of the Anne Arundel County Code;</section><section prefix="(vi)">The Route 198 corridor, consisting of properties located within 500 feet of the right-of-way of Maryland Route 198, from Maryland Route 32 on the east to the Prince George's County-Anne Arundel County line on the west;</section><section prefix="(vii)">A community revitalization zone with a designation in the series "A" through "P", inclusive, as shown on the map adopted by the Anne Arundel County Council by Bill 97-01;</section><section prefix="(viii)">The Severn Commercial District, consisting of properties designated as "commercial zoning" by the comprehensive rezoning maps adopted by the Anne Arundel County Council and located on that portion of Maryland Route 174 west of Maryland Route 100 and east of the railroad right-of-way owned by the National Railroad Passenger Corporation (Parcel 117, Anne Arundel County Tax Map 29);</section><section prefix="(ix)">The Edgewater/Mayo Commercial District, consisting of those properties that are designated "commercial zoning districts" on the comprehensive rezoning maps adopted by the Anne Arundel County Council for the Edgewater/Mayo Small Area Planning District;</section><section prefix="(x)">The Pasadena Commercial District, consisting of those properties that are designated "commercial zoning areas", including Lake Shore Crossing, Lake Shore Plaza, and the Mountain Marketplace Shopping Center on the comprehensive zoning maps adopted by the Anne Arundel County Council for the Pasadena Small Area Planning District; or</section><section prefix="(xi)">The area in Pasadena known as the Brumwell Property.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(l)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A licensee may be issued a fourth license if the license sought is a Class BLX license.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The restaurant for which the license is sought may be located anywhere in the county.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(m)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A licensee may be issued a fifth license if the license sought is a Class BLX license.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The restaurant for which the fifth license is sought may be located anywhere in the county.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(n)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A licensee may be issued a sixth, seventh, eighth, ninth, or tenth license if the license sought is a Class BLX license.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The restaurant for which the license is sought may be located anywhere in the county.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(o)">The hours and days that a licensee may exercise the privileges of sale under a BLX license are the same as those for a Class B (on-sale) beer, wine and liquor license in Anne Arundel County.</section>
    <section prefix="(p)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This subsection does not apply to a transfer of licensees for the same premises or a renewal of a BLX license.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A BLX license may not be transferred from the location site of its first issuance.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(q)">The Board shall adopt regulations to carry out this section.</section>
  </text>
</law>
