<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="g2b" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="6-401" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>g2b-6-401</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A Class D beer, wine and liquor license shall be issued by the license issuing authority of the county in which the place of business is located. It authorizes the holder to keep for sale and sell all alcoholic beverages at retail at the place described in it, for consumption on the premises or elsewhere. A license may not be issued for any drugstore.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The annual license fee shall be paid to the local collecting agent before any license is issued, for distribution as provided.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">In this section, "Board" means the Board of License Commissioners for the jurisdiction to which the subsection applies.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">In Allegany County the annual license fee is $700.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This subsection applies only in Anne Arundel County.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">There are two type Class D beer, wine and liquor licenses:<section prefix="(i)">A limited Class D license which allows for on premises consumption only.</section><section prefix="(ii)">A Class D license which allows for consumption on premises or elsewhere.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The annual license fee for a limited Class D license is $1,080.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The annual license fee for a Class D on- and off-sale license is $1,200.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The Board, upon the filing of an application for any new Class D beer, wine and liquor license, may limit the sale of alcoholic beverages to consumption only on the premises.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Subject to &#xA7; 11-503(b)(2) of this article, in Baltimore City the annual license fee is $825.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">In Baltimore City, the hours and days for sale for the license are as provided under &#xA7; 11-503 of this article.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This subsection applies only in Baltimore County.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The annual license fee is $1,500.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The area of the licensed premises normally used for the preparation and consumption of alcoholic beverages on the premises may occupy no less than 80 percent of the square foot area. These occupancy requirements do not apply to or affect any present licensee having this license prior to December 31, 1966.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This subsection applies only in Calvert County.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">This license may be issued in the entire county.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The annual license fee is:<section prefix="(i)">$1,250, if the place of business remains open until midnight; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">$2,250, if the place of business remains open until 2 a.m.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This subsection applies only in Caroline County.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The annual license fee is $1,250 for a 6-day license.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The annual license fee is $1,600 for a 7-day license.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">All alcoholic beverages sold under this license must be consumed on the premises.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">A licensee may sell beer, wine and liquor for consumption on the premises only.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(h)">This section does not apply in Carroll County.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This subsection applies only in Cecil County.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The annual license fee is $750.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(j)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This subsection applies only in Charles County.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The annual license fee:<section prefix="(i)">For on- and off-sale of all alcoholic beverages is $1,140; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">For off-sale for liquor and on- or off-sale for beer and wine is $720.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(k)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This subsection applies only in Dorchester County.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Board of License Commissioners may issue a Class D (on-sale) beer, wine and liquor license.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The annual license fee is $1,500.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">A license issued under this subsection is a 7-day license.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">Alcoholic beverages sold under this subsection may be consumed only on the licensed premises.</section>
      <section prefix="(6)">An individual who is under the age of 21 years may not be on the licensed premises.	</section>
      <section prefix="(7)">In accordance with &#xA7; 9-201 of this article, only the Board of License Commissioners may decide the number of Class D licenses to be issued.</section>
      <section prefix="(8)">The Board of License Commissioners shall:<section prefix="(i)">Determine whether the premises for which a Class D license is issued meets the requirements of &#xA7; 9-210 of this article; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Adopt regulations to carry out this subsection.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(l)">This section does not apply in Frederick County.</section>
    <section prefix="(m)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This subsection applies only in Garrett County.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">There are two types of Class D licenses, neither of which may be issued to any grocery store having a primary business of selling food at retail to the general public for off-premises consumption.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)"/>
        <section prefix="(iii)"/>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Until July 1, 1995, a holder of an existing Class D alcoholic beverages license prior to July 1, 1987 may apply for a license under paragraph (2) of this subsection using the procedure that the Board establishes.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">If the applicant is granted a license under paragraph (2) of this subsection, the applicant may be exempt from paying the issuing fee as provided under &#xA7; 9-212(c) of this article. However, the applicant shall pay:</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(n)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This subsection applies only in Harford County.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Subject to the provisions of this subsection, the Liquor Control Board may issue only to the current holder of any Class B license:<section prefix="(i)">A 7-day (on-sale) Class D license for all alcoholic beverages, with an annual license fee of $3,000; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">A 7-day (on- and off-sale) Class D license for all alcoholic beverages, with an annual license fee of $4,000.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The holder of a Class B license may apply for a Class D license authorized by this subsection.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The Liquor Control Board has sole authority, in accordance with &#xA7;&#xA7; 9-201 and 10-203 of this article, to decide the number of Class D licenses authorized by this subsection to be issued.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">Upon the issuance of a Class D license by the Liquor Control Board, the licensee to whom the Class D license is issued shall surrender to the Board the Class B license it held.</section>
      <section prefix="(6)">The Liquor Control Board shall ensure that any Class D license issued under the authority of this subsection meets the requirements of &#xA7; 9-213 of this article.</section>
      <section prefix="(7)">In accordance with &#xA7; 16-301(a) of this article, the Liquor Control Board shall adopt regulations to carry out this subsection.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(o)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This subsection applies only in Howard County.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Board may issue the following types of licenses:<section prefix="(i)"/><section prefix="(ii)"/><section prefix="(iii)"/><section prefix="(iv)"/></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(p)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This subsection applies only in Kent County.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Board may issue a Class D beer, wine and liquor license.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The annual license fee is $1,500.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">On Sunday, a licensee may sell only beer and light wine for off-premises consumption.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">A person under the age of 21 years is not permitted in a tavern or on the licensed premises of an establishment which has a license issued pursuant to this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(6)">
        <section prefix="(i)">A person under 21 years of age may not knowingly make any misrepresentation or false statement as to the person's age in order to gain entrance to an establishment licensed under this subsection.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">A police officer or alcoholic beverages inspector shall issue a citation under &#xA7; 10-119 of the Criminal Law Article to a person who violates the provisions of this paragraph.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">Penalties for offenses of this paragraph are as set forth in &#xA7; 10-119 of the Criminal Law Article.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(q)">This section does not apply in Montgomery County.</section>
    <section prefix="(r)">This section does not apply in Prince George's County.</section>
    <section prefix="(s)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This subsection applies only in Queen Anne's County.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A Class D beer, wine and liquor (on- and limited off-sale) license may be issued for on-premises consumption and the off-sale of beer only.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The annual license fee is $1,800.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(t)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This subsection applies only in St. Mary's County.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The annual license fee:<section prefix="(i)">For a Class D beer, wine and liquor license is $250; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">For a special Class D beer, wine and liquor license that entitles the holder to sell on Sunday is $650.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(u)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In Somerset County the annual license fee is $1,265.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Spirituous liquors may be sold for on-sale consumption only, but beer and wine may be sold for both on- and off-sale consumption.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(v)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This section does not apply in Talbot County.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Section 18-101 of this article permits the Talbot County Council to provide for the retail alcoholic beverages laws for the county which, if enacted, supersede the provisions of this article.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(w)">In Washington County the annual license fee is $750.</section>
    <section prefix="(x)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This subsection applies only in Wicomico County.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">There is a Class D beer, wine and liquor tavern license.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The annual license fee is $2,200.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">Any license issued under this paragraph is for 7 days.</section>
        <section prefix="(iv)">In order to qualify for a license under this paragraph, the premises that is the subject of the application shall:</section>
        <section prefix="(v)">Alcoholic beverages sold under this paragraph shall be consumed on the premises only.</section>
        <section prefix="(vi)">A person may not be on the premises if the person is under the legal drinking age for the consumption of alcohol in the State.</section>
        <section prefix="(vii)">All alcoholic beverages other than beer and light wine shall be purchased from the Liquor Control Board for Wicomico County and shall be charged not more than 15% above the wholesale cost to the dispensary.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">There is a Class D beer, wine and liquor entertainment and amusement license.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The annual license fee is $4,000.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">A license issued under this paragraph is a 7-day license for consumption on the premises only.</section>
        <section prefix="(iv)">To qualify for a license, the premises that is the subject of the application shall be an entertainment amusement center that:</section>
        <section prefix="(v)"/>
        <section prefix="(vi)">Except for beer and light wine, the license holder shall purchase all of the alcoholic beverages that are sold for consumption on the premises from a county dispensary and may not be charged more than 15% above the wholesale cost to the dispensary.</section>
        <section prefix="(vii)">An individual who is:</section>
        <section prefix="(viii)">The Board may adopt regulations to carry out this paragraph.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(y)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This subsection applies only in Worcester County.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">A Class D beer, wine and liquor license may be issued only within:</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The annual license fee for the six-day license set by the Worcester County Commissioners may not be less than $3,000.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">The annual license fee for the seven-day license set by the Worcester County Commissioners may not be less than $3,500.</section>
        <section prefix="(iv)">Seven-day license holders may sell beer, wine and liquor (on-sale) and beer and light wine (off-sale).</section>
        <section prefix="(v)">All license fees shall go to the general funds of the county. However, if the licensed premises are in a municipal corporation, 75 percent of the fees shall go to that municipal corporation.</section>
        <section prefix="(vi)"/>
        <section prefix="(vii)">The hours for sale are as provided in &#xA7; 11-524 of this article.</section>
        <section prefix="(viii)">With respect to the Ocean City Convention Hall, only the Convention Hall Commission and its successors may be issued an alcoholic beverages license. The Commission may permit its vendors to dispense alcoholic beverages pursuant to whatever license the Commission is granted. Further, the Commission may contract to receive some proportion of the revenue derived from the vendor's sale of alcoholic beverages. This license shall be subject to the following restrictions:</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)"/>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The holder may contract with and permit a concessionaire to keep for sale and sell beer, wine, and liquor for on premises consumption only.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">The hours and days of sale under the license are the same as a Class D beer, wine and liquor on-sale license under &#xA7; 11-524 of this article or during lesser hours specified by the holder.</section>
        <section prefix="(iv)">A license shall be issued and renewed without charge or an annual fee and may not be transferred.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
