<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="g2b" order_by="2" level="1">Alcoholic Beverages</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>g2b-8-408.1</section_number>
  <catch_line>In Howard County, the Board of License Commissioners may issue a beer and wine tasting (BWT) alcohol...</catch_line>
  <order_by>408.1</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In Howard County, the Board of License Commissioners may issue a beer and wine tasting (BWT) alcoholic beverages license.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, a BWT license may be issued to a holder of:<section prefix="(i)">A Class A beer, wine and liquor (BWL) license; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">A Class A beer and wine (BW) license.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A BWT license authorizes the on-premises consumption, for tasting or sampling only, of:<section prefix="(i)">Beer; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">Wine containing not more than 15.5% of alcohol by volume.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">A holder of a BWT license may not serve:<section prefix="(i)">Wine in a quantity of  more than 1 ounce from each given brand and no more than 4 ounces from all brands to any one person in a single day; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">Beer in a quantity of more than 3 ounces from each given brand and no more than 8 ounces from all brands to any one person in a single day.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(5)">The annual license fee for a BWT license is $100 in addition to the fee of any other alcoholic beverages license.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In Howard County, the Board of License Commissioners may issue a beer, wine and liquor tasting (BWLT) alcoholic beverages license.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, a BWLT license may be issued to a holder of a Class A beer, wine and liquor (BWL) license.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A BWLT license authorizes the on-premises consumption, for tasting or sampling only, of:<section prefix="(i)">Beer;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Wine containing not more than 15.5% of alcohol by volume; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">Liquor.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">A holder of a BWLT license may not serve:<section prefix="(i)">Wine in a quantity of  more than 1 ounce from each given brand and not more than 4 ounces from all brands to any one person in a single day;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Beer in a quantity of more than 3 ounces from each given brand and not more than 8 ounces from all brands to any one person in a single day; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">Liquor in a quantity of more than 1/4 ounce from each given brand and not more than 1 ounce from all brands to any one person in a single day.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(5)">The annual license fee for a BWLT license is $100 in addition to the fee for any other alcoholic beverages license.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Howard County Board of License Commissioners may adopt rules or regulations providing additional requirements to implement this section.</section>
  </text>
</law>
