<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="g2b" order_by="2" level="1">Alcoholic Beverages</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>g2b-8-302</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this section the following words have the meanings indicated....</catch_line>
  <order_by>302</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Board" means the Anne Arundel County Board of License Commissioners.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Festival" means the Anne Arundel County Beer and Wine Festival and the Benson-Hammond House Strawberry Festival.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">This section applies only in Anne Arundel County.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Board may issue a special festival (AABWF) license.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Notwithstanding any other provision of this article, an applicant for a special festival license shall be a holder of an existing State retail alcoholic beverages license, State Class 3 winery license, or State Class 4 limited winery license issued under this article.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">A special festival licensee shall:<section prefix="(1)">Only display and sell:<section prefix="(i)">Wine that is:<section prefix="1.">Manufactured and processed in any state;</section><section prefix="2.">Price filed in accordance with regulations adopted by the Comptroller; and</section><section prefix="3.">Distributed in the State at the time the application is filed; and</section></section><section prefix="(ii)">Beer that is brewed by a brewer:<section prefix="1.">Who brews less than 60,000 barrels of beer annually; and</section><section prefix="2.">Whose product is distributed in the State at the time the application is filed;</section></section></section><section prefix="(2)">Display and sell beer and wine at retail for consumption on or off the licensed premises on the days and for the hours designated for the Festival; and</section><section prefix="(3)">Display and sell wine that is manufactured and processed in any state at retail for consumption off the licensed premises on the days and for the hours designated for the Festival.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">This section does not prohibit the holder of a special festival license from holding another alcoholic beverages license of a different class or nature.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">The Board:<section prefix="(1)">May establish the license fee;</section><section prefix="(2)">May select one weekend, Friday through Sunday inclusive, annually for the Festival provided that the weekend that is selected does not occur within 14 days on either side of the Maryland Wine Festival;</section><section prefix="(3)">Shall choose a location in the county for this Festival which is not licensed under this article; and</section><section prefix="(4)">Shall assure that the primary focus of the Festival is the promotion of Maryland beer and wine.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(h)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Products displayed and sold shall be:<section prefix="(i)">Invoiced to the festival license holder by a licensed State wholesaler, winery, or limited winery; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Delivered to the Festival from the licensed premises of the wholesaler, winery, or limited winery.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Whenever a special festival license is issued under this section, holders of wholesale, winery, or limited winery licenses may enter into an agreement with the holder of a special festival license to deliver beer and wine 2 days prior to the effective date, and to accept returns 2 days after the expiration date of the special festival license.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(i)">The Board shall adopt regulations for implementing this section.</section>
  </text>
</law>
