<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="g2b" order_by="2" level="1">Alcoholic Beverages</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>g2b-12-204</section_number>
  <catch_line>This section applies only in Baltimore County....</catch_line>
  <order_by>204</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">This section applies only in Baltimore County.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A holder of a beer, wine, and liquor license, Class D, for the sale of alcoholic beverages on any premises, shall provide an entrance to the premises which shall be unlocked at all times during which sales are being made or while consumption is occurring.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In granting a license, the Board of License Commissioners may:<section prefix="(i)">Limit the license to a Class B (SB) restaurant - service bar beer, wine, and liquor (on-sale) license only; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">Restrict off sale privileges of the licensee.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The provisions of paragraph (1) of this subsection do not apply to a holder of a Class A beer, wine, and liquor license.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">In this subsection, "adult entertainment" means performances at licensed premises that are commonly called "go-go dancing", "male revues", "female revues", and "exotic dancing".</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">"Adult entertainment" includes performances by individuals who perform in any manner while in a state of dress in which clothing covers no more than the genitals, pubic region, and areola of the female breast, as well as portions of the body covered by supporting straps and devices.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The holder of any class of alcoholic beverages license may not permit adult entertainment on licensed premises or on property adjacent to the licensed premises over which the holder has ownership or control.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">If the Board finds that a violation of this subsection has occurred, the Board shall suspend or revoke the license for the premises where the violation occurred, impose a fine on the holder of the license for the premises where the violation occurred, or both.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The provisions of this subsection do not apply to:<section prefix="(i)">The holder of an alcoholic beverages license that offered adult entertainment on licensed premises for at least 5 calendar days between March 8, 1996 and April 8, 1996;</section><section prefix="(ii)">A transferee of an alcoholic beverages license from a holder described in item (i) of this paragraph as long as the transferee continues to offer adult entertainment on the same licensed premises; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">The holder of an alcoholic beverages license who operates a theater, a concert hall, an art center, a museum, or a similar establishment that is primarily devoted to the arts or theatrical performances, when the performances express matters of serious literary, artistic, scientific, or political value.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
