<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="g2b" order_by="2" level="1">Alcoholic Beverages</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>g2b-8-224</section_number>
  <catch_line>This section applies only in Worcester County....</catch_line>
  <order_by>224</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">This section applies only in Worcester County.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">There is a Class I beer, wine and liquor license.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A Class I beer, wine and liquor license may be issued only within:<section prefix="(1)">The corporate limits of Ocean City;</section><section prefix="(2)">The boundary lines of the 10th election district;</section><section prefix="(3)">The boundary lines of the 2nd precinct of the 3rd election district; or</section><section prefix="(4)">The area bounded by Maryland Route 589 to the north and east, U.S. Route 50 to the south, and U.S. Route 113 to the west, all of which lie within the 1st precinct of the 3rd election district.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The annual license fee for the 6-day license is $2,500.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The annual license fee for the 7-day license is $3,000.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">A licensee may sell beer, wine, and liquor for on-premises consumption only.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, all license fees shall go to the general funds of the county.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If the licensed premises are in a municipal corporation, 75 percent of the fees shall go to that municipal corporation.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Except as provided in subparagraph (ii) of this paragraph, a licensee shall purchase all alcoholic beverages, except light wine and beer, from the Worcester County Department of Liquor Control.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">Beginning on May 1, 2016, a licensee may elect to purchase wine and liquor from a licensed wholesaler or may continue to purchase all alcoholic beverages, except light wine and beer, from the Worcester County Department of Liquor Control.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A licensee may purchase beer and light wine from a licensed wholesaler.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A licensee shall be charged not more than 85 percent of the retail price or any special sale price or discount price, whichever is lower, set by the Department for wine and liquor.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(h)">The hours for sale are as provided in &#xA7; 11-524 of this article.</section>
  </text>
</law>
