<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="g2b" order_by="" level="1">Alcoholic Beverages</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>g2b-8-222</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>222</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">This section applies only in Washington County.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The operators of any amusement park, whether individual, association of individuals, or a corporation, may be entitled to a license for the sale of beer within the confines of its park.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The fee for such license shall be one hundred dollars ($100) each calendar year, and shall entitle the holder to sell beer at one or more locations within the park from 8 a.m. to midnight on every day from May 1 to September 30 of each year, except Sundays and election days.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Such licensees shall be subject to all laws, rules and regulations applicable in the county to the sale of beer, not inconsistent with the provisions of this section; nothing contained in &#xA7; 9-102 of this article shall apply to any license issued pursuant to this section.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A separate license, called a Class P "pouring license" may be issued countywide by the Board of License Commissioners.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The holder of a Class P "pouring license" may only sell alcoholic beverages for consumption on the premises.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The annual fee for each Class P "pouring license" is:<section prefix="(i)">$350 for a beer license;</section><section prefix="(ii)">$400 for a beer and light wine license;</section><section prefix="(iii)">$750 for a beer, light wine, and liquor license; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">$250 for a Sunday sale license.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this subsection, "premises" includes the entire stadium facility and the stadium parking lots.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Board of License Commissioners may issue a stadium (on-sale) license to the owner of a professional baseball team franchise.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The franchise may be in any form of business organization, including  partnership, corporation, and limited liability company.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The annual fee is $2,000.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">A license entitles the holder to sell beer and light wine:<section prefix="(i)">Subject to paragraph (4) of this subsection, for consumption on the  licensed premises to persons present at any event held in the stadium;</section><section prefix="(ii)">In plastic, Styrofoam, or paper containers; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">From the time the stadium opens for the event until the event ends.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(6)">The written approval of the Board of License Commissioners is required before beer and light wine may be sold, served, or consumed:<section prefix="(i)">On the parking lots of the stadium; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">During any event other than a baseball game in which the team of the license holder is playing.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(7)">Except for a wholesaler or distributor of beer and light wine that is conducting business with the license holder, the license holder may not allow any person to carry alcoholic beverages onto or from the licensed premises.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Board of License Commissioners may issue a sidewalk cafe license to a holder of a Class B or Class P "pouring license".</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A license entitles the holder to sell and serve alcoholic beverages in an area on the sidewalk directly in front of the licensed establishment.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The annual fee is $500.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">A sidewalk cafe license may be issued only with an application for a Class B license or Class P "pouring license".</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">To maintain a sidewalk cafe license, a holder:<section prefix="(i)">Shall comply with all rules and regulations applicable to the issuance of the underlying Class B license or Class P "pouring license" and with all municipal ordinances and fire and health department regulations;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Shall ensure that at least one employee is certified by an alcohol awareness program and  on the premises at all times during the operation of the sidewalk cafe; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Shall keep the kitchen open during all hours of operation and have prepared meals available to be served in the sidewalk cafe.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(6)">A holder may sell or serve alcoholic beverages in the sidewalk cafe from noon to midnight, every day of the week.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
