<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="g2b" order_by="2" level="1">Alcoholic Beverages</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>g2b-8-402</section_number>
  <catch_line>This section applies only in Anne Arundel County....</catch_line>
  <order_by>402</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">This section applies only in Anne Arundel County.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">In this section, "Board" means the Anne Arundel County Board of License Commissioners.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">There is a Class BWT beer and wine (on-premises) tasting license, a Class WS wine sampling (on-premises) license, and a Class WT wine tasting (on-premises) license.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A Class BWT license may only be issued to a holder of a Class BWL beer, wine and liquor (on-premises) license or a Class BW beer and wine (on-sale) license.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The annual fee for a Class BWT license is:<section prefix="(i)">$50 for a holder of a Class BWL license; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">$50 for a holder of a Class BW license.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The annual fee for a Class BWT license is in addition to the Class BWL or BW annual fee.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The Class BWT license authorizes a holder to permit the on-premises consumption of the following alcoholic beverages for tasting or sampling purposes only:<section prefix="(i)">Light wine to be served in a quantity of not more than 1 ounce from each given brand to any one person; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Beer to be served in a quantity of not more than 3 ounces to any one person.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Board may issue a WS (wine sampling) license to bona fide nonprofit organizations.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The WS license authorizes the consumption of wine for tasting or sampling purposes:<section prefix="(i)">On Class B beer and wine or beer, wine and liquor licensed premises with the consent of the licensee; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">On premises without a permanent alcoholic beverages license.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The licensee may not serve more than 2 ounces from each brand to any 1 person.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The bona fide nonprofit organization:<section prefix="(i)">Shall apply for a WS license at least 15 days prior to the day of issuance; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">May not be issued more than 12 WS licenses in any given license year.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(5)">The daily license fee is $15.</section>
      <section prefix="(6)">The WS licensee may bring wine onto Class B licensed premises for sampling or tasting purposes only.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A Class WT wine tasting (on-premises) license may only be issued to a holder of a Class BWL license or a holder of a Class BW license.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A Class WT wine tasting (on-premises) license authorizes a holder to permit the on-premises consumption for tasting or sampling purposes only of light wine to be served in a quantity of not more than 1 ounce from each given brand to any one person.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The annual license fee is:<section prefix="(i)">$150 for a holder of a Class BWL license; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">$50 for a holder of a Class BW license.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">The provisions of this section are not restricted by:<section prefix="(1)">The provisions in subsection (b) of &#xA7; 12-107 of this article; and</section><section prefix="(2)">The provisions of law under &#xA7; 9-102 of this article prohibiting the issuance of 2 licenses for the same premises.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(h)">In the City of Annapolis, the Mayor and City Council may approve the issuance of a BWT license or a WS license. The fees for the licenses shall be set by the Mayor and City Council.</section>
  </text>
</law>
