<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="g2b" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="11-502" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>g2b-11-502</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>In Anne Arundel County, notwithstanding any other provisions in this subtitle, the following restrictions, limitations, and regulations are in effect:<section prefix="(a)">The hours during which sales of alcoholic beverages may be made under all Class A, B, C, D, H, and special class licenses from 6 a.m. until 2 a.m. of the day following, except that no licensed premises shall be permitted to sell alcoholic beverages at any time on Sunday without a special Sunday license.</section><section prefix="(b)"><section prefix="(1)">Licensed premises may not remain open to the public or to private persons or parties for any purpose for more than 15 minutes after the hours and days for sales set forth in this section, even though no sales are made after the hours of closing.</section><section prefix="(2)">However, license commissioners may permit certain licensees to sell food or other nonalcoholic items until a specified hour, if:<section prefix="(i)">The licensee proves to the satisfaction of the Board of License Commissioners that suitable precautions have been taken to prevent the sale or consumption of alcoholic beverages on the licensed premises after the hours of closing; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">The applicant licensee holds:</section></section><section prefix="(3)">Permission shall be evidenced by a suitable license issued by the Board of License Commissioners.</section><section prefix="(4)">The annual fee is $10.</section><section prefix="(5)">Any violation of this subsection shall incur the same penalty as a violation for making a sale of alcoholic beverages after hours.</section></section><section prefix="(c)">The hours established in this article for the sale of alcoholic beverages in Anne Arundel County are hereby declared to be in accordance with Eastern Standard Time on the last Sunday of October in each year.</section><section prefix="(d)">Notwithstanding the provisions of other sections of this Code, sales may be made on Sundays by the holder of a special Sunday license according to the terms thereof.</section><section prefix="(e)">The hours during which sales of alcoholic beverages may be made under a "race track license" shall be from 2 hours preceding the running of any authorized race until 2 hours after the running of any authorized race, and not otherwise.</section><section prefix="(f)">The provisions of this section shall apply to the first, second, third, fourth, fifth, seventh and eighth election districts of Anne Arundel County only.</section><section prefix="(g)">In the City of Annapolis the Mayor, Counselor and Aldermen shall have the power to fix the hours of sale of the licenses authorized to be issued in said City.</section><section prefix="(h)">The Board of License Commissioners for Anne Arundel County may permit any bowling alley holding a Class B or Class D license, with 20 lanes or more, to stay open for bowling and serving food until a specified hour; provided, however, that all alcoholic beverages be kept under lock and key between the hours of 2:00 a.m. and 6:00 a.m. No person under the age of 18 is allowed on the premises between the hours of 2:00 a.m. and 6:00 a.m., unless accompanied by spouse, parent or guardian.</section><section prefix="(i)">Despite any other provisions of this Code, in Anne Arundel County, whenever a special Class C license is issued under the provisions of &#xA7; 7-101 of this article, holders of wholesale licenses may agree with the holder of a special Class C license to deliver beer on the effective date of the license and accept returns on the same day.</section><section prefix="(j)">The hours for the sale of alcoholic beverages under an entertainment facility license or an entertainment concessionaire license are the same as the hours of operation for a video lottery facility established under &#xA7; 9-1A-23 of the State Government Article.</section></text>
</law>
