<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="g2b" order_by="" level="1">Alcoholic Beverages</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>g2b-8-410.3</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>410.3</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">This section applies only in St. Mary's County.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Board of License Commissioners may issue a 1-day Class BWTS beer and wine (on-premises) tasting or sampling license.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A Class BWTS license may be issued only to a holder of a current alcoholic beverages license or an organization that qualifies for a special Class C beer, special Class C beer and wine license, or a special Class C beer, wine and liquor license under &#xA7; 7-101(r) of this article.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The license fee is $50.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">A Class BWTS license authorizes the holder to allow the consumption of wine or beer for tasting or sampling, if the alcoholic beverages are given to consumers at no charge.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">A person may consume wine or beer covered by a Class BWTS license in a quantity not exceeding:<section prefix="(1)">1 ounce from a single brand of wine, and 4 ounces from all brands in a single day; and</section><section prefix="(2)">3 ounces from a single brand of beer, and 8 ounces from all brands in a single day.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(g)">All consumption of alcoholic beverages shall occur on the licensed premises of the holder of the Class BWTS license.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">The Board of License Commissioners need not publish an application for a Class BWTS license before granting the license.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">A Class BWTS license may not be granted to a person more than 12 times in a calendar year.</section>
    <section prefix="(j)">At the end of the day for which a Class BWTS license is valid, the license holder shall dispose of unconsumed alcoholic beverages remaining in a container opened for tasting or sampling.</section>
  </text>
</law>
