<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="g2b" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="9-301" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>g2b-9-301</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>In the enumerated subdivisions below, a person, partnership, firm or corporation, except by way of renewal, may not have an interest in more than one license, whether held or controlled by direct or indirect ownership, by stock ownership, interlocking directors or interlocking stock ownership, or in any other manner, directly or indirectly. It is the intention of this section to prohibit any person, firm, partnership or corporation from having any interest, directly or indirectly, in more than one license.<section prefix=""><section prefix="(1)">In Baltimore County:<section prefix="(i)"/><section prefix="(ii)">Item 2 of subparagraph (i) is intended:</section></section><section prefix="(2)">Worcester County. - Except that the provisions of this section do not apply to any licenses issued under &#xA7; 9-102(j) of this title.</section><section prefix="(3)"><section prefix="(i)">In Anne Arundel County, a person, franchisor, franchisee, chain store operation, partnership, firm or corporation, except by way of renewal, may not have any interest in more than one license, whether held or controlled by direct or indirect ownership, by franchise operation, by chain store operation, by stock ownership, interlocking directors or interlocking stock ownership, or in any other manner directly or indirectly. It is the intention of this subsection to prohibit any such persons, franchisor, franchisee, chain store operation, firm, partnership, or corporation from having any interest, directly or indirectly, in more than one license. Nothing in this subsection applies to or affects any such type of business establishment already holding such a license or the possibility of such licensee having the license transferred to a similar type of business establishment.</section><section prefix="(ii)">This subsection does not apply to licenses issued under the provisions of &#xA7;&#xA7; 8-202(i) and 9-102(h-1) of this article.</section></section><section prefix="(4)">In Howard County:<section prefix="(i)"/><section prefix="(ii)">The prohibitions in this subsection do not apply to the number of licenses authorized under &#xA7; 8-408.1 or &#xA7; 9-102(o) of this article.</section></section><section prefix="(5)"><section prefix="(i)">In Baltimore City, except as authorized by &#xA7; 9-102 of this title, a person, franchisor, franchisee, chain store operation, partnership, firm or corporation, except by way of renewal, may not have any interest in more than one Class A license, whether held or controlled by direct or indirect ownership, by franchise operation, by chain store operation, by stock ownership, interlocking stock ownership, or in any other manner directly or indirectly. It is the intention of this subsection to prohibit any such persons, franchisor, franchisee, chain store operation, firm, partnership, or corporation from having any interest, directly or indirectly, in more than one Class A license. Nothing in this subsection applies to or affects any such type of business establishment already holding such a license or the possibility of such licensee having the license transferred to a similar type of business establishment.</section><section prefix="(ii)">This subsection is intended:</section></section></section></text>
</law>
