<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="g2b" order_by="" level="1">Alcoholic Beverages</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>g2b-8-804</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>804</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, "Board" means the Wicomico County Board of License Commissioners.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">This section applies only in Wicomico County.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Board may issue a special beer festival license.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A special beer festival license may be used only at a beer festival held on nonlicensed premises located in Wicomico County.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Notwithstanding any other provision in this article, an applicant for a special beer festival license shall be the holder of an existing Class 5 brewery, Class 6 pub-brewery, or Class 7 micro-brewery manufacturer's license issued under this article.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Each manufacturer that participates in the beer festival shall obtain a special beer festival license.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">A special beer festival licensee may display and sell beer at retail for consumption on the licensed festival premises only on the hours and days designated for the festival.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The products displayed and sold by a special beer festival licensee shall be products owned and manufactured by the licensee.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">This section does not prohibit a special beer festival licensee from holding another alcoholic beverages license of a different class or nature.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">The license fee is $50 per day.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">Each special beer festival license may be in effect for a period not exceeding 3 days.</section>
    <section prefix="(j)">The Board may:<section prefix="(1)">Adopt regulations to implement this section; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Designate the number of times during a calendar year that a special beer festival license may be issued.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
