<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="g2b" order_by="" level="1">Alcoholic Beverages</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>g2b-11-403</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>403</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A retail dealer holding a Class B or C license may not sell any alcoholic beverage at a bar or counter on Sunday.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">This paragraph does not apply in the City of Annapolis.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">In Anne Arundel County a licensee may sell, vend, serve, deliver and/or a patron may consume any alcoholic beverages permitted by law to be sold at any bar or counter on any day on which the sale of alcoholic beverages is permitted by law.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Except for the Class B Sunday off-sale license prohibition in the 47th alcoholic beverages district in Baltimore City as provided for in &#xA7; 6-201(d) of this article, in Baltimore City a Class B and a Class C beer and light wine or beer, wine and liquor licensee may sell alcoholic beverages at a bar or counter on Sunday.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">
          <section prefix="1.">Subject to the conditions provided in subsubparagraph 2 of this subparagraph and in addition to subparagraph (iii) of this paragraph, in Baltimore City, a holder of a Class A retail alcoholic beverages license may exercise the off-sale license privilege on the Sundays that fall between Thanksgiving Day and New Year's Day from 1 p.m. to 9 p.m.</section>
          <section prefix="2.">The holder of a Class A retail off-sale license may exercise the additional privilege authorized by this subparagraph in any year in which a supplementary license fee of $75 has been paid prior to October 1 for each day the additional privilege is to be exercised.</section>
        </section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">
          <section prefix="1.">The holder of a Class A retail alcoholic beverages license in Baltimore City may exercise the off-sale privilege on two additional Sundays during the calendar year.</section>
          <section prefix="2.">A holder shall pay a license fee of $75 at least 2 weeks before each time the privilege is exercised under this subparagraph.</section>
        </section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(4)">
        <section prefix="(i)">This paragraph applies only in Baltimore County.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">A Class B and a Class C beer and light wine or beer, wine and liquor licensee may sell alcoholic beverages at a bar or counter on Sunday.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">Between the hours of 7 a.m. and 9 p.m., a holder of any class of retail off-sale alcoholic beverages license may exercise the off-sale license privilege on the Sunday preceding Christmas Day, the Sunday preceding New Year's Day, the Sunday preceding Rosh Hashanah, and the Sunday preceding Yom Kippur.</section>
        <section prefix="(iv)">A holder of a Class A beer and light wine or beer, wine and liquor license may exercise the off-sale license privilege on the 2 Sundays preceding Passover if:<section prefix="1.">That holder does not exercise the off-sale privilege on the 2 Saturdays preceding Passover;</section><section prefix="2.">The off-premises sales are conducted on those Sundays between the hours of 6 a.m. and 12 midnight; and</section><section prefix="3.">The sales are limited to alcoholic beverages that are "kosher for Passover".</section></section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(5)">In Caroline County a Class B and Class C beer or beer, wine and liquor licensee may sell alcoholic beverages at a bar or counter on Sunday.</section>
      <section prefix="(6)">The prohibition specified in paragraph (1) of this subsection does not apply in Carroll County.</section>
      <section prefix="(7)">In Prince George's County, a Class B and Class C beer or beer, wine and liquor licensee may sell alcoholic beverages at a bar or counter on Sunday when December 24 and 31 fall on a Sunday.</section>
      <section prefix="(8)">
        <section prefix="(i)">In Washington County, except as provided in subparagraphs (ii) and (iii) of this paragraph, a Class A, Class B, and Class C on-sale licensee may sell alcoholic beverages on Sunday from 12 noon to 12 midnight.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">A Class B and Class C on-sale licensee may sell alcoholic beverages on Sunday from 11 a.m. to 12 noon in Washington County if:<section prefix="1.">The consumer places an order for a meal simultaneously or before placing an order for an alcoholic beverage; or</section><section prefix="2.">The consumer is entitled to a meal on the licensed premises as part of a prearranged event.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">When a federal holiday falls on a Monday, a Class A, Class B, Class C, or Class D on-sale licensee may sell alcoholic beverages from 12 noon on the immediately preceding Sunday to 2 a.m. on Monday.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(9)">In Garrett County, Sunday sales, where permitted, are governed by subsection (b)(5) of this section, &#xA7; 11-402 of this subtitle, and &#xA7; 11-512 of this title.</section>
      <section prefix="(10)">The prohibition specified in paragraph (1) of this subsection does not apply in Charles County.</section>
      <section prefix="(11)">The prohibition specified in paragraph (1) of this subsection does not apply in Dorchester County.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">In the jurisdictions in which this subsection is applicable, it is unlawful for anyone to sell or for any licensed dealer to deliver, give away or otherwise dispose of any alcoholic beverages on Sunday.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">Any person selling or any licensed dealer delivering, giving away or otherwise disposing of such beverages in such jurisdictions on Sundays is guilty of a misdemeanor and shall be fined not more than $50 for the first offense and not more than $100, or imprisoned in the county jail for not more than 30 days, or both for each succeeding offense.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">This subsection is applicable to Caroline, Cecil, Garrett, except as provided in paragraph (5) of this subsection, Harford, Kent, Queen Anne's, except as provided in subparagraph (v) of this paragraph, Somerset, Talbot, and Worcester (except as otherwise provided) counties.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">It does not apply to or affect special Class C licenses issued under the provisions of this article.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">In Washington County this section:<section prefix="1.">Does not apply to any Class A, Class B, Class C, Class D, and any special Sunday license from the hours of 12 noon to 12 midnight;</section><section prefix="2.">Does not apply to Sunday sales when New Year's Eve or New Year's Day falls on a Sunday which is governed by &#xA7; 11-402(w) of this article;</section><section prefix="3.">Provides that licensees selling alcoholic beverages on Sunday, except for holders of Class A light wine licenses for wineries, shall pay an annual fee of $250 in addition to their annual license fee; and</section><section prefix="4.">Provides that licensees may purchase a 1 day on-sale license for Sunday sale of alcoholic beverages when New Year's Eve falls on a Sunday. The licensee shall pay a $50 fee in addition to any other annual license fee.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(iv)">In Kent County, the hours of sale on Sunday are as provided under &#xA7; 11-515 of this article.</section>
        <section prefix="(v)">This section does not apply to holders of alcoholic beverages retail dealer licenses issued in Queen Anne's County.</section>
        <section prefix="(vi)">In Caroline County, on Sunday:<section prefix="1.">A Class A 7-day licensee may sell the alcoholic beverages authorized under the license from 8 a.m. to 12 midnight, except that if the sale of liquor is authorized under the license, liquor may only be sold from 1:00 p.m. to 12 midnight;</section><section prefix="2.">A Class C (clubs) beer, wine and liquor licensee may sell beer and wine:</section><section prefix="3.">A Class C (clubs) beer, wine and liquor licensee may sell liquor:</section><section prefix="4.">A Class C (clubs) beer licensee may sell beer from 8 a.m. to 12 midnight;</section><section prefix="5.">A Class D (taverns) beer, wine and liquor licensee may sell beer, wine, and liquor from 1 p.m. to midnight; and</section><section prefix="6.">A Class GC 7-day (golf course) beer, wine and liquor licensee may sell beer, wine, and liquor from 1 p.m. to 12 midnight.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(vii)">Notwithstanding the other provisions of this section and &#xA7; 11-508 of this title, in Cecil County it is lawful for Class C (on-sale) (clubs) beer, beer and light wine, or beer, wine and liquor licensees to permit the use and consumption of alcoholic beverages between the hours of 8 a.m. on Sunday and 2 a.m. the following day, and it is lawful for all classes of alcoholic beverage license holders to sell alcoholic beverages between 12 midnight and 2 a.m. on Sundays.</section>
        <section prefix="(viii)">In Worcester County the prohibition of this section is not applicable to Class B beer, wine and liquor licenses regulated by the provisions of &#xA7; 11-524 of this title.</section>
        <section prefix="(ix)">Where the provisions of this section are in conflict with &#xA7;&#xA7; 11-402 and 11-513 of this title for Harford County &#xA7;&#xA7; 11-402 and 11-513 shall govern.</section>
        <section prefix="(x)">For Somerset County the provisions of this section are subordinate to &#xA7; 11-520 of this title.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">In Talbot County it is lawful for a Class A beer licensee and a Class B beer, wine and liquor licensee to sell beer between the hours of 8:00 a.m. and 10:00 p.m. on Sundays. Between the hours of 12:30 o'clock p.m. and 10:00 o'clock p.m. on Sundays, it is lawful for a Class B or C beer licensee to sell beer and for a Class B or C beer, wine and liquor licensee to sell beer, wine and liquor, provided that these alcoholic beverages are consumed on the premises.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">In Allegany County, Sunday sales when New Year's Eve or New Year's Day falls on a Sunday are governed by &#xA7; 11-402(b) of this subtitle.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">
        <section prefix="(i)">This paragraph applies only in Garrett County.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">When New Year's Eve or New Year's Day falls on a Sunday, sales shall be governed by &#xA7; 11-402(m) of this subtitle.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">Provisions for Sunday sales for Class B and C licensees are governed by &#xA7; 11-512(c) of this title.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
