<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="g2b" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="12-113" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>g2b-12-113</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">For the prevention and detection of fraud by manufacturers, wholesalers and retail dealers, the Comptroller and/or the local liquor licensing boards shall be empowered to prescribe for use, and to authorize any of their deputies or inspectors to make use of such hydrometers, saccharometers, weighing and gauging instruments or other means, records or devices for ascertaining the quantity and/or quality of alcohol in any alcoholic beverage as they may deem necessary, and they may prescribe rules and regulations to secure a uniform and correct system of inspection, marking and gauging of all such beverages.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">No retail dealer or agent or employee of such retail dealer shall tamper with, by the addition to, or the change in any manner whatsoever of the quantity or quality, of the contents of any container of alcoholic beverages after such container of alcoholic beverages has been sealed in accordance with the laws of the United States and/or the laws of the State of Maryland, and while the contents remain in the original container.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Except as provided in &#xA7; 8-203(e) of this article, no retail dealer, or agent or employee of such retail dealer shall refill any container of alcoholic beverages with any substance whatsoever after such container has once been emptied of its original contents.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">No retail dealer shall keep or possess any container or containers of alcoholic beverages that have been tampered with in violation of subsection (b) of this section and no retail dealer shall keep or possess any container or containers of alcoholic beverages that have been refilled in violation of subsection (c) of this section. Any person violating any of the provisions of this section shall be deemed guilty of a misdemeanor and upon conviction thereof shall be subject to a fine of not more than one thousand dollars ($1,000.00) or to imprisonment for not more than two years in the house of correction or jail, or both fined and imprisoned in the discretion of the court.</section>
  </text>
</law>
