<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="g2b" order_by="" level="1">Alcoholic Beverages</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>g2b-5-201</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>201</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A Class B beer and light wine license shall be issued by the license issuing authority of the county in which the place of business is located. The holder may keep for sale and sell beer and light wines at retail at any hotel or restaurant, at the place described in the license, for consumption on the premises or elsewhere.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The annual fee shall be paid to the local collecting agent before any license is issued.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">This section does not apply in Allegany County.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This subsection applies only in Anne Arundel County.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The annual license fee for a Class B beer and light wine license is $480.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">In Baltimore City the annual license fee is $165.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In Baltimore County the annual license fee is $300.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The area of the licensed premises normally used as a restaurant for the preparation and consumption of food and beverage on the premises may occupy no less than 80 percent of the square foot area. These occupancy requirements do not apply to or affect any present licensee having this license prior to December 31, 1966.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">In Calvert County the annual license fee is $250.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">In Caroline County the annual license fee is $500.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">In Carroll County the annual license fee is:<section prefix="(1)">$160 for a 6-day license; and</section><section prefix="(2)">$1,000 for a 7-day license.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(i)">In Cecil County the annual license fee is $90.</section>
    <section prefix="(j)">This section does not apply in Charles County.</section>
    <section prefix="(k)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In Dorchester County the annual license fee is $300.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">On or after July 1, 2008, a Class B (on-sale) beer and light wine license shall be issued:<section prefix="(i)">Only to restaurants; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Without seating capacity restrictions.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A holder of a Class B (on-sale and off-sale) beer and light wine license issued on or before June 30, 2008, may:<section prefix="(i)">Continue to exercise all of the privileges of the license throughout the term of the license; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Renew the license.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The Dorchester County Board of License Commissioners may not approve the transfer of a Class B (on-sale and off-sale) beer and light wine license issued on or before June 30, 2008.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(l)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This subsection applies only in Frederick County.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The annual license fee is $160.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The area of the licensed premises normally used as a restaurant for the preparation and consumption of food and beverages on the premises may occupy no less than 80 percent of the square foot area, except for recreational use premises such as bowling alleys and pool halls.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The provisions of this paragraph of this subsection do not apply to or affect any licensee that had a license on December 31, 1993, or to any person who has a permit for a building that was under construction on that date.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(m)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This subsection applies only  in Garrett County.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">In this subsection, "license" means a Class B beer and light wine license.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Board of License Commissioners may issue a Class B beer and light wine license for use in:<section prefix="(i)">A bona fide hotel, motel, or inn that:<section prefix="1.">Is an establishment that accommodates the public;</section><section prefix="2.">Provides services ordinarily found in hotels, motels, or inns;</section><section prefix="3.">Is equipped with at least 10 bedrooms for public accommodation; and</section><section prefix="4.">Has a lobby with a registration and mail desk and seating facilities; or</section></section><section prefix="(ii)">A restaurant that:<section prefix="1.">Has a seating capacity at tables, not including seats at bars or counters, for at least 20 persons; and</section><section prefix="2.">Can prepare and serve full-course meals for at least 20 persons at one seating.</section></section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The Board of License Commissioners may issue a license without or with a catering option.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">A holder of a license  without a catering option  may sell:<section prefix="(i)">All alcoholic beverages for consumption on the licensed premises; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Brewed beverages for consumption off the licensed premises.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(6)">
        <section prefix="(i)">In addition to exercising the privileges stated in paragraph (5) of this subsection, a holder of a license with a catering option may keep for sale and sell beer and wine for consumption at events that the holder caters off the licensed premises.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">To exercise the catering option, a holder of a license:<section prefix="1.">Shall provide food if the holder provides alcoholic beverages at a catered event off the licensed premises; and</section><section prefix="2.">May exercise the catering option only during the hours and days that are allowed under the license.</section></section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(7)">For a license without a catering option:<section prefix="(i)">The issuing fee is $350; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">The annual fee is $350.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(8)">For a license with a catering option:<section prefix="(i)">The issuing fee is $475; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">The annual fee is $475.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(9)">The Board of License Commissioners may adopt regulations to carry out this subsection.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(n)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This subsection applies only in Harford County.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">
          <section prefix="1.">The annual license fee for a Class B-1 6-day restaurant license is $350.</section>
          <section prefix="2.">A Class B-1 6-day restaurant license is a 6-day, Monday through Saturday, license which may be issued by the Liquor Control Board to bona fide restaurants.</section>
        </section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">
          <section prefix="1.">The annual license fee for a Class B-1 7-day restaurant license is $500.</section>
          <section prefix="2.">A Class B-1 7-day restaurant license is a 7-day license which may be issued by the Liquor Control Board to bona fide restaurants.</section>
        </section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">The licensee shall comply with the food sale requirements of &#xA7; 1-102(a)(22) of this article only for the purpose of meeting the requirements of &#xA7; 6-201(n) of this article necessary to apply for a Class B restaurant license.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">
          <section prefix="1.">The annual license fee for a Class B-2 6-day restaurant license is $500.</section>
          <section prefix="2.">A Class B-2 6-day restaurant license is a 6-day, Monday through Saturday, license which may be issued by the Liquor Control Board to restaurants.</section>
        </section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">
          <section prefix="1.">The annual license fee for a Class B-2 7-day restaurant license is $700.</section>
          <section prefix="2.">A Class B-2 7-day restaurant license is a 7-day license which may be issued by the Liquor Control Board to bona fide restaurants.</section>
        </section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">These licenses may be issued to a licensee who has been operating that business establishment for one year prior to the application for the license and who, in the judgment of the Board, is equipped and stocked for the continued regular sale of food to customers and guests. The licensee does not have to comply with the food sale requirement set forth in &#xA7; 1-102(a)(22) of this article.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(4)">
        <section prefix="(i)">As to any Class B-1 or B-2 restaurant license issued prior to July 1, 1984, "off-sales" of licensees shall be limited to fermented beverages including split bottles and brewed beverages. However, brewed beverages sold in bottles or cans exceeding 12 ounces in weight or size, for consumption off the premises, may be sold in a numerical quantity of less than six. If brewed beverages are sold in a containerized package, the package shall hold a minimum of 6 bottles or containers.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">As to any Class B-1 or B-2 restaurant license issued on or after July 1, 1984, "off-sales" by Class B-1 and B-2 licensees are prohibited.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(5)">Provisions relating to Class B-3 licenses are found in &#xA7; 6-201(n)(3) of this article.</section>
      <section prefix="(6)">
        <section prefix="(i)">There is a Class B Cafe beer and wine license.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The annual license fee is $1,575.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">A cafe license entitles the holder to sell beer and wine for consumption on and off the licensed premises.	</section>
        <section prefix="(iv)">A cafe license is a 7-day license with an on-premises wine tasting privilege for every day of the year.</section>
        <section prefix="(v)">The Liquor Control Board may issue not more than five cafe licenses.</section>
        <section prefix="(vi)">The Liquor Control Board shall set a maximum  and a minimum seating capacity for each cafe license it issues.</section>
        <section prefix="(vii)">A cafe license may be exercised at an establishment only if:<section prefix="1.">The Liquor Control Board determines that the establishment has adequate tables, chairs, food, and facilities for preparing and serving meals;</section><section prefix="2.">The average gross monthly receipts from the sale of cooked or prepared food served at the establishment and other items approved by the Liquor Control Board exceed 50% of the average monthly receipts from the sale of beer and wine sold for on-premises consumption; and</section><section prefix="3.">Not more than 10% of the total square footage of the establishment is  dedicated to the public display of beer and wine  that is offered for sale.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(viii)">A cafe license may not be used for off-premises catering.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(o)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This subsection applies only in Howard County.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The annual license fee is $175.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Any restaurant that meets the definition of a restaurant under &#xA7; 1-102(a)(22) of this article may apply to the Board of License Commissioners for a Class B beer and light wine license.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(p)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This subsection applies only in Kent County.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The annual license fee is $1,000.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Any restaurant qualifying under &#xA7; 6-201(p)(2)(ii) and (iii) of this article may apply to the Board of License Commissioners for a special Class B beer and light wine license.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(q)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This subsection applies only in Montgomery County.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The annual license fee is $400.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">In this paragraph, "establishment" means a bowling alley, billiard hall, or drugstore or a restaurant located within these businesses.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">A license may not be issued to, or for use in conjunction with, or upon the premises of any establishment or for use upon any premises which has a door, archway, opening or other passageway providing direct public access to any establishment.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(r)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This subsection applies only in Prince George's County.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The annual license fee is $365.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Notwithstanding the provisions of subsection (a) of this section, the Board of License Commissioners may not issue any Class B beer and light wine license with other than the privilege of selling beer and light wine for consumption on the licensed premises (on-sale only).</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">However, licensees holding this class of license prior to July 1, 1975, who have been exercising the privilege of selling alcoholic beverages for consumption off the licensed premises may continue to exercise this privilege.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(4)">
        <section prefix="(i)">There is a Class B-Stadium beer and light wine license.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The annual license fee is $2,420.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">The license is a special 7-day Class B-Stadium (baseball stadium) license for on-sale consumption only for exclusive use on the premises of a baseball stadium owned or operated by the Maryland-National Capital Park and Planning Commission.</section>
        <section prefix="(iv)">The license may be issued either to the Maryland-National Capital Park and Planning Commission or to a private concessionaire that is under contract with the Commission.</section>
        <section prefix="(v)">Alcoholic beverages may be sold only by employees who are 18 years old or older.</section>
        <section prefix="(vi)">The residency requirement specified by &#xA7; 9-101 of this article does not apply to an applicant for a Class B-Stadium license.</section>
        <section prefix="(vii)">Any profit from the sale of beer or light wine made by the licensee may accrue to the benefit and use of either the Commission or the concessionaire.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(s)">In Queen Anne's County the annual license fee is $500.</section>
    <section prefix="(t)">In St. Mary's County the annual license fee is $400.</section>
    <section prefix="(u)">In Somerset County the annual license fee is $253.</section>
    <section prefix="(v)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This section does not apply in Talbot County.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Section 18-101 of this article permits the Talbot County Council to provide for the retail alcoholic beverage laws for the county which, if enacted, supersede the provisions of this article.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(w)">In Washington County the annual license fee is $200.</section>
    <section prefix="(x)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In Wicomico County the annual license fee is $400.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">This license may be issued only for a hotel or restaurant that has the average daily receipts from the sale of food for each month exceed the average daily receipts from the sale of alcoholic beverages.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">In calculating average daily receipts from the sale of food, an allocation of foodstuff contained in a mixed drink may not be included in average daily receipts from the sale of food.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(y)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This subsection applies only in Worcester County.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The annual license fee for a 6 day license is $300.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The annual license fee for a 7 day license, applied countywide (exclusive of tenth election district) is $400.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The annual license fee for a 7 day license, tenth election district only is $400.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
