<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="g2b" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="2-206" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>g2b-2-206</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">A Class 5 manufacturer's license:<section prefix="(1)">Is a brewery license; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Authorizes the holder to:<section prefix="(i)">Establish and operate in this State a plant for brewing and bottling malt beverages at the location described in the license;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Import beer from holders of nonresident dealer's permits; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Sell and deliver beer to any wholesale licensee in this State, or person outside of this State, authorized to acquire it.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A licensee may:<section prefix="(1)">Serve to a person of legal drinking age who participates in a guided tour of the facility or attends a scheduled promotional event or other organized activity at the licensed premises, not more than six samples of beer brewed at the licensed premises, with each sample consisting of not more than 3 ounces from a single style of beer; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Sell beer brewed at the brewery for off-premises consumption to anyone who participates in a guided tour of the brewery or attends a scheduled promotional event or other organized activity at the licensed premises, subject to the following restrictions:<section prefix="(i)">The purchase is limited to 288 ounces of beer per person; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">The person has attained the legal drinking age.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Office of the Comptroller may issue a special brewery promotional event permit to a holder of a Class 5 manufacturer's license.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The permit authorizes the holder to conduct on the premises of the brewery a promotional event at which the holder may:<section prefix="(i)">Provide samples of not more than 3 fluid ounces per brand to consumers; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Sell beer produced by the holder to persons who participate in the event.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The beer at the event shall be sold by the glass and for consumption on the premises only.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">A holder of a Class 5 manufacturer's license may not be issued more than 12 permits in a calendar year.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">A single promotional event may not exceed 3 consecutive days.</section>
      <section prefix="(6)">The permit fee is $25 per event.</section>
      <section prefix="(7)">To obtain a permit, a person, at least 15 days before the event, shall file with the Office of the Comptroller an application that the Office provides.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
