<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="g2b" order_by="" level="1">Alcoholic Beverages</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>g2b-8-310.1</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>310.1</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Board" means the Montgomery County Board of License Commissioners.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Festival" means the Montgomery County Wine Festival.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">"Festival organization" means a nonprofit organization that is selected by Montgomery County to organize the festival and that has extensive experience in organizing and managing large-scale public events.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">This section applies only in Montgomery County.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Under the supervision of the Montgomery County Department of Liquor Control, the county each year may conduct the Montgomery County Wine Festival on not more than 4 weekends that a festival organization selects.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A festival organization may contract with holders of a Montgomery County retail alcoholic beverage license, a State Class 3 winery license, or a State Class 4 limited winery license to sell and display wine at the festival.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A festival organization, through contractors who hold a special festival license issued under subsection (g) of this section, may display and sell wine that is price filed in accordance with regulations adopted by the State Comptroller and distributed in the State.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Wine may be displayed and sold at retail for consumption on or off the premises on the days and for the hours designated for the festival.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">A festival organization:<section prefix="(1)">Shall choose for the festival a location that is a licensed or an unlicensed premises in the county; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Shall assure that the primary focus of the festival is the promotion of Montgomery County.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Before a person may sell, offer for sale, or display wine at a festival, the person must contract with the festival organization and obtain a special festival license from the Board.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The license fee is $30 for each day of the festival.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, a person may hold a special festival license in addition to another license issued under this article.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The Board may deny a special festival license to any applicant, suspend or revoke a special festival license, or impose a fine not exceeding $20,000 if the applicant or license holder violates a provision of this article or the regulations of the Board.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, all license fees collected under this subsection shall be deposited into the general fund of the county.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(h)">The Board shall adopt regulations for implementing this section.</section>
  </text>
</law>
