<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="g2b" order_by="2" level="1">Alcoholic Beverages</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>g2b-9-219</section_number>
  <catch_line>This section applies only in St. Mary's County....</catch_line>
  <order_by>219</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">This section applies only in St. Mary's County.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, the Board of License Commissioners may not approve any application for a license to sell alcoholic beverages in any building the nearest wall of which measured in a direct line is within 300 feet of the nearest point of the main buildings of any public or nonpublic kindergarten, elementary or secondary school, church or other place of worship.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Paragraph (1) of this subsection is not applicable:<section prefix="(i)">To an application for a Class B (on-sale) beer, wine and liquor license for a premises located in Leonardtown; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">In the event any school, church, or other place of worship locates its building within 300 feet of any licensed premises after the licensed premises are there established.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Board of License Commissioners may not issue or transfer an off-sale alcoholic beverages license of any class for the use in a business that is intended to be operated as a drive-through purchase facility where alcoholic beverages are to be sold at retail and dispensed through a window or door to a purchaser in or on a motor vehicle for off-premises consumption.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Board of License Commissioners:<section prefix="(i)">May not issue more than 1 Class A alcoholic beverages license with an off-sale privilege for each unit of 1,350 people in each election district in the county; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Shall maintain the license quota stated in item (i) of this paragraph by using the population figures of the most recent St. Mary's County Planning Commission annual report.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A license issued under this subsection may not be transferred from one election district to another election district unless the transfer can be made without exceeding the license quota stated in paragraph (1)(i) of this subsection.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
