<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="g2b" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="11-516" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>g2b-11-516</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In Montgomery County, notwithstanding any other provisions of this subtitle, a holder of an alcoholic beverage license may not sell any alcoholic beverages between the hours of 1 a.m. and 10 a.m. on Sunday, except holders of Class A (off-sale) beer licenses and Class A (off-sale) beer and light wine licenses and Class B-BWL, Class B-BWL (H-M) and Class C, beer, wine and liquor licenses; Class B and Class D beer licenses and Class B and Class D beer and light wine licenses.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The privileges conferred by a Class C beer, wine and liquor license (on-sale - generally) may be exercised from 6 a.m. to 2 a.m. on the day following, except that a sale may not be made on Sunday between the hours of 2 a.m. and 10 a.m.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">This paragraph applies only to Class C beer, wine and liquor licenses issued pursuant to &#xA7; 6-301(q)(4) of this article.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The hours during which this license may be exercised are from 11 a.m. of one day to 1 p.m. the following day.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">This paragraph applies only to Class C beer, wine and liquor licenses issued pursuant to &#xA7; 6-301(q)(5) and (6) of this article.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">On Mondays through Saturdays, alcoholic beverages may not be sold, served, or consumed on the licensed premises before 11 a.m. or after 1 a.m. the following day. Alcoholic beverages may not be sold, served, or consumed on the licensed premises on Sundays between 1 a.m. and 12 noon.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The privileges conferred by a Class B beer, wine and liquor license (on-sale generally) and a Class B beer, wine and liquor (H-M) license may be exercised during the following hours, provided that the licensed establishment sells or makes available food for consumption on the premises during the hours that alcoholic beverages are permitted to be served:<section prefix="(1)">On Monday, Tuesday, Wednesday, and Thursday sales are permitted from 9 a.m. to 1 a.m. on the following day;</section><section prefix="(2)">On Friday and Saturday, sales are permitted from 9 a.m. to 2 a.m. on the following day;</section><section prefix="(3)">On Sunday, sales are permitted from 10 a.m. to 1 a.m. on the following day; provided, however, that sales are permitted until 2 a.m. on the following day when the following day (Monday) has been designated by the federal government as one of the following holidays: Washington's Birthday, Memorial Day, Independence Day, Labor Day, Veterans Day and Christmas.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The privileges conferred on a Class A (off-sale) beer license and Class A (off-sale) beer and light wine license may be exercised from 6 a.m. to 1 a.m. the day following for every day including Sunday.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The privileges conferred on a Class B and Class D beer license and the privileges conferred on a Class B and Class D beer and light wine license may be exercised from 6 a.m. to 1 a.m. the day following for every day including Sunday for off sale.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
