<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="g2b" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="13-101" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>g2b-13-101</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section "alcohol awareness program" means a program:<section prefix="(1)">That:<section prefix="(i)">Is approved and certified by the State Comptroller; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Has been issued an alcohol awareness program permit by the State Comptroller;</section></section><section prefix="(2)">That includes instruction on how alcohol affects a person's:<section prefix="(i)">Body; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Behavior;</section></section><section prefix="(3)">That provides education on the dangers of drinking and driving; and</section><section prefix="(4)">That defines effective methods for:<section prefix="(i)">Serving customers to minimize the chance of intoxication;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Ceasing service before the customer becomes intoxicated; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Determining if a customer is under the drinking age.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The provisions of this section apply to:<section prefix="(i)">Licensed premises that are operated by selling alcoholic beverages directly to a customer from a bar or service bar on the premises;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Premises licensed for off sale;</section><section prefix="(iii)">In Montgomery County, a holder of a caterer's license issued under &#xA7; 6-706.1 of this article; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">In Baltimore City, an establishment covered under &#xA7; 20-102(a) of this article.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">This section does not apply to:<section prefix="(i)">Temporary alcoholic beverages licenses issued under &#xA7; 7-101 of this article;</section><section prefix="(ii)">A Class E (on-sale) steamboat alcoholic beverages license;</section><section prefix="(iii)">A Class F (on-sale) railroad alcoholic beverages license; or</section><section prefix="(iv)">A Class G (on-sale) aircraft alcoholic beverages license.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A holder of any class of retail alcoholic beverages license or an employee designated by the holder shall complete training in an approved alcohol awareness program. The training shall be valid for a period of 4 years, and the holder shall complete retraining in an approved program for each successive 4-year period.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">This paragraph applies only in the following jurisdictions:</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">This paragraph does not apply to a licensee in Wicomico County with a Class C license.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">The licensee or a person who is employed in a supervisory capacity designated by the licensee:</section>
        <section prefix="(iv)"/>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">This paragraph applies only in Harford County.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The licensee or a person who is employed in a supervisory capacity designated by the licensee shall be certified by an approved alcohol awareness program and shall be present during the hours in which alcohol may be sold.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(4)">
        <section prefix="(i)">This paragraph applies only to an establishment covered under &#xA7; 20-102(a) of this article, in Baltimore City.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">Any bottle club owner or a person who is employed in a supervisory capacity designated by the owner shall be certified by an approved alcohol awareness program and shall be present during the hours in which alcohol is served or consumed.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Any licensee who violates the provisions of subsection (c) of this section is subject to:<section prefix="(1)">For the first offense, a $100 fine; and</section><section prefix="(2)">For each subsequent offense, a fine not to exceed $500 or a suspension or revocation of the license or both.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The State Comptroller:<section prefix="(i)">Shall approve and certify each alcohol awareness program that is in compliance with this section; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">May require recertification of the approved program to insure compliance with any changes in the program.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Any individual who is authorized or employed to teach an alcohol awareness program must obtain an alcohol awareness instructor's permit.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Each local licensing board is responsible for enforcing this section, including the penalty provision.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">
        <section prefix="(i)">A certificate of completion shall be issued for each completion of a certified program and it shall be valid for 4 years from the date of issuance.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">An up-to-date valid certificate shall be presented to the proper authority upon request.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(5)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Within 5 days after a licensee, bottle club owner, or an employee of a licensee or bottle club owner is sent a certificate of completion, the program provider shall inform the appropriate local licensing board of:</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">Any program provider who violates the provisions of this subsection is subject to a decertification of the program by the State Comptroller.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This section may not be construed to create or enlarge any civil cause of action or criminal proceeding against a licensee.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Evidence of a violation of this section may not be introduced in any civil or criminal proceeding, but may only be used as evidence before the local licensing board in actions brought before the board for violations of this section.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">The Comptroller may issue regulations to set standards and requirements pertaining to course content, course duration, course format and any other course related activities the Comptroller may require.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This subsection applies only in Dorchester County.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A certificate of completion of a certified alcohol awareness program held by an employee or an employee's employer may not be used at more than one licensed establishment.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
