<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="g2b" order_by="" level="1">Alcoholic Beverages</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>g2b-14-101</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>101</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Repealed.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">In Garrett County no retail license which has been refused, suspended or revoked after July 1, 1971, shall be granted until the applicant shall have executed a bond to the State of Maryland in the penal sum of one thousand dollars ($1,000.00), with two sufficient sureties to be approved by the Liquor Control Board of Garrett County, conditioned for the faithful observance of all laws of this State relating to the sale or furnishing of beer, or other alcoholic beverages and to pay all costs, fines, and penalties which may be imposed upon him or them on any warrant or indictment for violation of this article or any other act of assembly relating to selling or furnishing beer or any other alcoholic beverage in Garrett County, and the said bond when so approved shall be deposited with the Board of License Commissioners who shall record the same in a book to be kept by it for that purpose, and the record thereof, or a duly certified copy, shall be evidenced in any court of law.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">In Harford County no retail license which has been previously refused, suspended or revoked, shall be granted until the applicant shall have executed a bond to the State of Maryland in the penal sum of $1,000, with a corporate surety to be approved by the Liquor Control Board of Harford County, conditioned upon the faithful observance of all the laws of this State, general or local, and the regulations of the Board, controlling or affecting the sale of alcoholic beverages, and to pay all costs, fines and penalties which may be imposed upon the applicant, on any warrant or indictment for violation of this article or any other act of assembly or regulation of the Board relating to selling or furnishing alcoholic beverages in Harford County. The bond, when so approved, shall be deposited with the Board and recorded in a book to be kept for that purpose, and the record thereof, or a duly certified copy, shall be evidence in any court of record. If this bond has been provided for one calendar year and the Liquor Control Board finds that the licensee has complied faithfully with the terms thereof, then thereafter the Liquor Control Board may in its discretion waive the requirements of posting bond under this section. In the event of the failure to observe the terms of the bond and after due notice, the Liquor Control Board may file a petition for a forfeiture with the Circuit Court for Harford County. If the circuit court declares it forfeited, the bond shall belong to the Liquor Control Board. In lieu of the foregoing bond, the Liquor Control Board of Harford County may, in its discretion, accept $1,000 cash money, the deposit of the same to be deposited, conditioned, recorded and, if deemed advisable, waived. The Board may also, in its discretion, subsequently accept a bond as aforesaid in substitution of the cash money deposit.</section>
  </text>
</law>
