<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="g2b" order_by="2" level="1">Alcoholic Beverages</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>g2b-10-103</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this section the following words have the meanings indicated....</catch_line>
  <order_by>103</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Central Repository" means the Criminal Justice Information System Central Repository of the Department of Public Safety and Correctional Services.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"County police" as it applies to Harford County includes the Harford County Sheriff's Department and all Harford County municipal police departments.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(a-1)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This subsection applies to any criminal history records check requested by a local licensing board under this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The local licensing board shall apply to the Central Repository for a State and national criminal history records check for each applicant and license holder.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">As part of the application for a criminal history records check, the local licensing board shall submit to the Central Repository:<section prefix="(i)">Two complete sets of legible fingerprints of the applicant or license holder taken on forms approved by the Director of the Central Repository and the Director of the Federal Bureau of Investigation;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The fee authorized under &#xA7; 10-221(b)(7) of the Criminal Procedure Article for access to Maryland criminal history records; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">The mandatory processing fee that the Federal Bureau of Investigation requires for a national criminal history records check.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">In accordance with Title 10, Subtitle 2 of the Criminal Procedure Article, the Central Repository shall forward to the applicant or license holder and the local licensing board the criminal history record information of the applicant or licensee.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">Information obtained from the Central Repository under this section:<section prefix="(i)">Shall be confidential;</section><section prefix="(ii)">May not be redisseminated; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Shall be used only for the licensing purpose authorized by this section.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(6)">The subject of a criminal history records check under this subsection may contest the contents of the printed statement issued by the Central Repository as provided in &#xA7; 10-223 of the Criminal Procedure Article.</section>
      <section prefix="(7)">When criminal history record information of an applicant or license holder is reported to the Central Repository after the initial criminal history records check is completed, the Central Repository shall provide the local licensing board with a revised printed statement of the criminal record of the applicant or license holder.</section>
      <section prefix="(8)">If the local licensing board informs the Central Repository that an individual is no longer an applicant or license holder, the Central Repository shall stop providing the local licensing board with revised printed statements of the criminal record of the individual.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Except as otherwise provided in this subtitle, every new application for a license shall be made to the Board of License Commissioners on forms prescribed by the Comptroller and sworn to by the applicant. Every application for a license shall contain the following:<section prefix="(1)">The class of license desired;</section><section prefix="(2)">The name and residence of the applicant and how long he has resided at that address;</section><section prefix="(3)"><section prefix="(i)">A statement that the applicant is a citizen of the United States; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">In Prince George's County, if the applicant is not a citizen of the United States, a statement that the applicant is in legal status in accordance with federal law;</section></section><section prefix="(3-a)"><section prefix="(i)">In Baltimore County and Howard County, a statement whether the applicant is a natural-born citizen or a naturalized citizen and, if the applicant is not a natural-born citizen or a naturalized citizen, information or documentation required by the Baltimore County Board of Liquor License Commissioners or the Board of License Commissioners of Howard County to show proof of alien status.</section><section prefix="(ii)">The Baltimore County Board of Liquor License Commissioners and the Board of License Commissioners of Howard County may obtain information from the Social Security Administration and the Department of Homeland Security - Immigration and Customs to verify the applicant's citizenship or alien status.</section></section><section prefix="(4)"><section prefix="(i)">Except as provided in subparagraphs (ii) and (iv) of this paragraph, a statement that the applicant has been for two years next preceding the filing of the application a resident of the county or of the City of Baltimore in which the applicant proposes to operate under the license applied for. The Board of License Commissioners of Prince George's County shall apply the residency requirements as specified in &#xA7; 9-101 of this article;</section><section prefix="(ii)">In Dorchester County the residency requirement is 1 year;</section><section prefix="(iii)">In Carroll County, in addition to the applicant's residential statement required under this section, the license shall remain valid only for as long as the resident applicant remains a resident of the county;</section><section prefix="(iv)">In Baltimore County, a statement that the applicant has been for 2 years next preceding the filing of the application a resident of the State.</section></section><section prefix="(5)">The age and sex of the applicant;</section><section prefix="(6)">Except as provided in subsection (b-1) of this section, the place of birth of the applicant, and if a naturalized citizen, when and where the applicant was naturalized;</section><section prefix="(7)">The particular place for which a license is desired, designating the same by street and number if practicable; if not, by such other apt description as definitely locates it and also a description of the portion of the building in which the business will be conducted;</section><section prefix="(8)">The name of the owner of the premises upon which the business sought to be licensed is to be carried on;</section><section prefix="(9)"><section prefix="(i)">A statement that the applicant has never been convicted of a felony and a further statement as to whether he has ever been adjudged guilty of violating the laws governing the sale of alcoholic beverages or for the prevention of gambling in the State of Maryland;</section><section prefix="(ii)">In Worcester County a statement that the applicant has never offered a plea of nolo contendere to a felony indictment which was accepted by a court;</section><section prefix="(iii)">In Somerset and Wicomico counties, a statement that the applicant consents to the Board investigating the applicant's criminal record; and</section><section prefix="(iv)"><section prefix="1.">In Prince George's and Worcester counties, a signed statement by the applicant that the applicant has not been convicted of a felony or if the application is being made for the use of a corporation, that the applicant and none of the stockholders of that corporation have been convicted of a felony;</section><section prefix="2.">In Worcester County, that the owner of the corporation has not been convicted of a felony; and</section><section prefix="3.">In Charles County, a signed statement by the applicant that the applicant has not been convicted of a felony, or, except for an applicant for a Class B beer, wine and liquor (BLX) luxury restaurant license, if the application is being made for the use of a corporation, that the applicant and none of the stockholders of that corporation have been convicted of a felony;</section></section><section prefix="(v)"><section prefix="1."/><section prefix="2.">This subparagraph applies only in Somerset County.</section><section prefix="3.">The Board shall:</section><section prefix="4.">The Board may not disseminate information from criminal records to the public but may make information from criminal records available to members of the Board and their designees.</section><section prefix="5.">The Board shall charge an applicant a fee to cover the cost of fingerprinting and performing a State and national criminal history records check.</section><section prefix="6.">The Board may exempt from this subparagraph a license holder who seeks to renew an alcoholic beverages license.</section></section></section><section prefix="(10)">A statement that the applicant has a pecuniary interest in the business to be conducted under said license;</section><section prefix="(11)">A statement that the applicant has not had a license for the sale of alcoholic beverages revoked;</section><section prefix="(12)">A statement that the applicant, or person on behalf of whom the application is filed, is not pecuniarily interested in any other place of business in said county or City of Baltimore where or for which a license has been applied for, granted or issued under this article, except as otherwise permitted in this article;</section><section prefix="(13)"><section prefix="(i)"><section prefix="1.">A statement as to whether the applicant has ever been adjudged guilty of any offense against the laws of the State or of the United States.</section><section prefix="2.">The respective boards shall destroy the records obtained under subparagraphs (ii), (iv), (v), (vi), (vii), (viii), (ix), and (xii) of this paragraph upon completion of its necessary use of the records;</section></section><section prefix="(ii)"><section prefix="1.">The provisions of this subparagraph (ii) apply in the following:</section><section prefix="2.">The county board of license commissioners or the liquor control board may obtain criminal records on alcoholic beverages license applicants and their agents in its respective county from the Central Repository and county police.</section></section><section prefix="(iii)">The Worcester County Board of License Commissioners also may obtain criminal records pursuant to the provisions of subparagraph (ii) of this paragraph on the stockholders which hold at least 10% interest in the corporation and owners of a corporation when the application is being made for the use of the corporation;</section><section prefix="(iv)">In Montgomery County:<section prefix="1.">The Board of License Commissioners shall:</section><section prefix="2.">Applicants for license renewal may be subject to these provisions.</section></section><section prefix="(v)">In Frederick County:<section prefix="1.">The Board of License Commissioners shall:</section><section prefix="2.">Applicants for license renewal may not be subject to these provisions.</section></section><section prefix="(vi)"><section prefix="1.">The provisions of this subparagraph apply only in Cecil County, Charles County, Dorchester County, and Kent County.</section><section prefix="2.">The Boards of License Commissioners shall:</section><section prefix="3.">The County Commissioners may set a fee to cover the cost of obtaining the fingerprints and the Maryland and national criminal history records check.</section><section prefix="4.">Except as provided in subsubparagraph 6 of this subparagraph, the Boards shall keep all criminal records in a sealed envelope available only to the members of the Boards and the clerks to the Boards.</section><section prefix="5.">The hearing for a new applicant and the issuance of a license may not be delayed due to the failure of the Federal Bureau of Investigation to provide the requested criminal history records check by the date of the scheduled hearing.</section><section prefix="6.">The Kent County Board of License Commissioners shall:</section></section><section prefix="(vii)"><section prefix="1.">The provisions of this subparagraph apply only in Wicomico County.</section><section prefix="2.">The Board of License Commissioners shall:</section></section><section prefix="(viii)">In Harford County:<section prefix="1.">The Liquor Control Board shall:</section><section prefix="2.">Applicants for license renewal may not be subject to these provisions.</section></section><section prefix="(ix)">In Carroll County:<section prefix="1.">The Board of License Commissioners shall:</section><section prefix="2.">Applicants for license renewal may not be subject to these provisions.</section></section><section prefix="(x)"><section prefix="1.">This subparagraph applies only in Garrett County.</section><section prefix="2.">In this subparagraph, "applicant" includes:</section><section prefix="3.">The Board of License Commissioners may:</section><section prefix="4.">Criminal records shall be kept in a sealed envelope accessible only by Board members and their clerks, and the criminal records shall be destroyed on completion of their necessary use.</section></section><section prefix="(xi)"><section prefix="1.">In Calvert County, for each application for a new alcoholic beverages license or for a transfer of an existing alcoholic beverages license, the Board of License Commissioners shall:</section><section prefix="2.">This subparagraph does not apply to an alcoholic beverages license renewal applicant.</section></section><section prefix="(xii)">In Howard County:<section prefix="1.">The Board of License Commissioners shall:</section><section prefix="2.">Applicants for license renewal may be subject to this subparagraph.</section><section prefix="3.">The Board shall:</section></section><section prefix="(xiii)"><section prefix="1."/><section prefix="2.">This subparagraph applies only in Talbot County.</section><section prefix="3.">The Board shall:</section><section prefix="4.">The Board may not disseminate information from criminal records to the public but may make information from criminal records available to members of the Board and their designees.</section><section prefix="5.">The Board may charge an applicant for the cost of fingerprinting and performing a State and national criminal history records check.</section><section prefix="6.">The Board may exempt from this subparagraph a license holder who seeks to renew an alcoholic beverages license.</section></section><section prefix="(xiv)">In Baltimore City:<section prefix="1.">The Board of Liquor License Commissioners shall:</section><section prefix="2.">Applicants for license renewal may not be subject to the provisions of this subparagraph.</section></section><section prefix="(xv)"><section prefix="1.">In this subparagraph, "Board" means the Anne Arundel County Board of License Commissioners.</section><section prefix="2.">In Anne Arundel County, the Board shall apply to the Central Repository for State and national criminal history records checks for each alcoholic beverages license applicant.</section><section prefix="3.">As part of the application for a criminal history records check, the Board shall submit to the Central Repository:</section><section prefix="4.">In accordance with Title 10, Subtitle 2 of the Criminal Procedure Article, the Central Repository shall forward to the applicant and the Board the applicant's criminal history record information.</section><section prefix="5.">Information obtained from the Central Repository under this subparagraph shall be:</section><section prefix="6.">The subject of a criminal history records check under this subparagraph may contest the contents of the printed statement issued by the Central Repository under &#xA7; 10-223 of the Criminal Procedure Article.</section></section></section><section prefix="(14)">A statement as to whether the applicant has ever held a license for the sale of alcoholic beverages, and if so, in what state and at what location therein;</section><section prefix="(15)">A statement that no person except the applicant is in any way pecuniarily interested in said license or in the business to be conducted thereunder during the continuance of the license applied for, and a further statement that no manufacturer, brewer, distiller, or wholesaler, directly or indirectly, has any financial interest in the premises or business of the applicant and that the applicant will not thereafter convey or grant to any such manufacturer, brewer, distiller or wholesaler any such interest, except as otherwise permitted in this article; and that the applicant has at the time of making the application no indebtedness or other financial obligations and will not thereafter incur any such indebtedness or other financial obligation, directly or indirectly, to any manufacturer, brewer, distiller or wholesaler other than for the purchase of alcoholic beverages;</section><section prefix="(16)">A statement that the applicant will, if granted a license, conform to all laws and regulations relating to the business in which the applicant proposes to engage;</section><section prefix="(17)"><section prefix="(i)">A statement duly executed and acknowledged by the owner of the premises in which the business is to be conducted assenting to the granting of the license applied for, and authorizing the Comptroller, his duly authorized deputies, inspectors and clerks, the board of license commissioners of the county or city in which the place of business is located, its duly authorized agents and employees, any peace officer of that city or county, and any peace officer of any incorporated municipality in which the business is to be conducted, to inspect and search, without warrant, the premises upon which the business is to be conducted, and any and all parts of the building in which the business is to be conducted, at any and all hours.</section><section prefix="(ii)">In Montgomery County, a statement and acknowledgment is not required where the applicant for a license is the lessee of the entire building in which the business is to be conducted for the entire term of the license to be issued.</section><section prefix="(iii)">In Baltimore City, a statement and acknowledgment by the owner is not required when the applicant is applying for a license pursuant to &#xA7; 9-204.1(d) of this article if the applicant files an affidavit that the applicant is the lessee of the premises and accompanies the affidavit with a copy of the executed lease;</section></section><section prefix="(18)"><section prefix="(i)">A certificate signed by at least ten citizens who are owners of real estate and registered voters of the precinct in which the business is to be conducted, stating the length of time each has been acquainted with the applicant, or in the case of a corporation with the individuals making the application; that they have examined the application of the applicant and that they have good reason to believe that all the statements contained in this application are true, and that they are of the opinion that the applicant is a suitable person to obtain the license. The certificate must have a statement that the signers of it are familiar with the premises upon which the proposed business is to be conducted, and that they believe the premises are suitable for the conduct of the business of a retail dealer in alcoholic beverages.</section><section prefix="(ii)">In St. Mary's County, persons who are owners of real estate within 5 miles of the premises for which a license is sought and registered voters of St. Mary's County shall be those persons signing the certificate.</section><section prefix="(iii)">The certificate required by subparagraph (i) of this paragraph is not necessary for applications filed in Dorchester County, Prince George's County, Montgomery County, Anne Arundel County, and Baltimore County.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(b-1)">In Prince George's County, if the applicant is in legal status in accordance with federal law, the application for a license shall contain proof of the applicant's legal status.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In Caroline County, when considering an application for a new license or a transfer of an existing license, the Board of License Commissioners shall:<section prefix="(i)">Obtain criminal records of the applicant from the Central Repository;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Require the applicant to submit the applicant's fingerprints;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Forward the fingerprints through the Central Repository for transmittal to the Federal Bureau of Investigation for a national criminal history records check; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">Keep all criminal records in a sealed envelope available only to the members of the Board and their designees.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Board shall charge a fee that the Board sets to cover the cost of obtaining the fingerprints and the results of the State and national criminal history records check.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Board may require applicants for license renewals to meet the requirements of this subsection.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this subsection, "Board" means the St. Mary's County Alcoholic Beverage Board.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">This subsection applies only in St. Mary's County.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">For each license applicant, the Board shall:<section prefix="(i)">Apply to the Central Repository for a State and national criminal history records check; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Submit as part of an application for a criminal history records check:<section prefix="1.">Two complete sets of the applicant's legible fingerprints taken on forms approved by the Director of the Central Repository and the Director of the Federal Bureau of Investigation;</section><section prefix="2.">The mandatory processing fee required by the Federal Bureau of Investigation for a national criminal history records check; and</section><section prefix="3.">The fee authorized under &#xA7; 10-221(b)(7) of the Criminal Procedure Article for access to Maryland criminal history records.</section></section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The Central Repository shall provide the requested information in accordance with Title 10, Subtitle 2 of the Criminal Procedure Article.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">This subsection does not apply to an applicant for renewal of an alcoholic beverages license.</section>
      <section prefix="(6)">The Board may establish a fee to cover the cost of obtaining:<section prefix="(i)">The applicant's fingerprints; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">The State and national criminal history records check.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(7)">The Board shall:<section prefix="(i)">Keep all criminal records confidential; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Make all criminal records in its possession available only to Board members, the Board's designees, the Board Administrator, and the Board's inspector.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(8)">A hearing for an applicant for an alcoholic beverages license and the issuance of a license may not be delayed due to the failure of the Federal Bureau of Investigation to provide the requested criminal history records check by the date of the scheduled hearing.</section>
      <section prefix="(9)">The Board shall adopt regulations to implement this subsection.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">In this subsection the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">"Applicant" means an applicant for a new alcoholic beverages license or for a transfer of an existing alcoholic beverages license.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">"Board" means the Board of License Commissioners of Washington County.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">This subsection applies only in Washington County.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The Board shall apply to the Central Repository for a State and national criminal history records check for each applicant.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">As part of the application for a criminal history records check, the Board shall submit to the Central Repository:<section prefix="1.">Two complete sets of the applicant's legible fingerprints taken on forms approved by the director of the Central Repository and the director of the Federal Bureau of Investigation;</section><section prefix="2.">The fee authorized under &#xA7; 10-221(b)(7) of the Criminal Procedure Article for access to Maryland criminal history records; and</section><section prefix="3.">The mandatory processing fee required by the Federal Bureau of Investigation for a national criminal history records check.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">In accordance with Title 10, Subtitle 2 of the Criminal Procedure Article, the Central Repository shall forward to the applicant and the Board the applicant's criminal history record information.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The Board shall establish a fee to cover the cost of obtaining:<section prefix="(i)">The applicant's fingerprints; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">The State and national criminal records.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(5)">Information obtained from the Central Repository under this subsection:<section prefix="(i)">Is confidential and may not be redisseminated;</section><section prefix="(ii)">May be used only for licensing purposes;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Shall be kept in sealed envelopes available only to Board members, inspectors, administrators, and designees of the Board; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">Shall be destroyed on completion of their necessary use.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(6)">A hearing for an applicant and the issuance of a license may not be delayed due to the failure of the Federal Bureau of Investigation to provide the requested criminal records by the date of the scheduled hearing.</section>
      <section prefix="(7)">The subject of a criminal history records check under this subsection may contest the contents of the printed statement issued by the Central Repository under &#xA7; 10-223 of the Criminal Procedure Article.</section>
      <section prefix="(8)">The Board shall adopt regulations to implement this subsection and preserve the confidentiality of the information obtained under this subsection.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
