<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="g2b" order_by="2" level="1">Alcoholic Beverages</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>g2b-8-407</section_number>
  <catch_line>In Harford County, subject to the provisions of subsections (c) and (d) of this section, the Liquor ...</catch_line>
  <order_by>407</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In Harford County, subject to the provisions of subsections (c) and (d) of this section, the Liquor Control Board may issue:<section prefix="(1)">A CWBT license to holders of a Class A1 BWL license; and</section><section prefix="(2)">A WBT license to holders of a Class A BW license.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The CWBT license permits the on-premises consumption of cordials, wine, beer, and liquor for tasting or sampling purposes only.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The WBT license permits the on-premises consumption of wine and beer for tasting or sampling purposes only.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The holder of a Class A1 BWL license may apply for and the Liquor Control Board may issue a CWBT license that is effective for a maximum of:<section prefix="(i)">Any 26 days in a licensing period;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Any 52 days in a licensing period; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">365 days in a licensing period.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The fees for a CWBT license under this subsection are:<section prefix="(i)">For a license that is effective for any 26 days in a licensing period, $125;</section><section prefix="(ii)">For a license that is effective for any 52 days in a licensing period, $200; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">For a license that is effective for 365 days in a licensing period, $400.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The holder of a Class A BW license may apply for and the Liquor Control Board may issue a WBT license that is effective for a maximum of:<section prefix="(i)">Any 26 days in a licensing period;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Any 52 days in a licensing period; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">365 days in a licensing period.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The fees for a WBT license under this subsection are:<section prefix="(i)">For a license that is effective for any 26 days in a licensing period, $100;</section><section prefix="(ii)">For a license that is effective for any 52 days in a licensing period, $150; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">For a license that is effective for 365 days in a licensing period, $225.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">A licensee that is issued a CWBT or a WBT license under this section for any 26 days in a licensing period or any 52 days in a licensing period shall notify the Liquor Control Board at least 7 days prior to exercising the provisions of the tasting or sampling license, of the licensee's intent to have a tasting or sampling.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">Tasting and sampling servings per person are limited to:<section prefix="(1)">1 ounce of each given brand of beer or wine;</section><section prefix="(2)">One-half ounce of each given brand of cordial; and</section><section prefix="(3)">One-half ounce of each brand of any other alcoholic beverage.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(g)">The Liquor Control Board may adopt regulations providing additional requirements to implement this subsection.</section>
  </text>
</law>
