<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="g2b" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="9-204.1" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>g2b-9-204.1</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, "Board" means the Board of Liquor License Commissioners for Baltimore City.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">This section applies only in Baltimore City.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The alcoholic beverages districts described in this section at all times shall be coterminous with the legislative districts in the Legislative Districting Plan of 2002 as ordered by the Maryland Court of Appeals on June 21, 2002.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, new licenses for the sale of alcoholic beverages may not be issued in the following areas:<section prefix="(i)">The 40th alcoholic beverages district (entire district);</section><section prefix="(ii)">The 41st alcoholic beverages district (entire district);</section><section prefix="(iii)">The 43rd alcoholic beverages district (entire district);</section><section prefix="(iv)">The 44th alcoholic beverages district (entire district);</section><section prefix="(v)">The 45th alcoholic beverages district (entire district); and</section><section prefix="(vi)">The 46th alcoholic beverages district (entire district).</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Board may issue:<section prefix="(i)">Special 1-day licenses;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Class B beer, wine and liquor restaurant licenses to bona fide restaurants having:</section><section prefix="(iii)">A Class C beer, wine and liquor license in the 45th alcoholic beverages district.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Notwithstanding paragraph (2) of this subsection, new Class B beer, wine and liquor restaurant licenses may not be issued:<section prefix="(i)">In the 46th alcoholic beverages district, the area covered by the Key Highway East Industrial Area Urban Renewal Plan, as adopted by the Mayor and City Council of Baltimore City in Ordinance 986 on June 29, 1987;</section><section prefix="(ii)">In the 46th alcoholic beverages district, the area covered by the Key Highway Urban Renewal Plan, as adopted by the Mayor and City Council of Baltimore City in Ordinance 622 on March 12, 1986;</section><section prefix="(iii)">In the 46th alcoholic beverages district, ward 23, precinct 1, ward 1, precinct 4 or 5, and ward 24, precinct 5; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">In the area known as Pen Lucy, ward 9, precincts 1 and 2.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, licenses for the sale of alcoholic beverages of any class may not be transferred into the areas covered by this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">A licensed drugstore may transfer the license into the 45th alcoholic beverages district.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">One Class B-D-7 license issued for a property surrounded by West Preston Street on the north, Morton Street on the east, West Biddle Street on the south, and Maryland Avenue on the west may be transferred to a property surrounded by West Eager Street and East Eager Street on the north, Lovegrove Street on the east, West Read Street and East Read Street on the south, and Morton Street on the west.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This subsection applies only in the 46th alcoholic beverages district.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Notwithstanding &#xA7; 6-201(d)(1)(vii) of this article, and subject to paragraph (8) of this subsection, the Board may issue a Class B beer, wine and liquor license:<section prefix="(i)">For a restaurant in ward 26, precinct 8, if the restaurant has a minimum capital investment of $700,000, a seating capacity exceeding 150 persons, and average daily receipts from the sale of food that are at least 65% of the total daily receipts of the restaurant;</section><section prefix="(ii)">For a restaurant in ward 4, precinct 1 or ward 22, precinct 1, if the restaurant has a minimum capital investment of $700,000, a seating capacity that exceeds 75 persons, average daily receipts for the sale of food that are at least 65% of the total daily receipts of the restaurant, and no sales for off-premises consumption;</section><section prefix="(iii)">For not more than three restaurants in a residential planned unit development for Silo Point as approved by the Mayor and City Council of Baltimore City in Ordinance 04-697 on June 23, 2004, if the restaurant has a minimum capital investment of $700,000, a seating capacity that exceeds 75 persons, average daily receipts from the sale of food that are at least 65% of the total daily receipts of the restaurant, and no sales for off-premises consumption; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">For not more than three restaurants in a business planned unit development in ward 24, precinct 5 of the 46th alcoholic beverages district, which at all times shall be coterminous with the 46th Legislative District in the Legislative Districting Plan of 2002 as ordered by the Maryland Court of Appeals on June 21, 2002, if each restaurant has a minimum capital investment of $700,000, a seating capacity that exceeds 75 persons but is not more than 150 persons, average daily receipts from the sale of food that are at least 65% of the total daily receipts of the restaurant, and no sales for off-premises consumption.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Except as provided in subparagraph (ii) of this paragraph, the Board may not issue an alcoholic beverages license or transfer a license into ward 1, precincts 4 and 5, ward 23, precinct 1, or ward 24, precinct 5.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The Board may allow the transfer of one Class D license into the residential planned unit development for Silo Point located in ward 24, precinct 5 which was enacted by the Mayor and City Council of Baltimore City in Ordinance 04-697 on June 23, 2004, provided that the Class D license holder operates the establishment in accordance with the provisions of Ordinance 04-697.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(4)">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, a new Class B beer, wine and liquor license may not be transferred to another location or downgraded within the 46th alcoholic beverages district.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">A new Class B licensed restaurant must have average daily receipts from the sale of food that are at least 51% of the total daily receipts of the restaurant.</section>
      <section prefix="(6)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Except as provided in subparagraph (ii) of this paragraph, the Board may not transfer or issue a license if the transfer or issuance would result in:</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">This paragraph does not apply to a licensed restaurant in:</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(7)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Except as provided in subparagraph (ii) of this paragraph, a license for the sale of alcoholic beverages may not be transferred into, or transferred to a different location within, the following areas:</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">This paragraph does not apply to an application for a new license or a transfer from within the areas described in subparagraph (i) of this paragraph if the new license or transfer is for:</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(8)">Notwithstanding paragraph (2)(ii) through (iv) of this subsection, a license specified under this subsection, including a license that allows no sales for off-premises consumption, may include an off-sale privilege for sales of refillable containers under a refillable container license issued in accordance with &#xA7; 8-203(e) of this article.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">A Class A (off-sale) or Class D (on- and off-sale) alcoholic beverages license may not be issued within or transferred into the area bounded on the north by 39th Street, then following Ellerslie Avenue, then following Chestnut Hill Avenue, on the east by Loch Raven Boulevard, then following Walpert Avenue, then following Homewood Avenue, on the south by North Avenue, and on the west by Howard Street, then following Art Museum Drive, then following North Charles Street.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Board may issue a special Class BWL-MZ license for use at a zoo in Druid Hill Park.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The license may be used to sell beer, wine, and liquor for consumption only on the land and in the facilities used by the zoo.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">An applicant for a Class BWL-MZ license who has an alcoholic beverages license issued by the Board shall exchange that license for a Class BWL-MZ license.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The Board shall extinguish the license exchanged by the applicant.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(4)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The licensee may designate an agent to sell beer, wine, and liquor at the zoo.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The agent shall be considered the vendor for collecting and remitting the sales and use tax.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(5)">On approval by the Board, beer, wine, and liquor may be sold at the zoo in multiple locations.</section>
      <section prefix="(6)">The hours of sale for the license are from noon to 11 p.m. every day of the week.</section>
      <section prefix="(7)">The annual license fee is $500.</section>
      <section prefix="(8)">The Board may adopt regulations to carry out this section.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
