<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="g2b" order_by="2" level="1">Alcoholic Beverages</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>g2b-8-406</section_number>
  <catch_line>This section applies only in Frederick County....</catch_line>
  <order_by>406</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">This section applies only in Frederick County.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A beer and wine sampling or tasting (BWST) license may only be issued to a holder of a Class A license.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The annual license fee is $200.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Applications for a BWST license shall be made on forms supplied by the Board of License Commissioners.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Renewals of the license may be made at the time the regular license is renewed.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A license may be granted without a hearing.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">If application for a license is denied, the applicant may request a public hearing before the Board.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A holder of a BWST license may allow consumption by a single individual for sampling or tasting purposes of:<section prefix="(i)">Not more than 1 ounce of a given brand of light wine; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Not more than 3 ounces of a given brand of beer.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A maximum of six bottles of wine may be opened at any one time.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The licensee shall notify the Board in writing at least 5 days prior to each event.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">Once opened, each bottle used for the beer and wine sampling or tasting event shall be marked that it is to be used for that purpose only.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">The contents of each bottle may not be mixed with any other bottle and all bottles shall be destroyed once they are empty.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A BWST license is for on-premises consumption only.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Sampling or tasting of beer or wine may not be conducted from a drive-through window.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
