<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="g2b" order_by="2" level="1">Alcoholic Beverages</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>g2b-11-511</section_number>
  <catch_line>This section applies only in Frederick County....</catch_line>
  <order_by>511</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">This section applies only in Frederick County.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">This section does not apply to holders of Class E licenses.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Notwithstanding any other provision of this subtitle, the privilege conferred by every class of "on-sale" license may be exercised during the hours from 6 a.m. to 2 a.m. daily, except Sundays.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">On Sundays the hours are:<section prefix="(i)">On-sale - 11 a.m. to 2 a.m.; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Off-sale - 1 p.m. to 2 a.m.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A Class A wine licensee may sell wine on Sundays.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The Board of License Commissioners may grant a special Sunday opening permit to a Class A beer, wine and liquor (off-sale) licensee.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The special Sunday opening permit authorizes the holder to sell beer, wine and liquor for off-premises consumption on Sundays from 11 a.m. to 2 a.m. the following day.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">The annual fee for the special Sunday opening permit is $650 in addition to the annual fee for the Class A beer, wine and liquor (off-sale) license.</section>
        <section prefix="(iv)">The special Sunday opening permit is not considered a separate class of license and, if it is granted, the privilege shall be incorporated into the existing Class A beer, wine and liquor license.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The Board of License Commissioners may grant a special Sunday opening permit to a Class A beer and wine (off-sale) licensee.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The special Sunday opening permit authorizes the holder to sell beer and wine for off-premises consumption on Sundays from 11 a.m. to 2 a.m. the following day.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">The annual fee for the special Sunday opening permit is $140 in addition to the annual fee for the Class A beer and wine (off-sale) license.</section>
        <section prefix="(iv)">The special Sunday opening permit is not considered a separate class of license and, if it is granted, the privilege shall be incorporated into the existing Class A beer and wine license.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(4)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The Board of License Commissioners may grant a special Sunday opening permit to a Class A beer (off-sale) licensee.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The special Sunday opening permit authorizes the holder to sell beer for off-premises consumption on Sundays from 11 a.m. to 2 a.m. the following day.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">The annual fee for the special Sunday opening permit is $100 in addition to the annual fee for the Class A beer (off-sale) license.</section>
        <section prefix="(iv)">The special Sunday opening permit is not considered a separate class of license and, if it is granted, the privilege shall be incorporated into the existing Class A beer license.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
