<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="g2b" order_by="" level="1">Alcoholic Beverages</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>g2b-8-404.1</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>404.1</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">This section applies in Baltimore County.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Board of License Commissioners may issue a Class BWT beer and light wine (on-premises) tasting license to the holder of a Class A beer and light wine license.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Board of License Commissioners may issue a Class BWLT beer, wine and liquor (on-premises) tasting license to a holder of a Class A beer, wine and liquor license.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The fees for a Class BWT and Class BWLT license are as follows:<section prefix="(i)">$20 for a daily tasting license, which may be issued not more than 12 times in any annual license year;</section><section prefix="(ii)">$200 annually for a 26-day tasting license, which may be used consecutively or nonconsecutively;</section><section prefix="(iii)">$300 annually for a 52-day tasting license, which may be used consecutively or nonconsecutively; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">$400 annually for a 104-day tasting license, which may be used consecutively or nonconsecutively.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The fees for a Class BWT license and Class BWLT license are in addition to the Class A annual license fee.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Class BWT license authorizes the holder to allow the on-premises consumption of light wine or beer for tasting.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A person may consume light wine or beer covered by a Class BWT license in a quantity not exceeding:<section prefix="(i)">1 ounce of light wine from all brands in a single day; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">3 ounces of beer from all brands in a single day.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Class BWLT license authorizes the holder to allow the on-premises consumption of beer, light wine, and liquor for tasting or sampling.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A person may consume light wine, beer, or liquor covered by a Class BWLT license in a quantity not exceeding:<section prefix="(i)">1 ounce of light wine from all brands in a single day;</section><section prefix="(ii)">3 ounces of beer from all brands in a single day; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">One-half ounce of liquor from all brands in a single day.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">At the end of each day for which a Class BWT or a Class BWLT license is valid, the holder of the license shall dispose of any unconsumed alcoholic beverage remaining in a container that was opened for tasting or sampling.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Each Class A license holder that seeks issuance of a BWT or BWLT license for which they are eligible shall apply for the type of tasting license authorized by this section on forms provided by the Board of License Commissioners.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The forms provided by the Board of License Commissioners under paragraph (1) of this subsection shall specify the date or dates on which the tasting is requested to occur.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The application and payment for the daily license shall be submitted at least 7 days in advance of the tasting event or 7 days in advance of the first day of consecutive day tasting events.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The application and payment for the 26-day tasting license and the 52-day tasting license shall be made at least 7 days in advance of the first proposed tasting event.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">The holder of a 26-day tasting license and a 52-day tasting license shall notify the Board of License Commissioners, on forms approved by the Board, of additional tasting events authorized by the licenses.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(i)">The provisions of this section are not restricted by:<section prefix="(1)">&#xA7; 12-107(b) of this article; and</section><section prefix="(2)">The provisions in &#xA7; 9-102 of this article which prohibit the issuance of two licenses for the same premises.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(j)">The holder of a Class BWT or Class BWLT license may exercise the privileges of this section during the hours and days provided for under the holder's respective Class A license.</section>
  </text>
</law>
