<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="g2b" order_by="" level="1">Alcoholic Beverages</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>g2b-8-603</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>603</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In Worcester County the owner or owners of any regular licensed horse racing establishment, holding public meetings at which pari-mutuel betting is permitted, or the concessionaire or catering organization at that place, whether an individual, association or corporation, may procure without additional residential, voting or locative qualifications, a license for the sale of beer or beer and light wine within the confines of its racing park in the county, at the same cost for other beer and beer and light wine licenses in the county.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The person may procure a license for the sale of beer, wine and liquor within the confines of its racing park in the county, for a fee of $1,500 each year, which entitles the holder to sell at one or more locations within its park.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The licenses and the licensees are subject to all laws and regulations applicable in Worcester County to the sale of alcoholic beverages not inconsistent with the provisions of this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, all licensees shall purchase all liquors and wines, except light wine, from the Worcester County Department of Liquor Control. The licensee shall receive at least a 15 percent discount from the retail sales price or any special sale price or discount price, whichever is lower. All licensees may purchase beer and light wine from licensed wholesalers.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Beginning on May 1, 2016, a licensee may elect to purchase wine and liquor from a licensed wholesaler under &#xA7; 15-204(e) of this article.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
