<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="g2b" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="11-501" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>g2b-11-501</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In Allegany County, any person having a license under this article may not sell intoxicating beverages between the hours of 2 a.m. and 7:00 o'clock a.m. except as provided in subsection (b) of this section, it shall be unlawful after 2:00 a.m. Sunday to sell intoxicating beverages until 7:00 o'clock a.m. Monday. However, Sunday sales when New Year's Eve or New Year's Day falls on Sunday shall be governed by &#xA7; 11-402(b) of this article.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In Allegany County, notwithstanding any other provisions of this subtitle, holders of Class B and Class D licenses which are restaurants as defined in paragraph (2) of this subsection, holders of Class B licenses which are issued for use in a restaurant or banquet room located within a hotel or motel as provided under &#xA7; 6-201(b) of this article, and holders of Class C licenses, may, if they pay an additional fee of $250, sell alcoholic beverages for consumption on the premises only on Sunday between the hours of 1 p.m. and 2 a.m. Monday.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Except as provided for under &#xA7; 6-201(b) of this article, for purposes of this subsection, in Allegany County, "restaurant" means any establishment located in a permanent building with ample space and accommodations commonly known as a restaurant where meals are usually prepared, sold or served to the public during the hours it is regularly open for business.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In Allegany County, the Board of License Commissioners may issue a 2-day Sunday sales permit to a holder of any alcoholic beverages license other than a Class A license.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">An applicant for a 2-day Sunday sales permit need not have kitchen facilities on the licensed premises.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A 2-day Sunday sales permit authorizes the holder to sell beer, wine, and liquor for consumption on the premises on not more than two Sundays in a year between the hours of 1 p.m. Sunday and 2 a.m. the following Monday.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The permit fee is $50 for each time the permit is used.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
