<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="g2b" order_by="2" level="1">Alcoholic Beverages</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>g2b-8-310.2</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this section the following words have the meanings indicated....</catch_line>
  <order_by>310.2</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Board" means the Prince George's County Board of License Commissioners.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Festival" means the Prince George's County Wine Festival.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, this section applies only in Prince George's County.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">This section does not apply in the 24th Legislative District.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Board may issue one wine festival license each year.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Notwithstanding any other provision of this article, an applicant for a wine festival license shall be a holder of a retail alcoholic beverages license, a Class 3 winery license, or a Class 4 limited winery license.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Subject to paragraph (2) of this subsection, a holder of a wine festival license may display and sell wine at the Festival for consumption on or off the premises on the days and for the hours designated for the Festival.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The wine shall be:<section prefix="(i)">Manufactured and processed in any state;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Price filed in accordance with regulations that the Comptroller adopts; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Distributed in the State by the time the application for the wine festival license is filed.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">This section does not prohibit the holder of a wine festival license from holding another alcoholic beverages license of a different class or nature.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Board:<section prefix="(i)">May establish the license fee;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Shall choose a location in the county for this Festival which is not licensed under this article;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Shall assure that the primary focus of the Festival is the promotion of Maryland wine; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">Subject to paragraph (2) of this subsection, annually may select one weekend, Friday through Sunday inclusive, for the Festival.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The weekend chosen for the Festival may not:<section prefix="(i)">Be longer than 3 days;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Occur within 14 days before or after the Maryland Wine Festival in Carroll County; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Conflict with the dates chosen for:<section prefix="1.">The Anne Arundel County Beer and Wine Festival;</section><section prefix="2.">The Calvert County Wine Festival;</section><section prefix="3.">The Charles County Beer and Wine Festival; or</section><section prefix="4.">The Howard County Wine Festival.</section></section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(h)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Products displayed and sold shall be:<section prefix="(i)">Invoiced to the holder of the wine festival license by a licensed State wholesaler, winery, or limited winery; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Delivered to the Festival from the licensed premises of the wholesaler, winery, or limited winery.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Whenever a wine festival license is issued under this section, holders of wholesale, winery, or limited winery licenses may enter into an agreement with the holder of a wine festival license to deliver wine 2 days before the effective date, and to accept returns 2 days after the expiration date of the wine festival license.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(i)">The Board shall adopt regulations to carry out this section.</section>
  </text>
</law>
