<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="g2b" order_by="" level="1">Alcoholic Beverages</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>g2b-1-102</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>102</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this article the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">"Alcoholic beverages" means alcohol, brandy, whiskey, rum, gin, cordial, beer, ale, porter, stout, wine, cider, and any other spirituous, vinous, malt or fermented liquor, liquid, or compound, by whatever name called, which contains, except as provided in subparagraph (ii) of this paragraph, one-half of one percent or more of alcohol by volume, which is fit for beverage purposes.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">"Alcoholic beverages" does not include a confectionery food product that contains up to 5 percent of alcohol by volume and is regulated by the Department of Health and Mental Hygiene under &#xA7; 21-209 of the Health - General Article.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">"Beer" means any brewed alcoholic beverage.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">"Beer" includes:<section prefix="1.">Beer;</section><section prefix="2.">Ale;</section><section prefix="3.">Porter;</section><section prefix="4.">Stout;</section><section prefix="5.">Hard cider; and</section><section prefix="6.">Alcoholic beverages that contain:</section></section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(4)">
        <section prefix="(i)">"Club" means an association or corporation which is organized and operated exclusively for educational, social, fraternal, patriotic, political or athletic purposes and not for profit.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">In Allegany County the Board of Alcoholic Beverages License Commissioners shall be the judges of whether such an establishment is operated in good faith within the meaning of this subsection.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(5)">"Comptroller" means the Comptroller of the Treasury of the State.</section>
      <section prefix="(6)">"Consumer" means any natural person 21 years old or older, or any corporation not otherwise interdicted by this article or any other law of this State, who buys, possesses, keeps or transports alcoholic beverages upon which the taxes provided by the tax provisions of Title 5 of the Tax - General Article have been paid, for the person's own use and not for sale.</section>
      <section prefix="(7)">"Court" means the circuit court of a county or any judge of a circuit court.</section>
      <section prefix="(8)">"Family beer" means homemade beer produced for home consumption and not for sale and includes beer produced at a licensed family beer and wine facility.</section>
      <section prefix="(9)">"Family wine" means homemade wine produced for home consumption and not for sale and includes wine produced at a licensed family beer and wine facility.</section>
      <section prefix="(9-1)">"Hard cider" means a beverage derived primarily from apples or apple concentrate and water, containing no other fruit product, and containing at least one-half of 1% and less than 7% of alcohol by volume.</section>
      <section prefix="(10)">
        <section prefix="(i)">"Hotel" means an establishment:<section prefix="1.">Which accommodates the public;</section><section prefix="2.">Which is equipped with not less than ten bedrooms and a dining room with facilities for preparing and serving regular meals; and</section><section prefix="3.">In which the average daily receipts from the hire of rooms and the sale of foods exceed the average daily receipts from the sale of alcoholic beverages.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The board of license commissioners in any county or in Baltimore City, and the Mayor, Counselor and Aldermen of the City of Annapolis, may by regulation prescribe a different standard as to what constitutes a hotel.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">The requirements of this subsection relating to average daily receipts are not applicable to any licenses issued in Cecil County.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(11)">
        <section prefix="(i)">"Illicit alcoholic beverages" means any alcoholic beverages which have been manufactured, bottled or rectified within this State on any premises other than a premises licensed under this article, or which have been manufactured, bottled or rectified outside of this State on any premises other than a premises licensed under the United States Internal Revenue Code or the laws of a foreign country.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">Any alcoholic beverages found in any container without a regular label which truly describes its contents and which states the true name of the importer, manufacturer, bottler or rectifier are presumed to be illicit alcoholic beverages. However, the presumption does not apply to any alcoholic beverages found:<section prefix="1.">In drinking glasses or other similar open containers for drinking purposes;</section><section prefix="2.">In home-type decanters found in a dwelling house or in a punch bowl or other receptacle of a similar nature, if found under circumstances which indicate that the alcoholic beverages contained in the receptacles are intended for consumption on the premises by consumers and not for sale; or</section><section prefix="3.">In containers possessed by a proper retail alcoholic beverage licensee when the alcoholic beverages are premixed for lawful sale and consumption.</section></section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(12)">"Import" means to transport or ship, or to order or arrange for the transportation or shipment of, alcoholic beverages into this State from any other state, district, territory or country.</section>
      <section prefix="(13)">"Importer" means a person importing any alcoholic beverage.</section>
      <section prefix="(14)">"In this State" or "within this State" means in or within the territorial limits of this State.</section>
      <section prefix="(15)">
        <section prefix="(i)">"License holder" or "licensee" means the holder of any license or permit, issued under the provisions of this article or of any other law of this State, and includes a county liquor control board and a county dispensary.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">For the delivery and billing purposes of &#xA7;&#xA7; 2-301(b) and 2-401(b) of this article, "license holder" or "licensee" also means a corporation on whose behalf an individual or individuals have obtained a license.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(16)">
        <section prefix="(i)">"License issuing authority" means:<section prefix="1.">For a State license issued under this article, the State Comptroller; and</section><section prefix="2.">For a local license issued under this article, the board of license commissioners or other local agency expressly authorized by this article to issue the license.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">"License issuing authority" does not include a clerk of a circuit court.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(17)">"Light wine" means any naturally fermented wine containing not in excess of 15.5 percent of alcohol by volume.</section>
      <section prefix="(18)">
        <section prefix="(i)">"Local collecting agent" means:<section prefix="1.">In the City of Annapolis, the city clerk;</section><section prefix="2.">In Allegany County, Baltimore County, Howard County, Prince George's County, or Wicomico County, the director of finance;</section><section prefix="3.">In Calvert County, Dorchester County, St. Mary's County, or Somerset County, the treasurer of the county; and</section><section prefix="4.">In each other county, the board of license commissioners or other local agency expressly authorized by this article to collect fees under this article.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">"Local collecting agent" does not include a clerk of a circuit court.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(19)">"Local licensing board" means a board of license commissioners of a county or the Mayor and Aldermen of the City of Annapolis.</section>
      <section prefix="(20)">"Manufacturer" means a person operating a plant within this State for distilling, rectifying, blending, brewing, fermenting or bottling any alcoholic beverage.</section>
      <section prefix="(21)">"Person" means a natural person, an association, a partnership, a corporation, or a state, political subdivision, or municipality, or any agency or instrumentality of the State, any political subdivision, or municipality.</section>
      <section prefix="(22)">
        <section prefix="(i)">
          <section prefix="1.">"Restaurant" means an establishment:</section>
          <section prefix="2.">However the board of license commissioners in any county by regulation may prescribe a different standard as to what constitutes a restaurant.</section>
          <section prefix="3.">For a restaurant in Baltimore City, the average daily receipts from the sale of food must be at least 40% of the total daily receipts of the establishment.</section>
        </section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">In Baltimore City, the term "food" as used in the definition of "restaurant", whether the definition is established by State law or by regulations adopted by the Board of License Commissioners, may not include any ingredient or garnish used with or mixed with an alcoholic beverage that is prepared and served for consumption on the licensed premises.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">In Harford County a "restaurant" as used in &#xA7; 5-201 and &#xA7; 6-201(n)(9) of this article means a business establishment for the accommodation of the public, fully equipped with a proper and adequate dining room, tables, chairs and sufficient facilities for preparing and serving regular meals, as may be approved by the Liquor Control Board. The Board and Department of Health shall approve its sanitary facilities, running hot and cold water, equipment for the proper cleaning of dishes and kitchenware and adequate toilets. At all times there must be sufficient food on the premises for the regular serving of meals, with a proper sign or signs in front of the establishment designating "restaurant" or food and beverages sold, and not advertising any other business. In this establishment the average gross monthly receipts from the sale of foods cooked or prepared and served on the premises where the license is exercised, and other foods, commodities and items defined by the Liquor Control Board, shall exceed 50 percent of the average monthly receipts from the sale of beer and wine, except that a restaurant serving food and beverages whose gross monthly receipts from the sale of food averages $1,500 or more may not be required to sell food and food commodities in excess of 50 percent of the average monthly receipts from the sale of beer and wine.</section>
        <section prefix="(iv)">The requirements of this section relating to average daily receipts are not applicable to any licenses issued in Cecil County.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(23)">"Retail dealer" means a person who deals in or sells any alcoholic beverage to any person other than a license holder, and includes a county dispensary.</section>
      <section prefix="(24)">"Sparkling wine" means champagne or any artificially carbonated wine.</section>
      <section prefix="(25)">"This article" includes provisions in the Tax - General Article derived from this article.</section>
      <section prefix="(26)">In Baltimore City, "total daily receipts" does not include sales of novelty items, income from vending machines, or other receipts not resulting from the sale of food or beverages.</section>
      <section prefix="(27)">
        <section prefix="(i)">"Wholesaler" means:<section prefix="1.">A person who purchases or imports any alcoholic beverage for sale to wholesale or retail dealers only; or</section><section prefix="2.">A limited winery that sells wine to retail dealers.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">"Wholesaler" includes a county liquor control board and a county wholesale dispensary.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(28)">"Wine" means any fermented beverage, including light wines, and wines the alcoholic content of which has been fortified by the addition of alcohol, spirits or other ingredients.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this article the following words have the meanings indicated within the specified subdivisions.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">In Anne Arundel County, "taxpayer" means an individual who owns real property in the individual's own name, individually or jointly with others, and pays real property taxes to Anne Arundel County.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">In Prince George's and St. Mary's counties "taxpayer" means a resident who pays either real estate tax, income tax, or both.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">In Wicomico County, "bowling alley" means an establishment in which the primary business activity is to provide bowling lanes and bowling activities for the public, and which may be equipped with a dining room or snack bar area for the sale of food and beverages.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">In Worcester County, "taxpayer" means an individual who owns real estate in Worcester County in his own name, either individually or jointly with others, and actually pays real estate tax in Worcester County.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
