<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="g2b" order_by="2" level="1">Alcoholic Beverages</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>g2b-8-408.2</section_number>
  <catch_line>This section applies only in Montgomery County....</catch_line>
  <order_by>408.2</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">This section applies only in Montgomery County.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">In this section, "Board" means the Montgomery County Board of License Commissioners.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Subject to paragraph (2) of this subsection, the Board may issue a beer and wine sampling or tasting (BWST) license to a holder of a Class A license to hold tastings or samplings of beer or wine.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A holder of a Class A wine license may use a BWST license to hold tastings or samplings of wine only.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The annual license fee for a BWST license is $200.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A BWST license authorizes sampling or tasting of alcoholic beverages only on the licensed premises of the holder of a Class A license.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A holder of a BWST license may allow consumption by a single individual for sampling or tasting purposes of not more than:<section prefix="(i)">1 ounce from a single brand of wine;</section><section prefix="(ii)">4 ounces from all brands of wine in a single day;</section><section prefix="(iii)">3 ounces from a single brand of beer; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">12 ounces from all brands of beer in a single day.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Once opened, each bottle used for the beer and wine tasting or sampling shall be marked that it is to be used for that purpose only.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The holder of a BWST license shall notify the Board in writing at least 7 days before each sampling or tasting event.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">An application for a BWST license shall be made on a form supplied by the Board.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A BWST license may be issued without a public hearing.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">If an initial application for a BWST license is denied, the applicant may request a public hearing before the Board.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The Board may not require the publication of an application for a BWST license before issuing the license.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">A renewal of a BWST license may be made at the time the holder's Class A license is renewed.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">The provisions of this section are not restricted by:<section prefix="(1)">&#xA7; 12-107(b) of this article; and</section><section prefix="(2)">The provisions in &#xA7; 9-102 of this article that prohibit the issuance of two licenses for the same premises.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
