<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="g2b" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="15-101" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>g2b-15-101</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">For the jurisdictions in which this section is effective, the Governor, biennially, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate, if in session, and if not in session, then the Governor alone, shall appoint three persons who shall constitute and be styled "The Board of License Commissioners for Baltimore City or ............... County", as the case may be.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">In making the appointments, the Governor shall designate one of the appointees in Baltimore City and each of the counties to be the chairman of the respective boards.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The commissioners shall be residents and voters of Baltimore City or the respective counties, as the case may be, and they shall be persons of high character and integrity and of recognized business capacity.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">In the case of any vacancies in the number of the license commissioners in Baltimore City or in any county which occur when the legislature is not in session, the Governor shall appoint some eligible person to fill the vacancy during the remainder of the term of office of the person originally appointed.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This subsection applies only in Allegany County.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Appointments shall be for terms of 6 years each. The terms of the members are staggered as required by the terms of the members of the Board on January 1, 1994.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Two of the members of the Board of License Commissioners shall be members of that political party which at the last preceding general election in Allegany County polled the greatest number of votes in the aggregate for the several offices of County Commissioner therein. The third member of the Board of License Commissioners shall be a member of that political party which at the last preceding general election in Allegany County polled the second highest number of votes in the aggregate for the several offices of County Commissioner therein.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In Anne Arundel County not more than two members of the Board of License Commissioners shall belong to the same political party.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The provisions of &#xA7; 15-107 of this article apply in the City of Annapolis.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The provisions of this section apply in Baltimore City.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The provisions of &#xA7; 15-104 of this article apply in Baltimore County.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In Calvert County, 1 regular member of the Board shall always be a member of that political party which at the last preceding gubernatorial election polled the second highest number of votes throughout the State for that office.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">In addition to the regular members appointed to the Board, the Governor shall appoint an alternate Board member.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The alternate Board member's term shall run concurrently with the terms of the regular members serving in office on July 1, 1986.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">The alternate Board member serves on the Board in the absence of a regular Board member.</section>
        <section prefix="(iv)">When serving on the Board, the alternate Board member has all of the powers and responsibilities of a regular Board member.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This subsection applies only in Caroline County.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The members of the Liquor Control Board constitute the Board of License Commissioners.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The term of office for the members of the Board is 3 years.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">Appointments to the Board shall be made by the Governor with the advice and consent of the House of Delegates, if in session, and if not in session, the Governor shall make the appointments which shall continue in force until the end of the next session of the General Assembly.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">
        <section prefix="(i)">A substitute member of the Board shall be appointed by the Governor with the advice and consent of the House of Delegates, if in session, and if not in session the Governor shall make the appointment which shall continue in force until the end of the next session of the General Assembly.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The term of office of the substitute member shall be 3 years from the first Monday in May.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">In the event of the temporary or permanent incapacity, from any cause, of a regular member of the Board, or in the event of a vacancy from any cause on the regularly constituted Board, the substitute member upon the request of the chairman or the majority of the Board shall serve in the place of the regular member so incapacitated or causing the vacancy until the incapacity has terminated or the vacancy has been filled.</section>
        <section prefix="(iv)">While serving, the substitute member has all the powers and authority and is subject to all the duties imposed by law upon a regularly appointed member of the Board.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(h)">The provisions of &#xA7; 15-104 of this article apply in Carroll County.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">The provisions of &#xA7; 15-104 of this article apply in Cecil County.</section>
    <section prefix="(j)">The provisions of &#xA7; 15-104 of this article apply in Charles County.</section>
    <section prefix="(k)">The provisions of &#xA7; 15-105 of this article apply in Dorchester County.</section>
    <section prefix="(l)">The provisions of &#xA7; 15-103 of this article apply in Frederick County.</section>
    <section prefix="(m)">The provisions of &#xA7; 15-108 of this article apply in Garrett County.</section>
    <section prefix="(n)">The provisions of &#xA7; 15-201(c)(6) of this article apply in Harford County.</section>
    <section prefix="(o)">Repealed.</section>
    <section prefix="(p)">The provisions of &#xA7; 15-105 of this article apply in Kent County until the Board of County Commissioners passes the resolution for which provision is made by Chapter 236 of the Acts of the General Assembly of 1991.</section>
    <section prefix="(q)">The provisions of &#xA7; 15-104 of this article apply in Montgomery County.</section>
    <section prefix="(r)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This subsection applies in Prince George's County.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The Board of License Commissioners consists of 5 members.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The Governor shall appoint 4 of the 5 Commissioners from the political party obtaining the highest number of votes in the last gubernatorial general election in the county, and the Governor shall appoint 1 Commissioner from the political party obtaining the next highest number of votes in the county election.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">Before making the appointments or filling any vacancy, the Governor shall request the central committees for Prince George's County representing each of the 2 leading political parties of the State to designate at least 4 eligible candidates for each position; and the Governor shall appoint one of the persons so designated unless in his judgment all of the persons are unfit or incompetent, in which case he shall file a written statement to that effect with the Secretary of State. The statement shall set forth the facts and the grounds therefor and shall call upon the committees for Prince George's County for another list of 6 names for each position to be filled, from which list and the original list the Governor shall make the appointments.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The term of a member is 3 years. The terms of the members are staggered as required by the terms provided for members of the Board on July 1, 1985.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">Not more than 4 of the appointees shall belong to the same political party.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(s)">The provisions of &#xA7; 15-104 of this article apply in Queen Anne's County.</section>
    <section prefix="(t)">The provisions of &#xA7; 15-102 of this article apply in St. Mary's County.</section>
    <section prefix="(u)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The provisions of this subsection apply only in Somerset County.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Governor shall appoint three persons who constitute the Board of License Commissioners and who hold office for terms of 2 years each.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The appointments are subject to confirmation by the Senate of Maryland.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">One of the members of the Board shall be designated as its chairman, and not more than two members of the Board shall belong to the same political party.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(v)">In Talbot County the appointments shall be for terms of 6 years. The Board shall organize by electing its own chairman.</section>
    <section prefix="(w)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The provisions of this subsection apply only in Washington County.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">All terms shall be for 6 years and the terms of the members are staggered as required by the terms of the members of the Board on January 1, 1994.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">No more than two of the appointees shall belong to the same political party.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(x)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This subsection applies only in Wicomico County.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Governor shall appoint three persons, subject to the advice and consent of the Senate, who constitute the Board of License Commissioners.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The term of a member is 4 years.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The terms of members continue to be staggered as required by the terms provided for members of the Board on July 1, 1994.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">At the end of a term, a member continues to serve until a successor is appointed and qualifies.</section>
        <section prefix="(iv)">A member who is appointed after a term has begun serves only for the rest of the term and until a successor is appointed and qualifies.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(4)">One of the members of the Board shall be designated as its chairman.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(y)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This subsection applies only in Worcester County.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The Governor shall appoint three persons who constitute the Board of License Commissioners and who hold office for terms of 4 years each.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The terms of the members are staggered as required by the terms of the members of the Board on January 1, 1994.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The appointments are subject to confirmation by the Senate of Maryland.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">One of the members of the Board shall be designated as its chairman.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">
        <section prefix="(i)">In addition to the regular members appointed to the Board, the Governor shall appoint an alternate Board member.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The alternate Board member's term shall run concurrently with the term of the regular members.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">The alternate Board member shall serve on the Board in the absence of a quorum of the regular members due to illness or conflict of interest.</section>
        <section prefix="(iv)">When serving on the Board, the alternate Board member has all of the powers and duties of a regular Board member.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
