<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="g2b" order_by="2" level="1">Alcoholic Beverages</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>g2b-10-501</section_number>
  <catch_line>Except as otherwise provided under this section, licenses issued under provisions of this article sh...</catch_line>
  <order_by>501</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Except as otherwise provided under this section, licenses issued under provisions of this article shall not be regarded as property or as conferring any property rights. All such licenses shall be subject to suspension, restriction or revocation, and to all rules and regulations that may be adopted as herein provided.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This subsection applies only in Prince George's County.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Licenses issued under this article are not subject to writs of execution by a judgment creditor of a licensee nor are the licenses subject to a distraint for rent.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Board of License Commissioners may impose restrictions upon individual licensees to enable the Board to discharge the duties imposed upon it by this article if:<section prefix="(i)">The Board develops written restrictions that are reasonable, clear, and ascertainable; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">The Board develops written rules and regulations for the enforcement of the restrictions that comply with the due process:<section prefix="1.">Providing notice; and</section><section prefix="2.">Providing a hearing.</section></section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">
        <section prefix="(i)">A licensee may create a security interest in its license in favor of a landlord or any creditor of the licensee. The security interest shall be perfected in accordance with the Commercial Law Article.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The licensee shall deliver a copy of the underlying security agreement that is signed by or on behalf of the individual or entity that holds the license.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">Any transfer of a license pursuant to a security agreement shall be subject to approval by the Board in the same manner as is any other license transfer except that the written consent and cooperation of the existing licensee is not required.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">In Worcester County licenses issued under this article are not subject to writs of execution by a judgment creditor of a licensee nor are these licenses subject to a distraint for rent.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">In Howard County licenses issued under provisions of this article may not be:<section prefix="(1)">Regarded as property or as conferring any property rights;</section><section prefix="(2)">Subject to writs of execution by a judgment creditor of a licensee; or</section><section prefix="(3)">Subject to a distraint for rent.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">In Harford County, licenses issued under provisions of this article may not be subject to:<section prefix="(1)">Writs of execution by a judgment creditor of a licensee;</section><section prefix="(2)">A distraint for rent; or</section><section prefix="(3)">Sale or transfer per se, unless the license accompanies the business to which the license was issued.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">In Wicomico County, licenses issued under this article are not subject to writs of execution by a judgment creditor of a licensee or a distraint for rent.</section>
  </text>
</law>
