<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="g2b" order_by="2" level="1">Alcoholic Beverages</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>g2b-11-305</section_number>
  <catch_line>This section applies only in Baltimore City....</catch_line>
  <order_by>305</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">This section applies only in Baltimore City.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as otherwise provided by law or by regulation adopted under the authority of paragraph (2) of this subsection, between 2 a.m. and 6 a.m. on any day, a person may not consume any alcoholic beverages on any premises open to the general public, any place of public accommodation, or any place at which setups or other component parts of mixed alcoholic drinks are sold, whether or not the premises or place is licensed for the sale of alcoholic beverages or has any other license if any form of entertainment, live or recorded, is offered at the place or on the premises.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">This paragraph applies only on the inner perimeter of a rectangle bounded by 31st Street on the south, Greenmount Avenue on the east, 32nd Street on the north, and Barclay Street on the west.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">By regulation, the Board of License Commissioners may restrict the hours and days for the consumption of alcoholic beverages.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The owner, operator, or manager of the premises or place may not knowingly permit the consumption of alcoholic beverages that is prohibited by this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The owner, operator, or manager of any premises open to the general public or of any place of public accommodation where any form of entertainment is provided between 2 a.m. and 6 a.m. on any day and where alcoholic beverages are consumed at any hour of the day shall:<section prefix="(1)">Register with the fire department and the Department of Housing and Community Development; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Comply with all federal, State, and city building, fire, health, and zoning laws.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">Any person who consumes any alcoholic beverages on any premises enumerated in this section and any owner, operator, or manager of those premises or place who knowingly permits the consumption prohibited by this section is guilty of a misdemeanor and may be fined not more than $5,000 or imprisoned for not more than 3 years or both.</section>
  </text>
</law>
