<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="g2b" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="12-301" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>g2b-12-301</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A retail dealer may not employ any solicitor or salesman for the purpose of soliciting, outside of the licensed place of business, orders for the sale of any alcoholic beverages within this State.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The sale of alcoholic beverages may not be consummated outside of the licensed place of business.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">These provisions do not prohibit the receiving of orders by mail, telephone or messenger and the filling of such orders by delivery and the payment for them at the place of delivery.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Retail delivery to a purchaser of any alcoholic beverages is prohibited unless:<section prefix="(1)">The delivery is made from the retail licensed premises by the retail license holder or employee of the retail license holder authorized to sell and distribute alcoholic beverages by the local licensing authority in the jurisdiction where the delivery is made; and</section><section prefix="(2)">The retail license holder obtains a letter of authorization from the local licensing authority to make deliveries and complies with any regulations promulgated by the local licensing authority pertaining to those deliveries.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This subsection applies only in Howard County.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">An alcoholic beverages licensee may not make a retail delivery of alcoholic beverages unless the purchaser:<section prefix="(i)">Is physically present on the licensed premises when the purchaser orders the alcoholic beverages; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Makes payment for the purchase at the time of the order.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This subsection applies only in Montgomery County.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">An alcoholic beverages licensee may not make an off-site retail delivery of alcoholic beverages unless:<section prefix="(i)">The deliverer is at least:</section><section prefix="(ii)">The person taking possession of the delivery provides the deliverer with written certification supported by documentary proof that the person is of legal age to purchase alcoholic beverages. Certification shall be in the form set forth in &#xA7; 12-109(1) of this article.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Each certification executed under this subsection shall be retained by the licensee for at least 1 year.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The certifications shall be available for examination during regular business hours by an authorized representative of the Board of License Commissioners.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The Board of License Commissioners shall adopt regulations to implement this subsection.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This subsection applies only in Garrett County.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Board of License Commissioners may issue a delivery option that entitles an alcoholic beverages licensee or an authorized employee of the licensee to make an off-site retail delivery of alcoholic beverages if:<section prefix="(i)">The deliverer is at least 21 years old and certified by an approved alcohol awareness program;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The deliverer and purchaser endorse a delivery form that the Board of License Commissioners approves certifying that:</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Each delivery form endorsed under paragraph (2)(ii) of this subsection shall be submitted to the Board of License Commissioners on or before the 10th day of the following month.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The annual fee for a delivery option is $150.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">In addition to an annual fee, the Board of License Commissioners shall charge an issuing fee of $150.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(5)">The Board of License Commissioners shall adopt regulations to carry out this subsection.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">This section does not apply to:<section prefix="(1)">The delivery of wine from a direct wine shipper to a consumer using a common carrier in accordance with Title 7.5 of this article; or</section><section prefix="(2)">The holder of a common carrier permit in the course of delivering directly shipped wine in accordance with Title 7.5 of this article.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
