<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="g2b" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="11-510" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>g2b-11-510</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">This section applies only in Dorchester County.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Notwithstanding any other provisions of this subtitle, the hours for sale for alcoholic beverages are as follows:<section prefix="(1)">For the holders of a Class A (off-sale) beer license, sales are permitted Monday through Sunday from 6 a.m. to 12 midnight, except if Christmas Eve or New Year's Eve is on a Sunday, from 6 a.m. on Sunday to 2 a.m. on Monday.</section><section prefix="(2)">For the holders of a Class B (on-sale) beer license, sales are permitted:<section prefix="(i)">Monday through Saturday from 6 a.m. to 1:45 a.m. on the following day; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Sunday from 12 noon to 12 midnight, except if Christmas Eve or New Year's Eve is on a Sunday, from 12 noon to 2 a.m. the following day.</section></section><section prefix="(3)">For the holders of a Class B (on- and off-sale) beer and light wine license sales are permitted as follows:<section prefix="(i)">(On- and off-sale) is permitted on Monday through Saturday from 6 a.m. to 1:45 a.m. the following day;</section><section prefix="(ii)">(On-sale) is permitted on Sunday from 12 noon to 12 midnight, except if Christmas Eve or New Year's Eve is on a Sunday, from 12 noon to 2 a.m. the following day; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">(Off-sale) is prohibited on Sunday after 1 a.m.</section></section><section prefix="(4)">For the holders of a Class C (on-sale) beer license sales are permitted:<section prefix="(i)">Monday through Saturday from 10 a.m. to 1:45 a.m. the following day; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Sunday from 12 noon to 12 midnight, except if Christmas Eve or New Year's Eve is on a Sunday, from 12 noon to 2 a.m. the following day.</section></section><section prefix="(5)">For the holders of a Class D (on-sale) beer license sales are:<section prefix="(i)">Permitted Monday through Saturday from 6 a.m. to 1:45 a.m. on the following day; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Permitted on Sunday from 12 noon through 12 midnight, except if Christmas Eve or New Year's Eve is on a Sunday, from 12 noon to 2 a.m. the following day.</section></section><section prefix="(6)">For the holders of a Class B (on-sale) beer, wine and liquor license sales are permitted:<section prefix="(i)">Monday through Saturday from 7 a.m. through 1:45 a.m. the following day; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Sunday from 10 a.m. through 12 midnight, except if Christmas Eve or New Year's Eve is on a Sunday, from 10 a.m. to 2 a.m. the following day.</section></section><section prefix="(7)">For the holders of a Class C (on-sale) beer, wine and liquor license sales are permitted:<section prefix="(i)">Monday through Saturday from 10 a.m. through 1:45 a.m. the following day; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Sunday from 12 noon through 12 midnight, except if Christmas Eve or New Year's Eve is on a Sunday, from 12 noon to 2 a.m. the following day.</section></section><section prefix="(8)">For the holders of a Class 6 pub-brewery license, sales are permitted:<section prefix="(i)">Monday through Saturday from 7 a.m. through 1:45 a.m. the following day; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Sunday from 12 noon through 12 midnight, except if Christmas Eve or New Year's Eve is on a Sunday, from 12 noon through 2 a.m. the following day.</section></section><section prefix="(9)">For the holders of a Class A light wine license, sales are permitted:<section prefix="(i)">Monday through Saturday from 6 a.m. through 1 a.m. the following day; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Sunday from 12 noon through 12 midnight, except if Christmas Eve or New Year's Eve is on a Sunday, from 12 noon through 2 a.m. the following day.</section></section><section prefix="(10)">For the holders of a Class A beer and light wine license, sales are permitted:<section prefix="(i)">Monday through Saturday from 6 a.m. through midnight; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Sunday from 6 a.m. through midnight, except if Christmas Eve or New Year's Eve is on a Sunday, from 6 a.m. through 2 a.m. the following day.</section></section><section prefix="(11)">For the holders of a Class C beer and light wine license, sales are permitted:<section prefix="(i)">Monday through Saturday from 6 a.m. through 1:45 a.m. the following day; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Sunday from noon through midnight, except if Christmas Eve or New Year's Eve is on a Sunday, from noon through 2 a.m. the following day.</section></section><section prefix="(12)">For the holders of a Class D beer and light wine license, sales are permitted:<section prefix="(i)">Monday through Saturday from 6 a.m. through 1:45 a.m. the following day; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Sunday from noon through midnight, except if Christmas Eve or New Year's Eve is on a Sunday, from noon through 2 a.m. the following day.</section></section><section prefix="(13)">For the holders of a Class A beer, wine and liquor license, sales are permitted:<section prefix="(i)">Monday through Saturday from 6 a.m. through midnight; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Sunday from 6 a.m. through midnight, except if Christmas Eve or New Year's Eve is on a Sunday, from 6 a.m. through 2 a.m. the following day.</section></section><section prefix="(14)">For the holders of a Class D beer, wine and liquor license, sales are allowed:<section prefix="(i)">Monday through Saturday from 6 a.m. through 1:45 a.m. the following day; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Sunday from noon through midnight, except if Christmas Eve or New Year's Eve is on a Sunday, from noon through 2 a.m. the following day.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">On-sale consumption of alcoholic beverages is allowed:<section prefix="(i)">Until 2 a.m.; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">If Christmas Eve or New Year's Eve is on a Sunday, until 3 a.m. the following day.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">At the time consumption of alcoholic beverages must end under paragraph (1)(i) or (ii) of this subsection, all tables and bar areas must be cleared of alcoholic beverages.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
