<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="g2b" order_by="" level="1">Alcoholic Beverages</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>g2b-6-704</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>704</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This section applies only in Harford County.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The annual license fee is $1,500, which shall be paid to the Board before the license is issued and which shall be distributed as provided.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">In this section, "caterer" means an establishment that owns or leases 1 or more banquet rooms suitable for public gatherings, with food preparation facilities on the premises, which contracts to provide food and alcoholic beverages to sponsors of public or private events.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A Class H beer, wine and liquor license may be issued upon the approval of the Liquor Control Board and authorizes the owner or operator of a catering establishment to keep for sale and sell all alcoholic beverages at retail at the premises described therein for consumption on the premises during the catered event.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Notwithstanding the provisions of &#xA7; 12-107 of this article or any other contrary provision of this article, a caterer licensed under this section also may contract with patrons to permit them to bring personal alcoholic beverages onto the premises of the caterer for consumption at catered events.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A caterer licensed under this section may contract to provide alcoholic beverages at events held off the premises, provided that:<section prefix="(i)">The caterer contracts to provide food, as well as alcoholic beverages, for consumption at the catered event; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">The event is held in Harford County.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">A caterer licensed under this section may provide food and keep and sell at retail alcoholic beverages, for consumption only on the premises of the caterer, at a self-sponsored event held once during a calendar year on a day selected by the caterer.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This section does not require a hotel or restaurant which presently holds a Class B beer, wine and liquor license to obtain a Class H license if catering is, or has been, a part of the service provided by the hotel or restaurant.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If a holder of an existing hotel or restaurant Class B beer, wine and liquor license provides catering services on or off the licensed premises, the holder is subject to the requirements of subsection (b)(3) of this section.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A beer, wine and liquor license may be issued to a caterer who has entered into an exclusive lease with a volunteer fire company for a banquet facility owned by that volunteer fire company.</section>
  </text>
</law>
