<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="g2b" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="9-204.3" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>g2b-9-204.3</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, in Baltimore City, no new license, or removal of an existing license, shall be granted to sell alcoholic beverages in any building located within 300 feet of the nearest point of the buildings of a church or school, but the license of any person now holding a license for any building located within such distance of the building grounds of a church or school may be renewed or extended for the same building.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">In the 45th Legislative District in Baltimore City, a new Class A license of any type may not be issued for the sale of alcoholic beverages in a building located within 500 feet of the nearest point of the building of a place of worship or school.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The restrictions regarding distance in subsection (a)(1) of this section do not apply to the following licenses, which may be issued within the 300 feet limitation:<section prefix="(1)">Except in the 46th Legislative District, Class B beer and wine;</section><section prefix="(2)">Except in the 46th Legislative District, Class B beer, wine and liquor;</section><section prefix="(3)">Class C beer and wine; and</section><section prefix="(4)">Class C beer, wine and liquor.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Except in the 46th Legislative District, the governing body of any church in writing may waive the restrictions of this section regarding licenses not specified in subsection (b) with respect to cafes or restaurants located within 250 feet of a theater having a capacity of not less than 300 seats, which theater is operated by a nonprofit theater association.</section>
  </text>
</law>
