<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="g2b" order_by="" level="1">Alcoholic Beverages</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>g2b-8-204.8</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>204.8</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">This section applies only in Baltimore County.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Subject to &#xA7; 8-204.7 of this subtitle and paragraph (2) of this subsection, from May 1, 2012, to April 30, 2017, both inclusive, the Board of Liquor License Commissioners may authorize the transfer of a Class B or Class D license in existence in election district 15 on May 1, 2012, to an election district in which the number of licenses in existence, on the date of approval of the transfer, is not greater than 25% more than the number of licenses that would otherwise exist in that election district, based on the rule of the Board of Liquor License Commissioners that limits the total number of licenses available in an election district by population.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Not more than two licenses may be transferred under this subsection into any single election district each year from May 1, 2012, to April 30, 2017, both inclusive.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In accordance with this subsection, the Board of Liquor License Commissioners shall:<section prefix="(i)">Approve the transfer of Class B or Class D licenses from election district 15 to any other election district in the County; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">Issue new Class B Service Bar (SB) licenses under subsection (d) of this section.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">On or before April 30, 2013, the Board shall:<section prefix="(i)">Approve the transfer of five Class B or Class D licenses; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">If five licenses are not transferred, issue new Class B Service Bar (SB) licenses so that the number of licenses transferred or issued since May 1, 2012, totals five.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">On or before April 30, 2014, the Board shall:<section prefix="(i)">Approve the transfer of Class B or Class D licenses so that the cumulative number of licenses transferred or issued under this subsection since May 1, 2012, totals at least 10; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">If the number of licenses transferred under item (i) of this paragraph is not sufficient, issue new Class B Service Bar (SB) licenses so that the cumulative number of licenses transferred or issued under this subsection since May 1, 2012, equals 10.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">On or before April 30, 2015, the Board shall:<section prefix="(i)">Approve the transfer of Class B or Class D licenses so that the cumulative number of licenses transferred or issued under this subsection since May 1, 2012, totals at least 15; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">If the number of licenses transferred under item (i) of this paragraph is not sufficient, issue new Class B Service Bar (SB) licenses so that the cumulative number of licenses transferred or issued under this subsection since May 1, 2012, equals 15.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(5)">On or before April 30, 2016, the Board shall:<section prefix="(i)">Approve the transfer of Class B or Class D licenses so that the cumulative number of licenses transferred or issued under this subsection since May 1, 2012, totals at least 20; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">If the number of licenses transferred under item (i) of this paragraph is not sufficient, issue new Class B Service Bar (SB) licenses so that the cumulative number of licenses transferred or issued under this subsection since May 1, 2012, equals 20.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(6)">On or before April 30, 2017, the Board shall:<section prefix="(i)">Approve the transfer of Class B or Class D licenses so that the cumulative number of licenses issued or transferred under this subsection since May 1, 2012, totals at least 25; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">If the number of licenses transferred under item (i) of this paragraph is not sufficient, issue new Class B Service Bar (SB) licenses so that the cumulative number of licenses issued or transferred under this subsection since May 1, 2012, equals 25.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(7)">In any year, if the Board approves the transfer of more Class B or Class D licenses than are needed to meet the minimum total required for that year, the excess will be counted against the minimum total required for the next year.</section>
      <section prefix="(8)">The date a license is transferred under this subsection is the date of final, nonappealable approval of the application for a new license or for license transfer by the Board.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A Class B Service Bar (SB) beer and wine license may be issued only in compliance with this subsection.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A Class B Service Bar (SB) license may be used only in the operation of a restaurant, as defined by the Board of Liquor License Commissioners and this article, that maintains average daily receipts from the sale of food of at least 60% of the total daily receipts of the establishment.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A Class B Service Bar (SB) license shall allow on-premises sales of beer and wine only.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">A Class B Service Bar (SB) license allows alcoholic beverages to be served to patrons only as part of a meal.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">
        <section prefix="(i)">A Class B Service Bar (SB) license shall be restricted to restaurants that have table service.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">A Class B Service Bar (SB) license does not allow service to a customer who is standing or accepting delivery of purchased food or beverage items other than while seated at a table.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(6)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Except as provided in subparagraph (ii) of this paragraph, the proposed location of the restaurant for which a Class B Service Bar (SB) license is sought shall comply with the zoning ordinances of Baltimore County, including allowing seating for not fewer than 30 customers and not more than 100 customers.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The license may not be used in conjunction with the viewing of televised sporting events or the use of live bands, disc jockeys, karaoke, or any other form of live entertainment.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(7)">A Class B or D license transferred under subsection (b) of this section or a Class B Service Bar (SB) license issued under this subsection may not thereafter be transferred from the licensed premises or converted to another class of license.</section>
      <section prefix="(8)">Not more than one Class B Service Bar (SB) license may be issued in any one election district per year.</section>
      <section prefix="(9)">A Class B Service Bar (SB) license may not be issued for use on premises or a location for which any on-sale license has been issued within 2 years before the application for the Class B Service Bar (SB) license is filed.</section>
      <section prefix="(10)">Any person, including an individual or sole proprietorship, partnership, corporation, unincorporated association, and limited liability company, may not have a direct or indirect interest as defined in &#xA7; 9-102(b-3B) of this article in more than one Class B Service Bar (SB) license.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The annual fee for a Class B Service Bar (SB) beer and wine license issued under this section is $5,000.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">When a license is transferred from election district 15 to another election district under this section, the license may not be construed to exist in election district 15.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Subject to the 25% allowance authorized in subsection (b) of this section, a license transferred under this section shall be considered by the Board of Liquor License Commissioners as a regular license and not an exception license for determining the total number of licenses available in any election district based on the rule of the Board of Liquor License Commissioners that limits the total number of licenses available by population.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
