<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="g2b" order_by="2" level="1">Alcoholic Beverages</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>g2b-8-410.2</section_number>
  <catch_line>This section applies only in Somerset County....</catch_line>
  <order_by>410.2</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">This section applies only in Somerset County.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Board of License Commissioners may issue a wine tasting (WT) license for wine tasting and sampling.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A WT license may be issued only to a holder of a Class A beer and wine (off-sale) license.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The annual WT license fee is $150.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">An application for a WT license shall be made on a form that the Board of License Commissioners provides.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A renewal of the WT license may be made at the time the Class A beer and wine (off-sale) license is renewed.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Board of License Commissioners may grant a WT license without a hearing.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">If application for a WT license is denied, the applicant may request a public hearing before the Board of License Commissioners.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A WT license holder may not serve to any person for sampling or tasting purposes more than 1 ounce from each brand.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A maximum of six bottles may be opened at any one time at a wine sampling or tasting event.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The total number of days during which wine sampling or tasting events are held may not exceed 15 in any period for which a WT license is in effect.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">A WT license holder shall notify the Board of License Commissioners in writing at least 5 days before a wine sampling or tasting event.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">Once opened, each bottle used for a wine sampling or tasting event shall be marked that it is to be used for that purpose only.</section>
      <section prefix="(6)">The contents of each bottle may not be mixed with any other bottle, and all bottles shall be destroyed once they are empty.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A WT license is for on-premises consumption only.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Wine sampling or tasting may not be conducted from a drive-through window.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
