<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="g2b" order_by="" level="1">Alcoholic Beverages</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>g2b-2-209</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>209</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">There is a Class 8 farm brewery license.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Subject to paragraph (3) of this subsection, a Class 8 farm brewery license allows the licensee to sell and deliver beer manufactured in a facility on the licensed farm or in a facility other than one on the licensed farm to:<section prefix="(i)">A wholesaler licensed to sell and deliver beer in the State; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">A person in another state authorized to acquire beer.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The beer to be sold and delivered under paragraph (2) of this subsection shall be manufactured with an ingredient from a Maryland agricultural product, including hops, grain, and fruit, produced on the licensed farm.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">A Class 8 farm brewery may be located only at the place stated on the license.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">Notwithstanding any local law, a licensee may exercise the privileges of a Class 8 farm brewery license.</section>
      <section prefix="(6)">A licensee may:<section prefix="(i)">Sell beer produced by the licensee for consumption on the licensed farm;</section><section prefix="(ii)">In an amount not exceeding 6 fluid ounces per brand, provide samples of beer that the licensee produces to a consumer:<section prefix="1.">At no charge; or</section><section prefix="2.">For a fee; and</section></section><section prefix="(iii)">Sell or serve:<section prefix="1.">Bread and other baked goods;</section><section prefix="2.">Chili;</section><section prefix="3.">Chocolate;</section><section prefix="4.">Crackers;</section><section prefix="5.">Cured meat;</section><section prefix="6.">Fruits (whole and cut);</section><section prefix="7.">Salads and vegetables (whole and cut);</section><section prefix="8.">Hard and soft cheese (whole and cut);</section><section prefix="9.">Ice cream;</section><section prefix="10.">Jelly;</section><section prefix="11.">Jam;</section><section prefix="12.">Vinegar;</section><section prefix="13.">Pizza;</section><section prefix="14.">Prepackaged sandwiches and other prepackaged foods ready to be eaten;</section><section prefix="15.">Soup; and</section><section prefix="16.">Condiments.</section></section></section>
      <section prefix="(7)">Subject to subsections (d) and (e) of this section, a licensee may exercise the privileges of the license each day during the following times:<section prefix="(i)">From 10 a.m. to 6 p.m., for consumption of beer and sales and service of food at the licensed farm; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">From 10 a.m. to 10 p.m., for:<section prefix="1.">Sampling of beer;</section><section prefix="2.">Consumption of beer off the licensed farm if the beer is packaged in sealed or resealable containers, such as growlers; and</section><section prefix="3.">Guests who attend a planned promotion event or other organized activity at the licensed farm.</section></section></section>
      <section prefix="(8)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Except as provided in subparagraph (ii) of this paragraph, a Class 8 farm brewery license allows the licensee to operate 7 days a week.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">In Garrett County, a licensee may open on Sundays during the hours allowed under &#xA7; 11-512(c)(3) of this article to engage in the activities listed in paragraph (3) of this subsection only in an election district where the voters, in a referendum authorized by law, have approved Sunday sales at a farm.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(9)">Except as provided under subsection (d) of this section, a licensee may not sell or allow to be consumed at the location of the farm brewery any alcoholic beverage other than the beer produced by the licensee under the authority of this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(10)">Nothing in this subsection limits the application of relevant provisions of Title 21 of the Health - General Article, and regulations adopted under that title, to a licensee.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The place listed on the Class 8 farm brewery license shall be in compliance with &#xA7; 9-103 of this article.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A licensee may:<section prefix="(1)">Store on its licensed farm, in a segregated area approved by the Comptroller, beer produced at the licensed farm for sale and delivery to a wholesaler licensed in the State or a person outside of the State authorized to acquire the beer;</section><section prefix="(2)">Brew, bottle, or contract for not more than 15,000 barrels of beer each calendar year;</section><section prefix="(3)">Contract with the holder of a Class 5 brewery license or a Class 2 rectifying license to brew and bottle beer from ingredients produced on the licensed farm;</section><section prefix="(4)">Import, export, and transport its beer in accordance with this section; and</section><section prefix="(5)">Store beer at a warehouse for which the licensee has been issued an individual storage permit, for sale and delivery to a wholesaler licensed in the State or a person outside of the State authorized to acquire the beer, or shipment back to the licensed farm, if:<section prefix="(i)">The licensee does not serve or sell beer at the warehouse; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">The Comptroller has full access at all times to the warehouse to enforce this article.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A licensee may sponsor a multibrewery activity at the licensed farm that:<section prefix="(i)">Includes the products of other Maryland breweries; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Provides for the sale of beer by the glass for consumption on the premises only.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">In a segregated area approved by the Comptroller on the licensed farm, a licensee may store the products of other Maryland breweries for the multibrewery activity.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The multibrewery activity:<section prefix="(i)">May be held from 10 a.m. to 10 p.m. each day; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">May not exceed 3 consecutive days.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Office of the Comptroller may issue a special brewery promotional event permit to a licensee.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">At least 15 days before holding a planned promotional event, the licensee shall obtain a permit from the Comptroller by filing a notice of the promotional event on the form that the Comptroller provides.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The permit authorizes the licensee to conduct at the licensed farm a promotional event at which the licensee may:<section prefix="(i)">Provide samples of not more than 6 fluid ounces per brand to consumers; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Sell beer produced by the licensee to persons who participate in the event.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The beer at the event shall be sold by the glass and for consumption on the premises only.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">The licensee may not be issued more than 12 permits in a calendar year.</section>
      <section prefix="(6)">A single promotional event:<section prefix="(i)">May be held from 10 a.m. to 10 p.m. each day; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">May not exceed 3 consecutive days.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(7)">The permit fee is $25 per event.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
