<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="g2b" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="8-218" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>g2b-8-218</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In the alcoholic beverage laws for Queen Anne's County, the following words mean:<section prefix="(1)">The word "restaurant" as used in &#xA7; 3-201 and in &#xA7; 6-201 of this article, when applied to Queen Anne's County, means a business establishment for the accommodation of the public, fully equipped with a proper and adequate dining room having a seating capacity of at least 12 persons and with sufficient facilities for preparing and serving meals, which has been approved by the Board of License Commissioners of Queen Anne's County, wherein the average daily receipts from the sale of food comprise at least 51 percent of the average daily receipts of the business.</section><section prefix="(2)">The word "hotel" as used in &#xA7; 3-201 and &#xA7; 6-201 of this article, when applied to Queen Anne's County, means a building or structure erected or constructed for hotel purposes having 20 or more bedrooms providing services ordinarily found in hotels, for the accommodation of the public, containing a dining room with facilities for preparing and serving meals wherein the average daily receipts from the sale of food exceed the average daily receipts from the sale of alcoholic beverages.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Holders of all classes of retail alcoholic beverages licenses in Queen Anne's County may exercise their license privileges on Sunday from 8 a.m. until the closing hour permitted by that class of license during any other day of the week.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Any licensee holding a Class B license, of any type, issued in Queen Anne's County, biannually, on dates to be set by the Board of License Commissioners, shall file with the Board a sworn statement that the gross receipts from food sales in the restaurant for the six-month period immediately preceding the filing of this report, are in excess of the gross receipts from the sale of alcoholic beverages. However, nothing prohibits the Board of License Commissioners from requiring more frequent sworn statements.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Board may require any licensee to provide any supporting data as it, in its discretion, considers necessary in order to establish that the requirements of subsection (a) relating to the ratio of gross receipts from the sale of food to those from the sale of alcoholic beverages have been met.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">As a prerequisite for the initial issuance of a Class B license, of any type issued in Queen Anne's County, the applicants shall attest in a sworn statement that gross receipts from food sales in the restaurant will be in excess of the gross receipts from the sale of alcoholic beverages.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">In the event that a Class B licensee of any type issued in Queen Anne's County fails to maintain gross receipts from the sale of food in excess of gross receipts from the alcoholic beverages during any six-month period, the Board, in its discretion, may revoke the license.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Board of License Commissioners of Queen Anne's County may authorize the issuance of an additional license to be known as a Class B-D beer, wine, and liquor license. This special license authorizes the holder to keep for sale, and sell, all alcoholic beverages at retail at the place described on the license for consumption on the premises. The holder of this license may also sell beer for consumption off the premises.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">This license is issued only to establishments having facilities for preparing and serving food to the public, whose average daily gross receipts from the sale of food comprise at least 25 percent of the average daily gross receipts of the entire business and have been approved by the Board of License Commissioners for Queen Anne's County.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">All restaurants having a valid Class B beer, wine, and liquor license are entitled to exchange their current license for a Class B-D license.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The annual fee for this license is $1,800.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
