<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="g2b" order_by="" level="1">Alcoholic Beverages</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>g2b-20-105</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>105</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, "bottle club" means:<section prefix="(1)">Any person, corporation, partnership, club, or organization that:<section prefix="(i)">Offers or provides any form of live entertainment to its members or to the public; and</section><section prefix="(ii)"><section prefix="1.">Serves, sells, gives, or dispenses alcoholic beverages to its members or guests;</section><section prefix="2.">Keeps any alcoholic beverages for its members or guests; or</section><section prefix="3.">Allows members or guests to consume alcoholic beverages on its premises if the members or guests reserved, purchased, or brought the beverages to the premises;</section></section></section><section prefix="(2)">Any club that serves, gives, or allows alcoholic beverages to be consumed by patrons after legal closing hours for establishments licensed under this article from supplies that the patrons previously purchased or reserved; or</section><section prefix="(3)">Any club that sells, dispenses, serves, keeps, or allows any setups or other components of mixed alcoholic drinks to be consumed by its members or guests with privately obtained alcoholic beverages.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Bottle club" does not include any establishment if a license for the premises had been issued under the provisions of this article.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">This section applies only in Charles County.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A bottle club may not sell, give, serve, dispense, keep, or allow to be consumed on its premises, or on premises under its control or possession, any alcoholic beverages, setups, or other component parts of mixed alcoholic drinks.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The following are exempted from the provisions of subsection (d) of this section so long as live entertainment is not offered or provided on more than 8 days in any calendar month:<section prefix="(1)">The room of a registered guest in a hotel or motel;</section><section prefix="(2)">Property owned by a volunteer fire company;</section><section prefix="(3)">Property owned and operated by a community or homeowners association comprised solely of property owners in a single subdivision; or</section><section prefix="(4)">Property owned by a bona fide religious institution.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">A violation of this section is a misdemeanor and a fine of up to $10,000 or imprisonment for up to 2 years, or both, may be imposed.</section>
  </text>
</law>
