<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="g2b" order_by="2" level="1">Alcoholic Beverages</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>g2b-9-214</section_number>
  <catch_line>This section applies only in Howard County....</catch_line>
  <order_by>214</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">This section applies only in Howard County.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A license to sell alcoholic beverages may not be first issued after June 30, 1971, for any building located within 500 feet of the nearest point of the public school building.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A license issued on or before that date may be renewed for the same building and type of license.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A license issued on or before that date may be transferred or assigned to a new licensee for the same building and type of license.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">Any decision of the Board of Education after June 30, 1971, to locate a public school building within 500 feet of an existing licensee may not be the basis for the revocation or denial of renewal or transfer of that alcoholic beverages license.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Board of License Commissioners may not issue, transfer, or approve an application on behalf of an off-sale alcoholic beverages license of any class for the use in a business that is intended to be operated as a drive-through purchase facility where alcoholic beverages are to be sold at retail and dispensed through a window or door to a purchaser in or on a motor vehicle for off-premises consumption.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">When application for a liquor license is made to sell alcoholic beverages in a building which is not completed, the Board of License Commissioners may give tentative approval of the application on the basis of plans and specifications that accompany the application. Upon completion of the building in accordance with the plans and specifications, the Board may issue the license.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">On determining whether to approve an application for a new Class A license, regardless of kind, the Appointed Alcoholic Beverage Hearing Board shall include in its written decision findings as to each of the factors set forth in &#xA7; 10-202(a)(2)(i) of this article.</section>
  </text>
</law>
