<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="g2b" order_by="" level="1">Alcoholic Beverages</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>g2b-15-112</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>112</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The boards of license commissioners in this State may issue the alcoholic beverages licenses provided for by this article in their respective jurisdictions.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Each board may employ a secretary and inspectors, clerical and other assistance as is necessary, and fix the compensation of the employees, except as otherwise provided by this article.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">In this section, "Board" means the Board of License Commissioners, unless otherwise noted.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This subsection applies only in Allegany County.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The inspectors shall:<section prefix="(i)">Have all the powers of a peace officer or a constable or sheriff of this State;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Make oath to faithfully perform the duties entrusted to them, as provided in Article I, &#xA7; 9 of the Constitution of this State; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Furnish bond in the penalty of $2,000 to the Board and the Board of County Commissioners jointly, conditioned, "that inspectors shall well and faithfully execute the office in all things appertaining thereto". The cost of the bond shall be paid by the County Commissioners. The inspectors shall be known as "alcoholic beverage inspectors for Allegany County".</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">This subsection applies only in Anne Arundel County.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">Except for paragraph (2) of this subsection, it does not apply in the City of Annapolis.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">This paragraph applies only in the City of Annapolis.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The Mayor, Counsellor and Aldermen of Annapolis may make and enforce regulations and restrictions, in addition to, or in substitution of, those contained in this article, but not inconsistent therewith, as in their judgment would give the municipality more effective control of each of the places of business.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">In addition to the powers given to the Board in subsection (a) of this section, the Board may employ one part-time chief inspector at an annual salary of $10,000, one part-time deputy chief inspector at an annual salary of $8,000 and 18 part-time inspectors at an annual salary of $6,000 each.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">In addition to a salary stated in subparagraph (i) of this paragraph, each of the inspectors shall receive a monthly expense of $300 per month, subject to the approval of the State Comptroller.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The 20 inspectors shall:<section prefix="(i)">Have all the powers of a peace officer or a constable or sheriff of this State;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Make oath to faithfully perform the duties entrusted to them, as provided in Article I, &#xA7; 9 of the Constitution of this State; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Furnish bond in the penalty of $2,000 to the Board and the County Council jointly, conditioned "that inspector shall well and faithfully execute the office in all things appertaining thereto". The cost of the bond shall be paid by the county. The inspectors for Anne Arundel County are known as the "liquor inspectors for Anne Arundel County".</section></section>
      <section prefix="(5)">The Board of License Commissioners:<section prefix="(i)">May employ up to two full-time administrators whose annual salaries shall be fixed by the Board as in a general Anne Arundel County classified salary schedule, within pay grade 16;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Shall employ a full-time secretary whose annual salary shall be fixed by the Board as in a general county classified salary schedule, within pay grade 13; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Shall employ an attorney at an annual salary of $20,000.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(6)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The Board of License Commissioners may suspend immediately an alcoholic beverages license if a person authorized under &#xA7; 16-405 of this article alleges that the licensee has sold or furnished alcoholic beverages to a person under the age of 21 years with such frequency and during such a limited time period so as to demonstrate a willful failure to comply with &#xA7; 12-108(a) of this article.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">A suspension under this paragraph may not exceed 7 days.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">If a license is suspended under this paragraph, the Board shall:<section prefix="1.">Hold a hearing on the matter within 7 days after the suspension; and</section><section prefix="2.">Give notice to the licensee at least 2 days before the hearing.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(iv)">If the Board fails to provide the licensee with notice of a hearing before the end of the fifth day following a suspension, the suspension shall end, and the licensee shall be allowed to resume the sale of alcoholic beverages on the next day allowed under the license.</section>
        <section prefix="(v)">This paragraph does not prevent a licensee whose license is suspended under this paragraph from seeking an injunction or other appropriate relief.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This subsection applies only in Baltimore City.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A commissioner or employee of the Board:<section prefix="(i)">May not have any interest, direct or indirect, either proprietary or by means of any loan, mortgage or lien, or in any other manner, in or on any premises where alcoholic beverages are manufactured, distributed, or sold;</section><section prefix="(ii)">May not have any interest, direct or indirect, in any business wholly or partially devoted to the manufacture, distribution, or sale of alcoholic beverages;</section><section prefix="(iii)">May not own any stock in any corporation which has any interest, proprietary or otherwise, direct or indirect, in any premises where alcoholic beverages are manufactured, distributed, or sold or in any business wholly or partially devoted to the manufacture, distribution, or sale of alcoholic beverages; or</section><section prefix="(iv)">May not receive any salary or other compensation or any other thing of value from a business engaged in the manufacture, distribution, or sale of alcoholic beverages.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">An employee of the Board may not hold any other federal, State, or local public office or employment.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">A commissioner of the Board may hold any other public office or employment, federal, State or local, unless that public office or employment would pose a conflict of interest.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Every employee of the Board:<section prefix="1.">Shall devote that employee's whole time and attention to the business of the Board during the hours designated by the Board for the performance of official duties;</section><section prefix="2.">May not engage in any occupation, business or profession in any way connected or associated, directly or indirectly, with the manufacture or sale of alcoholic beverages; and</section><section prefix="3.">May not transact business of any kind whatsoever beyond his or her official duties with any licensee, or in connection with the operation of any establishment licensed for the manufacture or sale of alcoholic beverages.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">Any employee of the Board who violates any of the provisions of this subsection shall be removed.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(6)">
        <section prefix="(i)">As to any entity licensed under the provisions of this article, a commissioner or employee of the Board may not solicit or receive directly or indirectly any commission, remuneration or gift whatsoever from any:<section prefix="1.">Person or corporation engaged in the manufacture or sale of beer or other alcoholic beverages;</section><section prefix="2.">Agent or employee of that person or corporation; or</section><section prefix="3.">Licensee licensed under the provisions of this article.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">A person or corporation engaged in the manufacture or sale of beer or other alcoholic beverages, any agent or employee of that person or corporation, and a licensee licensed under the provisions of this article may not, either directly or indirectly, offer to pay any commission, profit or remuneration or make any gift to any commissioner or employee of the Board or to anyone on behalf of that commissioner or employee of the Board.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(7)">The chairman of the Board:<section prefix="(i)">Is its administrative officer and is charged with the duty of enforcing the provisions of this article;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Shall personally supervise the activities and investigations of the several inspectors and other employees of the Board;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Shall examine the location and general character of the licensees in the City; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">Shall make recommendations to the Board concerning zoning of licensees, methods of enforcement, and promulgation of regulations to carry out the purposes of this article.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(8)">Regulations adopted by the Board shall be published and distributed to whichever licensees are affected by them. The Board may require any licensee to display prominently in the licensee's place of business any regulation of the Board, or any excerpt or statement from this article.</section>
      <section prefix="(9)">The Board shall:<section prefix="(i)">Employ 12 permanent part-time inspectors; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Set the annual salary for permanent part-time inspectors at not less than $3,600.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(10)">The Board shall:<section prefix="(i)">Employ a qualified attorney to serve as appellate counsel for the Board in actions of appeal; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Set for appellate counsel the same compensation and benefits as are set for the Assistant Chief Inspector-Grade 097 or the Chief Inspector-Grade 099.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(11)">
        <section prefix="(i)">
          <section prefix="1.">In this paragraph, "inspectors" means full-time inspectors who are employees of the Board. "Inspectors" does not include an inspector supervisor or assistant inspector supervisor.</section>
          <section prefix="2.">Inspectors who were appointed prior to October 1, 1997, shall continue their appointment after that date unless removed in accordance with classified civil service procedures.</section>
        </section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">As of October 1, 1997:<section prefix="1.">Inspectors are part of the classified civil service of the City;</section><section prefix="2.">The Board may appoint and remove inspectors only in accordance with the provisions of law that govern classified civil service employees of the City;</section><section prefix="3.">An employee of the Board may not solicit or receive, directly or indirectly or on behalf of another person, a commission, political contribution, remuneration, or gift from:</section><section prefix="4.">An employee or other person specified in sub-subparagraph 3 of this subparagraph who violates the provisions of that sub-subparagraph is subject to the penalties specified in &#xA7; 16-503 of this article.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">The provisions of this paragraph do not alter the process by which inspectors' salaries are funded.</section>
        <section prefix="(iv)">The inspector supervisor and assistant inspector supervisor shall be residents of Baltimore City.</section>
        <section prefix="(v)">The inspector supervisor, assistant inspector supervisor, office assistant, accounting assistant, secretary III, office supervisor, and applications investigator appointed prior to October 1, 1998 shall continue their appointment after that date unless removed in accordance with classified civil service procedures.</section>
        <section prefix="(vi)">As of October 1, 1998:<section prefix="1.">The inspector supervisor, assistant inspector supervisor, office assistant, accounting assistant, secretary III, and office supervisor are part of the classified civil service of Baltimore City.</section><section prefix="2.">There shall be an assistant executive secretary which position shall replace the position of administrative coordinator. The assistant executive secretary shall be part of the classified civil service of Baltimore City.</section></section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(12)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Subject to the provisions in subparagraph (ii) of this paragraph, the salaries of employees of the Board shall be determined by the members of the Board with the advice and consent of the senators from Baltimore City.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The Board may consider an employee's length of service in determining the appropriate salary level.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(13)">The following is the schedule of City Union of Baltimore (CUB) salary grade levels for employees of the Board:<section prefix="(i)">Office Assistant - Grade 082;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Inspector I - Grade 082;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Inspection Division Office Assistant - Grade 082;</section><section prefix="(iv)">Inspector II - Grade 085;</section><section prefix="(v)">Accounting Assistant II - Grade 085;</section><section prefix="(vi)">Secretary III - Grade 086;</section><section prefix="(vii)">311 Call Center Supervisor - Grade 093;</section><section prefix="(viii)">Inspector III - Grade 088;</section><section prefix="(ix)">Assistant Executive Secretary - Grade 099;</section><section prefix="(x)">Assistant Chief Inspector - Grade 097; and</section><section prefix="(xi)">Chief Inspector - Grade 099.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(14)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Subject to subparagraph (ii) of this paragraph, each inspector employed by the Board may examine any identification used as proof of age by a person for the purchase of alcoholic beverages in the City.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">An examination shall be made on the premises of the licensed establishment where the purchase is attempted.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(15)">An action of a commissioner or employee of the Board is subject to State requirements for open or public meetings, including requirements for open sessions under Title 10, Subtitle 5 of the State Government Article.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This subsection applies only in Baltimore County.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Board may appoint a Chief License Inspector and at least 14 license inspectors. The salaries shall be as determined by the county, but the salary of the Chief License Inspector may not be less than $9,500 a year and the salary of each of the remaining license inspectors may not be less than $9,000 a year. Each license inspector and the Chief License Inspector may request and examine any identification used as proof of age by any person for the purchase of alcoholic beverages provided that the request and examination are made on the licensed premises in the county.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">In addition to the other powers and duties conferred on them, the Board may prescribe regulations:<section prefix="(i)">Regarding the presence of any person not designated under &#xA7; 1-102(a)(6) of this article on any premises licensed to sell alcoholic beverages; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Concerning the granting and the date of issuing licenses when the actual use of the license is to be deferred until the completion of construction work or alterations on the premises.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This subsection applies only in Calvert County.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Board may appoint:<section prefix="(i)">A clerk and an attorney at a salary to be set by the County Commissioners; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">With the approval of the County Commissioners, full-time or part-time alcoholic beverages inspectors whose salary shall be set by the County Commissioners on an annual or per diem basis, and who shall be paid reasonable expenses related to performance of duties.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This subsection applies only in Caroline County.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The county codes administrator is the inspector for the Board of License Commissioners.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The salary of the inspector shall be as provided in the county budget. The duties of the inspector shall be as specified by the Board, including the proper administration and enforcement of the alcoholic beverages laws of Caroline County.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The Board may appoint an attorney for the Board.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The compensation for the attorney shall be set by the County Commissioners.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">The attorney is subject to the county ethics ordinance.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(h)">Reserved.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This subsection applies only in Cecil County.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Board shall issue all retail alcoholic beverages licenses authorized under this article, except Class E, F, and G licenses.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Board may employ one full-time alcoholic beverages inspector and may also employ as many additional part-time alcoholic beverages inspectors as it deems necessary. The salary shall be as provided in the annual budget of the Board of County Commissioners for part-time inspectors and within the total appropriations for this purpose. The employment of the alcoholic beverages inspectors shall be subject to the provisions of the Cecil County Personnel Policy and Procedure Manual. The salaries and travel expenses of the alcoholic beverages inspectors shall be established by the Board of County Commissioners of Cecil County using county personnel department regulations and guidelines.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The inspector shall investigate all applicants for an alcoholic beverages license or transfer of license, enforce all alcoholic beverages laws, and investigate all violations of the alcoholic beverages laws and report them to the Board.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">The inspector shall:<section prefix="(i)">Have all the powers of a peace officer of this State in respect to the enforcement of the alcoholic beverages laws of the county;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Make an oath, as provided in the Constitution of Maryland, to faithfully perform the duties entrusted to him;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Visit and inspect at unannounced times every licensed premises in the county at least every 90 days; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">Make monthly reports in writing to the Board covering his activities, setting forth any complaints, and listing any violations that may have been observed or reported to the inspector.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(6)">A person may not accept appointment or continue as an inspector if either the inspector or any member of the inspector's immediate family has any personal or financial interest either directly or indirectly in any license or in any licensed premises under the provisions of this article.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(j)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This subsection applies only in Charles County.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Board is the alcoholic beverages license issuing authority.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(k)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This subsection applies only in Dorchester County.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">A member or employee of the Board may not:<section prefix="1.">Have any financial interest, directly or indirectly, in the manufacture of any alcoholic beverage or in any alcoholic beverage purchased or sold under the provisions of this article; or</section><section prefix="2.">Derive any profit or remuneration from the purchase or sale of any alcoholic beverage, other than the salary or wages payable for the performance of the duties of the office or position as required and authorized under this section.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">A person who violates this paragraph is guilty of a misdemeanor and on conviction is subject to a fine not exceeding $2,000 or a term of imprisonment not exceeding 30 days.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">With the approval of the Dorchester County Council, the Board may employ an inspector and a recording secretary who shall be employees of the county as provided in the county budget.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">With the approval of the Dorchester County Council, the Board may appoint legal counsel.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">Restrictions applicable to Board members shall apply to legal counsel and staff assigned to the Board.</section>
        <section prefix="(iv)">County personnel policies and rules shall apply to:<section prefix="1.">Staff assigned to the Board; and</section><section prefix="2.">Board and staff expenses.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(v)">Board and staff expenses shall be provided for in the county budget.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(l)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This subsection applies only in Frederick County.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The appointment of an inspector and the employment of clerical assistants are provided for in &#xA7; 15-103 of this article.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(m)">Reserved.</section>
    <section prefix="(n)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This subsection applies only in Harford County.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">In addition to any inspector who is serving prior to July 1, 1979, the Board and general manager may appoint additional inspectors as necessary to provide appropriate control over newly created Class A off-sale licensees.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(o)">Repealed.</section>
    <section prefix="(p)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This subsection applies only in Kent County.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Notwithstanding &#xA7;&#xA7; 10-401 and 10-403 of this article, the Board may suspend any alcoholic beverages license for any violation of this article for not less than 15 nor more than 90 days. An appeal does not stay the order of the Board suspending a license.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Board:<section prefix="(i)">Shall employ one full-time alcoholic beverages inspector whose salary shall be set by the County Commissioners; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">May employ one additional part-time or full-time alcoholic beverages inspector whose compensation shall be set by the County Commissioners.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Each inspector is entitled to reimbursement for travel expenses at a rate determined by the Board.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The compensation and travel expenses of each inspector shall be paid by the County Commissioners.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(5)">An alcoholic beverages inspector has the following powers and duties:<section prefix="(i)">To investigate all applicants for an alcoholic beverages license or transfer of license;</section><section prefix="(ii)">To enforce all alcoholic beverages laws of Kent County with the same powers as a law enforcement officer of the State;</section><section prefix="(iii)">To inspect, at unannounced times, every licensed premises at least once every 90 days;</section><section prefix="(iv)">To investigate all violations of the alcoholic beverages laws;</section><section prefix="(v)">To report all violations of the alcoholic beverages laws to the Board; and</section><section prefix="(vi)">To give monthly written reports to the Board covering all:<section prefix="1.">Inspection activities;</section><section prefix="2.">Complaints; and</section><section prefix="3.">Violations, either observed or reported.</section></section></section>
      <section prefix="(6)">Before a person qualifies as an alcoholic beverages inspector, the person shall make an oath to faithfully perform the duties entrusted, as provided in Article I, &#xA7; 9 of the Constitution of Maryland.</section>
      <section prefix="(7)">A person may not qualify nor continue service as an alcoholic beverages inspector if the inspector or the inspector's immediate family has any personal or financial interest, either directly or indirectly, in any license, licensee, or in any premises licensed under the provisions of this article.</section>
      <section prefix="(8)">
        <section prefix="(i)">After appointment, an alcoholic beverages inspector shall serve as such and shall be discharged only for cause involving dishonesty, incompetence, or immoral conduct while in the performance of duty.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">Before the discharge of an alcoholic beverages inspector, the Board shall give the inspector written notice of all pending charges and shall afford the inspector an opportunity to reply in an open hearing before the Board, either in person or by counsel.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">The Board shall give notice and hold the hearing in accordance with the Administrative Procedure Act.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(q)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This subsection applies only in Montgomery County.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The office of the County Attorney and other county departments shall be made available to the Board.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">A member of the Board may not:<section prefix="1.">Have any interest, direct or indirect, either proprietary or by means of any loan, mortgage or lien, or in any other manner, in or on any premises where alcoholic beverages are manufactured or sold;</section><section prefix="2.">Have any interest, direct or indirect, in any business wholly or partially devoted to the manufacture or sale of alcoholic beverages;</section><section prefix="3.">Own any stock in any corporation which has any interest, proprietary or otherwise, direct or indirect, in any premises where alcoholic beverages are manufactured or sold or in any business wholly or partially devoted to the manufacture or sale of alcoholic beverages; or</section><section prefix="4.">Hold any other public office, federal, State or local.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">Subject to the provisions of the Montgomery County public ethics law, a commissioner of the Board may be an employee of the federal, State, or local government. However, a commissioner may not be an employee of the county department of liquor control.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(4)">
        <section prefix="(i)">A commissioner or county employee may not solicit or receive directly or indirectly any commission, remuneration or gift whatsoever from any:<section prefix="1.">Person or corporation engaged in the manufacture or sale of beer or other alcoholic beverages;</section><section prefix="2.">Agent or employee of that person or corporation; or</section><section prefix="3.">Licensee licensed under the provisions of this article.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">A person or corporation engaged in the manufacture or sale of beer or other alcoholic beverages, or any agent or employee of that person or corporation, and a licensee licensed under the provisions of this article may not offer, either directly or indirectly, to pay any commission, profit or remuneration or make any gift to any commissioner or county employee or to anyone on behalf of the commissioner or county employee.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(5)">Notwithstanding any other law, the Board shall collect the license fees and issue the alcoholic beverages licenses provided for in this article.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(r)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This subsection applies only in Prince George's County.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Board shall appoint an administrator, an attorney, and all inspectors for the Board.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The inspectors shall:<section prefix="1.">Each have all the powers of a peace officer or a constable or sheriff of this State;</section><section prefix="2.">Make oath to faithfully perform the duties entrusted to them, as provided in Article I, &#xA7; 9 of the Maryland Constitution;</section><section prefix="3.">Be known as "alcoholic beverages inspectors for Prince George's County";</section><section prefix="4.">Have the duty of visiting and inspecting every licensed premises periodically; and</section><section prefix="5.">Carry on the other duties the Board prescribes.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">There are three full-time and 32 part-time inspectors, all of whom shall be county residents. The three full-time inspector positions shall be designated as the chief inspector and the deputy chief inspectors. The three full-time inspectors who meet the standards set out by the Prince George's County merit board and who are certified by the personnel director as meeting these standards shall be entitled to the provisions of the county merit system.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">Each part-time inspector shall receive an annual salary of not less than $9,976.</section>
        <section prefix="(iv)">The Board shall designate annually a chief inspector from among the three full-time inspectors. The chief inspector, under the direction of the Board, shall regulate the duties, hours, and assignments of the various inspectors.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(4)">A commissioner, inspector, or employee of the Board may not:<section prefix="(i)">Have any interest, either proprietary or by means of any loan, mortgage, or lien, or in any other manner, in or on any premises in this State where alcoholic beverages are manufactured or sold; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Have any interest in any business wholly or partially devoted to the manufacture or sale of alcoholic beverages in this State, or own any stock in any corporation which has any interest, proprietary or otherwise, direct or indirect, in any premises in this State where alcoholic beverages are manufactured or sold or in any business wholly or partially devoted to the manufacture or sale of alcoholic beverages in this State.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(5)">Employees of the Board:<section prefix="(i)">Shall devote their whole time and attention to the business of the Board during the hours designated by the Board for the performance of their official duties;</section><section prefix="(ii)">May not engage in any occupation, business, or profession in any way connected or associated with the manufacture or sale of alcoholic beverages; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">May not transact any business of any kind whatsoever beyond their official duties with any licensee, or in connection with the operation of any establishment licensed for the manufacture or sale of alcoholic beverages.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(6)">Any employee of the Board who violates any of the provisions of this section shall be removed.</section>
      <section prefix="(7)">A commissioner, inspector, or employee of the Board may not solicit or receive any commission, remuneration, or gift whatsoever from any person or corporation engaged in the manufacture or sale of beer or other alcoholic beverages, or from any agent or employee of the person or corporation, or from any licensee, licensed under the provisions of this article.</section>
      <section prefix="(8)">A commissioner shall immediately forfeit his office as a license commissioner for the county if the commissioner:<section prefix="(i)">Ceases to reside in the county; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">Ceases to be a registered voter of the county.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(9)">A license commissioner may not serve in any other position of public office. At the time of filing a certificate of candidacy for election to a public office, or within 30 days prior to the filing deadline for the primary election for the public office sought, whichever occurs later, a license commissioner shall certify to the local Board of Supervisors of Elections under oath that the individual is no longer a license commissioner. The certification shall be accompanied by a letter addressed to the Governor containing the resignation of the commissioner from the Board.</section>
      <section prefix="(10)">
        <section prefix="(i)">In this paragraph, "candidate", "contribution", and "political committee" have the meanings stated in &#xA7; 1-101 of the Election Law Article.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">A commissioner, inspector, or employee of the Board may not solicit or transmit any contribution for the benefit of any candidate or political committee from any:<section prefix="1.">Person or corporation engaged in the sale of beer or other alcoholic beverages in the county;</section><section prefix="2.">Agent or employee of the person or corporation; or</section><section prefix="3.">Licensee licensed under the provisions of this article.</section></section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(s)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This subsection applies only in Queen Anne's County.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Board shall appoint a full-time inspector and fix the inspector's compensation at an amount not less than $3,000 a year, plus a mileage allowance as determined by the County Commissioners. The inspector shall visit and inspect every premises in the county licensed under the provisions of this article at least every 60 days.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Board of County Commissioners also shall appoint an attorney to handle legal matters for the Board and set the attorney's compensation.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(t)">Reserved.</section>
    <section prefix="(u)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This subsection applies only in Somerset County.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Board:<section prefix="(i)">Shall appoint a clerk to the Board at an annual salary of $3,500; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">May designate an attorney for the Board at an annual salary of $4,000.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(v)">Reserved.</section>
    <section prefix="(w)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This subsection applies only in Washington County.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Board annually shall engage an independent certified public accounting firm to conduct an audit in accordance with government auditing standards to express an opinion on the fair presentation of the financial statements of the Board.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">By November 1 after the close of each fiscal year, the firm shall provide copies of the audit report to the members of the Board and the senators and delegates who constitute the Washington County Delegation to the Maryland General Assembly.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(x)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This subsection applies only in Wicomico County.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The Board shall appoint both an inspector and a part-time inspector whose salaries shall be as provided in the county budget.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The Board shall specify both the duties of the inspector and the part-time inspector, which shall be for the proper administration and enforcement of the alcoholic beverages laws in the county. For the purposes of the alcoholic beverages laws, both the inspector and the part-time inspector have the powers of a peace officer or sheriff of this State.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">Both the inspector and the part-time inspector shall make oath faithfully to perform the duties entrusted to them, as provided in Article I, &#xA7; 9 of the Maryland Constitution.</section>
        <section prefix="(iv)">Both the inspector and part-time inspector shall separately furnish a bond in the amount of $2,000 to the Board and the county, jointly, conditioned that the inspector and the part-time inspector will well and faithfully execute their offices in all things pertaining to them. The cost of the bonds shall be paid by the county.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Board shall coordinate the enforcement of all alcoholic beverages licensing laws for the county.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The Board may designate an attorney for the Board.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The annual salary is $10,000 which shall be provided in the county budget.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(y)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This subsection applies only in Worcester County.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The Board, with the consent of the County Commissioners, may appoint an inspector.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">
          <section prefix="1.">The salary of the inspector shall be as provided in the county budget.</section>
          <section prefix="2.">The duties of the inspector shall be as specified by the Board, including the proper administration and enforcement of the alcoholic beverages laws in the county.</section>
        </section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">For the purpose of the alcoholic beverages laws, the inspector shall have all the powers of a peace officer or sheriff of this State.</section>
        <section prefix="(iv)">The inspector shall make an oath to perform the duties entrusted, as provided in Article I, &#xA7; 9 of the Constitution of Maryland.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
