<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="g2b" order_by="2" level="1">Alcoholic Beverages</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>g2b-8-403.1</section_number>
  <catch_line>The Baltimore City Board of License Commissioners may issue a 1-day Class BWT beer and wine (on-prem...</catch_line>
  <order_by>403.1</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Baltimore City Board of License Commissioners may issue a 1-day Class BWT beer and wine (on-premises) tasting license.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Board may issue a maximum of 12 Class BWT licenses per year.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Board may issue a Class BWT license only to a Class A beer and light wine licensee or a Class A beer, wine and liquor licensee.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Board shall set a fee for a Class BWT license.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The fee for a Class BWT license is in addition to the Class A license annual fee.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">A holder of a Class BWT license may permit on-premises consumption of the following alcoholic beverages for tasting or sampling purposes only:<section prefix="(1)">Light wine, served in a quantity of not more than 1 ounce from a given brand to any one person; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Beer, served in a quantity of not more than 3 ounces from a given brand to any one person.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">At the end of the day for which a license is valid, a holder of a Class BWT license shall dispose of unconsumed alcoholic beverages remaining in a container opened for tasting or sampling.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">A Class BWT licensee is not restricted by:<section prefix="(1)">&#xA7; 12-107(b) of this article; or</section><section prefix="(2)">&#xA7; 9-102 of this article.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(h)">A Class BWT licensee may exercise the privileges under the Class BWT license only during the hours and days provided for under the respective Class A license.</section>
  </text>
</law>
