<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="g2b" order_by="2" level="1">Alcoholic Beverages</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>g2b-8-211</section_number>
  <catch_line>The provisions of this section apply only in Frederick County....</catch_line>
  <order_by>211</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The provisions of this section apply only in Frederick County.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A license for the sale of alcoholic beverages authorized by this article may not be issued for any place of business located in any of the following election districts:<section prefix="(1)">Catoctin (6th);</section><section prefix="(2)">Hauvers (10th);</section><section prefix="(3)">Jackson (16th);</section><section prefix="(4)">Linganore (19th); and</section><section prefix="(5)">Ballenger (23rd).</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Class A, B, and C licenses for the sale of beer only, as authorized by this article, shall be issued for places of business located in any of the following election districts:<section prefix="(1)">Jefferson (14th);</section><section prefix="(2)">Johnsville (17th); and</section><section prefix="(3)">Burkittsville (22nd).</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Class A, B, and C licenses for the sale of beer and light wine and A, B, and C licenses for the sale of beer, wine and liquor, as authorized by this article, shall be issued for places of business located in any of the following election districts:<section prefix="(1)">Buckeystown (1st);</section><section prefix="(2)">Frederick (2nd);</section><section prefix="(3)">Creagerstown (4th);</section><section prefix="(4)">Emmitsburg (5th);</section><section prefix="(5)">Urbana (7th);</section><section prefix="(6)">Liberty (8th);</section><section prefix="(7)">New Market (9th);</section><section prefix="(8)">Woodsboro (11th);</section><section prefix="(9)">Petersville (12th);</section><section prefix="(10)">Mt. Pleasant (13th);</section><section prefix="(11)">Thurmont (15th);</section><section prefix="(12)">Woodville (18th);</section><section prefix="(13)">Lewistown (20th);</section><section prefix="(14)">Tuscarora (21st);</section><section prefix="(15)">Braddock (24th);</section><section prefix="(16)">Brunswick (25th); and</section><section prefix="(17)">Walkersville (26th).</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d-1)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Board of License Commissioners may issue within the municipal boundaries of the municipal corporation of Middletown:<section prefix="(i)">Class A, B, or C beer licenses;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Class B beer, wine and liquor (on-sale) licenses if the licensed premises derive at least 70% of its monthly gross revenue from the sale of food; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">Middletown Wine Festival licenses.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">In all other areas of the Middletown (3rd) election district, the Board of License Commissioners may only issue:<section prefix="(i)">Class A, B, or C beer licenses; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">Middletown Wine Festival licenses.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">Class C licenses for the sale of beer, wine and liquor, as authorized by this article, shall be issued for places of business located in the 3rd election district.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Notwithstanding any other provisions of this section, wine may be sold as provided under a winery license, a limited winery license, or a Class A light wine license in any election district.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A holder of a limited winery license may provide tables and chairs on the premises of the licensed facility for the sale, by the glass, of wine and pomace brandy made at the facility to a person who participates in a guided tour of the facility or attends a scheduled promotional event or other organized activity at the licensed premises.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The restrictions in this section and in &#xA7; 7-101(g) of this article do not apply to licenses issued pursuant to this subsection.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The following entities may obtain a license for the sale of beer, wine and liquor:<section prefix="(i)">Middletown Volunteer Fire Company;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Wolfsville Volunteer Fire Company;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Jefferson Volunteer Fire Company; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">Myersville Volunteer Fire Company.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">All net proceeds from the sale of alcoholic beverages for the entities listed in paragraph (2) of this subsection shall be used solely to purchase fire and rescue equipment, for operating expenses, and for constructing and maintaining the buildings which house the emergency equipment.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(h)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Notwithstanding the restrictions in this section and in &#xA7; 7-101(g) of this article, the Board of License Commissioners may issue a one-day special beer, wine, and liquor license to St. Katharine Drexel Roman Catholic Congregation, Inc.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">All net proceeds from the sale of alcoholic beverages for St. Katharine Drexel Roman Catholic Congregation, Inc., under paragraph (1) of this subsection shall be used to fund building construction or for charitable purposes.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(i)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Notwithstanding the restrictions in this section and in &#xA7; 7-101(g) of this article, the Board of License Commissioners may issue a one-day special Class C beer and light wine license and a one-day special Class C beer, wine and liquor license to Holy Family  Catholic Community.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">All net proceeds from the sale of alcoholic beverages for Holy Family Catholic Community under paragraph (1) of this subsection shall be used to fund building construction or for charitable purposes.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(j)">Notwithstanding the restrictions in this section and in &#xA7; 7-101(g) of this article, the Board of License Commissioners may issue Class C (golf and country club) licenses for places of business in the 16th election district.</section>
  </text>
</law>
