<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="g2b" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="15-103" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>g2b-15-103</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">There is a Board of License Commissioners in Frederick County.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Board consists of 3 members.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Governor shall appoint the members of the Board.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">To qualify for appointment to the Board, a person:<section prefix="(i)">Shall be of good moral character and integrity;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Shall reasonably reflect the citizenry of the county; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Shall be a registered voter of the county and shall continue to be a registered voter of the county during the person's term of office.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(5)">The term of a member is 5 years.</section>
      <section prefix="(6)">The terms of the members are staggered as required by the terms provided for members of the Board on July 1, 1989.</section>
      <section prefix="(7)">A member who is appointed after a term has begun serves only until a successor is appointed and qualifies.</section>
      <section prefix="(8)">The Governor may remove a member for incompetence, misconduct, neglect of a duty required by law, unprofessional conduct, or dishonorable conduct.</section>
      <section prefix="(9)">The removal procedure is as provided in this article.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">From among its members, the Board shall elect a chairperson.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A majority of the members then serving on the Board is a quorum.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Board shall meet at least once a month.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The chairperson of the Board shall receive an annual compensation of $7,000 and be reimbursed for reasonable expenses.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The members shall receive an annual compensation of $6,500 and be reimbursed for reasonable expenses.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Governor shall appoint 1 alcoholic beverages inspector, with the advice and consent of:<section prefix="(i)">The Senate; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">If there is no resident Senator, then with the consent of the members of the Frederick County delegation of the General Assembly.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">To qualify for appointment as an alcoholic beverages inspector, a person:<section prefix="(i)">Shall be of high moral character;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Shall possess a sound reputation for sobriety, honesty, and integrity; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Shall devote full time to the duties of the office.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The term of an inspector is 5 years.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">An inspector who is appointed after a term has begun serves only until a successor is appointed.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The Governor may remove an inspector with the advice and consent of:<section prefix="(i)">The Senate; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">If there is no resident Senator, then with the consent of the members of the Frederick County delegation of the General Assembly.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(5)">Grounds for removal are:<section prefix="(i)">Incompetence;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Misconduct while performing the duties as an inspector;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Neglect of a duty required by law; or</section><section prefix="(iv)">Unprofessional or dishonorable conduct in performing the duties as an inspector.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(6)">
        <section prefix="(i)">An inspector shall receive an annual salary as set by the County Commissioners, be reimbursed for reasonable expenses, and receive mileage at the standard rate set by the County Commissioners.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">Mileage does not include travel to and from the inspector's home and office.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(7)">An inspector shall:<section prefix="(i)">Possess the power of a peace officer of this State with respect to the enforcement of the alcoholic beverages laws of Frederick County;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Make monthly reports in writing to the Board covering the activities and setting forth any complaints or violations that may have been observed or reported;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Assist the Board in enforcing the alcoholic beverages laws; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">Have any other duties as the Board may prescribe.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Board may appoint not more than two part-time alcoholic beverages inspectors.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">To qualify for appointment as a part-time alcoholic beverages inspector, a person shall:<section prefix="(i)">Be of high moral character; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Possess a sound reputation for sobriety, honesty, and integrity.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A part-time alcoholic beverages inspector shall:<section prefix="(i)">Possess the power of a peace officer of the State with respect to the enforcement of the alcoholic beverages laws of Frederick County;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Make monthly reports in writing to the Board covering the activities and setting forth any complaints or violations that may have been observed or reported;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Assist the Board in enforcing the alcoholic beverages laws; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">Have any other duties that the Board may require.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">A part-time inspector shall:<section prefix="(i)">Receive the compensation  set by the County Commissioners and provided for in the county budget;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Be reimbursed for reasonable expenses; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Receive reimbursement for mileage at the standard rate set by the County Commissioners.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(5)">Reimbursement for mileage does not include travel to and from the part-time inspector's home and office.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The chairperson of the Board, with the approval of the County Commissioners, may employ the clerical assistants necessary to carry out the duties of the Board and the salary of the clerical assistants shall be set by the County Commissioners and provided for in the county budget.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">A Commissioner, full-time or part-time inspector, or employee of the Board may not:</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">A Commissioner, full-time or part-time inspector, or employee of the Board may not solicit or receive, directly or indirectly, any commission, remuneration, or gift whatsoever from any person or corporation engaged in the manufacture or sale of beer or other alcoholic beverages, from any licensee, licensed under the provisions of this article.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">A person or corporation engaged in the manufacture or sale of beer or other alcoholic beverages, any agent or employee of that person or corporation, and any licensee licensed under the provisions of this article may not, directly or indirectly, offer to pay any commission, profit, or remuneration or make any gift to any Commissioner, full-time or part-time inspector, or employee of the Board.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Violations of this subsection are a misdemeanor punishable by a fine of not more than $1,000.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
