<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="g2b" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="9-223" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>g2b-9-223</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">This section applies only in Wicomico County.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Church" means a building principally used for religious services.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Downtown Plaza" means that area in the City of Salisbury from the intersection of Camden Avenue and Carroll Street eastward along Carroll Street to U.S. Route 13, thence in a northerly direction to U.S. Route 50, thence in a westerly direction to Mill Street, thence in a southerly direction to the point of origin. The area includes only the area encompassed within the polygon and does not include businesses located on the opposite sides of the streets.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">"Measurement" means the recording of the distance as a person could walk directly between the 2 points and not in a direct linear form commonly expressed as "how the crow flies".</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">"School" means a public or private elementary or secondary institution of education.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Board of License Commissioners may not issue any license to sell alcoholic beverages within a 500 foot measurement from the main entrance of the building that is the proposed establishment for which the license is requested to the main entrance of a school or of a church or other place of worship.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A person may apply for a license within 6 months following the termination of a license at an existing location that falls within the restrictions imposed by subsection (c) of this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">This section does not apply to:<section prefix="(1)">The issuance of special or temporary licenses; or</section><section prefix="(2)">The Downtown Plaza.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
