<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="g2b" order_by="2" level="1">Alcoholic Beverages</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>g2b-6-301</section_number>
  <catch_line>Except as provided in subsection (n) of this section, a Class C beer, wine and liquor license shall ...</catch_line>
  <order_by>301</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in subsection (n) of this section, a Class C beer, wine and liquor license shall be issued by the license issuing authority of the county in which the place of business is located. It authorizes the holder to keep for sale and sell all alcoholic beverages at retail at any club, at the place described in the license, for consumption on the premises only.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The annual fee for the license shall be paid to the local collecting agent before the license is issued, for distribution as provided.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">In this section, "board" means the board of commissioners for the jurisdiction to which the subsection applies.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">This subsection applies only in Allegany County.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The annual license fee for a Class C (general) beer, wine and liquor license is $500.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">Beverages may be sold for consumption on the premises or elsewhere.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">There is a Class C (volunteer company) beer, wine and liquor license.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">A volunteer company license may be issued to a volunteer fire company, a volunteer ambulance company, or a combined volunteer fire and ambulance company.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">A holder of a volunteer company license may keep and sell all alcoholic beverages for consumption on or off the premises.</section>
        <section prefix="(iv)">Patrons of a club for which a volunteer company license is issued are not limited to the  members of the license holder and their guests.</section>
        <section prefix="(v)">The annual license fee is $500.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This subsection applies only in Anne Arundel County.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The annual license fee is $480.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">There is a special Class C (veterans' organization) license.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The annual license fee is $400.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">The license shall be issued to any local unit of a nationwide bona fide nonprofit organization or club:<section prefix="1.">Which is composed solely of members who served in the armed forces of the United States in any war in which the United States has engaged;</section><section prefix="2.">Which has a charter from a national veterans' organization which was granted prior to the time of making application for the license;</section><section prefix="3.">Which has a bona fide membership of not less than 100 persons and dues of not less than $5 per year per person; and</section><section prefix="4.">Which operates solely for its members and meets in a clubhouse principally used for no other purpose.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(iv)">The license is subject to all other provisions of this article relating to Class C beer, wine and liquor licenses in Anne Arundel County.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(4)">
        <section prefix="(i)">There is a special Class C (fraternal/sororal) license.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The annual license fee is $400.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">The license shall be issued to any local unit of a lodge, political organization or chapter of any bona fide nonprofit and nationwide fraternal or service organization:<section prefix="1.">Which is composed solely of members duly elected and initiated in accordance with the rites and customs of the fraternal or service organization;</section><section prefix="2.">Which is in existence and operation in the county prior to the time when the organization made application for the license;</section><section prefix="3.">Which has a bona fide membership of not less than 100 persons and dues of not less than $5 per year per person; and</section><section prefix="4.">Which owns and operates a home or clubhouse principally for the use of its members and their guests when accompanied by such members, and is not directly or indirectly owned or operated as a public business.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(iv)">The licensee may keep for sale and sell at retail any alcoholic beverages to any member or guest when accompanied by a member. Consumption shall occur on the licensed premises only. The licensee is subject to all of the provisions of this article relating to Class C beer, wine and liquor licenses in Anne Arundel County.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(5)">
        <section prefix="(i)">There is a special Class C (yacht club) license.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The annual license fee is $1,800.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">Upon the approval of the Board, the license shall be issued to any yacht club in the county:<section prefix="1.">Which has 50 or more bona fide members who pay dues of not less than $75 per year per member; and</section><section prefix="2.">Which maintains at the time of application for the license:</section></section>
        <section prefix="(iv)">The licensee may keep for sale and sell at retail any alcoholic beverages, to any member or guest when accompanied by a member at the place described in the license. Consumption shall occur on the licensed premises only. The licensee is subject to all of the provisions of this article relating to Class C beer, wine and liquor licenses in Anne Arundel County.</section>
        <section prefix="(v)">The application for the license filed on behalf of any yacht club in the county shall be signed by at least one officer of the club, who shall be a resident, registered voter and taxpayer of Anne Arundel County.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(6)">
        <section prefix="(i)">There is a special Class C (golf and country club) license.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The annual license fee is $1,800.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">Upon approval by the Board, a license shall be issued to a golf and country club:<section prefix="1.">Which has 200 or more bona fide members paying dues of not less than $75 per annum per member; and</section><section prefix="2.">Which maintains at the time of the application for the license two or more tennis courts, a swimming pool at least 30 feet by 80 feet in size, and a regular or championship golf course of nine holes or more.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(iv)">The licensee may keep for sale and sell at retail any alcoholic beverages to any customer at the place described in the license for consumption on its premises.</section>
        <section prefix="(v)">The application for any license filed on behalf of a golf and country club shall be signed by at least one officer of the club, who is a resident, registered voter and taxpayer of the county.</section>
        <section prefix="(vi)">The golf and country club license is subject to all the provisions of this article, except that any restrictions against the sale of alcoholic beverages on Sundays do not apply to any licensee holding the special Class C (golf and country club) license.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(7)">
        <section prefix="(i)">There is a special Class C (country club) license.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The annual license fee is $750.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">The license may be issued to a country club meeting the requirements set forth in paragraph (6)(iii) of this subsection other than the requirements for a regular or championship golf course of nine holes or more. Instead, the country club shall have, in addition to the other requirements, not less than 15 acres of ground for the licensed premises and used in connection therewith.</section>
        <section prefix="(iv)">Special Class C (country club) licensees are subject to the restrictions in &#xA7; 11-502 of this article as to sale of alcoholic beverages on Sunday.</section>
        <section prefix="(v)">Licensees may not sell alcoholic beverages for consumption off their premises nor on its grounds.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(8)">A country club which was not under construction by July 1, 1977 shall have two or more tennis courts and a swimming pool that is at least 30 feet by 80 feet in size.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">In Baltimore City the annual license fee is $550.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">In Baltimore County the annual license fee is $1,000.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This subsection applies only in Calvert County.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Licenses may be issued for the following premises:<section prefix="(i)"><section prefix="1.">Bona fide yacht clubs, as approved by the Board of License Commissioners.</section><section prefix="2.">The annual license fee is $500.</section></section><section prefix="(ii)"><section prefix="1.">Country clubs.</section><section prefix="2.">The annual license fee is $1,000.</section></section><section prefix="(iii)"><section prefix="1.">Bona fide post homes of posts of the American Legion or Veterans of Foreign Wars.</section><section prefix="2.">The annual license fee is $500.</section><section prefix="3.">The licenses in any post homes of posts of the American Legion and/or Veterans of Foreign Wars shall allow only for the sale of liquor by the drink and on the premises.</section></section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The provisions of this subsection apply only in Caroline County.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The annual license fee is $1,000.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A license may be issued for the following premises:<section prefix="(i)">A bona fide nonprofit country club;</section><section prefix="(ii)">A nonprofit yacht club; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">A veterans organization composed solely of members.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The club or organization shall:<section prefix="(i)">Operate solely for the use of its own members and their guests, who shall accompany the members;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Meet in a clubhouse that is used for no other purpose and has 100 or more bona fide members paying whatever dues were required in the year immediately preceding the year for which the license is issued; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">For organizations composed exclusively of members who serve in the armed forces of the United States, which are affiliated with a national organization, have 50 or more bona fide members paying whatever dues were required by its national organization in the year immediately preceding the year for which the license is issued.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(h)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This subsection applies only in Carroll County.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">
          <section prefix="1.">The annual license fee is $1,200 for any club which is a local chapter of a nationally organized nonprofit fraternal or veterans' organization.</section>
          <section prefix="2.">The annual license fee is $1,500 for any other club.</section>
        </section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The license may be issued to a club which is equipped with a dining room and which has a regular seating capacity at tables (not including seats at bars or counters) for 50 or more persons and which is operating in facilities that have an assessed real property valuation of not less than $20,000.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">This license for a club permits consumption on the premises only.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(i)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This subsection applies only in Cecil County.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The annual license fee is $600.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Any incorporated club shall:<section prefix="(i)">Have been incorporated for a period of not less than 2 years prior to time of making application;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Have a bona fide membership of not less than 25 persons;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Have dues of not less than $50 per year per member;</section><section prefix="(iv)">Maintain at the time sleeping accommodations on the club premises for 25 club members or guests; and</section><section prefix="(v)">Have facilities for preparing and serving food on the premises to the members and guests, but the club may not operate as a place of public business.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">Upon the approval of the application by the Board and upon payment of the required license fee, an applicant may obtain a license from the Board.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(j)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This subsection applies only in Charles County.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The annual license fee is $300.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A license may be issued to:<section prefix="(i)">A bona fide nonprofit organization; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">A club composed solely of members who served in the armed forces of the United States, in any war in which the United States has engaged.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The organization or club shall:<section prefix="(i)">Operate solely for the use of its own members and their guests when accompanied by the members; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Meet in a clubhouse that is used for no other purpose.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(5)">This license permits on-premises consumption of alcoholic beverages in the clubhouse or on property that is directly contiguous to the clubhouse, is owned by the club or bona fide nonprofit organization, and is used exclusively by the members and their guests for social functions or business of the club or organization.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(k)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This subsection applies only in Dorchester County.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The annual license fee is $1,000.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A license may be obtained by any bona fide yacht club and golf and country club that:<section prefix="(i)">Has been incorporated for a period of not less than 5 years prior to the time of making application for the license;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Has a bona fide membership of not less than 250 persons and dues of not less than $10 per year per adult member;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Has facilities for preparing and serving food on the premises to members and their guests when accompanied by such members; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">Owns or operates a clubhouse located on premises principally used for no other purpose and not directly or indirectly owned or operated as a public business.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">A license may be obtained by any local unit of a nationwide bona fide nonprofit organization or club composed solely of members who served in the armed forces of the United States in any war in which the United States has engaged and:<section prefix="(i)">Has held a charter from a national veterans' organization for a period of not less than 5 years prior to the time of making application for the license;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Has a bona fide membership of not less than 50 persons and dues of not less than $5 per year per person;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Operates solely for the use of its own members and their guests when accompanied by such members; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">Meets in a clubhouse principally used for no other purpose.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(5)">A license may be obtained by any lodge or chapter of any bona fide nonprofit and nationwide fraternal organization composed of members duly elected and initiated in accordance with the rites and customs of the fraternal organization which:<section prefix="(i)">Has been in existence and operating in Dorchester County for a period of not less than 5 years prior to the time of making application for the license;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Has a bona fide membership of not less than 125 persons and dues of not less than $5 per annum per member;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Owns or operates a home or clubhouse principally for the use of its members and their guests when accompanied by such members; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">Is not directly or indirectly owned or operated as a public business.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(6)">
        <section prefix="(i)">A license may be obtained by Sailwinds of Cambridge, Inc., a nonprofit organization.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The license may be obtained and renewed so long as no individual or group of individuals derive any personal profits from the operation of Sailwinds of Cambridge, Inc.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">When alcoholic beverages are served at an event open to the public at Sailwinds of Cambridge, Inc., the licensee:<section prefix="1.">May distribute at the event a wristband to each individual who is at least 21 years old; and</section><section prefix="2.">If wristbands are distributed at the event, may not serve an alcoholic beverage to an individual who is not wearing a wristband.</section></section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(7)">Upon payment of the license fee, any organization specified by this subsection may obtain a license from the County Council.</section>
      <section prefix="(8)">If the organization specified by this subsection is located within the corporate limits of any city or town, the County Council shall pay the license fee to the mayor and city council of that city or town. Otherwise, they shall pay the fee to the Finance Department of Dorchester County.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(l)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The provisions of this subsection apply only in Frederick County.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The annual license fee is $600.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">This license may be issued only to a club which has been in business or regularly operating for at least 3 years prior to applying for the license. This time limit does not apply to any nationally chartered and recognized bona fide fraternal, charitable or veterans' organization.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">A licensee may sell only off-premises consumption special anniversary or special event collectible bottles of wine or liquor 30 calendar days prior to the special anniversary or special event.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">
        <section prefix="(i)">There is a special Class C (Weinberg Center) license for the Weinberg Center for the Arts. It shall be issued upon approval by the Board of Frederick County to the Weinberg Center for the Arts, which is a nonprofit organization, whereby no individual or group of individuals derive any personal profits from the operation of performing arts.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The annual license fee is $325.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">The license is a beer, wine and liquor license (Class C on-sale). The licensee may keep for sale and sell all alcoholic beverages at retail on the premises to any customer to be consumed in the central area known as the rotunda, or the lobby, commencing 1 hour prior to, during, and 1 hour after any performance, or for a special fund-raiser to be exclusively for the benefit of the performing arts center.</section>
        <section prefix="(iv)">The performing arts center licensee shall abide by all regulations set forth and mandated for this type license.</section>
        <section prefix="(v)">The application for the license filed on behalf of the Weinberg Center for the Arts shall be signed by the president and two other officers of the performing arts organization, two of whom shall be residents of Frederick County.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(6)">
        <section prefix="(i)">There is a special Class C (golf and country club) license.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The annual license fee is $1,500.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">The license may be issued to any golf and country club which maintains at the time of the application for the license and continues to maintain a regular or championship golf course of nine holes or more.</section>
        <section prefix="(iv)">The license authorizes the licensee to keep for sale and to sell at retail any alcoholic beverages to members and guests at the licensed premises for on-sale consumption only. A country club may not sell alcoholic beverages for consumption off the premises or off the grounds of the club.</section>
        <section prefix="(v)">The application for the license filed on behalf of any golf and country club shall be signed by the president and two other officers of the golf and country club, two of whom shall be residents of Frederick County.</section>
        <section prefix="(vi)">The golf and country club shall abide by &#xA7; 11-511 of this article pertaining to Sunday opening at one o'clock p.m.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(7)">
        <section prefix="(i)">There is a special Class C (private business club) license.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The annual license fee is $2,000.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">The Board may issue an on-sale beer, wine and liquor license for use in a private business club:<section prefix="1.">That is organized for business and professional persons;</section><section prefix="2.">That is nonprofit;</section><section prefix="3.">That has been incorporated for at least 1 year prior to the application for licensure;</section><section prefix="4.">That has at least 75 members;</section><section prefix="5.">That prepares and serves meals during regular operating hours to members and their guests; and</section><section prefix="6.">That has made capital expenditures for tenant improvements, equipment, and furnishings used in the business club in an amount not less than $100,000.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(iv)">An application for the special 7-day Class C (private business club) on-sale beer, wine and liquor license shall be made by 3 officers of the private business club, of whom at least 2 shall be residents of Frederick County.</section>
        <section prefix="(v)">The licensee may keep for sale and sell at retail alcoholic beverages to members and guests of the private business club for on-premises consumption only.</section>
        <section prefix="(vi)">The hours of sale under a special 7-day Class C (private business club) on-sale beer, wine and liquor license are the same as for a Class C beer, wine and liquor license in Frederick County.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(8)">
        <section prefix="(i)">There is a special 7-day Class C (private country club) on-sale beer, wine and liquor license.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The annual license fee is $2,000.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">The license may be issued to a private country club that:<section prefix="1.">Is organized for social purposes;</section><section prefix="2.">Has been incorporated for at least 1 year prior to the application for licensure;</section><section prefix="3.">Has at least 75 members;</section><section prefix="4.">Prepares and serves meals during regular operating hours to members and their guests;</section><section prefix="5.">Is located in the 14th election district or wherever else is permitted in the county; and</section><section prefix="6.">Has made capital expenditures for structures, improvements, equipment, and furnishings used in the private country club in an amount not less than $500,000.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(iv)">An application for the special 7-day Class C (private country club) on-sale beer, wine and liquor license shall be made by 3 officers of the private country club, of whom at least 2 are residents of Frederick County.</section>
        <section prefix="(v)">The licensee may keep for sale and sell at retail alcoholic beverages to members and guests of the private country club for on-premises consumption only in the structures and surrounding grounds.</section>
        <section prefix="(vi)">The hours of sale under a special 7-day Class C (private country club) on-sale beer, wine and liquor license are the same as for a Class C beer, wine and liquor license in the county.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(9)">
        <section prefix="(i)">There is a special Class C (Maryland Ensemble Theatre) on-sale beer and wine license.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">On approval by the Board of License Commissioners of Frederick County of the license application, the Board shall issue a license for the Maryland Ensemble Theatre.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">The annual license fee is $100.</section>
        <section prefix="(iv)">The licensee may store for sale and sell beer and wine to the public.</section>
        <section prefix="(v)">The beer and wine shall be consumed on the premises not earlier than 1 hour before and not later than 1 hour after:<section prefix="1.">A regular performance; or</section><section prefix="2.">A special fund-raiser performance exclusively for the benefit of the Maryland Ensemble Theatre.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(vi)">The president and two other officers of Maryland Ensemble Theatre shall sign the application for the license filed on behalf of the Maryland Ensemble Theatre.</section>
        <section prefix="(vii)">Two of the signatories from Maryland Ensemble Theatre shall be residents of Frederick County.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(m)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">This subsection applies only in Garrett County.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">In this subsection, "guest" means an individual who is specifically invited by a member of a club or organization where the member of the club or organization is in attendance.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">There is a club and organization license.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">
          <section prefix="1.">The annual license fee is $1,500.</section>
          <section prefix="2.">The issuing fee for a new license is $1,500, in addition to the annual fee.</section>
        </section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">The license permits the sale on the premises only of beer, wine, and liquor to the members and the guests of the clubs and organizations.</section>
        <section prefix="(iv)">The license shall be issued only to the following clubs and organizations:<section prefix="1.">A bona fide nationally chartered nonprofit organization or club which has been incorporated for a period of not fewer than 5 years immediately prior to the filing of the application, composed solely of members who served in the armed forces of the United States in any war in which the United States has engaged, which organization or club operates solely for the use of its own members and its guests when accompanied by such members, and meets in a clubhouse principally used for a club, and is neither directly nor indirectly operated as a public business.</section><section prefix="2.">Any lodge or chapter of a bona fide nonprofit and nationally chartered fraternal organization composed of members duly elected and initiated in accordance with the rites and customs of the fraternal organizations which is operating a home or clubhouse for the use of its members, and is neither directly nor indirectly operated as a public business. The club or organization shall have 100 or more bona fide members paying such dues as required by its national organization in the year immediately preceding the year in which the license is issued. The home or clubhouse shall have facilities for preparing and serving food on the premises to the members and their guests.</section><section prefix="3.">A bona fide yacht or boat club, owning real estate in the county and having a dues-paying membership of not less than 150 persons, not less than 50 of whom own yachts, boats, or other vessels.</section><section prefix="4.">A country club which has 75 or more bona fide members paying dues of not less than $40 per annum per member, which maintains at the time of the application for license a regular or championship golf course of 9 holes or more, or, in lieu of that golf course, a swimming pool at least 20 by 40 feet in size, and at least six tennis courts.</section><section prefix="5.">Before issuing any license pursuant to this paragraph, the Liquor Control Board shall determine whether the business to be operated by the prospective licensee is likely to enhance the recreational, business, and economic development of the county. If the Liquor Control Board in its discretion determines that the issuance of such a license will not enhance such development within the county, it shall reject the application for the license.</section></section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(n)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This subsection applies only in Harford County.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Liquor Control Board may issue 6-day (Monday through Saturday) and 7-day Class C-1, Class C-2, and Class C-3 (on-sale) organization or club beer, wine and liquor licenses in accordance with this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A license issued under this subsection authorizes the holder of the license to sell or provide alcoholic beverages only for on-premises consumption by the members and guests of the club or organization.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">
        <section prefix="(i)">In this paragraph, "war veterans organization" means a bona fide nationally chartered nonprofit organization or club that:<section prefix="1.">Has been incorporated for a period of not fewer than 5 years immediately before the filing of the application for a license under this paragraph;</section><section prefix="2.">Is composed solely of members who served in the armed forces of the United States in any war in which the United States was engaged;</section><section prefix="3.">Operates solely for the use of its own members and its guests when accompanied by such members;</section><section prefix="4.">Meets in a clubhouse principally used for a club; and</section><section prefix="5.">Is neither directly nor indirectly operated as a public business.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">A Class C-1 license may be issued only to a war veterans organization.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">For a club or organization that qualifies for a Class C-1 license under this paragraph and has a membership of 50 to 99 bona fide members, the annual fee for a 6-day, Monday through Saturday, (on-sale) Class C-1 license is $350.</section>
        <section prefix="(iv)">For a club or organization that qualifies for a Class C-1 license under this paragraph and has a membership of 50 to 99 bona fide members, the annual fee for a 7-day (on-sale) Class C-1 license is $450.</section>
        <section prefix="(v)">For a club or organization that qualifies for a Class C-1 license under this paragraph and has a membership of 100 to 250 bona fide members, the annual fee for a 6-day, Monday through Saturday, (on-sale) Class C-1 license is $600.</section>
        <section prefix="(vi)">For a club or organization that qualifies for a Class C-1 license under this paragraph and has a membership of 100 to 250 bona fide members, the annual fee for a 7-day (on-sale) Class C-1 license is $700.</section>
        <section prefix="(vii)">For a club or organization that qualifies for a Class C-1 license under this paragraph and has a membership of 251 to 450 bona fide members, the annual fee for a 6-day, Monday through Saturday, (on-sale) Class C-1 license is $850.</section>
        <section prefix="(viii)">For a club or organization that qualifies for a Class C-1 license under this paragraph and has a membership of 251 to 450 bona fide members, the annual fee for a 7-day (on-sale) Class C-1 license is $950.</section>
        <section prefix="(ix)">For a club or organization that qualifies for a Class C-1 license under this paragraph and has a membership of 451 or more bona fide members, the annual fee for a 6-day, Monday through Saturday, (on-sale) Class C-1 license is $1,000.</section>
        <section prefix="(x)">For a club or organization that qualifies for a Class C-1 license under this paragraph and has a membership of 451 or more bona fide members, the annual fee for a 7-day (on-sale) Class C-1 license is $1,100.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(5)">
        <section prefix="(i)">In this paragraph, "fraternal organization" means a lodge or chapter of a bona fide nationally chartered fraternal organization that:<section prefix="1.">Is composed of members duly elected and initiated in accordance with the rites and customs of the organization;</section><section prefix="2.">Operates a clubhouse or building:</section><section prefix="3.">Is neither directly nor indirectly operated as a public business; and</section><section prefix="4.">Has at least 100 bona fide members, each of whom paid dues as required by the national organization in the year immediately preceding the year for which the license was applied or issued.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">A Class C-2 license may be issued only to a fraternal organization.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">For a club or organization that qualifies for a Class C-2 license under this paragraph and has a membership of 100 to 250 bona fide members, the annual fee for a 6-day, Monday through Saturday, (on-sale) Class C-2 license is $800.</section>
        <section prefix="(iv)">For a club or organization that qualifies for a Class C-2 license under this paragraph and has a membership of 100 to 250 bona fide members, the annual fee for a 7-day (on-sale) Class C-2 license is $900.</section>
        <section prefix="(v)">For a club or organization that qualifies for a Class C-2 license under this paragraph and has a membership of 251 to 450 bona fide members, the annual fee for a 6-day, Monday through Saturday, (on-sale) Class C-2 license is $1,050.</section>
        <section prefix="(vi)">For a club or organization that qualifies for a Class C-2 license under this paragraph and has a membership of 251 to 450 bona fide members, the annual fee for a 7-day (on-sale) Class C-2 license is $1,150.</section>
        <section prefix="(vii)">For a club or organization that qualifies for a Class C-2 license under this paragraph and has a membership of 451 or more bona fide members, the annual fee for a 6-day, Monday through Saturday, (on-sale) Class C-2 license is $1,200.</section>
        <section prefix="(viii)">For a club or organization that qualifies for a Class C-2 license under this paragraph and has a membership of 451 or more bona fide members, the annual fee for a 7-day (on-sale) Class C-2 license is $1,300.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(6)">
        <section prefix="(i)">In this paragraph the following words have the meanings indicated.<section prefix="1.">"Miscellaneous organization or club" means a country club, a yacht or boat club, or topiary garden.</section><section prefix="2.">"Country club" means a club or organization that:</section><section prefix="3.">"Topiary garden" means an organization that:</section><section prefix="4.">"Yacht or boat club" means a club or organization that:</section></section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">A Class C-3 license may be issued only to a miscellaneous organization or club.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">
          <section prefix="1.">The fee for a 6-day, Monday through Saturday, (on-sale) Class C-3 license under this paragraph is $1,300.</section>
          <section prefix="2.">The fee for a 7-day Class C-3 license under this paragraph is $1,400.</section>
        </section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(o)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This subsection applies only in Howard County.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">There is a country club license.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The annual license fee is $1,500.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">The license may be issued to a country club or to its owner or owners, regardless of whether the club is operated for profit or not. The club shall have a bona fide annual limited membership and shall have at the time of issuance of the license a regular or championship golf course adjacent to the premises for which a license is sought of 18 holes and other club facilities.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">There is a veterans' club license.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The annual license fee is $250.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">The license may be issued to a club composed exclusively of members who served in the armed forces of the United States, which is affiliated with a national organization, and having 75 or more bona fide members paying such dues as required by its national organization in the year immediately preceding the year for which the license is issued. At least 75 percent of the members of the club shall have resided in Howard County for at least 2 years immediately preceding the date of application for the license and the club shall have maintained a post in the county for at least 3 years preceding the date of the application.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(4)">
        <section prefix="(i)">There is a conference center license.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The annual license fee is $700.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">The license may be issued to a conference center or to its owner or owners, whether or not operated for profit, having not less than 7,000 square feet of conference area with accommodations, equipment, and facilities designed for holding meetings, seminars and conferences.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(5)">
        <section prefix="(i)">There is a police officers' local affiliate license.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The annual license fee is $500.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">The license may be issued to a local affiliate of an international organization of police officers.</section>
        <section prefix="(iv)">To qualify for the license, a local affiliate shall:<section prefix="1.">Have at least 100 dues paying members; and</section><section prefix="2.">Charge each member at least $15 a month in dues.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(v)">The local affiliate shall operate the clubhouse where the license is to be in effect solely for its own members and their guests.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(p)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This section applies only in Kent County.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The annual license fee is $500.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">There is an organization or club license.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The license may be issued to a bona fide nonprofit organization or club composed solely of members:<section prefix="1.">That operates solely for the use of its own members and their guests when accompanied by such members;</section><section prefix="2.">That meets in a clubhouse that is used for no other purpose; and</section><section prefix="3.">That has 100 or more bona fide members paying such dues as were required in the year immediately preceding the year for which such license is issued.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">For clubs composed exclusively of members who served in the armed forces of the United States, which are affiliated with a national organization, a license may be issued provided the club has 50 or more bona fide members paying the dues required by its national organization for the full year immediately preceding the year for which the license is issued.</section>
        <section prefix="(iv)">The license permits the consumption of alcoholic beverages both on and off of the premises.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(q)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This subsection applies only in Montgomery County.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">There is a country club license.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The annual license fee is $2,000.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">The license shall be issued only to a country club:<section prefix="1.">Which has 100 or more bona fide members of whatever class;</section><section prefix="2.">Whose members pay an annual total amount of dues which averages at least $50 for each member; and</section><section prefix="3.">Which maintains at the time of the application for the license a regular or championship golf course of nine holes or more. However, any licensed premises which had a Class C beer, wine and liquor license on January 1, 1964 is not required to maintain a regular or championship golf course if it then maintained and continues to maintain, in lieu thereof, a swimming pool at least 20 by 40 feet in size and at least six lawn tennis courts.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(iv)">The licensee may keep for sale and sell any alcoholic beverages purchased from the Liquor Control Board for Montgomery County, at retail, to any customer at the place described in the license, for consumption on its premises only.</section>
        <section prefix="(v)">The application shall be signed by at least one officer of the club who shall be a resident or registered voter or taxpayer of Montgomery County.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">A licensee under paragraph (2) of this subsection may keep for sale and sell at the place described in the license any alcoholic beverages purchased from the Liquor Control Board, at retail, for consumption on its premises only, to any member of the country club, to a bona fide guest or guests of a member, to the immediate family of a member, or to persons residing temporarily in the clubhouse of the country club.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">In this paragraph "bona fide guest or guests of a member" includes, but is not limited to, any person 21 years of age or over with respect to the sale of all alcoholic beverages while the person is in attendance at a recognized national or regional athletic event being held on the premises of the licensee when:<section prefix="1.">The licensee has made application to the Board of License Commissioners for permission to sell alcoholic beverages to persons attending a national or regional athletic event to be held on the premises of the licensee;</section><section prefix="2.">The application has been made at least 60 days prior to the date that the specific athletic event is to take place; and</section><section prefix="3.">The Board has granted the permission requested in the application.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">An employee of the country club may not have guests at the country club for the purpose of the consumption of alcoholic beverages during the employee's normal working hours.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(4)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Any corporation, club, or organization which is a country club as defined in this subsection or eleemosynary and is a local post, chapter, lodge, council, or branch of a national organization having a membership of more than 300,000 and which local post, chapter, lodge, council, or branch has a minimum dues-paying membership of more than 200 members may, upon receiving this license, allow alcoholic beverages to be consumed on its premises.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">This license permits the consumption of alcoholic beverages by a bona fide member or his guest on the premises of the country club or eleemosynary corporation, club, or organization if the alcoholic beverages are supplied by a bona fide member.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">The annual license fee is $300.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(5)">
        <section prefix="(i)">There is a veterans' license.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The annual license fee is $1,000.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">The license may be issued to any local unit of a nationwide bona fide nonprofit organization composed solely of members who served in the armed forces of the United States that:<section prefix="1.">Has a charter from a national veterans' organization and is in existence and operating in Montgomery County prior to the time of making application for the license;</section><section prefix="2.">Has a bona fide membership of not less than 200 persons;</section><section prefix="3.">Has dues of not less than $5 per person; and</section><section prefix="4.">Owns or operates, solely for the use of its own members and their guests when accompanied by members, a clubhouse principally used for no other purpose, and not directly or indirectly owned or operated as a public business.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(iv)">The licensee may keep for sale and sell at retail any alcoholic beverages to any member or guest when accompanied by a member and is subject to all other provisions of this article relating to beer, wine and liquor licenses, Class C, in force in Montgomery County, except the provisions requiring the maintenance of a championship golf course. This license solely authorizes the sale and consumption on premises only.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(6)">
        <section prefix="(i)">There is a fraternal/sororal/service license.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The annual license fee is $1,000.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">The license may be issued to any local unit of a lodge or chapter of any bona fide nonprofit and nationwide fraternal, sororal, or service organization that:<section prefix="1.">Is composed solely of members duly elected and initiated in accordance with the rites and customs of that fraternal, sororal, or service organization;</section><section prefix="2.">Is in existence and operating in Montgomery County prior to the time of making application for a license;</section><section prefix="3.">Has a bona fide membership of not less than 200 persons and dues of not less than $5 per year per person; and</section><section prefix="4.">Owns and operates a clubhouse principally for the use of its members and their guests when accompanied by members and for no other purpose, and not directly or indirectly owned or operated as a public business.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(iv)">A licensee may keep for sale and sell at retail any alcoholic beverages to any member or guest when accompanied by a member.</section>
        <section prefix="(v)">The licensee is subject to all of the provisions of this article relating to beer, wine and liquor licenses, Class C, in force in Montgomery County, except the provisions requiring the maintenance of a championship golf course.</section>
        <section prefix="(vi)">This license solely authorizes the sale and consumption on premises only.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(7)">
        <section prefix="(i)">There is a Takoma Park veterans' license, which may be referred to as a Class C-TP license.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The annual license fee is $1,000. A Class C-TP licensee may not be charged for such a license until May 1, 1998.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">The license may be issued to any local unit located in that portion of the City of Takoma Park that was formerly part of Prince George's County of a nationwide bona fide nonprofit organization or club that:<section prefix="1.">Is composed solely of members who served in the armed forces of the United States in any war in which the United States has engaged;</section><section prefix="2.">Has a charter from a national veterans' organization prior to the time of making application for the license;</section><section prefix="3.">Has a bona fide membership of not less than 100 persons and dues of not less than $5 per year per person;</section><section prefix="4.">Operates solely for the use of its own members and their guests when accompanied by such members;</section><section prefix="5.">Possessed a club license originally issued by the Prince George's County Board of License Commissioners when the club was located in that portion of the City of Takoma Park that was formerly part of Prince George's County; and</section><section prefix="6.">Meets in a clubhouse principally used for no other purpose.</section></section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(8)">
        <section prefix="(i)">There is a Continuing Care Retirement Community license.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The annual license fee is $500.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">The license may be issued to a club that:<section prefix="1.">Is composed of residents of a continuing care retirement community that has obtained a certificate of registration from the State  Department of Aging under Title 10, Subtitle 4 of the Human Services Article;</section><section prefix="2.">Has at least 50 bona fide members; and</section><section prefix="3.">Has annual dues that average at least $5 per member.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(iv)">A licensee may keep for sale and sell at retail to a member or a guest when accompanied by a member at the place described in the license beer, wine and liquor, purchased from the Department of Liquor Control for Montgomery County, for consumption on the licensed premises only.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(r)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This subsection applies only in Prince George's County.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">There is a veterans' license.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The annual license fee is $910.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">The license shall be issued to any local unit of a nationwide bona fide nonprofit organization or club that:<section prefix="1.">Is composed solely of members who served in the armed forces of the United States in any war in which the United States has engaged;</section><section prefix="2.">Has a charter from a national veterans' organization prior to the time of making application for the license;</section><section prefix="3.">Has a bona fide membership of not less than 100 persons and dues of not less than $5 per year per person;</section><section prefix="4.">Operates solely for the use of its own members and their guests when accompanied by such members; and</section><section prefix="5.">Meets in a clubhouse principally used for no other purpose.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(iv)">The licensee is subject to all other provisions of this article relating to beer, wine and liquor licenses, Class C, in force and effect in Prince George's County.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">There is a fraternal/sororal/service license.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The annual license fee is $910.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">A license may be issued to any local unit of a lodge or chapter of any bona fide nonprofit and nationwide fraternal or service organization that:<section prefix="1.">Is composed solely of members duly elected and initiated in accordance with the rites and customs of the fraternal, sororal, or service organization;</section><section prefix="2.">Is in existence and operating in Prince George's County prior to the time of making application for the license;</section><section prefix="3.">Has a bona fide membership of not less than 100 persons and dues of not less than $5 per year per person; and</section><section prefix="4.">Owns or operates a home or clubhouse principally for the use of its members and their guests when accompanied by the members, and not directly or indirectly owned or operated as a public business.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(iv)">The licensee may keep for sale and sell at retail any alcoholic beverages to any member or guest when accompanied by a member for consumption on the licensed premises.</section>
        <section prefix="(v)">The licensee is subject to all the provisions of this article relating to beer, wine and liquor licenses, Class C, in force and effect in Prince George's County, except that restrictions on the sale of alcoholic beverages on Sunday found in &#xA7; 11-517 of this article and elsewhere do not apply.</section>
        <section prefix="(vi)">The licensee may permit persons who have leased a private room or other area of the licensed premises for a private social gathering to bring beer, wine, and liquor onto the licensed premises, provided that it is consumed on the premises.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(4)">
        <section prefix="(i)">There is a special Class C (yacht club) license in Prince George's County.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The annual license fee is $1,575.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">A license may be issued to a yacht club that:<section prefix="1.">Has 50 or more bona fide members paying dues of not less than $75 per year per member;</section><section prefix="2.">Maintains at the time of application for the license a clubhouse with a seating capacity sufficient to accommodate at one time at least 100 persons;</section><section prefix="3.">Has slips or berths for 75 boats or more; and</section><section prefix="4.">Has at least 5 acres of ground.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(iv)">The licensee may keep for sale and sell at retail any alcoholic beverages, to any member or guest when accompanied by a member at the place described in the license.</section>
        <section prefix="(v)">Alcoholic beverages may be consumed on the licensed premises only.</section>
        <section prefix="(vi)">The licensee is subject to all the provisions of this article relating to beer, wine and liquor licenses, Class C, in force and effect in Prince George's County. Restrictions on the sale of alcoholic beverages on Sunday found in &#xA7; 11-517 of this article and elsewhere do not apply.</section>
        <section prefix="(vii)">The application for license filed on behalf of any such yacht club shall be signed by at least one officer of the club, who shall be a resident, registered voter, and taxpayer of Prince George's County.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(5)">
        <section prefix="(i)">There is a special Class C (golf and country club) license.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The annual license fee is $1,815.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">The license may be issued to any golf and country club that:<section prefix="1.">Has:</section><section prefix="2.">Has:</section></section>
        <section prefix="(iv)">The licensee may keep for sale and sell at retail any alcoholic beverages, to any customer at the place described in the license.</section>
        <section prefix="(v)">The alcoholic beverages may be consumed on or off its premises.</section>
        <section prefix="(vi)">The application for the license shall be signed by at least one officer of the club, who shall be a resident, registered voter, and taxpayer.</section>
        <section prefix="(vii)">
          <section prefix="1.">The license is subject to all the provisions of this article.</section>
          <section prefix="2.">Any restrictions against the sale of alcoholic beverages on Sundays, appearing elsewhere in this article, do not apply to any licensee holding the special Class C (golf and country club) license. Sales on Sunday under the license shall be made only to the bona fide members of the golf and country club and to guests of those members for consumption on the premises and the grounds of the club used in connection with the club.</section>
        </section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(6)">
        <section prefix="(i)">There is a special Class C (country club) license.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The annual license fee is $1,100.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">The license may be issued to a country club meeting the requirements specified in paragraph (5) of this subsection other than the requirements for a regular or championship golf course of 9 holes or more. Instead, the club shall have, in addition to the other requirements, not less than 15 acres of ground for the licensed premises and used in connection therewith. Licensees are subject to restrictions appearing in &#xA7; 11-517 of this article as to sale of alcoholic beverages on Sunday.</section>
        <section prefix="(iv)">Alcoholic beverages may not be consumed off their premises or on the grounds of the club.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(7)">
        <section prefix="(i)">There is a special Class C (concession) beer, wine and liquor license.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The annual license fee is $1,815. The fee shall be paid prior to its issuance, regardless of any terms or conditions in any contractual agreement between the concessionaire and Prince George's County.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">The license may be issued to any person operating a concession subject to contractual agreement with Prince George's County on the premises of any golf and country club or country club owned by Prince George's County.</section>
        <section prefix="(iv)">The concessionaire holding this license may keep for sale and sell at retail any alcoholic beverages by the drink or the bottle for consumption on the premises only.</section>
        <section prefix="(v)">The concessionaire may be any natural person, association, firm, partnership, or corporation approved as such by the County Council and shall be a resident of the State of Maryland.</section>
        <section prefix="(vi)">The Board shall regulate the manner of dispensing alcoholic beverages, and shall authorize the number of outlets permitted to dispense alcoholic beverages on the licensed premises.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(s)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This subsection applies only in Queen Anne's County.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The annual license fee is $500.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The license shall be issued only to:<section prefix="(i)">A bona fide nonprofit organization or club composed solely of members who served in the armed forces of the United States in any war in which the United States has engaged and which organization or club operates solely for the use of its own members and their guests when accompanied by such members; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">A bona fide yacht club, golf club, fraternal club or order, country club, and/or social or recreational club, which is not operated for profit, and which has had for one year, immediately preceding the year for which the license is issued, 50 or more bona fide adult members paying dues of not less than $20 per annum, owning or operating a clubhouse or meeting rooms having facilities for preparing and serving food on the premises which are principally used for members and their guests, when accompanied by members, and not directly or indirectly owned or operated as a public business.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">This license permits the consumption of alcoholic beverages both on and off the licensed premises.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(t)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This subsection applies only in St. Mary's County.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The annual license fee is $350.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">This license may be issued to a bona fide nonprofit organization or club:<section prefix="(i)">That is composed solely of members who have served in the armed forces of the United States in any war in which the United States has engaged;</section><section prefix="(ii)">That operates solely for the use of:<section prefix="1.">Its members; and</section><section prefix="2.">A member's guest, provided the guest is accompanied by the member; and</section></section><section prefix="(iii)">If the club or organization meets in a clubhouse principally used for a club and is neither directly nor indirectly operated as a public business.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(u)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This subsection applies only in Somerset County.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The annual license fee is $316.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">There is a yacht or golf and country club license. The licensee shall:<section prefix="(i)">Have a bona fide membership of not less than 30 persons;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Charge dues of not less than $20 annually for each adult member; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Own and operate a clubhouse on premises principally used for no other purpose and not directly or indirectly owned or operated as a public business.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">There is a fraternal or sororal license. The licensee shall:<section prefix="(i)">Be a lodge or chapter of a bona fide nonprofit and nationwide fraternal or sororal organization composed of members duly elected and initiated in accordance with the rites and customs of such fraternal or sororal organization;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Have been in existence and operating in the county for a period of not less than 1 year prior to the time of making application for the license;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Have a bona fide membership of not less than 25 persons;</section><section prefix="(iv)">Charge dues of not less than $15 annually for each member; and</section><section prefix="(v)">Own or operate a home or clubhouse principally for the use of its members and their guests when accompanied by such members, and not directly or indirectly owned or operated as a public business.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(5)">There is a veterans' license. The licensee shall:<section prefix="(i)">Be a local unit of a nationwide bona fide nonprofit organization or club composed solely of members who served in the armed forces of the United States in any war in which the United States has engaged;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Have held a charter from a national veterans' organization for a period of not less than 1 year prior to the time of application for licensing;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Have a bona fide membership of not less than 35 persons;</section><section prefix="(iv)">Charge dues of not less than $4 annually for each member; and</section><section prefix="(v)">Own or operate a home or clubhouse which the organization or club operates solely for the use of its members and their guests when accompanied by such members and not directly or indirectly owned or operated as a public business.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(6)">Each licensee shall purchase all wines and liquors sold by the licensee from the Somerset County Liquor Control Board. The licensee shall be charged the invoice price charged to the Liquor Control Board, plus freight charges and a sum not to exceed 20 percent of the aggregate invoice price and freight charges.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(v)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This subsection applies only in Talbot County.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The annual license fee is $250.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A license shall be issued only to a club:<section prefix="(i)">Which is not operated for profit;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Which has had for 5 consecutive years, immediately preceding the year for which the license is issued, 50 or more bona fide members; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Whose members pay dues of not less than $10 annually.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">In the case of clubs composed exclusively of members who served in the armed forces of the United States, which are affiliated with a national organization, the license may be issued if the club had 50 or more bona fide members paying whatever dues that were required by its national organization in the year immediately preceding the year for which the license is issued.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">Section 18-101 of this article permits the Talbot County Council to provide for the retail alcoholic beverage laws for the county which, if enacted, supersede the provisions of this article.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(w)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This subsection applies only in Washington County.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The annual license fee is:<section prefix="(i)">$500 for clubs with less than 600 members (including social members); and</section><section prefix="(ii)">$1,000 for clubs with 600 or more members (including social members).</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">There is a special Class C golf and country club license. Upon the approval by the Board of License Commissioners, it shall be issued to any golf and country club in the county which:<section prefix="1.">Has 200 or more bona fide members paying dues of not less than $30 per annum per member, whether or not the club is operated for profit; and</section><section prefix="2.">Maintains a regular or championship golf course of 9 holes or more.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">
          <section prefix="1.">The licensee may keep for sale and sell at retail any alcoholic beverages to bona fide members of the club and their guests at the place described in the license.</section>
          <section prefix="2.">Alcoholic beverages may be consumed only on the premises and grounds of the club.</section>
          <section prefix="3.">The annual license fee for a golf and country club license is $1,000 for the license year commencing in May of each year.</section>
          <section prefix="4.">The application for a license filed on behalf of any such golf and country club shall be signed by 3 officers of the club.</section>
          <section prefix="5.">A golf and country club license shall be subject to all the provisions of this article and shall include all of the privileges and restrictions applicable thereunder to Class C license holders in Washington County.</section>
        </section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(x)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This subsection applies only in Wicomico County.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The annual license fee for a 6-day license is as follows:<section prefix="1.">For a club with 50 to 399 bona fide, dues-paying members - $275;</section><section prefix="2.">For a club with 400 to 599 such members - $550; and</section><section prefix="3.">For a club with 600 or more members - $825.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The license fee shall be established on the maximum number of dues-paying members during the calendar year immediately preceding the application for a license.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">The annual license fee for a 7-day license is as follows:<section prefix="1.">For a club with 50 to 399 bona fide, dues-paying members - $400;</section><section prefix="2.">For a club with 400 to 599 of those members - $675; and</section><section prefix="3.">For a club with 600 or more members - $950.</section></section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The license may be issued to a bona fide, nonprofit fraternal, social, or veterans' club which:<section prefix="1.">Has been incorporated for a period of not less than 5 years immediately prior to the filing of the application;</section><section prefix="2.">Is in a clubhouse or premises used principally for a club and neither directly nor indirectly operated as a public business;</section><section prefix="3.">Has had at least 100 bona fide, dues-paying members during the one year immediately prior to the filing of the application, except that if the club is composed solely of members who served in the armed forces of the United States, a minimum of 50 such members is sufficient; and</section><section prefix="4.">Has facilities for preparing and serving food on the premises to the members and their guests.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">This license for a club permits consumption on the premises only.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(4)">All alcoholic beverages, other than beer and light wine, sold or offered for sale shall be purchased from the Liquor Control Board, and each bottle shall be stamped or otherwise designated "on-sale only" by the Board.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(y)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This subsection applies only in Worcester County.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The annual license fee for a six-day license is $500; and</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The annual license fee for a seven-day license is $750.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">There is a golf, tennis, or swimming club license which is used in conjunction with a country club, excluding miniature golf courses operating in Worcester County.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The club shall:<section prefix="1.">Have been incorporated for a period of not less than one year prior to the time of making application for the license;</section><section prefix="2.">Have a bona fide membership of not less than 100 persons and dues of not less than $10 per year per adult member;</section><section prefix="3.">Have facilities for preparing and serving food on the premises to members and their guests when accompanied by members; and</section><section prefix="4.">Own or operate a clubhouse on premises principally used for no other purpose and not directly or indirectly owned or operated as a public business.</section></section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(4)">
        <section prefix="(i)">There is a veterans' license.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The license may be issued to any local unit of a nationwide bona fide nonprofit organization or club composed solely of members who served in the armed forces of the United States in any war in which the United States has engaged which:<section prefix="1.">Has held a charter from a national veterans' organization for a period of not less than 5 years prior to the time of making application for the license;</section><section prefix="2.">Has a bona fide membership of not less than 15 persons and dues of not less than $5 per year per person;</section><section prefix="3.">Operates solely for the use of its own members and their guests when accompanied by members; and</section><section prefix="4.">Meets in a clubhouse principally used for no other purpose.</section></section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(5)">
        <section prefix="(i)">There is a fraternal/sororal/service license.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The license may be issued to any lodge or chapter of any bona fide nonprofit and nationwide fraternal or service organization which:<section prefix="1.">Is composed of members duly elected and initiated in accordance with the rites and customs of the fraternal or service organization;</section><section prefix="2.">Is in existence and operating in Worcester County for a period of not less than 5 years prior to the time of making application for the license;</section><section prefix="3.">Has a bona fide membership of not less than 40 persons and dues of not less than $5 per year per member; and</section><section prefix="4.">Owns or operates a home or clubhouse principally for the use of its members and their guests when accompanied by members, and not directly or indirectly owned or operated as a public business.</section></section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(6)">
        <section prefix="(i)">There is a fishing club license.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The license may be issued to any club that is organized to promote the sport of fishing and that:<section prefix="1.">Owns its own building;</section><section prefix="2.">Has been in existence for at least 5 years prior to making application for the license;</section><section prefix="3.">Has a bona fide membership of not less than 25 persons and dues of not less than $25 per year per adult member;</section><section prefix="4.">Operates solely for the use of its own members and their guests, when accompanied by a member; and</section><section prefix="5.">Meets in a clubhouse used principally for no other purpose, and not directly or indirectly owned or operated as a public business.</section></section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(7)">Upon payment of the license fee, any applicant enumerated in this subsection may obtain the license from the Board.</section>
      <section prefix="(8)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Except as provided in subparagraph (ii) of this paragraph, every licensee shall purchase all wines and liquors, except light wine and beer, sold by them from the dispensaries of the Worcester County Department of Liquor Control. The licensee shall receive at least a 15 percent discount from the retail sales price or any special sale price or discount price, whichever is lower. All licensees may purchase beer and light wine from licensed wholesalers.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">Beginning on May 1, 2016, a licensee may elect to purchase wine and liquor from a licensed wholesaler under &#xA7; 15-204(e) of this article.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(9)">
        <section prefix="(i)">For the purpose of qualifying for a seven-day license, clubs defined in this subsection shall:<section prefix="1.">Have an enclosed dining area that has a seating capacity for 60 or more persons;</section><section prefix="2.">Serve full-course meals from menus at least twice daily; and</section><section prefix="3.">During the effective period of the license have daily average receipts from the sale of food in excess of those for the sale of alcoholic beverages.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The annual fee for a seven-day license is $300.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(10)">"Bottle club" means any club or organization:<section prefix="(i)">Which serves, sells, gives, or dispenses alcoholic beverages to its members or guests;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Which keeps for its members or guests any alcoholic beverages;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Which allows to be consumed on its premises any alcoholic beverages, by its members or guests, which beverages have been reserved by or purchased from the club by the members or guests;</section><section prefix="(iv)">At which patrons are served, given, or allowed to consume alcoholic beverages after legal closing hours from the supplies that the patrons have previously purchased or reserved; or</section><section prefix="(v)">That sells, dispenses, serves, keeps, or allows to be consumed any setups or other component parts of mixed alcoholic drinks to its members or guests.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(11)">A person, partnership, corporation, or any other organization may not maintain or operate a "bottle club". However, any club or organization which qualifies for and is granted a Class C license as provided in this subsection may operate also as a "bottle club" under this license.</section>
      <section prefix="(12)">This subsection may not be construed to apply to any "bring your own bottle" social function at which alcoholic beverages are furnished only by the guests or participants. If such a social function is held in a facility available to the public, the function shall be conducted during the hours of operation permitted for a Class C license establishment.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
