<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="g2b" order_by="" level="1">Alcoholic Beverages</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>g2b-10-205</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>205</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">No holder of any class of license shall be entitled to a refund of the unearned portion of the fee paid for a license, upon the surrender thereof, except:<section prefix="(1)">In the event of receivership or bankruptcy of the business in the event a transfer is not requested, and in such case the refund shall be made for the benefit of the creditors of such licensee; or</section><section prefix="(2)">In the event of the death of the license holder, and in such case the refund shall be made for the benefit of the estate of such deceased license holder; or</section><section prefix="(3)">In the event that the licensee has volunteered for or been called into the armed forces of the United States or the regular State Militia; or</section><section prefix="(4)">In the event that a license holder of one class surrenders his license and obtains a license of another class carrying a higher fee, in which case the refund shall be deducted from the amount of the fee to be paid for the newly obtained license; or</section><section prefix="(5)">In the event that a licensee, against whom charges are pending at the time he renews his annual license, is found guilty of such charges and his license is revoked, or upon appeal the board's decision is reversed and renewal of license is refused after he has paid his fee for the renewal thereof, in which case he shall be entitled to a refund of the unearned portion of his annual fee from the date the revocation becomes final; or</section><section prefix="(6)">In the event that the licensed premises are taken by the federal government, the State or any city or municipality for public use.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">There shall be no refunds on retail licenses issued for premises in Anne Arundel County.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">There shall be no refunds on retail licenses issued for premises in Calvert County.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">No refund of any part of any license fee shall be allowable in Prince George's County except upon the death of the licensee before the expiration of his or her license, when application for such refund may be made by the executor or administrator of the decedent.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">In Harford County a license holder is entitled to a refund of the unearned portion of the license fee if the license is voluntarily surrendered by the holder.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">In Harford County, the fee for every license issued for a period of less than one year, including Sunday licenses, is subject to the annual fee if issued during the first three months of the license year, three fourths of the annual fee if issued during the second quarter of the license year, one half of the annual fee if issued during the third quarter of the license year and one fourth of the annual license fee if issued during the fourth quarter of the license year. This section does not apply to temporary or special licenses.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">If a holder of a Kent County alcoholic beverages license voluntarily surrenders the license before its expiration date, the Kent County Board of License Commissioners shall grant a refund:<section prefix="1.">Based on the number of whole months remaining before the license expiration date; and</section><section prefix="2.">Calculated as 1/12 of 95 percent of the license fee paid for each whole month remaining before the license expiration date.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">All refunds shall be made 3 weeks after the license is surrendered to the Board of License Commissioners.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If an alcoholic beverages license is issued for a period of less than the full renewal period, the license fee shall be prorated based on the number of whole months remaining in that renewal period.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
