<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="g2b" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="10-504" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>g2b-10-504</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Except in Baltimore County, on the tenth day after the holder of any license issued under this article has vacated, or been evicted from the premises for which the license was issued, the license shall expire unless an application for approval of a transfer to another location or assignment to another person pursuant to &#xA7; 10-503 of this article or an application pursuant to &#xA7; 10-506 of this article has been approved or is then pending. However, the State Comptroller or local licensing board, as the case may be, may postpone the expiration for an additional period not exceeding 20 days in any case to avoid undue hardship.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">This section does not apply to the holder of any license whose premises have been acquired for public use.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The license for a premises acquired for public use shall expire within 180 days of acquisition unless an application for approval of a transfer of the license to another location or assignment to another person pursuant to &#xA7; 10-503 of this article or an application pursuant to &#xA7; 10-506 of this article has been approved or is then pending.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">This subsection applies only in Baltimore City.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">In this subsection, "Board" means the Board of License Commissioners or the Office of the Comptroller, whichever is the issuing party.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">180 days after the holder of any license issued under the provisions of this article has closed the business or ceased active alcoholic beverages business operations of the business for which the license is held, the license shall expire unless:<section prefix="(i)">An application for approval of a transfer to another location or an application for assignment to another person pursuant to &#xA7; 10-503(d) of this subtitle has been approved or is then pending;</section><section prefix="(ii)">An application pursuant to &#xA7; 10-506 of this subtitle has been approved or is then pending; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">A written request for a hardship extension, as provided in this subsection, is filed within the 180-day period.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The licensee or other appropriate interested parties may make a written request to the Board for an extension of the life of the license due to undue hardship, for a time period of no more than a cumulative period of 360 days after the date of closing or cessation of alcoholic beverages business operations of the business for which the license is held.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">After a hearing conducted on the extension request, on a finding that undue hardship currently exists causing the closing or cessation of business operations, the Board may grant an extension of the life of the license for a time period not to exceed 360 days as defined in paragraphs (3) and (5) of this subsection.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">It is the intent of this subsection that the total time period for which a license may be deemed unexpired under paragraph (2) of this subsection is 180 days if no undue hardship extension is granted, and no more than 360 days if an undue hardship extension has been granted. The time period begins at the earlier of the closing of the business or cessation of alcoholic beverages business, and shall be tolled only upon the filing of an application or request described in paragraph (2) of this subsection, the expiration period to begin running again, cumulatively to the time period before the filing of the application or request, upon the occurrence of the later to occur of the following events:<section prefix="(i)">Final action of the Board granting or denying a request authorized by paragraph (3) of this subsection;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Final action of the Board denying an application described under paragraph (2)(i) or (ii) of this subsection; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">Final judgment of the appellate court when judicial review of the Board's action on an application or request authorized by paragraph (2) or (3) of this subsection has been sought, or on dismissal of a petition for judicial review.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(6)">If an application or request to the Board described in paragraph (2) or (3) of this subsection is withdrawn, there shall be no tolling of the period for automatic expiration of the license and it shall be deemed as if no such application or request was filed.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">This subsection applies only in Baltimore County.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">In this subsection, "Board" means the Board of License Commissioners or the Office of the Comptroller, whichever is the issuing party.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">180 days after the holder of any license issued under the provisions of this article has closed the business or ceased active alcoholic beverages business operations of the business for which the license is held, the license shall expire unless:<section prefix="(i)">An application for approval of a transfer to another location or an application for assignment to another person pursuant to &#xA7; 10-503 of this article has been approved or is then pending;</section><section prefix="(ii)">An application pursuant to &#xA7; 10-506 of this article has been approved or is then pending; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">A written request for a hardship extension, as provided in this subsection, is filed within the 180-day period.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Except as provided in paragraph (7) of this subsection, the licensee or other appropriate interested parties may make a written request to the Board for an extension of the life of the license, due to undue hardship, for a time period of no more than a cumulative period of 360 days after the date of closing or cessation of alcoholic beverages business operations of the business for which the license is held.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">Except as provided in paragraph (7) of this subsection, after a hearing conducted on the extension request, upon a finding that undue hardship currently exists causing the closing or cessation of business operations, the Board may grant an extension of the life of the license for a time period not to exceed 360 days as defined in paragraphs (3) and (5) of this subsection.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">It is the intention of this subsection that the total time period for which a license may be deemed unexpired under paragraph (2) of this subsection is 180 days if no undue hardship extension is granted and no more than 360 days if an undue hardship extension has been granted. The time period begins at the earlier of the closing of the business or cessation of alcoholic beverages business, and shall be tolled only upon the filing of an application or request described in paragraph (2) of this subsection, the expiration period to begin running again, cumulatively to the time period before the filing of the application or request, upon the occurrence of the later to occur of the following events:<section prefix="(i)">Final action of the Board granting or denying a request authorized by paragraph (3) of this subsection;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Final action of the Board denying an application described by subparagraphs (i) or (ii) of paragraph (2) of this subsection; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">Final judgment of the appellate court when judicial review of the Board's action on an application or request authorized by paragraphs (2) or (3) of this subsection has been sought, or upon dismissal of a petition for judicial review.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(6)">In the event that an application or request to the Board described in paragraph (2) or (3) of this subsection is withdrawn, there shall be no tolling of the period for automatic expiration of the license and it shall be deemed as if no such application or request was filed.</section>
      <section prefix="(7)">If a licensed premises is forced to close because of a casualty loss, the Board, without circuit court approval, may extend the license for not more than 2 years after the closing.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In Charles and Wicomico counties, if the Board of License Commissioners in the respective county or the Harford County Liquor Control Board determines that a licensed premises under its jurisdiction is seasonally operated, the respective county board may authorize the closing of the premises in its respective jurisdiction for no more than 6 months.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">To qualify for this exception:<section prefix="(i)">The licensee shall submit a written request to the respective county board at least 30 days before the anticipated date of closing; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">In Harford County, the licensee shall also submit a written request to the Board at least 30 days before the anticipated date of reopening.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">In Cecil County an alcoholic beverages license is declared null and void if a licensee:<section prefix="(1)">Is no longer using the license and has the intention of terminating the business of the licensed premises; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Has not timely filed a transfer of the license with the Board of License Commissioners pursuant to &#xA7; 10-503 or &#xA7; 10-506 of this article.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(h)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">This subsection applies only in Allegany County.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">In this subsection, "Board" means the Board of License Commissioners.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">One hundred eighty days after the holder of any license issued under the provisions of this article has closed the business or ceased active alcoholic beverages business operations of the business for which the license is held, the license shall expire unless:<section prefix="(i)">An application for approval of a transfer to another location or an application for assignment to another person under &#xA7; 10-503(b) of this subtitle has been approved or is then pending;</section><section prefix="(ii)">An application under &#xA7; 10-506 of this subtitle has been approved or is then pending; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">A written request for a hardship extension, as provided in this subsection, is filed within the 180-day period.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The licensee or other appropriate interested parties may make a written request to the Board for an extension of the life of the license due to undue hardship, for a time period of no more than a cumulative period of 360 days after the date of closing or cessation of alcoholic beverages business operations of the business for which the license is held.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">After a hearing conducted on the extension request, on a finding that undue hardship currently exists causing the closing or cessation of business operations, the Board may grant an extension of the life of the license for a time period not to exceed 360 days as defined in paragraphs (3) and (5) of this subsection.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">
        <section prefix="(i)">It is the intent of this subsection that the total time period for which a license may be deemed unexpired under paragraph (2) of this subsection is 180 days if no undue hardship extension is granted, and no more than 360 days if an undue hardship extension has been granted.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The time period begins at the earlier of the closing of the business or cessation of alcoholic beverages business, and shall be tolled only on the filing of an application or request described in paragraph (2) of this subsection, the expiration period to begin running again, cumulatively to the time period before the filing of the application or request, on the occurrence of the later to occur of the following events:</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(6)">If an application or request to the Board described in paragraph (2) or (3) of this subsection is withdrawn, there shall be no tolling of the period for automatic expiration of the license and it shall be considered as if the application or request had not been filed.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
