<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="g2b" order_by="" level="1">Alcoholic Beverages</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>g2b-12-201</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>201</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">This section applies only in Allegany County.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A licensee may employ any person between the ages of 18 and 21 years for the general purposes of employment.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A person between ages 18 and 21 years may sell or serve beer and light wine.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">In order to be permitted to sell or serve distilled spirits, a person shall be 21 years of age or older.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A licensee may not allow a person not designated under &#xA7; 1-102(a)(6) of this article to loaf or loiter about the place of business for which the license is issued.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A manufacturer or wholesaler may not sell any beer to any retail dealer except for cash on delivery. No suit or action ex contractu to enforce or collect any claim for credit extended in violation of this section shall be maintained in this State.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">A licensee may not allow any gambling or gaming that is prohibited by law upon the premises for which the license is issued.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">A licensee may not allow any disorderly or disreputable persons to congregate at the place for which such license is granted.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">A licensee, holding a license under this article for the sale of alcoholic beverages by clubs, may not let the privilege granted under the license to any person by any manner of agreement under which the person to whom the privilege might be let could make a profit from it.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">All sales of alcoholic beverages by retail dealers shall be for cash only, and no suit may be maintained by any retail dealer against any person for alcoholic beverages which have been sold on credit.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In accordance with the provisions of paragraph (2) of this subsection, Class C and Class D licensees may permit persons under age 21 on the premises to hold or attend a dance or other function at which persons under age 21 may be present.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Alcoholic beverages may not be sold at the function nor may any alcoholic beverages be present within the room where the function is being held.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The sponsor of the function shall provide appropriate adult supervision at the function.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(j)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A person may not display or drink in any bar, restaurant, tavern or any other licensed place any alcoholic beverages other than those which may lawfully be sold by the licensee of the licensed place.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Any person who drinks or displays any such beverage in violation of the provisions of this subsection is guilty of a misdemeanor and upon conviction shall be fined not less than $25 nor more than $50.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">For the purposes of this section, "premises" includes any building, parking lot, terrace or grounds which form an integral part of the licensed premises.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">Any premises licensed for the sale of beer only or for the sale of beer and wine only shall have posted at least four conspicuous notices on the premises with the following words: "Unlawful to drink or expose liquor upon these premises".</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(k)">Any licensee or other person, upon indictment and conviction of violation of any provisions of this section, shall be fined not more than $1,000, or shall be imprisoned for up to 2 years, or both.</section>
  </text>
</law>
