<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="g2b" order_by="" level="1">Alcoholic Beverages</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>g2b-8-504</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>504</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">This section applies only in Howard County.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">In this section, "Board" means the Board of License Commissioners.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Board may issue a 7-day Class GC (golf course) beer and light wine license or a 7-day Class GC (golf course) beer, wine and liquor license.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A license may be issued on behalf of an organization that owns or manages a golf course with a minimum of 18 holes.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The annual license fee is:<section prefix="(1)">$350 for a 7-day Class GC (golf course) beer and light wine license; and</section><section prefix="(2)">$1,500 for a 7-day Class GC (golf course) beer, wine and liquor license.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The license is for the sale and consumption of alcoholic beverages on the licensed premises.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">The hours and days for sale are found in &#xA7; 11-514 of this article. However, the Board may reduce the hours and days for sale for all or a portion of the licensed premises.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">The Board may place conditions on the location of sales and consumption, including:<section prefix="(1)">Prohibiting the sale and consumption of liquor on specified areas of premises with a Class GC (golf course) beer, wine and liquor license; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Permitting the sale and consumption of only beer and light wine on specified areas of premises with a Class GC (golf course) beer, wine and liquor license.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(i)">The Board may restrict the sale of alcoholic beverages to beer and light wine on premises with a Class GC (golf course) beer, wine and liquor license if the Board determines that circumstances warrant.</section>
  </text>
</law>
