<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="g2b" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="3-301" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>g2b-3-301</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A Class C beer license shall be issued by the local licensing authority of the county in which the place of business is located. The holder of the license may keep for sale and sell beer at retail to bona fide members and their guests, at any club, at the place described in the license for consumption on the premises only.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The annual fee for the license shall be paid to the local collecting agent before any license is issued, for distribution as provided.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In Allegany County the annual license fee is $150.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Beer sold pursuant to this license may be consumed on the premises or elsewhere.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">This section does not apply in Anne Arundel County.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">This section does not apply in Baltimore City.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">This section does not apply in Baltimore County.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">In Calvert County the annual license fee is $50.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">In Caroline County the annual license fee is $250.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">In Carroll County the annual license fee is $50.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">In Cecil County the annual license fee is $75.</section>
    <section prefix="(j)">This section does not apply in Charles County.</section>
    <section prefix="(k)">In Dorchester County the annual license fee is $250.</section>
    <section prefix="(l)">In Frederick County the annual license fee is $50.</section>
    <section prefix="(m)">This section does not apply in Garrett County.</section>
    <section prefix="(n)">This section does not apply in Harford County.</section>
    <section prefix="(o)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In Howard County the annual license fee is $25.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The license shall be issued only to a club composed exclusively:</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">At least 75 percent of the members of the club shall have resided in Howard County for at least 2 years immediately preceding the date of the application for the license. The club shall also have maintained a post in the county for at least 3 years immediately preceding the date of the application.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(p)">This section does not apply in Kent County.</section>
    <section prefix="(q)">In Montgomery County the annual license fee is $50.</section>
    <section prefix="(r)">In Prince George's County the annual license fee is $245.</section>
    <section prefix="(s)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In Queen Anne's County the annual license fee is $50.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The license shall be issued to any local unit of a nationwide bona fide nonprofit organization or club:</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The license shall be issued only to a bona fide yacht club, golf club, fraternal club or order, country club, social or recreational club:</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(t)">This section does not apply in St. Mary's County.</section>
    <section prefix="(u)">In Somerset County the annual license fee is $32.</section>
    <section prefix="(v)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In Talbot County the annual license fee is $25.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Section 18-101 of this article permits the Talbot County Council to provide for the retail alcoholic beverage laws for the county which, if enacted, supersede the provisions of this article.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(w)">In Washington County the annual license fee is $100.</section>
    <section prefix="(x)">In Wicomico County the annual license fee is $75.</section>
    <section prefix="(y)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In Worcester County the annual license fee is $150.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The hours for sale shall be as provided in &#xA7; 11-524 of this article.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
