<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="g2b" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="6-101" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>g2b-6-101</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A Class A beer, wine and liquor license shall be issued by the license issuing authority of the county in which the place of business is located. The license authorizes the holder to keep for sale and to sell all alcoholic beverages at retail, in any quantity, at the place described in the license. The licensee shall deliver the alcoholic beverages in a sealed package or container and the package or container may not be opened nor its contents consumed on the premises where sold.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The annual license fee shall be paid to the local collecting agent before the license is issued, for distribution as provided.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A license may not be issued for any drugstore unless the applicant:<section prefix="(i)">Has been doing business at the location applied for, for at least 1 year prior to the date of the application for the license;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Is the assignee of a business established for that length of time at the location applied for; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">Has been actually engaged in the retail drug business for a period of not less than 3 years.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In Allegany County the annual license fee is $650.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The package or container may not be opened nor its contents consumed on any premises in which the licensee has any direct or indirect interest.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">In Anne Arundel County the annual license fee is $720.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">In Baltimore City the annual license fee is $858.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">In Baltimore County the annual license fee is $900.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">In Calvert County the annual license fee is $1,000.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This subsection applies only in Caroline County.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The annual license fee for a 6-day license is $1,250.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The annual license fee for a 7-day license is $1,600.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(h)">In Carroll County the annual license fee is $650.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">In Cecil County the annual license fee is $750.</section>
    <section prefix="(j)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In Charles County the annual license fee is $480.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">This license also authorizes the holder to serve beer, wine, and liquor for tasting and sampling purposes if:<section prefix="(i)">The tasting or sampling is held on the licensed premises; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">The holder serves not more than 1 ounce from each given brand of beer, wine, or liquor, in a container that holds not more than 4 ounces, to any one person.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(k)">In Dorchester County, the annual license fee is $2,500.</section>
    <section prefix="(l)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In Frederick County the annual license fee is $650.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A special Sunday opening permit may be granted for this license for an additional $650 as provided under this article.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(m)">This section does not apply in Garrett County.</section>
    <section prefix="(n)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This subsection applies only in Harford County.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The following licenses have the fees specified:<section prefix="(i)">The annual license fee for a 7-day Class A-1 off-sale beer, wine and liquor license is $1,470.</section><section prefix="(ii)">The annual license fee for a 6-day (Monday through Saturday) Class A-2 off-sale beer, wine and liquor license is $980.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Any license issued under the provisions of this section shall be issued by the Liquor Control Board.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">Each license issued under this section is subject to:<section prefix="(i)">The regulations of the Board;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The provisions of this section; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Section 5-101(n) of this article.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(5)">Any licensee who holds a Class B beer, wine and liquor license under &#xA7; 6-201(n) of this article or a Class B beer and wine license under &#xA7; 5-201(n) of this article, and who has been granted an option to the existing license that allows for off-sale liquor is subject to &#xA7; 6-201(n)(3) of this article.</section>
      <section prefix="(6)">A Class A-1 or Class A-2 licensee shall provide a separate outside entrance for the use of off-sale customers if the majority of the retail sales are of items other than alcoholic beverages. Additionally, if the business is predominately one of other types of retail sales, such as drugs or groceries, the alcoholic beverages shall be displayed and purchased in an area separate and distinct from that of the other retail items. The Board may require partitions if deemed conducive to the intent of this paragraph.</section>
      <section prefix="(7)">Any licensee having the off-sale option provided for in this section shall continually maintain a minimum stock of $8,000 wholesale value in beer, wine, and liquor.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(o)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This subsection applies only in Howard County.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The annual license fee for a 7-day Class A-1 license is $900.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The annual license fee for a 6-day Class A-2 license is $700.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(p)">In Kent County the annual license fee is $1,750.</section>
    <section prefix="(q)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This subsection applies only in Montgomery County.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The only Class A license that is available in the county is a Class A-TP 7-day license.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The annual license fee for a Class A-TP license is the same as for a license issued pursuant to subsection (r) of this section. Class A-TP licensees may not be charged for such a license until May 1, 1998.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The Board shall issue a Class A-TP license to any person who on June 30, 1997, both held a Class A beer, wine and liquor license and operated a Class A business where the licensed premises were located in that portion of the City of Takoma Park that was formerly part of Prince George's County.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">Unless revoked or not renewed for good cause, the license shall continue and be renewed, subject to payment of the annual license fee. The license is not transferable to any other location, but the license may be transferred to another person at any time, subject to the restrictions on similar transfers for other alcoholic beverages licenses in Montgomery County.</section>
      <section prefix="(6)">The Board shall promulgate regulations that govern the sale of alcoholic beverages by a Class A-TP licensee. These regulations shall include the hours for sale.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(r)">In Prince George's County the annual license fee is $910.</section>
    <section prefix="(s)">In Queen Anne's County the annual license fee is $2,000.</section>
    <section prefix="(t)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This subsection applies in St. Mary's County.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The annual license fee for a 7-day Class A-1 license is $400.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The annual license fee for a 6-day Class A-2 license is $300.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(u)">This section does not apply in Somerset County.</section>
    <section prefix="(v)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">In Talbot County this license may not be issued except to grocery stores, drugstores, incorporated clubs, restaurants and hotels which have been doing business in the county for more than 1 year prior to the date of the application for the license.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The annual fee for the license is $1,000.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Section 18-101 of this article permits the Talbot County Council to provide for the retail alcoholic beverages laws for the county, which, if enacted, supersede the provisions of this article.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(w)">In Washington County the annual license fee is $300.</section>
    <section prefix="(x)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This subsection applies only in Wicomico County.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The maximum number of licenses is three.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Any license issued under the provisions of this section shall be issued only to existing establishments that already have a Class B beer, wine and liquor (restaurant) license and have been continually operating as a restaurant in the county for 3 months prior to the application for this license.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">Any license issued under the provisions of this section shall apply only to the area described in the application and that area may not exceed 20 percent of the area normally used in the operation of the restaurant business. This area must be contiguous to and adjoin the restaurant establishment.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The annual license fee is $4,400.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">This fee shall be paid in addition to the fee paid for the Class B (restaurant) license.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(6)">All alcoholic beverages other than beer and light wine shall be purchased from the Liquor Control Board for Wicomico County and the licensee shall be charged not more than 15 percent above the wholesale operating cost to the dispensary.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(y)">This section does not apply in Worcester County.</section>
  </text>
</law>
