<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="g2b" order_by="" level="1">Alcoholic Beverages</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>g2b-8-505.1</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>505.1</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">This section applies only in Washington County.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">In this section, "Board" means the Board of License Commissioners.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Board may issue a 6-day Class C (golf course) beer and wine (on-sale) license and a 6-day Class C (golf course) beer, wine and liquor (on-sale) license.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Board may issue a Sunday Class C (golf course) beer and wine (on-sale) license and a Sunday Class C (golf course) beer, wine and liquor (on-sale) license.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A license may be issued to a public golf course or organization that has a regular or championship golf course with a minimum of nine holes.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The annual license fee is:<section prefix="(1)">$750 for a 6-day Class C (golf course) beer and wine (on-sale) license;</section><section prefix="(2)">$1,000 for a 6-day Class C (golf course) beer, wine and liquor (on-sale) license;</section><section prefix="(3)">$250 for a Sunday Class C (golf course) beer and wine (on-sale) license; and</section><section prefix="(4)">$250 for a Sunday Class C (golf course) beer, wine and liquor (on-sale) license.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">Subject to the approval of the Board of License Commissioners, a licensee under this section may sell alcoholic beverages for consumption only on the land and in the buildings, including the clubhouse, used for golfing purposes.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">A patron need not be seated to be served alcoholic beverages.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The hours and days of sale are as specified in &#xA7; 11-522 of this article.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Board may reduce a licensee's hours of sale of alcoholic beverages for all or a portion of the licensed premises.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
