<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="g2b" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="2-202" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>g2b-2-202</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">A Class 1 manufacturer's license:<section prefix="(1)">Is a distillery license;</section><section prefix="(2)">Authorizes the:<section prefix="(i)">Establishment and operation in this State of a plant for distilling brandy, rum, whiskey, alcohol and neutral spirits;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Sale and delivery of those alcoholic beverages in bulk to persons authorized in this State to acquire them; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Sale and delivery of those alcoholic beverages to persons located outside this State;</section></section><section prefix="(3)">Shall be obtained for each trade name and for each distillery in this State;</section><section prefix="(4)">Permits a distiller to manufacture alcoholic beverages in the name of another person or under a trade name, provided a distillery license has been issued to that other person or under that trade name, as the case may be;</section><section prefix="(5)">Permits the holder of the license to acquire bulk alcoholic beverages from the holder of a distillery, rectifying, or winery license in this State or from the holder of a nonresident dealer's permit; and</section><section prefix="(6)">Permits the holder of the license to:<section prefix="(i)">Conduct guided tours of the licensed premises;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Serve not more than three samples of products manufactured at the licensed premises, with each sample consisting of not more than one-half ounce from a single product, to persons who have attained the legal drinking age and participated in a guided tour of the licensed premises; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Subject to subsection (b) of this section, sell not more than three 750-milliliter bottles of products manufactured on the licensed premises, for consumption off the licensed premises, and related merchandise to persons who have attained the legal drinking age and participated in a guided tour of the licensed premises.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A holder of the license may sell bottles of products under subsection (a)(6)(iii) of this section only if the holder manufactures not more than 27,500 gallons of products annually.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A holder of a Class 1 manufacturer's license or entity in which a holder has a pecuniary interest may not act as a caterer of food.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Subject to subsection (e) of this section, a license holder may conduct the activities specified in subsection (a)(6) of this section:<section prefix="(1)">For consumption off the licensed premises of products manufactured at the licensed premises and for sampling, each day from 10 a.m. to 10 p.m.; and</section><section prefix="(2)">For consumption on the licensed premises of products manufactured at the licensed premises:<section prefix="(i)">From 10 a.m. to 6 p.m. each day; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">If guests are attending a planned promotional event or other organized activity on the licensed premises, from 10 a.m. to 10 p.m. each day.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, a Class 1 manufacturer's license allows the holder to operate 7 days a week.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">In Garrett County, a license holder may open on Sundays to engage in the activities listed in subsection (a)(6) of this section only in an election district where the voters, in a referendum authorized by law, have approved Sunday sales at a distillery.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">At least 14 days before holding a planned promotional event after 6 p.m., a license holder shall file a notice of the promotional event with the Comptroller on the form that the Comptroller provides.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, a license holder may not sell or allow to be consumed at the licensed premises any product other than products produced by the license holder under the authority of this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A holder of a caterer's license or privilege under Title 6, Subtitle 7 of this article may exercise the privileges of the license or privilege on the licensed premises of the license holder.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(h)">Nothing in this section limits the application of relevant provisions of Title 21 of the Health - General Article, and regulations adopted under that title, to a license holder.</section>
  </text>
</law>
