<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="g2b" order_by="" level="1">Alcoholic Beverages</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>g2b-9-211</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>211</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">This section applies only in Frederick County.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">There may not be issued more than one Class B on-sale beer license, nor more than one Class B on-sale beer and light wine license, for each unit of 4,000 people, or major fraction, in any one election district.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">There may not be issued more than one Class A off-sale beer, wine and liquor license, one Class A off-sale beer license, nor more than one Class A off-sale beer and light wine license, for each unit of 4,000 people, in any one election district. For the purposes of this section, the population of each election district shall be as determined by the last federal census.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">In any election district in which the number of any class of licenses issued as of June 1, 1949, exceeds the quota specified hereinabove, no new licenses of such class shall be issued unless and until the number of licenses of any such class shall have been so reduced by revocation or surrender as to create a vacancy under the particular quota specified hereinabove. For the purposes of this section, a transfer or renewal of an existing license shall in no way be construed to be a new license.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A Class A alcoholic beverage license may not be granted, transferred, issued to, or for use in conjunction with, or upon the premises of, or upon premises having any drug or pharmaceutical, or other business establishment of the type commonly known as chain stores, supermarkets, franchised establishments, or discount houses. "Franchised establishment" means premises operated under an agreement permitting the sale of a product or service under a name or mark under which the franchisee undertakes to conduct a business or sell a product or service in accordance with the methods and procedures prescribed by the franchisor in the agreement and the franchisor undertakes to assist the franchisee through advertising, promotion, or other services.</section>
  </text>
</law>
