<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="g2b" order_by="2" level="1">Alcoholic Beverages</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>g2b-11-509</section_number>
  <catch_line>In Charles County, notwithstanding any other provisions of this subtitle, the hours of sale for alco...</catch_line>
  <order_by>509</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In Charles County, notwithstanding any other provisions of this subtitle, the hours of sale for alcoholic beverages shall be as follows:<section prefix="(1)">Monday, 6 a.m. to Tuesday, 2 a.m.</section><section prefix="(2)">Tuesday, 6 a.m. to Wednesday, 2 a.m.</section><section prefix="(3)">Wednesday, 6 a.m. to Thursday, 2 a.m.</section><section prefix="(4)">Thursday, 6 a.m. to Friday, 2 a.m.</section><section prefix="(5)">Friday, 6 a.m. to Saturday, 2 a.m.</section><section prefix="(6)">Saturday, 6 a.m. to Sunday, 2 a.m.</section><section prefix="(7)">Sunday, 6 a.m. to Sunday, midnight.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">It is unlawful for any licensee, his agent or employee, to sell any alcoholic beverages on any day between the hours of 2 o'clock a.m. and 6 o'clock a.m. and that part of any premises where alcoholic beverages are sold or displayed shall be open only during the hours of sale for alcoholic beverages set out in subsection (a) of this section. In the case of any on-sale class of license, all bottles and containers must be removed from the table on or before the hours of closing indicated in subsection (a) of this section. It is unlawful to sell any alcoholic beverages between midnight, Sunday, and 6 o'clock a.m. Monday.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The hours established in this section for the sale of alcoholic beverages are hereby declared to be in accordance with Eastern Standard Time whenever such time is in effect or in accordance with daylight time whenever such time is in effect. Any person violating any of the provisions of this section shall be deemed guilty of a misdemeanor and upon trial and conviction shall be subjected to a fine of not less than fifty dollars ($50.00) nor more than two hundred and fifty dollars ($250.00), or may be confined in the county jail or in the house of correction for not less than sixty days, or both, in the discretion of the court.</section>
  </text>
</law>
