<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="g2b" order_by="2" level="1">Alcoholic Beverages</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>g2b-6-703.2</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this section, "holder" means a holder of a caterer's (CAT) license issued by the Board of License...</catch_line>
  <order_by>703.2</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, "holder" means a holder of a caterer's (CAT) license issued by the Board of License Commissioners of Garrett County.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">This section applies only in Garrett County.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Board of License Commissioners of Garrett County may issue a caterer's (CAT) license to a person who meets the requirements of this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A CAT license authorizes the holder to keep for sale and sell or provide off-sale alcoholic beverages during a catered event.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A holder may not:<section prefix="(i)">Hold a self-sponsored catered event; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">Provide only alcoholic beverages at a catered event.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Before a CAT license is issued or renewed, an applicant or holder:<section prefix="(i)">Shall have facilities to prepare food and deliver food to the site of catered events and obtain approval of the facilities from the Garrett County Department of Health; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">May not hold any other license issued by the Board of License Commissioners.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A holder need not have a banquet hall.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The annual CAT license fee is $500.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The issuing fee that is charged for each new CAT license is $500.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">A holder may exercise the privileges of a caterer's license only during the hours and days that are authorized for a Class B beer, wine and liquor license in Garrett County.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A holder shall:<section prefix="(i)">Purchase all alcoholic beverages from a wholesaler or retailer licensed to sell alcoholic beverages in Garrett County; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Contract for and provide food as well as alcoholic beverages for consumption at the catered event.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">During a catered event, a holder shall have at least one individual on site who has been certified by an alcohol awareness program licensed by the State Comptroller.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">At the end of a catered event, a holder shall return all containers of alcoholic beverages that are not empty to the holder's principal place of business.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
