<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="g2b" order_by="" level="1">Alcoholic Beverages</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>g2b-9-222</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>222</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In Washington County, except for a special or temporary license or a certificate of permission or renewal license issued to a personal representative under &#xA7; 10-506 of this article, the Board of License Commissioners may not issue a license to sell alcoholic beverages:<section prefix="(1)">Until all outstanding gaming proceeds, payments, and fines that are due and owing by the licensee or applicant have been paid or judicially satisfied; and</section><section prefix="(2)">For any premises that previously have been licensed under this article, until all county taxes that are due and owing by the licensee for the operation of the business under the previous license have been paid or judicially satisfied.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">In this subsection the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">"Population ratio quota" means 1 license for each 1,000 individuals, excluding individuals detained or confined in a correctional facility as defined under &#xA7; 1-101(d) of the Correctional Services Article, who reside in the election district where the license will be issued as determined by the last federal population census.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">"Restaurant" means an establishment that:<section prefix="1.">Is located in a permanent building;</section><section prefix="2.">Regularly sells and serves food to the general public;</section><section prefix="3.">Has a seating capacity of at least 75 persons; and</section><section prefix="4.">Has on an annual basis, gross sales of food and nonalcoholic beverages that exceed its annual gross sales of alcoholic beverages.</section></section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">In Washington County, except for a Class B alcoholic beverages (on-sale) license issued to a restaurant and any class of alcoholic beverages license renewed or transferred for the same premises, an alcoholic beverages license may not be issued within an election district if the number of alcoholic beverages licenses exceeds the population ratio quota.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">If the Washington County Board of License Commissioners determines that there is a public need including governmentally sanctioned economic revitalization for the issuance of a license notwithstanding the population ratio quota, the license may be issued by the Board.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The Board shall state in the order granting the issuance of the license the reasons for its decision to exceed the population ratio quota.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
