<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="g2b" order_by="" level="1">Alcoholic Beverages</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>g2b-11-303</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>303</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The hours during which the privileges conferred by a Class A beer, wine and liquor license may be exercised are from 6 a.m. to midnight, on every day except Sunday.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The provisions of paragraph (1) of this subsection are superseded as follows:<section prefix="(i)">In Annapolis, the hours may be fixed by the Mayor, Counselor, and Aldermen of the City of Annapolis;</section><section prefix="(ii)">In the Park Heights Redevelopment Area that is specified in the Park Heights Master Plan adopted by Baltimore City in 2006, the hours of sale begin at 9 a.m. each day;</section><section prefix="(iii)">In Caroline County, the hours of operation are from 6 a.m. to 2 a.m. the following day, on Monday through Sunday;</section><section prefix="(iv)">In Carroll County, the privileges conferred by a Class A beer, wine and liquor license may be exercised from 11 a.m. to 6 p.m. on Sunday;</section><section prefix="(v)">In Frederick County holders of a Class A beer, wine and liquor (off-sale) license may sell beer, wine and liquor for off-premises consumption on:<section prefix="1.">Monday through Saturday, from 6 a.m. to 2 a.m. the following day; and</section><section prefix="2.">Sunday, from 11 a.m. to 2 a.m. the following day, if they hold a special Sunday opening permit;</section></section><section prefix="(vi)">In Kent County, the provisions of &#xA7; 11-515 of this article apply;</section><section prefix="(vii)">In St. Mary's County, holders of a Class A-1 license may sell on Sunday; and</section><section prefix="(viii)">In Talbot County, the hours are from 8 a.m. to 12 midnight.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The hours during which the privileges conferred by a Class B beer, wine and liquor license may be exercised are from 6 a.m. to 2 a.m. on the following day.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">In Annapolis, the hours shall be as fixed by the Mayor, Counselor, and Aldermen of the City of Annapolis.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">In Montgomery County, except as provided in &#xA7; 11-516 of this article, the hours are from 9 a.m. on any day to 1 a.m. on the following day.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">In the 47th alcoholic beverages district in Baltimore City, the hours for off-sales under a Class B beer, wine and liquor license for use in a restaurant are as provided for in &#xA7; 6-201(d) of this article.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">In the Park Heights Redevelopment Area that is specified in the Park Heights Master Plan adopted by Baltimore City in 2006, the hours of sale begin at 9 a.m. each day.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The hours during which the privileges conferred by a Class C beer, wine and liquor license may be exercised are from 6 a.m. to 2 a.m. on the following day.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">In Annapolis, the hours are as fixed by the Mayor, Counselor, and Aldermen of Annapolis.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">In Kent County the hours of sale are as provided under &#xA7; 11-515 of this article.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">In Montgomery County, the hours of sale are as provided in &#xA7; 11-516 of this article.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The hours during which the privileges conferred by a Class D beer, wine and liquor license may be exercised are from 6 a.m. to midnight.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Except as otherwise provided in subsections (e), (f), and (g) of this section, in Baltimore City the hours are from 6 a.m. to 1 a.m.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">In Baltimore County the hours are from 6 a.m. to 2 a.m.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">In Caroline County the hours for a 6-day license holder and a 7-day license holder are from 6 a.m. to 2 a.m. the following day.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">In Queen Anne's County the hours on Monday through Saturday are from 6 a.m. to 2 a.m. on the following day.</section>
      <section prefix="(6)">In Wicomico County the hours are from 10 a.m. to 2 a.m., Monday through Saturday. Where sales are permitted until 2 a.m., alcoholic beverages may not be consumed after 2:30 a.m., at which time all tables and bar areas shall be cleared of all alcoholic beverages.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This subsection applies only in Baltimore City on the inner perimeter of a rectangle bounded by 31st Street on the south, Greenmount Avenue on the east, 32nd Street on the north, and Barclay Street on the west.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">By regulation, the Board of License Commissioners may restrict the hours and days for the sale and consumption of beer, wine and liquor.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In Baltimore City, in response to a complaint, the Board of License Commissioners may petition the circuit court for an order that limits the hours and days for the sale and consumption of beer, wine, and liquor on a licensee's premises.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The circuit court may issue a temporary order that limits the hours and days for the sale and consumption of beer, wine, and liquor on the licensed premises if the court finds by clear and convincing evidence that:<section prefix="(i)">The activities arising from sale and consumption of beer, wine, and liquor on the licensed premises result in an extreme and continuing disturbance to a residential community;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The licensee has failed to exercise good faith in attempting to remedy the disturbance at the request or order of the Board of License Commissioners; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">The Board has been unable to provide relief to the residential community by exercising its authority to suspend the license or reprimand the licensee.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The duration of the order of the court may not exceed the duration of the license term.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">Pending an appeal from the order of the circuit court, the order shall be stayed.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">This section may not be construed to limit any other powers of the Board of License Commissioners.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">In the Park Heights Redevelopment Area that is specified in the Park Heights Master Plan adopted by Baltimore City in 2006, the hours of sale begin at 9 a.m. each day.</section>
  </text>
</law>
