<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="g2b" order_by="2" level="1">Alcoholic Beverages</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>g2b-8-223</section_number>
  <catch_line>This section applies only in Wicomico County....</catch_line>
  <order_by>223</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">This section applies only in Wicomico County.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Board of License Commissioners may issue a Class B beer and light wine on-sale (stadium) license to the owner of any professional baseball team franchise, whether the franchise is a partnership or a corporation.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The license authorizes the holder to sell beer and, if sold with meals, light wine at the stadium:<section prefix="(1)">For consumption only on the licensed premises;</section><section prefix="(2)">In plastic, Styrofoam, or paper containers on the stadium premises, except that glass containers may be used in an enclosed dining premises in which the patrons are seated;</section><section prefix="(3)">To persons present:<section prefix="(i)">At the baseball game in which the licensee's team is playing; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">At other events that are held at the stadium; and</section></section><section prefix="(4)">During the hours and days for sale specified in &#xA7; 11-523(c)(8) of this article.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The annual license fee is $2,000.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">Except for a distributor of beer who is conducting business with the licensee for the purposes of this section, the licensee may not permit any person to carry any alcoholic beverages onto or from the licensed premises.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This license may be issued only for a stadium that has the average daily receipts from the sale of food for each month exceed the average daily receipts from the sale of alcoholic beverages.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">In calculating average daily receipts from the sale of food, an allocation of foodstuff contained in a mixed drink may not be included in average daily receipts from the sale of food.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
