<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="g2b" order_by="" level="1">Alcoholic Beverages</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>g2b-9-209</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>209</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">This section applies only in Charles County.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Board of License Commissioners may not issue more than 1 of any class of alcoholic beverages license with an off-sale privilege for each unit of 1,350 people, based on the population figures of the last federal census, within each election district in the county.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A license issued under this subsection may not be transferred from one election district to another.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">This subsection may not be construed to require the forfeiture or revocation of any alcoholic beverages license issued and outstanding on October 1, 1992.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">In any election district in which the quota is exceeded as of that date, the total number of licenses shall be reduced from time to time only by the voluntary relinquishment of licenses by the licensees, by bankruptcy, or by the workings of other provisions of this article. A new license may not be issued in any election district unless the issue may be made without exceeding the quota provided for in this subsection.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">When application for a liquor license is made to sell alcoholic beverages in a building which is not completed, the Board of License Commissioners may give tentative approval of the application on the basis of plans and specifications accompanying the application. Upon completion of the building in accordance with the plans and specifications, the Board may issue the license.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in paragraphs (2) and (3) of this subsection, the Board of License Commissioners may not issue any license to sell alcoholic beverages in any building the nearest wall of which measured in a direct line is within 500 feet of the property line of any school accredited by the State Board of Education.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">This subsection is not applicable in the event the school locates its building within 500 feet of any licensed premises after the licensed premises are located there.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">This subsection does not apply to a Class B (on-sale) beer, wine and liquor license that is issued for a premises located in a municipal corporation in Charles County.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">Subsections (c) and (d) do not apply to or affect or prohibit, in any manner, the renewal or transfer of any license issued prior to June 1, 1959.</section>
  </text>
</law>
