<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="g2b" order_by="2" level="1">Alcoholic Beverages</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>g2b-8-204.2</section_number>
  <catch_line>Notwithstanding the license population quota limitations, the Baltimore County Board of License Comm...</catch_line>
  <order_by>204.2</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Notwithstanding the license population quota limitations, the Baltimore County Board of License Commissioners may issue 10 Class B (SB) restaurant-service bar beer, wine and liquor (on-sale) licenses in the "Pikesville Revitalization Area" or "Pikesville Town Center" in Baltimore County for conversion purposes only, as provided under subsection (c) of this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The requirements for issuance qualifications, fee, and days and hours of sales under a Class B (SB) restaurant-service bar beer, wine and liquor (on-sale) license are the same as provided in this article for a Class B beer, wine and liquor (on-sale) hotel and restaurant license in Baltimore County with the following additional requirements:<section prefix="(1)"><section prefix="(i)">The licenses may be issued only to locations within the "Pikesville Revitalization Area", as defined by the Baltimore County Office of Planning and Zoning on or before July 1, 1988; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">The licenses may be issued only to locations within the "Pikesville Town Center", as defined by the Baltimore County Office of Planning and Zoning on or before July 1, 1988;</section></section><section prefix="(2)">The license shall be used in conjunction with the operation of a "restaurant" as defined by the rules of the Baltimore County Board of License Commissioners;</section><section prefix="(3)">The license shall allow on-premises sales only;</section><section prefix="(4)">The license shall be restricted to restaurants that have table service, specifically excluding any type of service while standing or where the customer accepts delivery of the purchased food items other than while seated at a table;</section><section prefix="(5)">The proposed location must otherwise comply with the zoning ordinances of Baltimore County;</section><section prefix="(6)">The license, once issued, may not be:<section prefix="(i)">Transferred outside of the "Pikesville Revitalization Area" or "Pikesville Town Center"; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">Converted to any other class of license; and</section></section><section prefix="(7)">The license may not be issued for use on premises or a location that has been licensed under any class of on-sale alcoholic beverages license within 2 years before the application for the Class B (SB) license is filed.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except for Class C licenses, 10 of any class beer, wine and liquor (on-sale) retail licenses in existence at any location in Baltimore County on January 1, 1988 may be transferred into the "Pikesville Revitalization Area" or the "Pikesville Town Center" in Baltimore County and converted into Class B (SB) licenses.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Upon transfer, the transferred license may not be considered as a license in the district from which it was transferred.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
