<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="g2b" order_by="" level="1">Alcoholic Beverages</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>g2b-11-304</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>304</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Between 2 a.m. and 6 a.m. on any day, a person may not consume any alcoholic beverages on any premises open to the general public, any place of public entertainment, or any place at which setups or other component parts of mixed alcoholic drinks are sold under any license issued under the provisions of the Business Regulation Article, and an owner, operator or manager of the premises or places may not knowingly permit such consumption.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Except as provided in this section, any person found consuming any alcoholic beverage on any premises open to the general public, and any owner, operator or manager of those premises or places who knowingly permits consumption between the hours provided by this section is guilty of a misdemeanor and, upon conviction, shall be fined not more than $50 and not less than $5.<section prefix="(i)">In Anne Arundel County the fine may not be more than $250.</section><section prefix="(ii)">In Worcester County the fine may not be more than $1,000.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This subsection applies only in Allegany County.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The prohibitions of this subsection apply after 1 a.m. on Sunday or between the hours of 1 a.m. and 7 a.m. on other days.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">A person may not consume any alcoholic beverages on any:<section prefix="1.">Premises open to the general public;</section><section prefix="2.">Place operated as a club;</section><section prefix="3.">Place of public entertainment; or</section><section prefix="4.">Place at which setups or other component parts of mixed alcoholic drinks are sold under any license issued under the provisions of this article.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">An owner, operator, or manager of the premises may not permit that consumption.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(4)">
        <section prefix="(i)">A person may not possess or consume any alcoholic beverage on any premises which is not licensed under this article but which is open to the general public and is operated as a club, a place of public entertainment, or a place where setups or other component parts of mixed alcoholic drinks are sold.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">An owner, operator, or manager of the premises may not permit that consumption or possession.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(5)">Any person who violates the provisions of this subsection is guilty of a misdemeanor and may be fined not less than $50 nor more than $500 for each offense.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">This subsection applies only in Anne Arundel County.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">In this paragraph, "premises" means a restaurant, tavern, hotel, club, dance studio, disco, or place of public entertainment, or a place open to the general public or in a place in any way licensed by this State or the county.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">
          <section prefix="1.">A person, corporation, club, or organization may not give or allow to be consumed on the premises or on premises under its possession or control any alcoholic beverages other than as specifically permitted or provided in this article.</section>
          <section prefix="2.">This does not apply to the room of a registered guest in any hotel, motel, or hospice.</section>
        </section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">A person may consume alcoholic beverages on the licensed premises of a video lottery facility only during the hours of operation established under &#xA7; 9-1A-23 of the State Government Article.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">A holder of an entertainment facility license or an entertainment concessionaire license or an employee of the license holder may not knowingly allow a person to consume alcoholic beverages on the licensed premises of a video lottery facility except during the hours of operation established under &#xA7; 9-1A-23 of the State Government Article.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Any owner, operator, manager, or employee of the premises who knowingly permits consumption in violation of this subsection is guilty of a misdemeanor and upon conviction may be fined not more than $250.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in this subsection, this section does not apply to premises conducted on New Year's Day by on-sale licensees in Baltimore City.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">In Baltimore City, a licensed premises shall cease all operations, including the serving of alcoholic beverages or food and providing entertainment, at the closing hour for that class of licensed premises specified in this article.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Notwithstanding paragraph (2) of this subsection, the Board of Liquor License Commissioners may grant an exemption for remaining open after hours to:<section prefix="(i)">A holder of a Class B restaurant license, only for serving food to patrons seated for dining;</section><section prefix="(ii)">A pharmacy that fills prescriptions; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">A holder of a Class D beer, wine and liquor license that operates a restaurant, if:<section prefix="1.">It is used only for serving food to patrons seated in a dining room that is not adjacent to a bar; and</section><section prefix="2.">The restaurant is located in the 46th Legislative District in the Legislative Districting Plan of 2002 as ordered by the Maryland Court of Appeals on June 21, 2002.</section></section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">A pharmacy that receives an exemption under paragraph (3) of this subsection may also sell products other than alcohol after normal closing hours.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">Notwithstanding the hour restrictions under paragraph (2) of this subsection, a hotel that holds a Class B license and that serves food to seated customers or to private functions or guest rooms may continue to provide food service.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This subsection applies only in Baltimore County.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">This section does not apply to activities on premises that are conducted on New Year's Day by on-sale licensees in the county.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Alcoholic beverages may not be brought onto any premises and consumed or transferred if the premises constitute a place of public entertainment and the entertainment is of the type prohibited under &#xA7; 10-405 of this article.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">Any person who operates a place of public entertainment who knowingly permits any violation of this subsection on the premises is guilty of a misdemeanor and on conviction may be fined up to $5,000 for each violation.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">Each day of operation in violation of this subsection is a separate violation.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">Reserved. (Calvert County)</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">Reserved. (Caroline County)</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">Reserved. (Carroll County)</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">Reserved. (Cecil County)</section>
    <section prefix="(j)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This subsection applies only in Charles County.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Alcoholic beverages may not be brought onto any premises and consumed or transferred if the premises constitute a place of public entertainment and the entertainment is of the type listed under &#xA7; 10-405(c) through (f) of this article.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">Any person who operates a place of public entertainment who knowingly permits any violation of this subsection on the premises is guilty of a misdemeanor and on conviction may be fined up to $5,000 for each violation.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">Each day of operation in violation of this subsection is a separate violation.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(k)">Reserved. (Dorchester County)</section>
    <section prefix="(l)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">This subsection applies only in Frederick County.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">Between 2 a.m. and 6 a.m. on any day, a person may not consume any alcoholic beverages on any premises open to the general public, any place of public entertainment, or any place at which setups or other component parts of mixed alcoholic drinks are sold under any license issued under the provisions of the Business Regulation Article, and any owner, operator, employee, or manager of those premises or places may not knowingly permit such consumption.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Unless otherwise specifically provided, any person violating the provisions of this subsection is subject to the general penalty provisions provided for in this section.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(m)">Reserved. (Garrett County)</section>
    <section prefix="(n)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">This subsection applies only in Harford County.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">
          <section prefix="1.">In this subsection the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
          <section prefix="2.">"Premises" means a restaurant, tavern, hotel, club, dance studio, disco, or place of public entertainment.</section>
          <section prefix="3.">"Person" means a person, club, organization, or place of public entertainment.</section>
        </section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">A person may not knowingly allow the consumption, possession, or transfer of alcoholic beverages on its premises except in a manner specifically permitted or provided for by this article if:<section prefix="1.">The person is in possession or control of the place or premises as owner, lessee, or user;</section><section prefix="2.">The place or premises is open to the general public or in any way licensed by this State or by the county; and</section><section prefix="3.">The place or premises is not the room of a registered guest in a hotel, motel, or hospice or the property of a volunteer fire company, bona fide catering establishment, community or civic association, swim club, or bona fide social, civic, nonprofit, charitable, fraternal, patriotic, educational, or public service organization, or bona fide religious institution which has been in existence for a minimum of 3 years.</section></section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Liquor Control Board may exempt from the provisions of this subsection places similar to those listed in sub-subparagraph 3 of subparagraph (iii) of paragraph (1) of this subsection on a case-by-case basis.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Liquor Control Board shall adopt uniform rules for the administration of exceptions specified in paragraph (1) of this subsection.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">Any owner, operator, manager, or employee of premises or places subject to the prohibitions of this subsection who knowingly permits the prohibited consumption in violation of this subsection is guilty of a misdemeanor and upon conviction may be fined not more than $1,000.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(o)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This subsection applies only in Howard County.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Alcoholic beverages may not be brought onto any premises and consumed or transferred if the premises constitute a place of public entertainment and the entertainment is of the type listed under &#xA7; 10-405(c) through (f) of this article.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">A person operating a place of public entertainment also violates the provisions of this subsection if a female entertainer exhibits her breasts below the top of the areola or exhibits the cleft of her buttocks.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">Any person who operates a place of public entertainment who knowingly permits any violation of this subsection on the premises is guilty of a misdemeanor and on conviction may be fined up to $5,000 for each violation.</section>
        <section prefix="(iv)">Each day of operation in violation of this subsection is a separate violation.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(p)">In Kent County the hours of sale under Classes B and D (on-sale) beer, wine and liquor licenses are as provided under &#xA7; 11-515 of this article.</section>
    <section prefix="(q)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This subsection applies only in Montgomery County.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">A person may not consume any alcoholic beverages between 1:30 a.m. and the next succeeding hour authorized by law for sales to begin on any premises open to the general public, or any place of public entertainment, which holds a:<section prefix="1.">Class B, Class C, Class D or Class H beer license;</section><section prefix="2.">Class B, Class C, Class D or Class H beer and light wine license; or</section><section prefix="3.">Class B beer, wine and liquor license.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">An owner, operator, or manager of the premises or place may not knowingly permit the consumption of alcoholic beverages between 1:30 a.m. and the next succeeding hour authorized by law for sales to begin under the respective licenses listed in subparagraph (i) of this paragraph.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">All containers of alcoholic beverages shall be removed from the table or tables prior to 1:30 a.m., except on Fridays and Saturdays when all containers of alcoholic beverages shall be removed prior to 2:30 a.m.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(r)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This subsection applies only in Prince George's County.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Alcoholic beverages may not be brought onto any unlicensed premises and consumed or transferred if the unlicensed premises constitute a place of public entertainment and the entertainment is of the type listed under &#xA7; 10-405(c) through (f) of this article.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">Any person who operates a place of public entertainment who knowingly permits any violation of this subsection on the unlicensed premises is guilty of a misdemeanor and on conviction may be fined up to $5,000 for each violation or imprisoned up to 1 year, or both.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">Each day of operation in violation of this subsection is a separate violation.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(s)">Reserved. (Queen Anne's County)</section>
    <section prefix="(t)">Reserved. (St. Mary's County)</section>
    <section prefix="(u)">Reserved. (Somerset County)</section>
    <section prefix="(v)">Reserved. (Talbot County)</section>
    <section prefix="(w)">In Washington County, this section is applicable from 1 a.m. to 6 a.m. and in all other respects as provided.</section>
    <section prefix="(x)">Reserved. (Wicomico County)</section>
    <section prefix="(y)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This subsection applies only in Worcester County.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Except as otherwise provided by this article and except as provided in paragraph (3) of this subsection, a person may not consume any alcoholic beverages at any time on any day of the week, including Saturday and Sunday, in any of the following premises:<section prefix="(i)">Restaurant;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Tavern;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Hotel;</section><section prefix="(iv)">Club;</section><section prefix="(v)">Dance studio;</section><section prefix="(vi)">Disco; and</section><section prefix="(vii)">Any other place of public entertainment.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The following are exempt from paragraph (2) of this subsection:<section prefix="1.">The room of a registered guest in a hotel, motel, or hospice; or</section><section prefix="2.">The property of a volunteer fire company.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The following are exempt from paragraph (2) of this subsection if they have been in existence for a minimum of 3 years:<section prefix="1.">A bona fide catering establishment;</section><section prefix="2.">A community or civic association;</section><section prefix="3.">A swim club;</section><section prefix="4.">A bona fide social, civic, nonprofit, charitable, fraternal, patriotic, educational, or public service organization; or</section><section prefix="5.">A bona fide religious institution.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">A fishing club that was established prior to January 1, 1970 is exempt from paragraph (2) of this subsection.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The Board of License Commissioners shall adopt uniform regulations for the administration of the provisions of this subsection.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">Any owner, operator, manager, or employee of premises or places subject to the prohibitions of this subsection who knowingly permits consumption in violation of this subsection is guilty of a misdemeanor and, on conviction, shall be fined not more than $10,000.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
