<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="g41" order_by="" level="1">Governor - Executive and Administrative Departments</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>g41-1-505</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>505</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, a licensing authority, before taking any action in regard to an initial license application, an application for a license renewal, or against a licensee under this subtitle, shall comply with the provisions of Title 10, Subtitle 2 of the State Government Article.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The provisions of the Maryland Rules shall govern in the case of a lawyer or an applicant for admission to the bar.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">In deciding whether to deny an applicant's application for a license or whether to impose license sanctions against a licensee and the nature of the sanctions, a licensing authority shall consider the following factors:<section prefix="(1)">The relationship between the drug crime and the license, including:<section prefix="(i)">The licensee's ability to perform the tasks authorized by the license; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Whether the public will be protected if:<section prefix="1.">In the case of an applicant, the license is issued; or</section><section prefix="2.">In the case of a licensee, the license is not suspended or revoked;</section></section></section><section prefix="(2)">The nature and circumstances of the drug crime;</section><section prefix="(3)">If an individual is applying for a license or license renewal, the date of the drug crime; and</section><section prefix="(4)">Any other relevant information.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">If a licensing authority decides that sanctions against a licensee may be appropriate, before imposing sanctions, the licensing authority:<section prefix="(1)">Shall consider the impact any sanctions may have on third persons; and</section><section prefix="(2)">May take any action to protect the rights of innocent third persons which is in the interests of justice and which is not inconsistent with the provisions of this subtitle.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">If a licensing authority decides to suspend or revoke a license, the licensing authority may grant the licensee a reasonable time period to complete any existing contracts.</section>
  </text>
</law>
