<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="g41" order_by="41" level="1">Governor - Executive and Administrative Departments</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>g41-1-501</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated....</catch_line>
  <order_by>501</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Drug crime" means:<section prefix="(1)">A violation of Title 5 of the Criminal Law Article;</section><section prefix="(2)">A violation of Title 12 of the Criminal Procedure Article; or</section><section prefix="(3)">A violation of the law of any other jurisdiction if the prohibited conduct would be a violation of Title 5 of the Criminal Law Article or Title 12 of the Criminal Procedure Article if committed in this State.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"License" means a license, permit, certification, registration, or other legal authorization:<section prefix="(i)">Issued to or granted to an individual by a licensing authority; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Required for engaging in employment or an occupation or profession.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"License" includes a commercial driver's license issued under Title 16, Subtitle 8 of the Transportation Article.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, "license" does not include:<section prefix="(i)">A license to drive a motor vehicle issued by the Motor Vehicle Administration under Title 16 of the Transportation Article; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">The registration of an agent, issuer agent, or investment advisor representative under the Maryland Securities Act (Title 11 of the Corporations and Associations Article) and regulations adopted under that Act.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">"Licensee" means a holder of a license issued by a licensing authority.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Licensing authority" means an agency of the State which issues a license.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Licensing authority" includes the Motor Vehicle Administration for purposes of issuing a commercial driver's license.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
