<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="g41" order_by="" level="1">Governor - Executive and Administrative Departments</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>g41-4-406</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>406</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The executive director shall administer the State Aid for Police Protection Fund.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The executive director shall:<section prefix="(1)">Certify to the Comptroller and to the subdivisions and qualifying municipalities the amount of payments to the subdivisions and qualifying municipalities; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Make such regulations and require such reports as are necessary to certify the amounts.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">In administering the Fund, the executive director shall:<section prefix="(1)">Make a continuing effort to establish standards of police protection adequate to the various local situations; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Subject to &#xA7; 2-1246 of the State Government Article, report periodically to the General Assembly on progress in establishing and meeting those standards, including the payment amounts certified under subsection (b) of this section and any other relevant fiscal information.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">In determining qualification under &#xA7; 4-403(a)(8) of this subtitle, the minimum standards determined by the Police Training Commission under authority of Title 3, Subtitle 2 of the Public Safety Article shall be applied.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The Police Training Commission shall print and distribute to all municipalities its rules and regulations setting forth the minimum standards of police qualifications.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In the event a municipality fails to meet the minimum standards for two successive years, the executive director shall withhold payments to the municipality with respect to the second year.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Any payment withheld for noncompliance is forfeited, and a claim may not be made by the municipality for the funds.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
