<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="g41" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="18-201" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>g41-18-201</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Subject to the initial approval of the Secretary of General Services, the services of the Purchasing Bureau of the Department of General Services may be used to purchase materials, supplies, and equipment by the county commissioners or the appropriate purchasing entity for:<section prefix="(1)">A county or Baltimore City;</section><section prefix="(2)">A municipal corporation;</section><section prefix="(3)">A governmental agency in the State;</section><section prefix="(4)">A public or quasi-public agency that:<section prefix="(i)">Receives State money; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Is exempt from taxation under &#xA7; 501(c)(3) of the Internal Revenue Code;</section></section><section prefix="(5)">A private elementary or secondary school that:<section prefix="(i)">Either has been issued a certificate of approval from the State Board of Education or is accredited by the Association of Independent Schools; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Is exempt from taxation under &#xA7; 501(c)(3) of the Internal Revenue Code; or</section></section><section prefix="(6)">A nonpublic institution of higher education under &#xA7; 17-106 of the Education Article.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The right to purchase through the Department of General Services under subsection (a) of this section shall be in addition to, but not in substitution for, the applicable purchasing power granted to any county, municipal corporation, the Mayor and City Council of Baltimore, any other governmental agency in this State, or any public or quasi-public agency pursuant to any statutory or charter provision.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Notwithstanding subsection (a)(5) and (6) of this section, the Department of General Services may not purchase religious materials on behalf of a private elementary or secondary school or a nonpublic institution of higher education.</section>
  </text>
</law>
