<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="g41" order_by="" level="1">Governor - Executive and Administrative Departments</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>g41-18-202</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>202</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Secretary of Agriculture shall study the effectiveness of an ethanol and gasoline mixture, known as gasohol, as an alternative fuel for motor vehicles. The Secretary of Agriculture shall initiate a 1-year program of tests using gasohol for fuel in eight presently owned State motor vehicles according to the provisions of this section. The purposes of the gasohol testing program are:<section prefix="(1)">To evaluate the cost-effectiveness of gasohol as an alternative fuel for motor vehicles;</section><section prefix="(2)">To evaluate the performance of gasohol as an alternative fuel for motor vehicles;</section><section prefix="(3)">To compare the performance of gasohol in a new motor vehicle with its performance in a used motor vehicle;</section><section prefix="(4)">To determine the negative effects, if any, from using gasohol in a motor vehicle for an extended period of time; and</section><section prefix="(5)">To investigate and review the feasibility of establishing a local source of supply for methanol or ethanol utilizing State agricultural produce.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The motor vehicles used in the gasohol testing program shall consist of the following:<section prefix="(1)">Four motor vehicles currently in use with the Department of General Services which have been in use for 1 year before the tests begin; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Four new motor vehicles of the Department of General Services may be used for the test.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The costs of the gasohol testing program shall be paid from funds appropriated in the State budget.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The gasohol testing program shall include, but is not limited to, at least one member from each of the following:<section prefix="(1)">The Department of Agriculture;</section><section prefix="(2)">The Department of General Services;</section><section prefix="(3)">The Department of the Environment; and</section><section prefix="(4)">The Department of Natural Resources.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The gasohol testing program shall conduct the testing program according to the following procedures:<section prefix="(1)">Locate gasohol suppliers and contract with a supplier, according to the procurement procedures of this subtitle, to provide a sufficient amount of gasohol for the testing program;</section><section prefix="(2)">The test motor vehicles shall be operated by Department of General Services personnel in the Department's routine operations;</section><section prefix="(3)">It shall provide for regular evaluation of the test vehicles during the course of the testing program;</section><section prefix="(4)">The test vehicles shall be operated throughout the State to provide as many diverse operating conditions as are practicable;</section><section prefix="(5)">It shall prepare a final report of the testing program which includes:<section prefix="(i)">A critical evaluation of the performance of gasohol;</section><section prefix="(ii)">A breakdown of the costs incurred in the operation of the test vehicles using gasohol; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Recommendations for future use of gasohol in State motor vehicles; and</section></section><section prefix="(6)">The gasohol testing program shall be submitted no later than January 1, 1980 to the Legislative Policy Committee.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The Legislative Policy Committee shall make a report of its recommendations to the Governor and to the General Assembly no later than January 31, 1980.</section>
  </text>
</law>
