<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="g49b" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="48" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>g49b-48</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">This section supersedes any contrary provisions of the St. Mary's County Open Meetings Act and the Maryland Public Information Act.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Subject to paragraph (2) of this subsection:<section prefix="(i)">All activities of the Commission that relate to an alternative dispute resolution, grievance, or complaint of discrimination shall be conducted in confidence and without publicity; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">The Commission may meet in closed or executive sessions when dealing with an alternative dispute resolution, grievance, or complaint of discrimination.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If all parties involved in an alternative dispute resolution, grievance, or complaint of discrimination consent in writing, the Commission's activities related to that alternative dispute resolution, grievance, or complaint of discrimination may be conducted publicly.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Except as provided under &#xA7; 51 of this subtitle, the Commission shall hold confidential all information concerning an alternative dispute resolution, grievance, or complaint of discrimination, including the identities of the parties involved.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Information related to the activities or involvement of the Commission in an alternative dispute resolution, grievance, or complaint of discrimination may not be admitted as evidence in any administrative proceeding or litigation.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The records of the Commission may not be discovered in any administrative proceeding or litigation.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided under &#xA7; 51 of this subtitle and paragraph (2) of this subsection, information or records related to the activities of the Commission or the involvement of the Commission in an alternative dispute resolution, grievance, or complaint of discrimination are not subject to public inspection under the Maryland Public Information Act.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Statistical information may be made available for public inspection under &#xA7; 10-624(e) of the State Government Article.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The Commission shall hold confidential any information and records obtained by a predecessor County body that was authorized to perform a function similar to that of the Commission before the effective date of this subtitle.</section>
  </text>
</law>
