<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="g95" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="22G" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>g95-22G</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">"Authorized participant" means:</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">"Pool" means the Local Government Investment Pool.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">There is a Local Government Investment Pool.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Pool consists of:<section prefix="(i)">All funds from authorized participants that are placed in the custody of the State; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Any funds of the State that are placed in the Pool by the Treasurer.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The investment policies for the Pool shall be established by the Treasurer.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">The Treasurer shall administer the Pool on behalf of the authorized participants and, to the extent that State money is included, on behalf of the State.</section>
      <section prefix="(6)">The Treasurer shall develop such procedures necessary for the efficient administration of the Pool, including:<section prefix="(i)">Specification of minimum and maximum amounts that may be deposited by any authorized participant in the Pool and minimum periods of time for which deposits shall be retained in the Pool;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Payment of amounts equivalent to administrative expenses from the earnings of the Pool; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Distribution of the earnings in excess of expenses, or allocation of losses, to the authorized participants in a manner that equitably reflects the differing amount of their respective investments and the differing periods of time for which the amounts were in the custody of the Pool.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Treasurer shall invest moneys in the Pool in accordance with the provisions set forth in &#xA7;&#xA7; 6-222 and 6-223 of the State Finance and Procurement Article.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Notwithstanding any provisions of law to the contrary or any limitation or restriction contained in any other law, the Treasurer may invest, redeem, sell, exchange, and reinvest moneys in the Pool in bankers' acceptances guaranteed by banking institutions.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The governing authority of any authorized participant having funds which are available for investment and which are not required by law or by any covenant or agreement with bondholders or others to be segregated and invested in a different manner may direct its financial officer to remit funds to the Treasurer for investment as part of the Pool.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The governing authority of any authorized participant having funds intended for other postemployment benefits that are available for investment, as authorized under &#xA7; 22 of this article, may direct its financial officer to remit those funds to the Treasurer for investment as part of the Pool.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Upon determination by the governing authority of an authorized participant that it is in the best interest of the authorized participant to deposit funds in the Pool, it shall adopt and file with the Treasurer a certified copy of a resolution or ordinance authorizing investment of its funds in the Pool. The resolution or ordinance shall name the official or officials of the authorized participant who are responsible for deposit and withdrawal of such funds.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The resolution or ordinance filed with the Treasurer shall be accompanied by a statement as to the approximate cash flow requirements of the authorized participant for the invested funds. Subsequent deposits into the Pool shall be accompanied by a statement as to the intended duration of the investment or the anticipated date of withdrawal of the funds from the Pool.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A separate account designated by name or number for each authorized participant in the Pool, including the State, shall be kept to record individual transactions and totals of all investments belonging to each authorized participant. A monthly report showing the changes in investments made during the preceding month shall be furnished to each authorized participant in the Pool. Details of any investment transaction shall be furnished to any authorized participant upon request.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The principal and credited income of each account maintained for an authorized participant in the Pool shall be subject to payment from the Pool upon request, provided that the request for payment is made in accordance with the terms of the deposit. Accumulated income shall be credited to each authorized participant account at least monthly.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">Except as provided in this section, all instruments of title of all investments of the Pool shall remain in the custody of the Treasurer. The Treasurer may deposit with one or more fiscal agents or banks those instruments of title the Treasurer considers advisable, to be held in safekeeping by the agents or banks for collection of the principal and interest or other income, or of the proceeds of sale. The Treasurer shall collect the principal and interest or other income from investments of the Pool, the instruments of title to which are in the Treasurer's custody, when due and payable.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">A payment may not be issued upon any account in an amount greater than the sum total of the particular account to which it applies. If such payment is issued, it shall be refunded by the distributee.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Subject to the objectives and requirements of this section, the Treasurer shall formulate procedures for the investment and reinvestment of funds in the Pool and the acquisition, retention, management, and disposition of investments of the Pool.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The Treasurer may enter into a contractual agreement with a qualified Maryland fiscal agent and may compensate the agent for services rendered.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The agent may perform investment and administrative services which the Treasurer is authorized by this section to perform.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(i)">Funds placed in the Pool, other than funds of the State, may not be considered to be money of the State.</section>
  </text>
</law>
