<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gag" order_by="" level="1">Agriculture</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gag-5-208</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>208</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">When a pesticide is applied, or at the time a customer enters into a contract with a licensee for pest control, a licensee shall provide a customer with the following written information:<section prefix="(1)">Name of licensee;</section><section prefix="(2)">Maryland pesticide business license number;</section><section prefix="(3)">Telephone number of licensee;</section><section prefix="(4)">Common name of pesticide or active ingredient applied;</section><section prefix="(5)">Pertinent safety information, as determined by the Department, including health risks for humans and animals, about pesticide in the end-use dilution applied;</section><section prefix="(6)">Maryland Poison Center telephone number; and</section><section prefix="(7)">Any other information required by the Department.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Upon the customer's request, the licensee shall provide the customer with advance notice of a pesticide application.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A licensee or public agency permittee applying a pesticide to a lawn or to exterior landscape plants shall post at the time of application a sign.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The sign shall remain 48 hours following the pesticide application, after which time the customer is responsible for the removal of the sign.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">A person may not remove, alter, or deface the sign or agree or conspire with another to remove, alter, or deface the sign within 48 hours of its posting.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The customer or licensee may not be held liable for any penalty for sign removal under this subtitle if the sign is removed by another person or cause over which the customer or licensee has no control.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The sign shall:<section prefix="(i)">Be clearly visible either from the principal place of access to the property; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">Be clearly visible on the portion of the property where the pesticide is applied.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(5)">The sign shall contain a uniform statement approved by the Department.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Before applying an experimental use pesticide, the holder of the required experimental use permit from the U.S. Environmental Protection Agency shall provide the Department with the following information:<section prefix="(1)">Name of cooperator;</section><section prefix="(2)">Location of planned application or treatment;</section><section prefix="(3)">Name of active ingredient of pesticide;</section><section prefix="(4)">Purpose of application or use;</section><section prefix="(5)">Total acreage being affected by application;</section><section prefix="(6)">Toxicological profile of pesticide; and</section><section prefix="(7)">Any other information required by the Department.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
