<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gag" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="8-803.1" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gag-8-803.1</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, "gross income" means the actual income that is received in a calendar year that results directly from the farm or agricultural use of the land.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">This section does not apply to:<section prefix="(1)">An agricultural operation with less than $2,500 in gross income; or</section><section prefix="(2)">A livestock operation with less than eight animal units defined as 1,000 pounds of live animal weight per animal unit.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Governor shall provide sufficient funding in each fiscal year's budget to:<section prefix="(1)">Assist in the development of nutrient management plans;</section><section prefix="(2)">Meet the technical assistance and evaluation requirements of this section;</section><section prefix="(3)">Meet the State's requirements for the implementation of the Manure Transportation Project under &#xA7; 8-704.2 of this title; and</section><section prefix="(4)">Provide State assistance under the Maryland Agricultural Water Quality Cost Share Program in the Department.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">State cost sharing may be made available to help offset the costs of having a nutrient management plan prepared by a certified nutrient management consultant who is not employed by the federal, State, or a local government.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Secretary of Agriculture shall adopt regulations authorizing the disbursement of State cost sharing funds under this subsection.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Department may procure the services of a private certified nutrient management consultant to develop nutrient management plans for persons operating a farm.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">By December 31, 2001, a person who, in operating a farm, uses chemical fertilizer, shall have a nutrient management plan for nitrogen and phosphorus that meets the requirements of this subtitle.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">By December 31, 2001, a person who, in operating a farm, uses sludge or animal manure, shall have a nutrient management plan for nitrogen.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">By July 1, 2004, a person who, in operating a farm, uses sludge or animal manure, shall have a nutrient management plan for nitrogen and phosphorus.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">By December 31, 2002, a person who, in operating a farm, uses chemical fertilizer, shall comply with a nutrient management plan for nitrogen and phosphorus that meets the requirements of this subtitle.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">By December 31, 2002, a person who, in operating a farm, uses sludge or animal manure, shall comply with a nutrient management plan for nitrogen that meets the requirements of this subtitle.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">By July 1, 2005, a person who, in operating a farm, uses sludge or animal manure, shall comply with a nutrient management plan for nitrogen and phosphorus that meets the requirements of this subtitle.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">A person may meet the requirements of subsection (e) of this section by requesting, at least 60 days before the applicable date set forth in subsection (e) of this section, the development of a nutrient management plan by a certified nutrient management consultant.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If a person violates the provisions of subsection (e) of this section, the Department shall notify the person that the person is in violation of the requirement to have a nutrient management plan.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">After a reasonable period of time, if the person fails to have a nutrient management plan, the person is subject to an administrative penalty not to exceed $250.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(i)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A person who violates any provision of subsection (f) of this section or of any rule, regulation, or order adopted or issued under this section is subject to:<section prefix="(i)">For a first violation, a warning; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">For a second or subsequent violation, after an opportunity for a hearing which may be waived in writing by the person accused of a violation, an administrative penalty that may be imposed by the Department of Agriculture.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The penalty imposed on a person under paragraph (1)(ii) of this subsection shall be:<section prefix="(i)">Up to $100 for each violation, but not exceeding $2,000 per farmer or operator per year; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Assessed with consideration given to:</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Except as provided in subparagraph (ii) of this paragraph, each day a violation occurs is a separate violation under this subsection.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">Daily penalties do not continue to accrue as long as the farmer takes reasonable steps to correct the violation.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(4)">Any penalty imposed under this subsection is payable to the Maryland Agricultural Water Quality Cost Share Program within the Department.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(j)">If a person violates any provision of this section, the Department may:<section prefix="(1)">Require repayment of cost share funds under Subtitle 7 of this title for the project that is in violation; or</section><section prefix="(2)">Deny or restrict future cost share payments under Subtitle 7 of this title.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(k)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Department shall determine compliance with the provisions of this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Department may review the nutrient management plan and records relating to the plan at a location agreed to by the Department and the person operating the farm.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">In conducting a site visit and reviewing the nutrient management plan and related records, the Department's evaluation shall be limited solely to determining whether the person operating the farm is in compliance with the provisions of this section or the regulations implementing this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">In conducting a site visit, the Department shall:<section prefix="(i)">Provide the person operating the farm at least 48 hours advance notice;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Enter the property at a reasonable time that allows the person operating the farm to be present; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Conduct the evaluation in a manner that minimizes any inconvenience to the person operating the farm.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(5)">If a person operating a farm fails to cooperate with the Department's request to conduct a site visit and review of a nutrient management plan and records relating to the plan, that person is subject to subsections (i) and (j) of this section.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
