<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gag" order_by="gag" level="1">Agriculture</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gag-8-7A-02</section_number>
  <catch_line>There is an Animal Waste Technology Fund in the Department....</catch_line>
  <order_by>02</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">There is an Animal Waste Technology Fund in the Department.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The purpose of the Animal Waste Technology Fund is to provide financial assistance to individuals and business enterprises that:<section prefix="(1)">Conduct research or develop technologies that are intended to reduce the amount of nutrients in animal waste;</section><section prefix="(2)">Alter the composition of animal waste;</section><section prefix="(3)">Develop alternative animal waste management strategies; or</section><section prefix="(4)">Use animal waste in a production process.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The goal of the Fund is to encourage the development and implementation of economically feasible technologies that help protect the public health and the environment by reducing the amount of nutrients from animal waste to enable farmers to meet nutrient management requirements and provide alternative animal waste management strategies to farmers.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Department shall administer the Fund;</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Secretary may:<section prefix="(i)">Delegate to any unit in the Department the underwriting, closing, monitoring, and workout functions for Fund loans; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">Contract with another entity to perform these functions.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Fund is a special continuing, nonlapsing fund that is not subject to reversion under &#xA7; 7-302 of the State Finance and Procurement Article.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The State Treasurer shall hold the Fund separately, and the Comptroller shall account for the Fund.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The Fund consists of:<section prefix="(1)">Money appropriated in the State budget to the Fund;</section><section prefix="(2)">Any other money from any other source accepted for the benefit of the Fund;</section><section prefix="(3)">Any investment earnings of the Fund;</section><section prefix="(4)">Repayments of principal and interest from loans made from the Fund;</section><section prefix="(5)">Income from equity investments that the State Treasurer makes from the Fund;</section><section prefix="(6)">Proceeds from the sale, disposition, lease, or rental by the Department of collateral related to any financing provided by the Department under this subtitle; and</section><section prefix="(7)">Application or other fees paid to the Department in connection with the processing of requests for assistance.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(g)">The Department may use money in the Fund to:<section prefix="(1)">Provide financial assistance to defray the costs of animal waste technology projects; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Pay expenses for administrative, actuarial, legal, and technical services associated with operating the Fund.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(h)">The Department may impose terms and conditions on financial assistance provided from the Fund, including administration and transaction fees.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">Financial assistance provided from the Fund may be:<section prefix="(1)">Used only to pay the costs of carrying out an animal waste technology project; and</section><section prefix="(2)">In the form of:<section prefix="(i)">A grant;</section><section prefix="(ii)">A loan;</section><section prefix="(iii)">A loan guarantee; or</section><section prefix="(iv)">A loan that is convertible in whole or in part to a grant on the satisfaction of specified conditions.</section></section></section>
  </text>
</law>
