<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gag" order_by="gag" level="1">Agriculture</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gag-3-117</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this section, "Fund" means the Animal Health Fund....</catch_line>
  <order_by>117</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, "Fund" means the Animal Health Fund.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">There is an Animal Health Fund.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The purpose of the Fund is to defray the Department's cost of issuing orders or conducting site visits and animal testing to prevent the spread of contagious or infectious diseases.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Department shall administer the Fund.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Fund is a special, nonlapsing fund that is not subject to &#xA7; 7-302 of the State Finance and Procurement Article.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Treasurer shall hold the Fund separately, and the Comptroller shall account for the Fund.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The Fund consists of:<section prefix="(1)">Administrative penalties distributed to the Fund under &#xA7; 3-116(c) of this subtitle;</section><section prefix="(2)">Money appropriated in the State budget to the Fund;</section><section prefix="(3)">Any investment earnings of the Fund; and</section><section prefix="(4)">Any other money from any other source accepted for the benefit of the Fund.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(g)">The Fund may be used only for defraying the Department's cost of issuing orders or conducting site visits and animal testing to prevent the spread of contagious or infectious diseases.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Treasurer shall invest the money of the Fund in the same manner as other State money may be invested.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Any investment earnings of the Fund shall be credited to the Fund.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(i)">Expenditures from the Fund may be made only in accordance with the State budget.</section>
  </text>
</law>
