<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gag" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="5-706" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gag-5-706</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Each party state pledges to each other party state that it will employ its best efforts to eradicate, or control within the strictest practicable limits, any and all pests. It is recognized that performance of this responsibility involves:<section prefix="(1)">The maintenance of pest control and eradication activities of interstate significance by a party state at a level that would be reasonable for its own protection in the absence of this compact.</section><section prefix="(2)">The meeting of emergency outbreaks or infestations of interstate significance to no less an extent than would have been done in the absence of this compact.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Whenever a party state is threatened by a pest not present within its borders but present within another party state, or whenever a party state is undertaking or engaged in activities for the control or eradication of a pest or pests, and finds that such activities are or would be impracticable or substantially more difficult of success by reason of failure of another party state to cope with infestation or threatened infestation, that state may request the governing board to authorize expenditures from the Insurance Fund for eradication or control measures to be taken by one or more of such other party states at a level sufficient to prevent, or to reduce to the greatest practicable extent, infestation or reinfestation of the requesting state. Upon such authorization the responding state or states shall take or increase such eradication or control measures as may be warranted. A responding state shall use moneys made available from the Insurance Fund expeditiously and efficiently to assist in affording the protection requested.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">In order to apply for expenditures from the Insurance Fund, a requesting state shall submit the following in writing:<section prefix="(1)">A detailed statement of the circumstances which occasion the request for the invoking of the compact.</section><section prefix="(2)">Evidence of need for eradication or control assistance because the pest in question constitutes a danger to an agricultural or forest crop, product, tree, shrub, grass or other plant having a substantial value to the requesting state.</section><section prefix="(3)">A statement of the extent of the present and projected program of the requesting state and its subdivisions, including full information as to the legal authority for the conduct of such program or programs and the expenditures being made or budgeted therefor, in connection with the eradication, control, or prevention of introduction of the pest concerned.</section><section prefix="(4)">Proof that the expenditures being made or budgeted as detailed in item (3) do not constitute a reduction of the effort for the control or eradication of the pest concerned or, if there is a reduction, the reasons why the level of program detailed in item (3) constitutes a normal level of pest control activity.</section><section prefix="(5)">A declaration as to whether, to the best of its knowledge and belief, the conditions which in its view occasion the invoking of the compact in the particular instance can be abated by a program undertaken with the aid of moneys from the Insurance Fund in one year or less, or whether the request is for an installment in a program which is likely to continue for a longer period of time.</section><section prefix="(6)">Such other information as the governing board may require consistent with the provisions of this compact.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The governing board or executive committee shall give due notice of any meeting at which an application for assistance from the Insurance Fund is to be considered. Such notice shall be given to the compact administrator of each party and to such other officers and agencies as may be designated by the laws of the party states. The requesting state and any other party state shall be entitled to be represented and present evidence and argument at such meeting.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">Upon the submission as required by paragraph (c) of this section and such other information as it may have or acquire, and upon determining that an expenditure of funds is within the purposes of this compact and justified thereby, the governing board or executive committee shall authorize support of the program. The governing board or the executive committee may meet at any time or place for the purpose of receiving and considering an application. Any and all determinations of the governing board or executive committee, with respect to an application, together with the reasons therefor shall be recorded and subscribed in such manner as to show and preserve the votes of the individual members thereof.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">A requesting state which is dissatisfied with a determination of the executive committee shall upon notice in writing given within 20 days of the determination with which it is dissatisfied, be entitled to receive a review thereof at the next meeting of the governing board. Determinations of the executive committee shall be reviewable only by the governing board at one of its regular meetings, or at a special meeting held in such manner as the governing board may authorize.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">Responding states required to undertake or increase measures pursuant to this compact may receive moneys from the Insurance Fund, either at the time or times when such state incurs expenditures on account of such measures, or as reimbursement for expenses incurred and chargeable to the Insurance Fund. The governing board shall adopt and, from time to time, may amend or revise procedures for submission of claims upon it and for payment thereof.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">Before authorizing the expenditure of moneys from the Insurance Fund pursuant to an application of a requesting state, the Insurance Fund shall ascertain the extent and nature of any timely assistance or participation which may be available from the federal government and shall request the appropriate agency or agencies of the federal government for such assistance and participation.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">The Insurance Fund may negotiate and execute a memorandum of understanding or other appropriate instrument defining the extent and degree of assistance or participation between and among the Insurance Fund, cooperating federal agencies, states and any other entities concerned.</section>
  </text>
</law>
