<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gag" order_by="gag" level="1">Agriculture</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gag-9.5-202</section_number>
  <catch_line>The Committee consists of the following members:...</catch_line>
  <order_by>202</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Committee consists of the following members:<section prefix="(1)">As ex officio members:<section prefix="(i)">The Secretary, or the Secretary's designee;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The Secretary of Natural Resources, or the Secretary's designee;</section><section prefix="(iii)">The Secretary of Transportation, or the Secretary's designee;</section><section prefix="(iv)">The Secretary of the Environment, or the Secretary's designee; and</section><section prefix="(v)">The Dean of the College of Agriculture and Natural Resources at the University of Maryland, College Park, or the Dean's designee; and</section></section><section prefix="(2)">Appointed by the Secretary:<section prefix="(i)">In consultation with the Secretary of Natural Resources:<section prefix="1.">One individual from a landscaping industry that is regulated by the Department;</section><section prefix="2.">One individual from a plant wholesale industry or a plant retail industry that is regulated by the Department; and</section><section prefix="3.">One individual from a nongovernmental environmental advocacy organization;</section></section><section prefix="(ii)">Two individuals with experience with invasive plants, agriculture, horticulture, gardening, conservation, or other relevant experience; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">One consumer member.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The term of an appointed member is 3 years and begins on January 1.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">An appointed member may not serve more than two consecutive terms.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">An appointed member shall serve at the pleasure of the Secretary.</section>
  </text>
</law>
