<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gag" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="2-1002" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gag-2-1002</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Young Farmers Advisory Board shall consist of 12 members appointed by the Governor.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Of the 12 members:<section prefix="(1)">One shall be from the Department of Agriculture;</section><section prefix="(2)">One shall be from the Department of Business and Economic Development;</section><section prefix="(3)">One shall be from the Forestry Program within the Department of Natural Resources;</section><section prefix="(4)">One shall be from the Maryland Farm Bureau; and</section><section prefix="(5)">Eight shall be appointed from the general public.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">To the extent practicable, the Governor shall attempt to ensure regional diversity among the members of the Advisory Board appointed from the general public.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Each member from the general public shall:<section prefix="(1)">Be interested in the preservation and development of agriculture and preservation of the agricultural way of life in Maryland;</section><section prefix="(2)">Be under the age of 45 years at the beginning of the member's term;</section><section prefix="(3)">Derive at least 50% of the member's personal income from farming or agricultural activities in the State; and</section><section prefix="(4)">Be a resident of the State.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except for the initial terms of the Advisory Board, the term of a member shall be 3 years.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The terms of members are staggered as required by the terms provided for members of the Advisory Board on October 1, 2004.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The terms of the initial members shall be staggered evenly between 2 years and 3 years as the Advisory Board shall determine at the Board's first meeting.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
