<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gag" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="2-503" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gag-2-503</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Maryland Agricultural Land Preservation Foundation shall be governed and administered by a board of trustees composed of the State Treasurer, who shall serve as an ex officio member, the Comptroller, who shall serve as an ex officio member, the Secretary of Planning, who shall serve as an ex officio member, and the Secretary who shall serve as an ex officio member, and nine members from the State at-large to be appointed by the Governor, at least six of whom shall be farmer representatives from different areas of the State. The State Treasurer may appoint, as the Treasurer's designee, a deputy treasurer to serve on the board of trustees. The Secretary of Planning may appoint as the Secretary's designee an individual within the Department of Planning. All of the farmer representatives shall be actively engaged in or retired from active farming. Four of the six farmer representatives shall be appointed as follows:<section prefix="(i)">One from a list of three nominees submitted by the Maryland Agricultural Commission;</section><section prefix="(ii)">One from a list of three nominees submitted by the Maryland Farm Bureau;</section><section prefix="(iii)">One from a list of three nominees submitted by the Maryland State Grange; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">One from a list of three nominees submitted by the Young Farmers Advisory Board.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Nominees under paragraph (1)(iv) of this subsection shall meet the requirements of &#xA7; 2-1002(d) of this title.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Governor shall appoint the chairman of the board, from among the nine at-large trustees. A majority of the members of the board serving at any one time constitutes a quorum for the transaction of business.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">Notwithstanding the provisions of &#xA7;&#xA7; 15-502 through 15-504 of the State Government Article, a person may be appointed to and serve on the board as an at-large member even if prior to the appointment the person sold an easement in the person's agricultural land to the Foundation.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The term of any trustee at-large serving on the board shall expire on July 1, 1977. The Governor then shall appoint trustees at-large for the following terms:<section prefix="(i)">Three for a term of four years;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Three for a term of three years; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Three for a term of two years.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">In appointing members at-large to replace members whose terms expire on July 1, 1977, the Governor may appoint members serving as of July 1, 1977. Thereafter, successors to trustees at-large whose terms expire shall be appointed for terms of four years. Vacancies shall be filled for the unexpired term. A trustee at-large may not serve more than two successive terms. Appointment to fill a vacancy may not be considered as one of two terms.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Trustees at-large shall take the oath of office as prescribed by law.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Compensation may not be paid to any trustee. Each trustee shall be reimbursed for travel and other expenses incurred by him in the performance of his duties on behalf of the Foundation.</section>
  </text>
</law>
