<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gag" order_by="" level="1">Agriculture</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gag-2-301</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>301</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Board" means the State Board of Veterinary Medical Examiners.</section>
    <section prefix="(b-1)">"Convicted" includes:<section prefix="(1)">A finding of guilt by a court or a jury; and</section><section prefix="(2)">The acceptance by a court of a defendant's plea of guilty, nolo contendere, or Alford plea.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Direct supervision" means that a veterinarian licensed and registered in the State is in the immediate vicinity where veterinary medicine is being performed and is actively engaged in the supervision of the practice of veterinary medicine.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">"License" means a license to practice veterinary medicine in the State.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"Member" means a member of the State Board of Veterinary Medical Examiners.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">"Practice of veterinary medicine" includes, but is not limited to, the practice by any person who:<section prefix="(1)">Diagnoses, advises, prescribes, or administers a drug, medicine, biological product, appliance, application, or treatment of any nature, for the prevention, cure, or relief of a wound, fracture, bodily injury, or disease of an animal;</section><section prefix="(2)">Performs a surgical operation, including cosmetic surgery, upon any animal;</section><section prefix="(3)">Performs dentistry on any animal;</section><section prefix="(4)">Performs any manual procedure upon an animal for the diagnosis or treatment of sterility or infertility of the animal;</section><section prefix="(5)">Represents himself as engaged in the practice of veterinary medicine;</section><section prefix="(6)">Offers, undertakes, or holds himself out as being able to diagnose, treat, operate, vaccinate, or prescribe for any animal disease, pain, injury, deformity, or physical condition; or</section><section prefix="(7)">Uses any words, letters, or titles in connection or under circumstances as to induce the belief that the person using them is engaged in the practice of veterinary medicine. This use is prima facie evidence of the intention to represent himself as engaged in the practice of veterinary medicine.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(g)">The term "practice of veterinary medicine" does not include or apply to:<section prefix="(1)">Any person practicing veterinary medicine in the performance of civil or military official duties in the service of the United States or of the State;</section><section prefix="(2)">Experimentation and scientific research of biological chemists or technicians engaged in the study and development of methods and techniques, directly or indirectly related or applicable to the problems of the practice of veterinary medicine;</section><section prefix="(3)">A person who advises with respect to or performs acts which the Board, by rule or regulation, has prescribed as accepted management practices in connection with livestock production;</section><section prefix="(4)">A physician licensed to practice medicine in the State or to his assistant while engaged in educational research;</section><section prefix="(5)">A person administering to the ills and injuries of his own animals if they otherwise comply with all laws, rules and regulations relative to the use of medicines and biologics;</section><section prefix="(6)">A farrier or a person actively engaged in the art or profession of horseshoeing as long as his actions are limited to the art of horseshoeing or trimming and maintaining horse hooves;</section><section prefix="(7)">Any nurse, attendant, technician, intern, or other employee of a licensed and registered veterinarian when administering medication or rendering auxiliary or supporting assistance under the responsible direct supervision of a licensed and registered veterinarian;</section><section prefix="(8)">A person who floats (files) equine teeth or removes caps;</section><section prefix="(9)">A person who scales or cleans animal teeth;</section><section prefix="(10)">A registered veterinary technician when performing a procedure under the responsible direct supervision of a veterinary practitioner as provided by regulations adopted by the Board;</section><section prefix="(11)">A person practicing acupuncture in accordance with the principles of oriental medical theories if the person:<section prefix="(i)">Is licensed under Title 1A of the Health Occupations Article;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Is certified as an animal acupuncturist by the Board of Acupuncture;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Practices only acupuncture, acupressure, and moxibustion;</section><section prefix="(iv)">Cooperates and consults with a veterinary practitioner by:<section prefix="1.">Beginning acupuncture treatment on an animal only if the animal has been seen by a veterinary practitioner within the previous 14 days;</section><section prefix="2.">Adhering to the terms and conditions of treatment decided by the veterinary practitioner, including the degree of communication and collaboration between the veterinary practitioner and the person practicing acupuncture;</section><section prefix="3.">Reporting to the veterinary practitioner at the end of treatment or at monthly intervals, at the discretion of the veterinary practitioner; and</section><section prefix="4.">Not working on an animal for which the person has not been appropriately trained, in accordance with regulations adopted by the Board of Acupuncture; and</section></section><section prefix="(v)">Has successfully completed a specialty training program in animal acupuncture that:<section prefix="1.">Is approved by the Board of Acupuncture;</section><section prefix="2.">Is offered by a school holding nationally recognized accreditation;</section><section prefix="3.">Consists of at least 135 hours; and</section><section prefix="4.">Enables the person to:</section></section></section><section prefix="(12)">A veterinarian licensed in another jurisdiction while consulting with a veterinary practitioner in this State; or</section><section prefix="(13)">A student of veterinary medicine practicing veterinary medicine who has successfully completed 3 years of veterinary education at an institution approved by the Board and who works under the responsible direct supervision, as defined by the Board, of a veterinary practitioner.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(h)">"Veterinarian" means any person who is a graduate of a college of veterinary medicine.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">"Veterinary practitioner" means a licensed and registered veterinarian engaged in the practice of veterinary medicine.</section>
    <section prefix="(j)">"Veterinary technician" means a person who is registered with the Board as a veterinary technician.</section>
  </text>
</law>
