<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gag" order_by="gag" level="1">Agriculture</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gag-11-401</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated....</catch_line>
  <order_by>401</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Calibrate" means to determine the value of, to mark correctly, and, when appropriate, to correct elements of an indicating system or other device on a milk tank.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Cooperative" means a corporation or association as defined in the Corporations and Associations Article. A cooperative is a producer and a purchaser within the provisions of this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Hauler" means any person who owns, leases or otherwise uses one or more mobile receiving stations and is engaged in transporting milk or other fluid dairy products.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Hauler" includes any cooperative engaged in the activity of a hauler.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Hauler" does not include:<section prefix="(i)">Any agent or employee of the owner, lessee, or other user; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">Any person receiving the transportation services of a mobile receiving station through its owner, lessee, or other user.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"Milk or other fluid dairy products" means the lacteal secretion obtained from a cow and any fluid component of the secretion, before any processing or manufacturing other than cream separation processing.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">"Producer" means any person who owns, controls, or operates a dairy herd for the production of milk or other fluid dairy products to be sold or offered for sale.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">"Purchaser" means the person who pays the producer or cooperative representing any producer for milk or other fluid dairy products.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">"Sample" means the portion of a person's shipment that may be used for an analysis of milk components that affects payment for the milk or other fluid dairy products.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Test" means an official procedure, approved by the Association of Official Analytical Chemists or American Public Health Association as published in the latest edition of its official publication and adopted by the Secretary, which is used to determine the amount of any milk components in any sample of milk or other fluid dairy products that affects payment for the milk or other fluid dairy products.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Test" includes the results of the analysis.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
