<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gag" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="8-804" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gag-8-804</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Department shall establish a Nutrient Management Advisory Committee. The Secretary shall appoint to the Committee representatives of the agricultural community, the environmental community, the commercial lawn care, biosolids, and agricultural fertilizer industries, academia, and appropriate government units. The Secretary also shall appoint to the Committee a representative of county government from a list submitted by the Maryland Association of Counties. The President of the Senate of Maryland shall appoint to the Committee one Senator and the Speaker of the House of Delegates shall appoint to the Committee one Delegate.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The Nutrient Management Advisory Committee shall report to the Governor and the General Assembly, in accordance with &#xA7; 2-1246 of the State Government Article, by July 1 of each year on the implementation of the requirements of the Water Quality Improvement Act of 1998.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The report required under subparagraph (i) of this paragraph shall include information regarding:</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">In consultation with the Nutrient Management Advisory Committee, the Department shall by regulation:<section prefix="(1)">Prescribe the criteria, form, and content for certified nutrient management plans applicable to licensees and certificate holders;</section><section prefix="(2)">Establish continuing education requirements for certified nutrient management consultants and persons receiving vouchers of completion under &#xA7; 8-803.3 of this subtitle; and</section><section prefix="(3)">Adopt guidelines and requirements for licensees and certified nutrient management consultants on record keeping and on reporting requirements to the Department on nutrient management plans.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
