<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gag" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="6-209" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gag-6-209</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Each person who registers any commercial fertilizer or soil conditioner in the State shall furnish the Secretary with a semiannual written statement of the tonnage of each grade of commercial fertilizer or each soil conditioner distributed in the State. This statement shall include every sale for the periods of January 1 through June 30 and July 1 through December 31 of each year.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">If the tonnage report is not filed and the inspection fee is not paid within 31 days after the end of the semiannual period, a collection fee amounting to 10 percent of the amount, or a minimum of $10, shall be assessed against the registrant. The amount of fees due constitute a debt and may become the basis of a judgment against the registrant.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Any person who distributes any commercial fertilizer or soil conditioner shall keep records necessary or required by the Secretary to indicate accurately the tonnage of commercial fertilizer and soil conditioner distributed in the State. The Secretary has the right to examine the records to verify any statement of tonnage.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Each registrant distributing or selling commercial fertilizer to a nonregistrant shall mail to the Secretary within ten days, excluding legal holidays and Sundays, after the last day of each month a statement showing the following information for that month: (1) the total tons of commercial fertilizer distributed by grades and analyses, (2) the counties to which it was distributed, and (3) the form in which the commercial fertilizer was shipped, such as, bags, bulk, or liquid. If more than one person is involved in the distribution of commercial fertilizer, the last registrant who distributes to a nonregistrant, whether a dealer or consumer, is responsible for reporting tonnage, unless a prior distributor has reported.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">This section does not require the disclosure of the name of the consignee or the sale price of the commercial fertilizer or any aspect of the operations of any person other than as specifically required. No information furnished pursuant to this section shall be disclosed in a way so as to divulge the operation of any person.</section>
  </text>
</law>
