<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gag" order_by="gag" level="1">Agriculture</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gag-2-505</section_number>
  <catch_line>The Maryland Agricultural Land Preservation Fund is created and continued for the purposes specified...</catch_line>
  <order_by>505</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Maryland Agricultural Land Preservation Fund is created and continued for the purposes specified in this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Maryland Agricultural Land Preservation Fund shall comprise:<section prefix="(1)">Any money made available to the Fund by general or special fund appropriations; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Any money made available to the Fund by grants or transfers from governmental or private sources.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Comptroller of the Treasury may not disburse any money from the Maryland Agricultural Land Preservation Fund other than:<section prefix="(i)">For costs associated with the staffing and administration of the Maryland Agricultural Land Preservation Foundation;</section><section prefix="(ii)">For reasonable expenses incurred by the members of the board of trustees of the Maryland Agricultural Land Preservation Foundation in the performance of official duties;</section><section prefix="(iii)">For consideration in the purchase of agricultural land preservation easements beginning with fiscal year 1979 and each fiscal year thereafter; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">For costs associated with acquisition of agricultural land preservation easements approved by the Foundation through the Critical Farms Program, as provided in &#xA7; 2-517 of this subtitle.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Maryland Agricultural Land Preservation Foundation may provide grants to the Maryland Agricultural and Resource-Based Industry Development Corporation, subject to conditions jointly agreed upon by the Foundation and the Corporation, to facilitate:<section prefix="(i)">An installment purchase agreement program; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">The funding of the Next Generation Farmland Acquisition Program.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Maryland Agricultural Land Preservation Foundation may provide grants to counties to facilitate:<section prefix="(i)">The Critical Farms Program, as provided in &#xA7; 2-517 of this subtitle, subject to conditions jointly agreed upon by the Foundation and the county;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The purchase of easements under a county installment purchase agreement program approved by the Foundation, as provided in &#xA7; 2-510.1 of this subtitle; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">The payment of the principal of and interest on bonds issued by a county for the sole purpose of purchasing agricultural land preservation easements that meet the requirements of this subtitle, subject to conditions jointly agreed upon by the Foundation and the county.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">Grants provided by the Maryland Agricultural Land Preservation Foundation may not be:<section prefix="(i)">Used to fund county land preservation programs; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">Pledged to secure county-issued bonds.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Any money remaining in the Fund at the end of a fiscal year may not revert to the general funds of the State, but shall remain in the Maryland Agricultural Land Preservation Fund to be used for the purposes specified in this subtitle. It is the intent of the General Assembly that, to the extent feasible, the Foundation utilize the full amount of money available for the purchase of easements in any fiscal year so as to minimize the amount of money remaining in the Fund at the end of any fiscal year.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">If a portion of a local subdivision's allocation of Program Open Space funds is transferred to the Maryland Agricultural Land Preservation Fund pursuant to the provisions of &#xA7; 5-903 of the Natural Resources Article, the Foundation may utilize such transferred funds only for purchases of easements on land located within the boundaries of the subdivision which requested the transfer of funds. Such transferred open space funds shall be available in addition to any funds which would otherwise be allotted under this subtitle for purchases of easements in the county which requested the transfer of funds; and at the discretion of the local governing body, such transferred open space funds may be used for general purchases, or applied as the local contribution in matching purchases as required in &#xA7;&#xA7; 2-508(a)(3) and 2-512(b)(1) of this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">Money in the Fund from the sale of tax-exempt general obligation bonds may not be used:<section prefix="(1)">To purchase easements under:<section prefix="(i)">An installment purchase agreement, as provided in &#xA7; 2-510(k)(3) of this subtitle;</section><section prefix="(ii)">A schedule of installments financed with certificates of deposit, as provided in &#xA7; 2-510(k)(2) of this subtitle; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">The Critical Farms Program, as provided in &#xA7; 2-517 of this subtitle; or</section></section><section prefix="(2)">For the payment of the principal of and interest on bonds issued by a county in accordance with subsection (c) of this section.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(g)">The estimated budget of the Foundation for the next fiscal year shall be included with the budget of the Department.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">The Fund shall be audited annually by the Legislative Auditor in the manner prescribed by law.</section>
  </text>
</law>
