<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gag" order_by="gag" level="1">Agriculture</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gag-5-505</section_number>
  <catch_line>A person may not ship or transport into this State any colony or used bee equipment that is not acco...</catch_line>
  <order_by>505</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">A person may not ship or transport into this State any colony or used bee equipment that is not accompanied by the following documents:<section prefix="(1)">An entry permit, issued by the Department; and</section><section prefix="(2)">A valid inspection certificate that:<section prefix="(i)">Has been issued by an authorized apiary inspector of the state of origin; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">States that the colony or equipment is disease free based on an inspection by that inspector within a time period as determined by the Department.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Before a person may ship or transport into this State any colony or used bee equipment, the person shall request an entry permit by submitting to the Department:<section prefix="(1)">An inspection certificate from the state of origin;</section><section prefix="(2)">The name, address, and state of residence of the shipper;</section><section prefix="(3)">The person to whom and destination to which the colony or bee equipment is to be shipped;</section><section prefix="(4)">The number of hives that contain bees;</section><section prefix="(5)">The type and quantity of bee equipment contained in the shipment;</section><section prefix="(6)">The date of the last official inspection of the apiary and bee equipment;</section><section prefix="(7)">The total number of colonies in the apiary inspected;</section><section prefix="(8)">The number of infected colonies, if any, that were found in the apiary on that last inspection; and</section><section prefix="(9)">The number of these infected colonies that were destroyed.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Without the prior written permission of the Department, a person may not transport into this State from outside of the United States a bee that belongs to the genus apis, used bee equipment, or a used appliance.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A person may not ship or transport into this State any queen bee or packaged bee unless it is accompanied by a valid certificate that:<section prefix="(1)">Was issued by an authorized apiary inspector of the state of origin; and</section><section prefix="(2)">States that the bee is from a disease free colony.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">A person, who receives a delivery of a colony or bee that was transported into this State without the documents required under this subtitle, immediately shall give to the Department notice of the delivery.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Any colony or bee that is transported into this State and that is not accompanied by the documents required under this subtitle shall be restricted to an area that the Department designates and may not be moved.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Department shall give the owner notice that unless the colony or bee is removed from the State within 24 hours, it may be destroyed by the Department at the expense of the owner.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Department may destroy at the expense of the owner any bee or colony that is not removed from this State within 24 hours after notice is given under this subsection.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">A transportation company or common carrier shall have the immunity from liability described under &#xA7; 5-415 of the Courts and Judicial Proceedings Article.</section>
  </text>
</law>
