<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gag" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="2-504.1" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gag-2-504.1</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In each county containing productive agricultural land, the county governing body shall appoint an agricultural preservation advisory board.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in paragraphs (2) and (3) of this subsection, the agricultural preservation advisory board shall consist of five members, at least three of whom shall be owner-operators of commercial farms who earn 50 percent or more of their income from farming.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">In Worcester County, the agricultural preservation advisory board shall consist of seven members, at least four of whom shall be owner-operators of commercial farms who earn 50 percent or more of their income from farming.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">In St. Mary's County, the agricultural preservation advisory board shall consist of five members, at least three of whom shall be actively pursuing the production of agricultural products for profit.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, each member of an agricultural preservation advisory board shall be appointed for a term of office of five years.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">In Charles County and in Worcester County, a member shall serve a term of office of 4 years.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">No member shall serve for more than two consecutive full terms.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">Appointment to fill a vacancy shall be for the remainder of the unexpired term.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Duties of each agricultural preservation advisory board shall be:<section prefix="(1)">To advise the county governing body with respect to the establishment of agricultural districts and the approval of purchases of easements by the Foundation within the county;</section><section prefix="(2)">To assist the county governing body in reviewing the status of agricultural districts and land under easement;</section><section prefix="(3)">To advise the Foundation concerning county priorities for agricultural preservation;</section><section prefix="(4)">To approve or disapprove an application by the county for certification under &#xA7; 5-408 of the State Finance and Procurement Article;</section><section prefix="(5)">To promote preservation of agriculture within the county by offering information and assistance to farmers with respect to establishment of districts and purchase of easements;</section><section prefix="(6)">To meet at least annually with forest conservation district boards in order to work cooperatively to encourage the promotion and retention of farmland and woodland in their respective jurisdictions; and</section><section prefix="(7)">To perform any other duties as assigned by the county governing body.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
