<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gag" order_by="" level="1">Agriculture</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gag-10-1905</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>1905</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">A person may designate a food product as "honey" if the product conforms to the Maryland standard of identity for honey set forth in &#xA7; 10-1904 of this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">If a food product contains any flavoring, spice, or other ingredient in addition to honey, the name of the product shall distinguish the product from pure honey and designate the food additive.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">If processing materially changes the flavor, color, viscosity, or other material characteristic of pure honey, the name of the product shall distinguish the product from pure honey and designate the modification.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">For blossom or nectar honey, the name of the food may be supplemented by the term "blossom" or "nectar".</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">For honeydew honey, the word "honeydew" may be placed in close proximity to the name of the food.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">For mixtures of blossom or nectar honey with honeydew honey, the name of the food may be supplemented with the words "a blend of honeydew honey with blossom honey" or "a blend of honeydew honey with nectar honey".</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Honey may be designated by the name of a geographical or topographical region if the honey was produced exclusively within the area referred to in the designation.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">When honey has been designated by the name of a geographical or topographical region, the name of the country where the honey has been produced shall be declared on the label.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(h)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Honey may be designated according to a floral or plant source if it comes wholly or mainly from that particular source and has the organoleptic, physicochemical, and microscopic properties corresponding with that origin.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">When honey has been designated according to a floral or plant source:<section prefix="(i)">The common name or the botanical name of the floral source shall be in close proximity to the word "honey"; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">The name of the country where the honey has been produced shall be declared on the label.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(i)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Honey may be designated according to the following methods of removal from the comb:<section prefix="(i)">"Extracted honey" is honey obtained by centrifuging decapped broodless combs;</section><section prefix="(ii)">"Pressed honey" is honey obtained by pressing broodless combs; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">"Drained honey" is honey obtained by draining decapped broodless combs.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The designations in paragraph (1) of this subsection may not be used unless the honey conforms to the applicable description.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(j)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Honey may be designated according to the following styles:<section prefix="(i)">"Honey" that is honey in liquid, crystalline state, or a mixture of the two;</section><section prefix="(ii)">"Comb honey" that is honey stored by bees in the cells of freshly built broodless combs and that is sold in sealed whole combs or sections of such combs; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">"Cut comb in honey", "honey with comb", or "chunk honey" that is honey containing one or more pieces of comb honey.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The styles designated in paragraph (1)(ii) and (iii) of this subsection shall be declared on the label.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
