<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gag" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="2-1501" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gag-2-1501</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">"Authorized equipment" means any equipment necessary for the management of forest land.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">"Authorized equipment" includes:</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Fund" means the Emerald Ash Borer Grant Fund.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">There is an Emerald Ash Borer Grant Fund.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The purpose of the Fund is to provide grants to local governments, businesses, and organizations to finance purchases of authorized equipment to remove, dispose of, and replace trees infested by the emerald ash borer:<section prefix="(1)">That are located within emerald ash borer quarantine areas; and</section><section prefix="(2)">In accordance with any applicable State or federal law, regulation, or quarantine.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Secretary shall administer the Fund.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">At the end of each fiscal year, any unspent or unencumbered balance in the Fund shall revert to the General Fund in accordance with &#xA7; 7-302 of the State Finance and Procurement Article.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The State Treasurer shall hold the Fund separately and the Comptroller shall account for the Fund.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The Fund consists of:<section prefix="(1)">Money appropriated in the State budget to the Fund;</section><section prefix="(2)">Any investment earnings of the Fund; and</section><section prefix="(3)">Any other money from any other source accepted for the benefit of the Fund.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Fund may be used only to provide grants in accordance with subsection (c) of this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A grant provided in accordance with this section may not exceed the amount that the local government, business, or organization has appropriated to finance purchases of equipment to remove, dispose of, and replace infested trees located in areas designated under subsection (c) of this section.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(h)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The State Treasurer shall invest the money of the Fund in the same manner as other State money may be invested.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Any investment earnings of the Fund shall be credited to the Fund.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(i)">The Secretary shall establish procedures for a person to apply for a grant from the Fund.</section>
  </text>
</law>
