<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gag" order_by="gag" level="1">Agriculture</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gag-4-220</section_number>
  <catch_line>Any poultry product, or any dead, dying, disabled, or diseased poultry, that is transported in intra...</catch_line>
  <order_by>220</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Any poultry product, or any dead, dying, disabled, or diseased poultry, that is transported in intrastate commerce or is held for sale, or donation in the State after transportation, and that (1) is or has been processed, sold, transported, or otherwise distributed or offered or received for distribution in violation of this subtitle; (2) is capable of use as human food and is adulterated or misbranded; or (3) in any other way violates this subtitle, shall be liable to be proceeded against, seized, and condemned, at any time, on a libel of information in any circuit court of any county within whose jurisdiction the article is found.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">If poultry or poultry products are condemned because of disease, the reason for condemnation shall be supported by scientific fact, information, or criteria. Condemnation under this subtitle shall be achieved through uniform inspection standards and uniform application.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Upon condemnation and after entry of the decree, the article shall be destroyed or sold as the court directs and, if sold, the proceeds, less the court costs, fees, storage, and other proper expenses, shall be paid into the State Treasury. The article may not be sold contrary to the provisions of this subtitle, or federal law.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Upon execution and delivery of a good and sufficient bond prohibiting the sale or any other disposal of the article contrary to this subtitle or federal law, the court may direct that the article be delivered to the owner subject to the supervision of the Secretary to insure compliance with the applicable laws.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">When a decree of condemnation is entered against the article and it is released under bond or destroyed, court costs, fees, storage, and other proper expenses shall be awarded against the person intervening as claimant of the article.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">Proceedings in libel cases shall conform to proceedings in admiralty to the extent possible. However, either party may demand a jury trial of any issue of fact joined in any case. Every proceeding shall be at the suit of and in the name of the State.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">This section does not derogate from authority for condemnation or seizure conferred by other provisions of this subtitle or other laws.</section>
  </text>
</law>
