<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gag" order_by="" level="1">Agriculture</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gag-8-803.4</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>803.4</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, "fertilizer" means a commercial fertilizer and specialty fertilizer.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This section applies to a professional fertilizer applicator who applies fertilizer to:<section prefix="(i)">Property that is not used for agricultural purposes; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">State property that is not used for agricultural purposes.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">This section does not apply to the application of fertilizer on commercial farms.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A professional fertilizer applicator may not:<section prefix="(1)">Apply fertilizer to turf without first obtaining a fertilizer application certification, unless the person is under the direct supervision of a certified professional fertilizer applicator, in accordance with &#xA7; 8-803.6 of this subtitle; or</section><section prefix="(2)">Apply fertilizer intended for use on turf on an impervious surface.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, a professional fertilizer applicator may not apply fertilizer containing phosphorus or nitrogen to turf:<section prefix="(i)">Before March 1 or after November 15 of any calendar year;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Any time the ground is frozen; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">In an amount that is inconsistent with the annual recommended rate established by the University of Maryland.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">From November 16 through December 1 of each calendar year, a professional fertilizer applicator may apply water-soluble nitrogen to turf at an application rate of no more than 0.5 pounds per 1,000 square feet of water-soluble nitrogen.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, a professional fertilizer applicator may not apply fertilizer containing phosphorus or nitrogen to turf that is within 15 feet of waters of the State.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">When a drop spreader, rotary spreader with a deflector, or targeted spray liquid is used for fertilizer application, the setback required under paragraph (1) of this subsection may be reduced to 10 feet.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The establishment of setbacks for fertilizer application under this subsection does not preclude the establishment or applicability of, or compliance with, any other environmental standards established under any other State or federal law, rule, or regulation.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, a professional fertilizer applicator may not apply fertilizer containing nitrogen to turf:<section prefix="(i)">At an application rate of more than 0.7 pounds per 1,000 feet of water-soluble nitrogen; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">At an application rate of more than 0.9 pounds per 1,000 square feet of total nitrogen.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Subject to subparagraphs (ii) and (iii) of this paragraph, a professional fertilizer applicator may apply an enhanced efficiency fertilizer:<section prefix="1.">At an annual application rate of no more than 2.5 pounds per 1,000 square feet of nitrogen; and</section><section prefix="2.">That has a release rate of no more than 0.7 pounds per 1,000 square feet of total nitrogen per month.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The annual total application rate of an enhanced efficiency fertilizer may not exceed 80% of the annual recommended rate for total nitrogen established by the University of Maryland.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">An enhanced efficiency fertilizer may not be applied after November 15 or before March 1 of each calendar year.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in paragraphs (2) and (4) of this subsection, a professional fertilizer applicator may not apply fertilizer containing phosphorus to turf.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A professional fertilizer applicator may apply organic or natural organic fertilizer containing phosphorus to turf when:<section prefix="(i)"><section prefix="1.">A soil test performed no more than 3 years before the fertilizer application indicates a low or medium level of phosphorus; and</section><section prefix="2.">The fertilizer is applied at a rate recommended by the University of Maryland; and</section></section><section prefix="(ii)"><section prefix="1.">Beginning October 1, 2013, a soil test performed no more than 3 years before the fertilizer application indicates a low or medium level of phosphorus; and</section><section prefix="2.">A low phosphorus fertilizer, as defined under &#xA7; 6-201 of this article, that is an organic or natural organic fertilizer is applied at a rate recommended by the University of Maryland.</section></section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Paragraph (2) of this subsection does not authorize a professional fertilizer applicator to apply fertilizer containing phosphorus when a soil test indicates an optimum or excessive level of phosphorus.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">A professional fertilizer applicator may apply fertilizer to turf containing phosphorus if the professional fertilizer applicator:<section prefix="(i)">Determines that the fertilizer is necessary for the specific soils and target vegetation in accordance with a soil test performed no more than 3 years before the fertilizer application, provided the application complies with the recommendations established by the University of Maryland;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Is establishing vegetation for the first time, such as after land disturbance, provided the application complies with the recommendations established by the University of Maryland; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">Is reestablishing or repairing a turf area.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(h)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A person who violates any provision of this section is subject to a civil penalty of not more than $1,000 for a first violation.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A person who violates any provision of this section is subject to a civil penalty of not more than $2,000 for each subsequent violation.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Each day a violation occurs under this section is a separate violation.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The total penalties imposed on a person for violations of this section that result from the same set of facts and circumstances may not exceed $10,000.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(i)">The penalty imposed on a person under this section shall be assessed with consideration given to:<section prefix="(1)">The willfulness of the violation, the extent to which the existence of the violation was known to the violator but uncorrected by the violator, and the extent to which the violator exercised reasonable care;</section><section prefix="(2)">Any actual harm to human health or to the environment including injury to or impairment of the use of the waters of the State or the natural resources of the State;</section><section prefix="(3)">The cost of control;</section><section prefix="(4)">The nature and degree of injury to or interference with general welfare, health, and property;</section><section prefix="(5)">The extent to which the location of the violation, including location near areas of human population, creates the potential for harm to the environment or to human health or safety; and</section><section prefix="(6)">The extent to which the current violation is part of a recurrent pattern of the same or similar type of violation committed by the violator.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(j)">Penalties collected by the Secretary under this section shall be paid into the General Fund of the State.</section>
    <section prefix="(k)">The Department may adopt regulations to implement this section.</section>
  </text>
</law>
