<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gag" order_by="" level="1">Agriculture</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gag-5-705</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>705</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In each party state there shall be a compact administrator, who shall be selected and serve in such manner as the laws of his state may provide, and who shall:<section prefix="(1)">Assist in the coordination of activities pursuant to the compact in his state; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Represent his state on the governing board of the Insurance Fund.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">If the laws of the United States specifically so provide, or if administrative provision is made therefor within the federal government, the United States may be represented on the governing board of the Insurance Fund by not to exceed three representatives. Any such representative or representatives of the United States shall be appointed and serve in such manner as may be provided by or pursuant to federal law, but no such representatives shall have a vote on the governing board or on the executive committee thereof.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The governing board shall meet at least once each year for the purpose of determining policies and procedures in the administration of the Insurance Fund and, consistent with the provisions of the compact, supervising and giving direction to the expenditure of moneys from the Insurance Fund. Additional meetings of the governing board shall be held on call of the chairman, the executive committee, or a majority of the membership of the governing board.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">At such times as it may be meeting, the governing board shall pass upon applications for assistance from the Insurance Fund and authorize disbursements therefrom. When the governing board is not in session, the executive committee thereof shall act as agent of the governing board, with full authority to act for it in passing upon such applications.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The executive committee shall be composed of the chairman of the governing board and four additional members of the governing board chosen by it so that there shall be one member representing each of four geographic groupings of party states. The governing board shall make such geographic groupings. If there is representation of the United States on the governing board, one such representative may meet with the executive committee. The chairman of the governing board shall be chairman of the executive committee. No action of the executive committee shall be binding unless taken at a meeting at which at least four members of such committee are present and vote in favor thereof. Necessary expenses of each of the five members of the executive committee incurred in attending meetings of such committee, when not held at the same time and place as a meeting of the governing board, shall be charges against the Insurance Fund.</section>
  </text>
</law>
