<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gag" order_by="" level="1">Agriculture</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gag-6-224</section_number>
  <catch_line>** TAKES EFFECT OCTOBER 1, 2013 PER CHAPTERS 484 AND 485 OF 2011 **...</catch_line>
  <order_by>224</order_by>
  <text>** TAKES EFFECT OCTOBER 1, 2013 PER CHAPTERS 484 AND 485 OF 2011 **<section prefix="(a)">Except as provided in subsection (b) of this section, any specialty fertilizer labeled for use on turf may not:<section prefix="(1)">Result in an application of more than 0.7 pounds per 1,000 square feet of water-soluble nitrogen and no more than 0.9 pounds per 1,000 square feet of total nitrogen, at least 20% of which shall consist of slow-release nitrogen, when applied in accordance with the instructions on the container;</section><section prefix="(2)">Contain phosphorus, except:<section prefix="(i)">For organic and natural organic fertilizer sold to a professional fertilizer applicator; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">When specifically labeled for the following purposes:<section prefix="1.">Providing nutrients to specific soils and target vegetation as determined to be necessary in accordance with a soil test that was:</section><section prefix="2.">Establishing vegetation for the first time, such as after land disturbance, provided the application is conducted in accordance with the recommended application rates established by the State; or</section><section prefix="3.">Reestablishing or repairing a turf area; and</section></section></section><section prefix="(3)">Be labeled for use as a de-icer.</section></section><section prefix="(b)">An enhanced-efficiency fertilizer labeled for use on turf may not:<section prefix="(1)">Result in an annual application of more than 2.5 pounds per 1,000 square feet of total nitrogen;</section><section prefix="(2)">Result in an application of more than 80% of the annual recommended rate for total nitrogen established by the University of Maryland; or</section><section prefix="(3)">Have a release rate of more than 0.7 pounds per 1,000 square feet of total nitrogen per month.</section></section><section prefix="(c)">Except as provided in subsections (d) and (e) of this section, a person may not offer to sell specialty fertilizer for use on turf that:<section prefix="(1)">Results in an application of more than 0.7 pounds per 1,000 square feet of water-soluble nitrogen and no more than 0.9 pounds per 1,000 square feet of total nitrogen, at least 20% of which shall consist of slow-release nitrogen, when applied in accordance with the instructions on the container; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Contains phosphorus and is intended for use on turf unless the intended use of the fertilizer is:<section prefix="(i)">For application to specific soils and turf as determined to be necessary pursuant to a soil test conducted by a laboratory identified in &#xA7; 8-803.7 of this article and performed no more than 3 years before the application, provided the application complies with recommended application rates established by the University of Maryland;</section><section prefix="(ii)">For the establishment of turf for the first time, such as after land disturbance, provided the application complies with recommended application rates established by the University of Maryland; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">For the reestablishment or repair of a turf area.</section></section></section><section prefix="(d)">A person may offer to sell an organic or natural organic fertilizer containing phosphorus to a professional fertilizer applicator.</section><section prefix="(e)">A person may not offer to sell enhanced-efficiency fertilizer for use on turf that:<section prefix="(1)">Results in an annual application of more than 2.5 pounds per 1,000 square feet of total nitrogen;</section><section prefix="(2)">Results in an application of more than 80% of the annual recommended rate for total nitrogen established by the University of Maryland; or</section><section prefix="(3)">Has a release rate of more than 0.7 pounds per 1,000 square feet of total nitrogen per month.</section></section><section prefix="(f)">A person may not offer to sell a commercial or specialty fertilizer product for use as a de-icer.</section></text>
</law>
