<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gag" order_by="gag" level="1">Agriculture</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gag-11-208</section_number>
  <catch_line>A weight and measure, unless inspected and approved by the Secretary, may not be used or possessed f...</catch_line>
  <order_by>208</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">A weight and measure, unless inspected and approved by the Secretary, may not be used or possessed for current use for:<section prefix="(1)">Buying or selling any commodity or object;</section><section prefix="(2)">Hire or award;</section><section prefix="(3)">Computing any charge or payment for services rendered on the basis of weight and measurement; or</section><section prefix="(4)">Determining any weight and measure for a charge.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A person is not liable for a violation of subsection (a) of this section, if:<section prefix="(1)">The person gives written notice to the Secretary stating that the weight and measure is correct and is available for examination; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Specific written permission to use the weight and measure is received from the Secretary.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A person may not impersonate in any way the Secretary or use the Secretary's seal or a counterfeit of it in any manner. Any person who violates this subsection is guilty of a misdemeanor and, upon conviction, is subject to a fine not exceeding $1,000, or by imprisonment not exceeding one year, or both, with costs imposed in the discretion of the court.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A person, on the person's own behalf, or by a servant or agent, or as the servant or agent of another person, may not:<section prefix="(1)">Use, sell, offer or expose for sale or hire, or possess for the purpose of using, selling, or hiring an incorrect weight or measure or any device or instrument used to or calculated to falsify any weight or measure;</section><section prefix="(2)">Dispose of any rejected or condemned weight or measure in a manner contrary to law or regulation;</section><section prefix="(3)">Remove from any weight and measure, contrary to law or regulation, any tag, seal, or mark placed by the Secretary;</section><section prefix="(4)">Sell, or offer or expose for sale, less than the quantity the person represents of any commodity, object, or service;</section><section prefix="(5)">Take more than the quantity the person represents of any commodity, object, or service when, as buyer, the person furnishes the weight or measure by means of which the amount of the commodity, object, or service is determined;</section><section prefix="(6)">Keep for sale, or advertise, offer or expose for sale, or sell any commodity, object, or service in a condition or manner contrary to this article or regulation issued under it;</section><section prefix="(7)">Use in retail trade, except in the preparation of medical prescriptions or packages put up in advance of sale, a weight or measure which is not so positioned that its indications may be accurately read and the weighing or measuring operations observed from some position which reasonably may be assumed by a customer;</section><section prefix="(8)">Violate any provision of this title or of any regulation adopted under this title;</section><section prefix="(9)">Manipulate or in any manner render a weight or measure to a state calculated to deceive or defraud anyone; or</section><section prefix="(10)">Misrepresent a weight, measurement, or count affecting any purchase, sale, award, or amounts paid or charged for a service.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
