<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gag" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="5-210.2" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gag-5-210.2</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A person who violates any provision of this subtitle is subject to a civil penalty of not more than $2,500 for a first violation of this subtitle.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A person who violates any provision of this subtitle is subject to a civil penalty of not more than $5,000 for each subsequent violation of this subtitle.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Each day a violation under this subsection occurs is a separate violation.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">In addition to the denial, suspension, or revocation of the license, permit or certificate, the Secretary may impose a civil penalty on the holder of a license, permit, or certificate under paragraph (1) or (2) of this subsection for each violation of this subtitle.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">The total penalties imposed on a person for violations under this subtitle that result from the same set of facts and circumstances may not exceed $25,000.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The penalty imposed on a person under this section shall be assessed with consideration given to:<section prefix="(1)">The willfulness of the violation, the extent to which the existence of the violation was known to the violator but uncorrected by the violator, and the extent to which the violator exercised reasonable care;</section><section prefix="(2)">Any actual harm to human health or to the environment including injury to or impairment of the use of the waters of this State or the natural resources of this State;</section><section prefix="(3)">The cost of control;</section><section prefix="(4)">The nature and degree of injury to or interference with general welfare, health, and property;</section><section prefix="(5)">The extent to which the location of the violation, including location near areas of human population, creates the potential for harm to the environment or to human health or safety; and</section><section prefix="(6)">The extent to which the current violation is part of a recurrent pattern of the same or similar type of violation committed by the violator.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Penalties collected by the Secretary under this section shall be paid into the General Fund of the State.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Secretary shall establish such rules and regulations as are necessary to carry out the provisions of this section.</section>
  </text>
</law>
