<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gag" order_by="gag" level="1">Agriculture</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gag-2-517.1</section_number>
  <catch_line>The Foundation may establish a Farmland Preservation Partnership Program that is governed by the req...</catch_line>
  <order_by>517.1</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Foundation may establish a Farmland Preservation Partnership Program that is governed by the requirements of this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Farmland Preservation Partnership Program may include the acquisition of easements under the Critical Farms Program as provided under &#xA7; 2-517 of this subtitle.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The objective of the Partnership Program is to preserve productive agricultural and forested lands.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The Foundation may form partnerships for the purpose of purchasing easements on qualifying properties.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">Except for the Critical Farms Program where State funds may be made available as determined by the Foundation, the Foundation's partners shall cover the full purchase price, which may include the administrative costs of any easement for which the Foundation will be the grantee or the co-grantee.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">The properties that qualify for the Partnership Program shall meet the criteria developed by the Foundation in accordance with subsection (b) of this section.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Foundation shall develop criteria that determine when a farm qualifies for the Partnership Program.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">At a minimum, any qualifying farm shall:<section prefix="(i)">Meet the Foundation's size criteria;</section><section prefix="(ii)">As determined by the Foundation, contain significant productive agricultural soil or forest soil; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Be approved for participation in the Partnership Program by the governing body of the local jurisdiction in which the property is located.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Notwithstanding any other provision of this subtitle, an easement acquired by the Foundation in accordance with this section is not subject to the ranking, valuation, or development restrictions of this subtitle, except as determined by the Foundation's board of trustees.</section>
  </text>
</law>
