<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gag" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="3-105" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gag-3-105</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">To prevent the spread of contagious or infectious diseases, the Secretary, or his agent, may:<section prefix="(1)">Visit at any time the location in any county where he has reason to believe any contagious or infectious disease may exist;</section><section prefix="(2)">Test any animal for any contagious disease by any method;</section><section prefix="(3)">Order every animal which has been exposed to a contagious or infectious disease to be isolated in the manner he deems necessary to prevent the spread of the disease;</section><section prefix="(4)">Order any location where any contagious or infectious disease has existed or presently exists to be quarantined, so that no domestic animal of the same species may be removed from or brought to the quarantined premises until it is properly disinfected;</section><section prefix="(5)">Issue any order he deems necessary or expedient to prevent the communication of any infectious or contagious disease from the quarantined area;</section><section prefix="(6)">Issue an order requiring the destruction of any animal infected with or exposed to an infectious or contagious disease, and for the proper destruction of its hide or carcass, and any object which might carry infection or contagion;</section><section prefix="(7)">Issue an order requiring disinfection of every building, premises, vehicle, and every object which may breed or convey any infectious or contagious disease;</section><section prefix="(8)">Destroy any building or article that is contaminated and incapable of proper disinfection;</section><section prefix="(9)">Modify, cancel, or withdraw the terms of any order the Secretary issues pursuant to this subtitle; and</section><section prefix="(10)">Institute a livestock patrol along the State borders to prevent any livestock affected with any contagious or infectious disease from being brought into the State contrary to the laws regulating shipment of livestock into the State.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The owner or his agent shall secure the animal to make it possible for the Secretary or his agent to apply any test.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Secretary may order any sheriff, deputy sheriff, or other law enforcement officer of the State or of any county to provide information or assist in the execution or enforcement of any order of the Department.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">For the performance of duties imposed by this section, the sheriff, deputy sheriff, or other law enforcement officer shall be compensated on a basis of performance of similar duties under existing laws.</section>
  </text>
</law>
