<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gag" order_by="" level="1">Agriculture</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gag-3-118</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>118</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">A person may not willfully make a false statement to the Department as to:<section prefix="(1)">The identity of an animal;</section><section prefix="(2)">The location of an animal;</section><section prefix="(3)">The place of origin or destination of an animal; or</section><section prefix="(4)">The health status of an animal, including whether an animal is infected with or has been exposed to a contagious or infectious disease.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A person may not willfully provide false information on any report to the Department or provide false information to any person completing any animal health certificate, any laboratory report, or other document pertaining to the health status of any animal.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A person may not willfully alter any animal health certificate or report issued by a veterinarian, any laboratory, any agency of the State of Maryland or its political subdivisions, any agency of the United States or the several states, U.S. territories and the District of Columbia or any sovereign nation regarding the health of any animal entering, leaving, transiting, or residing in the State.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A person may not knowingly possess any altered animal health certificate or animal health report or present to any party as genuine, an altered or invalid animal health certificate or report regarding the health of any animal entering, leaving, transiting, or residing in the State.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">A person may not willfully alter, damage, use, or attempt to use, with the intention to deceive, any animal cargo seal device, an animal or premises identification number, an animal or premises identification device, or an animal or premises registration document used in any animal health program of the Department.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">A person may not knowingly make false statements or misrepresentations of fact to the Department in the application for any animal health program license, permit, registration, certification, diagnostic service, or an application for participation in any other animal health program of the Department.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">A person may not willfully alter any license, permit, registration, certificate, laboratory or other report, order, sign, or any other completed document issued by the Department for the purpose of regulating or promoting animal health.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">A person may not knowingly possess or present to any party as genuine, an altered or invalid license, permit, registration, certificate, laboratory or other report, order, or any other completed document issued by the Department for the purpose of regulating or promoting animal health.</section>
  </text>
</law>
