<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gag" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="2-203" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gag-2-203</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Commission has 30 members.  One member is ex officio and is the principal administrative official for agricultural affairs at the University System of Maryland as designated by the Chancellor of the University. The Governor appoints the remaining 29 members as follows:<section prefix="(1)">	Two from a list of at least four nominees representing the dairy industry;</section><section prefix="(2)">Two from a list of at least four nominees representing the poultry industry;</section><section prefix="(3)">One from a list of at least two nominees representing the livestock industry;</section><section prefix="(4)">One from a list of at least two nominees representing the tobacco industry;</section><section prefix="(5)">Two from a list of at least four nominees representing the nursery industry;</section><section prefix="(6)">One from a list of at least two nominees representing the horticulture industry;</section><section prefix="(7)">One from a list of at least two nominees representing the field crops industry;</section><section prefix="(8)">One from a list of at least two nominees representing the vegetable industry;</section><section prefix="(9)">One from a list of at least two nominees representing the veterinary profession;</section><section prefix="(10)">One from a list of at least two nominees of the Maryland State Grange;</section><section prefix="(11)">One from a list of at least two nominees of the Maryland Farm Bureau;</section><section prefix="(12)">Two without nomination appointed at large from services related to agriculture;</section><section prefix="(13)">One from a list of at least two nominees representing the turf industry;</section><section prefix="(14)">One from a list of at least two nominees representing the horse-breeding industry;</section><section prefix="(15)">	One from a list of at least two nominees representing the food processing industry;</section><section prefix="(16)">One without nomination appointed at large from the general public to be the consumer member;</section><section prefix="(17)">One from a list of at least two nominees representing the organic farming industry;</section><section prefix="(18)">One from a list of at least two nominees representing direct farm marketing;</section><section prefix="(19)">One from a list of at least two nominees representing viticulture;</section><section prefix="(20)">One from a list of at least two nominees representing agriculture education in primary or secondary schools;</section><section prefix="(21)">One from a list of at least two nominees representing agri-business;</section><section prefix="(22)">One from a list of at least two nominees representing the forestry industry;</section><section prefix="(23)">One from a list of at least two nominees representing the aquaculture industry;</section><section prefix="(24)">One from a list of at least two nominees representing agri-tourism; and</section><section prefix="(25)">One from a list of two nominees representing the biofuel industry.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The consumer member of the Commission:<section prefix="(i)">Shall be a member of the general public;</section><section prefix="(ii)">May not be involved in any way with the activities on which the Commission advises the Secretary; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">May not, within 1 year before appointment, have had a financial interest in or have received compensation from a person who is involved in any way with the activities on which the Commission advises the Secretary.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">While a member of the Commission, the consumer member may not have a financial interest in or receive compensation from a person who is involved in any way with the activities on which the Commission advises the Secretary.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The term of membership is 3 years. A person may not serve more than two consecutive terms. Members of the Commission appointed before January 1, 1973, may continue to serve until the expiration of their terms. New appointments shall be made from nominees of the industry, profession, or organization represented by the member whose term is expiring.</section>
  </text>
</law>
