<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gag" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="2-508.1" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gag-2-508.1</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">If a county is certified by the Department of Planning under &#xA7; 5-408 of the State Finance and Procurement Article as having established an effective county agricultural land preservation program, and if there are moneys remaining in the Maryland Agricultural Land Preservation Fund at the end of the fiscal year, the county may apply to the Foundation for an amount equal to the difference between:<section prefix="(1)">The aggregate amount allotted on behalf of the county under general allotted purchases of easements as provided in &#xA7; 2-508(b) of this subtitle for the fiscal year in which easement purchases are made; and</section><section prefix="(2)">The amount committed by the Foundation on behalf of the county under general allotted purchases of easements as provided in &#xA7; 2-508(b) of this subtitle for the fiscal year in which easement purchases are made.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The distribution under this section shall be made within 60 days of the end of each fiscal year.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">If the moneys remaining in the Maryland Agricultural Land Preservation Fund at the end of the fiscal year are insufficient to distribute the total amount applied for under subsection (a) of this section, the maximum amount that may be distributed to any certified county is:<section prefix="(1)">The total sum available divided by the number of counties applying for additional funds under this section; less</section><section prefix="(2)">The amount committed by the Foundation on behalf of the county under general allotted purchases of easements as provided in &#xA7; 2-508(b) of this subtitle for the fiscal year in which easement purchases are made.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A county may use the additional funds distributed under this section only for an approved agricultural land preservation program for the purposes stated under &#xA7; 2-512 of this subtitle, including use for bond annuity funds, collateralizing loans, or matching funds.</section>
  </text>
</law>
