<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gag" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="4-301" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gag-4-301</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Consumer" means any person who purchases or otherwise acquires shell eggs for household consumption.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Distributor" means any person who:<section prefix="(i)">Sells, offers, or exposes for sale shell eggs;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Purchases shell eggs for other than household consumption; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">Distributes eggs to a retail outlet or food service facility owned by that person.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Distributor" does not include any person who purchases shell eggs either exclusively as a retailer or exclusively for use in a food service facility or exclusively both as a retailer and as a food service facility.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">"Food service facility" means any person who operates a facility where eggs are used in the preparation of food and who does not distribute eggs to a food service facility owned by that person.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"Packer" means any person who places shell eggs in the original case, carton, or container that is used to hold eggs for distribution or sale to a consumer.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">"Retailer" means any person who sells shell eggs to a consumer and who does not distribute eggs to a retail outlet owned by that person.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">"Shell eggs" means raw or treated chicken eggs that are still in the shell and intended for human consumption.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">"Treated egg" means a chicken egg that has been subjected to a process that alters the egg while still in the shell.</section>
  </text>
</law>
