<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gag" order_by="gag" level="1">Agriculture</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gag-4-123.1</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this section the following words have the meanings indicated....</catch_line>
  <order_by>123.1</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">"Humane method" means:<section prefix="1.">A method by which livestock are rendered insensible to pain, by a single blow or gunshot, or by an electrical, chemical, or other rapid and effective means, before being shackled, hoisted, thrown, cast, or cut; or</section><section prefix="2.">Ritual slaughter.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">"Humane method" does not include the use of a manually operated hammer, sledge, or poleax during a slaughtering operation.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">"Livestock" means cattle, calves, sheep, swine, horses, mules, goats, or other animals that may be used in the preparation of a meat product.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">"Livestock" does not include poultry or other fowl.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(4)">"Packer" means a person who is engaged in the business of:<section prefix="(i)">Slaughtering; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">Manufacturing or preparing a meat or livestock product for sale.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(5)">"Ritual slaughter" means a method of slaughter by which livestock suffer loss of consciousness by anemia of the brain caused by simultaneous and instantaneous severance of the carotid arteries with a sharp instrument in accordance with ritual requirements of a religious faith.</section>
      <section prefix="(6)">"Slaughterer" means a person who is regularly engaged in the commercial slaughtering of livestock.</section>
      <section prefix="(7)">"Stockyard" means a facility, consisting of pens, other enclosures, and appurtenances, operated for compensation or profit as a public market to handle, keep, and hold livestock for sale or shipment.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">It is the policy of the State to prevent inhumane methods of livestock slaughter at an official establishment.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">This section may not be construed to:<section prefix="(1)">Prohibit or limit the religious freedom of a person;</section><section prefix="(2)">Apply to a farmer while slaughtering livestock of the farmer; or</section><section prefix="(3)">Apply to ritual slaughter.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A slaughterer, packer, or stockyard operator may not, unless by a humane method:<section prefix="(1)">Shackle, hoist, or otherwise bring livestock into position for slaughter; or</section><section prefix="(2)">Bleed or slaughter livestock.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The Secretary shall inspect the handling of livestock in connection with slaughtering in an official establishment.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A person who violates this section is guilty of a misdemeanor and on conviction is subject to a fine not exceeding $100 for each violation.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">In addition to the penalty under paragraph (1) of this subsection, the Secretary may refuse to provide or may suspend temporarily inspection services for an establishment that violates this section with respect to the slaughter of livestock.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
