<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gag" order_by="" level="1">Agriculture</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gag-2-708.2</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>708.2</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, "Fund" means the Maryland Horse Industry Fund.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">There is a Maryland Horse Industry Fund in the Department.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Fund is a continuing, revolving special fund to be maintained by the State Treasurer.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The State Treasurer shall hold and the State Comptroller shall account for the Fund.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Fund shall be invested and reinvested. Any interest or other investment earnings of the Fund shall be credited and paid into the Fund.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">At the end of a fiscal year, any unspent or unencumbered balance in the Fund may not revert to the General Fund of the State.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The Fund consists of:<section prefix="(1)">Moneys made available from an assessment on equine feed as required under &#xA7; 6-107.2 of this article;</section><section prefix="(2)">Moneys made available to the Fund by general, federal, or special fund appropriations;</section><section prefix="(3)">Moneys made available to the Fund by gifts, grants or transfers from any government or unit or instrumentality of a government or from any private sector sources; and</section><section prefix="(4)">Moneys made available from licensing and inspection of horse stables as required under &#xA7;&#xA7; 2-711, 2-712, and 2-713 of this subtitle.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(g)">The Board shall use the moneys in the Fund in accordance with the provisions of &#xA7; 2-708 of this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">Except for the purposes in &#xA7; 2-708.1 of this subtitle, the Board may not use any moneys in the Fund for any other purpose of the Board.</section>
  </text>
</law>
