<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gag" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="8-801" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gag-8-801</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Certified nutrient management consultant" means an individual certified by the Department to prepare a nutrient management plan.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Commercial farm" means a farm that performs activities related to the production and sale of agricultural commodities, including row crops, fruits, vegetables, horticulture, and silvaculture.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">"Enhanced efficiency fertilizer" has the meaning stated in &#xA7; 6-201 of this article.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"Impervious surface" means any structure, surface, or improvement that reduces or prevents absorption of stormwater into land, and includes porous paving, paver blocks, gravel, crushed stone, decks, patios, elevated structures, and other similar structures, surfaces, or improvements.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">"Natural organic fertilizer" has the meaning stated in &#xA7; 6-201 of this article.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">"Nutrient management plan" means a plan prepared under this subtitle by a certified nutrient management consultant to manage the amount, placement, timing, and application of animal waste, commercial fertilizer, sludge, or other plant nutrients to prevent pollution by transport of bioavailable nutrients and to maintain productivity.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">"Organic fertilizer" has the meaning stated in &#xA7; 6-201 of this article.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Professional fertilizer applicator" means any person who:<section prefix="(i)">Is certified to apply fertilizer in accordance with &#xA7; 8-803.4 of this subtitle; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Applies fertilizer for hire.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Professional fertilizer applicator" includes the owner or manager of property, or an employee of a government entity who applies fertilizer within the scope of employment.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(j)">"Slow-release nitrogen" means nitrogen in a form that:<section prefix="(1)">Delays its availability for plant uptake and use after application; or</section><section prefix="(2)">Extends its availability to the plant significantly longer than a reference "rapidly available nutrient" such as ammonium nitrate or urea, ammonium phosphate, or potassium chloride.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(k)">"Soil test" means a technical analysis of soil conducted by a laboratory using standards recommended by the University of Maryland.</section>
    <section prefix="(l)">"Turf" means land, including residential property and publicly owned land that is planted in grass, except land that is used in the sale and production of sod, as defined in &#xA7; 9-101 of this article.</section>
    <section prefix="(m)">"Water-soluble nitrogen" means nitrogen that is readily soluble in water.</section>
    <section prefix="(n)">"Waters of the State" has the meaning stated in &#xA7; 5-101 of the Environment Article.</section>
  </text>
</law>
