<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gag" order_by="gag" level="1">Agriculture</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gag-5-704</section_number>
  <catch_line>The Insurance Fund shall be administered by a governing board and executive committee as hereinafter...</catch_line>
  <order_by>704</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Insurance Fund shall be administered by a governing board and executive committee as hereinafter provided. The actions of the governing board and executive committee pursuant to this compact shall be deemed the actions of the Insurance Fund.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The members of the governing board shall be entitled to one vote each on such board. No action of the governing board shall be binding unless taken at a meeting at which a majority of the total number of votes on the governing board are cast in favor thereof. Action of the governing board shall be only at a meeting at which a majority of the members are present.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Insurance Fund shall have a seal which may be employed as an official symbol and which may be affixed to documents and otherwise used as the governing board may provide.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The governing board shall elect annually, from among its members, a chairman, vice-chairman, a secretary and a treasurer. The chairman may not succeed himself. The governing board may appoint an executive director and fix his duties and his compensation, if any. Such executive director shall serve at the pleasure of the governing board. The governing board shall make provision for the bonding of such of the officers and employees of the Insurance Fund as may be appropriate.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">Irrespective of the civil service, personnel or other merit system laws of any of the party states, the executive director, or if there be no executive director, the chairman, in accordance with such procedures as the bylaws may provide, shall appoint, remove or discharge such personnel as may be necessary for the performance of the functions of the Insurance Fund and shall fix the duties and compensation of such personnel. The governing board in its bylaws shall provide for the personnel policies and programs of the Insurance Fund.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The Insurance Fund may borrow, accept or contract for the services of personnel from any state, the United States, or any other governmental agency, or from any person, firm, association or corporation.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">The Insurance Fund may accept for any of its purposes and functions under this compact any and all donations, and grants of money, equipment, supplies, materials and services, conditional or otherwise, from any state, the United States, or any other governmental agency, or from any person, firm, association or corporation, and may receive, utilize and dispose of the same. Any donation, gift or grant accepted by the governing board pursuant to this paragraph or services borrowed pursuant to paragraph (f) of this section shall be reported in the annual report of the Insurance Fund. Such report shall include the nature, amount and conditions, if any, of the donation, gift, grant or services borrowed and the identity of the donor or lender.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">The governing board shall adopt bylaws for the conduct of the business of the Insurance Fund and shall have the power to amend and rescind these bylaws. The Insurance Fund shall publish its bylaws in convenient form and shall file a copy thereof and a copy of any amendment thereto with the appropriate agency or officer in each of the party states.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">The Insurance Fund annually shall make to the Governor and legislature of each party state a report covering its activities for the preceding year. Reports made to the General Assembly shall be made subject to &#xA7; 2-1246 of the State Government Article. The Insurance Fund may make such additional reports as it may deem desirable.</section>
    <section prefix="(j)">In addition to the powers and duties specifically authorized and imposed, the Insurance Fund may do such other things as are necessary and incidental to the conduct of its affairs pursuant to this compact.</section>
  </text>
</law>
