<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gag" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="8-201" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gag-8-201</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The following persons shall serve as members of the Committee:<section prefix="(1)">The Secretary, or any employee of the Department the Secretary designates;</section><section prefix="(2)">The Secretary of Natural Resources, or any employee of the Department of Natural Resources whom the Secretary of Natural Resources designates;</section><section prefix="(3)">The Secretary of the Environment, or any employee of the Department of the Environment designated by the Secretary of the Environment;</section><section prefix="(4)">The principal administrative official for agricultural affairs at the University System of Maryland as designated by the Chancellor of the University;</section><section prefix="(5)">The Chairman of the Maryland Agricultural Commission, or the Chairman's designee;</section><section prefix="(6)">The President of the Maryland Association of Soil Conservation Districts;</section><section prefix="(7)">Five soil conservation district supervisors representing the five different geographic areas of the State, as provided in subsection (b) of this section;</section><section prefix="(8)">The Director of the Cooperative Extension Service and the principal administrative officer for Maryland of the Soil Conservation Service of the United States Department of Agriculture, who shall be nonvoting members; and</section><section prefix="(9)">Other representatives of cooperating State and federal agencies serving as consultants to the Committee as selected by the Committee.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Secretary shall appoint the soil conservation district supervisors from recommendations submitted by the district supervisors of each area represented. Each supervisor shall be from one of the following five geographic areas:<section prefix="(1)">Area No. 1: Garrett, Allegany, Washington County, Catoctin, Frederick, and Carroll Soil Conservation Districts;</section><section prefix="(2)">Area No. 2: Anne Arundel, Prince George's, Charles, St. Mary's, and Calvert Soil Conservation Districts;</section><section prefix="(3)">Area No. 3: Kent, Queen Anne's, Caroline, and Talbot Soil Conservation Districts;</section><section prefix="(4)">Area No. 4: Baltimore County, Harford, Montgomery, Howard and Cecil Soil Conservation Districts; and</section><section prefix="(5)">Area No. 5: Dorchester, Wicomico, Worcester, and Somerset Soil Conservation Districts.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The term of each supervisor appointed after July 1, 1974, is four years. Each supervisor shall serve until the supervisor's successor is appointed. A supervisor may not serve as a member more than two full successive terms. Every other member shall hold office as long as the member retains the office by virtue of which the member is serving on the Committee.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">An appointment to fill an unexpired term shall be made in the same manner as for a full term.</section>
  </text>
</law>
