<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gag" order_by="" level="1">Agriculture</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gag-2-509</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>509</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Foundation shall follow the provisions under this section for the easement application process.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Foundation shall adopt regulations and procedures for:<section prefix="(i)">Evaluation of land for which application is made to sell an easement; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Purchase of easements, including the purchase of easements under an installment purchase agreement.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Regulations and procedures adopted by the Foundation for the purchase of easements shall provide that:<section prefix="(1)">One or more owners of land actively devoted to agricultural use may file an application with the county governing body requesting the purchase of an easement by the Foundation on the land owned by the applicants. The application shall include maps and descriptions of the current use of land for the proposed easement, and any other information required by the Foundation to evaluate the land for purchase of an easement.</section><section prefix="(2)">Upon receipt of an application to purchase an easement the local governing body shall refer the application and accompanying materials both to the agricultural preservation advisory board and to the county planning and zoning body.<section prefix="(i)">After the referral of an application, the agricultural preservation advisory board shall advise the county governing body as to whether or not the land for the proposed easement meets the qualifications established by the Foundation under subsection (d) of this section, and whether or not the advisory board recommends the purchase of the easement.</section><section prefix="(ii)">In making its recommendation, the county agricultural preservation advisory board shall:<section prefix="1.">Take into consideration criteria and standards established by the Foundation under this subtitle, current local regulations, local patterns of land development, the kinds of development pressures currently existing on the land for the proposed easement, State smart growth goals, and any locally established priorities for the preservation of agricultural land; and</section><section prefix="2.">Recommend for ranking any application that qualifies and meets the priorities established by the county governing body for the preservation of agricultural land.</section></section><section prefix="(iii)">After the referral of an application, the county planning and zoning body shall advise the local governing body as to whether or not the purchase of the easement is compatible with existing and approved county plans and overall county policy, and whether or not the planning and zoning body recommends the purchase of the easement.</section></section><section prefix="(3)">If either the agricultural preservation advisory board or the planning and zoning body recommends approval, the county governing body shall hold a public hearing on the application for the proposed easement. Adequate notice of the hearing shall be given to all owners whose land would be encumbered by the proposed easement and all owners whose land is contiguous to the land for the proposed easement.</section><section prefix="(4)">In deciding whether to approve the application, the county governing body shall receive the recommendation of the county agricultural preservation advisory board established under &#xA7; 2-504.1 of this subtitle.</section><section prefix="(5)"><section prefix="(i)">After the receipt of the application and the recommendations of the agricultural preservation advisory board and the county planning and zoning body, the county governing body shall render a decision as to whether or not the application shall be recommended to the Foundation for approval.</section><section prefix="(ii)">If the county governing body decides to recommend approval of the application, it shall notify the Foundation and forward to the Foundation:<section prefix="1.">The application and all accompanying materials, including the recommendations of the advisory board and county planning and zoning body;</section><section prefix="2.">A ranking of all applications based on:</section><section prefix="3.">A statement of the total current development rights on the land for the proposed easement, which shall include the total number of development rights that have been subdivided or transferred.</section></section><section prefix="(iii)">If the county governing body recommends denial of the application, it shall inform the Foundation and the applicants.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Regulations and procedures adopted by the Foundation for the purchase and monitoring of easements may not require, in Garrett County or Allegany County, a natural gas rights owner or lessee to subordinate its interest to the Foundation's interest if the Foundation determines that exercise of the natural gas rights will not interfere with an agricultural operation conducted on land subject to an easement.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Regulations and criteria developed by the Foundation relating to land which may be considered for purchase of an easement shall provide that:<section prefix="(1)">Subject to item (2) of this subsection, land shall meet productivity, acreage, and locational criteria determined by the Foundation to be necessary for the continuation of farming;</section><section prefix="(2)">As long as all other criteria are met, land that is at least 50 acres in size or is contiguous to other permanently preserved land shall qualify for purchase of an easement;</section><section prefix="(3)">The Foundation shall attempt to preserve the minimum number of acres which may reasonably be expected to promote the continued availability of agricultural suppliers and markets for agricultural goods;</section><section prefix="(4)">Land within the boundaries of a 10-year water and sewer service district may be considered for purchase of an easement only if that land is outstanding in productivity and is of significant size;</section><section prefix="(5)">Land may be considered for purchase of an easement only if the county regulations governing the land permit the activities listed under &#xA7; 2-513(a) of this subtitle; and</section><section prefix="(6)">Land be evaluated for:<section prefix="(i)">Location in a priority preservation area of the county;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Soil and other land characteristics associated with agricultural and silvicultural productivity;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Agricultural and silvicultural production and contribution to the agricultural and silvicultural economy; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">Any other unique county considerations that support the goals of the program.</section></section></section>
  </text>
</law>
