<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gag" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="6-210" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gag-6-210</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Each brand and grade of commercial fertilizer distributed in the State shall be accompanied by a legible label bearing the following information:<section prefix="(1)">The net weight;</section><section prefix="(2)">The brand and grade under which the commercial fertilizer is distributed;</section><section prefix="(3)">The guaranteed analysis giving the minimum percentage of every plant nutrient claimed to be contained in the fertilizer; and</section><section prefix="(4)">Name and address of manufacturer.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">If distributed in bulk, a written or printed statement of the information required by subsection (a) of this section shall accompany delivery and be supplied to the purchaser at the time of delivery.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Any fertilizer mixed or blended according to a formula furnished by a purchaser shall be marked plainly or tagged with the words "buyer's mixture", or "mixed-to-order", or "custom-mix" together with a statement containing the following information:<section prefix="(1)">Net weight;</section><section prefix="(2)">The guaranteed analysis giving the minimum percentage of every plant nutrient claimed to be contained in the fertilizer; and</section><section prefix="(3)">Name and address of the manufacturer. In addition, the amounts or kinds of materials used in the formulation may be shown.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, a specialty fertilizer shall be labeled to contain all information required by subsection (a) of this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A specialty fertilizer used on turf shall be labeled to contain:<section prefix="(i)">All of the information required by subsection (a) of this section;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The percentage of total nitrogen, including the percentage of other water soluble nitrogen and water insoluble nitrogen;</section><section prefix="(iii)">The percentage of available phosphate;</section><section prefix="(iv)">The percentage of soluble potash; and</section><section prefix="(v)"/></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The information required under paragraphs (1) and (2) of this subsection shall be printed in a legible and conspicuous manner on at least one side of the container, or if it does not appear on the face or display side of the container, it shall appear on the upper third of the side used.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, on or after April 1, 2011, a lawn fertilizer with an available phosphate (P2O5) content greater than 5%:<section prefix="(i)">May not be labeled for use on established lawns or grass;</section><section prefix="(ii)">May not be labeled with spreader settings; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Shall be marked with the words "NOT FOR USE ON ESTABLISHED LAWNS OR GRASS" in at least a three-quarter inch font and in a legible and conspicuous manner on the front side of the container.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">This subsection does not apply to seed starter fertilizer for use on newly established lawns or turf.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">Each brand of soil conditioner distributed in the State shall be accompanied by a legible label bearing the following information:<section prefix="(1)">Net weight or other measure prescribed as satisfactory by the Secretary;</section><section prefix="(2)">The brand under which the soil conditioner is distributed;</section><section prefix="(3)">An accurate statement of composition and purpose; and</section><section prefix="(4)">Name and address of the registrant.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
