<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gag" order_by="" level="1">Agriculture</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gag-10-1504</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>1504</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">To be eligible for credits under this subtitle, an ethanol or biodiesel producer shall apply to the Board for certification on an application provided by the Board.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">An applicant shall show in the application to the satisfaction of the Board:<section prefix="(1)">That the applicant will construct or operate a facility capable of producing ethanol or biodiesel;</section><section prefix="(2)">That the applicant will invest or has invested substantial resources in the State in connection with the facility;</section><section prefix="(3)">That the facility will constitute a permanent fixture in the State;</section><section prefix="(4)">For an ethanol production facility, information demonstrating:<section prefix="(i)">The production capacity of the facility; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">The quantity and availability of small grains and other suitable agricultural products in the vicinity of the production facility that may be used by the facility;</section></section><section prefix="(5)">For a biodiesel production facility, information demonstrating:<section prefix="(i)">The production capacity of the facility; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">The quantity and availability of soybean oil and other suitable bio-based oils in the vicinity of the production facility that may be used by the facility;</section></section><section prefix="(6)">Information demonstrating:<section prefix="(i)">The availability and cost of energy sufficient to operate the facility;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The availability of sufficient water and waste disposal systems for the facility;</section><section prefix="(iii)">The availability of sufficient labor and a qualified site manager for the facility; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">That the facility will meet all State and federal environmental standards;</section></section><section prefix="(7)">Any proposed marketing agreements for the ethanol or biodiesel products;</section><section prefix="(8)">A plan to give farmers in the State the opportunity to invest in the facility; and</section><section prefix="(9)">That the applicant will meet any other requirement established by the Board.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Board shall:<section prefix="(1)">Review each application submitted under this subtitle;</section><section prefix="(2)">Approve or deny the application within 60 days of receipt of the application; and</section><section prefix="(3)">For an approved application, certify the producer as eligible for a credit in an amount that is:<section prefix="(i)">Based on the production capacity of the facility, as determined by the Board; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Consistent with subsection (d) of this section.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Board may not certify ethanol production credits for more than a total of 15,000,000 gallons per calendar year, of which at least 10,000,000 gallons shall be produced from small grains.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Board may not certify biodiesel production credits for more than a total of 5,000,000 gallons per calendar year, of which at least 2,000,000 gallons shall be from soybean oil produced:<section prefix="(i)">In a facility that began operating after December 31, 2004; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">Under the expanded capacity of a facility, the expansion of which occurred after December 31, 2004.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If eligible, a producer may apply to the Board for certification for additional credits if the producer increases the production capacity of the facility.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If a facility does not achieve its certified production capacity for 2 consecutive years, the Board may revise the stated production capacity of the facility and the corresponding credit certification of the producer to reflect actual production.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">An application submitted to the Board under this section is not subject to disclosure under the Maryland Public Information Act.</section>
  </text>
</law>
