<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gag" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="10-1506" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gag-10-1506</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">After February 1, 2008, to receive a credit payment a certified ethanol or biodiesel producer shall file a claim with the Board by the end of January, April, July, and October of each year.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A claim filed under this section shall state:<section prefix="(1)"><section prefix="(i)">The producer's total ethanol production in the State during the previous quarter, categorized by ethanol produced from small grains and ethanol produced from other agricultural products; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">The producer's total biodiesel production in Maryland during the previous quarter, categorized by biodiesel produced from:</section></section><section prefix="(2)">The location of the producer;</section><section prefix="(3)">The average number of Maryland citizens employed by the producer in the previous quarter;</section><section prefix="(4)"><section prefix="(i)">For an ethanol producer, the number of bushels of Maryland-grown small grains and other agricultural commodities used by the producer in the previous quarter; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">For a biodiesel producer, the number of gallons of Maryland-produced soybean oil and other bio-based oils used by the producer in the previous quarter; and</section></section><section prefix="(5)">Any other information that the Board requires.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A claim filed under this section shall be reviewed by an independent certified public accountant with respect to, as appropriate:<section prefix="(1)">The total ethanol production;</section><section prefix="(2)">The breakdown between ethanol produced from small grains and ethanol produced from other agricultural products;</section><section prefix="(3)">The total biodiesel production; and</section><section prefix="(4)">The breakdown between biodiesel produced from:<section prefix="(i)">Soybean oil produced in a facility that began operating after December 31, 2004, or under the expanded capacity of a facility, the expansion of which occurred after December 31, 2004; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Other feedstock, including soybean oil produced in a facility that began operating on or before December 31, 2004.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A claim submitted to the Board under this section is not subject to disclosure under the Maryland Public Information Act.</section>
  </text>
</law>
