<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gag" order_by="gag" level="1">Agriculture</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gag-8-302</section_number>
  <catch_line>The governing body of each district consists of five supervisors....</catch_line>
  <order_by>302</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The governing body of each district consists of five supervisors.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Each supervisor shall be interested and knowledgeable in conservation of soil, water, and related natural resources. By training and experience, each supervisor shall be qualified to perform the specialized skilled services which are required in performing the duties under this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The supervisors shall be appointed in the following manner, and consideration shall be given to representation from farming, forestry, wildlife, and urban interests where appropriate:<section prefix="(1)">One district resident by the county governing body and serving at the pleasure of the county governing body. In those counties with both an executive and a legislative branch of government, the appointment shall be made by the executive and approved by the legislative branch;</section><section prefix="(2)">One by the Committee from a list of three district residents submitted by the county farm bureau;</section><section prefix="(3)">One by the Committee from a list of three district residents submitted by the county extension service; and</section><section prefix="(4)">Two by the Committee from among residents of the district.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The term of office of each Committee appointed member is 5 years. Each supervisor shall hold office until his successor is appointed and qualifies. Vacancies shall be filled for any unexpired term by appointments made in the same manner as for the full term.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The Committee, upon notice and hearing, may remove any supervisor from office for neglect of duty or malfeasance in office. In addition, any supervisor who, during any period of 12 consecutive months, shall fail to attend at least 50 percent of all regular meetings of the board of supervisors of the district of which he is an appointed member, shall be considered to have resigned and the chairman of the board of supervisors shall notify the appropriate appointing body of the resultant vacancy. However, if the reasons for the supervisor's inability to attend meetings as required in this subtitle are found by the appointing body to be satisfactory, the appointing body may reinstate the supervisor to office.</section>
  </text>
</law>
