<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gag" order_by="" level="1">Agriculture</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gag-10-1904</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>1904</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">A product meets the Maryland standard of identity for honey if the product:<section prefix="(1)">Does not contain any substance other than honey, including any food additive as defined in &#xA7; 21-101 of the Health - General Article;</section><section prefix="(2)">Has not been subjected to chemical or biochemical treatments used to influence honey crystallization;</section><section prefix="(3)">Has not had any water added to the product in the course of extraction or packing for sale or resale as honey;</section><section prefix="(4)">Has not begun to ferment or effervesce;</section><section prefix="(5)">Does not have a moisture content greater than:<section prefix="(i)">23% for heather honey (Calluna); or</section><section prefix="(ii)">18.6% for all other honey;</section></section><section prefix="(6)">Does not have a water-insoluble-solids content greater than:<section prefix="(i)">0.5 gram per 100 grams for pressed honey; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">0.1 gram per 100 grams for all other honey;</section></section><section prefix="(7)">Does not have a fructose content greater than 50 grams per 100 grams;</section><section prefix="(8)">Has a total amount of fructose and glucose equal to at least:<section prefix="(i)">45 grams per 100 grams for honeydew honey and blends of honeydew honey with blossom honey; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">60 grams per 100 grams for all other honey; and</section></section><section prefix="(9)">Except as provided in subsection (b) of this section, has a sucrose content no greater than 5 grams per 100 grams.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The sucrose content of the following types of honey may be greater than 5 grams per 100 grams but not greater than 10 grams per 100 grams to meet the Maryland standard of identity for honey:<section prefix="(i)">Alfalfa (Medicago sativa);</section><section prefix="(ii)">Citrus spp.;</section><section prefix="(iii)">False Acacia (Robinia pseudoacacia);</section><section prefix="(iv)">French Honeysuckle (Hedysarum);</section><section prefix="(v)">Menzes Banksia (Banksia menziesii);</section><section prefix="(vi)">Red Gum (Eucalyptus camaldulensisi);</section><section prefix="(vii)">Leatherwood (Eucryphia lucida); and</section><section prefix="(viii)">Eucryphia milligami.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The sucrose content of the following types of honey may be greater than 5 grams per 100 grams but not greater than 15 grams per 100 grams to meet the Maryland standard of identity for honey:<section prefix="(i)">Lavender (Lavandula spp.); and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Borage (Borago officinalis).</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
