<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gag" order_by="" level="1">Agriculture</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gag-2-518</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>518</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, "area" means a priority preservation area.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A county may include a priority preservation area element in the county's comprehensive plan.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">An area shall:<section prefix="(1)"><section prefix="(i)">Contain productive agricultural or forest soils; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">Be capable of supporting profitable agricultural and forestry enterprises where productive soils are lacking;</section></section><section prefix="(2)">Be governed by local policies, ordinances, regulations, and procedures that:<section prefix="(i)">Stabilize the agricultural and forest land base so that development does not convert or compromise agricultural or forest resources; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Support the ability of working farms in the priority preservation area to engage in normal agricultural activities; and</section></section><section prefix="(3)">Be large enough to support normal agricultural and forestry activities in conjunction with the amount of development permitted by the county in the priority preservation area, as represented in its adopted comprehensive plan.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">An area may:<section prefix="(1)">Consist of a single parcel of land, multiple connected parcels of land, or multiple unconnected parcels of land; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Include rural legacy areas.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">A county's acreage goal for land to be preserved through easements and zoning within an area shall be equal to at least 80% of the remaining undeveloped land in the area, as calculated at the time of application for State certification of an area.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">Each time a county's comprehensive plan is updated, the update shall include an evaluation of:<section prefix="(1)">The county's progress toward meeting the goals of the Foundation;</section><section prefix="(2)">Any shortcomings in the county's ability to achieve the goals of the Foundation; and</section><section prefix="(3)">Past, current, and planned actions to correct any identified shortcomings.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(g)">In accordance with &#xA7; 5-408 of the State Finance and Procurement Article and any regulations adopted under the authority of that section, the Department of Planning and the Maryland Agricultural Land Preservation Foundation shall jointly certify an area.</section>
  </text>
</law>
