<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gag" order_by="gag" level="1">Agriculture</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gag-3-101</section_number>
  <catch_line>The Secretary shall protect the health of the domestic animals of the State from all contagious or i...</catch_line>
  <order_by>101</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Secretary shall protect the health of the domestic animals of the State from all contagious or infectious diseases. For this purpose, the Secretary may:<section prefix="(1)">Adopt and enforce quarantine, sanitary, or other rules and regulations he deems necessary;</section><section prefix="(2)">Make and prosecute diligent inquiries in the several counties to ascertain the exact condition of the health of the livestock; and</section><section prefix="(3)">Notwithstanding &#xA7; 3-102 of this subtitle, prohibit the importation from another state of any animal he has reason to believe is infected with or has been exposed to a contagious or infectious disease and detain the animal at any place for inspection or quarantine.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Secretary may establish, maintain, and enforce a quarantine order if he determines it is urgent and necessary for the prompt performance of the provisions provided in this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Secretary may adopt rules and regulations governing the importation of domestic animals into the State from another state.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, the Secretary shall maintain all animal health diagnostic or analytical reports and reports filed under an animal health program established by the Secretary in a manner that protects the identity of the animal owner.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">If the Secretary determines that the disclosure is necessary to protect the public health or prevent the spread of an infectious or contagious disease, the Secretary may disclose identifying information.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">In determining whether disclosure is necessary to protect the public health or prevent the spread of an infectious or contagious disease, the Secretary shall consult with the Secretary of Health and Mental Hygiene.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
