<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gag" order_by="" level="1">Agriculture</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gag-2-309</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>309</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">A person may register with the Board as a veterinary technician.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">There is a Veterinary Technician Committee under the Board's jurisdiction. The Committee consists of 7 members who are appointed by the Board, subject to the approval of the Secretary. The Board shall determine the qualifications and term of each member.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Each member of the Committee may not receive compensation but is entitled to reimbursement for expenses under the Standard State Travel Regulations as provided in the State budget.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Committee, subject to the Board's approval shall:<section prefix="(1)">Evaluate, examine, and determine the qualifications for applicants for registration as a veterinary technician;</section><section prefix="(2)">Recommend to the Board the subject, scope, form, date, time, and location for each examination;</section><section prefix="(3)">Establish continuing education requirements for veterinary technicians;</section><section prefix="(4)">Define the duties and responsibilities of registered veterinary technicians;</section><section prefix="(5)">Recommend to the Board reasonable rules and regulations to carry out the provisions of this section; and</section><section prefix="(6)">Generally assist the Board in registering and regulating veterinary technicians.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">To apply for registration, an applicant shall:<section prefix="(1)">Submit an application to the Board on the form the Board requires; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Pay to the Board an application fee set by the Board.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The Board shall register any applicant who:<section prefix="(1)">Meets the requirements of this section;</section><section prefix="(2)">Meets the Board's educational requirements;</section><section prefix="(3)">Passes a Board approved examination;</section><section prefix="(4)">Is of good moral character; and</section><section prefix="(5)">Is at least 18 years old.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">A registration is issued for a term of 3 years and expires on June 30 of the third year after the date issued unless the registration is renewed as provided in this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">The Board shall renew the registration of any applicant for an additional 3-year term if the applicant:<section prefix="(1)">Submits a renewal application on the form that the Board requires;</section><section prefix="(2)">Pays to the Board a renewal fee set by the Board;</section><section prefix="(3)">Complies with the Board's continuing education requirements; and</section><section prefix="(4)">Otherwise is entitled to be registered.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(h)">In accordance with the hearing provisions of &#xA7; 2-311 of this subtitle, the Board may refuse to register an applicant, suspend or revoke the registration, or reprimand and censure, or place on probation any veterinary technician, if the veterinary technician:<section prefix="(1)">Practices veterinary medicine except as permitted under this subtitle;</section><section prefix="(2)">Fraudulently or deceptively obtains a registration;</section><section prefix="(3)">Is professionally, physically, or mentally incompetent;</section><section prefix="(4)">Is convicted of a felony or a crime involving moral turpitude;</section><section prefix="(5)">Is convicted of a violation of any federal or State law relating to narcotic drugs;</section><section prefix="(6)">Is grossly negligent or deliberately cruel to an animal;</section><section prefix="(7)">Violates any provisions of this subtitle; or</section><section prefix="(8)">Is determined by the Board to be incompetent as a veterinary technician.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
