<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gag" order_by="" level="1">Agriculture</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gag-10-113</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>113</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">As an alternative method for the collection of assessments provided for in &#xA7; 10-110 of this subtitle, upon the request of the certified agency, the Secretary shall notify, by registered letter, all livestock dealers, operators of any livestock auction markets, slaughterhouses, packinghouses, and any other person engaged in the buying, selling, or handling of livestock for slaughter in the State. On and after the date specified in the letter, the assessments shall be deducted by the purchaser, or his agent or representative, from the purchase price of any livestock bought, acquired, or sold for slaughter.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The deducted assessment for any month shall be remitted by the purchaser to the Secretary by the 20th day of the following month, and the Secretary shall pay the amount of the assessment to the certified agency.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The books and records of every livestock dealer, operator of any livestock auction market slaughterhouse, packinghouse, or person engaged in buying, acquiring, or selling livestock for slaughter shall be open for the inspection by the Secretary at any time during regular business hours.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A livestock dealer, operator of any livestock auction market slaughterhouse, packinghouse, or its managers, or agents, or any person who buys, sells, or handles livestock for slaughter in the State may not fail to collect or pay the deducted assessments to the Secretary.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">If any person violates the provisions of subsection (d) of this section, the certified agency concerned may institute judicial proceedings to enforce the assessment.</section>
  </text>
</law>
