<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gag" order_by="gag" level="1">Agriculture</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gag-2-305</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this section, "animal control facility" means a humane society, as defined in &#xA7; 10-601 of the Cr...</catch_line>
  <order_by>305</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, "animal control facility" means a humane society, as defined in &#xA7; 10-601 of the Criminal Law Article, or a county or municipal designated animal shelter.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Board, on terms and conditions satisfactory to the Board, may issue a license to an animal control facility to allow the animal control facility to administer drugs needed to sedate, euthanize, or sedate and euthanize animals.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The owner of an animal control facility shall apply for the license.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The Board shall issue a license in the name of the owner of an animal control facility.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The application shall designate one individual at the facility responsible for the drugs.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The annual license fee is $100.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">In accordance with procedures set out in &#xA7; 2-311 of this subtitle, the Board may:<section prefix="(1)">Reject an application for a license; or</section><section prefix="(2)">Suspend or revoke a license for failure to comply with the Board's regulations.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">An animal control facility licensed under this section shall comply with the Board's requirements relating to employee training.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">A member of the Board, or the Board's designated inspector, may enter an animal control facility licensed under this section at any reasonable hour to enforce the Board's regulations.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">In consultation with the Department of Health and Mental Hygiene, the Board shall adopt regulations necessary to carry out this section.</section>
  </text>
</law>
