<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gag" order_by="gag" level="1">Agriculture</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gag-5-902</section_number>
  <catch_line>Except as provided in subsection (b) of this section, a person may not distribute, possess, sell, of...</catch_line>
  <order_by>902</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in subsection (b) of this section, a person may not distribute, possess, sell, offer for sale, use, or offer for use any antifouling paint containing a tributyltin compound.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A person may not distribute, possess, sell, offer for sale, use, or offer for use any substance that contains a tributyltin compound in concentrated form and that is labeled for mixing with paint by the user to produce an antifouling paint for use on a vessel.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A person may distribute or sell an antifouling paint containing a tributyltin compound with an acceptable release rate to the owner or agent of a commercial boatyard.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The owner or agent of a commercial boatyard may possess and apply or purchase for application an antifouling paint containing tributyltin with an acceptable release rate, if the antifouling paint:<section prefix="(i)">Is applied only within a commercial boatyard; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Is applied only to vessels exceeding 25 meters in length or that have aluminum hulls.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">This section does not prohibit the sale, use, distribution, or possession of an antifouling paint containing a tributyltin compound, if the antifouling paint:<section prefix="(1)">Is in a spray can of 16 ounces or less;</section><section prefix="(2)">Is commonly referred to as an outboard or lower drive unit paint; and</section><section prefix="(3)">Has an acceptable release rate.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
