<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gag" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="5-301" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gag-5-301</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Broker" means any person who solicits, takes orders, sells or distributes nursery stock in the State other than a nurseryman or dealer.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Dealer" means any person, except a nurseryman or broker, who advertises nursery stock for sale or installation or who buys, collects, or otherwise acquires wild plants or nursery stock for the purpose of selling, planting or distributing them.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Dealer" does not include a person who acquires plants for personal use.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">"Nursery" means any place where nursery stock is produced for sale or distribution.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"Nursery stock" means (1) any hardy plant or plant that survives Maryland winters, including a deciduous or evergreen tree, shrub, or woody vine whether cultivated, native, or wild, and all viable parts of the plant; (2) any nonhardy plant or plant part to be distributed in another state that requires plant inspection and certification before entering that state; and (3) any other plant included by the Secretary, if regulating its movement is necessary to control any dangerously injurious plant pest.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">"Nurseryman" means any person engaged in the production of nursery stock for sale or distribution.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">"Plant pest" means any insect, snail, nematode, fungus, virus, bacteria, weed, or any other form of terrestrial or aquatic plant or microorganisms (except viruses, bacteria, or other microorganisms on or in living man or another living animal) which is normally considered to be a plant pest or which the Secretary declares to be a pest.</section>
  </text>
</law>
