<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gag" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="2-802" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gag-2-802</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>** CONTINGENCY - NOT IN EFFECT - CHAPTER 226 OF 1998 **<section prefix="(a)">The Maryland delegation to the Northeast Interstate Dairy Compact Commission consists of the following five members, appointed by the Governor with the advice and consent of the Senate:<section prefix="(1)">Two dairy farmers who are actively engaged in the production of milk at the time of appointment;</section><section prefix="(2)">One dairy processor who is actively engaged in the processing of milk at the time of appointment; and</section><section prefix="(3)">Two consumers.</section></section><section prefix="(b)">The members of the delegation shall be selected to represent the diversity of the dairy interests and geographic representation of the State.</section><section prefix="(c)"><section prefix="(1)">The term of a member is 4 years and begins on October 1 in the year in which the member is appointed.</section><section prefix="(2)">At the end of a term, a member continues to serve until a successor is appointed and qualifies.</section><section prefix="(3)">A member appointed after a term has begun serves only for the rest of the term and until a successor is appointed and qualifies.</section><section prefix="(4)">The terms of the members are staggered as required by the terms provided for members of the delegation on October 1, 1998.</section><section prefix="(5)">A member may serve no more than 3 consecutive terms.</section><section prefix="(6)">The Governor may remove a member for incompetence or misconduct.</section><section prefix="(7)">If a vacancy arises other than by the expiration of a term, the Governor shall appoint within 30 days a successor to serve the remainder of the term.</section></section><section prefix="(d)">A member of the delegation:<section prefix="(1)">May not receive compensation for serving on the delegation; but</section><section prefix="(2)">Is entitled to reimbursement for expenses under the Standard State Travel Regulations, as provided in the State budget.</section></section></text>
</law>
