<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gag" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="5-207" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gag-5-207</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Each pest control consultant, pest control applicator, or public agency applicator shall obtain an annual certificate indicating competence in one or more established categories from the Secretary. Each private applicator shall obtain a certificate which shall require periodic renewal as determined by the Secretary.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Each application for a certificate by a pest control consultant or pest control applicator shall be accompanied by a $75 certificate fee plus $25 for each category in excess of one. Each application for a private applicator certificate shall be accompanied by a fee of $7.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Each applicant for a pest control consultant certificate, pest control applicator certificate, or public agency applicator certificate shall demonstrate competence to consult on pest control or to apply pesticides safely in the State by passing a written examination prepared and administered by the Department. There shall be no charge for an initial examination, provided that each pest control applicator or each pest control consultant shall pay $10 for each examination retaken after the initial examination. Each applicant for a private applicator certificate shall pass an examination given by the Department. A private applicator certificate is valid for 3 years and may be renewed by the certificate holder by participation in training approved by the Department.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Each certificate shall be renewed upon payment of the certificate fee and demonstration of satisfactory knowledge of pesticide use.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">Each place of business engaged in the business of conducting pest control shall obtain an annual license indicating the category of operation.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">Each place of business engaged in the business of pest control or pest control consulting shall pay to the Department an annual license fee of $150 and shall provide evidence of financial responsibility as required by the Department.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">Each license shall be renewed upon payment of the license fee and submission of proof of liability insurance.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">A person who sells or distributes a restricted use pesticide shall hold a dealer permit from the Secretary.<section prefix="(1)">Each application for a dealer permit shall be accompanied by a $25 permit fee.</section><section prefix="(2)">Each dealer permit shall be renewed annually upon payment of the permit fee.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(i)">A public agency that applies a pesticide shall hold an annual public agency permit from the Secretary.</section>
    <section prefix="(j)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Any person who operates a pest control business shall register annually with the Department each employee, other than a certified applicator, who offers or performs pest control at each business location.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The application fee to register an employee initially is $30.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The annual renewal fee to register an employee is $30.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(k)">If an application for renewal of a license, certificate, or registration is received by the Department more than 30 days after the expiration of the license, certificate, or registration, the applicant is subject to a $30 late fee.</section>
  </text>
</law>
