<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gag" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="10-1601" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gag-10-1601</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Farm product" means any agricultural, horticultural, vegetable, fruit product, whether raw, canned, frozen, dried, pickled, or otherwise processed, livestock, meats, marine food products, poultry, eggs, dairy products, nuts, honey, and every edible product of farm, orchard, garden, or water.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Program" means the Jane Lawton Farm-to-School Program.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">There is a Jane Lawton Farm-to-School Program in the Department.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Program is established for the purpose of:<section prefix="(1)">Promoting the sale of farm products grown in the State to Maryland schools in consultation with the State Department of Education;</section><section prefix="(2)">Soliciting farmers to sell their farm products to Maryland schools;</section><section prefix="(3)">Developing and regularly updating a database of farmers interested in selling their farm products to Maryland schools, including the types and amounts of farm products the farmers want to sell and the time periods in which the farmers want to sell;</section><section prefix="(4)">Facilitating purchases from farmers by interested Maryland schools in consultation with the State Department of Education and in compliance with applicable procurement requirements; and</section><section prefix="(5)">Providing outreach and guidance to farmers concerning the value of and procedure for selling their farm products to interested Maryland schools.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Program, in partnership with the State Department of Education and in consultation with school food service directors and interested farming organizations, shall establish promotional events that promote State agriculture and farm products to children through school meal and classroom programs.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">At least one promotional event shall:<section prefix="(i)">Last for a period of 1 week;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Be known as "Maryland Homegrown School Lunch Week";</section><section prefix="(iii)">Promote State agriculture and farm products to children through school meal and classroom programs; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">Arrange for interaction between students and farmers through promotional activities that may include field trips to farms and in-school presentations by farmers.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">On or before January 1 of each year, each local educational agency participating in the Program shall report to the Department the types and amounts of farm products purchased from farms in the State.</section>
  </text>
</law>
