<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gag" order_by="" level="1">Agriculture</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gag-8-205</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>205</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Committee may perform acts, hold public hearings, and, subject to the approval of the Secretary, adopt rules and regulations necessary for the execution of its functions under this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Committee may delegate to its chairman, any member, or any employee powers and duties it deems proper.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Committee shall:<section prefix="(1)">Adopt a seal which shall be judicially noticed;</section><section prefix="(2)">Offer assistance to the supervisors of soil conservation districts;</section><section prefix="(3)">Keep the supervisors of each district informed of the activities and experience of the other districts and facilitate cooperation and interchange of advice and experience between the districts;</section><section prefix="(4)">Coordinate the programs of the several soil conservation districts by advising and consulting with the districts;</section><section prefix="(5)">Secure the cooperation and assistance of the United States, its agencies, and State agencies in the work of the districts;</section><section prefix="(6)">Disseminate information throughout the State concerning the activities and programs of the soil conservation districts and encourage the formation of districts in any areas where their organization is desirable;</section><section prefix="(7)">Grant to the districts either directly or through the counties funds made available to the Committee for use by the districts in implementing the soil conservation program;</section><section prefix="(8)">Provide for the execution of surety bonds for every employee or officer entrusted with funds or property;</section><section prefix="(9)">Keep a full and accurate record of all proceedings and every rule or regulation or order issued or adopted; and</section><section prefix="(10)">Assign to the districts such clerical and administrative employees as authorized by the annual State budget or through agreement with local governments.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
