<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gag" order_by="" level="1">Agriculture</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gag-8-803.6</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>803.6</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Department shall, in consultation with the University of Maryland, establish a program to certify professional fertilizer applicators.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The certification program shall provide professional fertilizer applicators with training and education in the following subject areas:<section prefix="(i)">The proper use and calibration of fertilizer application equipment;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The hazards involved in, and the environmental impact of, applying fertilizer, including nutrient pollution to the waters of the State;</section><section prefix="(iii)">All applicable State and federal laws, rules, and regulations;</section><section prefix="(iv)">The correct interpretation of fertilizer labeling information; and</section><section prefix="(v)">The recommendations developed by the University of Maryland for nutrient management on turf, including the appropriate time to:<section prefix="1.">Apply fertilizer when rain is forecast; and</section><section prefix="2.">Apply fertilizer when soils are wet and the potential for fertilizer movement off-site exists.</section></section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">In establishing the certification program, the Department may:<section prefix="(1)">Charge reasonable fees, including an annual recertification fee, to cover costs associated with the certification program;</section><section prefix="(2)">Require continuing education or training for professional fertilizer applicators;</section><section prefix="(3)">Designate one or more entities to train, certify, and recertify professional fertilizer applicators, which may charge fees to cover the reasonable costs associated with the certification training and education; and</section><section prefix="(4)">Recognize the training program of an entity employing professional fertilizer applicators if the program meets the certification and recertification training and education standards established by the Department under this section.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Department shall publish and maintain a list of all certified professional fertilizer applicators and make the list available on the Department's Internet Web site.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Department may adopt regulations to implement this section.</section>
  </text>
</law>
