<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gag" order_by="gag" level="1">Agriculture</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gag-2-801</section_number>
  <catch_line>** CONTINGENCY - NOT IN EFFECT - CHAPTER 226 OF 1998 **...</catch_line>
  <order_by>801</order_by>
  <text>** CONTINGENCY - NOT IN EFFECT - CHAPTER 226 OF 1998 **<section prefix=""><section prefix="(1)">"Commission" means the Commission established by this Compact.</section><section prefix="(2)">"Compact" means this interstate Compact.</section><section prefix="(3)">"Region" means the territorial limits of the states which are or become parties to this Compact.</section><section prefix="(4)">"Participating state" means a state which has become a party to this Compact by the enactment of concurring legislation.</section><section prefix="(5)">"Regulated area" means any area within the region governed by and defined in regulations establishing a Compact over-order price or Commission marketing order.</section><section prefix="(6)">"Pool plant" means any milk plant located in a regulated area.</section><section prefix="(7)">"Partially regulated plant" means a milk plant not located in a regulated area but having Class I distribution within such area, or receipts from producers located in such area. Commission regulations may exempt plants having such distribution or receipts in amounts less than the limits defined therein.</section><section prefix="(8)">"Compact over-order price" means a minimum price required to be paid to producers for Class I milk established by the Commission in regulations adopted pursuant to &#xA7;&#xA7; 9 and 10 of this Compact, which is above the price established in federal marketing orders or by state farm price regulation in the regulated area. Such price may apply throughout the region or in any part or parts thereof as defined in the regulations of the Commission.</section><section prefix="(9)">"Commission marketing order" means regulations adopted by the Commission pursuant to &#xA7;&#xA7; 9 and 10 of this Compact in place of a terminated federal marketing order or state dairy regulation. Such order may apply throughout the region or in any part or parts thereof as defined in the regulations of the Commission. Such order may establish minimum prices for any or all classes of milk.</section><section prefix="(10)">"Milk" means the lacteal secretion of cows and includes all skim, butterfat, or other constituents obtained from separation or any other process. The term is used in its broadest sense and may be further defined by the Commission for regulatory purposes.</section><section prefix="(11)">"Class I milk" means milk disposed of in fluid form or as a fluid milk product, subject to further definition in accordance with the principles expressed in &#xA7; 3(b).</section><section prefix="(12)">"State dairy regulation" means any state regulation of dairy prices, and associated assessments, whether by statute, marketing order or otherwise.</section></section><section prefix="(a)">This Compact shall not be construed to displace existing federal milk marketing orders or state dairy regulation in the region but to supplement them. In the event some or all federal orders in the region are discontinued, the Compact shall be construed to provide the Commission the option to replace them with one or more Commission marketing orders pursuant to this Compact.</section><section prefix="(b)">This Compact shall be construed liberally in order to achieve the purposes and intent enunciated in &#xA7; 1. It is the intent of this Compact to establish a basic structure by which the Commission may achieve those purposes through the application, adaptation and development of the regulatory techniques historically associated with milk marketing and to afford the Commission broad flexibility to devise regulatory mechanisms to achieve the purposes of this Compact. In accordance with this intent, the technical terms which are associated with market order regulation and which have acquired commonly understood general meanings are not defined herein but the Commission may further define the terms used in this Compact and develop additional concepts and define additional terms as it may find appropriate to achieve its purposes.</section><section prefix="(a)">The Commission shall elect annually from among the members of the participating state delegations a chairperson, a vice-chairperson, and a treasurer. The Commission shall appoint an executive director and fix the duties and compensation of the executive director. The executive director shall serve at the pleasure of the Commission, and, together with the treasurer, shall be bonded in an amount determined by the Commission. The Commission may establish through its by-laws an executive committee composed of one member elected by each delegation.</section><section prefix="(b)">The Commission shall adopt by-laws for the conduct of its business by a two-thirds vote, and shall have the power by the same vote to amend and rescind these by-laws. The Commission shall publish its by-laws in convenient form with the appropriate agency or officer in each of the participating states. The by-laws shall provide for appropriate notice to the delegations of all Commission meetings and hearings and of the business to be transacted at such meetings or hearings. Notice also shall be given to other agencies or officers of participating states as provided by the laws of those states.</section><section prefix="(c)">The Commission shall file an annual report with the Secretary of Agriculture of the United States, and with each of the participating states by submitting copies to the governor, both houses of the legislature, and the head of the state department having responsibilities for agriculture.</section><section prefix="(d)">In addition to the powers and duties elsewhere prescribed in this Compact, the Commission shall have the power:<section prefix="(1)">To sue and be sued in any state or federal court;</section><section prefix="(2)">To have a seal and alter the same at pleasure;</section><section prefix="(3)">To acquire, hold, and dispose of real and personal property by gift, purchase, lease, license, or other similar manner, for its corporate purposes;</section><section prefix="(4)">To borrow money and to issue notes, to provide for the rights of the holders thereof and to pledge the revenue of the Commission as security therefor, subject to the provisions of &#xA7; 18 of this Compact;</section><section prefix="(5)">To appoint such officers, agents, and employees as it may deem necessary, prescribe their powers, duties, and qualifications; and</section><section prefix="(6)">To create and abolish such offices, employments, and positions as it deems necessary for the purposes of the Compact and provide for the removal, term, tenure, compensation, fringe benefits, pension, and retirement rights of its officers and employees. The Commission may also retain personal services on a contract basis.</section><section prefix="(1)">Investigate or provide for investigations or research projects designed to review the existing laws and regulations of the participating states, to consider their administration and costs, to measure their impact on the production and marketing of milk and their effects on the shipment of milk and milk products within the region.</section><section prefix="(2)">Prepare and transmit to the participating states model dairy laws and regulations dealing with the inspection of farms and plants, sanitary codes, labels for dairy products and their imitations, standards for dairy products, license standards, producer security programs, and fair trade laws.</section><section prefix="(3)">Study and recommend to the participating states joint or cooperative programs for the administration of the dairy laws and regulations and to prepare estimates of cost savings and benefits of such programs.</section><section prefix="(4)">Encourage the harmonious relationships between the various elements in the industry for the solution of their material problems. Conduct symposiums or conferences designed to improve industry relations, or a better understanding of problems.</section><section prefix="(5)">Prepare and release periodic reports on activities and results of the Commission's efforts to the participating states.</section><section prefix="(6)">Review the existing marketing system for milk and milk products and recommend changes in the existing structure for assembly and distribution of milk which may assist, improve, or promote more efficient assembly and distribution of milk.</section><section prefix="(7)">Investigate costs and charges for producing, hauling, handling, processing, distributing, selling and for all other services performed with respect to milk.</section><section prefix="(8)">Examine current economic forces affecting producers, probable trends in production and consumption, the level of dairy farm prices in relation to costs, the financial conditions of dairy farmers, and the need for an emergency order to relieve critical conditions on dairy farms.</section></section><section prefix="(a)">The powers granted in this section and &#xA7; 10 shall apply only to the establishment of a Compact over-order price, so long as federal milk marketing orders remain in effect in the region. In the event that any or all such orders are terminated, this article shall authorize the Commission to establish one or more Commission marketing orders, as herein provided, in the region or parts thereof as defined in the order.</section><section prefix="(b)">A Compact over-order price established pursuant to this section shall apply only to Class I milk. Such over-order price shall not exceed $1.50 per gallon. Beginning in 1990, and using that year as a base, the foregoing $1.50 per gallon maximum shall be adjusted annually by the rate of change in the Consumer Price Index as reported by the Bureau of Labor Statistics of the United States Department of Labor. For purposes of the pooling and equalization of an over-order price, the value of milk used in other use classifications shall be calculated at the appropriate class price established pursuant to the applicable federal order or state dairy regulation and the value of unregulated milk shall be calculated in relation to the nearest prevailing class price in accordance with and subject to such adjustments as the Commission may prescribe in regulations.</section><section prefix="(c)">A Commission marketing order shall apply to all classes and uses of milk.</section><section prefix="(d)">The Commission is hereby empowered to establish the minimum price for milk to be paid by pool plants, partially regulated plants and all other handlers receiving milk from producers located in a regulated area. This price shall be established either as a Compact over-order price or by one or more Commission marketing orders. Whenever such a price has been established by either type of regulation, the legal obligation to pay such price shall be determined solely by the terms and purpose of the regulation without regard to the situs of the transfer of title, possession or any other factors not related to the purposes of the regulation and this Compact. Producer-handlers as defined in an applicable federal market order shall not be subject to a Compact over-order price. The Commission shall provide for similar treatment of producer-handlers under Commission marketing orders.</section><section prefix="(e)">In determining the price, the Commission shall consider the balance between production and consumption of milk and milk products in the regulated area, the costs of production including, but not limited to the price of feed, the cost of labor including the reasonable value of the producer's own labor and management, machinery expense, and interest expense, the prevailing price for milk outside the regulated area, the purchasing power of the public and the price necessary to yield a reasonable return to the producer and distributor.</section><section prefix="(f)">When establishing a Compact over-order price, the Commission shall take such action as necessary and feasible to ensure that the over-order price does not create an incentive for producers to generate additional supplies of milk.</section><section prefix="(g)">The Commission shall whenever possible enter into agreements with state or federal agencies for exchange of information or services for the purpose of reducing regulatory burden and cost of administering the Compact. The Commission may reimburse other agencies for the reasonable cost of providing these services.<section prefix="(1)">Provisions classifying milk in accordance with the form in which or purpose for which it is used, or creating a flat pricing program.</section><section prefix="(2)">With respect to a Commission marketing order only, provisions establishing or providing a method for establishing separate minimum prices for each use classification prescribed by the Commission, or a single minimum price for milk purchased from producers or associations of producers.</section><section prefix="(3)">With respect to an over-order minimum price, provisions establishing or providing a method for establishing such minimum price for Class I milk.</section><section prefix="(4)">Provisions for establishing either an over-order price or a Commission marketing order may make use of any reasonable method for establishing such price or prices including flat pricing and formula pricing. Provision may also be made for location adjustments, zone differentials and for competitive credits with respect to regulated handlers who market outside the regulated area.</section><section prefix="(5)">Provisions for the payment to all producers and associations of producers delivering milk to all handlers of uniform prices for all milk so delivered, irrespective of the uses made of such milk by the individual handler to whom it is delivered, or for the payment of producers delivering milk to the same handler of uniform prices for all milk delivered by them.<section prefix="(A)">With respect to regulations establishing a Compact over-order price, the Commission may establish one equalization pool within the regulated area for the sole purpose of equalizing returns to producers throughout the regulated area.</section><section prefix="(B)">With respect to any Commission marketing order, as defined in &#xA7; 2(9), which replaces one or more terminated federal orders or state dairy regulation, the marketing area of now separate state or federal orders shall not be merged without the affirmative consent of each state, voting through its delegation, which is partly or wholly included within any such new marketing area.</section></section><section prefix="(6)">Provisions requiring persons who bring Class I milk into the regulated area to make compensatory payments with respect to all such milk to the extent necessary to equalize the cost of milk purchased by handlers subject to a Compact over-order price or Commission marketing order. No such provisions shall discriminate against milk producers outside the regulated area. The provisions for compensatory payments may require payment of the difference between the Class I price required to be paid for such milk in the state of production by a federal milk marketing order or state dairy regulation and the Class I price established by the Compact over-order price or Commission marketing order.</section><section prefix="(7)">Provisions specially governing the pricing and pooling of milk handled by partially regulated plants.</section><section prefix="(8)">Provisions requiring that the account of any person regulated under a Compact over-order price shall be adjusted for any payments made to or received by such persons with respect to a producer settlement fund of any federal or state milk marketing order or other state dairy regulation within the regulated area.</section><section prefix="(9)">Provisions requiring the payment by handlers of an assessment to cover the costs of the administration and enforcement of such order pursuant to Article VII, &#xA7; 18(a).</section><section prefix="(10)">Provisions for reimbursement to participants of the Women, Infants and Children Special Supplemental Food Program of the United States Child Nutrition Act of 1966.</section><section prefix="(11)">Other provisions and requirements as the Commission may find are necessary or appropriate to effectuate the purposes of this Compact and to provide for the payment of fair and equitable minimum prices to producers.</section></section><section prefix="(a)">In addition to the concise general statement of basis and purpose required by &#xA7; 4(b) of the federal Administrative Procedure Act, as amended (5 U.S.C. Sec. 553(c)), the Commission shall make findings of fact with respect to:<section prefix="(1)">Whether the public interest will be served by the establishment of minimum milk prices to dairy farmers under Article IV.</section><section prefix="(2)">What level of prices will assure that producers receive a price sufficient to cover their costs of production and will elicit an adequate supply of milk for the inhabitants of the regulated area and for manufacturing purposes.</section><section prefix="(3)">Whether the major provisions of the order, other than those fixing minimum milk prices, are in the public interest and are reasonably designed to achieve the purposes of the order.</section><section prefix="(4)">Whether the terms of the proposed regional order or amendment are approved by producers as provided in &#xA7; 13.</section></section><section prefix="(a)">For the purpose of ascertaining whether the issuance or amendment of regulations establishing a Compact over-order price or a Commission marketing order, including any provision with respect to milk supply under subsection 9(f), is approved by producers, the Commission shall conduct a referendum among producers. The referendum shall be held in a timely manner, as determined by regulation of the Commission. The terms and conditions of the proposed order or amendment shall be described by the Commission in the ballot used in the conduct of the referendum, but the nature, content, or extent of such description shall not be a basis for attacking the legality of the order or any action relating thereto.</section><section prefix="(b)">An order or amendment shall be deemed approved by producers if the Commission determines that it is approved by at least two-thirds of the voting producers who, during a representative period determined by the Commission, have been engaged in the production of milk the price of which would be regulated under the proposed order or amendment.</section><section prefix="(c)">For purposes of any referendum, the Commission shall consider the approval or disapproval by any cooperative association of producers, qualified under the provisions of the Act of Congress of February 18, 1922, as amended, known as the Capper-Volstead Act, bona fide engaged in marketing milk, or in rendering services for or advancing the interests of producers of such commodity, as the approval or disapproval of the producers who are members or stockholders in, or under contract with, such cooperative association of producers, except as provided in subdivision (1) hereof and subject to the provisions of subdivisions (2) through (5) hereof.<section prefix="(1)">No cooperative which has been formed to act as a common marketing agency for both cooperatives and individual producers shall be qualified to block vote for either.</section><section prefix="(2)">Any cooperative which is qualified to block vote shall, before submitting its approval or disapproval in any referendum, give prior written notice to each of its members as to whether and how it intends to cast its vote. The notice shall be given in a timely manner as established, and in the form prescribed, by the Commission.</section><section prefix="(3)">Any producer may obtain a ballot from the Commission in order to register approval or disapproval of the proposed order.</section><section prefix="(4)">A producer who is a member of a cooperative which has provided notice of its intent to approve or not to approve a proposed order, and who obtains a ballot and with such ballot expresses the producer's approval or disapproval of the proposed order, shall notify the Commission as to the name of the cooperative of which the producer is a member, and the Commission shall remove such producer's name from the list certified by such cooperative with its corporate vote.</section><section prefix="(5)">In order to insure that all milk producers are informed regarding a proposed order, the Commission shall notify all milk producers that an order is being considered and that each producer may register the producer's approval or disapproval with the Commission either directly or through the producer's cooperative.</section></section><section prefix="(a)">The Commission shall terminate any regulations establishing an over-order price or Commission marketing order issued under this article whenever it finds that such order or price obstructs or does not tend to effectuate the declared policy of this Compact.</section><section prefix="(b)">The Commission shall terminate any regulations establishing an over-order price or a Commission marketing order issued under this article whenever it finds that such termination is favored by a majority of the producers who, during a representative period determined by the Commission, have been engaged in the production of milk the price of which is regulated by such order; but such termination shall be effective only if announced on or before such date as may be specified in such marketing agreement or order.</section><section prefix="(c)">The termination or suspension of any order or provision thereof, shall not be considered an order within the meaning of this article and shall require no hearing, but shall comply with the requirements for informal rulemaking prescribed by &#xA7; 4 of the federal Administrative Procedure Act, as amended (5 U.S.C. Sec. 553).</section><section prefix="(a)">The Commission may by rule and regulation prescribe record keeping and reporting requirements for all regulated persons. For purposes of the administration and enforcement of this Compact, the Commission is authorized to examine the books and records of any regulated person relating to the person's milk business and for that purpose, the Commission's properly designated officers, employees, or agents shall have full access during normal business hours to the premises and records of all regulated persons.</section><section prefix="(b)">Information furnished to or acquired by the Commission officers, employees, or its agents pursuant to this section shall be confidential and not subject to disclosure except to the extent that the Commission deems disclosure to be necessary in any administrative or judicial proceeding involving the administration or enforcement of this Compact, an over-order price, a Compact marketing order, or other regulations of the Commission. The Commission may promulgate regulations further defining the confidentiality of information pursuant to this section. Nothing in this section shall be deemed to prohibit (1) the issuance of general statements based upon the reports of a number of handlers, which do not identify the information furnished by any person, or (2) the publication by direction of the Commission of the name of any person violating any regulation of the Commission, together with a statement of the particular provisions violated by such person.</section><section prefix="(c)">No officer, employee, or agent of the Commission shall intentionally disclose information, by inference or otherwise, which is made confidential pursuant to this section. Any person violating the provisions of this section shall upon conviction be subject to a fine of not more than $1,000 or to imprisonment for not more than one year, or to both, and shall be removed from office. The Commission shall refer any allegation of a violation of this section to the appropriate state enforcement authority or United States Attorney.</section><section prefix="(a)">The Commission is hereby authorized and empowered by its members and its properly designated officers to administer oaths and issue subpoenas throughout all signatory states to compel the attendance of witnesses and the giving of testimony and the production of other evidence.</section><section prefix="(b)">Any handler subject to an order may file a written petition with the Commission stating that any such order or any provision of any such order or any obligation imposed in connection therewith is not in accordance with law and praying for a modification thereof or to be exempted therefrom. The handler shall thereupon be given an opportunity for a hearing upon such petition, in accordance with regulations made by the Commission. After such hearing, the Commission shall make a ruling upon the prayer of such petition which shall be final, if in accordance with law.</section><section prefix="(c)">The District Courts of the United States in any district in which such handler is an inhabitant, or has the handler's principal place of business, are hereby vested with jurisdiction in equity to review such ruling, provided a bill in equity for that purpose is filed within thirty days from the date of the entry of such ruling. Service of process in such proceedings may be had upon the Commission by delivering to it a copy of the bill of complaint. If the court determines that such ruling is not in accordance with law, it shall remand such proceedings to the Commission with directions either (1) to make such ruling as the court shall determine to be in accordance with law, or (2) to take such further proceedings as, in its opinion, the law requires. The pendency of proceedings instituted pursuant to this subdivision shall not impede, hinder, or delay the Commission from obtaining relief pursuant to &#xA7; 17. Any proceedings brought pursuant to &#xA7; 17 (except where brought by way of counterclaim in proceedings instituted pursuant to this section) shall abate whenever a final decree has been rendered in proceedings between the same parties, and covering the same subject matter, instituted pursuant to this section.</section><section prefix="(a)">Any violation by a handler of the provisions of regulations establishing an over-order price or a Commission marketing order, or other regulations adopted pursuant to this Compact shall:<section prefix="(1)">Constitute a violation of the laws of each of the signatory states. Such violation shall render the violator subject to a civil penalty in an amount as may be prescribed by the laws of each of the participating states, recoverable in any state or federal court of competent jurisdiction. Each day such violation continues shall constitute a separate violation.</section><section prefix="(2)">Constitute grounds for the revocation of license or permit to engage in the milk business under the applicable laws of the participating states.</section></section><section prefix="(b)">With respect to handlers, the Commission shall enforce the provisions of this Compact, regulations establishing an over-order price, a Commission marketing order or other regulations adopted hereunder by:<section prefix="(1)">Commencing an action for legal or equitable relief brought in the name of the Commission in any state or federal court of competent jurisdiction; or</section><section prefix="(2)">With the agreement of the appropriate state agency of a participating state, by referral to the state agency for enforcement by judicial or administrative remedy.</section></section><section prefix="(c)">With respect to handlers, the Commission may bring an action for injunction to enforce the provisions of this Compact or the order or regulations adopted thereunder without being compelled to allege or prove that an adequate remedy of law does not exist.</section><section prefix="(a)">To provide for its start-up costs, the Commission may borrow money pursuant to its general power under &#xA7; 6(d)(4). In order to finance the costs of administration and enforcement of this Compact, including payback of start-up costs, the Commission is hereby empowered to collect an assessment from each handler who purchases milk from producers within the region. If imposed, this assessment shall be collected on a monthly basis for up to one year from the date the Commission convenes, in an amount not to exceed 0.001% of the applicable federal market order blend price per hundredweight of milk purchased from producers during the period of the assessment. The initial assessment may apply to the projected purchases of handlers for the two-month period following the date the Commission convenes. In addition, if regulations establishing an over-order price or a Compact marketing order are adopted, they may include an assessment for the specific purpose of their administration. These regulations shall provide for establishment of a reserve for the Commission's ongoing operating expenses.</section><section prefix="(b)">The Commission shall not pledge the credit of any participating state or of the United States. Notes issued by the Commission and all other financial obligations incurred by it, shall be its sole responsibility and no participating state or the United States shall be liable therefor.</section><section prefix="(a)">The Commission shall keep accurate accounts of all receipts and disbursements, which shall be subject to the audit and accounting procedures established under its rules. In addition, all receipts and disbursements of funds handled by the Commission shall be audited yearly by a qualified public accountant and the report of the audit shall be included in and become part of the annual report of the Commission.</section><section prefix="(b)">The accounts of the Commission shall be open at any reasonable time for inspection by duly constituted officers of the participating states and by any persons authorized by the Commission.</section><section prefix="(c)">Nothing contained in this article shall be construed to prevent Commission compliance with laws relating to audit or inspection of accounts by or on behalf of any participating state or of the United States.</section></text>
</law>
