<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gag" order_by="" level="1">Agriculture</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gag-8-801.1</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>801.1</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Each nutrient management plan shall be developed considering factors including:<section prefix="(i)">Levels of bioavailable nitrogen and phosphorus in the soil;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Levels of bioavailable nitrogen and phosphorus in all fertilizer materials to be applied;</section><section prefix="(iii)">The amount of nitrogen and phosphorus necessary to achieve the expected crop yield for the land that is the subject of the nutrient management plan, as determined by:<section prefix="1.">The field's actual yield record and soil productivity for that crop; or</section><section prefix="2.">If information concerning actual yield record and soil productivity for a crop is unavailable, relevant information concerning similar fields and soil;</section></section><section prefix="(iv)">Soil erodibility and nutrient retention capacity;</section><section prefix="(v)"><section prefix="1.">The best reasonable scientific methods accepted by the Department and the University of Maryland Cooperative Extension Service; or</section><section prefix="2.">Scientifically validated data for the development of a nutrient management plan as defined by the Department in regulation; and</section></section><section prefix="(vi)">Existing best management practices.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Each nutrient management plan shall provide flexibility for management decisions that may be required by conditions beyond the control of the farmer.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A summary of each nutrient management plan shall be filed and updated with the Department at a time and in a form that the Department requires by regulation.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Department shall maintain a copy of each summary for 3 years in a manner that protects the identity of the individual for whom the nutrient management plan was prepared.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
