<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gag" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="2-304" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gag-2-304</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Board may:<section prefix="(1)">Adopt rules and regulations to effectuate this subtitle;</section><section prefix="(2)">Engage additional employees for professional, clerical, and special work as necessary and as provided in the State budget;</section><section prefix="(3)">Subpoena any witness to take his testimony;</section><section prefix="(4)">Require production of books, papers, records, and other documentary evidence, and examine them in relation to any matter which the Board may investigate or hear; and</section><section prefix="(5)">Establish reasonable standards for the practice of veterinary medicine, including conduct and ethics.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Members or their designated inspectors may enter veterinary facilities at any reasonable hour to enforce the Board rules and regulations.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Board shall maintain an office within the State and a telephone number listed for use by the general public.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Board shall inspect every veterinary hospital facility in the State at least once every 2 years.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Board may authorize the practice of a health occupation on an animal by a health care practitioner licensed, certified, or otherwise authorized under the Health Occupations Article.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If the Board authorizes the practice of a health occupation on an animal under paragraph (1) of this subsection, the Board may:<section prefix="(i)">Impose requirements for education, training, and supervision by a veterinary practitioner; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Require the registration of each health care practitioner authorized to practice a health occupation on an animal in accordance with this subsection.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Board shall adopt regulations encouraging a veterinary practitioner to report suspected instances of animal cruelty, including suspected animal fighting, to a local law enforcement or county animal control agency.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A veterinary practitioner shall be immune from any civil liability that results from a report in good faith to a local law enforcement or county animal control agency under this subsection.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
