<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gag" order_by="gag" level="1">Agriculture</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gag-13-203</section_number>
  <catch_line>A person may not be a grain dealer without first obtaining an annual grain dealer's license from the...</catch_line>
  <order_by>203</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">A person may not be a grain dealer without first obtaining an annual grain dealer's license from the Secretary.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Each license shall be issued upon payment of the applicable fee required by subsection (d) of this section and providing proof of adequate insurance under &#xA7; 13-212 of this subtitle and shall be effective until December 31, following, unless revoked.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Fees collected for the issuance of licenses under this subtitle shall be deposited in the Administration Fund.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The fees for the different types of grain dealers' licenses are as follows:</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In determining the type of license to issue under this section, the Secretary may rely on representations of the number of bushels of grain handled in the most recent grain records of the grain dealer.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">For a person who is applying for licensure as a grain dealer for the first time in this State, the Secretary may rely on the representations made by the person of the number of bushels of grain that the person anticipates handling in the year for which the license is sought.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A person who applies for renewal or original licensure as a grain dealer shall make an oath under penalty of perjury that all representations made by the person in the most recent grain records are true and correct.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A person immediately shall notify the Department if their status as to the type of license changes.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
