<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gag" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="2-1401" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gag-2-1401</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, "Fund" means the Maryland Dairy Farmer Emergency Trust Fund.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">There is a Maryland Dairy Farmer Emergency Trust Fund.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The purpose of the Fund is to provide financial assistance to dairy farmers during periods of economic hardship due to depressed milk prices.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Secretary shall administer the Fund.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">At the end of each fiscal year, any unspent or unencumbered balance in the Fund that exceeds $15,000,000 shall revert to the General Fund in accordance with &#xA7; 7-302 of the State Finance and Procurement Article.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The State Treasurer shall hold the Fund separately and the Comptroller shall account for the Fund.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Fund consists of:<section prefix="(i)">Money appropriated in the State budget to the Fund;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Any investment earnings of the Fund; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Any other money from any other source accepted for the benefit of the Fund.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Governor may include an appropriation in the State budget each fiscal year for the Fund.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">The Fund may be used only to provide financial assistance to dairy farmers during periods of economic hardship due to depressed milk prices.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Treasurer shall invest the money of the Fund in the same manner as other State money may be invested.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Any investment earnings of the Fund shall be credited to the Fund.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(i)">The Secretary shall establish procedures for dairy farmers to apply for financial assistance from the Fund.</section>
  </text>
</law>
