<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gag" order_by="gag" level="1">Agriculture</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gag-8-403</section_number>
  <catch_line>The supervisors of each resulting district shall file a verified application with the Secretary of S...</catch_line>
  <order_by>403</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The supervisors of each resulting district shall file a verified application with the Secretary of State when the property, assets, and rights to which they are entitled under division or combination, or both, are received.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The application shall recite:<section prefix="(1)">The petition for the division or combination, or both, of the district was filed with the Committee pursuant to the provisions of this subtitle;</section><section prefix="(2)">The proceedings specified in this subtitle were taken pursuant to the petition;</section><section prefix="(3)">The application is being filed in order to complete the division or combination, or both, of any old district;</section><section prefix="(4)">The supervisors have been appointed;</section><section prefix="(5)">The name and official residence of each supervisor, together with a certified copy of the appointments evidencing his rights to office;</section><section prefix="(6)">The term of office of each supervisor;</section><section prefix="(7)">The name of the district; and</section><section prefix="(8)">The location of the principal office of the supervisors.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The application shall be executed and sworn to by each supervisor before an officer, authorized by law to take and certify oaths, who shall certify on the application that he personally knows each supervisor, knows him to be the officer as affirmed in the application, and that each has subscribed to the application in his presence.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The application shall be accompanied by a statement of the Committee, which shall recite the fact that:<section prefix="(1)">A petition was filed;</section><section prefix="(2)">Notice was given;</section><section prefix="(3)">A referendum was held on the question of dividing or combining, or both, the named districts;</section><section prefix="(4)">The Committee determined that division or combination, or both, was administratively feasible;</section><section prefix="(5)">The division or combination, or both, of the property, assets, and rights was decided upon and carried out in accordance with this subtitle; and</section><section prefix="(6)">The boundaries of the district are as described in the petition, or as further defined by the Committee.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
