<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gag" order_by="gag" level="1">Agriculture</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gag-9-107</section_number>
  <catch_line>No person may transport, offer for transportation, sell, offer or expose for sale within the State, ...</catch_line>
  <order_by>107</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">No person may transport, offer for transportation, sell, offer or expose for sale within the State, sod for planting purposes:<section prefix="(1)">Not labeled in accordance with the provisions of this subtitle;</section><section prefix="(2)">Having an incomplete, false, or misleading label or claim;</section><section prefix="(3)">Which has been falsely advertised or advertised in a misleading manner;</section><section prefix="(4)">Containing prohibited noxious weeds in any amount;</section><section prefix="(5)">Containing restricted noxious weeds except as prescribed by rules and regulations adopted under this subtitle;</section><section prefix="(6)">To which there is affixed names or terms that create an incomplete or misleading impression as to the kind, variety, history, productivity, quality, or origin of the sod;</section><section prefix="(7)">Represented to be "inspected", "approved", "certified", "registered", or "foundation" unless it has been produced, processed, and labeled in accordance with procedures and rules and regulations of an officially recognized certifying agency;</section><section prefix="(8)">Which in the form of turf sod, or turf plugs, do not contain at least one-half inch of sod and roots and which do not remain intact after folding, rolling or plugging; or</section><section prefix="(9)">Containing destructively injurious insects, other animal pests, or plant diseases.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A person may not alter or substitute sod in any manner that may defeat the purpose of the provisions of this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A person may not disseminate any false or misleading advertisement in any manner concerning sod, sod mixtures, plugs, or sprigs.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A person may not fail to comply with, or supply false information in reply to a "stop-sale order", or remove tags attached to or dispose of sod, sod mixtures, plugs, or sprigs held under the order, except as specified by the enforcement officer.</section>
  </text>
</law>
