<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gag" order_by="gag" level="1">Agriculture</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gag-13-212</section_number>
  <catch_line>A license may not be issued or renewed under this subtitle until the applicant has:...</catch_line>
  <order_by>212</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">A license may not be issued or renewed under this subtitle until the applicant has:<section prefix="(1)"><section prefix="(i)">Filed with the Secretary a financial statement, as provided in subsection (b) of this section, establishing the net worth of the applicant's grain business; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">Posted a surety bond, irrevocable letter of credit, or cash guaranty at least as large as the following amounts for the different types of licenses:</section></section><section prefix="(2)">Demonstrated proof of insurance coverage as required by this subtitle.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">An applicant for a Type A or B license shall submit a financial statement that:<section prefix="(i)">Is prepared and signed by a person other than the applicant or a member of the applicant's business or family;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Establishes a net worth for the applicant; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Is signed by the applicant.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A Type C or D license may not be issued or renewed under this subtitle until the applicant has:<section prefix="(i)">Filed with the Secretary a financial statement reviewed by a certified public accountant establishing the net worth of the applicant's business as provided in paragraph (3) of this subsection; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">Filed with the Secretary a letter from a certified public accountant stating that a review of the applicant's business records shows a net worth as provided in paragraph (3) of this subsection.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The financial statement shall indicate a minimum net worth for each type of grain dealer's license as follows:</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
