<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gag" order_by="gag" level="1">Agriculture</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gag-10-1802</section_number>
  <catch_line>Except as provided in subsection (b) of this section, a person shall register annually with the Depa...</catch_line>
  <order_by>1802</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Except as provided in subsection (b) of this section, a person shall register annually with the Department before transporting waste kitchen grease.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A person may transport waste kitchen grease to property owned by the person to convert the waste kitchen grease to biofuel for the person's own use provided that the person:<section prefix="(i)">Transports only 275 gallons of waste kitchen grease in a single vehicle;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Possesses or controls no more than a total of 1,320 gallons of waste kitchen grease, biofuel feedstock derived from waste kitchen grease, or biofuel stock; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Has not obtained any of the waste kitchen grease that will be transported from:<section prefix="1.">A container owned by a registrant or a commercial renderer; or</section><section prefix="2.">A food establishment under contract with a registrant.</section></section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A person may transport waste kitchen grease to a facility to convert the waste kitchen grease to biofuel provided that:<section prefix="(i)">The person:<section prefix="1.">Meets all of the requirements of paragraph (1) of this subsection; and</section><section prefix="2.">Other than to a property owned by the person, will transport the waste kitchen grease to only one facility during a single 24-hour period; and</section></section><section prefix="(ii)">The receiving facility:<section prefix="1.">Has a production capacity not exceeding 500 gallons of biofuel a day; and</section><section prefix="2.">Possesses or controls no more than a total of 1,320 gallons of waste kitchen grease, biofuel feedstock derived from waste kitchen grease, or biofuel.</section></section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Biofuel used to power the vehicle transporting the waste kitchen grease is excluded for the purposes of paragraphs (1) and (2) of this subsection.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
