<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gag" order_by="" level="1">Agriculture</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gag-9-207</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>207</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Each container of agricultural seeds which is sold, offered or exposed for sale, or transported in the State for planting purposes shall bear or have attached in a conspicuous place a plainly written or printed label or tag in the English language, except when the scientific name is the commonly accepted name, giving the following information:<section prefix="(1)">The name and address of the person who labeled the seed or who sells, offers, or exposes the seed for sale within the State;</section><section prefix="(2)">Commonly accepted name of (i) kind, or (ii) kind and variety, of each agricultural seed component in excess of 5 percent of the whole, and the percentage by weight of each in the order of its predominance;</section><section prefix="(3)">Where more than one component is required to be named, the word "mixture" or the word "mixed" shall be shown conspicuously on the label;</section><section prefix="(4)">Origin of alfalfa, red clover, orchard grass, white clover, and field corn (except hybrid corn), but if the origin is unknown, that fact shall be stated;</section><section prefix="(5)">Lot number or other identification;</section><section prefix="(6)">Percentage by weight of seeds other than that required to be named on the label;</section><section prefix="(7)">Percentage by weight of inert matter;</section><section prefix="(8)">Percentage by weight of every weed seed;</section><section prefix="(9)">The name and number of each kind of restricted noxious weed seed: per ounce in Group 1 and per pound in Group 2 when present singly or collectively in any amount but the amount may not exceed 16 per ounce in Group 1 and 16 per pound in Group 2.</section><section prefix="(10)">For each named agricultural seed (i) percentage of germination, exclusive of hard seed, (ii) percentage of hard seed, if present, and (iii) the calendar month and year the test was completed to determine such percentages. Following (i) and (ii) the additional statement: "total germination and hard seed" may be stated, if desired. However, if the total of (i) and (ii) is stated, the total shall be subject to the tolerance that applies to a percentage of germination of like magnitude.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Every determination for purity, germination, and noxious weed seed is subject to the tolerance and method of determination prescribed in the rules and regulations adopted under this subtitle.</section>
  </text>
</law>
