<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gag" order_by="gag" level="1">Agriculture</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gag-2-302.1</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this section, "veterinary review committee" means a committee or board that:...</catch_line>
  <order_by>302.1</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, "veterinary review committee" means a committee or board that:<section prefix="(1)">Is within one of the categories described in subsection (b) of this section; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Performs any of the functions listed in subsection (c) of this section.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">For purposes of this section, a veterinary review committee is:<section prefix="(1)">A regulatory board or agency that is established by State or federal law to license, certify, or discipline any veterinary practitioner;</section><section prefix="(2)">A committee of the Maryland Veterinary Medical Association or any of its component societies; or</section><section prefix="(3)">Any person who contracts with a veterinary practitioner to perform any of those functions listed in subsection (c) of this section that are limited to the review of services provided by the veterinary practitioner.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">For purposes of this section, a veterinary review committee has the following powers and duties:<section prefix="(1)">To evaluate and seek to improve the quality of veterinary care that is provided by veterinary practitioners;</section><section prefix="(2)">To evaluate the need for and the level of performance of veterinary care that is provided by veterinary practitioners; or</section><section prefix="(3)">To evaluate and provide assistance to any veterinary practitioner who is in need of treatment and rehabilitation for alcoholism, drug abuse, chemical dependency, or other physical, emotional, or mental condition.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Except as otherwise provided in the section, the proceedings, records, and files of a veterinary review committee are not discoverable and are not admissible in evidence in any civil action arising out of matters that are being reviewed and evaluated by the veterinary review committee.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">Subsection (d) of this section does not apply to:<section prefix="(1)">A civil action brought by a party who claims to be aggrieved by a decision of the veterinary review committee; or</section><section prefix="(2)">Any record or document that:<section prefix="(i)">Is considered by a veterinary review committee; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Otherwise would be subject to discovery and introduction into evidence in a civil trial.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">A person who acts in good faith and within the scope of jurisdiction of a veterinary review committee is not civilly liable for:<section prefix="(1)">Any action as a member of the veterinary review committee; or</section><section prefix="(2)">Giving information to, participating in, or contributing to the function of the veterinary review committee.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
