<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gag" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="8-303" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gag-8-303</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The supervisors shall designate annually a chairman and such other officers as may be necessary, and shall have authority to change these designations. A majority of the supervisors constitutes a quorum and the concurrence of a majority in any matter is required for its determination. A supervisor may receive his travel expenses and per diem allowance, as set by the Committee and provided in the annual State budget, for each day spent in the performance of his duties. A supervisor may receive an additional per diem allowance provided by sources other than the State, not to exceed the allowance set by the Committee.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The supervisors may employ a secretary, technical experts, and other permanent and temporary officers and employees as they require, and shall determine their qualifications, duties, and compensation. The supervisors may delegate to the chairman, to any supervisor, or any employee powers and duties as they deem proper.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The supervisors shall provide for the execution of surety bonds for every employee and officer who is entrusted with funds or property. They shall provide for the keeping of a full and accurate record of all proceedings and of all resolutions, rules and regulations, and orders issued or adopted. They shall provide for an annual audit of the accounts of receipts and disbursements.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The supervisors may invite the legislative body of any municipality or county, located near or within the district, to designate a representative to advise and consult with the supervisors of the district on all questions of program and policy which may affect the property, water supply, or other interests of the municipality or county.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The Office of the Attorney General may provide services to the supervisors as needed.</section>
  </text>
</law>
