<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gag" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="11-204.1" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gag-11-204.1</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Secretary may establish a program to test any weight and measure to determine if it conforms to the requirements of the National Conference on Weights and Measures.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Secretary may:<section prefix="(1)">Issue a certificate of approval to any person for a weight and measure that meets the requirements of this section;</section><section prefix="(2)">Deny or revoke a certificate of approval if the Secretary determines that:<section prefix="(i)">A person has provided false or misleading information to the Secretary about any weight and measure; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">The weight and measure does not conform to the requirements of this section; and</section></section><section prefix="(3)">Charge the appropriate fee established under subsection (e) of this section in order to cover the cost of inspecting or testing any weight and measure as provided by this section.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">There is a Weight and Measure Testing Fund within the Maryland Department of Agriculture. The Fund is a special fund established for the purpose of paying the expenses incurred in testing and approving any weight and measure as provided under this section. Unspent portions of the Fund shall revert to the General Fund of the State.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Unless issued a certificate of approval from the Secretary, a person may not represent any weight and measure as approved under this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Secretary shall establish by regulation fees for services performed under this section to provide type evaluation and other testing, and for the use of laboratory equipment, special prototype test equipment, and vehicles.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">In establishing fees under this section, the Secretary shall only charge a fee to cover the cost of providing the technical service or evaluation by those industries requesting the service.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
