<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gag" order_by="gag" level="1">Agriculture</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gag-2-307.1</section_number>
  <catch_line>In reviewing an application for licensure of a veterinarian or in investigating any matter brought a...</catch_line>
  <order_by>307.1</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In reviewing an application for licensure of a veterinarian or in investigating any matter brought against a veterinary practitioner, the Board may direct the applicant, veterinarian, or veterinary practitioner to submit to a mental or physical examination when the Board has reasonable evidence indicating the inability of that individual to practice veterinary medicine competently.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">In return for the privilege given by the State in issuing a license or registration, the applicant, veterinarian, or veterinary practitioner is deemed to have:<section prefix="(1)">Consented to submit to an examination under this section if directed by the Board in writing; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Waived any claim of privilege as to the examination report or testimony regarding the report.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The report or testimony of an examining physician or other person designated by the Board is confidential except as to contested case proceedings as defined by the Administrative Procedure Act.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The unreasonable failure or refusal of an  applicant, a veterinarian, or a veterinary practitioner to submit to an examination is prima facie evidence of the applicant's, veterinarian's, or veterinary practitioner's inability to practice veterinary medicine competently unless the Board finds that the failure or refusal was beyond the control of the applicant, veterinarian, or veterinary practitioner.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The Board shall pay the reasonable cost of any examination made under this section.</section>
  </text>
</law>
