<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gag" order_by="gag" level="1">Agriculture</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gag-2-718</section_number>
  <catch_line>Any person who violates any provision of this subtitle is guilty of a misdemeanor and on conviction ...</catch_line>
  <order_by>718</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Any person who violates any provision of this subtitle is guilty of a misdemeanor and on conviction is subject to a fine not exceeding $500 or imprisonment not exceeding 11 months or both.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Instead of pursuing criminal penalties under subsection (a) of this section, the Board may impose an administrative penalty on any person who violates any provision of &#xA7; 2-710 or &#xA7; 2-715 of this subtitle.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The penalty imposed under this subsection may not exceed $2,000 for each violation of this subtitle.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">All penalties collected under this subsection shall be paid into the General Fund of the State.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The Board shall adopt regulations necessary to implement the provisions of this subsection.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Except as otherwise provided in the Administrative Procedure Act, before the Board takes any action under &#xA7; 2-710 or &#xA7; 2-715 of this subtitle, it shall give the person against whom the action is contemplated an opportunity for a hearing before the Board.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Board shall give notice and hold the hearing in accordance with the Administrative Procedure Act.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The person may be represented at the hearing by counsel.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The Board may issue subpoenas in connection with any investigation of charges under &#xA7; 2-710 of this subtitle or proceedings under this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">If, after due notice, the person against whom the action is contemplated fails or refuses to appear, the Board may hear and determine the matter.</section>
  </text>
</law>
