<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gag" order_by="" level="1">Agriculture</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gag-5-201</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>201</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Application" means the spreading of pesticides, by contract or otherwise, for any person owning or renting property.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Certified applicator" means a person who is certified by the Secretary under this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">"Customer" means a person who has entered into a contract with a licensee for pest control.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"Device" means an instrument or mechanical contrivance intended to trap, locate, destroy, control, repel, or mitigate pests.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">"Label" means the written, printed, or graphic matter on, or attached to, the pesticide or device, or any of its containers or wrappers.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">"Labeling" means all written, printed, or graphic matter:<section prefix="(1)">Accompanying the pesticide or device at any time; or</section><section prefix="(2)">To which reference is made on the label or in literature accompanying the pesticide or device, except to current official publications of the:<section prefix="(i)">Environmental Protection Agency;</section><section prefix="(ii)">United States Departments of Agriculture, Interior, and Health and Human Services;</section><section prefix="(iii)">State experiment stations;</section><section prefix="(iv)">State agricultural colleges; or</section><section prefix="(v)">Other similar federal or State institutions or agencies authorized by law to conduct research in the field of pesticides.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(h)">"Pest" means an insect, snail, slug, rodent, nematode, fungus, weed, or any other form of terrestrial or aquatic plant or animal life or virus, bacteria, or other microorganism (except viruses, bacteria, or other microorganisms, on or in living man or any other living animal) which normally is considered to be a pest or which the Secretary declares to be a pest.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">"Pest control" means engaging in, or offering to engage in, recommending, advertising, soliciting the use of, supervising the use of, or using, a pesticide or a device for the identification, control, eradication, mitigation, detection, inspection, or prevention of a pest in, on, or around any house, building, water, air, land, plant, structure, or animal.</section>
    <section prefix="(j)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Pest control applicator" means a person engaged in the business of pest control.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Except as provided by the Secretary, "pest control applicator" includes a person who applies pesticides on any premises where the public is commonly invited for the sale of goods or services.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(k)">"Pest control consultant" means a person who engages in the business of:<section prefix="(1)">Offering or supplying technical advice or supervision;</section><section prefix="(2)">Inspecting for or identifying pests; or</section><section prefix="(3)">Recommending the use of a specific pesticide for the purpose of controlling a pest in or on water, air, land, plants, structures, or animals.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(l)">"Pesticide" means any substance or mixture of substances intended for:<section prefix="(1)">Preventing, destroying, repelling, or mitigating any pest;</section><section prefix="(2)">Use as a plant regulator, defoliant, or desiccant; or</section><section prefix="(3)">Use as a spray adjuvant such as a wetting agent or adhesive.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(m)">"Pesticide business license" means a license issued by the Secretary to any business in accordance with this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(n)">"Place of business" means any location from which pest control is conducted.</section>
    <section prefix="(o)">"Private applicator" means a person who uses a restricted use pesticide for the purpose of producing any agricultural commodity on property owned or rented by the applicator or applicator's employer.</section>
    <section prefix="(p)">"Public agency applicator" means a person employed by a unit of federal, State, county or local government or any training institution which is engaged in pest control.</section>
    <section prefix="(q)">"Registered employee" means an employee of a firm or public agency engaged in pest control.</section>
    <section prefix="(r)">"Restricted use pesticide" means a pesticide so classified by the provisions in this title or by the federal government or the Secretary of Agriculture, State of Maryland.</section>
    <section prefix="(s)">"Supervision" means, unless otherwise provided by federal or State labeling, the act or process whereby the application of a pesticide is made by a competent person acting under the instructions and control of a certified applicator who is:<section prefix="(1)">Responsible for actions of that person; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Available when needed, though the certified applicator may not be physically present at the time and place the pesticide is applied.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
