<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gag" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="8-803" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gag-8-803</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">To apply for certification as a nutrient management consultant, an applicant shall:<section prefix="(1)">Submit to the Department an application on the form the Department requires; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Pay to the Department the certification fee stated in &#xA7; 8-806 of this subtitle.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Department shall certify any individual who:<section prefix="(1)">Meets the requirements of this subtitle;</section><section prefix="(2)">Meets the Department's educational requirements, including a program on the proper application of nutrients;</section><section prefix="(3)">Passes a Department approved examination; and</section><section prefix="(4)"><section prefix="(i)">Is employed by a person licensed under this subtitle; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">Holds a license as required by this subtitle.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">To apply for a license an applicant shall:<section prefix="(1)">Submit to the Department an application on the form the Department requires; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Pay to the Department the applicable license fee stated in &#xA7; 8-806 of this subtitle.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Department shall license a person who meets the requirements of this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">A certificate or license is issued for 1 year unless the certificate or license is renewed as provided by this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The Department shall renew the certificate or license of any applicant for a 3-year term if the applicant:<section prefix="(1)">Submits a renewal application on the form that the Department requires;</section><section prefix="(2)">Pays to the Department the applicable fee stated in &#xA7; 8-806 of this subtitle;</section><section prefix="(3)">Complies with applicable continuing education requirements;</section><section prefix="(4)">Complies with applicable record keeping and reporting requirements; and</section><section prefix="(5)">Otherwise is entitled to be certified or licensed.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Department may issue a farm operator's plan development certificate to a person operating a farm for the development of that person's own nutrient management plan.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The certificate is valid provided the person operating the farm:<section prefix="(i)">Has paid the one-time fee provided in &#xA7; 8-806 of this subtitle;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Has passed an examination as determined by the Department;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Complies with applicable continuing education requirements;</section><section prefix="(iv)">Complies with applicable record keeping and reporting requirements; and</section><section prefix="(v)">Otherwise is entitled to be certified.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
