<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gag" order_by="gag" level="1">Agriculture</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gag-11-315</section_number>
  <catch_line>All liquid fuel shall be sold by liquid measure or by net weight in accordance with the provisions o...</catch_line>
  <order_by>315</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">All liquid fuel shall be sold by liquid measure or by net weight in accordance with the provisions of &#xA7; 11-304 of this subtitle. Price lists of liquid fuel shall be posted or otherwise made available upon request.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Upon delivery of liquid fuel not in package form and in an amount greater than ten gallons in the case of sale by liquid measure, or 100 pounds in the case of sale by weight, a delivery ticket or written statement shall be delivered to the purchaser, either at the time of delivery or within a period mutually agreed upon in writing or otherwise between the vendor and the purchaser. The delivery ticket or a written statement shall have the following information clearly readable in ink or by means of other indelible marking equipment:<section prefix="(1)">The name and address of the vendor;</section><section prefix="(2)">The name and address of the purchaser;</section><section prefix="(3)">The identity of the type of fuel comprising the delivery;</section><section prefix="(4)">The unit price, that is, the price per gallon or per pound of the fuel delivered;</section><section prefix="(5)">In the case of sale by liquid measure, the liquid volume of the delivery, together with any meter readings from which the liquid volume is computed, expressed in terms of the gallon and its binary or decimal subdivisions; and</section><section prefix="(6)">In the case of sale by weight, the net weight of the delivery, together with any weighing scale readings from which the net weight is computed, expressed in terms of tons or pounds avoirdupois.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The provisions of subsection (b) of this section do not apply to deliveries of liquid fuel made on the premises of the vendor if the vendor is supplying the fuel tank of a motor vehicle, motorized equipment, aircraft, or watercraft. The requirement of  subsection (b)(4) of this section does not apply when the product is liquified petroleum gas, which is defined for the purpose of this subsection as a petroleum product composed predominately of propane, propylene, butane, isobutane, butylenes, or mixtures of those products, if the delivery ticket, written statement, or invoice states that the price list is available on request. A ticket or other written statement accompanying the delivery of any other liquid fuels and used only as a bill of lading or manifest is exempt from the requirement of subsection (b)(4) of this section if the ticket or written statement utilized as an invoice for payment indicates all of the information set forth in subsection (b) of this section.</section>
  </text>
</law>
