<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gbo" order_by="gbo" level="1">Business Occupations and Professions</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gbo-15-316</section_number>
  <catch_line>The Board may issue a retired status license to an individual who:...</catch_line>
  <order_by>316</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Board may issue a retired status license to an individual who:<section prefix="(1)">is currently licensed in Maryland as a professional land surveyor or a property line surveyor;</section><section prefix="(2)">has been either licensed as a professional land surveyor or a property line surveyor or was authorized to practice land surveying or property line surveying under &#xA7; 15-303 of this subtitle for at least 25 years, of which 5 years were in Maryland;</section><section prefix="(3)">is not the subject of a pending disciplinary action related to the practice of land surveying or property line surveying in this or another state;</section><section prefix="(4)">submits to the Board an application on the form provided by the Board; and</section><section prefix="(5)">pays to the Board a fee, as set by the Board.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The holder of a retired status license issued under this section may not engage in the practice of professional land surveying or property line surveying.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The holder of a professional land surveyor retired status license may use the designation of "retired professional land surveyor".</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The holder of a property line surveyor retired status license may use the designation of "retired property line surveyor".</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Board may reactivate the license of a retired status license if that individual:<section prefix="(1)">submits to the Board an application for reactivation on the form approved by the Board;</section><section prefix="(2)">meets all continuing competency requirements, not exceeding 48 credit hours, that would have been required for renewal of a license under &#xA7; 15-314 of this subtitle if the licensee had not been placed on retired status;</section><section prefix="(3)">pays to the Board a reactivation fee as set by the Board; and</section><section prefix="(4)">is not the subject of a pending disciplinary action related to the practice of land surveying or property line surveying in this or any other state.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
