<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gbo" order_by="gbo" level="1">Business Occupations and Professions</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gbo-6-306</section_number>
  <catch_line>Except as otherwise provided in &#xA7; 6-306.1 of this subtitle, an applicant who otherwise qualifies fo...</catch_line>
  <order_by>306</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Except as otherwise provided in &#xA7; 6-306.1 of this subtitle, an applicant who otherwise qualifies for a State license is entitled to be examined as provided in this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The State Board shall give examinations to qualified applicants at least twice a year, at the dates, times, and places that the State Board determines.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">At least 15 days before the examination, the State Board shall notify each applicant whether the applicant is eligible to be examined under this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The notice shall specify the passing score for the examination.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The State Board shall determine the subjects and scope of the examination from a list of questions submitted by the Maryland Uniform Electrical Licensing Examination Committee, Inc.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The State Board shall choose examination questions that:<section prefix="(i)">test the applicant's knowledge of all applicable codes, laws, or principles of electrical installation; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">are constructed to determine the fitness of the applicant for a State license.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The State Board may appoint a committee to develop examination questions.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The form of the examination shall be objective and written.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The passing score for the examination shall be 70%.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">Within 45 days after the examination, the State Board shall mail to each applicant notice of the applicant's examination score.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">On written request to the State Board, an applicant who failed an examination may review the answers that the applicant gave and the scores for those answers, at a time and place that the State Board determines.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If an applicant fails to appear for a scheduled examination, the applicant may reapply for an examination.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The applicant:<section prefix="(i)">shall submit to the State Board an application for reexamination on the form that the State Board provides; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">unless, for good cause, the State Board waives payment of the examination fee, shall again pay the examination fee under &#xA7; 6-305 of this subtitle.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
