<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gbo" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="5-605" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gbo-5-605</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Except as provided in &#xA7;&#xA7; 5-302 and 5-303 of this title and subsection (b) of this section, a person may not practice cosmetology, provide esthetic services, or provide nail technician services in any place other than:<section prefix="(1)">a beauty salon that holds a beauty salon permit; or</section><section prefix="(2)">a barbershop that holds a barbershop permit issued under Title 4 of this article.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A licensed cosmetologist, esthetician, or nail technician may practice cosmetology and provide services in:<section prefix="(i)">a facility in which beautification-oriented medical services, authorized by the Department of Health and Mental Hygiene, are provided;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the residence of an individual confined to the residence by reason of a physical or mental infirmity;</section><section prefix="(iii)">an assisted living facility as defined in &#xA7; 19-1801 of the Health - General Article;</section><section prefix="(iv)">a hospice facility defined in &#xA7; 19-901(c) of the Health - General Article;</section><section prefix="(v)">a nursing home as defined in &#xA7; 19-1401(e) of the Health - General Article; or</section><section prefix="(vi)">a hospital as defined in &#xA7; 19-301 of the Health - General Article or a similar institution.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">To practice in any of the locations specified in this subsection:<section prefix="(i)">the licensed cosmetologist, esthetician, or nail technician shall be sponsored by a beauty salon in which the cosmetologist, esthetician, or nail technician is authorized to practice;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the patron to whom the services are rendered shall be a customer of the beauty salon; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">the services shall be rendered by appointment through the beauty salon.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
