<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gbo" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="17-315" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gbo-17-315</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">To qualify for renewal of a license under this subtitle, a licensee shall complete at least 15 clock hours of continuing education instruction, as provided in subsection (b) of this section, during the preceding 2-year term.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Notwithstanding paragraph (1) of this subsection, a licensee shall complete at least 7.5 clock hours of continuing education instruction as provided for in subsection (b) of this section if the licensee:<section prefix="(i)"/><section prefix="(ii)">is not a broker, an associate broker, or a salesperson designated as a branch office manager or team leader.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">For a licensee who provides real estate brokerage services solely in connection with nonresidential real estate, of the clock hours required under paragraph (1) of this subsection, 1.5 clock hours may be satisfied by a course regarding fair housing laws and regulations or the federal Americans with Disabilities Act.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">A licensee who is required to complete continuing education instruction under paragraph (2) of this subsection shall complete the requirements of subsection (b)(2)(ii) and (v) of this section in alternate licensing periods.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">A licensee holding a license from another state must complete at least the number of clock hours of continuing education instruction required under paragraph (1) of this subsection during each 2-year license term and may substitute clock hours of continuing education instruction earned in another state, if those clock hours:<section prefix="(i)">are approved as real estate continuing education in that state; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">meet the distribution requirements of subsection (b)(2) of this section.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(6)">The Commission shall grant the substitution of clock hours in paragraph (5) of this subsection only if the other state permits the substitution of clock hours of continuing education instruction approved by the Commission for a licensee of this State.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Commission shall approve the form, substance, and, as provided under paragraph (2) of this subsection, subject matter of all continuing education courses.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The subject matter approved by the Commission shall:<section prefix="(i)">relate to real estate or to a subject matter intended to assist a licensee in providing real estate brokerage services to the public in a more efficient and effective manner, provided that the subject matter is related to helping the public buy or sell real estate;</section><section prefix="(ii)">every 2 years, include at least one 3 clock hour course that outlines relevant changes that have occurred in federal, State, or local laws and regulations, court cases and industry trends that have an impact on those laws and regulations, or any combination of those laws, regulations, court cases, and industry trends;</section><section prefix="(iii)">every 2 years, include at least one 1.5 clock hour course that outlines federal, State, and local fair housing laws and regulations, including fair housing advertising;</section><section prefix="(iv)">every 2 years, include at least one 3 clock hour ethics course that includes the Maryland Code of Ethics and a discussion of the practices of flipping and predatory lending;</section><section prefix="(v)">every 4 years, include at least one 3 clock hour course that includes the principles of agency and agency disclosure; and</section><section prefix="(vi)">every 4 years for the renewal of a real estate broker license and the renewal of the license of an individual designated as a branch office manager or a team leader, include at least one 3 clock hour course that includes the requirements of broker supervision.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The requirement of paragraph (2)(iii) of this subsection does not apply to a licensee who provides real estate brokerage services solely in connection with nonresidential real estate.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">To be acceptable for credit as a continuing education course under this section, the course shall cover 1 or more topics approved by the Commission.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Continuing education courses may be conducted by:<section prefix="(i)">the Maryland Association of Realtors or its member boards;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the Real Estate Brokers of Baltimore, Inc.;</section><section prefix="(iii)">any similar professional association; or</section><section prefix="(iv)">an educational institution approved by the Commission.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Continuing education courses shall be taught by a qualified instructor who is experienced in the real estate industry.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">On or before January 1, 2003, the Commission shall adopt regulations that provide for the conduct of continuing education instruction courses by:<section prefix="(i)">remote access satellite;</section><section prefix="(ii)">closed-circuit video;</section><section prefix="(iii)">computer, including transmission over the Internet and the World Wide Web;</section><section prefix="(iv)">home study; and</section><section prefix="(v)">any other delivery system approved by the Commission.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">If feasible, continuing education courses shall be offered at reasonable intervals in each county and in each major geographic area of the larger counties.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Subject to subsection (f) of this section, on completion of a continuing education course by a licensee, the entity that conducted the course or the instructor shall issue to the licensee a certificate of completion that states the number of clock hours of that course.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Commission shall accept as evidence of completion of a continuing education course the certificate of completion, a photocopy of the certificate, an electronic mail certificate, or a photocopy of an electronic mail certificate.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Instead of providing a certificate of completion to the licensee under subsection (e) of this section, the entity that conducted the course may submit the course completion information directly to the Commission and the licensee by electronic means.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">On or after January 1, 2013, the Commission may require all entities conducting continuing education courses to submit course completion information only by electronic means.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">The Commission may waive the requirements of this section for a licensee if the licensee shows good cause for being unable to meet the requirements.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">The Commission shall require each course provider to pay a continuing education course application fee of $25.</section>
  </text>
</law>
