<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gbo" order_by="gbo" level="1">Business Occupations and Professions</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gbo-11-409</section_number>
  <catch_line>Subject to the hearing provisions of &#xA7; 11-410 of this subtitle, the Board may deny a license to any...</catch_line>
  <order_by>409</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Subject to the hearing provisions of &#xA7; 11-410 of this subtitle, the Board may deny a license to any applicant, reprimand any licensee, or suspend or revoke a license if the applicant or licensee:<section prefix="(1)">fraudulently or deceptively obtains or attempts to obtain a license for the applicant or licensee or for another;</section><section prefix="(2)">fraudulently or deceptively uses a license;</section><section prefix="(3)">under the laws of the United States or of any state, is convicted of:<section prefix="(i)">a felony; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">a misdemeanor that is directly related to the fitness and qualification of the applicant or licensee to provide pilotage;</section></section><section prefix="(4)">pilots or attempts to pilot a vessel while under the influence of:<section prefix="(i)">alcohol;</section><section prefix="(ii)">narcotics; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">any other substance that impairs the physical or mental ability of the pilot to perform in a safe manner;</section></section><section prefix="(5)">pilots a vessel in a negligent or reckless manner;</section><section prefix="(6)">anchors a vessel during a pilotage transit unless:<section prefix="(i)">the anchorage was ordered by the master of the vessel; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">the anchorage was necessary for reasons of safety or prudent navigation;</section></section><section prefix="(7)">violates the conflict-of-interest provisions of &#xA7; 11-603 of this title;</section><section prefix="(8)">violates any regulation adopted by the Board; or</section><section prefix="(9)">violates any order passed by the Board.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Subject to the hearing provisions of &#xA7; 11-410 of this subtitle, the Board shall revoke the license of any pilot who does not provide pilotage for 1 year.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Notwithstanding paragraph (1) of this subsection, the Board may not revoke a license under this subsection if the failure of the pilot to provide pilotage was due to:<section prefix="(i)">sickness of the pilot; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">assignment to administrative duties.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Subject to the hearing provisions of &#xA7; 11-410 of this subtitle, the Board shall revoke the license of a pilot who, after receiving notice, refuses to aid a vessel in distress:<section prefix="(1)">within 18 nautical miles south of Cape Henry;</section><section prefix="(2)">within 18 nautical miles east of Cape Henry;</section><section prefix="(3)">in the Chesapeake Bay; or</section><section prefix="(4)">in the ports of Maryland.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Instead of or in addition to suspending or revoking a license under subsection (a) of this section, the Board may impose a penalty not to exceed $2,000 for each violation.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">To determine the amount of the penalty imposed under this subsection, the Board shall consider:<section prefix="(i)">the seriousness of the violation;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the harm caused by the violation;</section><section prefix="(iii)">the good faith of the licensee; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">any history of previous violations by the licensee.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The Board shall consider the following facts in the granting, denial, renewal, suspension, or revocation of a license or the reprimand of a licensee when an applicant or licensee is convicted of a felony or misdemeanor described in subsection (a)(3) of this section:<section prefix="(1)">the nature of the crime;</section><section prefix="(2)">the relationship of the crime to the activities authorized by the license;</section><section prefix="(3)">with respect to a felony, the relevance of the conviction to the fitness and qualification of the applicant or licensee to provide pilotage;</section><section prefix="(4)">the length of time since the conviction; and</section><section prefix="(5)">the behavior and activities of the applicant or licensee before and after the conviction.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
