<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gbo" order_by="gbo" level="1">Business Occupations and Professions</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gbo-21-206</section_number>
  <catch_line>The Board may investigate a complaint that alleges a violation of this title....</catch_line>
  <order_by>206</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Board may investigate a complaint that alleges a violation of this title.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">On receipt of the results of an investigation made under this section, the Board shall promptly take action that is appropriate under this title to ensure compliance with this title.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If the Board concludes that conduct alleged to be in violation of this title will result in harm to a resident of the State, the Board may seek a permanent or temporary injunction with respect to the conduct from the circuit court of the county in which the alleged violation occurs.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">In seeking an injunction under this subsection, the Board is not required to:<section prefix="(i)">post bond;</section><section prefix="(ii)">allege or prove that an adequate remedy at law does not exist; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">allege or prove that substantial or irreparable damage would result from the continued violation.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A member of the Board may not be held personally liable for action taken under this subsection in good faith with reasonable grounds.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Board, or a hearing officer designated by the Board, may administer oaths, hold hearings, and take testimony about all matters within the jurisdiction of the Board.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Board or its designee may issue a subpoena for the attendance of a witness to testify or the production of evidence in connection with:<section prefix="(i)">a disciplinary action brought under this title; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">a proceeding brought for an alleged violation of this title.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If an individual fails to comply with a subpoena issued under this subsection, on petition of the Board, a court of competent jurisdiction may compel compliance with the subpoena.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
