<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gbo" order_by="" level="1">Business Occupations and Professions</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gbo-13-410</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>410</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Subject to this section, the Secretary shall commence proceedings under &#xA7; 13-409 of this subtitle on the Secretary's own complaint or on a complaint made to the Secretary by any person.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A complaint shall:<section prefix="(i)">be in writing;</section><section prefix="(ii)">be signed by the complainant; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">state specifically the facts on which the complaint is based.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If a complaint is made by any person other than the Secretary, the complaint shall be made under oath by the person who submits the complaint.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">On receipt of a complaint that alleges facts that are grounds for action under &#xA7; 13-409 of this subtitle, the Secretary shall appoint an officer of the Department of State Police, with the rank of lieutenant or above, as the investigating officer for the complaint.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The investigating officer may assign responsibility for conducting the investigation to other members of the Department of State Police.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">On conclusion of the investigation, the investigating officer shall determine whether there is a reasonable basis to believe that there are grounds for disciplinary action under &#xA7; 13-409 of this subtitle.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If the investigating officer finds a reasonable basis as provided under paragraph (1) of this subsection, the Secretary shall act on the complaint as provided under &#xA7; 13-411 of this subtitle.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
