<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gbo" order_by="gbo" level="1">Business Occupations and Professions</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gbo-17-307</section_number>
  <catch_line>An applicant for a license:...</catch_line>
  <order_by>307</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">An applicant for a license:<section prefix="(1)">shall submit to the Commission an application on the form that the Commission provides;</section><section prefix="(2)">if a testing service was used to administer the examination, shall submit to the Commission a copy of the examination results of the applicant;</section><section prefix="(3)">shall pay into the Guaranty Fund any fee required under &#xA7; 17-403 of this title;</section><section prefix="(4)">shall pay to the Commission a fee set by the Commission; and</section><section prefix="(5)">shall submit to the Commission any additional information or documentation that the Commission requires, including any information or documentation to determine the professional competence or the good character and reputation of the applicant.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">If the applicant is applying for a real estate broker license, the applicant:<section prefix="(1)">shall have submitted to the Commission, by a credit reporting agency approved by the Commission, a credit report that contains the information required by the Commission; or</section><section prefix="(2)">shall have paid to the Commission or the Commission's designee a credit report fee in an amount not to exceed the cost charged by a credit reporting agency approved by the Commission to obtain a credit report that contains the information required by the Commission.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">If the applicant is applying for a real estate salesperson or associate real estate broker license, the applicant shall submit to the Commission adequate evidence that the applicant has obtained, from a licensed real estate broker, a commitment providing that the applicant shall become affiliated with the licensed real estate broker as a real estate salesperson or an associate real estate broker on the granting of a real estate salesperson license or an associate real estate broker license to the applicant.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">If the applicant currently is licensed as a real estate salesperson or an associate real estate broker, the applicant shall submit to the Commission a copy of the written notice required under &#xA7; 17-313 of this subtitle informing each real estate broker with whom the applicant currently is affiliated that the applicant intends to affiliate with an additional real estate broker or to obtain a real estate broker license.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">If the applicant is not a resident of this State, the applicant shall submit to the Commission a consent and any related document required under &#xA7; 17-514 of this title.</section>
  </text>
</law>
