<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gbo" order_by="gbo" level="1">Business Occupations and Professions</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gbo-17-526</section_number>
  <catch_line>The purpose of this section is to prohibit certain discriminatory real estate practices with respect...</catch_line>
  <order_by>526</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The purpose of this section is to prohibit certain discriminatory real estate practices with respect to housing in Montgomery County to:<section prefix="(1)">ensure fair and equal real estate housing practices for all of its residents, regardless of race, color, religion, sex, marital status, national origin, or, as defined in &#xA7; 20-701 of the State Government Article, disability;</section><section prefix="(2)">provide fair and equal real estate housing opportunities for all of its residents, regardless of race, color, religion, sex, marital status, national origin, or, as defined in &#xA7; 20-701 of the State Government Article, disability;</section><section prefix="(3)">ensure fair and equal real estate housing practices and provide fair and equal real estate housing opportunities for those individuals who are at least 62 years of age; and</section><section prefix="(4)">protect and ensure the peace, health, safety, prosperity, and general welfare of all residents of Montgomery County.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">This section applies only in regard to residential property in Montgomery County.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Each real estate broker shall maintain a current and complete registry of all residential properties that:<section prefix="(i)">the broker personally lists for sale or rent in Montgomery County; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">if the broker is a member of a multiple listing service, are listed with the multiple listing service in Montgomery County.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The real estate broker shall break down the properties listed in the registry into price categories that are established by the Commission or the multiple listing service.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">If a prospective buyer or renter requests to see the registry, the real estate broker shall allow the prospective buyer or renter to see the part of the registry for the price category in which the prospective buyer or renter indicates interest.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The Commission shall:<section prefix="(i)">prepare a notice that sets forth the exact language of paragraphs (1) through (3) of this subsection; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">distribute a copy of the notice to each real estate office that is located in Montgomery County.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(5)">Each real estate broker shall post the notice in a conspicuous place in each real estate office of the broker that is located in Montgomery County.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A real estate broker, an associate real estate broker, or a real estate salesperson may not refuse to show any residential property or prospective site for a residence that is available for sale, rent, or sublease to a prospective buyer or renter because of:<section prefix="(i)">the race, color, religion, sex, marital status, national origin, or, as defined in &#xA7; 20-701 of the State Government Article, disability of the prospective buyer or renter; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">the composition or character of the neighborhood where the property is located.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If the representation is made because of the race, color, religion, sex, marital status, national origin, or, as defined in &#xA7; 20-701 of the State Government Article, disability of the prospective buyer or renter or because of the composition or character of the neighborhood where the property is located, a real estate broker, an associate real estate broker, or a real estate salesperson may not represent to a prospective buyer or renter that the available residential properties, prospective sites for a residence, or listings in a specified price range are limited to those already shown when, in fact, there is an additional residential property, a prospective site for a residence, or a listing in a specified price range that is available and within the price range specified by the prospective buyer or renter.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The Commission shall enforce the provisions of this section and, for this purpose, may receive complaints, conduct investigations, issue subpoenas, and hold hearings.</section>
  </text>
</law>
