<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gbo" order_by="gbo" level="1">Business Occupations and Professions</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gbo-17-532</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this section, "client" includes a prospective buyer or lessee under a presumed buyer's agency rel...</catch_line>
  <order_by>532</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, "client" includes a prospective buyer or lessee under a presumed buyer's agency relationship or a presumed lessee's agency relationship as described in &#xA7; 17-533 of this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A licensee shall comply with the provisions of this section when providing real estate brokerage services.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A licensee shall:<section prefix="(i)">act in accordance with the terms of the brokerage agreement;</section><section prefix="(ii)">promote the interests of the client by:<section prefix="1.">seeking a sale or lease of real estate at a price or rent specified in the brokerage agreement or at a price or rent acceptable to the client;</section><section prefix="2.">seeking a sale or lease of real estate on terms specified in the brokerage agreement or on terms acceptable to the client; and</section><section prefix="3.">unless otherwise specified in the brokerage agreement, presenting in a timely manner all written offers or counteroffers to and from the client, even if the real estate is subject to an existing contract of sale or lease;</section></section><section prefix="(iii)">disclose to the client all material facts as required under &#xA7; 17-322 of this title;</section><section prefix="(iv)">treat all parties to the transaction honestly and fairly and answer all questions truthfully;</section><section prefix="(v)">in a timely manner account for all trust money received;</section><section prefix="(vi)">exercise reasonable care and diligence; and</section><section prefix="(vii)">comply with all:<section prefix="1.">requirements of this title;</section><section prefix="2.">applicable federal, State, and local fair housing laws and regulations; and</section><section prefix="3.">other applicable laws and regulations.</section></section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Unless the client consents in writing to the disclosure, a licensee may not disclose confidential information received from or about a client to any other party or licensee acting as the agent of that party or other representative of that party.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Unless the client to whom the confidential information relates consents in writing to a disclosure of that confidential information, a licensee who receives confidential information from or about the licensee's own past or present client or a past or present client of the licensee's broker may not disclose that information to:<section prefix="(i)">any of the licensee's other clients;</section><section prefix="(ii)">any of the clients of the licensee's broker;</section><section prefix="(iii)">any other party;</section><section prefix="(iv)">any licensee acting as an agent for another party; or</section><section prefix="(v)">any representative of another party.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">Unless otherwise specified in the brokerage agreement, a licensee is not required to seek additional offers to purchase or lease real estate while the real estate is subject to an existing contract of sale or lease.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">An intra-company agent may disclose confidential information to the broker or dual agent for whom the intra-company agent works but the broker or dual agent may not disclose that confidential information to the other party or the intra-company agent for the other party, as provided in &#xA7; 17-530(d).</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A licensee does not breach any duty or obligation to the client by:<section prefix="(1)">showing other available properties to prospective buyers or lessees;</section><section prefix="(2)">representing other clients who have or are looking for similar properties for sale or lease;</section><section prefix="(3)">representing other sellers or lessors who have similar properties to that sought by the buyer or lessee; and</section><section prefix="(4)">showing the buyer other available properties.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">This title does not limit the applicability of &#xA7; 10-702 of the Real Property Article.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The requirements of this section are in addition to any other duties required of the agent by law that are not inconsistent with these duties.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">The duties specified in this section may not be waived or modified.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">A licensee who performs ministerial acts for a person may not be construed to:<section prefix="(1)">violate the licensee's duties to the client, provided that the client has consented in the brokerage agreement to the licensee's provision of ministerial acts; or</section><section prefix="(2)">form an agency relationship between the licensee and the person for whom the ministerial acts are performed.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
