<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gbo" order_by="" level="1">Business Occupations and Professions</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gbo-2-101</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>101</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this title the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"AICPA" means the American Institute of Certified Public Accountants.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Attest" means to provide the following financial statement services:<section prefix="(1)">an audit or other engagement performed in accordance with the Statements on Auditing Standards issued by AICPA;</section><section prefix="(2)">a review of a financial statement performed in accordance with the Statements on Standards for Accounting and Review Services issued by AICPA;</section><section prefix="(3)">a compilation;</section><section prefix="(4)">an examination of prospective financial information performed in accordance with the Statements on Standards for Attestation Engagements issued by AICPA; and</section><section prefix="(5)">any engagement performed in accordance with the Auditing Standards of the Public Company Accounting Oversight Board.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">"Board" means the State Board of Public Accountancy.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"Compilation" means a presentation of information in the form of a financial statement that is performed in accordance with the Statements on Standards for Accounting and Review Services issued by AICPA.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">"Home office" is the location specified by a client of a certified public accountant as the address to which a service described in &#xA7; 2-401(a) of this title is directed.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">"License" means, unless the context requires otherwise, a license issued by the Board to practice certified public accountancy.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">"License fee" means the fee paid in connection with the issuance or renewal of a license.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">"Licensed certified public accountant" means, unless the context requires otherwise, an individual licensed by the Board to practice certified public accountancy.</section>
    <section prefix="(j)">"Permit" means, unless the context requires otherwise, a permit issued by the Board to allow a partnership or corporation to operate a business through which an individual may practice certified public accountancy.</section>
    <section prefix="(k)">"Permit fee" means the fee paid in connection with the issuance or renewal of a permit.</section>
    <section prefix="(l)">"Practice certified public accountancy" means to perform any of the following accountancy services:<section prefix="(1)">conducting an audit, review, or compilation of financial statements; or</section><section prefix="(2)">providing a written certificate or opinion offering positive or negative assurance or full or limited assurance on the correctness of the information or on the fairness of the presentation of the information in:<section prefix="(i)">a financial statement;</section><section prefix="(ii)">a report;</section><section prefix="(iii)">a schedule; or</section><section prefix="(iv)">an exhibit.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(m)">"Practice privilege" means the right granted to an individual who is licensed by another state to practice certified public accountancy in this State without a license issued by this State.</section>
    <section prefix="(n)">"Principal place of business" means the office location designated by the licensee for purposes of substantial equivalency and reciprocity.</section>
    <section prefix="(o)">"NASBA" means the National Association of Boards of Accountancy.</section>
  </text>
</law>
