<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gbo" order_by="" level="1">Business Occupations and Professions</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gbo-12-305</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>305</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Subject to the limitations in this section, the Board may waive any of the qualifications for a journey plumber license or a master plumber license for an individual who holds a journey plumber license or a master plumber license issued by Baltimore County or by the Washington Suburban Sanitary Commission.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Board may grant a waiver under this section only if the applicant:<section prefix="(1)">pays the appropriate license fee required under &#xA7; 12-306 of this subtitle;</section><section prefix="(2)">holds a license that is similar to the license for which the applicant is seeking a waiver;</section><section prefix="(3)">if contracting to provide plumbing services in the name of the applicant or another person, submits proof of the liability insurance as required under &#xA7; 12-501 of this title; and</section><section prefix="(4)">provides adequate evidence that the applicant:<section prefix="(i)">meets the qualifications otherwise required by this subtitle; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">at the time that the applicant became licensed in Baltimore County or by the Washington Suburban Sanitary Commission, the applicant:<section prefix="1.">passed an examination that was given by Baltimore County or the Washington Suburban Sanitary Commission and was substantially equivalent to the examination that then was required by the Board; and</section><section prefix="2.">met qualifications for licensing that were set by Baltimore County or the Washington Suburban Sanitary Commission and were substantially equivalent to the qualifications that then were required by the Board.</section></section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Subject to paragraph (2) of this subsection, the Board may grant a waiver of the qualification and examination requirements of &#xA7; 12-302 of this subtitle only if Baltimore County or the Washington Suburban Sanitary Commission waives the qualifications and examination required for individuals licensed by the Board to a similar extent as the Board waives those requirements for individuals licensed by Baltimore County or the Washington Suburban Sanitary Commission.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">An agreement may be made with Baltimore County that, if an individual who is licensed by the Board as a journey plumber or a master plumber resides in Baltimore County, the individual may be required to pass a licensing examination for a journey plumber or master plumber given by Baltimore County.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
