<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gbo" order_by="" level="1">Business Occupations and Professions</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gbo-5-304</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>304</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">To qualify for a license to practice as a cosmetologist, an applicant shall be an individual who meets the requirements of this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The applicant shall be at least 17 years old.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The applicant shall have completed successfully a 9th grade education or the equivalent.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Except as otherwise provided in this subsection, an applicant shall have received training by:<section prefix="1.">serving as a registered apprentice as provided under &#xA7;&#xA7; 5-404 and 5-405(e) of this title; or</section><section prefix="2.">successfully completing a required program of at least 1,500 hours of training in a cosmetology school that is approved by the State Board of Education or the Maryland Higher Education Commission in consultation with the Board.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">If an applicant is a barber or master barber currently licensed in this State, the Board shall:<section prefix="1.">credit the applicant with having met one-half of the training requirements of subparagraph (i) of this paragraph; and</section><section prefix="2.">determine the manner in which the credit will be applied.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">An applicant meets the requirements of this subsection if:<section prefix="1.">the applicant has held a cosmetologist license in another state or foreign country and has actively practiced cosmetology in the other state or foreign country for a period of 6 months; or</section><section prefix="2.">the applicant has been trained in a cosmetology school in another state or foreign country that has standards substantially equivalent to or more stringent than the standards of a school that is approved by the State Board of Education or the Maryland Higher Education Commission in consultation with the Board.</section></section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(5)">Except as otherwise provided in this subtitle, the applicant shall pass a written and practical examination given by the Board under this subtitle.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">To qualify for a license as a senior cosmetologist, an applicant shall:<section prefix="(1)">have 2 years of experience as a licensed cosmetologist; and</section><section prefix="(2)">pass an examination approved by the Board.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
