<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gbo" order_by="gbo" level="1">Business Occupations and Professions</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gbo-6.5-312</section_number>
  <catch_line>Except as provided in subsection (e) of this section and unless a license is renewed for a 2-year te...</catch_line>
  <order_by>312</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Except as provided in subsection (e) of this section and unless a license is renewed for a 2-year term as provided in this section, the license expires every other year on the anniversary of the date of issuance of the license.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">At least 1 month before a license expires, the Board shall mail to the licensee, at the last known address of the licensee:<section prefix="(i)">a renewal application form; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">a notice that states:<section prefix="1.">the date on which the current license expires;</section><section prefix="2.">the date by which the Board must receive the renewal application for the renewal to be issued and mailed before the license expires; and</section><section prefix="3.">the amount of the renewal fee as required under &#xA7; 6.5-207 of this title.</section></section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The failure of a licensee to receive the notice as provided for in this subsection does not prevent the license from expiring as specified under subsection (a) of this section.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Before a license expires, the licensee periodically may renew it for an additional 2-year term, if the licensee:<section prefix="(1)">otherwise is entitled to be licensed;</section><section prefix="(2)">pays to the Board the appropriate license renewal fee required under &#xA7; 6.5-207 of this title; and</section><section prefix="(3)">submits to the Board a renewal application on the form that the Board provides.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Board shall renew the license of and issue a renewal certificate to each licensee who meets the requirements of this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Board shall include on each renewal certificate that the Board issues the date on which the current license expires.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The Secretary may determine that licenses issued under this subtitle shall expire on a staggered basis.</section>
  </text>
</law>
