<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gbo" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="10-101" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gbo-10-101</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this title the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Admission to the Bar" means, unless the context requires otherwise, authorization by the Court of Appeals to practice law in the State.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Attorney at law" means a lawyer who, while practicing law, represents another person.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">"Bar" means, unless the context requires otherwise, the Bar of the Court of Appeals of Maryland.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"Board" means the State Board of Law Examiners.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Court" means, unless the context requires otherwise:<section prefix="(i)">the Court of Appeals;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the Court of Special Appeals;</section><section prefix="(iii)">a circuit court; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">the District Court of Maryland.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Court" does not include:<section prefix="(i)">an orphans' court; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">the Maryland Tax Court.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">"Lawyer" means an individual who is admitted to the Bar.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Practice law" means to engage in any of the following activities:<section prefix="(i)">giving legal advice;</section><section prefix="(ii)">representing another person before a unit of the State government or of a political subdivision; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">performing any other service that the Court of Appeals defines as practicing law.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Practice law" includes:<section prefix="(i)">advising in the administration of probate of estates of decedents in an orphans' court of the State;</section><section prefix="(ii)">preparing an instrument that affects title to real estate;</section><section prefix="(iii)">preparing or helping in the preparation of any form or document that is filed in a court or affects a case that is or may be filed in a court; or</section><section prefix="(iv)">giving advice about a case that is or may be filed in a court.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
