<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gbo" order_by="" level="1">Business Occupations and Professions</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gbo-20-401</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>401</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">A private home detention monitoring agency shall:<section prefix="(1)">monitor individuals in accordance with any applicable orders of court;</section><section prefix="(2)">monitor 24 hours a day and 7 days a week individuals who are under a court order that requires monitoring by a private home detention monitoring agency; and</section><section prefix="(3)">utilize electronic equipment or other monitoring methods that meet or exceed standards established in regulations by the Secretary.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Upon determining that a defendant subject to private home detention monitoring under the provisions of &#xA7; 5-201(b) of the Criminal Procedure Article has been missing for 24 hours, the private home detention monitoring agency responsible for monitoring the defendant shall, on the next business day, notify the court that ordered private home detention monitoring as a condition of the defendant's pretrial release.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If the court that ordered private detention monitoring as a condition of a defendant's pretrial release under the provisions of &#xA7; 5-201(b) of the Criminal Procedure Article requests that it be notified if the defendant violates any other conditions of pretrial release, the private home detention monitoring agency responsible for monitoring the defendant shall provide the court with the requested notice.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Upon determining that an individual who is subject to private home detention monitoring as a condition of probation has been missing for 24 hours, the private home detention monitoring agency responsible for monitoring the individual shall, on the next business day, notify the Division of Parole and Probation.</section>
  </text>
</law>
