<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gbo" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="15-101" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gbo-15-101</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this title the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Board" means the State Board for Professional Land Surveyors.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Design coordination" means the review and coordination of services provided by individuals licensed or certified under Titles 3, 8, 9, 14, and 15 of this article.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">"Land surveyor" means an individual who practices land surveying.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"License" means, unless the context requires otherwise, a license issued by the Board to practice:<section prefix="(i)">land surveying; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">property line surveying.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"License" includes, unless the context requires otherwise:<section prefix="(i)">a license to practice land surveying; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">a license to practice property line surveying.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">"License fee" means, as applicable, the fee paid in connection with the issuance and renewal of a license and the issuance of a limited license, temporary license, and reciprocal license.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">"Licensed property line surveyor" means, unless the context requires otherwise, a property line surveyor who is licensed by the Board to practice property line surveying.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">"Permit" means, unless the context requires otherwise, a permit issued by the Board to allow a corporation or partnership to operate a business through which an individual may practice land surveying or property line surveying.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">"Permit fee" means, as applicable, the fee paid in connection with the issuance and renewal of a permit.</section>
    <section prefix="(j)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Practice land surveying" means any service, work, documentation, or practice, the performance or preparation of which requires the application of special knowledge of the principles of mathematics, the related physical and applied sciences, and the requirements of the relevant law, as applied to:<section prefix="(i)">measuring, platting, and locating lines, angles, elevations, natural or artificial features in the air, on the surface of the earth, in underground work, and on the beds of bodies of water for the purpose of determining and reporting positions, topography, areas, and volumes;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the platting or replatting, establishing or reestablishing, locating or relocating, or setting or resetting the monumentation for boundaries of real property, easements, or rights-of-way;</section><section prefix="(iii)">platting, layout, and preparation of surveys, plats, plans, and drawings, including:</section><section prefix="(iv)">conducting horizontal and vertical control surveys, layout or stake-out of proposed construction, and the preparation and platting of as-constructed surveys;</section><section prefix="(v)">utilizing measurement devices or systems, such as aerial photogrammetry, global positioning systems, land information systems, geographic information systems, or similar technology for evaluation or location of boundaries of real property, easements, or rights-of-way; and</section><section prefix="(vi)">in conjunction with the site development or subdivision of land, the preparation and design of plans for the following projects, provided that such preparation and design are in accordance with design manuals, details, and standards accepted by the State or local authority:</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Practice land surveying" does not include the design, preparation, or specifications for:<section prefix="(i)">community water or wastewater treatment collection or distribution systems;</section><section prefix="(ii)">community pumping or lift stations; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">geotechnical or structural design components of sediment control or stormwater management ponds or basins.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(k)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Practice property line surveying" means to practice land surveying, except for the services excluded under paragraph (2) of this subsection.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Practice property line surveying" does not include the performance of the services described in subsection (j)(1)(vi) of this section.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(l)">"Professional land surveyor" means, unless the context requires otherwise, a land surveyor who is licensed by the Board to practice land surveying.</section>
    <section prefix="(m)">"Property line surveyor" means an individual who practices property line surveying.</section>
    <section prefix="(n)">"Responsible charge" means direct control and personal direction of the investigation, design, construction, or operation of land surveying work that requires initiative, professional skill, and independent judgment.</section>
  </text>
</law>
