<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gbo" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="6-401" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gbo-6-401</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Subject to the limitations in this subtitle, an individual who holds a State license or qualifies for a State license may use the State license to:<section prefix="(1)">obtain a local license; and</section><section prefix="(2)">assign that local license to another person, including a sole proprietorship, who engages in the business of providing electrical services.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Subject to the limitations in this section, if an individual obtains a State license on the basis of a local license under Subtitle 5 of this title and that local license has been assigned to a person who engages in the business of providing electrical services, the individual shall identify on the State license the person to whom that local license has been assigned.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Subject to the limitations in this section, if an individual obtains a local license on the basis of a State license and intends to assign that local license to a person who engages in the business of providing electrical services, the individual shall identify on the State license the person to whom that local license is to be assigned.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If, at the time of application for a State license, an individual intends to assign a local license obtained on the basis of the State license, the individual shall:<section prefix="(i)">meet the requirements for issuance of a State license under &#xA7; 6-309 of this title;</section><section prefix="(ii)">include, on the application form submitted to the State Board, the name of the person to whom the local license is to be assigned;</section><section prefix="(iii)">pay the appropriate State license fee under &#xA7; 6-309 of this title; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">submit to the State Board proof of general liability and property damage insurance as required under &#xA7; 6-604 of this title.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If an individual obtains a State license on the basis of a local license that has been assigned, the individual shall:<section prefix="(i)">meet the requirements for issuance of a State license under &#xA7; 6-309 of this title;</section><section prefix="(ii)">include, on an application form submitted to the State Board, the name of the person to whom the local license has been assigned;</section><section prefix="(iii)">pay the appropriate State license fee under &#xA7; 6-309 of this title; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">submit to the State Board proof of general liability and property damage insurance as required under &#xA7; 6-604 of this title.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">If, after issuance of a State license to an individual, the individual intends to assign a local license obtained on the basis of the State license, the individual shall:<section prefix="(i)">meet the notification requirements of &#xA7; 6-314 of this title;</section><section prefix="(ii)">submit to the State Board an application for identification of the assignment on the State license;</section><section prefix="(iii)">pay to the State Board an identification fee of $50;</section><section prefix="(iv)">submit to the State Board proof of general liability and property damage insurance as required under &#xA7; 6-604 of this title; and</section><section prefix="(v)">return the State license.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If an individual obtains a local license by the use of the State license of the individual, the local license may be assigned at any 1 time to only 1 person who engages in the business of providing electrical services.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If at any time an individual holds 2 or more current local licenses that were obtained by the use of a State license, the individual may assign those local licenses only if the assignment is made to the same person.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
