<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gbo" order_by="" level="1">Business Occupations and Professions</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gbo-16-211</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>211</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Commission shall refer to the appropriate hearing board for a hearing any matter for which a hearing may be required under &#xA7; 16-701, &#xA7; 16-701.1, or &#xA7; 16-701.2 of this title.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The hearing board may exercise the same powers and shall conduct a hearing in accordance with the same procedures applicable to the Commission under &#xA7; 16-602 of this title.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The hearing board shall determine if there is a reasonable basis to believe that there are grounds for disciplinary action under this title against a licensee.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">If the hearing board finds a reasonable basis as provided under paragraph (1) of this subsection, the hearing board shall:<section prefix="1.">hold a hearing on the matter; and</section><section prefix="2.">file its finding with the Commission.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">If the hearing board does not find a reasonable basis as provided under paragraph (1) of this subsection, the hearing board shall dismiss the complaint.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A hearing board shall advise the Commission specifically of any action brought against a licensee as a result of monetary loss, misappropriation of money, or fraud.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Within 15 days after the filing of a decision by a hearing board, the Commission or any of its members may file an exception to the decision of the hearing board.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">On the filing of an exception under subparagraph (i) of this paragraph, the Commission shall set a hearing on the matter.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If an exception is not filed within the time allowed under paragraph (1)(i) of this subsection:<section prefix="(i)">the decision of the hearing board shall be considered as the final decision of the Commission; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">any party aggrieved by the decision may take a judicial appeal as provided in this title.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
