<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gbo" order_by="" level="1">Business Occupations and Professions</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gbo-16-101</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>101</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this title the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Appraisal" means an analysis, conclusion, or opinion about the nature, quality, utility, or value of interests in or aspects of identified real estate.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Appraisal" includes:<section prefix="(i)">a valuation appraisal;</section><section prefix="(ii)">an analysis assignment; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">a review assignment.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Appraisal" does not include an opinion to a potential seller or third party by a person licensed under Title 17 of this article about the recommended listing price or recommended purchase price of real estate, provided that the opinion is not referred to as an appraisal.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Appraisal report" means any communication, oral or written, of an appraisal.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Certificate" means, unless the context requires otherwise, a certificate issued by the Commission that allows an individual to provide certified real estate appraisal services.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Certificate" includes, unless the context requires otherwise, each of the following certificates:<section prefix="(i)">a certificate to provide certified real estate appraisal services for general real estate; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">a certificate to provide certified real estate appraisal services for residential real estate.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"Certified appraisal report" means an appraisal report prepared and signed by a certified real estate appraiser.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Certified real estate appraiser" means, unless the context requires otherwise, an individual who is certified by the Commission to provide certified real estate appraisal services.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Certified real estate appraiser" includes:<section prefix="(i)">a certified real estate appraiser for general real estate; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">a certified real estate appraiser for residential real estate.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">"Commission" means the State Commission of Real Estate Appraisers, Appraisal Management Companies, and Home Inspectors.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">"Home inspection" means a written evaluation of one or more of the components of an existing residential building, including the heating system, cooling system, plumbing system, electrical system, structural components, foundation, roof, masonry structure, exterior and interior components, or any other related residential housing component.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">"Home inspector" means an individual who provides home inspection services for compensation.</section>
    <section prefix="(j)">"License" means, unless the context requires otherwise, a license issued by the Commission to provide real estate appraisal services or to provide home inspection services.</section>
    <section prefix="(k)">"Licensed home inspector" means an individual who is licensed by the Commission to provide home inspection services.</section>
    <section prefix="(l)">"Licensed real estate appraiser" means an individual who is licensed by the Commission to provide real estate appraisal services.</section>
    <section prefix="(m)">"Provide certified real estate appraisal services" means to provide real estate appraisal services as a certified real estate appraiser.</section>
    <section prefix="(n)">"Provide home inspection services" means to provide home inspection services as a licensed home inspector.</section>
    <section prefix="(o)">"Provide real estate appraisal services" means to make for consideration an appraisal of real estate or prepare or sign an appraisal report in connection with a federally related transaction, as defined in the federal Financial Institutions Reform, Recovery, and Enforcement Act of 1989.</section>
    <section prefix="(p)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Real estate" means any interest in real property that is located in the State or elsewhere.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Real estate" includes:<section prefix="(i)">an interest in a condominium; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">a time-share estate or a time-share license, as those terms are defined in &#xA7; 11A-101 of the Real Property Article.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(q)">"Real estate appraiser trainee" means an individual who is licensed by the Commission to provide real estate appraisal services while:<section prefix="(1)">under the supervision of a supervising appraiser; and</section><section prefix="(2)">in training to become a licensed real estate appraiser or certified real estate appraiser.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(r)">"Supervising appraiser" means a certified residential real estate appraiser or a certified general real estate appraiser who has the responsibility of supervising one or more real estate appraiser trainees.</section>
    <section prefix="(s)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Supervision" means the responsibility of a supervising appraiser to provide on-site direction or immediately available direction, through written instructions or by electronic means, to real estate appraiser trainees performing real estate appraisal services.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Supervision" includes a supervising appraiser accepting direct responsibility for a real estate appraisal prepared by the real estate appraiser trainee while the trainee is under the supervising appraiser's direction on a specific appraisal assignment.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
