<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gbo" order_by="" level="1">Business Occupations and Professions</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gbo-13-101</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>101</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this title the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Central Repository" means the Criminal Justice Information System Central Repository of the Department of Public Safety and Correctional Services.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Certification card" means a card issued by the Secretary under &#xA7; 13-406 of this title to an individual certified as a private detective.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">"Firm" means a partnership or corporation.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"Firm member" means a partner of a partnership or an officer or director of a corporation.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">"License" means, unless the context requires otherwise, a license issued by the Secretary to conduct a business to provide private detective services.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">"Licensed private detective agency" means, unless the context requires otherwise, a person who is licensed by the Secretary to conduct a business that provides private detective services.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">"Private detective" means an individual who personally provides private detective services.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">"Private detective agency" means a person who conducts a business that provides private detective services.</section>
    <section prefix="(j)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Provide private detective services" means to provide, for compensation, the service of:<section prefix="(i)">conducting an investigation that concerns:<section prefix="1.">a crime or wrong committed, assumed to have been committed, or threatened to be committed;</section><section prefix="2.">the identity, habits, conduct, movement, location, affiliations, associations, transactions, reputation, or character of any person;</section><section prefix="3.">the credibility of a witness or of any other individual;</section><section prefix="4.">the location of a missing individual;</section><section prefix="5.">the location or recovery of lost or stolen property;</section><section prefix="6.">the origin or cause of or responsibility for:</section><section prefix="7.">the affiliation, connection, or relation of any person with an organization or other person; or</section><section prefix="8.">the activities, conduct, efficiency, loyalty, or honesty of any employee, agent, contractor, or subcontractor;</section></section><section prefix="(ii)">securing evidence for use before any investigating committee, board of award, or board of arbitration or for use in the trial of any civil or criminal cause;</section><section prefix="(iii)">nonuniformed personal protection; or</section><section prefix="(iv)">conducting an investigation to locate or apprehend a fugitive from justice, unless the person:<section prefix="1.">conducting the investigation is a property bail bondsman or licensed by the Insurance Commissioner of the State or a similar licensing body of another state as a bail bondsman;</section><section prefix="2.">is an employee of a property bail bondsman or a licensed bail bondsman for the purpose of locating or apprehending fugitives from justice; or</section><section prefix="3.">is authorized as an agent by a property bail bondsman or licensed bail bondsman in advance of the apprehension of a fugitive from justice.</section></section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Provide private detective services" does not include:<section prefix="(i)">performing any activity of a person who is engaged exclusively in the business of making investigations and reports that relate to the financial standing, creditworthiness, or financial responsibility of any person;</section><section prefix="(ii)">performing any activity of a person who is engaged exclusively in the business of making a report for an insurance or credit purpose, except if the making of the report involves an investigation or surveillance of a sort normally performed by a person who otherwise is subject to this title;</section><section prefix="(iii)">monitoring an electronically controlled burglar or fire alarm system with a central unit; or</section><section prefix="(iv)">making a marketing survey.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(k)">"Representative member" means a firm member who is appointed under &#xA7; 13-302(b) of this title to act on behalf of the firm.</section>
    <section prefix="(l)">"Secretary" means the Secretary of State Police.</section>
  </text>
</law>
