<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gbo" order_by="gbo" level="1">Business Occupations and Professions</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gbo-16-5A-03</section_number>
  <catch_line>A supervising appraiser shall:...</catch_line>
  <order_by>03</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">A supervising appraiser shall:<section prefix="(1)">review, sign, and certify that the real estate trainee's appraisal report complies with the uniform standards of professional appraisal practice;</section><section prefix="(2)">physically inspect each appraised property with the real estate appraiser trainee until the supervising appraiser determines that the real estate appraiser trainee is competent in accordance with paragraph (3) of this subsection;</section><section prefix="(3)">determine that the real estate appraiser trainee meets the competency requirements of the uniform standards of professional appraisal practice;</section><section prefix="(4)">at least once a month, sign and affix the supervising appraiser's license or certification number to the real estate appraiser trainee's experience log;</section><section prefix="(5)">ensure that the tasks assigned a real estate appraiser trainee will, over time, provide the full range of experience required by the Commission;</section><section prefix="(6)">provide the real estate appraiser trainee with a copy of all appraisal reports prepared by the real estate appraiser trainee that the Commission requests for review; and</section><section prefix="(7)">keep copies of appraisal reports prepared by the real estate appraiser trainee for the later of:<section prefix="(i)">5 years; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">5 years after final disposition of any judicial proceeding in which testimony was given.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A real estate appraiser trainee shall:<section prefix="(1)">keep separate experience logs for each supervising appraiser;</section><section prefix="(2)">sign appraisal reports that the real estate appraiser trainee prepares; and</section><section prefix="(3)">upon request, provide experience logs to the Commission.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A real estate appraiser trainee may have more than one supervising appraiser.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A real estate appraiser trainee may obtain copies of appraisal reports which were prepared by that trainee from the supervising appraiser.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">An appraiser trainee is subject to the uniform standards of professional appraisal practice.</section>
  </text>
</law>
