<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gbo" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="15-315" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gbo-15-315</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Board shall reinstate the license of an individual who, for any reason, has failed to renew the license if the individual:<section prefix="(1)">applies to the Board for reinstatement within 2 years after the license expires;</section><section prefix="(2)">meets the renewal requirements of &#xA7; 15-314 of this subtitle; and</section><section prefix="(3)">except as otherwise provided in subsection (d) of this section, pays to the Board a reinstatement fee set by the Board.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If an individual has failed to renew a license to practice land surveying for any reason and then applies to the Board for reinstatement more than 2 years after the license has expired, the Board:<section prefix="(i)">may require the individual to reapply for a license in the same manner as an applicant applies for an original license under this subtitle; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">subject to paragraph (2) of this subsection, may reinstate the license.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Board may reinstate a license under paragraph (1) of this subsection only if the individual:<section prefix="(i)">meets the renewal requirements of &#xA7; 15-314 of this subtitle;</section><section prefix="(ii)">if required by the Board, states reasons why reinstatement should be granted; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">except as otherwise provided in subsection (d) of this section, pays to the Board a reinstatement fee set by the Board.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If an individual has failed to renew a license to practice property line surveying for any reason and then applies to the Board for reinstatement more than 2 years after the license has expired, the Board, subject to paragraph (2) of this subsection, may reinstate the license.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Board may reinstate a license under paragraph (1) of this subsection only if the individual:<section prefix="(i)">meets the renewal requirements of &#xA7; 15-314 of this subtitle;</section><section prefix="(ii)">if required by the Board, states reasons why reinstatement should be granted; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">except as otherwise provided in subsection (d) of this section, pays to the Board a reinstatement fee set by the Board.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Board may waive a reinstatement fee for a licensee who provides evidence satisfactory to the Board that the licensee did not practice land surveying or property line surveying, as appropriate, during the time the license lapsed.</section>
  </text>
</law>
