<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gbo" order_by="gbo" level="1">Business Occupations and Professions</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gbo-12-205</section_number>
  <catch_line>The Board may adopt regulations to amend the State Plumbing Code....</catch_line>
  <order_by>205</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Board may adopt regulations to amend the State Plumbing Code.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Board may adopt, as part of the State Plumbing Code, regulations to carry out the purposes of and to enforce &#xA7;&#xA7; 12-605 and 12-606 of this title.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Board may adopt standards of the American National Standards Institute or any other nationally recognized organization.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Board shall adopt, as part of the State Plumbing Code, regulations to carry out the purposes of and to enforce &#xA7;&#xA7; 12-605.1 and 12-605.2 of this title.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">At least once a year, the Board shall review:<section prefix="(i)">new and existing standards of the American National Standards Institute and any other organization listed in the State Plumbing Code or the Model Performance Building Code for water conserving appliances, devices, fittings, and fixtures; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">the availability and cost of water conserving appliances, devices, fittings, and fixtures that conform to the standards.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If the Board finds that a water conserving appliance, device, fitting, or fixture that conforms to the standards of the American National Standards Institute or any other organization listed in the State Plumbing Code or the Model Performance Building Code is readily available at reasonable cost, the Board shall amend the State Plumbing Code to:<section prefix="(i)">incorporate the standards for and require use of the water conserving appliance, device, fitting, or fixture; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">require the use of a water supply system and a drainage and venting system that are designed based on the hydraulic requirements of the required water conserving appliances, devices, fittings, and fixtures.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Notwithstanding the availability and cost of the appliance, device, fitting, or fixture, the Board may allow, under the State Plumbing Code, the installation of a water conserving appliance, device, fitting, or fixture that meets the standards of the American National Standards Institute or any other organization listed in the State Plumbing Code or the Model Performance Building Code, subject to the use of a water supply system and a venting and drainage system design based on the hydraulic requirements of the appliance, device, fitting, or fixture.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">On or before July 1 of each year and subject to &#xA7; 2-1246 of the State Government Article, the Board shall submit to the General Assembly a written report on the implementation of this subsection, including the results of the review conducted under this subsection.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Board shall:<section prefix="(1)">periodically publish an updated version of the State Plumbing Code; and</section><section prefix="(2)">make available on request of any person a copy of the State Plumbing Code for a reasonable fee.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
