<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gbo" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="4-407" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gbo-4-407</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Subject to the hearing provisions of &#xA7; 4-408 of this subtitle, the Board may deny registration as an apprentice barber to any applicant, reprimand any individual registered as an apprentice barber, or suspend or revoke the registration of any individual registered as an apprentice barber:<section prefix="(1)">for any applicable ground under &#xA7; 4-314 of this title;</section><section prefix="(2)">if the applicant or individual fraudulently or deceptively obtains or attempts to obtain registration for the applicant or individual or for another; or</section><section prefix="(3)">if the applicant or individual fraudulently or deceptively uses a certificate of registration.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Instead of or in addition to reprimanding an individual registered as an apprentice barber or suspending or revoking the registration under this section, the Board may impose a penalty not exceeding $300 for all violations cited on a single day.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">To determine the amount of the penalty imposed under this section, the Board shall consider:<section prefix="(i)">the seriousness of the violation;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the good faith of the violator;</section><section prefix="(iii)">the violator's history of previous violations;</section><section prefix="(iv)">the deleterious effect of the violation on the complainant, the public, and the barber industry; and</section><section prefix="(v)">any other factors relevant to the determination of the penalty.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Board shall pay any penalty collected under this section into the General Fund of the State.</section>
  </text>
</law>
