<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gbo" order_by="gbo" level="1">Business Occupations and Professions</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gbo-5-205</section_number>
  <catch_line>In addition to any duties set forth elsewhere, the Board shall adopt:...</catch_line>
  <order_by>205</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In addition to any duties set forth elsewhere, the Board shall adopt:<section prefix="(1)">bylaws for the conduct of its proceedings;</section><section prefix="(2)">regulations for qualification and examination of applicants for licenses, registration, and permits and issuance of licenses, certificates of registration, and permits;</section><section prefix="(3)">regulations to govern the conduct of persons regulated under this title;</section><section prefix="(4)">regulations to govern sanitation and safety in practicing cosmetology, including regulations that establish precautions to prevent the spread of infectious and contagious diseases; and</section><section prefix="(5)">regulations to govern the direct supervision of the operation of limited practice beauty salons.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Board shall establish reasonable fees for licensing, licensing renewal, examinations, reinstatements, certifications, applications, preopening inspections, per diem fees for Board members, compensation for inspectors appointed by the Board, and for any other service performed by the Board necessary to carry out the provisions of this title.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Except for the examination fees which the Board shall establish in amounts not to exceed the costs of the examinations and subject to subparagraph (ii) of this paragraph, the fees established by the Board shall be set in a manner that will produce funds sufficient to cover the actual direct and indirect costs of regulating the cosmetology industry in the State in accordance with the provisions of this title.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The Board may not set fees for licensing and license renewals that exceed $50.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The total cost of regulating the cosmetology industry in the State in accordance with the provisions of this title may not be more than the revenues generated by the fees established under paragraph (1) of this subsection.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Board shall adopt regulations that establish detailed curriculum standards for use by the State Board of Education or the Maryland Higher Education Commission in approving applications for instruction in the practice of cosmetology, the provision of esthetic services, and the provision of nail technician services at public schools or private career schools.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The curriculum standards established under paragraph (1) of this subsection shall:<section prefix="(i)">incorporate modern methods and practices for:<section prefix="1.">practicing cosmetology;</section><section prefix="2.">providing esthetic services; and</section><section prefix="3.">providing nail technician services;</section></section><section prefix="(ii)">include a reference to each topic and the emphasis of each topic required of a comprehensive curriculum in the appropriate licensing area; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">be reviewed and updated periodically as determined by the Board.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
