<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gbo" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="21-403" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gbo-21-403</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">An individual tax preparer shall maintain for a length of time specified by the Board that is not more stringent than a length of time specified under federal law all records of personal income tax returns prepared by the individual tax preparer.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Prior to rendering individual tax preparation services, an individual tax preparer shall disclose to the customer, in writing:<section prefix="(i)">the individual tax preparer's name, address, and telephone number;</section><section prefix="(ii)">that the individual tax preparer is not a certified public accountant, an enrolled agent, or a tax attorney;</section><section prefix="(iii)">services that the individual tax preparer is qualified to provide;</section><section prefix="(iv)">the individual tax preparer's education and training, including examinations taken and successfully passed; and</section><section prefix="(v)">any other information that the Board requires.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A disclosure required under this subsection shall be provided to a customer:<section prefix="(i)">at an initial meeting between the individual tax preparer and the customer; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">if the individual tax preparer maintains a website, on the website.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">An individual tax preparer may not:<section prefix="(1)">fail to sign a customer's individual tax return;</section><section prefix="(2)">obtain the customer's signature on an individual tax return or other authorizing document prior to the completion of the individual tax preparation services; or</section><section prefix="(3)">disclose information received for the purposes of preparing a customer's federal or State income tax return, unless:<section prefix="(i)">consented to in writing by the customer;</section><section prefix="(ii)">expressly authorized by law;</section><section prefix="(iii)">necessary for the preparation of the tax return; or</section><section prefix="(iv)">in accordance with a court order.</section></section></section>
  </text>
</law>
