<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gbo" order_by="gbo" level="1">Business Occupations and Professions</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gbo-6-604</section_number>
  <catch_line>This section does not apply to a State licensee on inactive status....</catch_line>
  <order_by>604</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">This section does not apply to a State licensee on inactive status.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A master electrician who is licensed by the State Board and provides electrical services or a person to whom the master electrician assigns a local license under this title shall:<section prefix="(1)">maintain general liability insurance in the amount of at least $300,000;</section><section prefix="(2)">maintain property damage insurance in the amount of at least $100,000; and</section><section prefix="(3)">submit proof of the required insurance to the State Board.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">An applicant for a State license shall submit proof of the insurance required under this section to the State Board with the license application.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The State Board may not issue a State license to an applicant to whom the insurance requirements of this section would apply unless the applicant submits proof of the insurance.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Unless an applicant meets the insurance requirements of this section, the State Board may not renew a State license of the applicant to whom the insurance requirements of this section would apply.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">If the insurance required under this section is canceled, the insurer shall notify the State Board within 10 days after the date of cancellation.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">If a local jurisdiction requires an applicant for a local license to execute a bond to the local jurisdiction, the applicant may satisfy the bond requirement by submitting proof of the insurance required under this section.</section>
  </text>
</law>
