<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gbo" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="4-101" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gbo-4-101</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this title the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Apprentice barber" means an individual who, under the supervision of a master barber, is learning to practice barbering in a barbershop that holds a barbershop permit.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Barber" means an individual who practices barbering.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Barbershop" means any commercial establishment, except a beauty salon, in which an individual practices barbering.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Barbershop" does not include a clinic in a barber school.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"Barbershop permit" means a permit issued by the Board to operate a barbershop.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">"Board" means the State Board of Barbers.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"License" means, unless the context requires otherwise, a license issued by the Board to practice barbering.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"License" includes, unless the context requires otherwise, each of the following licenses:<section prefix="(i)">a master barber license; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">a barber license.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(h)">"Master barber" means a barber who:<section prefix="(1)">has at least 15 months experience as a licensed barber; and</section><section prefix="(2)">has passed a test approved by the Board.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(i)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Practice barbering" means to provide to an individual for compensation the service of:<section prefix="(i)">cutting, razor cutting, styling, relaxing, body waving, shampooing, or coloring the hair;</section><section prefix="(ii)">shaving or trimming the beard;</section><section prefix="(iii)">massaging the face;</section><section prefix="(iv)">designing, fitting, or cutting a hairpiece; or</section><section prefix="(v)">performing any other similar procedure on the hair, beard, face, or hairpiece of the individual.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Practice barbering" does not include:<section prefix="(i)">the mere sale of wigs or hairpieces; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">the services performed by an employee under the supervision of a master barber in a barbershop that holds a barbershop permit that are restricted to:</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
