<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gbo" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="17-505" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gbo-17-505</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">A real estate broker shall maintain trust money in an account authorized under this Part I of this subtitle until:<section prefix="(1)">the real estate transaction for which the trust money was entrusted is consummated or terminated;</section><section prefix="(2)">the real estate broker receives proper written instructions from the owner and beneficial owner directing withdrawal or other disposition of the trust money;</section><section prefix="(3)">on an interpleader filed by the real estate broker, a court orders a different disposition; or</section><section prefix="(4)">the owner or beneficial owner of the trust money fails to complete the real estate transaction for which the trust money was entrusted and the real estate broker, in the real estate broker's sole discretion, decides to distribute the trust money in accordance with subsection (b) of this section.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Prior to distributing the trust money under subsection (a)(4) of this section, the real estate broker shall notify both the owner and the beneficial owner that the real estate broker intends to distribute the trust money to the person who, in the good faith opinion of the real estate broker, is entitled to receive the trust money in accordance with the terms of the real estate contract which established the trust.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The notice required under this subsection shall:<section prefix="(i)">be in writing;</section><section prefix="(ii)">state whether the trust money will be paid to the owner or beneficial owner; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">disclose to the owner and the beneficial owner that:</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The notice required under this subsection shall be:<section prefix="(i)">hand delivered to both the owner and beneficial owner; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">sent by certified mail, return receipt requested, and regular mail to both the owner and beneficial owner.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">
        <section prefix="(i)">An owner or beneficial owner may protest the distribution of the trust money.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">An owner or beneficial owner shall submit the protest to the real estate broker holding the trust money within 30 days from the date the notice required in paragraph (1) of this subsection was delivered or mailed by the real estate broker.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">A protest shall be in writing and either:</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(5)">
        <section prefix="(i)">If a written protest is received by the real estate broker, the real estate broker shall distribute the trust money in accordance with subsection (a)(1), (2), or (3) of this section.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">If no written protest is received by the real estate broker holding the trust money, the real estate broker shall distribute the trust money in accordance with the terms of the notice as required in this section.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">When the duty of the real estate broker to maintain trust money in an account terminates, the real estate broker promptly shall account for all trust money.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A real estate broker may invest trust money:<section prefix="(1)">as the owner and beneficial owner of the trust money instruct in writing; or</section><section prefix="(2)">as the real estate broker, owner, and beneficial owner of the trust money agree in writing.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">A real estate broker may not be liable to an owner or beneficial owner of the trust money for:<section prefix="(1)">a good faith decision to distribute the trust money under subsection (a)(4) of this section; or</section><section prefix="(2)">a decision not to distribute the trust money under subsection (a)(4) of this section.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">An agreement under which a real estate broker is entrusted with the trust money shall contain a statement that the real estate broker may distribute the trust money in accordance with subsection (b) of this section if the owner or beneficial owner of the trust money fails to complete the real estate transaction for which the trust money was entrusted.</section>
  </text>
</law>
