<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gbo" order_by="" level="1">Business Occupations and Professions</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gbo-9-303</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>303</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Before an applicant takes the examination given by the Board, the applicant shall qualify under this section by meeting the educational and experience requirements set forth in subsection (b), (c), (d), or (e) of this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">An applicant qualifies under this section if the applicant:<section prefix="(1)">has been graduated from a college or school of landscape architecture that holds accredited status from the national Landscape Architectural Accreditation Board; and</section><section prefix="(2)">has at least 2 years of work experience in landscape architecture that is:<section prefix="(i)">under the responsible charge of a licensed landscape architect or other authorized individual; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">otherwise satisfactory to the Board.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">An applicant qualifies under this section if the applicant:<section prefix="(1)">has been graduated on completion of at least a 4-year curriculum in a design-related discipline from a college or university that is accredited by, or is a constituent unit of an institution accredited by, the Middle States Association of Colleges and Schools or the equivalent regional accrediting association of other regional areas; and</section><section prefix="(2)">has at least 4 years of work experience in landscape architecture that is:<section prefix="(i)">under the responsible charge of a licensed landscape architect or other authorized individual; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">otherwise satisfactory to the Board.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">An applicant qualifies under this section if the applicant:<section prefix="(1)">has been graduated on completion of at least a 4-year curriculum in a nondesign-related discipline from a college or university that is accredited by, or is a constituent unit of an institution accredited by, the Middle States Association of Colleges and Schools or the equivalent regional accrediting association of other regional areas; and</section><section prefix="(2)">has at least 6 years of practical work experience in landscape architecture that is:<section prefix="(i)">under the responsible charge of a licensed landscape architect or other authorized individual; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">otherwise satisfactory to the Board.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">An applicant qualifies under this section if the applicant:<section prefix="(i)">is a high school graduate or the equivalent; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">has at least 8 years of practical work experience in landscape architecture that is:<section prefix="1.">under the responsible charge of a licensed landscape architect or other authorized individual; and</section><section prefix="2.">otherwise satisfactory to the Board.</section></section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Board may count each full year of study at a college or school of landscape architecture that meets the criteria set forth in subsection (b) of this section as one of the years of the work experience required under this subsection.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
