<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gbo" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="7-308" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gbo-7-308</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Unless a license is renewed for a 2-year term as provided in this section, the license expires on the first September 30 that comes:<section prefix="(1)">after the effective date of the license; and</section><section prefix="(2)">in an even-numbered year.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">At least 30 days before a license expires, the Board shall mail to the licensee, at the last known address of the licensee:<section prefix="(1)">a renewal application form; and</section><section prefix="(2)">a notice that states:<section prefix="(i)">the date on which the current license expires;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the date by which the Board must receive the renewal application for the renewal to be issued and mailed before the license expires; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">the amount of the renewal fee.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Before a license expires, the licensee periodically may renew it for an additional 2-year term, if the licensee:<section prefix="(i)">otherwise is entitled to be licensed;</section><section prefix="(ii)">except as provided in subsection (d) of this section, pays to the Board a renewal fee of $100; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">submits to the Board a renewal application on the form that the Board provides.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)"/>
        <section prefix="(ii)">To qualify for renewal of a license, for each 2-year license term of a license, a licensee shall complete successfully at least 8 hours of instruction provided through programs that the Board approves.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A licensee serving on active duty in the armed forces of the United States is exempt from the renewal fee required by this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The Board shall renew the license of each licensee who meets the requirements of this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The Secretary may determine that licenses issued under this subtitle shall expire on a staggered basis.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A licensee may apply to the Board for inactive status.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Board shall grant inactive status to a licensee if the licensee:<section prefix="(i)">otherwise is entitled to be licensed; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">pays to the Board an inactive license fee of $25.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">An individual may return to active status if the individual meets the requirements for renewal of a license under this section.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
