<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gbo" order_by="" level="1">Business Occupations and Professions</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gbo-18-3A-10</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>10</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Before the Secretary takes any final action under &#xA7; 18-3A-09 of this subtitle, the Secretary shall give the individual against whom the action is contemplated an opportunity for either:<section prefix="(i)">a hearing before the Secretary; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">a hearing before an advisory panel consisting of the following members appointed by the Secretary:<section prefix="1.">a member of the Department of State Police;</section><section prefix="2.">a representative of the security systems industry;</section><section prefix="3.">one member who has engaged the services of a security systems agency; and</section><section prefix="4.">two members representing consumers.</section></section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A hearing before an advisory panel under this section does not preclude a hearing before the Secretary.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Secretary or the advisory panel shall give notice and hold the hearing in accordance with Title 10, Subtitle 2 of the State Government Article.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The hearing notice to be given to the individual shall be sent by certified mail to the last known address of the individual at least 10 business days before the hearing.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Secretary or the advisory panel may administer oaths in connection with any proceeding under this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The individual may be represented at the hearing by counsel.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">If, after due notice, the individual against whom the action is contemplated fails or refuses to appear, the Secretary or the advisory panel may, nevertheless, hear and determine the matter.</section>
  </text>
</law>
