<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gbo" order_by="gbo" level="1">Business Occupations and Professions</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gbo-6.5-307</section_number>
  <catch_line>Subject to the limitations in subsections (b) and (c) of this section, on the affirmative vote of a ...</catch_line>
  <order_by>307</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Subject to the limitations in subsections (b) and (c) of this section, on the affirmative vote of a majority of its voting members then serving, the Board may waive the examination requirements of this title for an individual who is licensed in another state or in a locality in another state to provide stationary engineer services.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Board may grant a waiver under this section only if the applicant:<section prefix="(1)">pays to the Board the nonrefundable application fee required under &#xA7; 6.5-304 of this subtitle; and</section><section prefix="(2)">provides adequate evidence that the applicant:<section prefix="(i)">meets the qualifications otherwise required by this subtitle;</section><section prefix="(ii)">holds an active license in good standing in the other state or the locality;</section><section prefix="(iii)">holds a license that is equivalent to the State license; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">became licensed in the other state or the locality after meeting the state's or locality's requirements that are at least equivalent to the licensing requirements of the State, including the number of years of work experience equivalent to the experience required under &#xA7; 6.5-303(c) of this subtitle.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Board may grant a waiver only if the state or the locality in which the applicant is licensed waives the examination of licensees of this State to a similar extent as the State waives the examination requirements for individuals licensed in that state or locality.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this subsection, "BRAC" means the Base Realignment and Closure process as announced by the United States Department of Defense.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Notwithstanding the provisions of subsections (a), (b), and (c) of this section, the Board shall grant a waiver to an applicant who files a request before July 1, 2012, if the applicant:<section prefix="(i)">pays to the Board the nonrefundable application fee required under &#xA7; 6.5-304 of this subtitle;</section><section prefix="(ii)">holds an active stationary engineer's license in good standing from Virginia or New Jersey, or from a locality of one of those states, that is equivalent to the State license;</section><section prefix="(iii)">has experience in the provision of stationary engineer services that meets the time requirements of &#xA7; 6.5-303 of this subtitle; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">has relocated to the State as a family member of a BRAC employee.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
