<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gbo" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="2-4A-05" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gbo-2-4A-05</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Prior to conducting a peer review, an individual must be approved by the Board.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">In order to receive approval from the Board, a peer reviewer shall:<section prefix="(1)">have and maintain an active license as a certified public accountant in this or any other state;</section><section prefix="(2)">possess a level of knowledge of applicable professional standards acceptable to the Board;</section><section prefix="(3)">possess at least 5 years recent experience in the practice of public accounting;</section><section prefix="(4)">have received a passing report on the most recent peer review of the prospective peer reviewer; and</section><section prefix="(5)">complete an appropriate training course as determined by the Board.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">In order to serve as a team captain of a system review, a peer reviewer must have and maintain ownership or management of a firm or comparable responsibility.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A peer reviewer shall have no connection to the licensee or permit holder being reviewed that might impair the peer reviewer's independence.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">A peer reviewer shall:<section prefix="(1)">prepare a report of findings in accordance with the standards for performing and reporting on peer reviews of the American Institute of Certified Public Accountants; and</section><section prefix="(2)">maintain the report for a period of 3 years.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">A peer reviewer shall provide a copy of the report to the Board only if the licensee or permit holder being reviewed has:<section prefix="(1)">been directed to take corrective action and has failed to satisfy the peer reviewer that such action has been completed in a timely manner;</section><section prefix="(2)">received a second consecutive report indicating pass with deficiencies; or</section><section prefix="(3)">received a failing report.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(g)">A peer reviewer shall comply with all Board regulations and directives regarding the peer review process.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">The Board may revoke its approval of a peer reviewer under this section if the peer reviewer:<section prefix="(1)">violates any provision of this title;</section><section prefix="(2)">violates any regulation adopted by the Board; or</section><section prefix="(3)">is sanctioned by any state board of accountancy or any unit of State or federal government.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
