<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gbo" order_by="gbo" level="1">Business Occupations and Professions</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gbo-14-310</section_number>
  <catch_line>Subject to this section, an individual may apply to the Board to take the examination in the fundame...</catch_line>
  <order_by>310</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Subject to this section, an individual may apply to the Board to take the examination in the fundamentals of engineering given by the Board under this subtitle, before the individual completes the requirements set forth in &#xA7; 14-305(b) and (c) of this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">To take the fundamentals of engineering examination early:<section prefix="(1)">the applicant shall be in the process of completing a curriculum at a college or university, as required under &#xA7; 14-305(b) or (c) of this subtitle, and the college or university shall provide to the Board evidence that the college or university expects the applicant to complete the curriculum within 6 months after the next scheduled administration of the fundamentals of engineering examination; or</section><section prefix="(2)">the applicant shall have been graduated from a college or university on completion of a curriculum, as required under &#xA7; 14-305(b) or (c) of this subtitle.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">An applicant for early examination shall:<section prefix="(i)">submit to the Board an application on the form that the Board provides; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">pay to the Board or the Board's designee:<section prefix="1.">a nonrefundable application fee set by the Board; and</section><section prefix="2.">an examination fee set by the Board in an amount not to exceed the cost of the examination.</section></section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The procedures and requirements for the application shall be the same as provided under &#xA7; 14-306 of this subtitle for applications for licenses.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">An applicant who meets the requirements of this section is entitled to take the fundamentals of engineering examination.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">If an individual passes a fundamentals of engineering examination under this section and pays the Board a certification fee set by the Board, the Board shall:<section prefix="(1)">keep a record that the individual passed the examination; and</section><section prefix="(2)">issue to the individual a certificate that states that the individual is an engineer-in-training because the individual has passed the examination and that sets forth:<section prefix="(i)">the full name of the individual;</section><section prefix="(ii)">a certificate number assigned by the Board to the individual; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">the signatures of the chairman and secretary of the Board, under seal of the Board.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">If an individual takes and fails a fundamentals of engineering examination under this section, the individual shall have the same rights regarding notice, review procedures, and reexamination provided to an applicant under &#xA7;&#xA7; 14-308 and 14-309 of this subtitle.</section>
  </text>
</law>
