<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gbo" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="10-206" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gbo-10-206</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Except as otherwise provided by law, before an individual may practice law in the State, the individual shall:<section prefix="(1)">be admitted to the Bar; and</section><section prefix="(2)">meet any requirement that the Court of Appeals may set by rule.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">This section does not apply to:<section prefix="(1)">a person while representing a landlord in a summary ejectment or a rent escrow proceeding in the District Court of Maryland;</section><section prefix="(2)">a person while representing a tenant in a summary ejectment or a rent escrow proceeding in the District Court of Maryland if the person is:<section prefix="(i)">a law student practicing in a clinical law program at a law school accredited by the American Bar Association with the in-court supervision of a faculty member; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">employed by a nonprofit organization receiving grants from the Maryland Legal Services Corporation and:</section></section><section prefix="(3)">an insurance company while defending an insured through staff counsel;</section><section prefix="(4)">an officer of a corporation, an employee designated by an officer of a corporation, a partner in a business operated as a partnership or an employee designated by a partner, a member of a limited liability company or an employee designated by a member of a limited liability company, or an employee designated by the owner of a business operated as a sole proprietorship while the officer, partner, member, or employee is appearing on behalf of the corporation, partnership, limited liability company, or business in a civil action in the District Court of Maryland if:<section prefix="(i)">the action:</section><section prefix="(ii)">in the case of a designated employee, the employee:</section><section prefix="(iii)">the corporation, partnership, limited liability company, or business does not contract, hire, or employ another business entity to provide appearance services;</section></section><section prefix="(5)">an individual who is authorized by a county employee to represent the employee at any step of the county's grievance procedure; or</section><section prefix="(6)">a director or an officer of a common ownership community while representing the common ownership community in a dispute, hearing, or other matter before a board or commission established to oversee one or more of the following common ownership communities:<section prefix="(i)">a development subject to a declaration enforced by a homeowners association as defined in &#xA7; 11B-101 of the Real Property Article;</section><section prefix="(ii)">a residential condominium as defined in &#xA7; 11-101 of the Real Property Article; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">a cooperative housing corporation as defined in &#xA7; 5-6B-01 of the Corporations and Associations Article.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this subsection, "practice patent law":<section prefix="(i)">means to perform professional services that the Patent and Trademark Office requires to be performed by an individual registered to practice before that Office; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">includes preparing a copyright application or assignment and submitting it to the Copyright Office of the Library of Congress.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">While there is a Patent and Trademark Office in the State, an individual may practice patent law in the State if the individual is:<section prefix="(i)">authorized to practice law in any other state; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">registered to practice patent law before the Patent and Trademark Office.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Unless otherwise authorized under this title, an individual who practices patent law under this subsection may not:<section prefix="(i)">appear as an attorney at law in a court; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">practice law generally in the State.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Subject to paragraph (2) of this subsection, this section does not apply to an individual while giving legal advice to a corporation in this State if the individual is:<section prefix="(i)">employed by the corporation; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">admitted to the bar of any other state.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">An individual who gives legal advice under this subsection:<section prefix="(i)">is subject to disciplinary proceedings as the Maryland Rules provide; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">may not appear before a unit of the State government or of a political subdivision unless a court grants the individual a special admission in accordance with &#xA7; 10-215 of this subtitle.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
