<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gbo" order_by="gbo" level="1">Business Occupations and Professions</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gbo-12-503</section_number>
  <catch_line>Each individual whom the State, a county, or a local government appoints or employs as a plumbing in...</catch_line>
  <order_by>503</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Each individual whom the State, a county, or a local government appoints or employs as a plumbing inspector shall:<section prefix="(1)">each year attend a continuing education course that the Board or, with the approval of the Board, a county or local government conducts; and</section><section prefix="(2)">meet minimum standards that:<section prefix="(i)">adequately ensure that the plumbing inspector is qualified to inspect in accordance with the State Plumbing Code;</section><section prefix="(ii)">are established:<section prefix="1.">by the county or local government in consultation with the Board; or</section><section prefix="2.">if there is no standard established by the county or local government, by the Board; and</section></section><section prefix="(iii)">are administered:<section prefix="1.">for a county or local government inspector, by the county or local government that appoints or employs the inspector; and</section><section prefix="2.">for a State inspector, by the State.</section></section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">An individual may not have any financial interest in any plumbing business while employed by the State, a county, or any local government as a plumbing inspector.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">On appointment or employment, the individual shall place the master plumber license, journey plumber license, or limited license on inactive status.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Board may issue a plumbing inspector identification card to a plumbing inspector who has placed the appropriate license on inactive status.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">On termination of the appointment or employment of an individual as a plumbing inspector, the Board shall reactivate the master plumber license, journey plumber license, or limited license of an individual who is on inactive status, without examination, if the individual:<section prefix="(i)">makes a written request to the Board; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">pays to the Board a reactivation fee of:<section prefix="1.">$20, for a journey plumber or holder of a limited journey plumber license; or</section><section prefix="2.">$50, for a master plumber or holder of a limited master plumber license.</section></section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Board may impose a reasonable fee to cover the costs of conducting the continuing education courses under subsection (a) of this section.</section>
  </text>
</law>
