<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gbo" order_by="" level="1">Business Occupations and Professions</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gbo-18-401</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>401</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In order to obtain a license, an applicant shall:<section prefix="(1)"><section prefix="(i)">execute a fidelity bond as provided in subsection (c) of this section; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">maintain general liability insurance as provided in subsection (d) of this section; and</section></section><section prefix="(2)">maintain in an office in the State, documents or other records that are made in the State or relate to a service performed in the State and make those records available for inspection by the Secretary for compliance with this title.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Secretary may not issue or renew a license or registration unless the applicant, licensee, or registrant submits proof of compliance with subsection (a) of this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The fidelity bond required by subsection (a)(1) of this section shall cover all individuals who:<section prefix="(i)">are licensed to provide security systems services, are registered as security systems technicians, or have access to circumventional information; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">are applicants for a license or registration.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The fidelity bond shall be used for the benefit of any person injured on the premises of a consumer of security systems services by any fraudulent or dishonest act of a licensee, a security systems technician, or other individual who has access to circumventional information that is willful or malicious.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The applicant for a license or registration shall submit a copy of the fidelity bond to the Secretary with the license or registration application.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The amount of the fidelity bond required under subsection (c)(1) of this section shall be at least $50,000.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The total liability of the surety to all insured persons under the fidelity bond may not exceed the sum of the fidelity bond.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(5)">
        <section prefix="(i)">If an employer's fidelity bond is canceled, forfeited, or terminated by the surety, the surety shall immediately notify the Secretary.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">If a surety fails to notify the Secretary as required by this paragraph, the fidelity bond shall continue in effect until the notice is given to the Secretary.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">General liability insurance required by subsection (a)(1)(ii) of this section shall be in the amount of at least $50,000.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">An applicant for a license or registration shall submit proof of insurance meeting the requirements of paragraph (1) of this subsection to the Secretary with the application.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">If the general liability insurance required under this section is canceled, the insured shall immediately notify the Secretary.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">If an agency fails to maintain the required fidelity bond or liability insurance as required in this section, upon notification, the Secretary:<section prefix="(1)">shall suspend the license; and</section><section prefix="(2)">may not reinstate the license until the agency submits proof of the required bond or insurance to the Secretary.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">In addition to &#xA7; 18-504 of this title, a court of competent jurisdiction may enjoin the operation of any employer who violates the requirements of this section.</section>
  </text>
</law>
