<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gbo" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="18-303" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gbo-18-303</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">An applicant for a license shall:<section prefix="(1)">submit to the Secretary an application on the form that the Secretary provides;</section><section prefix="(2)">submit the documents required by this section; and</section><section prefix="(3)">pay to the Secretary an application fee of $150 which shall include the cost of the Maryland and national criminal records check.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The application form provided by the Secretary shall contain a statement advising the applicant that willfully making a false statement on an application is a misdemeanor, subject to a fine or imprisonment or both, as provided under &#xA7; 18-504 of this title.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">If the applicant is a firm, the representative member shall complete the application form and otherwise be responsible for the firm's compliance with this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The application shall be accompanied by at least two written recommendations for the applicant.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Each recommendation shall be signed, under oath, by a reputable citizen of the State.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">An applicant for a license shall submit with the application a set of legible fingerprints of the applicant on a form approved by the Criminal Justice Information System Central Repository and the Director of the Federal Bureau of Investigation.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If the applicant is a firm, the applicant shall pay the cost of the fingerprint card records check for each firm member.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">An applicant for a license shall submit with the application a copy of a bond or proof of insurance in accordance with the requirements of &#xA7; 18-401 of this title.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">The Secretary may waive the requirements of subsections (a)(2) and (3), (d), and (e) of this section and issue a license to an applicant who:<section prefix="(1)">provides adequate evidence that the applicant:<section prefix="(i)">is licensed to engage in the business of providing security systems services in another state; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">became licensed in the other state:</section></section><section prefix="(2)">pays to the Secretary a processing fee of $150.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
