<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gbo" order_by="" level="1">Business Occupations and Professions</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gbo-17-328</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>328</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Subject to the provisions of subsection (b) of this section, the Commission may order summarily the suspension of the license of a licensee if the licensee:<section prefix="(1)">fails to account promptly for any money held in trust;</section><section prefix="(2)">on demand, fails to display to the Commission all records, books, and accounts of any money held in trust;</section><section prefix="(3)">has been convicted of a felony under the laws of the United States or of any state; or</section><section prefix="(4)">within 10 days after the conviction or within 10 days following release from incarceration as a result of the conviction, whichever is later, fails to disclose to the Commission that the licensee has been convicted of a felony under the laws of the United States or of any state.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Commission may order summarily a suspension under this section only if the Commission gives the licensee:<section prefix="(1)">written notice of the suspension and the finding on which the suspension is based; and</section><section prefix="(2)">after the summary suspension is effective, an opportunity to be heard promptly before the Commission or, as provided under &#xA7; 17-326 of this subtitle, before a hearing board.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A summary suspension ordered by the Commission under this section:<section prefix="(1)">may start immediately or at any later date, as set by the order; and</section><section prefix="(2)">shall continue until:<section prefix="(i)">the licensee complies with the conditions set forth by the Commission in its order; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">the Commission orders a different disposition after a hearing held under this section.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Rather than order summarily a suspension of a license under this section, the Commission may elect not to suspend the license until after the licensee is given an opportunity for a hearing.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If the Commission elects to give the licensee an opportunity for a hearing before suspending the license for the grounds set forth in this section, the Commission shall give notice and hold the hearing in the same manner as required under &#xA7; 17-324 of this subtitle.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
