<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gbo" order_by="" level="1">Business Occupations and Professions</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gbo-6-103</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>103</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">This title does not affect the right of any local jurisdiction of the State:<section prefix="(1)">to regulate the quality and character of work of a person who engages in the business of providing electrical services by establishing a system of licenses, permits, fees, and inspections designed to:<section prefix="(i)">ensure compliance with and implementation of State and local building laws; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">enforce other local laws protecting public health and safety;</section></section><section prefix="(2)">to require a person who engages in the business of providing electrical services to submit any plan or specification for approval before the electrical services are provided;</section><section prefix="(3)">to establish a local board;</section><section prefix="(4)">except as provided in &#xA7;&#xA7; 6-504 and 6-602 of this title, to require an examination before issuing a license to provide electrical services within the local jurisdiction; or</section><section prefix="(5)">to collect, from a person who is licensed with a local board, fees for:<section prefix="(i)">an examination for a license to provide electrical services;</section><section prefix="(ii)">issuance and renewal of the license; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">an inspection.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">If a local jurisdiction licenses any class of electricians other than master electricians, that class is also under the control and supervision of the local board.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">This title may not be construed to waive any requirement of an ordinance or regulation that sets out the type of work to be performed by a person who engages in the business of providing electrical services as required under State or local building laws.</section>
  </text>
</law>
