<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gbo" order_by="" level="1">Business Occupations and Professions</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gbo-19-309</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>309</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">As a condition for license renewal, a licensee shall submit to the Secretary with the renewal application:<section prefix="(1)">a certification or, as authorized by the Secretary, other documentation that the licensed security guard agency has paid, for the past 3 years, all withholding and Social Security taxes;</section><section prefix="(2)">a certification or, as authorized by the Secretary, other documentation that the licensed security guard agency has paid, for the past 3 years, all other obligations payable for the employees of the licensed security guard agency to the State or the federal government;</section><section prefix="(3)">a certificate from an insurance carrier or, as authorized by the Secretary, other documentation showing that the licensed security guard agency has in effect commercial general and workers' compensation insurance for its covered employees, as defined in &#xA7; 9-101 of the Labor and Employment Article; and</section><section prefix="(4)">a certificate from the Comptroller's Office or, as authorized by the Secretary, other documentation showing that the State income tax of the licensed security guard agency has been paid for the past 3 years.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">If the Secretary does not receive the documents required under subsection (a) of this section at least 15 days before the license expiration date, the Secretary shall charge the licensee a late fee of $10 per day until the documents are received.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Secretary may inspect any of the business records of a licensee that relate to any matter that is subject to certification or documentation under this section.</section>
  </text>
</law>
