<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gbo" order_by="" level="1">Business Occupations and Professions</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gbo-17-533</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>533</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">A licensee who assists a prospective buyer or lessee in locating residential real estate for purchase or lease and is neither affiliated with nor acting as the listing real estate broker for any real estate shown or located, is presumed to be acting as the buyer's or lessee's agent representing the buyer or lessee unless either the licensee or the buyer or lessee expressly declines to have the licensee act as a buyer's or lessee's agent.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A presumed buyer's or lessee's agency relationship shall be terminated if:<section prefix="(1)">either the buyer, lessee, or licensee expressly states a wish to terminate the presumed agency relationship; or</section><section prefix="(2)">the licensee and either the buyer or the lessee enter into a brokerage agreement.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The buyer or lessee does not have an obligation to continue to work with the licensee or to pay the licensee while acting under a presumed agency relationship.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A licensee who is acting as a presumed buyer's or lessee's agent may show and assist the buyer or lessee only on real estate that is not listed by the broker of that licensee.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">Before the licensee may show or assist the buyer or lessee in locating real estate listed for sale by the broker with whom the licensee is affiliated, the licensee shall disclose to the prospective buyer or lessee that the licensee represents the seller or lessor for that real estate as provided in &#xA7; 17-530(b) of this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">A licensee may represent the prospective buyer or lessee for such real estate as an intra-company agent provided that:<section prefix="(1)">the licensee has executed a written consent for dual agency agreement; and</section><section prefix="(2)">the licensee has made the necessary disclosure and obtained consent as required by &#xA7; 17-530(d).</section></section>
    <section prefix="(g)">Before the licensee may present an offer to purchase or lease or negotiate the purchase or lease of real estate, the presumed buyer's or lessee's agency must be terminated and the buyer or lessee and the licensee shall enter into a brokerage agreement for that licensee to act as an exclusive buyer's or lessee's agent or as an intra-company agent for the buyer or lessee.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">The licensee acting as the presumed buyer's or lessee's agent shall comply with &#xA7; 17-532 of this subtitle and has the duties stated in the required disclosure form under &#xA7; 17-530 of this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">At the first meeting of the licensee and the buyer or lessee, the licensee shall:<section prefix="(1)">orally advise the prospective buyer or lessee that the licensee will act as the buyer's or lessee's agent in locating residential real estate unless the buyer or lessee declines the agency; and</section><section prefix="(2)">provide the prospective buyer or lessee with a copy of the disclosure form required by &#xA7; 17-530 of this subtitle, but the licensee is not required to obtain the signature of the buyer or lessee before or during the presumed agency relationship.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(j)">A licensee acting as a presumed buyer's agent shall orally disclose that fact to the seller or lessor or the licensee acting as the agent of the seller or lessor at their first contact.</section>
  </text>
</law>
