<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gbo" order_by="" level="1">Business Occupations and Professions</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gbo-3-101</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>101</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this title the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Architect" means an individual who practices architecture.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Board" means, unless the context requires otherwise, the State Board of Architects.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">"Code official" means a public official responsible for the review of building permit documents or the issuance of building permits.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"Contact hour" means a minimum of 50 minutes of actual class time for each 60-minute hour.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">"Design coordination" means the review and coordination of services provided by individuals licensed or certified under Titles 3, 8, 9, 14, and 15 of this article.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">"License" means, unless the context requires otherwise, a license issued by the Board to practice architecture.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">"License fee" means, as applicable, the fee paid in connection with the issuance and renewal of a license and the issuance of a reciprocal license.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">"Licensed architect" means, unless the context requires otherwise, an architect who is licensed by the Board to practice architecture.</section>
    <section prefix="(j)">"Permit" means, unless the context requires otherwise, a permit issued by the Board to allow a partnership or corporation to operate a business through which an individual may practice architecture.</section>
    <section prefix="(k)">"Permit fee" means, as applicable, the fee paid in connection with the issuance and renewal of a permit.</section>
    <section prefix="(l)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Practice architecture" means to provide any service or creative work:<section prefix="(i)">in regard to an addition to, alteration of, or construction of a building or an integral part of a building; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">that requires education, training, and experience in architecture.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Practice architecture" includes:<section prefix="(i)">architectural design and preparation of related documents;</section><section prefix="(ii)">consultation;</section><section prefix="(iii)">design coordination;</section><section prefix="(iv)">evaluation;</section><section prefix="(v)">investigation; and</section><section prefix="(vi)">planning.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(m)">"Public use" means the use of a building or other structure for the primary purpose of human use or habitation.</section>
    <section prefix="(n)">"Residential use" means the use of a building or other structure as a dwelling.</section>
  </text>
</law>
