<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gbo" order_by="gbo" level="1">Business Occupations and Professions</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gbo-5-405</section_number>
  <catch_line>Except as otherwise provided in subsection (g) of this section, the initial term of registration as ...</catch_line>
  <order_by>405</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Except as otherwise provided in subsection (g) of this section, the initial term of registration as an apprentice is 2 years.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Unless registration as an apprentice is renewed for one additional 2-year term as provided in this section, the registration expires on the date set by the Board.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">At least 1 month before the registration of an individual expires, the Board shall mail to the individual, at the last known address of the individual:<section prefix="(1)">a renewal application form; and</section><section prefix="(2)">a notice that states:<section prefix="(i)">the date on which the current registration expires;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the date by which the Board must receive the renewal application for the renewal to be issued and mailed before the registration expires; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">the amount of the renewal fee.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Before the registration of an individual expires, the individual may renew it for an additional term, if the individual:<section prefix="(1)">otherwise is entitled to be registered;</section><section prefix="(2)">pays to the Board a renewal fee established by the Board in accordance with &#xA7; 5-205 of this title; and</section><section prefix="(3)">submits to the Board a renewal application on the form that the Board provides.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">Except as otherwise provided in subsection (g) of this section, an individual registered as an apprentice may renew the registration only one time for a 2-year term.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The Board shall renew the registration of and issue a renewal certificate to each individual who meets the requirements of this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">A registration as an apprentice for any limited practice of cosmetology expires 12 months after the date of its issuance unless the limited practice apprentice registration is renewed for one 1-year term.</section>
  </text>
</law>
