<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gbo" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="19-101" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gbo-19-101</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this title the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Central Repository" means the Criminal Justice Information System Central Repository of the Department of Public Safety and Correctional Services.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Certification card" means a card issued by the Secretary under &#xA7; 19-405 of this title to an individual certified as a security guard.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">"Firm" means a partnership or corporation.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"Firm member" means a partner of a partnership or an officer or director of a corporation.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">"License" means, unless the context requires otherwise, a license issued by the Secretary to conduct a business to provide security guard services.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">"Licensed security guard agency" means a person who is licensed by the Secretary to conduct a business that provides security guard services.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">"Representative member" means a firm member who is appointed under &#xA7; 19-302(b) of this title to act on behalf of the firm.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">"Secretary", unless the context requires otherwise, means the Secretary of State Police.</section>
    <section prefix="(j)">"Security guard" means an individual who provides security guard services to any person on behalf of a security guard agency, regardless of whether the individual is described as a security guard, watchman, or private patrolman or by other title.</section>
    <section prefix="(k)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Security guard agency" means a person who conducts a business that provides security guard services.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Security guard agency" does not include a person that is primarily engaged in the business of owning, maintaining, or otherwise managing property.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(l)">"Security guard services" includes any activity that is performed for compensation as a security guard to protect any individual or property, except the activities of an individual while performing as:<section prefix="(1)">a marine guard or ship watchman, regardless of whether the guard or watchman is stationed aboard a ship or on a pier; or</section><section prefix="(2)">a special police officer appointed and while performing under Title 3, Subtitle 3 of the Public Safety Article or &#xA7; 16-16 of the Code of Public Local Laws of Baltimore City.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
