<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gbo" order_by="" level="1">Business Occupations and Professions</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gbo-17-520</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>520</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Within the time set by the Commission, a real estate broker shall submit to the Commission:<section prefix="(1)">written notice of any change in the address of the principal office of the broker on the form that the Commission provides;</section><section prefix="(2)">the license certificate and pocket card of the broker; and</section><section prefix="(3)">a fee for issuance of a new license certificate and pocket card of $5.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">On receipt of the notice, fee, license certificate, and pocket card, the Commission shall issue a new license certificate and pocket card to the real estate broker for the unexpired period of the broker's license.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Within the time set by the Commission, a real estate broker shall submit to the Commission:<section prefix="(1)">written notice of any change in the address of a branch office of the broker on the form that the Commission provides;</section><section prefix="(2)">the branch office certificate; and</section><section prefix="(3)">a fee for the issuance of a new branch office certificate of $5.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">On receipt of the notice, fee, and branch office certificate, the Commission shall issue a new branch office certificate to the real estate broker for the unexpired period of the branch office certificate.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">If a real estate broker changes the address of the principal office or a branch office of the broker and fails to submit the required notice, the license of the broker shall be suspended automatically until the broker submits the required notice.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">If the address of the affiliated brokerage of a licensed associate real estate broker or a licensed real estate salesperson changes, within the time set by the Commission, the licensee shall submit to the Commission:<section prefix="(1)">written or electronic notice of any change in the address of the brokerage;</section><section prefix="(2)">the license certificate and pocket card of the licensee; and</section><section prefix="(3)">a fee for the issuance of a new license certificate and pocket card of $5.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
