<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gbo" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="4-511" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gbo-4-511</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Board may adopt regulations to ensure that each barber school approved by the State Board of Education or the Maryland Higher Education Commission is operated in a sanitary manner.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The regulations adopted under subsection (a) of this section shall provide for:<section prefix="(1)">the reporting of violations of the regulations to the Department of Education or the Maryland Higher Education Commission; and</section><section prefix="(2)">the imposition of a fine not to exceed $300 for a violation of the regulations.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">In determining the amount of financial penalty to be imposed under this section, the Board shall consider the following:<section prefix="(1)">the seriousness of the violation;</section><section prefix="(2)">the good faith of the violator;</section><section prefix="(3)">the violator's history of previous violations;</section><section prefix="(4)">the deleterious effect of the violation on the complainant, the public, and the barber industry; and</section><section prefix="(5)">any other factors relevant to the determination of the financial penalty.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Board shall commence proceedings to assess a penalty under this section on a complaint to the Board by a member of the Board or any person.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A complaint shall:<section prefix="(i)">be in writing;</section><section prefix="(ii)">include the name and necessary contact information of the individual filing the complaint, as determined by the Board;</section><section prefix="(iii)">state specifically the facts on which the complaint is based;</section><section prefix="(iv)">be submitted to the Executive Director of the Board; and</section><section prefix="(v)">be served on the person to whom it is directed:</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If service is made by certified mail, the person who mails the document shall file with the Board verified proof of mailing.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">If a complaint is made by any person other than a member of the Board, the complaint shall be made under oath by the person who submits the complaint.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If the Board finds that there is a violation that relates to the sanitary condition of the barber school, the Board shall provide the owner of the barber school an opportunity to correct the alleged violation.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If the school owner fails to correct each alleged violation within 10 days of written notification by the Board, the Board shall act on the complaint as provided under &#xA7; 4-514 of this subtitle.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">If the school owner corrects each alleged violation within 10 days of notice, the Board shall:<section prefix="(i)">dismiss the complaint; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">provide the school owner written notification of dismissal.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
