<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gbo" order_by="gbo" level="1">Business Occupations and Professions</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gbo-17-324</section_number>
  <catch_line>Except as otherwise provided in &#xA7; 10-226 of the State Government Article, before the Commission tak...</catch_line>
  <order_by>324</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Except as otherwise provided in &#xA7; 10-226 of the State Government Article, before the Commission takes any final action under &#xA7; 17-322 of this subtitle, it shall give the individual against whom the action is contemplated an opportunity for a hearing before the Commission or, as provided under &#xA7; 17-326 of this subtitle, a hearing board.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Commission shall give notice and hold the hearing in accordance with Title 10, Subtitle 2 of the State Government Article.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">In connection with any proceeding under this section, the following individuals may administer oaths:<section prefix="(1)">a member of the Commission;</section><section prefix="(2)">the executive director of the Commission; and</section><section prefix="(3)">the assistant director of the Commission.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">At least 10 days before the hearing, the hearing notice to be given to the individual shall be:<section prefix="(i)">served personally on the individual; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">sent by certified mail to the last known business address of the individual.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If the individual is an associate real estate broker or a real estate salesperson, at least 10 days before the hearing, the Commission shall give notice of the hearing to each real estate broker with whom the associate real estate broker or the real estate salesperson is affiliated by sending notice by certified mail to the last known business address of the real estate broker.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The individual may be represented at the hearing by counsel.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">If, after due notice, the individual against whom the action is contemplated fails or refuses to appear, nevertheless the Commission may hear and determine the matter.</section>
  </text>
</law>
