<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gbo" order_by="gbo" level="1">Business Occupations and Professions</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gbo-17-528</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this Part III of this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated....</catch_line>
  <order_by>528</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this Part III of this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Agency relationship" means each relationship in which a licensee acts for or represents another person with the person's authority in a residential real estate transaction.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Broker" means a licensed real estate broker, including a corporation, limited liability company, partnership, or sole proprietorship through which a licensed real estate broker provides real estate brokerage services under &#xA7; 17-321 of this title.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">"Brokerage agreement" means a written agreement between a broker and a client to provide real estate brokerage services under a brokerage relationship.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"Brokerage relationship" means an agency relationship under a brokerage agreement between a client and a broker who has been engaged by the client to provide real estate brokerage services in a residential real estate transaction.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">"Client" means a person who has entered into a brokerage agreement with a broker under a brokerage relationship.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Common source information company" means any person that is a source, compiler, or supplier of information regarding residential real estate for sale or lease or other data.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Common source information company" includes a multiple listing service.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(h)">"Confidential information" includes information that:<section prefix="(1)">the seller or lessor will accept a price or rent less than the price or rent as set forth in the brokerage agreement or will accept terms other than those contained in the brokerage agreement;</section><section prefix="(2)">the buyer or lessee is willing to pay a price or rent higher than the price or rent the buyer or lessee offered or will accept terms other than those contained in the offer of the buyer or lessee;</section><section prefix="(3)">discloses the motivation of a buyer, lessee, seller, or lessor or the need or urgency of a seller to sell, a buyer to buy, a lessee to lease, or a lessor to lease;</section><section prefix="(4)">discloses any facts that led the seller to sell, the buyer to buy, the lessee to lease, or the lessor to lease; or</section><section prefix="(5)">relates to the negotiating strategy of a client.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(i)">"Ministerial act" means an act that:<section prefix="(1)">a licensee performs on behalf of a client before and after the execution of a contract of sale or lease;</section><section prefix="(2)">assists another person to complete or fulfill a contract of sale or lease with the client of the licensee; and</section><section prefix="(3)">does not involve discretion or the exercise of the licensee's own judgment.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(j)">"Subagent" includes a cooperating agent who acts on behalf of a client of another broker.</section>
    <section prefix="(k)">"Timely" means a reasonable time under the particular facts and circumstances.</section>
  </text>
</law>
