<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gbo" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="12-305.1" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gbo-12-305.1</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Subject to the provisions of this section, the Board may waive the examination requirements for a master plumber license or a journey plumber license for an individual who is licensed to provide plumbing services in another state on the affirmative vote of at least a majority of the authorized membership of the Board.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Board may grant a waiver under this section only if an applicant:<section prefix="(1)">pays the appropriate fee required under &#xA7; 12-306 of this subtitle; and</section><section prefix="(2)">provides adequate evidence that the applicant:<section prefix="(i)">meets the qualifications otherwise required by this title;</section><section prefix="(ii)">holds an active license in good standing in the other state;</section><section prefix="(iii)">holds a license that is equivalent to the State license; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">became licensed in the other state after meeting requirements that are at least equivalent to the licensing requirements of this State.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Board may grant a waiver only if the state in which the applicant is licensed waives the examination of licensees of this State to a similar extent as this State waives the examination requirements for individuals licensed in that state.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this subsection, "BRAC" means the Base Realignment and Closure process as announced by the United States Department of Defense.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Notwithstanding the provisions of subsections (a), (b), and (c) of this section, the Board shall grant a waiver to an applicant who files a request before July 1, 2012, if the applicant:<section prefix="(i)">pays the appropriate fee required under &#xA7; 12-306 of this subtitle;</section><section prefix="(ii)">holds an active Virginia or New Jersey master plumber's license or an active Virginia journey plumber's license in good standing that is equivalent to the State license;</section><section prefix="(iii)">has experience in the provision of plumbing services that meets the time requirements of &#xA7; 12-302 of this subtitle; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">has relocated to the State as a family member of a BRAC employee.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
