<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gbo" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="11-506" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gbo-11-506</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Board of Supervisors of the Association shall maintain a Maintenance and Replacement Fund for the replacement and repair of the major equipment of the Association.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The State Board of Pilots shall determine a percentage of the pilotage fees collected by the Association to be set aside in the Fund.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Board of Supervisors of the Association shall obtain written approval from the State Board of Pilots for any expenditures from the Fund.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, the balance in the Fund shall remain at or above $500,000.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The balance of the Fund may fall below $500,000 for expenditures authorized by the Board.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The balance of the Fund may not remain below $500,000 for more than 10 consecutive years.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">At no time shall the balance of the Fund fall below $100,000.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The Board of Supervisors of the Association shall deposit the moneys authorized under subsection (b) of this section into the Maintenance and Replacement Fund.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Board of Supervisors of the Association shall hold the Maintenance and Replacement Fund in trust.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Association:<section prefix="(i)">may invest or hold the Fund in any manner that the Association finds desirable, in light of the nature and purpose of the Fund;</section><section prefix="(ii)">may place control and management of the Fund, or a part of the Fund, with a bank or trust company that is subject to State or federal regulation; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">is not limited to investments in property that has been designated, under any law of the State, as strictly suitable for investment of a trust fund.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">Assets held in trust under this section are not subject to attachment or execution.</section>
  </text>
</law>
