<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gbo" order_by="" level="1">Business Occupations and Professions</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gbo-4-304</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>304</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Except as otherwise provided in &#xA7; 4-304.1 of this subtitle, an applicant is entitled to be examined as provided in this section if the applicant:<section prefix="(1)">otherwise qualifies for a license under this title; and</section><section prefix="(2)">pays an examination fee established by the Board in accordance with &#xA7;&#xA7; 4-206 and 4-303 of this title to the Board or the Board's designee.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Board periodically shall give examinations to applicants at the times and places that the Board determines.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Board shall give each qualified applicant notice of the time and place of examination.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Board shall determine the subjects, scope, and form of and the passing score for examinations given under this subtitle.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">An examination may consist of written and practical parts.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Subject to &#xA7; 2-110 of the Business Regulation Article, an applicant whose primary language is not English may use a Board approved interpreter for the written part of an examination, but not for the practical part of an examination.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The passing of the practical part of an examination without an interpreter demonstrates that the applicant possesses sufficient command of English to understand and properly respond to an English-speaking customer.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">Subject to &#xA7; 2-110 of the Business Regulation Article, in the case of an applicant who demonstrates dyslexia or other reading impairment to the Board:<section prefix="(1)">the Board may grant 1 or both of the following:<section prefix="(i)">additional time to complete all or part of the examination; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">oral examination for all or part of the written part of the examination.</section></section><section prefix="(2)">the Board shall approve for licensing an applicant who:<section prefix="(i)">passes the examination; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">demonstrates to the Board that the applicant's dyslexia or other reading impairment, if any, does not significantly impair the applicant's ability to function as a licensee.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(g)">If an applicant fails to appear for a scheduled examination, the Board may require the applicant to pay another examination fee under &#xA7; 4-303 of this subtitle before rescheduling an examination for the applicant.</section>
  </text>
</law>
