<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gbo" order_by="" level="1">Business Occupations and Professions</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gbo-16-511</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>511</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">To qualify for renewal of a certificate under this subtitle, a holder of a certificate shall provide to the Commission adequate evidence that the holder meets the continuing education requirements established for certification under the federal Financial Institutions Reform, Recovery, and Enforcement Act of 1989.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A holder of a certificate may partly satisfy the requirement of subsection (a) of this section if the holder provides to the Commission adequate evidence that the holder:<section prefix="(1)">has completed an educational program that the Commission determines to be equal to that which the Commission approves; or</section><section prefix="(2)">in an educational program that the Commission approves and that is about real property appraisal theory and practice:<section prefix="(i)">has participated as a teacher, preparer of instructional materials, or in another similar capacity; but</section><section prefix="(ii)">has not participated as a student.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The continuing education courses shall be conducted by:<section prefix="(1)">an accredited university, college, or community or junior college;</section><section prefix="(2)">an approved appraisal society, institute, or association; or</section><section prefix="(3)">another school that the Commission approves.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">If feasible, continuing education courses shall be offered at reasonable intervals in each county and in each major geographic area of the larger counties.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">On completion of a continuing education course by a certificate holder, the entity that conducted the course or the instructor shall issue to the certificate holder a document of completion that states the number of classroom hours of that course.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The Commission may waive the requirements of this section for a certificate holder if the certificate holder shows good cause for being unable to meet the requirements.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A real estate appraiser has a grace period of 6 months after the certificate of the real estate appraiser expires in which to renew it retroactively, if:<section prefix="(i)">the real estate appraiser is otherwise entitled to have it renewed;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the Commission determines that the real estate appraiser has failed to meet the requirements for renewal through mistake, misunderstanding, or circumstances beyond the control of the real estate appraiser; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">pays the renewal fee to the Commission.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If a real estate appraiser renews a certificate within the 6-month grace period, the term of the renewal shall start the day after the certificate held originally by the real estate appraiser expired.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
