<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gbo" order_by="" level="1">Business Occupations and Professions</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gbo-8-101</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>101</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this title the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Board" means the State Board of Certified Interior Designers.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Certificate" means a certificate issued by the Board to use the title "certified interior designer".</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">"Certificate fee" means, as applicable, the fee paid in connection with the issuance and renewal of a certificate and issuance of a reciprocal certificate.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"Certified interior design services" means interior design services provided by a certified interior designer.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">"Certified interior designer" means an interior designer who is certified by the Board.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">"Design coordination" means the review and coordination of services provided by individuals licensed or certified under Titles 3, 8, 9, 14, and 15 of this article.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">"Interior design services" means rendering or offering to render services for a fee or other valuable consideration, in the preparation and administration of interior design documents (including drawings, schedules and specifications) which pertain to the planning and design of interior spaces including furnishings, layouts, fixtures, cabinetry, lighting fixtures, finishes, materials, and interior construction not materially related to or materially affecting the building systems, all of which shall comply with applicable laws, codes, regulations, and standards. The scope of work described herein shall not be construed as authorizing the planning and design of engineering and architectural interior construction as related to the building systems, including structural, electrical, plumbing, heating, ventilating, air conditioning or mechanical systems and shall not be construed as authorizing the practice of architecture or engineering as defined in Title 3 or Title 14 of this article. The interior design plans as described above are not to be construed as those architectural plans which may be required to be filed with any county or municipality.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">"Public use" means the use of a building or other structure for the primary purpose of human use or habitation.</section>
    <section prefix="(j)">"Residential use" means the use of a building or other structure as a dwelling.</section>
  </text>
</law>
