<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gbo" order_by="gbo" level="1">Business Occupations and Professions</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gbo-17-205</section_number>
  <catch_line>The Secretary shall appoint the executive director of the Commission from a list of 3 nominees submi...</catch_line>
  <order_by>205</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Secretary shall appoint the executive director of the Commission from a list of 3 nominees submitted by the Commission.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The executive director serves at the pleasure of the Secretary.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The executive director shall:<section prefix="(1)">possess a broad knowledge of generally accepted practices in the real estate business in the State; and</section><section prefix="(2)">be reasonably well informed of the general laws that govern agency and contracts for the conveyance or leasing of real estate.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The executive director shall devote full time to the duties of office.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The executive director may not hold any position or engage in another business that:<section prefix="(i)">interferes with the position of executive director; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">might conflict with the position of executive director.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">While employed by the Commission, the executive director may not:<section prefix="(i)">be licensed in any state as a real estate broker, an associate real estate broker, or a real estate salesperson;</section><section prefix="(ii)">engage in any act for which a license is required under this title; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">in connection with any real estate transaction, directly or indirectly receive or become entitled to receive any fee, perquisite, or compensation.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The executive director is entitled to:<section prefix="(1)">compensation in accordance with the State budget; and</section><section prefix="(2)">reimbursement for expenses under the Standard State Travel Regulations, as provided in the State budget.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The executive director is a special appointment in the State Personnel Management System.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">While employed as executive director, the executive director shall be covered by a surety bond in the form and amount required by law.</section>
  </text>
</law>
