<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gbo" order_by="gbo" level="1">Business Occupations and Professions</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gbo-17-306</section_number>
  <catch_line>An applicant who otherwise qualifies for a license is entitled to be examined as provided in this se...</catch_line>
  <order_by>306</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">An applicant who otherwise qualifies for a license is entitled to be examined as provided in this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Commission periodically shall give examinations to applicants at the times and places that the Commission determines.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Except as provided in subsection (f)(2)(ii) of this section, the Commission shall give each qualified applicant notice of the time and place of examination.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">To take an examination, an applicant shall pay:<section prefix="(1)">to the Commission, an examination fee set by the Commission; and</section><section prefix="(2)">to the Commission or a testing service chosen by the Commission, an amount covering the cost of the examination.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as otherwise provided in this subsection, the Commission shall determine the subjects, scope, and form of and the passing score for examinations given under this subtitle.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">To ensure the protection of the interests of those persons who are represented by licensed real estate brokers, the Commission shall structure the examinations for a real estate broker license to test:<section prefix="(i)">the ability of an applicant to perform the services authorized by a real estate broker license; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">the knowledge of the applicant of the general practice for handling real estate transactions.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The examinations shall be written.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">To eliminate the possibility of discrimination in the administration of the examination, each copy of an examination for a particular license given on a particular date shall contain the same questions. However, the questions may be in different order.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Commission may use a testing service to administer the examinations under this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If the Commission uses a testing service under this subsection, the testing service, subject to the requirements set by the Commission, may:<section prefix="(i)">set the times and places of examinations; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">give applicants notice of the examinations.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
