<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gbo" order_by="gbo" level="1">Business Occupations and Professions</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gbo-6.5-303</section_number>
  <catch_line>Except as otherwise provided in this title, to qualify for licensure as a stationary engineer, an ap...</catch_line>
  <order_by>303</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Except as otherwise provided in this title, to qualify for licensure as a stationary engineer, an applicant shall meet the requirements of this section and pass an examination administered by the Board.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">In addition to the other qualifications for a license set forth in this subtitle, an applicant shall qualify under this section by meeting the educational and experience requirements set forth in subsection (c) of this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">An applicant for the Grade 1 stationary engineer's examination qualifies under this section if the applicant possesses at least one of the following qualifications:<section prefix="(i)">5 years of documented experience as an active Grade 2 stationary engineer under the direction and control of a Grade 1 stationary engineer, toward which an applicant may receive:<section prefix="1.">1 year of credit for 6 credit hours of classes or continuing education units in boiler safety or operations; and</section><section prefix="2.">1 year of credit for holding a current active license as a:</section></section><section prefix="(ii)">a 4-year degree in mechanical engineering from an accredited university or college;</section><section prefix="(iii)">licensure as a professional engineer including:<section prefix="1.">1 year of documented experience as a professional engineer; and</section><section prefix="2.">1 year of documented experience as a Grade 2 stationary engineer under the direction and control of a Grade 1 stationary engineer; or</section></section><section prefix="(iv)">a valid marine engineer's certificate or a chief petty officer's certificate from the United States Navy with documentation of steam boiler engineer training.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">An applicant for a Grade 2 stationary engineer's examination qualifies under this section if the applicant possesses at least one of the following qualifications:<section prefix="(i)">36 months of documented experience as an active Grade 3 engineer under the direction and control of a licensed Grade 2 or Grade 1 stationary engineer, that may include:<section prefix="1.">1 year of credit for 6 credit hours of classes or continuing education units in boiler safety or operations; and</section><section prefix="2.">1 year of credit for holding a current active license as a:</section></section><section prefix="(ii)">a 4-year degree in mechanical engineering from an accredited university or college;</section><section prefix="(iii)">licensure as a professional engineer and 6 months of documented experience as a Grade 3, Grade 4, or Grade 5 stationary engineer; or</section><section prefix="(iv)">a valid marine engineer's certificate or chief petty officer's certificate from the United States Navy.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">An applicant for a Grade 3 stationary engineer's examination qualifies under this section if the applicant possesses at least one of the following qualifications:<section prefix="(i)">2 years of documented experience as an active Grade 4 or Grade 5 stationary engineer;</section><section prefix="(ii)">1 year of documented experience as an active Grade 4 or Grade 5 engineer and 6 credit hours or continuing education units of classes in boiler operations or safety; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">a valid marine engineer's certificate or chief petty officer's certificate from the United States Navy.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">An applicant for a Grade 4 stationary engineer's examination qualifies under this section if the applicant possesses at least one of the following qualifications:<section prefix="(i)">6 months of documented experience as an active Grade 5 stationary engineer; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">3 credit hours or continuing education units of classes in boiler operations or safety.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(5)">An applicant for a Grade 5 stationary engineer's examination qualifies under this section if the applicant possesses a high school diploma or graduate equivalence diploma.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
