<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gbo" order_by="" level="1">Business Occupations and Professions</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gbo-10-605.2</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>605.2</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This section applies only to a communication:<section prefix="(i)">in a form described under subsection (c) of this section;</section><section prefix="(ii)">sent by a lawyer, directly or through an agent or employee, to a prospective client for the purpose of obtaining professional employment; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">if the communication concerns:<section prefix="1.">an action for personal injury or wrongful death, or otherwise relates to an accident or disaster involving the person to whom the communication is sent or the person's relative; or</section><section prefix="2.">a criminal prosecution, or a prosecution of a traffic offense that is punishable by a period of incarceration, involving the person to whom the communication is sent or the person's relative.</section></section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">This section does not apply to a direct marketing communication that is not related to:<section prefix="(i)">a specific accident or disaster described under paragraph (1)(iii)1 of this subsection; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">a specific criminal prosecution or traffic offense described under paragraph (1)(iii)2 of this subsection.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">This section does not apply to a communication sent to a prospective client at the request of the prospective client.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">This section applies only to the following forms of communication:<section prefix="(1)">an audio recording;</section><section prefix="(2)">a computer on-line transmission;</section><section prefix="(3)">a facsimile transmission;</section><section prefix="(4)">a letter or other form of written communication;</section><section prefix="(5)">a telegraphic transmission;</section><section prefix="(6)">a telephonic transmission; and</section><section prefix="(7)">a video recording.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Each communication shall include the words "this is an advertisement" in a prominent place at the beginning and end of each communication as required in this subsection.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">In a communication sent by computer on-line transmission, facsimile, mail, or telegraph, the required wording shall appear in conspicuous print size and in a freestanding form:<section prefix="(i)">on the outside of the envelope, if any; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">at the beginning and end of the contents of the communication.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">If the form of the communication is a self-mailing brochure or pamphlet, the required wording shall appear on the address panel of the brochure or pamphlet.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">In a video recording communication, the required wording:<section prefix="(i)">shall appear conspicuously in the communication for at least five seconds at the beginning and for at least five seconds at the end of the communication; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">of the audio recording portion, if any, of the communication shall meet the requirements of paragraph (5) of this subsection.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(5)">In an audio recording communication, the required wording shall appear, at the beginning and end of the communication, in a tone, volume, clarity, and speed of delivery at least substantially equivalent to the quality of the tone, volume, clarity, and speed of the audio elsewhere in the communication.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">A written communication may not be in the form of, or include, legal pleadings or legal documents.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">A communication may not reveal on the envelope, or on the outside of a self-mailing brochure or pamphlet, the nature of the prospective client's legal matter.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">In addition to meeting the requirements of this section, a communication shall comply with Maryland Rules of Professional Conduct 7.1 through 7.4.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this subsection, "Bar Counsel" means the principal executive officer of the disciplinary system for lawyers under the Maryland Rules.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Subject to the provisions of this subsection, a person who sends a communication shall, within 3 days after the date that the communication is sent, file the following with the Bar Counsel:<section prefix="(i)">a copy of the communication, together with a sample copy of the envelope, if any, used in conjunction with the communication; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">the name of the person to whom the communication was sent and the person's mailing address, telephone number, or telecommunication address to which the communication was sent.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">If communications identical in content are sent to two or more persons, a person may comply with the provisions of paragraph (2) of this subsection by filing with the Bar Counsel within 3 days after the date that the communication was sent a single copy of the communication together with a list of the names and the applicable mailing addresses, telephone numbers, or telecommunication addresses of the persons to whom the communication was sent.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">If the person periodically sends an identical communication to additional persons, the person may comply with the provisions of paragraph (2) of this subsection by filing with Bar Counsel lists of additional names and the applicable mailing addresses, telephone numbers, or telecommunication addresses not less than monthly.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">A communication may not state or imply that a communication is approved by the Bar Counsel, the State, or any unit of the State.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(i)">A lawyer, or a person acting as an agent or employee of the lawyer, may not send, or knowingly permit to be sent, on a lawyer's behalf, on the behalf of a lawyer's firm, partner, or associate, or on behalf of any other lawyer affiliated with the lawyer, a communication that does not meet the requirements of this section.</section>
  </text>
</law>
