<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gbo" order_by="gbo" level="1">Business Occupations and Professions</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gbo-17-317</section_number>
  <catch_line>A licensed real estate broker shall display at all times:...</catch_line>
  <order_by>317</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A licensed real estate broker shall display at all times:<section prefix="(i)">the license certificate of the real estate broker in a conspicuous place in the principal office of the real estate broker; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">in accordance with paragraph (2) of this subsection, the license certificate of each associate real estate broker and real estate salesperson who is affiliated with the real estate broker.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">If an associate real estate broker or a real estate salesperson who is affiliated with the real estate broker works primarily out of the principal office of the real estate broker, the real estate broker shall display the license certificate of the associate broker or salesperson in a conspicuous place in the principal office.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">If an associate real estate broker or a real estate salesperson who is affiliated with the real estate broker works primarily out of a branch office of the real estate broker, the real estate broker shall display the license certificate of the associate broker or salesperson in a conspicuous place in the branch office out of which the associate broker or salesperson primarily works.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If a license certificate is lost or destroyed, the licensee immediately shall notify the Commission.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">To receive a duplicate license certificate, the licensee shall submit to the Commission:<section prefix="(i)">an affidavit stating that the license certificate has been lost or destroyed; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">a fee set by the Commission.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">On receipt of the affidavit and fee, the Commission shall issue an appropriate duplicate license certificate to the licensee.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If a pocket card is lost or destroyed, the licensee immediately shall notify the Commission.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">To receive a duplicate pocket card, the licensee shall submit to the Commission:<section prefix="(i)">an affidavit stating that the pocket card has been lost or destroyed; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">a fee set by the Commission.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">On receipt of the affidavit and fee, the Commission shall issue an appropriate duplicate pocket card to the licensee.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
