<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gbo" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="17-518" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gbo-17-518</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Subject to the provisions of this subtitle, a licensed real estate broker may maintain branch offices in the State.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A licensed real estate broker shall obtain a branch office certificate before the broker may maintain a branch office in the State.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">An applicant for a branch office certificate shall:<section prefix="(i)">submit to the Commission an application on the form that the Commission provides;</section><section prefix="(ii)">submit to the Commission written notice of the identity of the individual appointed as manager of the branch office under subsection (d) of this section; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">pay to the Commission an application fee of $5.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Commission shall issue a branch office certificate to each licensed real estate broker who meets the requirements of this section.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Subject to paragraph (2) of this subsection, the licensed real estate broker shall designate a manager for each branch office of the broker.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The manager shall be:<section prefix="(i)">a licensed associate real estate broker;</section><section prefix="(ii)">a licensed real estate salesperson who has at least 3 years' experience providing real estate brokerage services; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">a licensed real estate salesperson who:</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A licensed real estate salesperson seeking to qualify as a branch office manager under paragraph (2)(iii) of this subsection shall submit to the Commission, before taking the real estate broker's examination, a commitment from the licensed real estate broker proposing to engage the salesperson as a branch office manager.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The manager shall have the responsibility to supervise the provision of real estate brokerage services by the associate brokers and sales agents registered to that office as provided for in &#xA7; 17-320 of this title.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Unless a branch office certificate is renewed for a 2-year term as provided in this subsection, the certificate expires on the first April 30 that comes:<section prefix="(i)">after the effective date of the certificate; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">in an even-numbered year.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Before a branch office certificate expires, a licensed real estate broker periodically may renew it for an additional 2-year term, if the broker:<section prefix="(i)">submits to the Commission a renewal application on the form that the Commission provides accompanied by the license renewal application of the manager of the branch office; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">pays to the Commission a renewal fee of $5.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Commission shall renew the branch office certificate of each licensed real estate broker who meets the requirements of this section.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
