<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gbo" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="8-310" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gbo-8-310</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Subject to the hearing provisions of &#xA7; 8-312 of this subtitle, the Board may deny a certificate to any applicant, reprimand any certificate holder, or suspend or revoke a certificate if the applicant or certificate holder:<section prefix="(i)">fraudulently or deceptively obtains or renews or attempts to obtain or renew a certificate for the applicant or certificate holder or for another;</section><section prefix="(ii)">fraudulently or deceptively uses the title "certified interior designer" or the term "certified interior design services";</section><section prefix="(iii)">under the laws of the United States or of any state, is convicted of:</section><section prefix="(iv)">is guilty of any fraud, gross negligence, incompetence, or misconduct in the use of the title "certified interior designer" or the term "certified interior design services";</section><section prefix="(v)">signs or seals any interior design documents after a certificate holder's certificate expires or has been suspended or revoked by the Board;</section><section prefix="(vi)">violates any regulation that the Board adopts; or</section><section prefix="(vii)">violates any provision of this title.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Instead of or in addition to reprimanding a certificate holder or suspending or revoking a certificate under this subsection, the Board may impose a penalty not exceeding $5,000 for each violation.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">To determine the amount of the penalty imposed under this subsection, the Board shall consider:</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Board shall pay any penalty collected under this subsection into the General Fund of the State.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Board shall consider the following facts in the granting, denial, renewal, suspension, or revocation of a certificate or the reprimand of a certificate holder when an applicant or certificate holder is convicted of a felony or misdemeanor described in subsection (a)(1)(iii) of this section:<section prefix="(1)">the nature of the crime;</section><section prefix="(2)">the relationship of the crime to the activities authorized by the certificate;</section><section prefix="(3)">with respect to a felony, the relevance of the conviction to the fitness and qualification of the applicant or licensee to perform interior design services;</section><section prefix="(4)">the length of time since the conviction; and</section><section prefix="(5)">the behavior and activities of the applicant or certificate holder before and after the conviction.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
