<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gbo" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="17-202" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gbo-17-202</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Commission consists of 9 members.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Of the 9 members of the Commission:<section prefix="(i)">5 shall be licensed real estate brokers, licensed associate real estate brokers, or licensed real estate salespersons; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">4 shall be consumer members.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Of the 5 professional members:<section prefix="(i)">1 shall be a resident of any county in the area that consists of Cecil, Caroline, Dorchester, Kent, Queen Anne's, Somerset, Talbot, Wicomico, and Worcester counties;</section><section prefix="(ii)">1 shall be a resident of any county in the area that consists of Baltimore, Carroll, Harford, and Howard counties;</section><section prefix="(iii)">1 shall be a resident of Baltimore City;</section><section prefix="(iv)">1 shall be a resident of any county in the area that consists of Anne Arundel, Calvert, Charles, Prince George's, and St. Mary's counties; and</section><section prefix="(v)">1 shall be a resident of any county in the area that consists of Allegany, Frederick, Garrett, Montgomery, and Washington counties.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The Governor shall appoint the members with the advice of the Secretary and with the advice and consent of the Senate.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Each member of the Commission shall be a citizen of the State.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Each professional member of the Commission shall have been:<section prefix="(1)">a resident of any of the counties in the area from which the member is appointed for at least 5 years immediately before appointment; and</section><section prefix="(2)">a licensed real estate broker, a licensed associate real estate broker, or a licensed real estate salesperson for at least 10 years immediately before appointment.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Each consumer member of the Commission:<section prefix="(i)">shall be a member of the general public;</section><section prefix="(ii)">may not be a licensee or otherwise be subject to regulation by the Commission;</section><section prefix="(iii)">may not be required to meet the qualifications for the professional members of the Commission; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">may not, within 1 year before appointment, have had a financial interest in or have received compensation from a person regulated by the Commission.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">While a member of the Commission, a consumer member may not:<section prefix="(i)">have a financial interest in or receive compensation from a person regulated by the Commission; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">grade any examination given by or for the Commission.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">Before taking office, each appointee to the Commission shall take the oath required by Article I, &#xA7; 9 of the Maryland Constitution.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The term of a member is 4 years and begins on June 1.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The terms of members are staggered as required by the terms provided for members of the Commission on October 1, 1989.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">At the end of a term, a member continues to serve until a successor is appointed and qualifies.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">A member who is appointed after a term has begun serves only for the rest of the term and until a successor is appointed and qualifies.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">The Governor may remove a member for incompetence or misconduct.</section>
  </text>
</law>
