<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gbo" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="17-314" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gbo-17-314</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Except as provided in subsection (c) of this section, unless a real estate broker license is renewed for a 2-year term as provided in this section, the license expires on the first March 1 that comes:<section prefix="(1)">after the effective date of the license; and</section><section prefix="(2)">in an even-numbered year.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Except as provided in subsection (c) of this section, unless an associate real estate broker or real estate salesperson license is renewed for a 2-year term as provided in this section, the license expires on the first April 30 that comes:<section prefix="(1)">after the effective date of the license; and</section><section prefix="(2)">in an even-numbered year.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Secretary may determine that licenses issued under this title shall expire on a staggered basis.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">At least 1 month before a license expires, the Commission shall mail to the licensee, as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection:<section prefix="(i)">a renewal application form; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">a notice that states:</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">If the licensee is a real estate broker, the Commission shall mail the renewal application form and notice to the principal office of the broker.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">If the licensee is an associate real estate broker or a real estate salesperson, the Commission shall mail the renewal application form and notice to the principal office of the real estate broker with whom the licensee is affiliated.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">Before a license expires, the licensee periodically may renew it for an additional 2-year term, if the licensee:<section prefix="(1)">otherwise is entitled to be licensed;</section><section prefix="(2)">pays to the Commission a renewal fee set by the Commission;</section><section prefix="(3)">submits to the Commission a renewal application on the form that the Commission provides;</section><section prefix="(4)">submits to the Commission the original certificate of completion verifying that the licensee has complied with the continuing education requirements under &#xA7; 17-315 of this subtitle;</section><section prefix="(5)">notifies the Commission of the name of each real estate broker with whom the licensee then is affiliated; and</section><section prefix="(6)">for the renewal of a real estate broker license:<section prefix="(i)">submits to the Commission, by a credit reporting agency approved by the Commission, a credit report that contains the information required by the Commission; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">pays to the Commission or the Commission's designee a credit report fee in an amount not to exceed the cost charged by a credit reporting agency approved by the Commission to obtain a credit report that contains the information required by the Commission for renewal of a real estate broker license.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The Commission shall renew the license of and issue a renewal certificate and pocket card to each licensee who meets the requirements of this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">The Commission shall reinstate the license of a licensee under this title whose license has expired if the licensee:<section prefix="(1)">applies to the Commission for reinstatement within 3 years after the license expires;</section><section prefix="(2)">meets the requirement of good character and reputation;</section><section prefix="(3)">complies with the applicable continuing education requirement for the period during which the individual was not licensed; and</section><section prefix="(4)">pays to the Commission a reinstatement fee set by the Commission.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
