<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gbo" order_by="" level="1">Business Occupations and Professions</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gbo-4-301.1</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>301.1</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Subject to the provisions of this subsection, a student who has completed at least 80 hours of training at a school of barbering may practice barbering, without a license, at the school.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A student may practice barbering under this subsection only:<section prefix="(i)">in the course of the practical work required as part of the training of the student;</section><section prefix="(ii)">while the student is under the direct supervision of a teacher who meets the requirements established by the Department of Education for public school programs or the Maryland Higher Education Commission for private school programs; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">if the individual to whom a service is to be provided agrees to the service after being informed that a student in training is to provide the service.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Subject to the provisions of this subsection, a student who has completed at least 850 hours of training at a school of barbering may practice barbering, without a license, in a:<section prefix="(i)">hospital;</section><section prefix="(ii)">nursing home; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">correctional facility that does not house a barber school.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A student may practice barbering under this subsection only:<section prefix="(i)">in the course of the practical work required as part of the training of the student;</section><section prefix="(ii)">while the student is under the direct supervision of a teacher who meets the requirements established by the Department of Education for public school programs or the Maryland Higher Education Commission for private school programs; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">if the individual to whom a service is to be provided:<section prefix="1.">is confined to a hospital, nursing home, or correctional facility that does not house a barber school; and</section><section prefix="2.">agrees to the service after being informed that a student in training is to provide the service.</section></section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
