<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gbo" order_by="gbo" level="1">Business Occupations and Professions</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gbo-20-305</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this section, "Central Repository" means the Criminal Justice Information System Central Reposito...</catch_line>
  <order_by>305</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, "Central Repository" means the Criminal Justice Information System Central Repository of the Department of Public Safety and Correctional Services.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">An applicant for a license under this title and an individual whose name must be submitted under &#xA7; 20-303(c)(5) of this subtitle shall apply to the Central Repository for State and national criminal history records checks on a form approved by the Director of the Central Repository.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">For each individual applying for State and national criminal history records checks under subsection (b) of this section, the Central Repository shall:<section prefix="(1)">notify the Secretary of the receipt of the application for State and national criminal history records checks;</section><section prefix="(2)">process the State and national criminal history records checks and forward to the Secretary and the individual a printed statement listing the finding of a felony conviction; and</section><section prefix="(3)">process an update of the initial State criminal history records check and forward to the Secretary a revised printed statement listing the finding of a felony conviction for an offense occurring in the State after the date of the initial criminal history records check.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">An individual applying for State and national criminal history records checks shall submit to the Central Repository:<section prefix="(1)">a complete set of legible fingerprints taken at any designated State or local law enforcement office in the State or other location approved by the Secretary;</section><section prefix="(2)">the mandatory processing fee required by the Federal Bureau of Investigation for a national criminal history records check; and</section><section prefix="(3)">the fee authorized under &#xA7; 10-221(b)(7) of the Criminal Procedure Article for access to Maryland criminal history records.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">A private home detention monitoring agency or an applicant for a license to operate a private home detention monitoring agency may pay the fees required in subsection (d) of this section for an individual it intends to employ as a private home detention monitor.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">Information obtained by the Secretary under this section shall be confidential and may not:<section prefix="(1)">be used for any purpose other than that for which it was disseminated; and</section><section prefix="(2)">be redisseminated.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
