<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gbo" order_by="gbo" level="1">Business Occupations and Professions</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gbo-4-405</section_number>
  <catch_line>The initial term of registration as an apprentice barber is 2 years....</catch_line>
  <order_by>405</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The initial term of registration as an apprentice barber is 2 years.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">An apprentice barber may renew the apprentice barber registration one time.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The one-time renewal of an apprentice barber registration expires on the date set by the Board.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">At least 1 month before registration as an apprentice barber expires, the Board shall mail to the apprentice barber, at the last known address of the apprentice barber:<section prefix="(1)">a renewal application form; and</section><section prefix="(2)">a notice that states:<section prefix="(i)">the date on which the current registration as an apprentice barber expires;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the date by which the Board must receive the renewal application for the renewal to be approved, issued, and mailed before the registration expires; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">the amount of the renewal fee.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Before the registration of an individual expires, the individual may renew it for an additional term if the individual:<section prefix="(1)">otherwise is entitled to be registered;</section><section prefix="(2)">pays to the Board a renewal fee established by the Board in accordance with &#xA7; 4-206 of this title; and</section><section prefix="(3)">submits to the Board a renewal application on the form that the Board provides.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The Board shall renew the apprentice barber registration of and issue a renewal certificate to each apprentice barber who meets the requirements of this section.</section>
  </text>
</law>
