<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gbo" order_by="gbo" level="1">Business Occupations and Professions</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gbo-16-5A-04</section_number>
  <catch_line>Unless a real estate appraiser trainee license is renewed under this section, the license expires 3 ...</catch_line>
  <order_by>04</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Unless a real estate appraiser trainee license is renewed under this section, the license expires 3 years after the effective date of the license.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Before a real estate appraiser trainee license expires, the licensee may renew the license for one additional 3-year term if the licensee:<section prefix="(i)">is otherwise entitled to be licensed;</section><section prefix="(ii)">pays to the Commission a renewal fee set by the Commission; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">submits to the Commission:<section prefix="1.">a renewal application on the form that the Commission requires; and</section><section prefix="2.">adequate evidence that the licensee meets the minimum continuing education requirements established under the federal Financial Institutions Reform, Recovery, and Enforcement Act of 1989.</section></section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">At least 1 month before a real estate appraiser trainee license expires, the Commission shall mail to the licensee, at the last known address of the licensee:<section prefix="(i)">a renewal application form; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">a notice that states:<section prefix="1.">the date on which the current license expires;</section><section prefix="2.">the date by which the Commission must receive the renewal application for the renewal to be issued and mailed before the license expires; and</section><section prefix="3.">the amount of the renewal fee.</section></section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The failure of a licensee to receive the notice under this subsection does not prevent the license from expiring as specified under subsection (a) of this section.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
