<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gbo" order_by="gbo" level="1">Business Occupations and Professions</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gbo-17-530</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this section the following words have the meanings indicated....</catch_line>
  <order_by>530</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Buyer's agent" means a licensed real estate broker, licensed associate real estate broker, or licensed real estate salesperson who represents a prospective buyer or lessee in the acquisition of real estate for sale or for lease.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Cooperating agent" means a licensed real estate broker, licensed associate real estate broker, or licensed real estate salesperson who:<section prefix="(i)">is not affiliated with or is not acting as the listing real estate broker for a property; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">assists a prospective buyer or lessee as a subagent of the listing real estate broker, in the acquisition of real estate for sale or for lease.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">"Intra-company agent" means a licensed associate real estate broker or licensed real estate salesperson who has been designated by the real estate broker who the associate real estate broker or licensed real estate salesperson is affiliated with to act as a dual agent on behalf of a seller or lessor or buyer or lessee in the purchase, sale, or lease of real estate that is listed with the real estate broker.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">"Dual agent" means a licensed real estate broker, licensed associate real estate broker, or licensed real estate salesperson who acts as an agent for both the seller and the buyer or the lessor and the lessee in the same real estate transaction.</section>
      <section prefix="(6)">"Seller's agent" means a licensed real estate broker, licensed associate real estate broker, or licensed real estate salesperson who:<section prefix="(i)">is affiliated with or acts as the listing broker for real estate; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">assists a prospective buyer or lessee in the acquisition of real estate for sale or for lease.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A licensee who participates in a residential real estate transaction as a seller's agent, buyer's agent, or as a cooperating agent shall disclose in writing that the licensee represents the seller or lessor or the buyer or lessee.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The disclosure shall occur not later than the first scheduled face-to-face contact with the seller or lessor or the buyer or lessee.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">In any residential real estate transaction involving a cooperating agent as defined in this section, it shall be the obligation of the cooperating agent to make the written disclosure to the buyer or lessee required under this section.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">In any residential real estate transaction that does not involve a cooperating agent as defined in this section, it shall be the obligation of the seller's agent, as defined in this section, to make the written disclosure to the buyer or lessee required under this section.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(4)">In any residential real estate transaction involving a buyer's agent, it shall be the obligation of the buyer's agent to make the written disclosure to the seller or lessor or the agent of the seller or lessor as required under this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">The written disclosure shall explain:<section prefix="(i)">the differences between a seller's agent, buyer's agent, cooperating agent, dual agent, and intra-company agent;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the duties of a licensee to exercise reasonable care and diligence and maintain confidentiality;</section><section prefix="(iii)">that a licensee who assists a buyer or lessee in locating residential real estate for purchase or lease and is neither affiliated with nor acting as the listing real estate broker for any real estate shown or located, is presumed to be acting as a buyer's agent on behalf of the prospective buyer or lessee, unless either the licensee or the prospective buyer or lessee expressly declines to have the licensee act as a buyer's agent;</section><section prefix="(iv)">that regardless of whom a licensee represents in a real estate transaction, the licensee has a duty to treat each party fairly, promptly present each written offer and counteroffer, respond truthfully to each question, disclose all material facts that are known or should be known relating to a property, and offer each property without discrimination;</section><section prefix="(v)">that a licensee is qualified to advise only on real estate matters and that legal or tax advice should be obtained from a licensed attorney or accountant;</section><section prefix="(vi)">the need for an agreement with a seller's agent, buyer's agent, or dual agent to be in writing and to include the duties and obligations of the agent, how and by whom the agent will be compensated, and any fee-sharing arrangements with other agents;</section><section prefix="(vii)">the duty of a buyer's agent to assist in the:<section prefix="1.">evaluation of a property, including the provision of a market analysis of the property; and</section><section prefix="2.">preparation of an offer on a property and to negotiate in the best interests of the buyer;</section></section><section prefix="(viii)">the possibility that a dual agency may arise in a real estate transaction and the options that would become available to the buyer and seller or lessee and lessor; and</section><section prefix="(ix)">that any complaints concerning a licensee may be filed with the State Real Estate Commission.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Except as otherwise provided in subsection (d) of this section, a licensed real estate broker, licensed associate real estate broker, or licensed real estate salesperson may not act as a dual agent in this State.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">If a licensed real estate broker or a designee of the real estate broker obtains the written informed consent of all parties to a real estate transaction, the real estate broker may act as a dual agent in the transaction.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">When acting as a dual agent in a real estate transaction, a real estate broker or a designee of the real estate broker shall assign a licensed associate real estate broker or licensed real estate salesperson affiliated with the real estate broker to act as the intra-company agent on behalf of the seller or lessor and another licensed associate real estate broker or licensed real estate salesperson affiliated with the real estate broker to act as the intra-company agent on behalf of the buyer or lessee.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">
          <section prefix="1.">Except as otherwise required by this title and except to the intra-company agent's real estate broker or a designee of the real estate broker, an intra-company agent may not disclose information that a seller or buyer in a real estate transaction requests to remain confidential.</section>
          <section prefix="2.">Except as otherwise required by this title, the real estate broker or the designee of the real estate broker acting as the dual agent may not disclose confidential information to the buyer or seller or the buyer's or seller's intra-company agent in the same real estate transaction.</section>
        </section>
        <section prefix="(iv)">If a real estate broker offers any financial bonuses to licensees affiliated with the broker for the sale or lease of real property listed with the real estate broker, the real estate broker shall provide to each party to a real estate transaction a statement that discloses that financial bonuses are offered.</section>
        <section prefix="(v)">An intra-company agent representing the seller or buyer may provide the same services to the client as an exclusive agent for the seller or buyer, including advising the client as to price and negotiation strategy, provided that the intra-company agent has made the appropriate disclosures to the client and the client has consented, as required by this section, to dual agency representation.</section>
        <section prefix="(vi)">The provisions of the services specified in this subsection may not be construed to be a breach of duty of the licensee, provided that the licensee has complied with the duties specified in &#xA7; 17-522 of this subtitle.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The written consent shall identify each property for which the real estate broker will serve as a dual agent.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The written consent shall include a statement that:<section prefix="(i)">the real estate broker receives compensation on the sale of a property listed only by the broker;</section><section prefix="(ii)">as a dual agent the real estate broker represents both the seller and the buyer and there may be a conflict of interest because the interests of the seller and the buyer may be different or adverse;</section><section prefix="(iii)">as a dual agent the real estate broker does not owe undivided loyalty to either the seller or the buyer;</section><section prefix="(iv)">except as otherwise required by this title, a dual agent may not disclose information that a seller or buyer in a real estate transaction requests to remain confidential to the buyer or seller in the same real estate transaction;</section><section prefix="(v)">unless authorized by the seller, a dual agent may not tell a buyer that the seller will accept a price lower than the listing price or accept terms other than those contained in the listing agreement or suggest that the seller accept a lower price in the presence of the buyer;</section><section prefix="(vi)">unless authorized by the buyer, a dual agent may not tell a seller that the buyer is willing to pay a price higher than the price the buyer offered or accept terms other than those contained in the offer of the buyer or suggest that the buyer pay a higher price in the presence of the seller;</section><section prefix="(vii)">a dual agent may not disclose the motivation of a buyer or seller or the need or urgency of a seller to sell or a buyer to buy;</section><section prefix="(viii)">except as otherwise required by this title, if the information is confidential, a dual agent may not disclose any facts that lead the seller to sell;</section><section prefix="(ix)">the buyer or seller does not have to consent to the dual agency;</section><section prefix="(x)">the buyer or seller has voluntarily consented to the dual agency; and</section><section prefix="(xi)">the terms of the dual agency are understood by the buyer or seller.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">
        <section prefix="(i)">A cause of action may not arise against a licensee for disclosure of the dual agency relationship as provided by this section.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">A dual agent does not terminate any brokerage relationship by making any required disclosure of dual agency.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(5)">
        <section prefix="(i)">In any residential real estate transaction, a licensee may withdraw from representing a client who refuses to consent to a disclosed dual agency and to terminate the brokerage relationship with the client.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The withdrawal may not prejudice the ability of the licensee to continue to represent the other client in the transaction, nor to limit the licensee from representing the client who refused the dual agency in other transactions not involving dual agency.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The State Real Estate Commission shall require a licensed real estate broker, licensed associate real estate broker, or licensed real estate salesperson who participates in a residential real estate transaction to utilize a standard disclosure form in each real estate transaction that includes the information specified in subsection (b)(5) of this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The State Real Estate Commission shall require a licensed real estate broker who acts as a dual agent and a licensed real estate associate broker or licensed real estate salesperson who acts as an intra-company agent in a real estate transaction to utilize a standard consent form that includes the information specified in subsection (d)(3) of this section.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The State Real Estate Commission shall prepare and provide a copy of:<section prefix="(i)">the standard disclosure form required under subsection (b) of this section to each licensee in this State; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">the standard consent form required under subsection (d) of this section to each licensee in this State.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The disclosure form and the consent form shall be:<section prefix="(i)">written in a clear and coherent manner using words with common and everyday meanings;</section><section prefix="(ii)">appropriately divided and captioned by their various sections; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">printed in at least 10 point type.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
