<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gbo" order_by="" level="1">Business Occupations and Professions</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gbo-18-102</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>102</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">This title does not apply to an officer or employee of any unit of the United States, of any state, or of any county, municipal corporation, or other political subdivision of any state, while performing a duty of the office or employment.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This title does not supersede any local law or ordinance in the State that establishes standards or qualifications for electricians or for electrical work involved in the installation of security systems or security alarms.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">This title does not authorize an individual to perform electrical work that otherwise requires an electrician's license under any State or local law or ordinance.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Except as provided in paragraph (4) of this subsection, this title supersedes any local law or ordinance in the State that requires registration, training, bonding, or insurance for security systems technicians or other individuals who have access to circumventional information.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">This title does not preempt local governments from licensing or regulating security system agencies or security system users.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The licensing requirements of this title do not apply to a master electrician who:<section prefix="(i)">currently is licensed in that occupation under State or local law; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">is acting only within the scope of that occupation.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A master electrician may not:<section prefix="(i)">personally provide security systems services unless the master electrician is registered as a security systems technician; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">obtain access to circumventional information unless the master electrician is registered as an individual with access to circumventional information.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">This title does not apply to a person who sells security systems at a retail establishment or by means of a catalog or brochure for future delivery, provided that the person does not:<section prefix="(1)">enter the premises of the customer's property; or</section><section prefix="(2)">have access to circumventional information.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">This title does not apply to a commercial property owner or its authorized agent performing the routine operation, including the changing of the passcodes, of a security system that protects the premises of the owner's commercial property.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">This title may not be construed to require:<section prefix="(1)">a person engaged in the business of providing security systems services for compensation to obtain more than one license under this title to provide security systems services;</section><section prefix="(2)">a security systems technician, in addition to being registered under this title, to obtain a license under this title, if the security systems technician is employed by or under contract with a security systems agency; or</section><section prefix="(3)">an individual who is licensed under this title to be registered under Subtitle 3A of this title.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
