<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gbo" order_by="gbo" level="1">Business Occupations and Professions</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gbo-16-506</section_number>
  <catch_line>Except as otherwise provided in &#xA7; 16-506.1 of this subtitle, an applicant who otherwise qualifies f...</catch_line>
  <order_by>506</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Except as otherwise provided in &#xA7; 16-506.1 of this subtitle, an applicant who otherwise qualifies for a certificate is entitled to be examined as provided in this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Commission periodically shall give examinations to qualified applicants at the times and places that the Commission determines.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Commission shall give each qualified applicant notice of the time and place of examination.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">To take an examination, an applicant shall pay an examination fee to the Commission or the Commission's designee in an amount not to exceed the cost of the examination as established by the Commission.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as otherwise provided in this subsection, the Commission shall determine the scope and the passing score for examinations given under this subtitle.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The form of an examination shall be written.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">An examination shall test knowledge of:<section prefix="(i)">technical terms commonly used in real estate appraising and economic concepts applicable to real estate;</section><section prefix="(ii)">real estate appraisal theory and practice and real estate appraisal process;</section><section prefix="(iii)">standards for the development and communication of real estate appraisals;</section><section prefix="(iv)">standards of conduct that the Commission adopts under &#xA7; 16-208 of this title;</section><section prefix="(v)">theories of depreciation, cost estimating, methods of capitalization, the mathematics of real estate appraisal, and other principles that are appropriate for the certificate for which the applicant applies;</section><section prefix="(vi)">basic real estate law; and</section><section prefix="(vii)">misconduct for which disciplinary proceedings may be started against a certified real estate appraiser for residential real estate or a certified real estate appraiser for general real estate.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
