<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gbo" order_by="gbo" level="1">Business Occupations and Professions</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gbo-17-525</section_number>
  <catch_line>The purpose of this section is to prohibit steering and other discriminatory real estate practices w...</catch_line>
  <order_by>525</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The purpose of this section is to prohibit steering and other discriminatory real estate practices with respect to residential housing in Baltimore City to:<section prefix="(1)">ensure fair and equal real estate housing practices in Baltimore City for all of its residents, regardless of race, color, sex, religion, or national origin;</section><section prefix="(2)">provide fair and equal real estate housing opportunities in Baltimore City for all of its residents, regardless of race, color, sex, religion, or national origin; and</section><section prefix="(3)">protect and ensure the peace, health, safety, prosperity, and general welfare of all residents of Baltimore City.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">This section applies only in regard to residential property in Baltimore City.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, each real estate broker shall maintain a current and complete registry of all residential properties that the broker lists for sale in Baltimore City.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The real estate broker shall break down the properties listed in the registry into price categories that are established by the Commission.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">If a prospective buyer requests to see the registry, the real estate broker shall allow the prospective buyer to see the part of the registry for the price category in which the prospective buyer indicates interest.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">This subsection does not require a real estate broker who is a member of a multiple listing service to disclose properties that are obtained from multiple listing.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Unless requested to do so by a prospective buyer or renter, a real estate broker, an associate real estate broker, or a real estate salesperson may not fail or refuse to show any residential property that is available for sale, rent, or sublease to a prospective buyer or renter because of:<section prefix="(i)">the race, color, sex, religion, or national origin of the prospective buyer or renter; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">the racial composition or character of the neighborhood where the property is located.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A real estate broker, an associate real estate broker, or a real estate salesperson may not fail or refuse to show all available listed residential properties that are in a certain area and within a specified price range to a prospective buyer or renter who has requested to be shown all available properties that are in the area and within the specified price range.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">If the representation is made because of the race, color, sex, religion, or national origin of the prospective buyer or renter or because of the racial composition or character of the area where the property is located, a real estate broker, an associate real estate broker, or a real estate salesperson may not represent to a prospective buyer or renter that the available residential properties, prospective sites for a residence, or listings are limited to those already shown when, in fact, there is a residential property, a prospective site for a residence, or a listing that is available and within the price range specified by the prospective buyer or renter.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">This section does not prohibit a real estate broker, an associate real estate broker, or a real estate salesperson from charging a reasonable fee for showing a residential property to a prospective buyer or renter.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The Commission shall enforce the provisions of this section and, for this purpose, may receive complaints, conduct investigations, issue subpoenas, administer oaths, and hold hearings.</section>
  </text>
</law>
