<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gbo" order_by="gbo" level="1">Business Occupations and Professions</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gbo-11-504</section_number>
  <catch_line>A pilot is eligible for payments as an inactive pilot under &#xA7; 11-505 of this subtitle if the pilot:...</catch_line>
  <order_by>504</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">A pilot is eligible for payments as an inactive pilot under &#xA7; 11-505 of this subtitle if the pilot:<section prefix="(1)"><section prefix="(i)">chooses to be placed on the list of inactive pilots maintained by the Association; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">has been, for at least 25 years:<section prefix="1.">a member in good standing of the Association; and</section><section prefix="2.">licensed by the Board to provide pilotage for vessels of unlimited draft; or</section></section></section><section prefix="(2)"><section prefix="(i)"><section prefix="1.">has been certified by two physicians chosen by the Board to be permanently incapable of providing pilotage; or</section><section prefix="2.">has had a federal or State pilot's license revoked for physical disability; and</section></section><section prefix="(ii)">before becoming permanently disabled, the pilot was:<section prefix="1.">a member in good standing of the Association; and</section><section prefix="2.">licensed by the Board to provide pilotage for vessels of any draft.</section></section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A pilot is eligible for reduced payments as an inactive pilot under &#xA7; 11-505 of this subtitle if the pilot:<section prefix="(1)">chooses to be placed on the list of inactive pilots maintained by the Association; and</section><section prefix="(2)">has been, for at least 20 years:<section prefix="(i)">a member in good standing of the Association; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">licensed by the Board to provide pilotage for vessels of unlimited draft.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Eligibility for payments as an inactive pilot shall cease if:<section prefix="(1)">a pilot who was declared permanently incapable of providing pilotage becomes capable of providing pilotage; or</section><section prefix="(2)">a pilot who had a federal or State pilot's license revoked for physical disability has the license reissued.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Time of service as a licensed docking master on or before September 30, 2004, shall be included in determining a pilot's eligibility for payment as an inactive pilot.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">A pilot who held an unlimited docking master license on October 1, 2000, is eligible for reduced payments as an inactive pilot under &#xA7; 11-505 of this subtitle if the pilot:<section prefix="(1)">chooses to be placed on the list of inactive pilots maintained by the Association; and</section><section prefix="(2)">has been, for at least 5 years:<section prefix="(i)">a member in good standing of the Association or of the Association of Maryland Docking Pilots; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">licensed by the Board to provide pilotage for vessels of unlimited draft.</section></section></section>
  </text>
</law>
