<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gbo" order_by="" level="1">Business Occupations and Professions</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gbo-9-101</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>101</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this title the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Board" means the State Board of Examiners of Landscape Architects.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Design coordination" means the review and coordination of services provided by individuals licensed or certified under Titles 3, 8, 9, 14, and 15 of this article.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">"Landscape architect" means an individual who practices landscape architecture.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"License" means, unless the context requires otherwise, a license issued by the Board to practice landscape architecture.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">"License fee" means, as applicable, the fee paid in connection with the issuance and renewal of a license or the issuance of a reciprocal license.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">"Licensed landscape architect" means a landscape architect who is licensed by the Board to practice landscape architecture.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">"Permit" means a permit issued by the Board to allow a partnership or corporation to operate a business through which an individual may practice landscape architecture.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">"Permit fee" means, as applicable, the fee paid in connection with the issuance and renewal of a permit.</section>
    <section prefix="(j)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Practice landscape architecture" means:<section prefix="(i)">to provide any service or creative work in the analysis or design of land and natural resources that requires training and experience in the application of the biological, physical, mathematical, and social sciences; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">to perform design coordination of a project or portion of a project provided that the licensed landscape architect holds a current license issued by the Board and has adequate education and experience in, and understanding of, the project or portion of the project being coordinated.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Practice landscape architecture" includes:<section prefix="(i)">consultation, research, analysis, assessment, selection, and allocation of land and natural resources;</section><section prefix="(ii)">development of graphic, written, digital, and other appropriate criteria to govern the planning and design of land development and construction programs, including:<section prefix="1.">preparation, review, and analysis of master plans, site plans, and land development plans;</section><section prefix="2.">reconnaissance, planning, design, and preparation of construction documents;</section><section prefix="3.">construction, observation, administration, and project management;</section><section prefix="4.">preservation, restoration, conservation, reclamation, rehabilitation, and management of land and natural resources;</section><section prefix="5.">preparation of feasibility and site selection studies, environmental studies, and cost estimate reports; and</section><section prefix="6.">design and analysis of grading and drainage, irrigation, erosion and sediment control systems, and pedestrian and vehicular circulation systems; and</section></section><section prefix="(iii)">in conjunction with site plan preparation, the performance of the following:<section prefix="1.">determining a grade;</section><section prefix="2.">determining drainage; and</section><section prefix="3.">preparing and designing stormwater drainage systems provided that the preparation and design:</section></section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(k)">"Responsible charge" means direct control and personal supervision of landscape architecture services that requires initiative, professional skill, and independent judgment.</section>
  </text>
</law>
