<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gbo" order_by="" level="1">Business Occupations and Professions</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gbo-6-311</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>311</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The State Board shall place a State licensee on inactive status and issue an inactive status certificate to the State licensee, if the State licensee:<section prefix="(1)">submits to the State Board an application for inactive status on the form that the State Board provides;</section><section prefix="(2)">pays to the State Board any applicable inactive status application fee;</section><section prefix="(3)">except for the insurance requirements of &#xA7; 6-604 of this title, qualifies for an active State license; and</section><section prefix="(4)">returns the State license to the State Board.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The State Board shall place an applicant for an initial State license on inactive status and issue an inactive status certificate to the applicant, if the applicant:<section prefix="(1)">submits to the State Board an application for inactive status on the form that the State Board provides;</section><section prefix="(2)">pays to the State Board an inactive status application fee of an amount equal to the State license fee under &#xA7; 6-309 of this subtitle; and</section><section prefix="(3)">except for the insurance requirements of &#xA7; 6-604 of this title, qualifies for an active State license.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A licensee on inactive status may not use a State license to obtain a local license for providing electrical services as a master electrician in a local jurisdiction of the State.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">In a county that requires a State license, a licensee on inactive status may not provide electrical services as a master electrician.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Unless the individual applies for another 2-year term as provided in this subsection, an individual on inactive status loses that status on the first June 30 that comes:<section prefix="(i)">after the inactive status registration certificate is issued to the licensee; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">in an odd-numbered year.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">At least 1 month before the inactive status of an individual expires, the State Board shall mail to the individual, at the last known address of the individual:<section prefix="(i)">a renewal application form; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">a notice that states:<section prefix="1.">the date on which the inactive status expires;</section><section prefix="2.">the date by which the State Board must receive the renewal application for the renewal to be issued and mailed before the inactive status expires; and</section><section prefix="3.">the amount of the renewal fee.</section></section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Before the inactive status expires, an individual on inactive status periodically may renew it for an additional 2-year term, if the individual:<section prefix="(i)">otherwise is entitled to be placed on inactive status;</section><section prefix="(ii)">except for an electrical inspector, pays to the State Board a renewal fee of $50; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">submits to the State Board a renewal application on the form that the Board provides.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">After an inactive status expires, the former licensee may reapply for inactive status only if the former licensee:<section prefix="(i)">otherwise is entitled to be placed on inactive status;</section><section prefix="(ii)">pays to the Board a reapplication fee of $100; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">reapplies to the Board for inactive status within 2 years after initial expiration of inactive status on a form that the Board provides.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(5)">The State Board shall renew the inactive status of each individual or grant the reapplication for inactive status of each former licensee who meets the requirements of this subsection.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">If a former licensee on inactive status who has failed to renew the inactive status within 2 years of its expiration reapplies for that status, the State Board shall require the former licensee to comply with the requirements for obtaining a State license under &#xA7;&#xA7; 6-304, 6-307, and 6-503 of this title as well as the requirements for inactive status under this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The State Board shall reactivate the State license of an individual who is on inactive status, if the individual:<section prefix="(1)">meets the renewal requirements that are in effect when the individual requests the reactivation of the State license;</section><section prefix="(2)">submits to the State Board an application for reactivation on the form that the State Board provides; and</section><section prefix="(3)">pays to the State Board a reactivation fee of $50.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
