<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gbo" order_by="" level="1">Business Occupations and Professions</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gbo-14-305</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>305</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In addition to the other qualifications for a license set forth in this subtitle, an applicant shall qualify under this section by meeting the educational and experience requirements set forth in subsection (b), (c), or (d) of this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">An applicant qualifies under this section if the applicant:<section prefix="(i)">has been graduated from a college or university on completion of at least a 4-year curriculum in engineering, or its equivalent, that the Board approves;</section><section prefix="(ii)">subject to paragraph (2) of this subsection, has at least 4 years of work experience in engineering that is satisfactory to the Board and that indicates to the Board that the applicant may be competent to practice engineering;</section><section prefix="(iii)">has passed the examination in the fundamentals of engineering given by the Board under this subtitle; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">after passing the examination in fundamentals, has passed the examination in the principles and practice of engineering given by the Board under this subtitle.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If an applicant has completed graduate study in engineering that is satisfactory to the Board, it may allow the applicant up to a 1-year credit toward the experience requirement of paragraph (1)(ii) of this subsection.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">An applicant qualifies under this section if the applicant:<section prefix="(1)">has been graduated from a college or university on completion of at least a 4-year curriculum in engineering, or its equivalent, that the Board has not approved;</section><section prefix="(2)">has at least 8 years of work experience in engineering that is satisfactory to the Board and that indicates to the Board that the applicant may be competent to practice engineering;</section><section prefix="(3)">has passed the examination in the fundamentals of engineering given by the Board under this subtitle; and</section><section prefix="(4)">after passing the examination in fundamentals, has passed the examination in the principles and practice of engineering given by the Board under this subtitle.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">An applicant qualifies under this section if the applicant:<section prefix="(i)">subject to paragraph (2) of this subsection, has at least 12 years of work experience in engineering that is satisfactory to the Board, in at least 5 years of which the applicant has been in responsible charge, if the collective experience indicates to the Board that the applicant may be competent to practice engineering; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">has passed the examination in the principles and practice of engineering given by the Board under this subtitle.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If an applicant has completed 1 or more years of a college or university curriculum in engineering that the Board approves, it may allow, for each of those years, a 1-year credit towards the experience requirement of paragraph (1)(i) of this subsection.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">If an applicant has completed 1 or more years of a college or university curriculum in engineering that has not been approved by the Board, the Board may allow, for each of those years, a credit of up to 6 months towards the experience requirement under paragraph (1)(i) of this subsection.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">If an applicant has taught undergraduate or graduate courses in the practice of engineering or has directed engineering research and projects in the applicant's field in a college or university offering an engineering curriculum that is approved by the Board, the Board may count the teaching experience as work experience for purposes of the experience requirements under any subsection of this section.</section>
  </text>
</law>
