<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gbo" order_by="" level="1">Business Occupations and Professions</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gbo-17-527.2</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>527.2</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Advertise" means the use of any oral, written, or visual advertisement by a licensed real estate salesperson, licensed real estate broker, licensed associate real estate broker, or other person on behalf of a licensed real estate salesperson, licensed real estate broker, or licensed associate real estate broker.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">"Advertisement" means, unless the context requires otherwise, any oral, written, or printed media advertisement.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">"Advertisement" includes any correspondence, mailing, newsletter, brochure, business card, for sale or for lease sign and sign rider, promotional item, automobile signage, telephone directory listing, television announcement, radio announcement, telephone solicitation, and World Wide Web and Internet voice-overs.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(4)">
        <section prefix="(i)">"Designated name" means the individual name of a licensed real estate salesperson, licensed real estate broker, or licensed associate real estate broker other than the licensed real estate salesperson's, licensed real estate broker's, or licensed associate real estate broker's full legal name.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">"Designated name" includes a first name, nickname, or last name.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A licensed real estate salesperson, licensed real estate broker, or licensed associate real estate broker may not advertise unless:<section prefix="(1)">the name or designated name of the licensed real estate salesperson, licensed real estate broker, or licensed associate real estate broker, as the name or designated name appears on the license certificate and pocket card issued by the Commission, is meaningfully and conspicuously included in the advertisement; and</section><section prefix="(2)">the name of the business with which the licensed real estate salesperson, licensed real estate broker, or licensed associate real estate broker is affiliated:<section prefix="(i)">is meaningfully and conspicuously included in the advertisement; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">is the full name of the business and not a logo used by the business.</section></section></section>
  </text>
</law>
