<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gbo" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="19-404.1" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gbo-19-404.1</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">By regulation, the Secretary shall stagger the terms of the certifications.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Unless a certification is renewed for a 3-year term as provided in this section, the certification expires on the date the Secretary sets.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">At least 90 days before a certification expires, the applicant shall mail to the Secretary:<section prefix="(1)">a renewal application form;</section><section prefix="(2)">the amount of the renewal fee; and</section><section prefix="(3)">the amount of any late fee, as determined by the Secretary.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">An individual periodically may renew the certification for an additional 3-year term, if the individual:<section prefix="(1)">otherwise is entitled to be certified;</section><section prefix="(2)">pays to the Secretary:<section prefix="(i)">a renewal fee of $10;</section><section prefix="(ii)">payment for the cost of a fingerprint card record check by the Federal Bureau of Investigation; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">any late fee required under this subtitle; and</section></section><section prefix="(3)">submits to the Secretary a renewal application on the form that the Secretary provides.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Subject to paragraph (2) of this subsection, if a complete application for renewal of certification as required under this subtitle is not received by the Secretary on or before the first business day of the next calendar month immediately following the renewal date, the Secretary shall assess a late fee of $5 per day until the application is received by the Secretary.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The Secretary may not charge a late fee under paragraph (1) of this subsection if the applicant did not make timely renewal because of incapacity, hospitalization, being called to active military duty, or other hardship.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The total amount of late fees assessed against an applicant under this subsection may not exceed $150.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Secretary may not certify any applicant under this subtitle if the applicant has outstanding late fee obligations.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Secretary shall renew the certification of each individual who meets the requirements of this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Within 5 days after the Secretary refuses to renew the certification of an individual as a security guard, the Secretary shall send written notice of the refusal to the individual who submitted the renewal application.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
