<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gbo" order_by="" level="1">Business Occupations and Professions</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gbo-14-101</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>101</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this title the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Board" means the State Board for Professional Engineers.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Design coordination" means the review and coordination of services provided by individuals licensed or certified under Titles 3, 8, 9, 14, and 15 of this article.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">"License" means, unless the context requires otherwise, a license issued by the Board to practice engineering.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"License fee" means, as applicable, the fee paid in connection with the issuance and renewal of a license and the issuance of a reciprocal license.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Practice engineering" means to provide any service or creative work the performance of which requires education, training, and experience in the application of:<section prefix="(i)">special knowledge of the mathematical, physical, and engineering sciences; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">the principles and methods of engineering analysis and design.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">In regard to a building or other structure, machine, equipment, process, works, system, project, or public or private utility, "practice engineering" includes:<section prefix="(i)">consultation;</section><section prefix="(ii)">design;</section><section prefix="(iii)">evaluation;</section><section prefix="(iv)">inspection of construction to ensure compliance with specifications and drawings;</section><section prefix="(v)">investigation;</section><section prefix="(vi)">planning; and</section><section prefix="(vii)">design coordination.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Practice engineering" does not include the exclusive and sole performance of nontechnical management activities.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">"Professional engineer" means, unless the context requires otherwise, an engineer who is licensed by the Board to practice engineering.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Responsible charge" means direct control and personal supervision of engineering that requires initiative, professional skill, and independent judgment.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Responsible charge" includes responsible engineering teaching.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
