<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gbo" order_by="" level="1">Business Occupations and Professions</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gbo-5-520</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>520</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Board may appoint inspectors to conduct inspections.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Subject to the State budget, each inspector is entitled to:<section prefix="(i)">reasonable compensation set by the Board for each day on which the inspector is engaged in the duties of the appointment; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">reimbursement for expenses under the Standard State Travel Regulations.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Board shall inspect beauty salons.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Board shall inspect the facilities of applicants for beauty salon permits before the beauty salon:<section prefix="(i)">initially opens for business;</section><section prefix="(ii)">opens for business at a new location; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">continues business under a new owner.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A beauty salon that remodels and reopens with the same owner is not subject to the inspection requirement of this subsection.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Board or an inspector may enter and inspect a cosmetology school approved by the State Board of Education or the Maryland Higher Education Commission at any time during business hours to determine the sanitary condition of the cosmetology school.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If, during an inspection of a cosmetology school, an inspector finds an unsanitary condition, the inspector promptly shall report the condition to the Board.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A beauty salon shall allow an inspector, on presentation of credentials, to enter and inspect the facility at any time during business hours.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">During inspection of a beauty salon, the owner, lessee, or manager of the beauty salon shall accompany the inspector.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">An inspector shall make an inspection report after an inspection and give a copy to the individual who accompanied the inspector during the inspection.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The individual shall sign the inspection report for the beauty salon or cosmetology school to acknowledge receipt of a copy of the report.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
