<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gbo" order_by="" level="1">Business Occupations and Professions</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gbo-6.5-101</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>101</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this title the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Board" means the State Board of Stationary Engineers.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Boiler" means:<section prefix="(1)">a closed vessel in which water is heated, steam is generated, steam is superheated, or a combination of these functions is accomplished, under pressure or vacuum for use externally to the vessel by the direct application of heat from the combustion of fuels or from electricity or nuclear energy; or</section><section prefix="(2)">a fired unit for heating or vaporizing liquids other than water if the unit is separate from a processing system and is complete within itself.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">"Heating boiler" means:<section prefix="(1)">a steam boiler that operates at pressures not exceeding 15 psig; or</section><section prefix="(2)">a hot water boiler that operates at pressures not exceeding 160 psig or temperatures not exceeding 250 degrees Fahrenheit.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"License" means, unless the context requires otherwise, a license issued by the Board to perform the functions of a stationary engineer.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"License" includes, unless the context requires otherwise:<section prefix="(i)">a Grade 5 license;</section><section prefix="(ii)">a Grade 4 license;</section><section prefix="(iii)">a Grade 3 license;</section><section prefix="(iv)">a Grade 2 license; and</section><section prefix="(v)">a Grade 1 license.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Provide stationary engineer services" means to oversee the operation of a power plant, plant of machinery, or boiler, each generating pressure of more than 15 psi and operating at 30 or more horsepower.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Provide stationary engineer services" does not include overseeing the operation of a heating boiler.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">"Stationary engineer" means an individual who is licensed by the Board to provide stationary engineer services in accordance with the license grades described in &#xA7; 6.5-302 of this title.</section>
  </text>
</law>
