<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gbo" order_by="gbo" level="1">Business Occupations and Professions</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gbo-17-321</section_number>
  <catch_line>Subject to the provisions of this section, a licensed real estate broker may provide real estate bro...</catch_line>
  <order_by>321</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Subject to the provisions of this section, a licensed real estate broker may provide real estate brokerage services through a corporation, limited liability company, or partnership.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">To qualify to provide real estate brokerage services through a corporation, limited liability company, or partnership, the licensed real estate broker:<section prefix="(1)">shall be employed by or have another contractual relationship with the corporation, limited liability company, or partnership;</section><section prefix="(2)">shall have been designated by the corporation, limited liability company, or partnership as the broker of the firm, to be individually responsible for the provision of real estate brokerage services through the corporation, limited liability company, or partnership; and</section><section prefix="(3)">shall submit notice to the Commission as provided in subsection (c) of this section.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Before a licensed real estate broker may provide real estate brokerage services through a corporation, limited liability company, or partnership, the broker shall submit to the Commission a notice that states the broker's intent to provide services through a corporation or partnership. The notice shall include:<section prefix="(i)">the name of the real estate broker submitting the notice;</section><section prefix="(ii)">a statement that the named individual has been designated as the broker of the firm;</section><section prefix="(iii)">the address of the firm's principal place of business and of each proposed branch office;</section><section prefix="(iv)">any trade or fictitious name that the firm intends to use while conducting the business of the firm;</section><section prefix="(v)">a list of all the licensed associate real estate brokers and licensed real estate salespersons who will be affiliated with the broker of the firm; and</section><section prefix="(vi)">any other information that the Commission may require by regulation.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Commission may set by regulation procedures for maintaining current information about any corporation, limited liability company, or partnership through which real estate brokerage services are provided.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">An individual may provide real estate brokerage services through a firm only if:<section prefix="(i)">the individual is the licensed real estate broker who has been designated as the broker of the firm; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">the individual:<section prefix="1.">is licensed as an associate real estate broker or real estate salesperson to provide real estate brokerage services on behalf of the broker of the firm; and</section><section prefix="2.">continues to be affiliated with the broker of the firm.</section></section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">This subsection applies regardless of whether the individual is associated with the firm as a partner, officer, member, or shareholder or in any other capacity.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">An individual who serves as a broker of the firm under this section shall be responsible for the provision of real estate brokerage services through the firm and is subject to all of the provisions of this title regarding those services.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A corporation, limited liability company, or partnership that provides real estate brokerage services under this section is not, by its compliance with this section, relieved of any responsibility that the corporation, limited liability company, or partnership may have for an act or omission of its officer, partner, member, employee, or agent.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">An individual who provides real estate brokerage services through a corporation, limited liability company, or partnership is not, by reason of the individual's employment or other relationship with the corporation, limited liability company, or partnership, relieved of any individual responsibility that the individual may have regarding those services.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
