<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gbo" order_by="gbo" level="1">Business Occupations and Professions</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gbo-17-608</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this subsection, "handicap" and "familial status" each have the meanings indicated in the federal...</catch_line>
  <order_by>608</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this subsection, "handicap" and "familial status" each have the meanings indicated in the federal Fair Housing Act.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Whether or not acting for monetary gain, a person may not knowingly induce or attempt to induce another person to sell or rent a dwelling or otherwise transfer real estate or knowingly discourage or attempt to discourage another person from buying real estate by:<section prefix="(i)">making representations about the entry or prospective entry into a neighborhood of individuals of a particular race, color, sex, religion, handicap, familial status, or national origin;</section><section prefix="(ii)">making representations about the existing or potential proximity of real property owned or used by individuals of a particular race, color, sex, religion, handicap, familial status, or national origin; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">representing that the existing or potential proximity of real property owned or used by individuals of a particular race, color, sex, religion, handicap, familial status, or national origin will or may result in:<section prefix="1.">the lowering of property values;</section><section prefix="2.">a change in the racial, religious, or ethnic character of the block, neighborhood, or area;</section><section prefix="3.">an increase in criminal or antisocial behavior in the area; or</section><section prefix="4.">a decline in the quality of schools serving the area.</section></section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A person may not provide financial assistance by loan, gift, or otherwise to another person if the person has actual knowledge that the financial assistance will be used in a transaction that results from a violation of subsection (a) of this section.</section>
  </text>
</law>
