<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gbo" order_by="gbo" level="1">Business Occupations and Professions</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gbo-3-404</section_number>
  <catch_line>To qualify for a permit, a corporation, limited liability company, or partnership shall meet the req...</catch_line>
  <order_by>404</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">To qualify for a permit, a corporation, limited liability company, or partnership shall meet the requirements of this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">At least two-thirds of the directors of a corporation shall be licensed in this or another state to practice architecture, engineering, or landscape architecture.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">At least two-thirds of the partners of a partnership shall be licensed in this or another state to practice architecture, engineering, or landscape architecture.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">If the partnership is a limited partnership, at least two-thirds of the general partners of the limited partnership shall be licensed in this or another state to practice architecture, engineering, or landscape architecture.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">At least two-thirds of the members of a limited liability company shall be licensed in this or another state to practice architecture, engineering, or landscape architecture.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A corporation, limited liability company, or partnership shall have appointed at least 1 responsible member of the corporation, limited liability company, or partnership.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A responsible member shall be in charge of architecture practiced through the corporation, limited liability company, or partnership.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Each responsible member shall be:<section prefix="(i)">a director of a corporation, a member of a limited liability company, or a partner of a partnership; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">a licensed architect.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
