<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gbo" order_by="gbo" level="1">Business Occupations and Professions</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gbo-2-102</section_number>
  <catch_line>If the person does not engage in any activity expressly included in the definition of practice certi...</catch_line>
  <order_by>102</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">If the person does not engage in any activity expressly included in the definition of practice certified public accountancy, this title does not prohibit:<section prefix="(1)">an individual from serving as an employee of or assistant to a licensee or permit holder;</section><section prefix="(2)">a public official or public employee from performing the duties of the position of that individual; or</section><section prefix="(3)">a person from providing or offering to the public bookkeeping and accounting services, including:<section prefix="(i)">development or installation of a bookkeeping system;</section><section prefix="(ii)">recordation or presentation of financial information;</section><section prefix="(iii)">preparation of:<section prefix="1.">a financial statement;</section><section prefix="2.">a compilation of a financial statement that:</section><section prefix="3.">a report;</section><section prefix="4.">a schedule; or</section><section prefix="5.">an exhibit; or</section></section><section prefix="(iv)">any similar activity.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">This title does not prohibit a licensee or permit holder from:<section prefix="(1)">employing a certified public accountant licensed by another state or a foreign country; or</section><section prefix="(2)">listing that individual as a certified public accountant, if the individual qualifies for a practice privilege under &#xA7; 2-321 of this title.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Board shall adopt regulations that specify the language of the disclosure statement relating to exemption from peer review that is required to be included in a compilation of a financial statement prepared under subsection (a)(3)(iii)2 of this section.</section>
  </text>
</law>
