<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gbo" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="18-101" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gbo-18-101</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this title the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Circumventional information" means information, including pass codes, that allows an individual to alter the operation of a security system.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Circumventional information" does not include generic user or installation manuals.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Firm" means a partnership or corporation.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">"Firm member" means a partner of a partnership or an officer or director of a corporation.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"License" means a license issued by the Secretary or the Secretary's designee to engage in the business of providing security systems services for compensation.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">"Providing security systems services" means providing, on the premises of a person's residential or commercial property, the service of:<section prefix="(1)">surveying the property for purposes of installing a security system;</section><section prefix="(2)">physically installing, maintaining, or repairing a security system for the customer; or</section><section prefix="(3)">responding to a distress call or an alarm sounding from a security system.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(g)">"Representative member" means a firm member who is appointed under this title to act on behalf of the firm.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">"Secretary" means the Secretary of State Police or the Secretary's designee.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">"Security systems agency" means an individual or a firm that conducts a business that provides security systems services.</section>
    <section prefix="(j)">"Security systems technician" means a person who personally provides security systems services.</section>
  </text>
</law>
