<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gbo" order_by="" level="1">Business Occupations and Professions</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gbo-13-605</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>605</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">A nonresident applicant for a license shall submit to the Secretary of State a consent, as provided under this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The consent required under this section shall:<section prefix="(1)">specify that service of process on the Secretary of State shall bind the applicant in any action, suit, or proceeding brought against the applicant;</section><section prefix="(2)">specify that an action, suit, or proceeding may be brought against the applicant in any county where:<section prefix="(i)">the cause of action arose; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">the plaintiff resides; and</section></section><section prefix="(3)">be signed by the representative member of the applicant.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">In addition to submitting a consent, a nonresident applicant shall submit to the Secretary of State a certified copy of a resolution adopted by the firm that confirms that the firm members, board of directors, or other managing board of the firm authorized the representative member to execute and submit the consent on behalf of the firm.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">An applicant who is required under this section to submit a consent or a consent and authorization to the Secretary of State shall submit copies of the signed documents to the Secretary.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The Secretary may not issue a license to a nonresident applicant, unless the nonresident applicant complies with the requirements of subsections (a) through (d) of this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Subject to paragraph (2) of this subsection, service of process on the Secretary of State binds a person who has submitted a consent to the Secretary of State, as required under this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If service of process is made on the Secretary of State as authorized under this section, the person initiating the action, suit, or proceeding immediately shall send a copy, by certified mail, return receipt requested, to the principal office in the State of the person against whom the action, suit, or proceeding is directed.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">As to any person who submits a consent as required under this section, any action, suit, or proceeding may be brought in any county where:<section prefix="(i)">the cause of action arose; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">the plaintiff resides.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
