<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gbo" order_by="gbo" level="1">Business Occupations and Professions</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gbo-11-502</section_number>
  <catch_line>The Public Service Commission shall establish pilotage fees in accordance with &#xA7; 4-303 of the Publi...</catch_line>
  <order_by>502</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Public Service Commission shall establish pilotage fees in accordance with &#xA7; 4-303 of the Public Utilities Article.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Regardless of whether the employment is required under &#xA7; 11-501(a) of this subtitle or voluntary under &#xA7; 11-501(b) of this subtitle, a vessel that employs a licensed pilot to provide pilotage shall pay the licensed pilot the full pilotage fee.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Regardless of whether the vessel uses the services of the pilot for the entire pilotage, a vessel that employs a licensed pilot to provide pilotage shall pay the licensed pilot the full pilotage fee.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Notwithstanding any contract between a licensed pilot who has provided pilotage for a vessel and the master, owner, charterer, or agent of the vessel or any other party, the vessel, its tackle, apparel, and furniture, and the master, owner, charterer, and agent of the vessel shall be jointly and severally liable for payment of the pilotage fee to the licensed pilot.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A licensed pilot who has provided pilotage for a vessel shall have a lien for the amount of the pilotage fee due, enforceable in a court of competent jurisdiction, on the vessel and its tackle, apparel, and furniture.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">If a vessel fails to employ a licensed pilot to provide pilotage as required under &#xA7; 11-501(a) of this subtitle, the vessel and its master, owner, charterer, and agent shall be jointly and severally liable for payment of the full pilotage fee as if a licensed pilot had been employed.</section>
  </text>
</law>
