<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gbo" order_by="gbo" level="1">Business Occupations and Professions</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gbo-3-103</section_number>
  <catch_line>Except as otherwise provided in this section, all architectural documents prepared in connection wit...</catch_line>
  <order_by>103</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Except as otherwise provided in this section, all architectural documents prepared in connection with the addition, alteration, construction, or design of a building, an integral part of a building, or a group of buildings which are intended for public use or residential use shall be signed, sealed, and dated by a licensed architect in accordance with &#xA7; 3-501 of this title.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A licensed architect may perform design coordination for a project or portion of a project provided that the licensed architect:<section prefix="(1)">holds a current license issued by the Board; and</section><section prefix="(2)">has adequate experience in, and understanding of, achieving the purpose of the project or portion of the project being coordinated.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">This title does not limit the right of:<section prefix="(1)">a construction contractor to administer construction contracts;</section><section prefix="(2)">a developer, builder, or contractor to provide design services related to the developer's, builder's, or contractor's own construction of new or existing single-family or two-family dwellings, or structures ancillary to them, or farm buildings;</section><section prefix="(3)">a certified interior designer or other individual to provide interior design services as that term is defined in Title 8 of this article; or</section><section prefix="(4)">an individual to prepare plans, drawings, and other documents in connection with the addition, alteration, construction, design, or repair of a single-family dwelling and appurtenances that are for the personal use of that individual or a member of the immediate family of that individual.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A person may not be required to employ a licensed architect in connection with the alteration or repair of an existing building or structure in a municipal corporation if the alteration or repair:<section prefix="(i)">does not exceed $5,000 in estimated costs, including labor and materials;</section><section prefix="(ii)">is limited to:<section prefix="1.">interior alterations or repairs;</section><section prefix="2.">storefronts or facades;</section><section prefix="3.">fixtures, cabinetwork or furniture; or</section><section prefix="4.">exterior stairways, landings, decks, and ramps; and</section></section><section prefix="(iii)">does not adversely affect the structural system of the building, including foundations, footings, walls, floors, roofs, bearing partitions, beams, columns, joists, or the mechanical, electrical, or plumbing systems.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Any work performed under this subsection shall be in compliance with the Americans with Disabilities Act and the Maryland Building Performance Standards set forth in Title 12, Subtitle 5 of the Public Safety Article.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The exclusion provided for in this subsection shall be used only once per building or structure in a 12-month period.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">A building permit issued under this subsection:<section prefix="(i)">shall contain an affidavit signed by the person who has submitted the permit stating that the repair or alteration is in compliance with this subsection; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">may not be amended or revised in any way to cause the alteration or repair to exceed $5,000 in total costs, including labor and materials.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(5)">Any building permit issued under this subsection that contains technical submissions that fail to conform to the requirements of this subsection shall be invalid.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">Notwithstanding the provisions of subsection (d) of this section, a code official may require that architectural documents for alterations or repairs of existing buildings or structures be signed and sealed by a licensed architect if the code official determines that the signature and seal of a licensed architect is necessary to provide conformity with the Maryland Building Performance Standards or to otherwise provide for the health and safety of the public.</section>
  </text>
</law>
