<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gbo" order_by="" level="1">Business Occupations and Professions</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gbo-2-308</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>308</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Subject to the provisions of this section, the Board may waive any examination requirement of this subtitle for:<section prefix="(1)">a certified public accountant licensed by another state; or</section><section prefix="(2)">the holder of a license, certificate, or degree that is issued by another country and is recognized as authority for the holder to practice public accountancy in that country in a manner comparable to practicing certified public accountancy in this State.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Board may grant a waiver under this section only if the applicant:<section prefix="(1)">is of good character and reputation;</section><section prefix="(2)">is at least 18 years of age;</section><section prefix="(3)">pays to the Board:<section prefix="(i)">a nonrefundable application fee set by the Board; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">a license fee set by the Board; and</section></section><section prefix="(4)">provides adequate evidence that the applicant has met educational, examination, and experience requirements that are:<section prefix="(i)">substantially equivalent to those required by the laws of this State;</section><section prefix="(ii)">substantially equivalent to those required by the laws of the State at the time the applicant was licensed in another state; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">after passing the Uniform Certified Public Accountancy Examination, has obtained 4 years of practical work experience, as defined in &#xA7; 2-302(f) of this subtitle, within the last 10 years immediately preceding submission of the application.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">For the purposes of this subtitle, "substantial equivalency" means a determination made by the Board or its designee that:<section prefix="(i)">the education, examination, and experience requirements contained in the laws or administrative rules of another jurisdiction are comparable to, or exceed, the education, examination, and experience requirements contained in the Uniform Accountancy Act; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">an individual's education, examination, and experience are comparable to or exceed the education, examination, and experience requirements contained in the Uniform Accountancy Act.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">In determining substantial equivalency, the Board shall take into account an individual's qualifications without regard to the sequence in which the education, examination, or experience requirements are met.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
