<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gbo" order_by="gbo" level="1">Business Occupations and Professions</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gbo-2-4A-04</section_number>
  <catch_line>A system review is required for a licensee or permit holder that performs any of the following servi...</catch_line>
  <order_by>04</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">A system review is required for a licensee or permit holder that performs any of the following services:<section prefix="(1)">engagements governed by the Statements on Auditing Standards of the American Institute of Certified Public Accountants; or</section><section prefix="(2)">engagements governed by the government auditing standards issued by the U.S. Government Accountability Office;</section><section prefix="(3)">examinations of prospective financial information under:<section prefix="(i)">the Statements on Standards for Attestation Engagements of the American Institute of Certified Public Accountants; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">the government auditing standards issued by the U.S. Government Accountability Office; or</section></section><section prefix="(4)">audits of issuers not registered with the U.S. Securities and Exchange Commission that are performed under standards of the Public Company Accounting Oversight Board.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">An engagement review is required for a licensee or permit holder not required to have a system review that performs any of the following services:<section prefix="(1)">review of historical financial statements in accordance with the Statements on Standards for Accounting and Review Services of the American Institute of Certified Public Accountants;</section><section prefix="(2)">compilation of historical financial statements with disclosures performed under the Statements on Standards for Accounting and Review Services of the American Institute of Certified Public Accountants;</section><section prefix="(3)">compilation of historical financial statements that omit substantially all disclosures performed under the Statements on Standards for Accounting and Review Services of the American Institute of Certified Public Accountants; or</section><section prefix="(4)">engagements performed under the Statements on Standards for Attestation Engagements of the American Institute of Certified Public Accountants other than the examination of prospective financial statements.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
