<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gbo" order_by="" level="1">Business Occupations and Professions</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gbo-12-208</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>208</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Board may conduct investigations into and, subject to the State budget, may employ an investigative staff to investigate any complaint that alleges facts that constitute:<section prefix="(1)">a ground for disciplinary action under &#xA7; 12-312 of this title; or</section><section prefix="(2)">a violation of this title.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">On receipt of the results of an investigation made under this section, the Board promptly shall take the action that is appropriate under this title to ensure compliance with this title.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If a complaint is made to the Board from a county, municipal corporation, or unit of the State government, the Board reasonably and promptly shall give the county, municipal corporation, or unit notice of the action taken.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If the Board concludes that conduct alleged to be a violation of this title may result in irreparable harm to any person, the Board may sue to enforce any provision of this title by ex parte, interlocutory, or final injunction.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">In seeking an injunction under this subsection, the Board need not:<section prefix="(i)">post bond, if the injunction is sought against a person who does not hold a license issued under this title; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">allege or prove that an adequate remedy at law does not exist.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Board shall bring suit under this subsection in the circuit court for the county where:<section prefix="(i)">the violation allegedly is occurring;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the principal place of business of the alleged violator is located; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">the alleged violator resides.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
