<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gbo" order_by="" level="1">Business Occupations and Professions</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gbo-18-3A-03</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>03</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">An applicant for registration shall:<section prefix="(1)">submit to the Secretary an application on the form that the Secretary provides;</section><section prefix="(2)">submit the documents required by this section; and</section><section prefix="(3)">pay to the Secretary:<section prefix="(i)">an application fee that is the higher of $15 or an amount the Secretary determines based on actual processing costs; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">the cost of any background checks.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The application form provided by the Secretary shall contain a statement advising the applicant that willfully making a false statement on an application is a misdemeanor, subject to a fine or imprisonment or both, as provided under &#xA7; 18-504 of this title.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">An applicant for registration shall submit with the application a set of legible fingerprints of the applicant on forms approved by the Criminal Justice Information System Central Repository and the Director of the Federal Bureau of Investigation.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Secretary may waive the requirements of this section and register an applicant who:<section prefix="(1)">provides adequate evidence that the applicant:<section prefix="(i)">is licensed in another state to engage in the business of providing security systems services or registered in another state as a security systems technician or other individual who has access to circumventional information; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">became licensed or registered in the other state:<section prefix="1.">after meeting qualifications that are at least equivalent to those required in this State; and</section><section prefix="2.">after submitting to a State and national criminal records check; and</section></section></section><section prefix="(2)">pays to the Secretary a processing fee that is the higher of $15 or an amount the Secretary determines based on actual processing costs.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">A minor in an apprenticeship program approved by the Department of Labor, Licensing, and Regulation or a cooperative education program established under &#xA7; 18-3A-02 of this subtitle is not required to meet the criminal background check and fingerprint requirements of this section.</section>
  </text>
</law>
