<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gbo" order_by="gbo" level="1">Business Occupations and Professions</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gbo-15-314</section_number>
  <catch_line>Unless a license is renewed for a 2-year term as provided in this section, the license expires on th...</catch_line>
  <order_by>314</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Unless a license is renewed for a 2-year term as provided in this section, the license expires on the first June 30 that comes:<section prefix="(1)">after the effective date of the license; and</section><section prefix="(2)">in an odd-numbered year.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">At least 1 month before a license expires, the Board shall mail to the licensee, at the last known address of the licensee:<section prefix="(i)">a renewal application form; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">a notice that states:<section prefix="1.">the date on which the current license expires;</section><section prefix="2.">the date by which the Board must receive the renewal application for the renewal to be issued and mailed before the license expires; and</section><section prefix="3.">the amount of the license fee.</section></section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The failure of a licensee to receive the notice for which this subsection provides does not prevent the license from expiring as specified under subsection (a) of this section.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Before a license expires, the licensee periodically may renew it for an additional 2-year term, if the licensee:<section prefix="(1)">otherwise is entitled to be licensed;</section><section prefix="(2)">pays to the Board a license fee set by the Board; and</section><section prefix="(3)">submits to the Board a renewal application on the form that the Board provides.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Board shall renew the license of and issue a renewal certificate to each licensee who meets the requirements of this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Board shall include on each renewal certificate that the Board issues:<section prefix="(i)">the date on which the current license expires; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">the signatures of the chairman and secretary of the Board, under seal of the Board.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The Secretary may determine that licenses issued under this subtitle shall expire on a staggered basis.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The Board shall adopt regulations to require a demonstration of continuing professional competency for a licensee as a condition of renewal of a license under this section in accordance with the following:<section prefix="(1)">a continuing professional competency requirement does not apply to the first renewal of a license;</section><section prefix="(2)">if a license expires on or before September 30, 2002, a professional land surveyor or licensed property line surveyor is not required to fulfill the continuing professional competency requirement;</section><section prefix="(3)">if a license expires between October 1, 2002 and September 30, 2003, a professional land surveyor or licensed property line surveyor is required to fulfill 50 percent of the continuing professional competency requirement as provided in the regulations adopted by the Board under this subsection; and</section><section prefix="(4)">if a license expires on or after October 1, 2003, a professional land surveyor or licensed property line surveyor is required to fulfill the full continuing professional competency requirement as provided in the regulations adopted by the Board under this subsection.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
