<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gbo" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="12-301" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gbo-12-301</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as otherwise provided in this title, an individual shall be licensed by the Board to provide plumbing services before the individual may provide plumbing services in the State.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Except as otherwise provided in this title, an individual shall be licensed by the Board to provide or to assist in providing plumbing services before the individual may assist in providing plumbing services in the State.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Except as otherwise provided in this title, an individual shall be licensed by the Board to provide plumbing services or certified by the Board to provide propane gas services before the individual may provide propane gas services in the State.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">Except as otherwise provided in this title, an individual shall be licensed by the Board to provide natural gas services before the individual may provide natural gas services in the State.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Subject to paragraph (2) of this subsection, this section does not apply to an individual who personally provides plumbing services in the residence of the individual.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">An individual may not provide plumbing services that make a final connection between the residence of the individual and a public or private disposal system or water supply system.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">This section does not apply to an employee of a gas company regulated by the Public Service Commission while making a connection to a gas appliance for domestic purposes or while installing, repairing, maintaining, replacing, or performing any other work on a natural gas, propane gas, or other gas distribution system, including customer-owned gas piping systems.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">This section does not apply to an individual performing work that is only incidental to the licensee providing or assisting in providing plumbing services.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">This section does not apply to an individual who, without compensation, provides plumbing services that the Board defines by regulation to be only incidental plumbing services.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">This section does not apply to an employee of a building owner, manager, or maintenance company who provides plumbing services that the Board defines by regulation to be only minor plumbing repair services.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">This section does not apply to an individual who is licensed as an appliance installer in Allegany County, Frederick County, Garrett County, or Washington County while acting within the scope of the license.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">This section does not apply to an individual who is licensed in Washington County to work as or for a septic system installer or an on-site utility contractor installing water or sewer service in the county at least 5 feet from a building being served.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">Subsection (a)(3) and (4) of this section does not apply to an individual licensed by the State Board of Heating, Ventilation, Air-Conditioning, and Refrigeration Contractors while servicing an existing propane gas or existing natural gas appliance if the individual has completed a manufacturer's training course certifying competence to work on that particular type of appliance.</section>
  </text>
</law>
