<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gbo" order_by="gbo" level="1">Business Occupations and Professions</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gbo-5-305</section_number>
  <catch_line>To qualify for a limited license to practice cosmetology, an applicant shall be an individual who me...</catch_line>
  <order_by>305</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">To qualify for a limited license to practice cosmetology, an applicant shall be an individual who meets the requirements of this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">An applicant for a limited license to provide esthetic services shall:<section prefix="(1)">be at least 17 years old;</section><section prefix="(2)">have completed successfully a 9th grade education or the equivalent; and</section><section prefix="(3)">have received training by:<section prefix="(i)">serving as a registered apprentice for at least 6 months as provided under &#xA7;&#xA7; 5-404 and 5-405 of this title; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">successfully completing at least 600 hours of instruction in providing esthetic services in a cosmetology school approved by the State Department of Education or the Maryland Higher Education Commission in consultation with the Board.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">An applicant for a limited license to provide nail technician services shall:<section prefix="(1)">be at least 17 years old;</section><section prefix="(2)">have successfully completed a 9th grade education or the equivalent; and</section><section prefix="(3)">have received training by:<section prefix="(i)">serving as a registered apprentice for at least 3 months as provided under &#xA7;&#xA7; 5-404 and 5-405 of this title; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">successfully completing at least 250 hours of instruction in providing nail technician services in a cosmetology school approved by the State Department of Education or the Maryland Higher Education Commission in consultation with the Board.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">If an applicant is licensed to practice as an esthetician or nail technician in another state or foreign country, the applicant meets the training requirements of this section if the applicant has held a limited license in the other state or foreign country and has actively practiced in the other state or foreign country for a period of 6 months.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">An applicant for a limited license shall pass an examination given by the Board under this subtitle.</section>
  </text>
</law>
