<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gbo" order_by="" level="1">Business Occupations and Professions</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gbo-17-319</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>319</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Subject to the provisions of subsection (b) of this section, on the death of a licensed real estate broker, any adult member of the family of the deceased broker may carry on the business of the deceased broker for up to 6 months for the purposes of closing and terminating the business.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">To qualify to carry on the business of a deceased real estate broker, a family member shall:<section prefix="(1)">surrender the license certificate and pocket card of the deceased real estate broker to the Commission; and</section><section prefix="(2)">submit to the Commission any information or documentation required by the Commission.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Commission shall reissue the license of a deceased real estate broker to a family member who qualifies to carry on the business of the broker under subsection (b) of this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The term of the reissuance shall be 6 months.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Before the end of the 6-month period for carrying on the business of a deceased real estate broker, an individual may qualify for the license of the deceased broker if:<section prefix="(1)">the individual is a member of the immediate family of the deceased broker;</section><section prefix="(2)">the individual has been continuously licensed as a real estate salesperson for the immediately preceding 3 years;</section><section prefix="(3)">regardless of whether the individual has met the educational requirements for a real estate broker license under &#xA7; 17-305 of this subtitle, the individual passes the real estate broker's examination under &#xA7; 17-306 of this subtitle;</section><section prefix="(4)">the individual surrenders the real estate salesperson license certificate and pocket card of the individual to the Commission; and</section><section prefix="(5)">there has been compliance with the requirements of subsection (b) of this section.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The Commission shall reissue the license of a deceased real estate broker to an individual who qualifies for the license of the broker under subsection (d) of this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">An individual who qualifies for and is reissued the license of a deceased real estate broker may hold the license for up to 4 years from the time of reissuance without meeting the educational requirements for a real estate broker license under &#xA7; 17-305 of this subtitle.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Subject to the 4-year restriction under paragraph (1) of this subsection, an individual who has been reissued the license of a deceased real estate broker is responsible for renewing the license as required under &#xA7; 17-314 of this subtitle.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">If an individual who has been reissued the license of a deceased real estate broker does not meet the educational requirements for a real estate broker license within the 4-year period, the license shall expire automatically at the end of that period.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">If an individual who has been reissued the license of a deceased real estate broker meets the educational requirements for a real estate broker license within the 4-year period, the individual may continue to hold the license and may renew the license under &#xA7; 17-314 of this subtitle.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
