<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gbo" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="17-410" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gbo-17-410</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Commission shall order payment of a claim by the Guaranty Fund if, on the hearing, the claimant:<section prefix="(1)">proves that the claimant has a valid claim under this subtitle; and</section><section prefix="(2)">presents evidence, satisfactory to the Commission, that the claimant is not:<section prefix="(i)">the spouse of the licensee or the unlicensed employee alleged to be responsible for the act or omission giving rise to the claim; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">the personal representative of the spouse of the licensee or the unlicensed employee alleged to be responsible for the act or omission giving rise to the claim.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Commission may order payment by the Guaranty Fund only for the actual monetary loss suffered by the claimant as a result of the claim proven by the claimant.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">For any claim, the Commission may not order a payment by the Guaranty Fund of more than $25,000.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A payment may not be made by the Guaranty Fund under an order of the Commission until:<section prefix="(1)">the expiration of the time provided under Title 10, Subtitle 2 of the State Government Article for seeking judicial review of the Commission's order; or</section><section prefix="(2)">the expiration of any judicial stay of the order of the Commission.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Commission shall order payment of each claim due in the order in which the claim was awarded.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">If, at the time a payment is due, the money in the Guaranty Fund is insufficient to satisfy fully the order for payment, the Commission:<section prefix="(1)">immediately shall pay to the claimant the amount that is available in the Guaranty Fund; and</section><section prefix="(2)">when sufficient funds are available in the Guaranty Fund, shall pay the claimant:<section prefix="(i)">the balance due on the order; plus</section><section prefix="(ii)">interest calculated on that balance at an annual rate of 10%.</section></section></section>
  </text>
</law>
