<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gbo" order_by="" level="1">Business Occupations and Professions</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gbo-16-503</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>503</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">To qualify for a certificate for residential or general real estate appraisal, an applicant shall be an individual who meets the requirements of this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">An applicant shall:<section prefix="(i)">be of good character and reputation;</section><section prefix="(ii)">be at least 18 years old; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">satisfy the minimum real estate appraiser qualifications for residential certification or general certification, as appropriate, established under the federal Financial Institutions Reform, Recovery, and Enforcement Act of 1989.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">An applicant shall have completed at least 2,000 hours providing real estate appraiser services as a real estate appraiser trainee under the supervision of a licensed or certified appraiser.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Classroom hours of study required under this section may be conducted by:<section prefix="(i)">an accredited university, college, or community or junior college;</section><section prefix="(ii)">an approved appraisal society, institute, or association; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">another school that the Commission approves.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The Commission shall approve all courses of study required under this section.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">An applicant shall pass the examination for a certificate for residential or general real estate appraisal given by the Commission or the Commission's designee under this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If an applicant is not a resident of the State, the applicant shall submit to the Commission an irrevocable consent, as provided under this subsection.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The consent required under this subsection shall specify that service of process on the Secretary of State shall bind the applicant in any action about the provision of certified real estate appraisal services against the applicant in any county of the State.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">An applicant shall meet any other requirement that the Commission adopts by regulation.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The Commission shall adopt additional requirements under this section if necessary to comply with the minimum real estate appraiser qualifications established under the federal Financial Institutions Reform, Recovery, and Enforcement Act of 1989.</section>
  </text>
</law>
