<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gbr" order_by="" level="1">Business Regulation</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gbr-1-404</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>404</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">If a person uses a mark in the State, the person may register the mark in accordance with this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A person may not register a mark that:<section prefix="(1)">is deceptive, immoral, or scandalous;</section><section prefix="(2)">may disparage, falsely suggest a connection with, or bring into contempt or disrepute:<section prefix="(i)">a belief;</section><section prefix="(ii)">an individual, living or dead;</section><section prefix="(iii)">an institution; or</section><section prefix="(iv)">a national symbol;</section></section><section prefix="(3)">is, simulates, or includes a coat of arms, flag, or other insignia of a government;</section><section prefix="(4)">is or includes the name, portrait, or signature of a living individual, except with the written consent of the individual; or</section><section prefix="(5)">is likely, when applied to the goods or services of the person, to confuse or deceive because the mark resembles:<section prefix="(i)">another mark registered in the State; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">a mark or trade name that another person has used in the State and has not abandoned.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Unless the mark has become distinctive of the person's goods or services, a person may not register a mark that:<section prefix="(i)">only describes or deceptively misdescribes goods or services;</section><section prefix="(ii)">primarily describes or deceptively misdescribes the geographic origin of goods or services; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">is primarily merely a surname.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">As evidence that a mark has become distinctive of the goods or services of a person, the Secretary of State may accept proof that the person has used the mark as a mark in the State or elsewhere continuously for at least 5 years immediately before the day on which the person applies for registration.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A person may not register a trade name that is not a mark.</section>
  </text>
</law>
