<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gbr" order_by="" level="1">Business Regulation</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gbr-16-201</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>201</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"License" means:<section prefix="(1)">a license issued by the Comptroller under &#xA7; 16-205(a) of this subtitle to:<section prefix="(i)">act as a manufacturer;</section><section prefix="(ii)">act as a subwholesaler;</section><section prefix="(iii)">act as a vending machine operator;</section><section prefix="(iv)">act as a wholesaler; or</section><section prefix="(v)">act as a storage warehouse; or</section></section><section prefix="(2)">a license issued by the clerk under &#xA7; 16-205(b) of this subtitle to act as a retailer.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Licensed manufacturer" means a person licensed by the Comptroller under &#xA7; 16-205(a) of this subtitle to act as a manufacturer.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">"Licensed retailer" means a person licensed by the clerk under &#xA7; 16-205(b) of this subtitle to act as a retailer.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"Licensed storage warehouse" means a facility licensed by the Comptroller under &#xA7; 16-205(a) of this subtitle to act as a storage warehouse.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">"Licensed subwholesaler" means a person licensed by the Comptroller under &#xA7; 16-205(a) of this subtitle to act as a subwholesaler.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">"Licensed vending machine operator" means a person licensed by the Comptroller under &#xA7; 16-205(a) of this subtitle to act as a vending machine operator.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">"Licensed wholesaler" means a person licensed by the Comptroller under &#xA7; 16-205(a) of this subtitle to act as a wholesaler.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">"Manufacturer" means a person who:<section prefix="(1)"><section prefix="(i)">operates one or more cigarette manufacturing plants; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">is a participating manufacturer; and</section></section><section prefix="(2)"><section prefix="(i)">sells unstamped cigarettes to a licensed cigarette wholesaler located in Maryland;</section><section prefix="(ii)">sells unstamped cigarettes that may lawfully be sold in Maryland to a licensed cigarette wholesaler located outside of Maryland;</section><section prefix="(iii)">unless otherwise prohibited or restricted under local law, this article, or the Criminal Law Article, distributes sample cigarettes to consumers located in Maryland; or</section><section prefix="(iv)">stores unstamped cigarettes in a cigarette storage warehouse in Maryland for subsequent shipment to licensed wholesalers, federal reservations, or persons out of state.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(j)">"Participating manufacturer" has the meaning stated in &#xA7; 16-501 of this title.</section>
    <section prefix="(k)">"Retailer" means a person who:<section prefix="(1)">sells cigarettes to consumers through vending machines on fewer than 40 premises;</section><section prefix="(2)">otherwise sells cigarettes to consumers; or</section><section prefix="(3)">holds cigarettes for sale to consumers.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(l)">"Stamped cigarettes" means a package of cigarettes to which tobacco tax stamps are affixed in the amount and manner required by &#xA7; 12-304 of the Tax - General Article.</section>
    <section prefix="(m)">"Storage warehouse" means a storage facility in Maryland operated for the purpose of storing unstamped cigarettes on behalf of a licensed cigarette manufacturer.</section>
    <section prefix="(n)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Subwholesaler" means a person who:<section prefix="(i)">holds stamped cigarettes for sale to another person for resale; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">sells stamped cigarettes to another person for resale.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Subwholesaler" does not include a person who sells unstamped cigarettes or holds unstamped cigarettes for sale.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(o)">"Unstamped cigarettes" means a package of cigarettes to which tobacco tax stamps are not affixed in the amount and manner required by &#xA7; 12-304 of the Tax - General Article.</section>
    <section prefix="(p)">"Vending machine operator" means a person who:<section prefix="(1)">holds cigarettes for sale to consumers through vending machines on 40 or more premises; or</section><section prefix="(2)">sells cigarettes to consumers through vending machines on 40 or more premises.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(q)">"Wholesaler" means a person who:<section prefix="(1)">holds cigarettes for sale to another person for resale; or</section><section prefix="(2)">sells cigarettes to another person for resale.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
