<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gbr" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="1-406" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gbr-1-406</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">An applicant for registration of a mark shall:<section prefix="(1)">submit to the Secretary of State:<section prefix="(i)">an application on the form that the Secretary of State provides; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">3 specimens or reproductions of the mark; and</section></section><section prefix="(2)">pay to the Secretary of State a fee of $50.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">An application shall be signed, under oath:<section prefix="(1)">for an individual, by the individual;</section><section prefix="(2)">for a partnership, by a partner; or</section><section prefix="(3)">for a corporation or association, by an officer of the corporation or association.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">In addition to any other information required on an application form, the form shall require:<section prefix="(1)">the name of the applicant;</section><section prefix="(2)">the business address of the applicant;</section><section prefix="(3)">for an applicant that is a corporation, the state of incorporation;</section><section prefix="(4)">the goods or services with which the applicant uses the mark;</section><section prefix="(5)">the way the applicant uses the mark with the goods or services;</section><section prefix="(6)">the class under &#xA7; 1-405 of this subtitle to which the goods or services belong;</section><section prefix="(7)">the date when the applicant or the applicant's predecessor in business:<section prefix="(i)">first used the mark anywhere; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">first used the mark in the State; and</section></section><section prefix="(8)">a statement that:<section prefix="(i)">the applicant owns the mark;</section><section prefix="(ii)">another person does not have the right to use the mark in the State; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">the mark is not deceptively similar to a mark that another person has a right to use in the State.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A single application for registration of a mark:<section prefix="(1)">may cover use of the mark with any number of goods or services in a single class; but</section><section prefix="(2)">may not cover use of the mark with goods or services in different classes.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
