<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gbr" order_by="" level="1">Business Regulation</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gbr-5-304</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>304</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Each applicant designated as the responsible party shall demonstrate the financial stability of the business with which the applicant is affiliated by providing the Director with a financial statement or other reports required under subsection (e) of this section with the application for registration.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">If the business is a cemetery that sells burial goods and is an existing business, the financial statement shall:<section prefix="(1)">be on the form that the Director requires;</section><section prefix="(2)">contain a statement by a certified public accountant retained by the business, detailing the assets and liabilities of the cemetery for the last fiscal year; and</section><section prefix="(3)">contain a review by the certified public accountant as to the financial stability of the cemetery.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">If the business is an existing cemetery that does not sell burial goods or an existing burial goods business not affiliated with a cemetery, the applicant shall:<section prefix="(1)">complete a form that the Director requires; and</section><section prefix="(2)">satisfy criteria that the Director adopts under subsection (e) of this section.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">If the business is a new business, the applicant shall:<section prefix="(1)">complete a form that the Director requires; and</section><section prefix="(2)">satisfy criteria that the Director adopts under subsection (e) of this section.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Director shall make a determination of the financial stability of each applicant based on criteria that the Director adopts for each class of business.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Director shall adopt separate criteria to determine the financial stability of applicants that are new businesses or existing businesses.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Director shall require that all financial statements of a new cemetery submitted under subsection (d) of this section be prepared by a certified public accountant retained by the business.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
