<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gbr" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="16-604" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gbr-16-604</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>** CONTINGENCY - IN EFFECT - CHAPTER 497 OF 2007 **<section prefix="(a)">Cigarettes that have been certified in accordance with &#xA7; 16-603 of this subtitle shall be marked in accordance with the requirements of this section.</section><section prefix="(b)">The marking shall:<section prefix="(1)">consist of:<section prefix="(i)">any marking in use and approved for sale in New York under the New York fire safety standards for cigarettes; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">the letters "FSC" to signify Fire Standards Compliant;</section></section><section prefix="(2)">be in a font of at least 8 point type; and</section><section prefix="(3)">be permanently printed, stamped, engraved, or embossed on the package at or near the area of the UPC code, if present.</section></section><section prefix="(c)">A manufacturer may propose an alternative marking that:<section prefix="(1)">meets the criteria under subsection (b)(2) and (3) of this section; and</section><section prefix="(2)">consists of a visible combination of alphanumeric or symbolic characters or text permanently stamped, engraved, embossed, or printed:<section prefix="(i)">in conjunction with the UPC code; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">on the cigarette pack or cellophane wrap.</section></section></section><section prefix="(d)"><section prefix="(1)">A manufacturer shall request approval of a proposed marking from the Comptroller.</section><section prefix="(2)"><section prefix="(i)">The Comptroller shall approve a marking specified in subsection (b)(1) of this section.</section><section prefix="(ii)">A marking is deemed approved if the Comptroller fails to act within 10 business days after receiving a request for approval.</section></section><section prefix="(3)">A manufacturer may not use a modified marking unless the modification has been approved in accordance with this section.</section><section prefix="(4)">A manufacturer shall use only one marking on all brands that the manufacturer markets.</section><section prefix="(5)">A marking or modified marking approved by the Comptroller shall be applied uniformly on all brands marketed and on all packages, including packs, cartons, and cases marketed by that manufacturer.</section></section></text>
</law>
