<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gbr" order_by="gbr" level="1">Business Regulation</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gbr-8-403</section_number>
  <catch_line>The Commission shall:...</catch_line>
  <order_by>403</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Commission shall:<section prefix="(1)">establish a Home Improvement Guaranty Fund;</section><section prefix="(2)">keep the Fund at a level of at least $250,000; and</section><section prefix="(3)">submit a report detailing actions being taken to restore the balance of the Fund to a sustainable level to the Senate Education, Health, and Environmental Affairs Committee and the House Economic Matters Committee within 30 days of projecting that the Fund balance will be less than $250,000.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as otherwise provided by law, the Commission shall deposit all money collected to the credit of the Fund with the State Treasurer for placement in a special account.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The Commission shall establish and maintain within the Fund a separate account to be held with the State Treasurer for the payment of necessary expenses for expert witnesses used to resolve claims against the Fund.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">One-half of the money collected under &#xA7; 8-620(c) of this title shall be credited to the account established in subparagraph (i) of this paragraph.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">One-half of the money collected under &#xA7; 8-620(c) of this title shall be credited to the General Fund of the State.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The State Treasurer shall invest the money in the Fund in the same way that money in the State Retirement and Pension System is invested.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">Investment earnings shall be credited to the Fund.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Commission shall administer the Fund in accordance with this subtitle.</section>
  </text>
</law>
