<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gbr" order_by="" level="1">Business Regulation</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gbr-9-301</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>301</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">An employment agency shall submit to the Commissioner a penal bond.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The bond shall:<section prefix="(1)">run to the State;</section><section prefix="(2)">be in the amount of $7,000;</section><section prefix="(3)">be signed by an individual authorized to do so by the employment agency as principal and by a surety company authorized to do business in the State as surety; and</section><section prefix="(4)">be conditioned that the employment agency will comply with this title and will pay to any person all damages caused by deceit, fraud, misrepresentation, or misstatement of the employment agency or an agent or employee of the employment agency.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">To ensure that each employment agency submits the penal bond in accordance with this section, the Commissioner may initiate an investigation or investigate a complaint that an employment agency has failed to submit a penal bond.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">If, after investigation, the Commissioner finds that an employment agency has failed to submit a penal bond as required by this section, the Commissioner shall give written notice that directs the employment agency, within 15 days after receipt of the notice:<section prefix="(1)">to submit the required bond; or</section><section prefix="(2)">to show written cause why the employment agency is not required to comply with this section.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If the employment agency complies with the requirement to submit a bond or otherwise submits a timely response, the Commissioner may:<section prefix="(i)">terminate proceedings against the employment agency; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">schedule a hearing and, by certified mail, give the employment agency written notice of the date, place, and time of the hearing.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If the employment agency fails to comply with a lawful order of the Commissioner or fails to submit a timely response, the Commissioner may impose a civil penalty of not less than $500 and not more than $1,000 for each failure to comply with the order or failure to submit a timely report.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">If after a hearing, the Commissioner finds that the employment agency has violated the provisions of this section, the Commissioner may impose a civil penalty of not less than $500 and not more than $1,000 for each violation of this section.</section>
  </text>
</law>
