<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gbr" order_by="gbr" level="1">Business Regulation</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gbr-14-110</section_number>
  <catch_line>Whenever the Commissioner determines that a person has engaged or is about to engage in an act or pr...</catch_line>
  <order_by>110</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Whenever the Commissioner determines that a person has engaged or is about to engage in an act or practice that constitutes a violation of this subtitle or a violation of a regulation adopted or order passed under this subtitle, the Commissioner may, without a prior hearing, pass a summary order directing the person to cease and desist from engaging in the activity that constitutes a violation.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The summary order shall provide:<section prefix="(i)">notice of the opportunity for a hearing before the Commissioner to determine whether the cease and desist order should be vacated, modified, or entered as final; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">notice that the Commissioner shall enter the order as final if the person subject to the cease and desist order fails to request a hearing within 15 days after the receipt of the cease and desist order.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Whenever the Commissioner determines after notice and a hearing that a person has engaged in any act or practice constituting a violation of this subtitle, the Commissioner may in the discretion of the Commissioner and in addition to taking any other action authorized under this subtitle:<section prefix="(i)">pass a final cease and desist order against the person;</section><section prefix="(ii)">bar the person from engaging in the offer and sale of business opportunities in the State; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">take any combination of the actions specified in this section.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The person subject to the cease and desist order may waive the right to a hearing.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If a person subject to a cease and desist order waives the right to a hearing, the Commissioner is not required to hold a hearing to take any action under subsection (a)(3) of this section.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Whenever the Commissioner determines that any person has engaged in or is about to engage in an act or practice constituting a violation of this subtitle or a violation of a regulation or order under this subtitle, the Commissioner may sue in the circuit court to obtain one or more of the following remedies:<section prefix="(i)">a temporary restraining order;</section><section prefix="(ii)">a temporary or permanent injunction;</section><section prefix="(iii)">a declaratory judgment;</section><section prefix="(iv)">the appointment of a receiver or conservator for the defendant or the defendant's assets;</section><section prefix="(v)">a freeze of the defendant's assets;</section><section prefix="(vi)">a civil penalty up to a maximum amount of $5,000 for any single violation of this subtitle;</section><section prefix="(vii)">restitution;</section><section prefix="(viii)">rescission; or</section><section prefix="(ix)">any other relief as the court finds just.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Commissioner may not be required to post a bond in any action under this section.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
