<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gbr" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="16-501" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gbr-16-501</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Brand family" means all styles of cigarettes sold under the same trademark, regardless of whether the cigarettes are differentiated from one another by means of additional modifiers or descriptors such as "menthol", "lights", "kings", "100s", or other differentiation.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Brand family" includes any use of a brand name (alone or in conjunction with any other word) trademark, logo, symbol, motto, selling message, recognizable pattern of colors, or any other indicia of product identification identical or similar to, or identifiable with, a previously known brand of cigarettes.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Cigarette" has the meaning stated in &#xA7; 16-402(e) of this title (the Escrow Act).</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">"Comptroller" means the Comptroller of the State or any authorized agent of the Comptroller who is responsible for collection of the excise tax on cigarettes.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"Escrow Act" means Subtitle 4 of this title.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">"Licensed wholesaler" means a wholesaler who is licensed under Subtitle 2 of this title to act as a wholesaler and any person who is an authorized agent of the licensed wholesaler for the stamping and distribution of cigarettes.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">"Master Settlement Agreement" has the meaning stated in &#xA7; 16-402(f) of this title (the Escrow Act).</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">"Nonparticipating manufacturer" means any tobacco product manufacturer that is not a participating manufacturer.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">"Participating manufacturer" has the meaning stated in section II(jj) of the Master Settlement Agreement and all amendments to the Agreement.</section>
    <section prefix="(j)">"Qualified escrow fund" has the meaning stated in &#xA7; 16-402(g) of this title (the Escrow Act).</section>
    <section prefix="(k)">"Tobacco product manufacturer" has the meaning stated in &#xA7; 16-402(j) of this title (the Escrow Act).</section>
    <section prefix="(l)">"Units sold" has the meaning stated in &#xA7; 16-402(k) of this title (the Escrow Act).</section>
  </text>
</law>
