<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gbr" order_by="" level="1">Business Regulation</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gbr-14-210</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>210</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Whenever the Commissioner finds that a person has violated or is about to violate this subtitle or a regulation adopted or order passed under it, the Commissioner may order the person to cease and desist from the further offer to sell or sale of the franchise until the offer or sale complies with this subtitle.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">After passage of a cease and desist order, the alleged violator may submit to the Commissioner a written request for a hearing.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The hearing shall begin:<section prefix="(i)">within 15 business days after the Commissioner receives the request for a hearing; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">at a later date, with the consent of the alleged violator.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">Unless there is a timely hearing, the cease and desist order is rescinded.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Whenever the Commissioner finds that a person has violated or is about to violate this subtitle or a regulation adopted or order passed under it, the Commissioner may sue in the circuit court to enjoin the violation or enforce this subtitle or the regulation or order.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The court shall:<section prefix="(i)">determine if a violation of this subtitle has been or is about to be committed; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">if so, pass any order the court considers necessary to prevent the violation or remove the effects of the violation and prevent it from continuing or being renewed in the future.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The court may exercise all equitable powers necessary for this purpose, including:<section prefix="(i)">injunction;</section><section prefix="(ii)">revocation, forfeiture, or suspension of the charter authority or privileges of a business organization operating under the laws of the State;</section><section prefix="(iii)">dissolution of a corporation or association organized under the laws of the State;</section><section prefix="(iv)">suspension or termination of the right of a corporation or association organized under the laws of another state or country to do business in the State;</section><section prefix="(v)">restitution;</section><section prefix="(vi)">restraining order;</section><section prefix="(vii)">award of damages to be paid by a franchisor or subfranchisor to a person injured by a violation of this subtitle; and</section><section prefix="(viii)">appointment of a receiver or conservator.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The court may not require the Commissioner to post bond.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Commissioner may not exercise a power under this section more than 3 years after the violation occurs.</section>
  </text>
</law>
