<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gbr" order_by="gbr" level="1">Business Regulation</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gbr-8-308</section_number>
  <catch_line>The Secretary may stagger the terms of licenses....</catch_line>
  <order_by>308</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Secretary may stagger the terms of licenses.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Unless a license is renewed for a 2-year term as provided in this section, the license expires:<section prefix="(1)">if the Secretary staggers the terms of licenses, on the date that the Secretary sets; or</section><section prefix="(2)">if the Secretary does not stagger the terms of licenses, on the first June 30 that comes after the effective date of the license in an odd-numbered year.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">At least 1 month before a license expires, the Commission shall mail to the licensee, at the last known address of the licensee:<section prefix="(1)">a renewal application form; and</section><section prefix="(2)">a notice that states:<section prefix="(i)">the date on which the current license expires;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the date by which the Commission must receive the renewal application for the renewal to be issued and mailed before the license expires; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">the amount of the renewal fee.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Before a license expires, the licensee periodically may renew it for an additional 2-year term, if the licensee:<section prefix="(i)">otherwise is entitled to be licensed;</section><section prefix="(ii)">submits to the Commission a renewal application on the form that the Commission provides;</section><section prefix="(iii)">submits to the Commission proof of compliance with the insurance requirement of &#xA7; 8-302.1 of this subtitle, if the licensee is renewing a contractor license;</section><section prefix="(iv)">submits to the Commission the Department of the Environment lead paint abatement accreditation number and accreditation expiration date, if the licensee provides lead paint abatement services; and</section><section prefix="(v)">pays to the Commission a renewal fee.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The renewal fee:<section prefix="(i)">for a contractor license is $250 for each place of business of the contractor;</section><section prefix="(ii)">for a subcontractor license is $150; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">for a salesperson license is $100.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Notwithstanding paragraph (2) of this subsection, a licensee that is incorporated or has its principal office in another state shall pay to the Commission the fee imposed in that state on a similar nonresident business if that fee is higher than the renewal fee under paragraph (2) of this subsection.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">For renewal of a contractor license, the licensee shall:<section prefix="(1)">submit to the Commission, by a credit reporting agency approved by the Commission, a credit report that contains the information required by the Commission; or</section><section prefix="(2)">pay to the Commission or the Commission's designee a credit report fee in an amount not to exceed the cost charged by a credit reporting agency approved by the Commission to obtain a credit report that contains the information required by the Commission for renewal of a contractor license.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Commission shall renew the license of each licensee who meets the requirements of this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Commission may not renew a contractor license unless the contractor submits proof of compliance with the insurance requirement of &#xA7; 8-302.1 of this subtitle.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">A licensed contractor shall give the Commission notice of the cancellation of insurance required under &#xA7; 8-302.1 of this subtitle at least 10 days before the effective date of the cancellation.</section>
  </text>
</law>
