<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gbr" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="11-808" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gbr-11-808</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">An employee of a receiving track is not considered an employee of the sending track because of this part.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Commission has jurisdiction over all intertrack betting and other activities at a receiving track to the same extent as when live racing is held at the track.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Commission shall adopt regulations to carry out this part.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Only a licensee may operate a receiving track or a sending track.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A receiving track shall transmit directly to the sending track all pari-mutuel information about the money bet at the receiving track.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A sending track shall incorporate this information with information on pari-mutuel betting at the sending track.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">Money bet in intertrack betting shall be:<section prefix="(1)">included in the applicable mutuel pools at the sending track; and</section><section prefix="(2)">considered as if bet at the sending track.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The breakage, State tax, and takeout on all intertrack betting at a receiving track shall be computed in the way normally applicable to pari-mutuel betting on a race at the sending track.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The takeout shall be allocated in the same proportions that are normally applicable to racing held at the sending track, after deductions for:<section prefix="(i)">the State tax;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the amount to be kept by the receiving track under the simulcast agreement with the sending track; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">the cost to the sending track of the transmission.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
