<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gbr" order_by="gbr" level="1">Business Regulation</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gbr-11-202</section_number>
  <catch_line>The Commission consists of 9 members, appointed by the Governor with the advice and consent of the S...</catch_line>
  <order_by>202</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Commission consists of 9 members, appointed by the Governor with the advice and consent of the Senate.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">At the time of appointment and qualification:<section prefix="(1)">each member shall be:<section prefix="(i)">at least 25 years old;</section><section prefix="(ii)">a resident of the State who has resided in the State for at least the last 5 years;</section><section prefix="(iii)">a qualified voter of the State; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">an individual who has not been convicted of a crime that involves moral turpitude;</section></section><section prefix="(2)">at least 3 members of the Commission shall be knowledgeable or experienced in an aspect of thoroughbred racing; and</section><section prefix="(3)">at least 3 other members shall be knowledgeable or experienced in an aspect of harness racing.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A member of the Commission may not hold an official relation to a licensee or hold any stocks, bonds, or other financial interest in a licensee.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Not more than 4 members who are appointed after July 1, 1989, may have a financial interest in racing in the State.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Not more than 6 members may be of the same political party.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Before taking office, each appointee to the Commission shall take the oath required by Article I, &#xA7; 9 of the Maryland Constitution.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The term of a member of the Commission is 4 years and begins on July 1.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The terms of members are staggered as required by the terms provided for members of the Commission on October 1, 1992.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">At the end of a term, a member continues to serve until a successor is appointed and qualifies.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">A member who is appointed after a term has begun serves only for the rest of the term and until a successor is appointed and qualifies.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Subject to the hearing requirements of this subsection, the Governor, with the advice of the Secretary, may remove a member of the Commission for inefficiency, misconduct in office, or neglect of duty.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Before the Governor removes a member, the Governor shall give the member an opportunity for a public hearing.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">At least 10 days before the hearing, the Governor shall give the member:<section prefix="(i)">a copy of the charges; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">notice of the time and place of the hearing.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The member may be represented at the hearing by counsel.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">If the Governor removes a member, the Governor shall submit to the Secretary of State:<section prefix="(i)">a statement of all charges made against the member;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the findings of the Governor; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">a record of the proceedings.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">The Governor shall appoint one member of the Commission to serve as a liaison to the State Lottery Commission established under Title 9 of the State Government Article.</section>
  </text>
</law>
