<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gbr" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="12-305" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gbr-12-305</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)"/>
        <section prefix="(ii)">A dealer who holds a license in Prince George's County and who acquires a precious metal object, other than a pawned precious metal object described in subparagraph (i)2 of this paragraph, shall keep it in Prince George's County from the time of acquisition until at least 30 days after submitting a copy of a record of its acquisition under &#xA7; 12-304 of this subtitle.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A dealer who acquires a precious metal object at an event which takes place at a location other than the dealer's fixed business address shall place the object and a record of its acquisition at a location in accordance with subsection (d)(1) or (2) of this section by the next business day after acquiring the object.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">In partial compliance with the 18-day holding requirement under this subsection, a dealer may maintain an object and the record of its acquisition at a location other than the dealer's fixed business address, if the local law enforcement unit in the jurisdiction where the item was acquired provides written approval.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A dealer may submit to the primary law enforcement unit a written request for a shorter holding period for a specific precious metal object.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Within 48 hours after the primary law enforcement unit receives a request, the primary law enforcement unit shall approve or deny the request.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">After inspecting the precious metal object, the primary law enforcement unit may authorize in writing a shorter holding period.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">If the primary law enforcement unit denies the request, the primary law enforcement unit shall state the reasons in writing.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, a dealer may not alter a precious metal object before or during the holding period.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">During the holding period, a dealer may chemically test a precious metal object to determine its metal content or value if the dealer does not alter the precious metal object so as to affect its identification or value.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">During the holding period for a precious metal object, a dealer shall keep the precious metal object and the record of its acquisition in:<section prefix="(1)">the place of business of the dealer; or</section><section prefix="(2)">a storage facility specified in the license application of the dealer.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
