<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gbr" order_by="gbr" level="1">Business Regulation</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gbr-17-1905</section_number>
  <catch_line>The clerk shall give each vending machine licensee an identification label for each vending machine....</catch_line>
  <order_by>1905</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The clerk shall give each vending machine licensee an identification label for each vending machine.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Subject to regulations adopted by the Comptroller, the identification label shall be attached to the vending machine so that the identification label is easily visible.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">In addition, the name and telephone number of the vending machine licensee or owner of the vending machine shall be displayed on each vending machine so that the name and telephone number are easily visible.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If an inspector finds that a vending machine does not display the identification label required by this section, the inspector promptly shall:<section prefix="(i)">notify the vending machine licensee or owner in writing of the violation; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">require that the vending machine licensee or owner display the identification label properly within 10 days after receiving notice of the violation.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If the vending machine licensee or owner fails to display the identification label properly within 10 days, the inspector shall:<section prefix="(i)">seal the vending machine to prevent further use; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">take necessary action to enforce the licensing provisions of this subtitle.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">If neither the identification label nor the name and telephone number of the vending machine licensee or owner are displayed properly, the inspector:<section prefix="(i)">immediately shall seal the vending machine to prevent further use; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">shall take necessary action to enforce this subtitle.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
