<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gbr" order_by="" level="1">Business Regulation</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gbr-7-205</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>205</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">To carry out this title, the Board may, subject to &#xA7; 7-103(b) of this title:<section prefix="(1)">receive a written complaint and hold a hearing on an alleged violation by a collection agency of the Maryland Consumer Debt Collection Act or this title;</section><section prefix="(2)">mediate a dispute between a consumer and a collection agency and suggest monetary compensation of the consumer in an amount agreeable to the consumer and collection agency or other appropriate resolution or both; and</section><section prefix="(3)">issue orders:<section prefix="(i)">to cease and desist from the violation and any further similar violations; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">requiring the violator to take affirmative action to correct the violation.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">If a violator fails to comply with a lawful order issued by the Board, the Board may impose a penalty of up to $500 for each violation cited in the order, not to exceed $5,000, from which the violator failed to cease and desist or for which the violator failed to take affirmative action to correct, as ordered by the Board.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">In determining the amount of any penalty to be imposed under subsection (b) of this section, the Board shall consider:<section prefix="(1)">the seriousness of the violation;</section><section prefix="(2)">the good faith of the violator;</section><section prefix="(3)">the violator's history of previous violations;</section><section prefix="(4)">the deleterious effect of the violation on the public and the collection industry; and</section><section prefix="(5)">any other factors relevant to the determination of the financial penalty.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
