<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gbr" order_by="gbr" level="1">Business Regulation</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gbr-1-410</section_number>
  <catch_line>Unless registration of a mark is renewed for a 10-year term as provided in this section, the registr...</catch_line>
  <order_by>410</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Unless registration of a mark is renewed for a 10-year term as provided in this section, the registration expires on the tenth anniversary of its effective date.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Within 1 year before registration of a mark expires, the Secretary of State shall mail to the registrant, at the last known address of the registrant:<section prefix="(1)">a renewal application form; and</section><section prefix="(2)">a notice that states:<section prefix="(i)">the date on which the current registration expires;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the date by which the Secretary of State must receive the renewal application for the renewal to be issued and mailed before the registration expires; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">the amount of the renewal fee.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Before the registration of a mark expires, the registrant periodically may renew it for an additional 10-year term if, within 6 months before the expiration of the term of the registration:<section prefix="(1)">the registrant submits to the Secretary of State a renewal application on the form that the Secretary of State provides;</section><section prefix="(2)">the registrant states in the renewal application that the mark is still in use in the State;</section><section prefix="(3)">the mark otherwise is entitled to be registered; and</section><section prefix="(4)">the registrant pays to the Secretary of State a renewal fee of $50.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Secretary of State shall renew the registration of and issue a renewal certificate to each registrant who meets the requirements of this section.</section>
  </text>
</law>
