<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gbr" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="12.5-202" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gbr-12.5-202</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The owner of a business or the owner's designee shall apply on behalf of the business for a license under this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">An applicant for a license shall:<section prefix="(i)">submit to the Secretary an application on the form that the Secretary provides;</section><section prefix="(ii)">submit a passport-size photograph, taken within 6 months immediately preceding the date of the filing of the application, of each of the following individuals:</section><section prefix="(iii)">provide any other documents or information required by this section or required by the Secretary; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">pay to the Secretary an application fee set by the Secretary.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The application fee is nonrefundable.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The applicant owner or designee shall sign the application under oath.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">In addition to any other information that the Secretary requires, the application shall state:<section prefix="(1)">the name, birth date, and residence address of the following individuals:<section prefix="(i)">the applicant owner or designee; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">each employee of the applicant;</section></section><section prefix="(2)">the fixed business address of the applicant;</section><section prefix="(3)">a telephone number at which the applicant can be reached during normal business hours, and, if applicable, an electronic mail address;</section><section prefix="(4)">each address where the applicant has conducted any business during the 36 months before application;</section><section prefix="(5)">the driver's license number of the applicant owner or designee and each employee of the applicant; and</section><section prefix="(6)">the name of the insurer and policy number of the general liability insurance coverage required under &#xA7; 12.5-205 of this subtitle.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The application form provided by the Secretary shall contain a statement advising the applicant that willfully making a false statement on an application is a misdemeanor, subject to a fine or imprisonment or both, as provided under &#xA7; 12.5-504 of this title.</section>
  </text>
</law>
