<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gbr" order_by="gbr" level="1">Business Regulation</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gbr-11-804</section_number>
  <catch_line>The intent of this section is similar to that of the Interstate Horseracing Act of 1978, 15 U.S.C. &#xAE;..</catch_line>
  <order_by>804</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The intent of this section is similar to that of the Interstate Horseracing Act of 1978, 15 U.S.C. &#xA7;&#xA7; 3001 through 3007.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">If the Commission approves, a licensee may contract to hold pari-mutuel betting on a race that is held at an out-of-state track where betting on racing is lawful.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Pari-mutuel betting under this section may only occur:<section prefix="(1)">on a racing day when the Commission has authorized the licensee to hold racing; and</section><section prefix="(2)"><section prefix="(i)">at the track of the licensee;</section><section prefix="(ii)">at any track where pari-mutuel betting on races on the racing program of the licensee for that day is authorized; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">at a satellite simulcast facility.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The breakage and takeout for pari-mutuel betting under this section shall be computed in the way normally applicable to pari-mutuel betting on racing the licensee holds.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">From the takeout the licensee shall deduct:<section prefix="(i)">the State tax on all mutuel pools;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the amount to be paid under the contract to the out-of-state track; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">the cost of transmission.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The licensee shall then allocate the rest of the takeout in the way applicable to the racing that the licensee holds.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">A contract with an out-of-state track under this section is subject to the approval of the group that represents a majority of the owners and trainers who race horses at that track and the group that represents a majority of the applicable breeders in this State.</section>
  </text>
</law>
