<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gbr" order_by="" level="1">Business Regulation</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gbr-11-316</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>316</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Before a prospective buyer buys a majority controlling interest in a licensee, the Commission shall review the personal and financial background of the prospective buyer.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Commission shall adopt regulations to carry out this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The regulations shall:<section prefix="(i)">require a personal and financial background check of the prospective buyer;</section><section prefix="(ii)">specify a period of time to review the required personal and financial information before a purchase or transfer of racing days is made; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">require that notice and an invitation to comment be given to the Legislative Policy Committee at least 15 days before final approval of a purchase or transfer of racing days resulting from a purchase.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The background check shall include:<section prefix="(i)">a review by a certified public accountant of certified financial statements, including contingent or pledged liabilities, sufficient to determine the ability of the prospective buyer to buy and maintain the licensee;</section><section prefix="(ii)">an income statement for the most recent year;</section><section prefix="(iii)">a statement of financial and related records of any person in which the prospective buyer has at least a majority interest;</section><section prefix="(iv)">a disclosure of each financial interest in racing;</section><section prefix="(v)">a disclosure of each person who will have beneficial ownership of the licensee as a result of the purchase;</section><section prefix="(vi)">a criminal history records check under &#xA7; 11-312 of this subtitle; and</section><section prefix="(vii)">a character review.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
