<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gbr" order_by="" level="1">Business Regulation</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gbr-5-801</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>801</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">At the time of entering into a contract with a consumer for the sale of burial goods or services, registrants, permit holders, or any other person subject to the provisions of this title shall make the following written disclosures:<section prefix="(1)">the itemized cost for each service performed under the contract;</section><section prefix="(2)">a list of services incidental to burial that are not covered by the contract;</section><section prefix="(3)">a statement regarding the cemetery's policy on the use of independent monument companies; and</section><section prefix="(4)">the name, address, and telephone number for the State Office of Cemetery Oversight.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The disclosures required under subsection (a)(1), (2), and (3) of this section shall be conspicuously incorporated in the contract in 12-point type.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The disclosure required under subsection (a)(4) of this section shall be on a form separate from the contract and must be separately signed and dated by the consumer.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The disclosure must be signed and dated by the consumer.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The consumer must be provided with a copy of the contract and a copy of the form required under subsection (b)(2) of this section at the time of purchasing the burial goods or services.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The disclosure shall occur:<section prefix="(1)">not later than the first scheduled face-to-face contact with the purchaser or party representing the purchaser; or</section><section prefix="(2)">if no face-to-face contact occurs, at the time of the execution of the contract by the purchaser or party representing the purchaser.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The Director, by regulation, may prescribe the form and wording of the disclosure.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">If the purchase by the consumer includes a cemetery plot, the registered cemeterian, permit holder, or any other person subject to the provisions of this title shall provide the consumer with a copy of a location survey, performed by a licensed land surveyor, which indicates the location of the purchased plot within the cemetery, or by any other means approved by the Director.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">Registrants, permit holders, or any other person subject to the provisions of this title shall provide each buyer or prospective buyer with a general price list for the buyer or prospective buyer to keep which shall include:<section prefix="(1)">specific prices for:<section prefix="(i)">ground opening and closing;</section><section prefix="(ii)">extra depth interment;</section><section prefix="(iii)">interment of cremated remains; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">mausoleum entombment; and</section></section><section prefix="(2)">general price ranges for burial space or burial goods.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
