<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gbr" order_by="gbr" level="1">Business Regulation</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gbr-11-101</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this title the following words have the meanings indicated....</catch_line>
  <order_by>101</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this title the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Breakage" means the odd cents that remain after all successful bettors are paid to the next lowest multiple of 10 cents.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Central Repository" means the Criminal Justice Information System Central Repository of the Department of Public Safety and Correctional Services.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">"Commission" means the State Racing Commission.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"Handle" means the gross amount, less refunds, of money bet.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">"Harness racing" means the racing of horses that trot or pace in harness while pulling drivers in sulkies.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">"Intertrack betting" means:<section prefix="(1)">pari-mutuel betting at a receiving track in the State on a race that is:<section prefix="(i)">held live or by interstate simulcast at a sending track in the State; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">shown simultaneously by video signal at the receiving track; and</section></section><section prefix="(2)">transmission of the bets at the receiving track to the sending track.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(h)">"License" means a license issued by the Commission to hold a race meeting.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">"Licensee" means a person who has been awarded racing days for the current calendar year.</section>
    <section prefix="(j)">"Mile thoroughbred racing" means thoroughbred horse races at a track that is at least 1 mile long.</section>
    <section prefix="(k)">"Multiple mutuel pool" means a separate pari-mutuel betting pool in which an interest is represented by a single bet on 2 or more horses.</section>
    <section prefix="(l)">"Mutuel pool" includes a multiple mutuel pool and a regular mutuel pool.</section>
    <section prefix="(m)">"Pari-mutuel betting" means the system of betting in which those who successfully bet on horses that finish in specified positions share the mutuel pool, less the takeout and the breakage.</section>
    <section prefix="(n)">"Purse" means the prize money divided among the owners of horses that finish in specified positions in a race.</section>
    <section prefix="(o)">"Race meeting" means a period of time to hold racing that extends between specific dates over a number of racing days at a single track.</section>
    <section prefix="(p)">"Racing" includes:<section prefix="(1)">harness racing;</section><section prefix="(2)">mile thoroughbred racing;</section><section prefix="(3)">special thoroughbred racing;</section><section prefix="(4)">steeplechase or hurdle racing;</section><section prefix="(5)">flat racing; and</section><section prefix="(6)">quarter horse racing.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(q)">"Receiving track" means a track where pari-mutuel betting is done on races held at another track.</section>
    <section prefix="(r)">"Regular mutuel pool" means a separate pari-mutuel betting pool in which an interest is represented by a single bet on 1 horse.</section>
    <section prefix="(s)">"Sending track" means a track where a race is held live or by interstate simulcast and is sent simultaneously by video signal to a receiving track or a satellite simulcast facility under Subtitle 8, Part III of this title.</section>
    <section prefix="(t)">"Special thoroughbred racing" means thoroughbred horse racing held by the Maryland State Fair and Agricultural Society, Inc., or the Maryland-National Capital Park and Planning Commission.</section>
    <section prefix="(u)">"Takeout" means the part of the handle that is not returned to successful bettors but is otherwise allocated under this title.</section>
    <section prefix="(v)">"Track" means a place where racing is held.</section>
  </text>
</law>
