<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gbr" order_by="gbr" level="1">Business Regulation</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gbr-4-310</section_number>
  <catch_line>Subject to the hearing provisions of &#xA7; 4-311 of this subtitle, the Commission may deny a license to...</catch_line>
  <order_by>310</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Subject to the hearing provisions of &#xA7; 4-311 of this subtitle, the Commission may deny a license to an applicant, reprimand a licensee, or suspend or revoke a license if the applicant or licensee:<section prefix="(i)">fraudulently or deceptively obtains or attempts to obtain a license for the applicant or licensee or for another person;</section><section prefix="(ii)">fraudulently or deceptively uses a license;</section><section prefix="(iii)">violates this title; or</section><section prefix="(iv)">violates a regulation adopted under this title.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Instead of or in addition to reprimanding a licensee or suspending or revoking a license under this subsection, the Commission may impose a penalty of up to $5,000 for each violation.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">To determine the amount of the penalty imposed under this subsection, the Commission shall consider:<section prefix="1.">the seriousness of the violation;</section><section prefix="2.">the good faith of the violator;</section><section prefix="3.">any previous violations;</section><section prefix="4.">the assets of the violator; and</section><section prefix="5.">the harmful effect of the violation on the general public and the sporting industry.</section></section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">In addition to the grounds in subsection (a) of this section, the Commission may deny a boxer, kick boxer, or mixed martial arts contestant license to an applicant or suspend or revoke a boxer, kick boxer, or mixed martial arts contestant license if the Commission finds that the applicant or licensee is not fit, based on the neurological examination required under &#xA7;&#xA7; 4-304 and 4-314 of this subtitle and the recommendation of the physician who made the examination.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Subject to the hearing provisions of &#xA7; 4-311 of this subtitle, the Commission shall suspend or revoke a boxer, kick boxer, or mixed martial arts contestant license and the boxer, kick boxer, or mixed martial arts contestant shall forfeit the purse or other compensation from the contest if the boxer, kick boxer, or mixed martial arts contestant:<section prefix="(1)">refuses to submit to the urine test required under &#xA7; 4-315(b) of this subtitle; or</section><section prefix="(2)">submits a urine sample that tests positive for the presence of a controlled dangerous substance defined in &#xA7; 5-101 of the Criminal Law Article or other substance that the Commission prohibits by regulation.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Subject to the hearing provisions of &#xA7; 4-311 of this subtitle, the Commission shall deny a promoter license to an applicant or revoke a promoter license if the applicant or licensee:<section prefix="(i)">fails to pay the boxing and wrestling tax required under Title 6 or Title 13 of the Tax - General Article; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">holds or participates in a fake boxing, wrestling, or mixed martial arts contest.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If a person fails to pay the boxing and wrestling tax, the Commission shall:<section prefix="(i)">impose a penalty not exceeding $5,000; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">act to enforce the bond of the promoter.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
