<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gbr" order_by="" level="1">Business Regulation</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gbr-16-204</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>204</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">An applicant for a license to act as a manufacturer shall:<section prefix="(1)">submit an application to the Comptroller on the form and containing the information that the Comptroller requires; and</section><section prefix="(2)">pay to the Comptroller a fee of $25.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">An applicant for a license to act as a retailer shall:<section prefix="(i)">obtain the county license required under &#xA7; 16-301 of this title;</section><section prefix="(ii)">submit to the clerk an application for each permanent or temporary place of business located in the same enclosure and operated by the same applicant; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">pay to the clerk a fee of $30.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The application shall:<section prefix="(i)">be made on the form that the clerk requires; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">contain the information that the Comptroller requires.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">An applicant for a license to act as a storage warehouse shall:<section prefix="(1)">submit an application to the Comptroller on the form and containing the information that the Comptroller requires; and</section><section prefix="(2)">pay to the Comptroller a fee of $25.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">An applicant for a license to act as a subwholesaler shall:<section prefix="(1)">submit an application to the Comptroller on the form and containing the information that the Comptroller requires; and</section><section prefix="(2)">pay to the Comptroller a fee of:<section prefix="(i)">$500 for a 1-year term; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">the amount that results when $500 is prorated to the nearest month, if the application is for less than a 1-year term.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">An applicant for a license to act as a vending machine operator shall:<section prefix="(1)">obtain the county license required under &#xA7; 16-301 of this title;</section><section prefix="(2)">submit an application to the Comptroller on the form and containing the information that the Comptroller requires; and</section><section prefix="(3)">pay to the Comptroller a fee of $500.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">An applicant for a license to act as a wholesaler shall:<section prefix="(1)">submit an application to the Comptroller on the form and containing the information that the Comptroller requires; and</section><section prefix="(2)">pay to the Comptroller a fee of $750.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(g)">If a person has had a license revoked under &#xA7; 16-210 of this subtitle, the person may not reapply for a license within 1 year after the date when the prior license was revoked.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In addition to the license fee otherwise required under this section:<section prefix="(i)">an applicant for the initial issuance of a license issued by the Comptroller under this title shall pay to the Comptroller a nonrefundable application fee of $200; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">an applicant for renewal of a license issued by the Comptroller under this title shall pay to the Comptroller a renewal fee of $30.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The application and renewal fees required under this subsection do not apply to a license that is issued by the clerk or to a storage warehouse license application.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
