<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gbr" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="16-504" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gbr-16-504</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Except as provided in subsection (b) of this section, the Attorney General shall develop and make available for public inspection a directory listing all tobacco product manufacturers that have provided current and accurate certifications conforming to the requirements of &#xA7; 16-503 of this subtitle and all brand families that are listed in such certifications.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Attorney General may not include or retain in the directory the name or brand families of any nonparticipating manufacturer that fails to provide the required certification or whose certification the Attorney General determines is not in compliance with &#xA7; 16-503(c)(3) and (d) of this subtitle, unless the Attorney General has determined that the violation has been cured to the satisfaction of the Attorney General.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Neither a tobacco product manufacturer nor a brand family may be included or retained in the directory if the Attorney General concludes, in the case of a nonparticipating manufacturer, that:<section prefix="(i)">any escrow payment required under &#xA7; 16-403(a)(2) of this title (the Escrow Act)  for any period for any brand family, whether or not listed by such nonparticipating manufacturer, has not been fully paid into a qualified escrow fund governed by a qualified escrow agreement that has been approved by the Attorney General; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">any outstanding final judgment, including interest on the judgment, for a violation of the Escrow Act has not been fully satisfied for the brand family or the manufacturer.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Attorney General shall update the directory as necessary in order to correct mistakes and to add or remove a tobacco product manufacturer or brand family to keep the directory in conformity with the requirements of this subtitle.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">Each licensed wholesaler shall provide and update as necessary an electronic mail address to the Attorney General for the purpose of receiving any notifications that may be required by this subtitle.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A person may not:<section prefix="(1)">affix a stamp to a package or other container of cigarettes of a tobacco product manufacturer or brand family not included in the directory; or</section><section prefix="(2)">sell, offer or possess for sale in this State, or import for personal consumption in this State, cigarettes of a tobacco product manufacturer or brand family not included in the directory.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
