<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gbr" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="7-308" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gbr-7-308</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Subject to the hearing provisions of &#xA7; 7-309 of this subtitle, the Board may reprimand a licensee or suspend or revoke a license if the licensee or any owner, director, officer, member, partner, or agent of the licensee:<section prefix="(1)">makes any material misstatement in an application for a license;</section><section prefix="(2)">is convicted under the laws of the United States or of any state of:<section prefix="(i)">a felony; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">a misdemeanor that is directly related to the fitness and qualification of the person to engage in the collection agency business;</section></section><section prefix="(3)">in connection with the collection of any consumer claim:<section prefix="(i)">commits any fraud; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">engages in any illegal or dishonest activities;</section></section><section prefix="(4)">knowingly or negligently violates the Maryland Consumer Debt Collection Act; or</section><section prefix="(5)">fails to comply with a lawful order that the Board passes under this title.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">If the Board finds that a ground for suspension or revocation of a license applies to more than 1 place of business that the licensee operates, the Board may act against:<section prefix="(1)">each license of the licensee; or</section><section prefix="(2)">only the licenses to which the ground applies.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">In determining whether to reprimand a licensee or to suspend or revoke a license for a reason described in subsection (a)(2) of this section, the Board shall consider:<section prefix="(1)">the nature of the crime;</section><section prefix="(2)">the relationship of the crime to the activities authorized by the license;</section><section prefix="(3)">with  respect to a felony, the relevance of the conviction to the fitness and qualification of the licensee to engage in the collection agency business;</section><section prefix="(4)">the length of time since the conviction; and</section><section prefix="(5)">the behavior and activities of the licensee since the conviction.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
