<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gbr" order_by="gbr" level="1">Business Regulation</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gbr-15-207</section_number>
  <catch_line>The Department shall design a sign that states the following:...</catch_line>
  <order_by>207</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Department shall design a sign that states the following:</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The sign shall:<section prefix="(i)">be at least 3 by 5 inches in size;</section><section prefix="(ii)">contain the text required under paragraph (1) of this subsection in English, Spanish, and any other languages required by the federal Voting Rights Act;</section><section prefix="(iii)">draw attention to the phone number of the National Human Trafficking Resource Center Hotline by showing the phone number in bold type; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">be placed on the Department website.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A State, county, or municipal law enforcement agency may issue a civil citation to a lodging establishment requiring it to post prominently in each guest room for 1 year the sign that is identical to the notice required to be placed on the website of the Department under subsection (a) of this section, if the lodging establishment is located on property where arrests leading to convictions of prostitution, solicitation of a minor, or human trafficking under Title 11, Subtitle 13 of the Criminal Law Article have occurred.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A State, county, or municipal law enforcement agency shall consider any assistance it receives from a lodging establishment in an investigation leading to a conviction under paragraph (1) of this subsection in determining whether to issue a citation under this subsection.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The owner of a lodging establishment that violates subsection (b)(1) of this section is subject to a civil penalty not exceeding $1,000.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Each guest room that does not have a sign is not a separate violation.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
