<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gbr" order_by="gbr" level="1">Business Regulation</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gbr-14-222</section_number>
  <catch_line>After passing a stop order, the Commissioner promptly shall send to the applicant or registrant a no...</catch_line>
  <order_by>222</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">After passing a stop order, the Commissioner promptly shall send to the applicant or registrant a notice that:<section prefix="(1)">states that the stop order has been passed;</section><section prefix="(2)">states the reasons for the stop order; and</section><section prefix="(3)">informs the applicant or registrant of the right to a hearing under this section.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The applicant or registrant may submit to the Commissioner a written request for a hearing on the stop order.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Commissioner shall schedule a hearing within 15 business days after the Commissioner receives the request unless the applicant or registrant consents to a later date.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Commissioner may schedule a hearing even if the applicant or registrant does not request a hearing.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If a hearing is not requested and is not scheduled by the Commissioner and therefore is not held, the stop order remains in effect until the Commissioner modifies or vacates it.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If a hearing is held, after the hearing, the Commissioner may modify or vacate the stop order or extend it until the Commissioner makes a final determination.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Commissioner may modify or vacate a stop order if the Commissioner finds that:<section prefix="(i)">conditions have changed; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">it is otherwise in the public interest to vacate or modify the stop order.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
