<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gbr" order_by="" level="1">Business Regulation</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gbr-11-617</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>617</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">From a licensee's share of the takeout on each mutuel pool, the licensee whose average handle is $600,000 or less shall allocate 1.75% to increased purses.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">From the licensee's share of the takeout on each mutuel pool, a licensee whose average handle is over $150,000 shall allocate equally to the Sires Stakes Program and the Foaled Stakes Program of the Maryland Standardbred Race Fund the following amounts:<section prefix="(1)">on the first $125,000 of the average handle:<section prefix="(i)">0.50% of each regular mutuel pool;</section><section prefix="(ii)">0.50% of each multiple mutuel pool on 2 horses; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">1% of each multiple mutuel pool on 3 or more horses.</section></section><section prefix="(2)">on the rest of the average handle:<section prefix="(i)">1% of each regular mutuel pool;</section><section prefix="(ii)">1% of each multiple mutuel pool on 2 horses; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">1.5% of each multiple mutuel pool on 3 or more horses.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A licensee whose average handle is $150,000 or less shall allocate equally to the Sires Stakes Program and the Foaled Stakes Program of the Maryland Standardbred Race Fund:<section prefix="(1)">0.50% of each regular mutuel pool;</section><section prefix="(2)">0.50% of each multiple mutuel pool for 2 horses; and</section><section prefix="(3)">1% of each multiple mutuel pool for 3 or more horses.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">From the licensee's share of the takeout, the licensee shall allocate 0.50% on the part of an average handle over $150,000 to pay for:<section prefix="(1)">purses;</section><section prefix="(2)">personnel-related expenses, physical improvements, track maintenance, and indebtedness related to the track, including indebtedness for clubhouse and grandstand construction; and</section><section prefix="(3)">maintenance of proper living conditions in the backstretch.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">From the licensee's share of the takeout, the licensee shall allocate 0.25% of each mutuel pool to improve the facilities and services of the track and to increase marketing activity, so as to promote:<section prefix="(i)">increased attendance and pari-mutuel betting; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">enhanced well-being of the standardbred racing industry.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The General Assembly, by statute, may direct that the Commission not award in the following calendar year part or all of the racing days authorized under &#xA7; 11-610 of this subtitle to the licensee if the General Assembly finds that:<section prefix="(i)">the proposed use of the allocation under this subsection is inconsistent with the purposes specified in this section; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">the licensee has not spent the allocation in a way that is consistent with the proposal.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">From the licensee's share of the takeout on each multiple mutuel pool on 2 horses, the licensee shall allocate at least 1% of the mutuel pool as follows:<section prefix="(1)">one-half to purses; and</section><section prefix="(2)">one-half to personnel-related expenses, physical improvements, track maintenance, and indebtedness related to the track, including indebtedness for clubhouse and grandstand construction.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(g)">From the licensee's share of the takeout on each multiple mutuel pool on 3 or more horses, a licensee shall allocate at least 6.5% of each mutuel pool as follows:<section prefix="(1)">one-half to purses; and</section><section prefix="(2)">one-half to personnel-related expenses, physical improvements, track maintenance, and indebtedness related to the track, including indebtedness for clubhouse and grandstand construction.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
