<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gbr" order_by="gbr" level="1">Business Regulation</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gbr-9A-506</section_number>
  <catch_line>Any subdivision of the State which required a local license to provide heating, ventilation, air-con...</catch_line>
  <order_by>506</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Any subdivision of the State which required a local license to provide heating, ventilation, air-conditioning, or refrigeration services on or before January 1, 1990 may continue to require a local license for services performed within that subdivision.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A subdivision of the State which requires a local license to provide heating, ventilation, air-conditioning, or refrigeration services may not discriminate against applicants who are not residents of the subdivision.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A subdivision of the State which requires a local license to provide heating, ventilation, air-conditioning, or refrigeration services shall issue a local license to any individual licensed by the Board on receipt from the individual of any application and fee required by the subdivision of the State.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A subdivision of the State may not require an applicant for a local license to provide heating, ventilation, air-conditioning, or refrigeration services to take an examination if the applicant is licensed by the Board.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">In the event that any subdivision which requires a local license discontinues that requirement after the effective date of this Act, that subdivision may not thereafter adopt a license requirement.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A State license is required to provide heating, ventilation, air-conditioning, or refrigeration services anywhere within the State, whether or not the individual holds a local license.</section>
  </text>
</law>
