<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gbr" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="7-101" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gbr-7-101</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this title the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Board" means the State Collection Agency Licensing Board.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Collection agency" means a person who engages directly or indirectly in the business of:<section prefix="(1)"><section prefix="(i)">collecting for, or soliciting from another, a consumer claim; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">collecting a consumer claim the person owns, if the claim was in default when the person acquired it;</section></section><section prefix="(2)">collecting a consumer claim the person owns, using a name or other artifice that indicates that another party is attempting to collect the consumer claim;</section><section prefix="(3)">giving, selling, attempting to give or sell to another, or using, for collection of a consumer claim, a series or system of forms or letters that indicates directly or indirectly that a person other than the owner is asserting the consumer claim; or</section><section prefix="(4)">employing the services of an individual or business to solicit or sell a collection system to be used for collection of a consumer claim.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">"Commissioner" means the Commissioner of Financial Regulation.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"Consumer claim" means a claim that:<section prefix="(1)">is for money owed or said to be owed by a resident of the State; and</section><section prefix="(2)">arises from a transaction in which, for a family, household, or personal purpose, the resident sought or got credit, money, personal property, real property, or services.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">"License" means a license issued by the Board to do business as a collection agency.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">"Licensed collection agency" means a person who is licensed by the Board to do business as a collection agency.</section>
  </text>
</law>
