<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gbr" order_by="gbr" level="1">Business Regulation</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gbr-4-304.1</section_number>
  <catch_line>Each applicant for a license to participate as a boxer, kick boxer, or mixed martial arts contestant...</catch_line>
  <order_by>304.1</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Each applicant for a license to participate as a boxer, kick boxer, or mixed martial arts contestant in a contest shall present documentary evidence, satisfactory to the Commission, that:<section prefix="(1)">within the prior 30-day period, the applicant has been tested for the presence of:<section prefix="(i)">antibodies to the human immunodeficiency virus (HIV);</section><section prefix="(ii)">the antigen of virus hepatitis B; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">antibodies to virus hepatitis C; and</section></section><section prefix="(2)">the results of all tests are negative.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Whenever directed by the Commission, an individual who is licensed to participate as a boxer, kick boxer, or mixed martial arts contestant in a contest shall present documentary evidence, satisfactory to the Commission, that:<section prefix="(1)">within 30 days prior to participating in a contest, the individual has been tested for the presence of:<section prefix="(i)">antibodies to the human immunodeficiency virus (HIV);</section><section prefix="(ii)">the antigen of virus hepatitis B; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">antibodies to virus hepatitis C; and</section></section><section prefix="(2)">the results of all tests are negative.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A test for the presence of HIV conducted under the provisions of this section shall be conducted in accordance with the provisions of Title 4, Subtitle 3 and &#xA7; 18-336 of the Health - General Article.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If the Commission denies a license, suspends or revokes a license, denies renewal of a license, or does not allow an individual to participate in a contest because of the failure of the individual to comply with this section, the Commission shall keep the information confidential and may not disclose the reason for its action.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A person who violates paragraph (1) of this subsection is guilty of a misdemeanor and on conviction is subject to a fine not exceeding $1,000 for the first offense and not exceeding $5,000 for each subsequent conviction.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
