<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gbr" order_by="" level="1">Business Regulation</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gbr-17-1012</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>1012</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, "historic marker or plaque" means a marker, plaque, or tablet commemorating a historic person or event, or identifying a historic place, structure, or object.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">This section applies to all junk dealers, scrap metal processors, and antique dealers who are residents of the State.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Each junk dealer, scrap metal processor, or antique dealer subject to this section who purchases a historic marker or plaque shall register with the sheriff or other law enforcement official designated by the governing body of the county in which the business of the junk dealer, scrap metal processor, or antique dealer is located a complete description of the historic marker or plaque.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The description shall include:<section prefix="(i)">the date and time of purchase;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the name and address of the seller;</section><section prefix="(iii)">the license tag number of any vehicle used; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">a description of the historic marker or plaque, including the full text, any installation date, and the name of any installation sponsor.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The registration required under this section shall be made within 3 business days after the date of the purchase of the historic marker or plaque.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The sheriff or other law enforcement official promptly shall notify the Maryland Historical Trust with a copy to the junk dealer, scrap metal processor, or antique dealer who registered with the sheriff.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">A historic marker or plaque may not be sold or otherwise disposed of for a period of 30 days from the date of the notice required under subsection (d) of this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">A person who violates this section is guilty of a misdemeanor and, on conviction, is subject to a fine not exceeding $100.</section>
  </text>
</law>
