<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gbr" order_by="gbr" level="1">Business Regulation</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gbr-2-103</section_number>
  <catch_line>With the approval of the Governor, the Secretary shall appoint a deputy secretary....</catch_line>
  <order_by>103</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">With the approval of the Governor, the Secretary shall appoint a deputy secretary.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The deputy secretary:<section prefix="(i)">serves at the pleasure of the Secretary;</section><section prefix="(ii)">is entitled to the salary provided in the State budget; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">has the duties provided by law or delegated by the Secretary.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Secretary may employ a staff attached to the Office of the Secretary, in accordance with the State budget.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Each staff assistant in the Office of the Secretary in charge of a particular area of responsibility and each professional consultant is in the executive service, management service, or is a special appointment in the State Personnel Management System and is appointed by and serves at the pleasure of the Secretary.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Unless otherwise provided by law, the Secretary shall appoint and remove all other staff in the Office of the Secretary in accordance with the provisions of the State Personnel and Pensions Article.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The Secretary may review any personnel action taken by any unit in the Department. The Secretary may delegate to the head or governing body of any unit in the Department the power to approve any appointment or removal.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">Whenever the Secretary is authorized by law to make an appointment with the approval of the Governor, the Secretary may not remove the appointee without first obtaining the approval of the Governor.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
