<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gbr" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="14-203" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gbr-14-203</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">This subtitle applies to an offer to sell or sale of a franchise if:<section prefix="(1)">the franchisee must pay a franchise fee of more than $100; and</section><section prefix="(2)"><section prefix="(i)">the offeree or franchisee is a resident of the State;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the franchised business will be or is operated in the State;</section><section prefix="(iii)">the offer to sell is made in the State; or</section><section prefix="(iv)">the offer to buy is accepted in the State.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">For purposes of this section, an offer to sell is made in the State if the offer:<section prefix="(i)">originates from the State; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">is directed by the offeror to the State and is received at the place to which it is directed.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">For purposes of this section, an offer to sell is not made in the State only because the franchisor circulates or there is circulated on the franchisor's behalf in the State an advertisement in:<section prefix="(i)">a newspaper or other publication of general, regular, and paid circulation that has had two-thirds of its circulation outside the State during the past 12 months; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">a radio or television broadcast that originates outside the State and is received in the State.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">For purposes of this section, an offer to buy is accepted in the State when acceptance is communicated to the offeror in the State.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">For purposes of this section, acceptance is communicated to the offeror in the State when:<section prefix="(i)">the offeree directs acceptance to the offeror in the State reasonably believing the offeror to be in the State; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">the acceptance is received at the place to which it is directed.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">This subtitle does not apply to the renewal or extension of an existing franchise if there is no interruption in the operation of the franchised business.</section>
  </text>
</law>
