<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gbr" order_by="gbr" level="1">Business Regulation</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gbr-8-312</section_number>
  <catch_line>Except as otherwise provided in &#xA7; 10-226 of the State Government Article, before the Commission tak...</catch_line>
  <order_by>312</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Except as otherwise provided in &#xA7; 10-226 of the State Government Article, before the Commission takes any final action under &#xA7; 8-311 of this subtitle, or if requested under &#xA7; 8-620(c) of this title, it shall give the person against whom the action is contemplated an opportunity for a hearing before the Commission or, as provided under &#xA7; 8-313 of this subtitle, a hearing board.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Commission shall give notice and hold the hearing in accordance with Title 10, Subtitle 2 of the State Government Article.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Commission may administer oaths in a proceeding under this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The hearing notice to be given to the person shall be sent at least 10 days before the hearing by certified mail to the business address of the licensee on record with the Commission.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">For purposes of this subsection, the State is divided into:<section prefix="(i)">the region that includes Allegany, Carroll, Frederick, Garrett, and Washington counties;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the region that includes Anne Arundel, Calvert, Charles, and St. Mary's counties;</section><section prefix="(iii)">the region that includes Baltimore City and Baltimore and Howard counties;</section><section prefix="(iv)">the region that includes Caroline, Cecil, Dorchester, Harford, Kent, Queen Anne's, Somerset, Talbot, Wicomico, and Worcester counties; and</section><section prefix="(v)">the region that includes Montgomery and Prince George's counties.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Commission shall set the time and place of the hearing but shall hold the hearing in the appropriate region to accommodate the needs of:<section prefix="(i)">disabled witnesses;</section><section prefix="(ii)">indigent witnesses; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">a majority of witnesses.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The person may be represented at the hearing by counsel.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">In connection with a proceeding under this section, the Commission may:<section prefix="(1)">issue subpoenas for the attendance of witnesses to testify or to produce evidence; and</section><section prefix="(2)">take testimony in the same manner and with the same fees and compensation for mileage as provided in civil cases in the State.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(h)">If, after due notice, the person against whom the action is contemplated does not appear, nevertheless the Commission may hear and determine the matter.</section>
  </text>
</law>
