<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gbr" order_by="" level="1">Business Regulation</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gbr-17-1804</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>1804</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Except as otherwise provided in this subtitle, a person must have a trader's license whenever the person:<section prefix="(1)">does business as a trader in the State; or</section><section prefix="(2)">does business as an exhibitor in the State.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A separate trader's license is required for each store or fixed place of business that a person operates in the State.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">This section does not apply to:<section prefix="(1)">a grower, maker, or manufacturer of goods;</section><section prefix="(2)">a nonresident traveling salesperson, sample merchant, or representative of a foreign mercantile or manufacturing business while selling to or soliciting an order from a licensed trader in the State; or</section><section prefix="(3)">a private individual while publicly selling the individual's personal effects on the individual's property, if the individual holds only 1 sale not exceeding 14 consecutive days in a calendar year.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">An exhibitor need not get a trader's license for a show if the show is promoted by:<section prefix="(i)">a church, as defined in &#xA7; 5-301(b) of the Corporations and Associations Article;</section><section prefix="(ii)">a governmental unit;</section><section prefix="(iii)">an amateur radio organization;</section><section prefix="(iv)">an antique vehicle, machine, and equipment organization;</section><section prefix="(v)">a volunteer fire department or rescue squad; or</section><section prefix="(vi)">a model train collectors' association.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">An exhibitor need not get a trader's license for a show if the exhibitor gives to the promoter an exhibitor's affidavit stating that the exhibitor:<section prefix="(i)">receives less than 10% of the exhibitor's annual income from selling the kind of goods that the exhibitor will display and sell at the show; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">has not participated in more than three shows, not including participation in one show sponsored by a national organization that is exempt from taxation under &#xA7; 501(c)(3) of the Internal Revenue Code, during the previous 365 days.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">An exhibitor at an antique show, coin show, or collector show need not get a trader's license for the show if the exhibitor gives to the promoter an exhibitor's affidavit stating that the exhibitor:<section prefix="(i)">will display and sell at the show;</section><section prefix="(ii)">receives less than 10% of the exhibitor's annual income in the State from selling the kind of goods that the exhibitor will display and sell at the show; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">has not participated in more than three antique shows, coin shows, or collector shows in the State during the previous 365 days.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">An exhibitor who has a trader's license need not get an additional trader's license for a show if, before the show, the exhibitor gives the promoter a photocopy of the trader's license.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
