<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gbr" order_by="" level="1">Business Regulation</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gbr-9A-309</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>309</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Unless the license is renewed for a 2-year term as provided in this section, a license expires on the first October 1 that comes:<section prefix="(1)">after the effective date of the license; and</section><section prefix="(2)">in an odd-numbered year.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Before the license expires, the licensee may renew it for an additional 2-year term, if the licensee:<section prefix="(1)">otherwise is entitled to be granted a license;</section><section prefix="(2)">pays to the Board a renewal fee established by the Board; and</section><section prefix="(3)">submits:<section prefix="(i)">proof of insurance as provided by &#xA7; 9A-402 of this title; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">a renewal application in the form that the Board provides.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Board shall renew the license of and issue a renewal certificate to each licensee who meets the requirements of this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">At the time of renewal, a licensee who holds a valid heating, ventilation, air-conditioning, and refrigeration contractor license may apply to the Board for inactive status, during which time the licensee may not provide heating, ventilation, air-conditioning, or refrigeration services in the State.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If an individual wishes to renew a license on inactive status, the individual shall meet the requirements of subsection (b)(1), (2), and (3)(ii) of this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">To return to active status the licensee must meet the renewal requirements of subsection (b) of this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">Unless a licensee on inactive status renews the license as provided in this section, or reactivates the license as provided in this section, the license expires on the first October 1 that comes:<section prefix="(i)">after the inactive status certificate has been issued to the licensee; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">in an odd-numbered year.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If application for restoration is made within 90 days of expiration of a license, the license may be restored only on payment of a renewal fee.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If application for restoration is not made within the 90-day period, the Board may require compliance with the process for initial applications as if the applicant had never been licensed.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">Except as provided in subsection (g) of this section, a license issued under this title is not transferable.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">On the death of a licensed heating, ventilation, air-conditioning, and refrigeration contractor, the personal representative of the deceased licensee may retain the license for up to 6 months for the purpose of winding up the business.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">In cases of extreme hardship, the Board may allow the personal representative to retain the license for an additional period not to exceed 24 months upon a good faith showing that the personal representative has:<section prefix="(i)">acted diligently to conclude the business of the deceased licensee; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">complied with the provisions of this title.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(h)">The Secretary may determine that licenses issued under this subtitle shall expire on a staggered basis.</section>
  </text>
</law>
