<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gbr" order_by="" level="1">Business Regulation</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gbr-3-402</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>402</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Commissioner shall inspect:<section prefix="(1)">annually, each amusement attraction at an amusement park;</section><section prefix="(2)">annually, each inflatable amusement attraction in which, while in contact with the attraction, an individual is 4 feet or more above the ground;</section><section prefix="(3)">except for an inflatable amusement attraction, each amusement attraction, if moved, before it begins operation at another location; and</section><section prefix="(4)">each new or modified amusement attraction before it begins public operation.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">An amusement owner shall notify the Commissioner before operating an amusement attraction that is new, modified, or reconstructed.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">An owner or lessee of a carnival or fair shall:<section prefix="(i)">notify the Commissioner in writing at least 30 days before opening the carnival or fair at each location; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">give the Commissioner immediate notice of a change in the schedule of locations or dates if the schedule changes after notification.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Commissioner shall issue to an amusement owner a certificate of inspection for each amusement attraction at a carnival, fair, or amusement park if:<section prefix="(1)">after inspection the Commissioner finds that the amusement attraction complies with this title and the regulations adopted under it; and</section><section prefix="(2)">the amusement owner submits to the Commissioner a certificate of insurance for the amusement attraction as required by &#xA7; 3-403 of this subtitle.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A certificate of inspection for an amusement attraction at an amusement park expires not more than 1 year after the date of issuance.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A certificate of inspection for an amusement attraction at a fair or carnival expires not more than 30 days after the date of issuance.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A certificate of inspection for an inflatable amusement attraction in which, while in contact with the attraction, an individual is 4 feet or more above the ground expires not more than 1 year after the date of issuance.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The certificate of inspection shall be posted in plain view on the amusement attraction.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">On information or notification of an accident or complaint that involves an amusement attraction, the Commissioner shall investigate the accident or complaint and inspect the amusement attraction.</section>
  </text>
</law>
