<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gbr" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="6-205" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gbr-6-205</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Secretary of State or the Secretary's designee may investigate an alleged violation of this title.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">In the course of any examination, investigation, or hearing, the Secretary of State may subpoena witnesses, administer oaths, examine an individual under oath, serve written interrogatories, and compel production of records, books, papers, and other documents.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">In the course of any examination, investigation, or hearing, the legal counsel for the Office of the Secretary of State may administer oaths and examine an individual under oath.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">Information obtained under this subsection is not admissible in a subsequent criminal proceeding against the person who provided the information.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">If the Secretary of State finds or has reasonable grounds to believe that a charitable organization, charitable representative, or public safety solicitor has violated this title, the Secretary of State may take 1 or more of the following actions:<section prefix="(1)">by mediation with the apparent violators and any representatives they may choose to assist them, enter into a written assurance of discontinuance, written assurance of voluntary compliance, or other settlement agreement with the apparent violators, in accordance with subsection (c) of this section;</section><section prefix="(2)">summarily issue a cease and desist order to the violator, if the Secretary of State:<section prefix="(i)">finds that this title has been violated and that the public health, safety, or welfare requires emergency action; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">gives the violator written notice of the order, the reasons for the order, and the right of the violator to request a hearing under subsection (g) of this section; or</section></section><section prefix="(3)">refer the matter to:<section prefix="(i)">the Attorney General for civil enforcement; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">the appropriate State's Attorney for prosecution.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A settlement agreement under subsection (b)(1) of this section may include one or more of the following stipulations or conditions:<section prefix="(1)">payment by the apparent violator of the cost of the investigation;</section><section prefix="(2)">payment by the apparent violator of civil penalties a court could order under this title;</section><section prefix="(3)">payment by the apparent violator of refunds to donors a court could order under this title;</section><section prefix="(4)">payment by the apparent violator of contributions received to charitable or public safety beneficiaries or for charitable or public safety purposes consistent with the beneficiaries named or purposes represented in the charitable or public safety solicitations which generated the contributions; or</section><section prefix="(5)">any other stipulation, condition, or remedy that will correct a violation of this title.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">An agreement under this section is for conciliation purposes only and does not constitute an admission by any party that the law has been violated.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">It is a violation of this title to fail to adhere to any provision contained in a settlement agreement.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A failure of the Secretary of State to enforce a violation of any provision of a settlement agreement does not constitute a waiver of that or any other provision, or of any right of the Secretary of State.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">On referral by the Secretary of State, the Attorney General may sue in the Circuit Court for Anne Arundel County for an order that:<section prefix="(1)">restrains further violation of this title;</section><section prefix="(2)">restrains the defendant from making further charitable or public safety solicitations in the State;</section><section prefix="(3)">except as provided under &#xA7; 6-5A-11 of this title, recovers for the State a civil penalty not to exceed $5,000 for each willful violation of this title;</section><section prefix="(4)">except as provided under &#xA7; 6-5A-11 of this title, recovers for the State a civil penalty not to exceed $3,000 for each grossly negligent violation of this title;</section><section prefix="(5)">enforces compliance with this title; or</section><section prefix="(6)">secures any other appropriate relief, including:<section prefix="(i)">refunds to donors; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">payment of the charitable or public safety contributions received by the solicitor to charitable or public safety purposes or beneficiaries consistent with the purposes represented or beneficiaries named in the charitable or public safety solicitations which generated the contributions.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If the Secretary of State issues a cease and desist order to a person, the person may request a hearing from the Secretary of State.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Within 30 days after a request is submitted, the Secretary of State shall hold a hearing in accordance with Title 10, Subtitle 2 of the State Government Article.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
