<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gbr" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="11-825" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gbr-11-825</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">A satellite simulcast facility:<section prefix="(1)">shall be in premises owned or leased by a permit holder;</section><section prefix="(2)">may not be within a 35-mile radius of any mile thoroughbred track or harness track unless approved by the track licensee, the group that represents a majority of the applicable owners and trainers licensed in the State and the group that represents a majority of the applicable breeders in the State, considered separately;</section><section prefix="(3)">unless the track agrees otherwise, may not operate during hours on those days that racing with pari-mutuel betting is permitted at a racetrack located in this State within a 35-mile radius of the satellite simulcast facility; and</section><section prefix="(4)">shall offer pari-mutuel betting facilities and amenities that the Commission finds are:<section prefix="(i)">comparable to those available in the sports palace facilities of the mile thoroughbred racing licensees including:</section><section prefix="(ii)">appropriate for the area where the satellite simulcast facility is located.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A mile thoroughbred racing licensee or a harness racing licensee shall own or lease the pari-mutuel betting equipment at a satellite simulcast facility and shall, with its employees, operate the equipment.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A mile thoroughbred racing licensee or a harness racing licensee shall submit to the Commission all contracts and agreements relating to satellite simulcast betting under this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Commission shall periodically be assured by permit holders that facilities continue to meet the requirements of this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The Commission shall inspect satellite simulcast facilities at least four times each year to determine if the permit holders are continuing to comply with the provisions of this section.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The inspections under this subsection shall include evaluations of the financial and physical conditions of each satellite simulcast facility.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">If the Commission finds that a permit holder is not complying with the provisions of this section, the Commission may impose a penalty on the permit holder similar to those penalties levied on licensees as provided under &#xA7; 11-308 of this title.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
