<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gbr" order_by="gbr" level="1">Business Regulation</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gbr-10-315</section_number>
  <catch_line>A person who sells motor fuel at retail shall display signs in accordance with this section....</catch_line>
  <order_by>315</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">A person who sells motor fuel at retail shall display signs in accordance with this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">All dispensing equipment for motor fuel shall be marked conspicuously to show in numerals of equal size the price, including taxes, of a gallon of the motor fuel offered for sale.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If numerals that show a fractional cent are used, the combined height and width of the numerator and denominator shall equal the height and width of the other numerals used.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A sign or other means on the premises and approaches to a retail outlet that advertises the retail price of motor fuel:<section prefix="(i)">may list the price and each tax separately if the listing of the total of the price and all taxes is the same size as the separate listing of the price; but</section><section prefix="(ii)">shall list the total of the price and all taxes by numerals of uniform size.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">In the listing of the total of the price and all taxes, a denominator need not be used to indicate a fraction, but:<section prefix="(i)">if a denominator is used, the numerator and denominator combined shall be the same size as the numeral that indicates the whole number; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">if a denominator is not used, the numerator shall be the same size as the numeral that indicates the whole number.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">If the retail price of motor fuel is advertised on a sign or by other means on the premises of and approaches to the retail outlet, the grade designation displayed for any motor fuel in the advertisement shall be the same as the grade designation that is required to be displayed for that motor fuel on the retail dispensing pump as specified by the Comptroller.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This subsection does not apply to a retail service station dealer who operates with not more than 3 dispensing units that combined have not more than 6 nozzles.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Each retail service station dealer shall keep a sign on the premises that:<section prefix="1.">states the lowest price for a whole measurement unit of regular gasoline sold on the premises;</section><section prefix="2.">states the unit of measurement used; and</section><section prefix="3.">is readable by passing motorists.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The sign required under subparagraph (i) of this paragraph also may state the lowest price for a whole measurement unit of diesel and other motor fuel products sold on the premises.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">All numerals on the sign shall:<section prefix="(i)">be uniform;</section><section prefix="(ii)">be at least 8 inches high and 3.5 inches wide; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">have a brush stroke of at least 1 inch.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">A numeral in a fraction or a letter shall be at least one-third the height of a numeral that indicates a whole number.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">If a new or additional sign is required to comply with this subsection, the supplier of the gasoline shall provide the sign and numerals without cost to the retail service station dealer.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">A sign required at a service station by this section or any other State or federal law is exempt from the provisions of a local law, ordinance, or regulation for the purpose of determining:<section prefix="(1)">the total number of signs permitted; and</section><section prefix="(2)">the area of signs permitted.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(g)">Except as provided in subsection (f) of this section, signs regulated by this section or other State law or by federal law may be regulated by the local zoning authority and shall be consistent with the local law, ordinance, or regulation governing signs.</section>
  </text>
</law>
