<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gbr" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="8-303" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gbr-8-303</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">An applicant for a license shall:<section prefix="(i)">submit to the Commission an application on the form that the Commission provides;</section><section prefix="(ii)">submit to the Commission with the license application proof of compliance with the insurance requirement of &#xA7; 8-302.1 of this subtitle, if the applicant is applying for a contractor license;</section><section prefix="(iii)">pay into the Fund the fee required under &#xA7; 8-404(a) of this title, if the applicant is applying for a contractor license; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">pay to the Commission an application fee.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The application fee:<section prefix="(i)">for a contractor license is $250 for each place of business of the contractor;</section><section prefix="(ii)">for a subcontractor license is $150; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">for a salesperson license is $100.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The fee for processing an application is $20.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">In addition to any other information required on an application form, the form shall require:<section prefix="(1)">for an individual applicant, the name and address of the applicant;</section><section prefix="(2)">for a corporate applicant, the name and address of each officer;</section><section prefix="(3)">for a partnership applicant, the name and address of each partner;</section><section prefix="(4)">for a joint venture applicant, the name and address of each party to the joint venture;</section><section prefix="(5)">if the applicant acts as a contractor or subcontractor through a corporation or limited partnership, the name and address of the resident agent of the corporation or limited partnership in the State;</section><section prefix="(6)">if the applicant is applying for a contractor license or subcontractor license, a complete description of the nature of the contracting business of the applicant;</section><section prefix="(7)">if the applicant is applying for a salesperson license, a complete description of the duties of the applicant;</section><section prefix="(8)">a record of the applicant's experience in the field of home improvement or other construction work, including dates when and addresses where the applicant has resided and done business;</section><section prefix="(9)">if the applicant provides lead paint abatement services, the Department of the Environment lead paint abatement accreditation number and accreditation expiration date;</section><section prefix="(10)">whether the applicant has ever held a professional or vocational license in this or any other state; and</section><section prefix="(11)">whether the applicant has had a professional or vocational license denied, suspended, or revoked.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">To evaluate the qualifications of an applicant for a license, the Commission may ask the applicant for:<section prefix="(1)">information about the applicant's character, experience, and financial stability; and</section><section prefix="(2)">any other information that the Commission needs.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">If the applicant is applying for a contractor license, the applicant shall:<section prefix="(1)">have submitted to the Commission, by a credit reporting agency approved by the Commission, a credit report that contains the information required by the Commission; or</section><section prefix="(2)">have paid to the Commission or the Commission's designee a credit report fee in an amount not to exceed the cost charged by a credit reporting agency approved by the Commission to obtain a credit report that contains the information required by the Commission.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">Financial information that an applicant submits to the Commission:<section prefix="(1)">is confidential and is not a public record; but</section><section prefix="(2)">if relevant, is admissible as evidence in an administrative or judicial proceeding.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">Notwithstanding subsection (a) of this section, an applicant that is incorporated or has its principal office in another state shall pay to the Commission the fee imposed in that state on a similar nonresident business if that fee is higher than the application fee under subsection (a) of this section.</section>
  </text>
</law>
