<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gbr" order_by="gbr" level="1">Business Regulation</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gbr-11-312</section_number>
  <catch_line>On request of the Commission, the following individuals shall give the Commission their fingerprints...</catch_line>
  <order_by>312</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">On request of the Commission, the following individuals shall give the Commission their fingerprints:<section prefix="(1)">each individual licensee;</section><section prefix="(2)">each individual member of an unincorporated association that is a licensee;</section><section prefix="(3)">each officer or director of a corporation that is a licensee;</section><section prefix="(4)">each employee of a licensee who actively participates in the racing action of the licensee;</section><section prefix="(5)">each individual who actively participates in the racing action of a licensee, including each agent, blacksmith, driver, apprentice jockey, jockey, manager, owner, trainer, stable employee, and veterinarian;</section><section prefix="(6)">each member of the Commission;</section><section prefix="(7)">the Executive Director of the Commission;</section><section prefix="(8)">each employee of the Commission under &#xA7;&#xA7; 11-206 and 11-207 of this title; and</section><section prefix="(9)">each individual who is subject to &#xA7; 11-316 of this subtitle.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Commission shall:<section prefix="(1)">apply to the Central Repository for a State and national criminal history records check for each individual listed in subsection (a) of this section; and</section><section prefix="(2)">as part of the application for a criminal history records check, submit to the Central Repository:<section prefix="(i)">a complete set of the individual's legible fingerprints taken on a form approved by the Director of the Central Repository; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">the fee authorized under &#xA7; 10-221(b)(7) of the Criminal Procedure Article for access to Maryland criminal history records.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In addition to a State criminal history records check under this section, the Commission may require an individual listed in subsection (a) of this section to obtain a criminal history records check from the Federal Bureau of Investigation, through the Central Repository.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">For each applicant who is required by the Commission to obtain a criminal history records check from the Federal Bureau of Investigation under paragraph (1) of this subsection, the Commission shall apply to the Central Repository for a national criminal history records check.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">As part of the application for a national criminal history records check, the Commission shall submit to the Central Repository:<section prefix="(i)">a complete set of the individual's legible fingerprints taken on a form approved by the Director of the Federal Bureau of Investigation; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">the mandatory processing fee required by the Federal Bureau of Investigation for a national criminal history records check.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In accordance with &#xA7;&#xA7; 10-201 through 10-234 of the Criminal Procedure Article, the Central Repository shall forward to the individual and the Commission the individual's criminal history record information.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Information obtained from the Central Repository under this section shall be:<section prefix="(i)">confidential and may not be disseminated; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">used only for the purpose authorized by this section.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The subject of a criminal history records check under this section may contest the contents of the printed statement issued by the Central Repository as provided in &#xA7; 10-223 of the Criminal Procedure Article.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
