<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gbr" order_by="gbr" level="1">Business Regulation</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gbr-11-515</section_number>
  <catch_line>Except as provided in &#xA7; 11-516 of this subtitle, the takeout that a licensee deducts from the handl...</catch_line>
  <order_by>515</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Except as provided in &#xA7; 11-516 of this subtitle, the takeout that a licensee deducts from the handle of a race shall be allocated in accordance with this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A licensee shall:<section prefix="(1)">keep 50% of the breakage;</section><section prefix="(2)">allocate 45% of the breakage for purses; and</section><section prefix="(3)">allocate 5% of the breakage to the Maryland-Bred Race Fund.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">From the amount that a licensee deducts from each regular mutuel pool, the licensee shall:<section prefix="(1)">keep 7.70% of each regular mutuel pool, from which the licensee shall pay 0.25% of each regular mutuel pool to the Maryland Race Track Employees Pension Fund;</section><section prefix="(2)">allocate 0.32% of each regular mutuel pool to the Commission for State tax;</section><section prefix="(3)">allocate 1.10% of each regular mutuel pool to the Maryland-Bred Race Fund;</section><section prefix="(4)">allocate 7.70% of each regular mutuel pool for purses;</section><section prefix="(5)">allocate 0.18% of each regular mutuel pool as an additional amount for purses; and</section><section prefix="(6)">allocate 1% of each regular mutuel pool paid to the Maryland Million, Ltd., for purses of Maryland Million races.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">From the amount that a licensee deducts from each multiple mutuel pool on 2 horses, the licensee shall:<section prefix="(1)">keep 8.70% of each multiple mutuel pool, from which the licensee shall pay 0.25% of each multiple mutuel pool to the Maryland Race Track Employees Pension Fund;</section><section prefix="(2)">allocate 0.32% of each multiple mutuel pool to the Commission for State tax;</section><section prefix="(3)">allocate 1.10% of each multiple mutuel pool to the Maryland-Bred Race Fund;</section><section prefix="(4)">allocate 8.70% of each multiple mutuel pool for purses;</section><section prefix="(5)">allocate 0.18% of each multiple mutuel pool as an additional amount for purses; and</section><section prefix="(6)">allocate 2% of each multiple mutuel pool paid to the Maryland Million, Ltd., for purses of Maryland Million races.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">From the amount that a licensee deducts from each multiple mutuel pool on 3 or more horses, the licensee shall:<section prefix="(1)">keep 11.70% of each multiple mutuel pool, from which the licensee shall pay 0.25% of each multiple mutuel pool to the Maryland Race Track Employees Pension Fund;</section><section prefix="(2)">allocate 0.32% of each multiple mutuel pool to the Commission for State tax;</section><section prefix="(3)">allocate 1.10% of each multiple mutuel pool to the Maryland-Bred Race Fund;</section><section prefix="(4)">allocate 11.70% of each multiple mutuel pool for purses;</section><section prefix="(5)">allocate 0.18% of each multiple mutuel pool as an additional amount for purses; and</section><section prefix="(6)">allocate 0.75% of each multiple mutuel pool paid to the Maryland Million, Ltd., for purses of Maryland Million races.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
