<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gbr" order_by="gbr" level="1">Business Regulation</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gbr-5-707</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this section, "seller's account" means:...</catch_line>
  <order_by>707</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, "seller's account" means:<section prefix="(1)">the total of specific funds deposited from all preneed burial contracts of a seller commingled in a single fund; and</section><section prefix="(2)">any income derived from investing the money in the fund.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Trust accounts shall be administered as this subtitle provides.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as otherwise provided in this subtitle, a trustee appointed under this subtitle is subject to the law that is generally applicable to trustees.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If a trustee appointed under this subtitle is not located in the State, the agreement between the seller and the trustee expressly shall incorporate this subtitle.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A trustee:<section prefix="(1)">may rely on all certifications made under or required by this subtitle; and</section><section prefix="(2)">is not liable to any person for that reliance.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A trustee may invest money of a trust account in any security that is a lawful investment for a fiduciary, including a time deposit or certificate of deposit issued by the trustee.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Except as otherwise provided in this subtitle, to ensure that money in the trust account is adequate, the trust income shall:<section prefix="(i)">remain in the trust account;</section><section prefix="(ii)">be reinvested and compounded; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">be disbursed only for payment of appropriate trustee's fees, commissions, and other costs of the trust account.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A seller, on written notice to the trustee and in accordance with the agreement between them, may transfer the seller's account to another trustee.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A trustee, on written notice to the seller and in accordance with the agreement between them, may transfer the seller's account to another trustee.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
