<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gbr" order_by="" level="1">Business Regulation</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gbr-16-505</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>505</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Any nonresident or foreign nonparticipating manufacturer that has not registered to do business in the State as a foreign corporation or business entity shall, as a condition precedent to having its brand families included or retained in the directory described in &#xA7; 16-504 of this subtitle, appoint and continually engage without interruption the services of an agent in the United States to act as an agent for the service of process on the nonresident or foreign nonparticipating manufacturer.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Any process and any action or proceeding against the nonresident or foreign nonparticipating manufacturer concerning or arising out of the enforcement of this subtitle or the Escrow Act may be served in any manner authorized by law.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The service of process shall constitute legal and valid service of process on the nonparticipating manufacturer. The nonparticipating manufacturer shall provide, to the satisfaction of the Attorney General, the name, address, phone number, and proof of the appointment and availability of the agent to the Attorney General.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The nonparticipating manufacturer shall provide:<section prefix="(i)">notice to the Attorney General at least 30 calendar days prior to termination of the authority of an agent; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">proof to the satisfaction of the Attorney General of the appointment of a new agent not less than 5 calendar days prior to the termination of an existing agent appointment.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If an agent terminates an agency appointment, the nonparticipating manufacturer shall:<section prefix="(i)">notify the Attorney General of the termination within 5 calendar days; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">include proof to the satisfaction of the Attorney General of the appointment of a new agent.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
