<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gbr" order_by="" level="1">Business Regulation</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gbr-16.5-203</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>203</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">An applicant for a license to act as a licensed other tobacco products manufacturer shall:<section prefix="(1)">submit an application to the Comptroller on the form and containing the information that the Comptroller requires; and</section><section prefix="(2)">pay to the Comptroller a fee of $25.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">An applicant for a license to act as an other tobacco products retailer or a tobacconist:<section prefix="(i)">shall obtain a county license by submitting to the clerk an application for each permanent or temporary place of business located in the same enclosure and operated by the same applicant; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, shall pay to the clerk a fee of $15.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A person who has a license issued under Title 16 of this article to act as a cigarette retailer or to act as a special cigarette retailer is not required to pay the license fee.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The application shall:<section prefix="(i)">be made on the form that the clerk requires; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">contain the information that the Comptroller requires.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">An applicant for a license to act as an other tobacco products storage warehouse shall:<section prefix="(1)">submit an application to the Comptroller on the form and containing the information that the Comptroller requires; and</section><section prefix="(2)">pay to the Comptroller a fee of $25.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">An applicant for a license to act as an other tobacco products wholesaler shall:<section prefix="(i)">submit an application to the Comptroller on the form and containing the information that the Comptroller requires; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, pay to the Comptroller a fee of $250.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A person who has a license issued under Title 16 of this article to act as a cigarette wholesaler is not required to pay the license fee.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">A licensee shall display a license in the way that the Comptroller requires by regulation.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">If a person has had a license revoked under &#xA7; 16.5-208 of this subtitle, the person may not reapply for a license within 1 year after the date when the prior license was revoked.</section>
  </text>
</law>
