<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gbr" order_by="" level="1">Business Regulation</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gbr-9-101</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>101</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this title the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Client" means an individual who seeks employment through an employment agency.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Commissioner" means the Commissioner of Labor and Industry.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Employment agency" means a person who, for a fee:<section prefix="(i)">obtains, offers to obtain, or attempts to obtain:<section prefix="1.">an employee for a person who seeks an employee; or</section><section prefix="2.">employment for a client;</section></section><section prefix="(ii)">provides to a client information to enable the client to obtain employment;</section><section prefix="(iii)">obtains, offers to obtain, or attempts to obtain employment or an engagement in connection with an entertainment, exhibition, or performance, including:<section prefix="1.">a ballet;</section><section prefix="2.">a circus;</section><section prefix="3.">a concert;</section><section prefix="4.">the legitimate theater;</section><section prefix="5.">modeling;</section><section prefix="6.">a motion picture;</section><section prefix="7.">an opera;</section><section prefix="8.">a phonograph recording;</section><section prefix="9.">the radio;</section><section prefix="10.">a transcription;</section><section prefix="11.">television;</section><section prefix="12.">the variety field; or</section><section prefix="13.">vaudeville; or</section></section><section prefix="(iv)"><section prefix="1.">obtains, offers to obtain, or attempts to obtain an alien labor certification or immigrant visa for an individual; and</section><section prefix="2.">participates directly or indirectly in the recruitment or supply of an individual who resides outside of the continental United States for employment in the continental United States.</section></section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Employment agency" does not include a person who merely:<section prefix="(i)">conducts a business that directly employs individuals to provide part-time or temporary services to another person;</section><section prefix="(ii)">as a lawyer, directly obtains an immigrant visa for an individual;</section><section prefix="(iii)">conducts a business that:<section prefix="1.">receives a fee that is paid wholly by an employer;</section><section prefix="2.">does not collect money from an individual seeking employment; and</section><section prefix="3.">does not require an individual seeking employment to make a contract; or</section></section><section prefix="(iv)">operates a nursing referral service agency that is licensed under Title 19, Subtitle 4B of the Health - General Article.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
