<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gbr" order_by="gbr" level="1">Business Regulation</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gbr-6-407</section_number>
  <catch_line>A charitable organization that collects less than $25,000 in charitable contributions from the publi...</catch_line>
  <order_by>407</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">A charitable organization that collects less than $25,000 in charitable contributions from the public in a year need not pay an annual fee, except that, if the charitable organization uses a professional solicitor, it shall pay an annual fee of $50.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Each charitable organization that submits a separate registration statement and collects at least $25,000 in charitable contributions from the public in a year shall pay an annual fee based on the charitable contributions collected.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The annual fee shall be:<section prefix="(i)">$50, if charitable contributions from the public are at least $25,000 but less than $50,001;</section><section prefix="(ii)">$75, if charitable contributions from the public are at least $50,001 but less than $75,001;</section><section prefix="(iii)">$100, if charitable contributions from the public are at least $75,001 but less than $100,001; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">$200, if charitable contributions from the public are at least $100,001.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">An organization failing to file an annual report either by the end of the 6-month period after the end of the charitable organization's fiscal year or within any period of extension granted shall pay, in addition to the annual fee, $25 for each month or part thereof after the date on which the annual report was due to be filed or after the period of extension granted for such filing.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The late fee shall be assessed 60 days after:<section prefix="(i)">the end of the 6th month after the end of the fiscal year; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">the period of extension.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Failure to remit an assessed late fee is a violation of this title.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
