<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gbr" order_by="gbr" level="1">Business Regulation</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gbr-18-101</section_number>
  <catch_line>This section does not apply to the laws that relate to the sale of alcoholic beverages....</catch_line>
  <order_by>101</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This section does not apply to the laws that relate to the sale of alcoholic beverages.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">This section does not apply in Wicomico County.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Subject to this section and &#xA7; 3-704 of the Labor and Employment Article, a retail or wholesale establishment may do business on Sunday.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Notwithstanding an agreement to the contrary between a merchant and landlord:<section prefix="(1)">the landlord may not directly or indirectly require the merchant to open the merchant's place of business on Sunday; and</section><section prefix="(2)">a landlord may not directly or indirectly cancel or refuse to renew the merchant's lease because the merchant refuses to open the merchant's place of business on Sunday.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Except in Howard, Montgomery, and Prince George's counties, and except as provided in subsections (g) and (h) of this section, a new or used car dealer may not sell, barter, deliver, give away, show, or offer for sale a motor vehicle or certificate of title for a motor vehicle on Sunday.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">In Anne Arundel County, a dealer may sell, barter, deliver, give away, show, or offer for sale on Sunday a new or used camping trailer, mobile home, or travel trailer, as those terms are defined in Title 11 of the Transportation Article.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">A new or used car dealer who violates subsection (d) of this section is guilty of a misdemeanor and, on conviction, is subject to a fine not exceeding $10,000.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">In Anne Arundel County and Worcester County, a dealer may sell, barter, deliver, give away, show, or offer for sale a motorcycle, as defined in &#xA7; 11-136 of the Transportation Article, or certificate of title for a motorcycle on Sunday.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">In Baltimore City, a used car dealer may sell, barter, deliver, give away, show, or offer for sale a motor vehicle or certificate of title for a motor vehicle on Sunday, instead of Saturday, if the dealer notifies the Motor Vehicle Administration in advance that the dealer intends to conduct business on Sunday, instead of Saturday.</section>
  </text>
</law>
