<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gbr" order_by="gbr" level="1">Business Regulation</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gbr-6-501</section_number>
  <catch_line>An agreement between a charitable organization and a fund-raising counsel or professional solicitor ...</catch_line>
  <order_by>501</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">An agreement between a charitable organization and a fund-raising counsel or professional solicitor and any subcontract or other contract in furtherance of such an agreement shall be in writing.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A fund-raising counsel or professional solicitor shall submit to the Secretary of State a copy of all agreements under subsection (a) on or before the earlier of:<section prefix="(1)">the tenth day after the agreement is made; or</section><section prefix="(2)">the start of a charitable solicitation.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The text that a professional solicitor or associate solicitor uses in a charitable solicitation shall be attached to the agreement and shall include:<section prefix="(1)">the name of the charitable organization for which the charitable solicitation is made;</section><section prefix="(2)">the specific charitable purpose that is to be advanced with charitable contributions as shown in the registration statement; and</section><section prefix="(3)">a statement that the person who solicits charitable contributions:<section prefix="(i)">is a paid fund-raiser; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">on request, will provide a copy of the charitable organization's financial statement.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">An agreement between a professional solicitor, fund-raising counsel, or charitable organization and a person engaged to receive or hold contributions resulting from a professional solicitor or fund-raising counsel agreement shall be attached to the professional solicitor or fund-raising counsel agreement filed with the Secretary of State.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">An agreement between a charitable organization and a fund-raising counsel or professional solicitor may not contain a provision that states:<section prefix="(1)">that the charitable organization may not use contributions from a solicitation for its charitable purposes until some or all fund-raising expenses have been paid; or</section><section prefix="(2)">that the professional solicitor or fund-raising counsel may engage in a direct mail or other solicitation in the charity's name for the purpose of paying or offsetting preexisting fund-raising expenses.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
