<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gbr" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="17-905" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gbr-17-905</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Part II of this subtitle does not apply in Anne Arundel, Baltimore, Calvert, Cecil, Howard, Montgomery, and Prince George's counties.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">In Allegany County, Part II of this subtitle does not apply to a trader who holds a trader's license and has kept a regular place of business in Allegany County for at least 5 years.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">In Charles County, Part II of this subtitle:<section prefix="(1)">applies to the sale of goods from a motor vehicle or temporary stand; but</section><section prefix="(2)">does not apply to the sale of goods from a motor vehicle or temporary stand in connection with a permanent business in Charles County if:<section prefix="(i)">the seller has the written permission of the owner of the business; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">the motor vehicle or temporary stand is on or adjacent to the premises of the business.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">In Harford County, Part II of this subtitle:<section prefix="(1)">applies to the sale of goods from a vehicle or temporary stand; and</section><section prefix="(2)">does not apply to:<section prefix="(i)">the sale of goods on property that the seller owns or leases; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">a not for profit organization.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">In St. Mary's County, Part II of this subtitle applies to a nonresident of St. Mary's County who sells goods from a motor vehicle, temporary stand, or other temporary location.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">Except in Harford County, Part II of this subtitle does not apply to the sale of:<section prefix="(1)">fish or oysters in their natural and unpreserved condition; or</section><section prefix="(2)">perishable fruits or vegetables in their natural condition.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
