<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gbr" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="8-101" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gbr-8-101</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this title the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Commission" means the Maryland Home Improvement Commission.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Contractor" means a person, other than an employee of an owner, who performs or offers or agrees to perform a home improvement for an owner.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">"Contractor license" means a license issued by the Commission to act as a contractor.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"Fund" means the Home Improvement Guaranty Fund.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">"Hearing board" means a home improvement hearing board appointed by the Commission under &#xA7; 8-313 of this title.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Home improvement" means:<section prefix="(i)">the addition to or alteration, conversion, improvement, modernization, remodeling, repair, or replacement of a building or part of a building that is used or designed to be used as a residence or dwelling place or a structure adjacent to that building; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">an improvement to land adjacent to the building.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Home improvement" includes:<section prefix="(i)">construction, improvement, or replacement, on land adjacent to the building, of a driveway, fall-out shelter, fence, garage, landscaping, deck, pier, porch, or swimming pool;</section><section prefix="(ii)">a shore erosion control project, as defined under &#xA7; 8-1001 of the Natural Resources Article, for a residential property;</section><section prefix="(iii)">connection, installation, or replacement, in the building or structure, of a dishwasher, disposal, or refrigerator with an icemaker to existing exposed household plumbing lines;</section><section prefix="(iv)">installation, in the building or structure, of an awning, fire alarm, or storm window; and</section><section prefix="(v)">work done on individual condominium units.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Home improvement" does not include:<section prefix="(i)">construction of a new home;</section><section prefix="(ii)">work done to comply with a guarantee of completion for a new building project;</section><section prefix="(iii)">connection, installation, or replacement of an appliance to existing exposed plumbing lines that requires alteration of the plumbing lines;</section><section prefix="(iv)">sale of materials, if the seller does not arrange to perform or does not perform directly or indirectly any work in connection with the installation or application of the materials;</section><section prefix="(v)">work done on apartment buildings that contain four or more single-family units; or</section><section prefix="(vi)">work done on the commonly owned areas of condominiums.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(h)">"Home improvement contract" means an oral or written agreement between a contractor and owner for the contractor to perform a home improvement.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"License" means, except where it refers to a license other than one issued under this title, a license issued by the Commission.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"License" includes:<section prefix="(i)">a contractor license;</section><section prefix="(ii)">a subcontractor license; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">a salesperson license.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(j)">"Licensed contractor" means a person who is licensed by the Commission to act as a contractor.</section>
    <section prefix="(k)">"Owner" includes a homeowner, tenant, or other person who buys, contracts for, orders, or is entitled to a home improvement.</section>
    <section prefix="(l)">"Salesperson" means a person who sells a home improvement.</section>
    <section prefix="(m)">"Salesperson license" means a license issued by the Commission to sell a home improvement.</section>
    <section prefix="(n)">"Sell a home improvement" means:<section prefix="(1)">to negotiate or offer to negotiate a home improvement contract with an owner; or</section><section prefix="(2)">to seek to get a home improvement contract from an owner.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(o)">"Subcontractor" means a person, other than a laborer or supplier of materials, who makes an oral or written agreement with:<section prefix="(1)">a contractor to perform all or part of a home improvement contract; or</section><section prefix="(2)">another subcontractor to perform all or part of a subcontract to a home improvement contract.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(p)">"Subcontractor license" means a license issued by the Commission to act as a subcontractor.</section>
  </text>
</law>
