<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gbr" order_by="gbr" level="1">Business Regulation</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gbr-13-105</section_number>
  <catch_line>If a trading stamp company fails to redeem its trading stamps, each rightful holder of its trading s...</catch_line>
  <order_by>105</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If a trading stamp company fails to redeem its trading stamps, each rightful holder of its trading stamps may make a claim against the bond in accordance with this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">For purposes of this section, a rightful holder includes a retailer that rightfully holds trading stamps for issuance to customers.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The claim shall be submitted to the Secretary of State within 3 months after the failure to redeem trading stamps.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Secretary of State promptly shall determine whether the trading stamp company should have redeemed its trading stamps.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If the Secretary of State so determines, the Secretary of State shall notify the trading stamp company of that determination.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If the trading stamp company fails to redeem its trading stamps within 10 days after the notification, the Secretary of State shall publish notice of the failure in 3 consecutive issues of 1 or more newspapers that have general circulation in the State.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The notice shall state the time within which proofs of claim and the trading stamps on which they are based must be submitted to the Secretary of State.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">Proofs of claim and the trading stamps on which they are based shall be submitted to the Secretary of State within 3 months after the first publication of the notice.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">Promptly after the end of the 3-month period, the Secretary of State shall determine the validity of all claims.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">The surety shall pay to the Secretary of State the lesser of:<section prefix="(1)">the amount necessary to satisfy:<section prefix="(i)">all valid claims; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">reasonable administrative costs to determine and pay the claims; or</section></section><section prefix="(2)">the amount of the bond.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(h)">The Secretary of State promptly shall:<section prefix="(1)">distribute equitably to the claimants the proceeds of the bond, less reasonable administrative costs; and</section><section prefix="(2)">destroy the trading stamps surrendered to the Secretary of State.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(i)">
      <section prefix="(1)">On the effective date of each new bond that a trading stamp company submits, all liability on earlier bonds ends.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A rightful holder who makes a claim under this section on or after that date shall make the claim only against the new bond.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
