<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gbr" order_by="" level="1">Business Regulation</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gbr-3-504</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>504</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Commissioner shall impose a civil penalty for a violation of this title only:<section prefix="(1)">in accordance with this section; and</section><section prefix="(2)">after issuing a citation under &#xA7; 3-406 of this title for the violation.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Commissioner may impose a civil penalty, not exceeding $500 for each violation, against an amusement owner who:<section prefix="(1)">violates this title or an order passed or regulation adopted under this title, if the Commissioner finds that the violation is not serious; or</section><section prefix="(2)">violates a requirement for posting imposed under this title.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Commissioner may impose a civil penalty, not exceeding $500 for each day a violation continues, against an amusement owner who fails to correct the violation in the time set for its correction.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Commissioner may impose a civil penalty, not exceeding $1,000 for each violation, against an amusement owner who violates this title or an order passed or regulation adopted under this title if a substantial probability of death or serious physical injury exists because of the violation, unless the amusement owner did not know and with reasonable diligence could not have known of the violation.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The Commissioner may impose a civil penalty, not exceeding $2,000 for each violation, against a person who:<section prefix="(1)">operates an amusement attraction without a certificate of inspection from the Commissioner; or</section><section prefix="(2)">willfully or repeatedly violates this title or an order passed or regulation adopted under this title.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">Before the Commissioner imposes a civil penalty, the Commissioner shall consider the appropriateness of the penalty in relation to:<section prefix="(1)">the size of the business of the amusement owner against whom the penalty is to be imposed;</section><section prefix="(2)">the gravity of the violation for which the penalty is to be imposed;</section><section prefix="(3)">the good faith of the amusement owner; and</section><section prefix="(4)">any previous violations by the amusement owner.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(g)">Each civil penalty shall be paid into the General Fund of the State.</section>
  </text>
</law>
