<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gbr" order_by="" level="1">Business Regulation</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gbr-8-308.1</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>308.1</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Commission shall place the license of a licensee on inactive status, and issue an inactive status certificate to the licensee, if the licensee:<section prefix="(1)">submits to the Commission an application for inactive status on the form that the Commission provides;</section><section prefix="(2)">pays to the Commission an inactive status application fee not exceeding $50, as set by the Commission;</section><section prefix="(3)">except for the liability insurance requirement of &#xA7; 8-302.1 of this subtitle, qualifies for an active license; and</section><section prefix="(4)">returns the license of the licensee to the Commission.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The holder of a contractor license that is on inactive status may not act as a contractor in the State.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The holder of a subcontractor license that is on inactive status may not act as a subcontractor in the State.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The holder of a salesperson license that is on inactive status may not sell a home improvement in the State.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The holder of a contractor license that is on inactive status is not required to meet the liability insurance requirement of &#xA7; 8-302.1 of this subtitle.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The holder of a contractor license that is on inactive status is not subject to an assessment for the Fund under &#xA7; 8-404(b) of this title.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The placement of a license on inactive status does not affect the power of the Commission to suspend or revoke the license or to take any other disciplinary action against the licensee.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A licensee whose license is on inactive status remains responsible for renewing the license as required under &#xA7; 8-308 of this subtitle.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The holder of a contractor license that is on inactive status may renew the license without complying with the liability insurance requirement of &#xA7; 8-302.1 of this subtitle.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Notwithstanding &#xA7; 8-308 of this subtitle, a licensee whose license is on inactive status shall pay to the Commission a renewal fee of:<section prefix="(i)">$112.50 for a contractor license;</section><section prefix="(ii)">$62.50 for a subcontractor license; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">$37.50 for a salesperson license.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The Commission shall reactivate the license of a licensee that is on inactive status and reissue the license to the licensee, if the licensee:<section prefix="(1)">submits to the Commission an application for reactivation on the form that the Commission provides;</section><section prefix="(2)">pays to the Commission a reissuance fee of $10; and</section><section prefix="(3)">meets the requirements for a license, including, in the case of a contractor, the liability insurance requirement under &#xA7; 8-302.1 of this subtitle.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
