<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gbr" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="19-101" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gbr-19-101</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">A person other than as an agent or employee of the United States or a state or a political subdivision of the United States or a state may not use the word "official", or its equivalent, in connection with a tourist or travelers' guide or information service or with related advertising or publicity.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this subsection, "advertisement" includes a display or sign that is visible from a public highway.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A person may not conduct or operate a tourist or travelers' information service unless each affixed advertisement that announces the service by the prominent display of the word "information" or a synonym includes, in letters that are at least half the size of the largest letters in the advertisement and that are lighted and displayed with substantially equal prominence, a complete list of names, headed "Sales Agents For" or the equivalent, of each business from which a person, directly or indirectly connected with the service, receives a commission, fee, or other payment or remuneration for referrals to the business.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">This subsection does not apply to:<section prefix="(i)">a bona fide chamber or association of commerce of cities, towns, or counties of the State; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">an information service furnished by a retail business if remuneration is not received from any other business other than for goods sold on the premises.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Any person who violates any provision of this section is guilty of a misdemeanor and on conviction is subject to a penalty not exceeding $500 for each offense.</section>
  </text>
</law>
