<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gbr" order_by="gbr" level="1">Business Regulation</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gbr-19-703</section_number>
  <catch_line>A retail pet store that sells dogs shall:...</catch_line>
  <order_by>703</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">A retail pet store that sells dogs shall:<section prefix="(1)">post conspicuously on each dog's cage:<section prefix="(i)">the breed, age, and date of birth of the dog, if known;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the state in which the breeder or dealer of the dog is located; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">the United States Department of Agriculture license number of the breeder or dealer, if required;</section></section><section prefix="(2)">maintain a written record that includes the following information about each dog in the possession of the retail pet store:<section prefix="(i)">the breed, age, and date of birth of the dog, if known;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the sex, color, and any identifying markings of the dog;</section><section prefix="(iii)">documentation of all inoculations, worming treatments, and other medical treatments, if known, including the date of the medical treatment, the diagnoses, and the name and title of the treatment provider;</section><section prefix="(iv)">the name and address of:<section prefix="1.">the breeder or dealer who supplied the dog;</section><section prefix="2.">the facility where the dog was born; and</section><section prefix="3.">the transporter or carrier of the dog, if any;</section></section><section prefix="(v)">the United States Department of Agriculture license number of the breeder or dealer, if required;</section><section prefix="(vi)">any identifier information, including a tag, tattoo, collar number, or microchip; and</section><section prefix="(vii)">if the dog is being sold as registered or registrable:<section prefix="1.">the names and registration numbers of the sire and dam; and</section><section prefix="2.">the litter number; and</section></section></section><section prefix="(3)">for each dog acquired by the retail pet store, maintain a written record of the health, status, and disposition of the dog, including any documents that are required at the time of sale.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A retail pet store shall maintain a copy of the records required under subsection (a)(2) of this section for at least 1 year after the date of sale of the dog.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A retail pet store shall make the records required under subsection (a)(2) of this section available to:<section prefix="(1)">the Division of Consumer Protection of the Office of the Attorney General on reasonable notice;</section><section prefix="(2)">any bona fide prospective purchaser on request; and</section><section prefix="(3)">the purchaser at the time of a sale.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
