<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gbr" order_by="" level="1">Business Regulation</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gbr-12-304</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>304</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A dealer shall submit the required information from each record to the primary law enforcement unit in accordance with subsection (b) of this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If the dealer transacts business in accordance with &#xA7; 12-206(b) of this title, the dealer also shall submit the required information from the records to the local law enforcement unit in accordance with subsection (b) of this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">On the request of a dealer, the Secretary shall provide to the dealer a list of local law enforcement units.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Subject to paragraph (2) of this subsection, the dealer shall submit the records by transmitting the required information from the records electronically, in a format acceptable to the receiving law enforcement unit, by noon of the next business day.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A dealer may request an extension of up to 48 hours to submit the records required under paragraph (1) of this subsection.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Each record, submitted to the primary law enforcement unit and, if applicable, local law enforcement unit, shall include:<section prefix="(1)">the license number of the dealer;</section><section prefix="(2)">the location of each item listed in the record; and</section><section prefix="(3)">the information required under &#xA7; 12-302 of this subtitle.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The required information from a record submitted under this section:<section prefix="(1)">shall be kept confidential;</section><section prefix="(2)">is not a public record; and</section><section prefix="(3)">is not subject to Title 10, Subtitle 6 of the State Government Article.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The primary law enforcement unit shall adopt a procedure for a dealer to amend a record required to be submitted under this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">A law enforcement unit may cease to maintain a record submitted under this section after 1 year from the date the law enforcement unit receives the copy.</section>
  </text>
</law>
