<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gbr" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="8-313" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gbr-8-313</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">With the approval of the Secretary, the Commission may appoint a home improvement hearing board.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A hearing board shall consist of at least 3 members of the Commission.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Of the members of the hearing board:<section prefix="(i)">at least 1 shall have experience in some phase of the business of home improvement; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">at least 1 shall be a consumer member of the Commission.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Commission shall appoint a chairman from among the members of the hearing board.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Commission may refer to a hearing board a charge, claim, complaint, or license application made by the Commission or by any person under this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">Each procedure applicable to a hearing before the Commission is applicable to a hearing before the hearing board.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A decision of the hearing board shall be:<section prefix="(i)">by a majority vote of the entire membership of the hearing board;</section><section prefix="(ii)">in writing; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">submitted to the Commission.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Unless, within 15 days after the hearing board submits its decision to the Commission, the Commission or a member of the Commission finds that a full hearing by the Commission is required:<section prefix="(i)">the decision of the hearing board is final;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the decision is a final decision of the Commission; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">a party who is aggrieved by the decision may take an appeal as provided in &#xA7; 8-314 of this subtitle.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
