<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gbr" order_by="" level="1">Business Regulation</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gbr-3-405</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>405</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Commissioner may prohibit use of an amusement attraction if, after an inspection or investigation, the Commissioner finds that:<section prefix="(1)">the amusement attraction violates a regulation adopted under this title; and</section><section prefix="(2)">there is a substantial probability of death or serious physical injury from continued use of the amusement attraction.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">To prohibit use of an amusement attraction, the Commissioner shall give an amusement owner written notice that prohibits use of the amusement attraction.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Commissioner shall post a copy of the notice on the amusement attraction.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Only the Commissioner may remove the copy of the notice.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The amusement attraction may not be operated until it is made safe for public use and each required safeguard is provided.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A person who is aggrieved by a decision of the Commissioner under this section may appeal to a court of competent jurisdiction in accordance with the Maryland Rules.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The filing of an appeal does not stay the decision of the Commissioner.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">However, after giving the Commissioner notice and an opportunity for a hearing, the court in which the appeal is pending may stay the decision of the Commissioner on conditions that the court considers proper.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">The conditions may include a requirement to post security.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
