<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gbr" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="16.5-101" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gbr-16.5-101</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this title the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"County license" means a license issued by the clerk to sell other tobacco products at retail in a county.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"License" means:<section prefix="(1)">a license issued by the Comptroller under &#xA7; 16.5-204(a) of this title to:<section prefix="(i)">act as a licensed other tobacco products manufacturer;</section><section prefix="(ii)">act as an other tobacco products wholesaler; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">act as an other tobacco products storage warehouse; or</section></section><section prefix="(2)">a license issued by the clerk under &#xA7; 16.5-204(b) of this title to act as an other tobacco products retailer or a tobacconist.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">"Licensed other tobacco products manufacturer" means a person licensed by the Comptroller under &#xA7; 16.5-204(a) of this title who:<section prefix="(1)">manufactures or otherwise produces other tobacco products in the State intended for sale in the State, including other tobacco products intended for sale in the State through an importer; and</section><section prefix="(2)"><section prefix="(i)">sells other tobacco products on which the tobacco tax has not been paid to a licensed other tobacco products wholesaler in the State;</section><section prefix="(ii)">sells other tobacco products on which the tobacco tax has not been paid and which may lawfully be sold in the State to a licensed other tobacco products wholesaler located outside of the State;</section><section prefix="(iii)">unless otherwise prohibited or restricted under local law, this article, or the Criminal Law Article, distributes sample other tobacco products to consumers located in the State; or</section><section prefix="(iv)">stores other tobacco products in an other tobacco products warehouse in the State for subsequent shipment to licensed wholesalers, federal reservations, or persons outside of the State.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"Licensed other tobacco products retailer" means a person licensed by the clerk under &#xA7; 16.5-204(b) of this title to act as an other tobacco products retailer.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">"Licensed other tobacco products storage warehouse" means a facility licensed by the Comptroller under &#xA7; 16.5-204(a) of this title to act as an other tobacco products storage warehouse.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">"Licensed other tobacco products wholesaler" means a person licensed by the Comptroller under &#xA7; 16.5-204(a) of this title to act as an other tobacco products wholesaler.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">"Licensed tobacconist" means a person licensed by the clerk of a circuit court under &#xA7; 16.5-204(b) of this title to act as a tobacconist.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">"Other tobacco products" means:<section prefix="(1)">any cigar or roll for smoking, other than a cigarette, made in whole or in part of tobacco; or</section><section prefix="(2)">any other tobacco or product made primarily from tobacco, other than a cigarette, that is intended for consumption by smoking or chewing or as snuff.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(j)">"Other tobacco products manufacturer" means a person who:<section prefix="(1)">manufactures or otherwise produces other tobacco products intended for sale in this State, including other tobacco products intended for sale in the United States through an importer;</section><section prefix="(2)"><section prefix="(i)">sells other tobacco products on which the tobacco tax has not been paid to a licensed other tobacco products wholesaler in Maryland;</section><section prefix="(ii)">sells other tobacco products on which the tobacco tax has not been paid and which may lawfully be sold in Maryland to a licensed other tobacco products wholesaler located outside Maryland;</section><section prefix="(iii)">unless otherwise prohibited or restricted under local law, this article, or the Criminal Law Article, distributes sample other tobacco products to consumers located in Maryland; or</section><section prefix="(iv)">stores other tobacco products in an other tobacco products storage warehouse in Maryland for subsequent shipment to licensed other tobacco products wholesalers, federal reservations, or persons out of state; or</section></section><section prefix="(3)">is a licensed other tobacco products manufacturer under this title.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(k)">"Other tobacco products retailer" means a person who:<section prefix="(1)">sells other tobacco products to consumers; or</section><section prefix="(2)">holds other tobacco products for sale to consumers.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(l)">"Other tobacco products storage warehouse" means a storage facility in Maryland operated for the purpose of storing other tobacco products on which the tobacco tax has not been paid on behalf of an other tobacco products manufacturer.</section>
    <section prefix="(m)">"Other tobacco products wholesaler" means a person who:<section prefix="(1)">holds other tobacco products for sale to another person for resale; or</section><section prefix="(2)">sells other tobacco products to another person for resale.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(n)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Package" means a pack, box, carton, can, wrap, pouch, bag, or container of any kind designed for retail consumption in which other tobacco products are offered for sale, sold, or otherwise distributed.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Package" includes not more than 10 cigars offered for sale, sold, or distributed as single cigars.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(o)">"Pipe tobacco" means any tobacco that, because of its appearance, type, packaging, or labeling, is suitable for use and likely to be offered to, or purchased by, consumers as tobacco to smoke in a pipe.</section>
    <section prefix="(p)">"Premium cigars" means cigars that:<section prefix="(1)">have hand-rolled wrappers made from whole tobacco leaves where the filler, binder, and wrapper are made of all tobacco, and may include adhesives or other materials used to maintain size, texture, or flavor; or</section><section prefix="(2)">are designated as premium cigars by the Comptroller by regulation.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(q)">"Sell" means to exchange or transfer, or to agree to exchange or transfer, title or possession of property, in any manner or by any means, for consideration.</section>
    <section prefix="(r)">"Sell other tobacco products at retail" means to sell other tobacco products to a consumer.</section>
    <section prefix="(s)">"Tobacconist" means an other tobacco products business that derives at least 70% of its revenues, measured by average daily receipts, from the sale of other tobacco products and tobacco-related accessories.</section>
  </text>
</law>
