<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gbr" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="11-207" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gbr-11-207</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">On the recommendation of the executive director, the Commission may employ additional employees or agents, including auditors, experts, guards, inspectors, a breathalyzer operator at each harness racing track, scientists, Commission secretaries, specimen collectors, veterinarians, and others whom the Commission considers to be essential at or in connection with a race meeting in the best interests of racing.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The licensee who holds the race meeting for which an additional employee is used shall pay:<section prefix="(1)">the employer contribution for the employee under the Employees' Pension System;</section><section prefix="(2)">the employer contribution, as determined by the Department of Budget and Management, for the retiree under &#xA7; 2-508 of the State Personnel and Pensions Article; and</section><section prefix="(3)">an amount required under &#xA7; 23-306.1(b) of the State Personnel and Pensions Article, if any.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A licensee who holds a race meeting shall employ and pay the officials at the race meeting, other than stewards and harness judges, including each clerk of the course, clerk of the scales, handicapper, paddock judge, patrol judge, placing judge, racing secretary, starter, assistant starter, and timer.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Notwithstanding any other provision of this title, if a licensee is required to allocate 0.25% of handle to either the Maryland Race Track Employees Pension Fund or the Maryland Harness Track Employees Pension Fund, the licensee shall first pay from the allocation any amounts required to be paid by the licensee under subsection (b) of this section and the remainder shall be paid to the appropriate pension fund.</section>
  </text>
</law>
