<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gbr" order_by="gbr" level="1">Business Regulation</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gbr-14-227</section_number>
  <catch_line>A person who sells or grants a franchise is civilly liable to the person who buys or is granted a fr...</catch_line>
  <order_by>227</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A person who sells or grants a franchise is civilly liable to the person who buys or is granted a franchise if the person who sells or grants a franchise offers to sell or sells a franchise:<section prefix="(i)">without the offer of the franchise being registered under this subtitle; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">by means of an untrue statement of a material fact or any omission to state a material fact necessary in order to make the statements made, in light of the circumstances under which they are made, not misleading, if the person who buys or is granted a franchise does not know of the untruth or omission.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">In determining liability under this subsection, the person who sells or grants a franchise has the burden of proving that the person who sells or grants a franchise did not know and, in the exercise of reasonable care, could not have known of the untruth or omission.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The person who buys or is granted a franchise may sue under this section to recover damages sustained by the grant of the franchise.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A court may order the person who sells or grants a franchise to:<section prefix="(1)">rescind the franchise; and</section><section prefix="(2)">make restitution to the person who buys or is granted a franchise.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Joint and several liability under this section extends to:<section prefix="(i)">each person who directly or indirectly controls a person liable under this section;</section><section prefix="(ii)">each partner in a partnership liable under this section;</section><section prefix="(iii)">each principal officer or director of a corporation liable under this section;</section><section prefix="(iv)">each other person that has a similar status or performs similar functions as a person liable under this section; and</section><section prefix="(v)">each employee of a person liable under this section, if the employee materially aids in the act or transaction that is a violation under this subtitle.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">However, liability under this subsection does not extend to a person who did not have knowledge of or reasonable grounds to believe in the existence of the facts by which the liability is alleged to exist.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">An action under this section must be brought within 3 years after the grant of the franchise.</section>
  </text>
</law>
