<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gbr" order_by="" level="1">Business Regulation</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gbr-5-101</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>101</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this title the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Burial goods" means goods that are used in connection with burial.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Burial goods" includes:<section prefix="(i)">a casket;</section><section prefix="(ii)">a grave liner;</section><section prefix="(iii)">a memorial;</section><section prefix="(iv)">a monument;</section><section prefix="(v)">a scroll;</section><section prefix="(vi)">an urn;</section><section prefix="(vii)">a vase; and</section><section prefix="(viii)">a vault.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Burial goods business" means a business that provides burial goods.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Cemetery" means land used or to be used for interment.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Cemetery" includes a structure used or to be used for interment.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"Cremation" means the process of reducing human remains to bone fragments through intense heat and evaporation, including any mechanical or thermal process.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">"Crematory" means a building, portion of a building, or structure that houses the necessary appliances and facilities for cremation.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">"Director" means the Director of the Office of Cemetery Oversight.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">"Engage in the operation of a cemetery" means owning, controlling, or managing a cemetery, including performing activities necessary for:<section prefix="(1)">the establishment, improvement, care, preservation, or embellishment of a cemetery;</section><section prefix="(2)">interment; and</section><section prefix="(3)">the providing of burial space or burial goods.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(i)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Engage in the operation of a crematory" means controlling or managing a crematory.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Engage in the operation of a crematory" does not include:<section prefix="(i)">the practice of funeral direction or the practice of mortuary science; or</section><section prefix="(ii)"><section prefix="1.">assistance in making decisions and filling out forms that are not directly related to cremation;</section><section prefix="2.">obtaining vital statistics, signatures, and other information necessary to complete a death certificate;</section><section prefix="3.">transportation of a body to the place of disposition; or</section><section prefix="4.">any other services regarding the disposition of a body that are not directly related to cremation.</section></section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(j)">"Funeral establishment" means a building, structure, or premises from which the business of funeral directing or embalming is conducted.</section>
    <section prefix="(k)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Human remains" means:<section prefix="(i)">the body of a deceased person; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">a part of a body or limb that has been removed from a living person.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Human remains" includes the body or part of a body or limb in any state of decomposition.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(l)">"Interment" means all final disposition of human remains, including:<section prefix="(1)">earth burial;</section><section prefix="(2)">mausoleum entombment; and</section><section prefix="(3)">niche or columbarium interment.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(m)">"Office" means the Office of Cemetery Oversight.</section>
    <section prefix="(n)">"Permit" means a permit issued by the Director to allow a partnership, limited liability company, or corporation to operate a business through which a registrant may:<section prefix="(1)">engage in the operation of a cemetery or crematory; or</section><section prefix="(2)">provide burial goods.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(o)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Preneed goods" means burial goods that are sold before the buyer's death.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Preneed goods" does not include burial space.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(p)">"Provide burial goods" means a retail transaction:<section prefix="(1)">to erect, service, or inscribe burial memorials; or</section><section prefix="(2)">to sell burial goods.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(q)">"Registered cemeterian" means an individual registered to operate a cemetery as a sole proprietor or on behalf of a sole proprietor or of a permit holder.</section>
    <section prefix="(r)">"Registered crematory operator" means an individual registered to operate a crematory as a sole proprietor or on behalf of a sole proprietor or permit holder.</section>
    <section prefix="(s)">"Registered seller" means an individual registered to provide burial goods as a sole proprietor or on behalf of a sole proprietor or of a permit holder.</section>
    <section prefix="(t)">"Registration" means a registration issued by the Director authorizing an individual to operate a cemetery, to operate a crematory, or to provide burial goods.</section>
    <section prefix="(u)">"Responsible party" means a sole proprietor or the individual designated by a partnership, limited liability company, or corporation to be responsible for the operations of a cemetery, crematory, or burial goods business.</section>
  </text>
</law>
