<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gbr" order_by="" level="1">Business Regulation</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gbr-8-711</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>711</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Subject to the hearing provisions of &#xA7; 8-712 of this subtitle, the Commission may deny a license to any applicant, reprimand any licensee, or suspend or revoke a license if the Commission finds that the applicant or licensee:<section prefix="(1)">obtained a license by false or fraudulent representation;</section><section prefix="(2)">transferred the authority granted by the license to another person;</section><section prefix="(3)">willfully or deliberately disregarded and violated any regulations established by the Commission under this subtitle;</section><section prefix="(4)">willfully or deliberately disregarded and violated laws of the State or of any municipality, city, or county of the State;</section><section prefix="(5)">is convicted of:<section prefix="(i)">a felony; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">a misdemeanor that is directly related to the fitness and qualification of the applicant or licensee to provide mold remediation services;</section></section><section prefix="(6)">aided or abetted a person to evade a provision of this subtitle by allowing a license to be used by an unlicensed person, firm, or corporation;</section><section prefix="(7)">performed work under a mold remediation services contract or project that is inadequate or incomplete;</section><section prefix="(8)">made any material misrepresentation in the procurement of a mold remediation services contract or project; or</section><section prefix="(9)">violated this subtitle.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Subject to the hearing provisions of &#xA7; 8-712 of this subtitle, the Commission may reprimand a licensee or suspend or revoke a license of a licensee for a violation of this title by an agent, director, employee, manager, officer, partner, or salesperson of the licensee, unless the Commission finds that the licensee:<section prefix="(1)">had no knowledge of the wrongful conduct; or</section><section prefix="(2)">could not prevent the violation.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Instead of or in addition to reprimanding a licensee or suspending or revoking a license, the Commission may impose a civil penalty under &#xA7; 8-620 of this title.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Commission shall consider the following facts in the granting, denial, renewal, suspension, or revocation of a license or the reprimand of a licensee when an applicant or licensee is convicted of a felony or misdemeanor:<section prefix="(1)">the nature of the crime;</section><section prefix="(2)">the relationship of the crime to the activities authorized by the license;</section><section prefix="(3)">with respect to a felony, the relevance of the conviction to the fitness and qualification of the applicant or licensee to provide mold remediation services;</section><section prefix="(4)">the length of time since the conviction; and</section><section prefix="(5)">the behavior and activities of the applicant or licensee before and after the conviction.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The Commission shall pay any penalty collected under this section into the General Fund of the State.</section>
  </text>
</law>
