<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gbr" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="9A-304" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gbr-9A-304</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">An applicant who otherwise qualifies for a license is entitled to be examined as provided in this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Board shall offer examinations to applicants at least twice annually, at places within the State and at times that the Board determines.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Board shall send written notice of the date, hour, and place of examination to each applicant for a license who is required to pass the examination.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Board shall determine the subjects, scope, and form of and the passing score for examinations given under this title.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Board shall provide examination questions that test the competency and qualifications of the applicant.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">An applicant for a master restricted, journeyman restricted, or limited heating, ventilation, air-conditioning, and refrigeration contractor license shall be examined only on subjects in which the applicant has the experience required under &#xA7; 9A-302 of this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">To take an examination, an applicant shall pay to the Board or a testing service chosen by the Board the examination fee set by the Board in an amount not to exceed the cost of the examination.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Board may use a testing service to administer the examinations given under this title.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If the Board uses a testing service, the testing service, subject to requirements set by the Board, may:<section prefix="(i)">set the time and place of examinations;</section><section prefix="(ii)">give qualified applicants notice of the time and place of examinations; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">furnish any other information that the Board may require the testing service to provide.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
