<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gbr" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="12-202" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gbr-12-202</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">An applicant for a license shall:<section prefix="(i)">submit to the Secretary an application on the form that the Secretary provides; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">pay to the Secretary an application fee of $300.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The application fee is nonrefundable.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The applicant shall sign the application under oath.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">In addition to any other information that the Secretary requires, the application shall state:<section prefix="(1)">the name, date of birth, and residence address of the applicant;</section><section prefix="(2)">the fixed business address of the applicant;</section><section prefix="(3)">the fixed address in the State where precious metal objects will be stored, if different from the fixed business address, provided, however, that a bank or safe deposit box is not an acceptable storage location unless written consent by the applicant and a bank official authorizing access to the storage facility and examination of its contents by law enforcement officers or agents accompany the application;</section><section prefix="(4)">a telephone number at which the applicant can be reached during normal business hours;</section><section prefix="(5)">each address where the applicant has conducted any business during the 36 months before application;</section><section prefix="(6)">the driver's license number, if any, of the applicant; and</section><section prefix="(7)">the name and permanent address of each employee who will work with the applicant in the business of the applicant.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The application form shall contain, immediately above the signature line, the following:</section>
  </text>
</law>
