<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gbr" order_by="" level="1">Business Regulation</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gbr-5-710</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>710</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Each seller shall keep detailed records of all preneed burial contracts and specific funds.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The records of each seller and of each trustee appointed by the seller are subject to examination by:<section prefix="(i)">the Director;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the Attorney General or an authorized representative of the Attorney General; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">the State's Attorney for the county where the seller does business.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Each seller subject to the trust requirements of this subtitle shall submit a report to the Director within 120 days after the close of each calendar or other fiscal year chosen by the seller.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The report shall:<section prefix="(i)">be on the form that the Director requires;</section><section prefix="(ii)">be certified by a certified public accountant retained by the seller;</section><section prefix="(iii)">be accompanied by a trustee's annual summary statement of assets from the trustee for the reporting period which includes:<section prefix="1.">the amount of money in the preneed trust fund at the beginning of the reporting period;</section><section prefix="2.">an investment portfolio summary describing the asset and the market value for each investment class;</section><section prefix="3.">a transaction summary of the preneed trust fund containing:</section><section prefix="4.">the amount of money in the preneed trust fund at the end of the reporting period;</section></section><section prefix="(iv)">be accompanied by a fee of $25; and</section><section prefix="(v)">include:<section prefix="1.">the name of the seller;</section><section prefix="2.">each location of the seller;</section><section prefix="3.">the amount of money that the seller received during that year that is subject to the trust requirements of this subtitle;</section><section prefix="4.">the amount of money actually deposited into trust accounts in that year;</section><section prefix="5.">the amount of money required to be disbursed from the trust accounts in that year;</section><section prefix="6.">the amount of money actually disbursed from the trust accounts in that year; and</section><section prefix="7.">the name and address of the trustee.</section></section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">If the Director determines, after a review of the report and annual summary statement of assets required by this subsection, that additional documentation is required, a seller subject to the trust requirements of this subtitle shall provide the additional documentation to the Director.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">
        <section prefix="(i)">A seller of preneed goods or preneed services that sells its business, files a petition in bankruptcy, or ceases to operate shall provide written notice within 15 days:<section prefix="1.">to the Director, detailing the changes and the arrangements the seller has made for carrying out the preneed burial contracts and the disbursement of any moneys held in an escrow or trust account; and</section><section prefix="2.">to each buyer of a preneed burial contract, advising the buyer of the buyer's options under State law in regard to the preneed contract.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">Nothing in this paragraph exempts a seller of preneed goods or services that sells its business, files a petition in bankruptcy, or ceases to operate from filing the annual report required under this section.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A seller of a preneed burial contract shall provide each buyer or prospective buyer with a general price list for the buyer or prospective buyer to keep which shall include:<section prefix="(1)">specific prices for:<section prefix="(i)">ground opening and closing;</section><section prefix="(ii)">extra depth interment;</section><section prefix="(iii)">interment of cremated remains; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">mausoleum entombment; and</section></section><section prefix="(2)">general price ranges for burial space or preneed goods.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A seller of a preneed burial contract shall disclose to the buyer:<section prefix="(1)">all goods and services that are reasonably expected to be required at the time of need that are not included in the preneed burial contract;</section><section prefix="(2)">the buyer's cancellation and refund rights under &#xA7; 5-709 of this subtitle;</section><section prefix="(3)">the person responsible for installation of the goods sold and any warranties for the goods sold; and</section><section prefix="(4)">if the preneed contract provides for goods or services to be delivered or performed before death:<section prefix="(i)">that interest or finance charges may be imposed;</section><section prefix="(ii)">that interest or finance charges are not allowed on other preneed burial contracts that do not provide for goods or services to be delivered or performed before death;</section><section prefix="(iii)">the manner of delivery of goods including where the goods are stored; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">the buyer's remedy if delivered goods are damaged or destroyed.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The Director may require a seller to correct any underfunding, including interest, due to the preneed trust account.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The Director may adopt regulations:<section prefix="(1)">to administer this section; and</section><section prefix="(2)">for determining whether sellers are complying with this subtitle.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
