<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gbr" order_by="" level="1">Business Regulation</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gbr-12-102</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>102</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">This title does not apply to a transaction that involves:<section prefix="(1)">merchandise acquired from an established manufacturer or dealer who holds a license under this title, other than a pawnbroker, if the dealer who acquires the merchandise keeps an invoice or other customary proof of origin for the merchandise;</section><section prefix="(2)">a metal acquired for use in dentistry by a dentist licensed to practice dentistry under Title 4 of the Health Occupations Article;</section><section prefix="(3)">coins or numismatic items; or</section><section prefix="(4)">the purchase of junk or scrap metal that is subject to the record keeping and reporting requirements under &#xA7; 17-1011 of this article.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">If a retail jeweler has a fixed business address in the State, this title does not apply to a transaction in which the retail jeweler:<section prefix="(1)">accepts, in accordance with a posted return policy, the return of an item that the jeweler originally sold;</section><section prefix="(2)">accepts, in accordance with a published trade-in policy, merchandise in trade that the jeweler originally sold;</section><section prefix="(3)">repossesses merchandise that the jeweler originally sold, if the original buyer has defaulted;</section><section prefix="(4)">retains merchandise that the jeweler originally accepted for repair as a bailee for hire, if the customer who deposited the merchandise:<section prefix="(i)">defaulted; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">failed to reclaim the merchandise within the time agreed on with the jeweler; or</section></section><section prefix="(5)">accumulates pieces of precious metals in the course of performing repairs, remountings, fabrications, or custom orders.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Except as otherwise provided in this title, this title does not apply to a pawnbroker located in a county that regulates pawnbrokers unless the pawnbroker does business as a dealer.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A county or municipal corporation may not enact a law to regulate dealers, coins, or numismatic items.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">This title supersedes any existing law of a county or municipal corporation that regulates dealers, coins, or numismatic items.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
