<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gbr" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="10-303" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gbr-10-303</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Before storing or selling motor fuel in the State, a person or governmental unit shall register with the Comptroller.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A separate registration is required for each location where a person or governmental unit stores or sells motor fuel.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">An applicant for registration shall submit to the Comptroller in the form that the Comptroller requires:<section prefix="(1)">a statement that the applicant intends to store or sell motor fuel in the State;</section><section prefix="(2)">a statement that the motor fuel, as supplied or bought from the supplier, conforms to the specifications set by the Comptroller;</section><section prefix="(3)">the brand, type, and grade of the motor fuel to be stored or sold;</section><section prefix="(4)">the name and address of the supplier;</section><section prefix="(5)">if applicable, the number of retail nozzles by type of motor fuel;</section><section prefix="(6)">the legal business name and federal identification number of the applicant; and</section><section prefix="(7)">the address of the location where the motor fuel will be stored or sold.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Comptroller shall issue a certificate of registration to each applicant who meets the requirements of this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Comptroller shall set the form of the certificate of registration.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">Registration expires on the first May 31 after its effective date.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">Each registrant shall display the certificate of registration conspicuously in each location where the registrant stores or sells motor fuel.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">A certificate of registration issued under this title is not transferable.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">The Comptroller may waive this section only when consumers in the State otherwise would be subject to extreme hardship during an emergency or civil disturbance.</section>
  </text>
</law>
