<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gbr" order_by="gbr" level="1">Business Regulation</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gbr-19-207</section_number>
  <catch_line>A person may not falsely impersonate an officer or member of a military or patriotic organization, g...</catch_line>
  <order_by>207</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">A person may not falsely impersonate an officer or member of a military or patriotic organization, grand or subordinate lodge, or fraternal or sororal society that is chartered or has grand or subordinate lodges in the State.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Subject to paragraph (2) of this subsection, a person may not wear, or use to obtain aid, assistance, or personal or social recognition from a person in the State, the insignia of a military or patriotic organization, or a lodge or fraternal society that is chartered or has grand or subordinate lodges in the State, unless the person is entitled to use or wear the insignia under the constitution, bylaws, or rules of the organization, lodge, or society.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Nothing in this subsection may be construed to prohibit a person from wearing an insignia of a lodge or society if the person is a parent, sibling, child, or spouse of a member of the lodge or society who is entitled to wear the insignia under this subsection.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A person who violates this subsection is guilty of a misdemeanor and on conviction is subject to a fine not exceeding $200.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A person may not wear willfully, or use to obtain aid or assistance in the State, the insignia of the American Legion, the Veterans of Foreign Wars of the United States, or the Disabled American Veterans, unless the person is entitled to use or wear the insignia under the constitution, bylaws, or rules of the organization.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A person who violates this subsection is guilty of a misdemeanor and on conviction is subject to:<section prefix="(i)">a fine not exceeding $25; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">if payment of the fine is defaulted, imprisonment not exceeding 30 days.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A person may not willfully wear, exhibit, display, print, or use the insignia that is registered under this subtitle, unless the person is entitled to use or wear the insignia under the constitution, bylaws, or rules of the organization.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A person who violates this subsection is guilty of a misdemeanor and on conviction is subject to:<section prefix="(i)">a fine not exceeding $100; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">if payment of the fine is defaulted, imprisonment not exceeding 60 days.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
