<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gbr" order_by="gbr" level="1">Business Regulation</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gbr-11-526</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this section, "Park and Planning Commission" means the Maryland-National Capital Park and Plannin...</catch_line>
  <order_by>526</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, "Park and Planning Commission" means the Maryland-National Capital Park and Planning Commission.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The State Racing Commission shall issue a special thoroughbred racing license to the Park and Planning Commission to hold racing in 4 one-day race meetings at the Prince George's Equestrian Center.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The racing days shall be held:<section prefix="(1)">on dates that the Park and Planning Commission chooses and the State Racing Commission approves;</section><section prefix="(2)">on dates when a mile thoroughbred racing licensee does not hold a race; and</section><section prefix="(3)">in connection with or for the benefit of a county fair or equestrian exhibition or activity.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Park and Planning Commission shall deduct from the handle:<section prefix="(i)">17% of all money bet in each regular mutuel pool;</section><section prefix="(ii)">19% of all money bet in each multiple mutuel pool on 2 horses; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">25% of all money bet in each multiple mutuel pool on 3 or more horses.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Park and Planning Commission shall pay to the Maryland Equestrian Foundation, Inc., a not for profit organization:<section prefix="(i)">from the amount deducted under paragraph (1) of this subsection, 8% of the total amount bet in all of the mutuel pools; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">any profit from admission fees or other receipts, less expenses from the operation of racing days.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">On races that the Park and Planning Commission holds each year, the Park and Planning Commission shall allocate for purses:<section prefix="(i)">5% of each regular mutuel pool;</section><section prefix="(ii)">7% of each multiple mutuel pool on 2 horses;</section><section prefix="(iii)">13% of the money bet in the first race of the day with a multiple mutuel pool on 3 or more horses; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">9.25% of the money bet in every other race with a multiple mutuel pool on 3 or more horses.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">Repealed.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">An officer of the Park and Planning Commission may not receive a salary or dividends from racing authorized under this section.</section>
  </text>
</law>
