<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gbr" order_by="" level="1">Business Regulation</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gbr-16-223</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>223</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">This section applies to a person who is engaged in the business of selling or distributing cigarettes.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, a person covered under this section may not:<section prefix="(i)">sell or ship cigarettes, ordered or purchased by mail or through a computer network, telephonic network, or other electronic network by a consumer or other unlicensed recipient, directly to a consumer or other unlicensed recipient in this State; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">cause cigarettes, ordered or purchased by mail or through a computer network, telephonic network, or other electronic network by a consumer or other unlicensed recipient, to be shipped directly to a consumer or other unlicensed recipient in this State.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A licensed retailer may deliver no more than two cartons of cigarettes directly to a consumer if the delivery is made by the licensed retailer or an employee of the licensed retailer.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A licensee who sells or ships cigarettes in violation of this section or causes cigarettes to be shipped in violation of this section is:<section prefix="(i)">subject to discipline by the Comptroller under &#xA7; 16-210 of this subtitle; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">guilty of a felony and, on conviction, is subject to a fine not exceeding $50 for each carton of cigarettes transported or imprisonment not exceeding 2 years or both.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A person other than a licensee who sells or ships cigarettes in violation of this section or causes cigarettes to be shipped in violation of this section is guilty of a felony and, on conviction, is subject to a fine not exceeding $50 for each carton of cigarettes transported or imprisonment not exceeding 2 years or both.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
