<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gbr" order_by="gbr" level="1">Business Regulation</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gbr-11-404</section_number>
  <catch_line>To help pay for facilities and services in communities within 2 miles of the Pimlico Race Course or ...</catch_line>
  <order_by>404</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">To help pay for facilities and services in communities within 2 miles of the Pimlico Race Course or 3 miles of the Laurel Race Course, the Comptroller shall pay money to Baltimore City, the City of Laurel, and Anne Arundel and Howard counties in accordance with this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The money shall be paid from the Special Fund in half-yearly installments.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">In any year, payments required under this section may not be less than the total allocated for 140 days of live racing at each track.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If 140 or more days of live racing in a year are held at Pimlico Race Course, the Comptroller shall pay to Baltimore City:<section prefix="(i)">$2,800 for each day of live racing; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">$1,400 for each additional day of intertrack betting without live racing held.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If fewer than 140 days of live racing in a year are held at Pimlico Race Course, the Comptroller shall pay to Baltimore City:<section prefix="(i)">$2,800 for each day of live racing or intertrack betting without live racing held, up to a maximum payment for 140 days; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">$1,400 for each additional day of intertrack betting without live racing held.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If 140 or more days of live racing in a year are held at Laurel Race Course, the Comptroller shall pay:<section prefix="(i)">for each day of live racing, $2,000 to Anne Arundel County, $500 to Howard County, and $300 to the City of Laurel; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">for each additional day of intertrack betting without live racing held, $1,000 to Anne Arundel County, $250 to Howard County, and $150 to the City of Laurel.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If fewer than 140 days of live racing in a year are held at Laurel Race Course, the Comptroller shall pay:<section prefix="(i)">for each day of live racing or each day of intertrack betting without live racing held, up to a maximum payment for 140 days, $2,000 to Anne Arundel County, $500 to Howard County, and $300 to the City of Laurel; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">for each additional day of intertrack betting without live racing held, $1,000 to Anne Arundel County, $250 to Howard County, and $150 to the City of Laurel.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
