<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gbr" order_by="gbr" level="1">Business Regulation</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gbr-11-524</section_number>
  <catch_line>The Commission shall issue a special thoroughbred racing license to the State Fair Society to hold a...</catch_line>
  <order_by>524</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Commission shall issue a special thoroughbred racing license to the State Fair Society to hold a race meeting.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The race meeting shall:<section prefix="(i)">last not more than 10 days in a calendar year;</section><section prefix="(ii)">be held with or for the benefit of the State Fair or a county fair or agricultural exhibition; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">comply with this title.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The State Fair Society shall pay to the county treasurer of the county where the fair or exhibition is held, for the use of the county, a fee of $50 for each racing day of the race meeting.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Commission may authorize the State Fair Society to transfer a race meeting from the State Fair Society's own track to the track of a mile thoroughbred racing licensee:<section prefix="(1)">on receipt of the appropriate license fees; and</section><section prefix="(2)">with the express consent of the owner or lessee of the track to which the transfer is made.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">If the State Fair Society ends special thoroughbred racing at the Timonium Race Course, the racing days that were awarded to it may be awarded to a mile thoroughbred licensee on the same terms as the additional racing days under &#xA7; 11-511 of this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">If racing is discontinued at the Timonium Race Course:<section prefix="(1)">compensation may not be paid to the State Fair Society to offset revenue loss from the discontinuance of racing; and</section><section prefix="(2)">payment of the grant to Baltimore County under &#xA7; 11-403 of this title shall end.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
