<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gbr" order_by="" level="1">Business Regulation</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gbr-9A-402</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>402</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">A holder of a master, master restricted, or limited heating, ventilation, air-conditioning, and refrigeration license may not contract to provide services on behalf of the licensee, or another person who provides heating, ventilation, air-conditioning, or refrigeration services, unless the work of the licensee, including completed operations, is covered by:<section prefix="(1)">general liability insurance in the amount of at least $300,000; and</section><section prefix="(2)">property damage insurance in the amount of at least $100,000.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The insurance required under this section may be bought:<section prefix="(i)">by a holder of a master, master restricted, or limited heating, ventilation, air-conditioning, and refrigeration license; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">by the person who engages in the business of providing heating, ventilation, air-conditioning, or refrigeration services and employs the holder of the master, master restricted, or limited license.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The insurance requirement of this section is not meant for work that a master, master restricted, or limited license holder does outside the scope of employment for the person who carries the insurance.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A licensed apprentice, licensed journeyman, or licensed journeyman restricted in the employ of a master, master restricted, or limited licensee need not obtain separate insurance while providing or assisting in providing heating, ventilation, air-conditioning, or refrigeration services under the control and supervision of the licensee.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Subject to the restrictions of &#xA7; 9A-309 of this title regarding inactive status, inactive licensees who have had their inactive status approved by the Board need not obtain insurance while maintaining inactive status.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">An applicant for any license under this title shall submit proof of the insurance required under this section to the Board with the license application.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Unless the applicant submits proof of insurance, the Board may not issue any license to an applicant to whom the insurance requirements of this section apply.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">Unless an applicant meets the insurance requirements of this section, the Board may not renew any license of the applicant to whom the insurance requirements of this section apply.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">A holder of a master, master restricted, or limited license shall give the Board notice of the cancellation of insurance at least 10 days before the effective date of the cancellation.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">If a county, municipal corporation, special taxing district, or other political subdivision requires a master, master restricted, or limited heating, ventilation, air-conditioning, and refrigeration license holder, or other person who engages in the business of providing heating, ventilation, air-conditioning, and refrigeration services, to execute a surety bond under local heating, ventilation, air-conditioning, and refrigeration requirements, the person may satisfy the bond requirement by submitting proof of the insurance required under this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">The Board shall specify on each license whether the license holder meets the insurance requirements of this section.</section>
  </text>
</law>
