<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gbr" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="12.5-101" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gbr-12.5-101</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this title the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Business" means a commercial entity that provides locksmith services.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Employee" means an individual employed by a licensed locksmith to provide locksmith services on behalf of the licensed locksmith.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">"Fixed business address" means a single physical location where a licensee conducts business and at which the licensee or an employee of the licensee is available:<section prefix="(1)">during normal business hours; or</section><section prefix="(2)">other hours as provided in the application for the license.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"License" means a license issued by the Secretary to provide locksmith services.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">"Licensed locksmith" means, unless the context requires otherwise, a business that is licensed by the Secretary to provide locksmith services.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">"Local law enforcement unit" means the Department of State Police, a police department in the State, or sheriff in the State:<section prefix="(1)">designated by the county or municipal governing body for a licensee with an in-State fixed business address; or</section><section prefix="(2)">designated by the Secretary for a licensee with an out-of-state fixed business address.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(h)">"Provide locksmith services" means to engage professionally and for compensation in:<section prefix="(1)">repairing, rebuilding, rekeying, repinning, recombinating, adjusting, or installing mechanical, electrical, or electromechanical locking devices, safes, vaults, or safe deposit boxes; or</section><section prefix="(2)">operating a mechanical, electrical, or electromechanical locking device or opening safes, vaults, or safe deposit boxes by a means other than that intended by the manufacturer of such locking devices.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
