<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gbr" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="6-401" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gbr-6-401</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">A charitable organization shall register and receive a registration letter from the Secretary of State before the charitable organization:<section prefix="(1)">solicits charitable contributions in the State;</section><section prefix="(2)">has charitable contributions solicited on its behalf in the State; or</section><section prefix="(3)">solicits charitable contributions outside of the State, if the charitable organization is in the State.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A separate registration statement and a registration letter is necessary before any of the following charitable organizations can solicit:<section prefix="(1)">a federated fund-raising organization consisting of independent charitable organizations, including a united fund and a community chest, that:<section prefix="(i)">have joined to solicit charitable contributions and distribute them among themselves; but</section><section prefix="(ii)">keep their own operating authority and control; or</section></section><section prefix="(2)">an independent charitable organization, including one that is a member of a federated fund-raising organization, unless it is specifically exempted or it does not solicit charitable contributions other than as a member of a federated fund-raising organization.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A parent organization shall submit a consolidated registration statement for the affiliates, branches, or chapters in the State that it coordinates, controls, or supervises.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">An affiliate, branch, or chapter of a charitable organization shall:<section prefix="(i)">report information needed for a consolidated registration statement to its parent organization;</section><section prefix="(ii)">submit a separate registration statement; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">receive a registration letter from the Secretary of State prior to soliciting.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">For purposes of this subsection, an independent member agency of a federated fund-raising organization is not an affiliate, branch, or chapter.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
