<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gbr" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="5-708" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gbr-5-708</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The trustee may not disburse specific funds until preneed goods are delivered or preneed services are performed as provided in the preneed burial contract or in this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">On performance of a preneed burial contract:<section prefix="(1)">the seller shall certify to the trustee:<section prefix="(i)">delivery of the preneed goods or performance of the preneed services; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">the amount of specific funds in the trust account; and</section></section><section prefix="(2)">the trustee shall then pay to the seller the specific funds and accrued interest.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In a seller's records, the seller may itemize preneed goods or preneed services to which the trust requirements of this subtitle apply and the consideration paid or to be paid for each item.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If a seller itemizes in accordance with paragraph (1) of this subsection, on performance of that part of a preneed burial contract identified for itemized preneed goods or preneed services:<section prefix="(i)">the seller shall certify to the trustee:</section><section prefix="(ii)">the trustee shall then pay to the seller those specific funds and accrued interest.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If a preneed burial contract provides, for 2 or more individuals, preneed goods or preneed services to which the trust requirements of this subtitle apply, a seller may designate in the seller's records the consideration paid for each individual.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">On performance of that part of the preneed burial contract identified to a particular individual:<section prefix="(i)">the seller shall certify to the trustee:</section><section prefix="(ii)">the trustee shall then pay to the seller those specific funds and accrued interest.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
