<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gbr" order_by="" level="1">Business Regulation</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gbr-11-811</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>811</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Fair Hill" means the Cecil County Breeders' Fair, Inc., or its successor.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"State Fair Society" means the Maryland State Fair and Agricultural Society, Inc.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">This section applies only to intertrack betting in which:<section prefix="(1)">the sending track is equipped to transmit simulcast races and is:<section prefix="(i)">a mile thoroughbred track;</section><section prefix="(ii)">a harness track;</section><section prefix="(iii)">a track where racing is conducted by Fair Hill; or</section><section prefix="(iv)">a track where racing is conducted by the State Fair Society; and</section></section><section prefix="(2)">the receiving track is:<section prefix="(i)">equipped to receive simulcast races and hold intertrack betting on those races; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">one of the tracks specified in item (1) of this subsection.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Commission may authorize intertrack betting involving tracks of:<section prefix="(1)">mile thoroughbred racing licensees;</section><section prefix="(2)">harness racing licensees;</section><section prefix="(3)">Fair Hill; or</section><section prefix="(4)">the State Fair Society.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Commission may authorize licensees, Fair Hill, or the State Fair Society to participate in intertrack betting by operating sending tracks and receiving tracks only if:<section prefix="(1)">the operators of the sending track and the receiving track submit a joint application to the Commission;</section><section prefix="(2)">the Commission holds a public hearing on the matter;</section><section prefix="(3)">the operator of the receiving track shows to the satisfaction of the Commission that the operator has held, is holding, or will hold regularly scheduled race meetings at the receiving track in accordance with a license and has complied with the terms of the license; and</section><section prefix="(4)">the receiving track meets the requirements of subsection (e) of this section, unless the Commission has waived them, and subsection (f) of this section.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Laurel Race Course, a track where racing is conducted by the State Fair Society or Rosecroft Raceway may be a receiving track only if live racing was held there in the previous calendar year on at least 75% of the racing days available to it.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Ocean Downs may be a receiving track only if at least 40 days of live racing were held there in the previous calendar year.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Pimlico Race Course may be a receiving track only if at least 90 days of live racing were held there in the previous calendar year.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">A track where racing is conducted by Fair Hill may be a sending track only on days when Fair Hill is licensed to conduct and actually conducts live racing.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">A track in Allegany County may be a sending track:<section prefix="(i)">to any receiving track:<section prefix="1.">on days when the track is licensed to conduct and actually conducts live racing; and</section><section prefix="2.">for live races conducted at the track; and</section></section><section prefix="(ii)">to a receiving track located more than 35 miles from any of Laurel Park, Pimlico Race Course, and Rosecroft Raceway:<section prefix="1.">on any day the Commission has authorized the licensee to hold racing; and</section><section prefix="2.">for simulcast races conducted at the track.</section></section></section>
      <section prefix="(6)">Subject to &#xA7; 11-804.2 of this subtitle, nothing in paragraph (5) of this subsection shall limit the ability of a track in Allegany County to act as a sending track to a satellite simulcast facility.</section>
      <section prefix="(7)">A track in Allegany County may be a receiving track:<section prefix="(i)">during its opening year if it has scheduled at least 21 days of live racing within 12 months of its opening and the Commission has granted its application to race on those days; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">in subsequent years if at least 21 days of live racing were held at the track in the previous calendar year.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(8)">The Commission may waive a requirement of this subsection if the receiving track could not meet the requirement because of:<section prefix="(i)">an act of God; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">what the Commission finds to be an emergency.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Intertrack betting may be held only if the organizations specified in this subsection approve the agreement between the receiving track and the sending track to simulcast races.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If the sending track is a mile thoroughbred track or a track where racing is conducted by the State Fair Society or Fair Hill, approval shall be by an organization representing:<section prefix="(i)">a majority of the owners and trainers at the sending track; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">a majority of the thoroughbred breeders in the State.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">If the sending track is a harness track, approval shall be by an organization representing:<section prefix="(i)">a majority of the owners, trainers, and drivers of standardbred horses at the sending track; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">a majority of the standardbred breeders in the State.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">If the receiving track is a mile thoroughbred track or a track where racing is conducted by the State Fair Society, approval shall be by an organization representing:<section prefix="(i)">a majority of the owners and trainers at the receiving track; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">a majority of the thoroughbred breeders in the State.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(5)">If the receiving track is a harness track, approval shall be by an organization representing:<section prefix="(i)">a majority of the owners, trainers, and drivers of standardbred horses at the harness track; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">a majority of the standardbred breeders in the State.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The simulcast signal shall be encoded.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The licensee of the receiving track may not transmit the simulcast signal beyond the premises where pari-mutuel betting is allowed.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(h)">Notwithstanding the provisions of subsection (f) of this section, if a track where racing is conducted by the State Fair Society is within the 35-mile radius of a mile thoroughbred track, it shall first obtain the concurrence of that mile thoroughbred track before it may be a receiving track during a period of time when the State Fair Society is not licensed to conduct live racing.</section>
  </text>
</law>
