<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gbr" order_by="" level="1">Business Regulation</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gbr-8-501</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>501</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">A home improvement contract that does not comply with this section is not invalid merely because of noncompliance.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Each home improvement contract shall:<section prefix="(1)">be in writing and legible;</section><section prefix="(2)">describe clearly each document that it incorporates; and</section><section prefix="(3)">be signed by each party to the home improvement contract.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In addition to any other matters on which the parties lawfully agree, each home improvement contract shall contain:<section prefix="(i)">the name, address, telephone number, and license number of the contractor;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the name and license number of each salesperson who solicited the home improvement contract or sold the home improvement;</section><section prefix="(iii)">the approximate dates when the performance of the home improvement will begin and when it will be substantially completed;</section><section prefix="(iv)">a description of the home improvement to be performed and the materials to be used;</section><section prefix="(v)">the agreed consideration;</section><section prefix="(vi)">the number of monthly payments and the amount of each payment, including any finance charge;</section><section prefix="(vii)">a description of any collateral security for the obligation of the owner under the home improvement contract;</section><section prefix="(viii)">a notice that gives the telephone number and Web site of the Commission and states that:<section prefix="1.">each contractor and each subcontractor must be licensed by the Commission; and</section><section prefix="2.">anyone may ask the Commission about a contractor or subcontractor; and</section></section><section prefix="(ix)">a notice set by the Commission by regulation that:<section prefix="1.">specifies the protections available to consumers through the Commission; and</section><section prefix="2.">advises the consumer of the right to purchase a performance bond for additional protection against loss.</section></section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If payment for work performed under the home improvement contract will be secured by an interest in residential real estate, a written notice in not smaller than 10 point bold type that is on the first page of the contract shall state in substantially the following form: "This contract creates a mortgage or lien against your property to secure payment and may cause a loss of your property if you fail to pay the amount agreed upon. You have the right to consult an attorney. You have the right to rescind this contract within 3 business days after the date you sign it by notifying the contractor in writing that you are rescinding the contract."</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The notice under paragraph (2) of this subsection shall be independently initialed by the homeowner.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Before the performance of a home improvement begins, the owner shall be given a copy of the home improvement contract signed by the contractor.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">A salesperson or other agent or employee of a contractor may not make a change in a home improvement contract for an owner.</section>
  </text>
</law>
