<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gbr" order_by="gbr" level="1">Business Regulation</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gbr-16.5-205</section_number>
  <catch_line>An other tobacco products manufacturer may:...</catch_line>
  <order_by>205</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">An other tobacco products manufacturer may:<section prefix="(1)">sell other tobacco products on which the tobacco tax has not been paid to:<section prefix="(i)">a licensed other tobacco products wholesaler located in Maryland;</section><section prefix="(ii)">a licensed other tobacco products wholesaler located outside Maryland if the other tobacco products may be sold lawfully in Maryland; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">a licensed tobacconist;</section></section><section prefix="(2)">sell premium cigars or pipe tobacco on which the tobacco tax has not been paid to a licensed other tobacco products retailer;</section><section prefix="(3)">except as otherwise prohibited or restricted under local law, this article, or the Criminal Law Article, distribute sample other tobacco products to consumers located in Maryland;</section><section prefix="(4)">store other tobacco products on which the tobacco tax has not been paid in a licensed other tobacco products storage warehouse for subsequent shipment to licensed other tobacco products wholesalers, federal reservations, or persons out of state; and</section><section prefix="(5)">on approval of the Comptroller, act as an agent of a Maryland other tobacco products wholesaler for distribution of other tobacco products.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">An other tobacco products retailer license authorizes the licensee to:<section prefix="(1)">act as an other tobacco products retailer;</section><section prefix="(2)">buy other tobacco products on which the tobacco tax has been paid from an other tobacco products wholesaler; and</section><section prefix="(3)">buy premium cigars or pipe tobacco on which the tobacco tax has not been paid from an other tobacco products manufacturer.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">An other tobacco products storage warehouse license authorizes the licensee to operate a storage facility in Maryland for the purpose of storing other tobacco products on which the tobacco tax has not been paid on behalf of a licensed other tobacco products manufacturer.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If an other tobacco products storage warehouse licensee is a licensed other tobacco products wholesaler, the other tobacco products storage warehouse license authorizes the holder to store other tobacco products on which the tobacco tax has been paid and other tobacco products on which the tobacco tax has been paid to another state.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">An other tobacco products wholesaler license authorizes the licensee to:<section prefix="(1)">act as an other tobacco products wholesaler;</section><section prefix="(2)">buy other tobacco products on which the tobacco tax has not been paid directly from an other tobacco products manufacturer;</section><section prefix="(3)">hold other tobacco products on which the tobacco tax has not been paid;</section><section prefix="(4)">transport other tobacco products on which the tobacco tax has not been paid in the State;</section><section prefix="(5)">sell other tobacco products on which the tobacco tax has not been paid to another licensed other tobacco products wholesaler if the Comptroller specifically authorizes; and</section><section prefix="(6)">store other tobacco products on which the tobacco tax has not been paid at a licensed other tobacco products storage warehouse.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">A tobacconist license authorizes the licensee to:<section prefix="(1)">act as a tobacconist; and</section><section prefix="(2)">buy other tobacco products on which the tobacco tax has not been paid from an other tobacco products manufacturer.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
