<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gbr" order_by="gbr" level="1">Business Regulation</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gbr-3-406</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this section, "workday" means a day that is not a Saturday, a Sunday, or a State holiday....</catch_line>
  <order_by>406</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, "workday" means a day that is not a Saturday, a Sunday, or a State holiday.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">If, after an inspection or investigation, the Commissioner finds that, within the immediately preceding 6 months, an amusement owner has violated this title or an order passed or regulation adopted under this title, the Commissioner promptly shall issue a citation to the amusement owner.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Each citation shall:<section prefix="(1)">describe, in detail, the nature of the alleged violation;</section><section prefix="(2)">cite the provision of this title, order, or regulation that the amusement owner is alleged to have violated; and</section><section prefix="(3)">set a reasonable time for correction of the alleged violation.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Within a reasonable time after issuance of a citation, the Commissioner shall send by certified mail to the amusement owner a notice that:<section prefix="(1)">states the proposed civil penalty, if any, that the Commissioner intends to impose under this title; and</section><section prefix="(2)">informs the amusement owner of the right to a hearing under this section.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">In accordance with any regulation that the Commissioner adopts under this title, an amusement owner who receives a citation shall post the citation or a copy of it conspicuously at or near each place where the citation alleges that a violation occurred.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">Within 15 workdays after an amusement owner receives a notice under subsection (d) of this section, the amusement owner may submit to the Commissioner a written request for a hearing on the citation or proposed civil penalty.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">Unless an amusement owner requests a hearing as provided in this section, a citation and a notice of a proposed civil penalty are final orders.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">After an opportunity for a hearing under this section, the Commissioner may pass an order that affirms or modifies a requirement of a citation for correction of a violation if the amusement owner shows that the amusement owner:<section prefix="(1)">has made a good faith effort to comply with the requirement; but</section><section prefix="(2)">has not complied because of a factor beyond the reasonable control of the amusement owner.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(i)">An amusement owner shall correct each violation for which the Commissioner issues a citation within the time set for correction in a final order under this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(j)">If the Commissioner has reason to believe that an amusement owner has failed to correct a violation in a timely manner, the Commissioner shall send by certified mail to the amusement owner a notice that:<section prefix="(1)">states that the amusement owner has failed to correct the violation;</section><section prefix="(2)">states the proposed civil penalty, if any, that the Commissioner intends to impose under this title for the failure; and</section><section prefix="(3)">informs the amusement owner that, within 15 workdays after receipt of the notice, the amusement owner may submit to the Commissioner a written request for a hearing on the failure to correct the violation or proposed civil penalty.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(k)">Unless an amusement owner requests a hearing as provided in this section, the notice, including any proposed civil penalty, is a final order.</section>
    <section prefix="(l)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Whenever the Commissioner receives a request for a hearing made in accordance with this section, the Commissioner shall hold a hearing.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">To the extent practicable, the hearing shall be held within 30 days after receipt of the request.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(m)">The Commissioner shall give notice and hold the hearing under this section in accordance with Title 10, Subtitle 2 of the State Government Article.</section>
    <section prefix="(n)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If a hearing examiner or other officer is appointed to hold a hearing under this section, the officer shall prepare a record that includes testimony.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The officer shall submit a report to the Commissioner and send a copy of the report to any amusement owner affected by the report.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The report becomes final unless, within 10 workdays after the report, the amusement owner submits a written request for a review of the proceeding by the Commissioner.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">After a review of a proceeding under this subsection, with or without a hearing, the Commissioner shall pass an order based on findings of fact. The order shall affirm, modify, or vacate the citation or proposed civil penalty or direct other appropriate relief.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">An order of the Commissioner under paragraph (4) of this subsection is final 15 days after passage of the order.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
