<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gbr" order_by="gbr" level="1">Business Regulation</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gbr-12-301</section_number>
  <catch_line>Each dealer shall make a written record, on a form provided by the Secretary, of each business trans...</catch_line>
  <order_by>301</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Each dealer shall make a written record, on a form provided by the Secretary, of each business transaction that involves the acquisition of a secondhand precious metal object when the transaction is made.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Each dealer shall retain the original copy of the written record required to be made under paragraph (1) of this subsection at the dealer's place of business.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Each pawnbroker shall make a written record, on a form provided by the Secretary, of each business transaction that involves:<section prefix="(1)">lending money on pledge of personal property, other than a security or printed evidence of indebtedness;</section><section prefix="(2)">buying personal property on condition of selling it back at a stipulated price; or</section><section prefix="(3)">buying the following items for the purpose of resale:<section prefix="(i)">binoculars;</section><section prefix="(ii)">cameras;</section><section prefix="(iii)">firearms;</section><section prefix="(iv)">furs;</section><section prefix="(v)">household appliances;</section><section prefix="(vi)">musical instruments;</section><section prefix="(vii)">office machines or equipment;</section><section prefix="(viii)">radios, televisions, videodisc machines, videocassette recorders, and stereo equipment;</section><section prefix="(ix)">personal computers, tapes, and disc recorders;</section><section prefix="(x)">watches;</section><section prefix="(xi)">bicycles; and</section><section prefix="(xii)">tangible personal property pledged as collateral.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Each pawnbroker shall make a written record, on a form provided by the Secretary, of each transaction that involves the acquisition of an item described in subsection (b)(3) of this section for the purpose of resale.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A separate record entry shall be made for each item involved in a transaction.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Items in a matching set may be recorded as a set if acquired in a single transaction.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">During the holding period required under &#xA7; 12-305 of this subtitle, a dealer may place all of the items acquired in a single transaction in a secure container that has been approved by the primary law enforcement unit, if:<section prefix="(1)">each item in the transaction has a separate record entry in the written record required under this section; and</section><section prefix="(2)">the secure container is tagged by the dealer with the number that corresponds to the transaction under which the items were acquired and the written record listing the items obtained in the transaction.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">When a dealer places items into their inventory, the dealer shall tag each item individually with a number that corresponds to the transaction under which it was acquired. However, items acquired in a matching set may be tagged as a set.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Each item tagged by a dealer under paragraph (1)  of this subsection shall remain tagged for the entire period the item is stored in the dealer's inventory.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">For the purposes of this subtitle, there is a presumption that an object is a precious metal object if:<section prefix="(1)">it reasonably appears to be a precious metal object; and</section><section prefix="(2)">it was received by a dealer in the course of business or is found in the place of business or storage facility of a dealer.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
