<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gbr" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="8-302" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gbr-8-302</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">An applicant for a contractor's, subcontractor's, or salesperson's license must pass the examination prior to submitting an application for a license.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">An applicant may receive a license only if the applicant passes the examination that the Commission requires.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">To take an examination, an applicant shall pay to the Commission or a testing service chosen by the Commission the examination fee set by the Commission to cover the cost of the examination.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The examination fee is nonrefundable.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Commission shall schedule the applicant for an examination to be held within 45 days after the Commission receives an application for examination.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The examination shall be held at a location:<section prefix="(i)">that is within the general geographic area where the applicant resides, if the applicant resides in the State; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">that the Commission determines, if the applicant resides out of State.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The Commission shall give each qualified applicant notice of the time and place of examination.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as otherwise provided in this section, the Commission shall determine the subjects, scope, and form of and the passing score for examinations.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The examination shall test:<section prefix="(i)">the applicant's knowledge of the law about home improvement; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">the applicant's competency to engage in the licensed occupation.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The competency part of the examination may be oral or written.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Commission may use a testing service to administer the examinations given under this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If the Commission uses a testing service under this subsection, the testing service, subject to the requirements set by the Commission, may:<section prefix="(i)">set the time and place of examinations;</section><section prefix="(ii)">give qualified applicants notice of the time and place of examinations; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">furnish any other information that the Commission may require the testing service to provide.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(h)">Within 30 days after the first meeting of the Commission after an examination date, the Commission shall notify an applicant in writing of the examination score of the applicant.</section>
  </text>
</law>
