<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gbr" order_by="" level="1">Business Regulation</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gbr-10-311</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>311</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Except as provided in subsections (c) and (d) of this section, each retail service station in the State:<section prefix="(1)">shall be operated by a retail service station dealer; and</section><section prefix="(2)">may not be operated by a producer or refiner of motor fuel:<section prefix="(i)">with a commissioned agent, company personnel, or a subsidiary company; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">under a contract with a person who manages the station on a fee arrangement with the producer or refiner.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">This section does not apply to facilities that an agricultural cooperative association owns and operates if:<section prefix="(1)">the agricultural cooperative association is certified by a bank for cooperatives to be eligible to borrow from the bank under Subchapter III of the federal Farm Credit Act of 1971;</section><section prefix="(2)">the certification is submitted to the Comptroller with the application for registration of a retail service station dealer under this subtitle;</section><section prefix="(3)">the agricultural cooperative association owns the property on which the facilities are located; and</section><section prefix="(4)">on the property, the agricultural cooperative association, as part of its business, sells or provides farm supplies or farm business services or distributes motor fuel in bulk to farmers on farms.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A retail service station shall be exempt from subsection (a) of this section for a fiscal year that starts July 1, if:<section prefix="(1)">on January 1, 1979, the station was operated by a subsidiary of a producer or refiner of motor fuel; and</section><section prefix="(2)">the gross revenues of the subsidiary from the sale of motor fuel in the State for the preceding calendar year is less than 2% of the gross revenues of the subsidiary from all retail operations in the State for the preceding calendar year.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">If a dealer has previously operated a retail service station, the Comptroller may adopt regulations that define the circumstances in which a producer or refiner temporarily may operate the station.</section>
  </text>
</law>
