<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gbr" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="12.5-303" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gbr-12.5-303</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A licensed locksmith shall provide to a local law enforcement unit or the Department a copy of each invoice or receipt for services requested by either a local law enforcement unit or the Department.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Secretary shall encourage licensed locksmiths to develop a system for maintaining the records required by this subtitle electronically.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">On a request for an invoice or a receipt for services under subsection (a) of this section, the licensed locksmith shall submit the item by one of the following methods:<section prefix="(1)">by delivering or mailing a copy of the invoice or receipt for services within 5 business days after receiving the request; or</section><section prefix="(2)">by transmitting a copy of the invoice or receipt for services electronically, in a format acceptable to the receiving local law enforcement unit or the Department, within 2 business days after receiving the request.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Each copy of an invoice or a receipt for services, submitted to the local law enforcement unit or the Department, shall include:<section prefix="(1)">the license number of the licensed locksmith; and</section><section prefix="(2)">the information required under &#xA7; 12.5-301 of this subtitle.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A copy of an invoice or receipt for services submitted under this section:<section prefix="(1)">shall be kept confidential;</section><section prefix="(2)">is not a public record; and</section><section prefix="(3)">is not subject to Title 10, Subtitle 6 of the State Government Article.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">A local law enforcement unit or the Department may destroy the copy of an invoice or receipt for services submitted under this section after 1 year from the date the local law enforcement unit or the Department receives the copy.</section>
  </text>
</law>
