<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gbr" order_by="gbr" level="1">Business Regulation</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gbr-16-603</section_number>
  <catch_line>** CONTINGENCY - IN EFFECT - CHAPTER 497 OF 2007 **...</catch_line>
  <order_by>603</order_by>
  <text>** CONTINGENCY - IN EFFECT - CHAPTER 497 OF 2007 **<section prefix="(a)"><section prefix="(1)">Each manufacturer shall submit to the Comptroller written certification attesting that each cigarette has been tested in accordance with and has met the performance standard required under &#xA7; 16-602 of this subtitle.</section><section prefix="(2)">A certification under paragraph (1) of this subsection may not list more than 50 cigarettes.</section></section><section prefix="(b)">The description of each cigarette listed in the certification shall include:<section prefix="(1)">the brand or trade name on the package;</section><section prefix="(2)">the style, such as light or ultra light;</section><section prefix="(3)">the length in millimeters;</section><section prefix="(4)">the circumference in millimeters;</section><section prefix="(5)">the flavor, such as menthol or chocolate, if applicable;</section><section prefix="(6)">whether filtered or nonfiltered;</section><section prefix="(7)">a package description, such as a soft pack or box;</section><section prefix="(8)">the mark approved in accordance with &#xA7; 16-604 of this subtitle;</section><section prefix="(9)">if different from the manufacturer, the name, address, and telephone number of the laboratory that conducted the test; and</section><section prefix="(10)">the date of the testing.</section></section><section prefix="(c)">The certification shall be made available to:<section prefix="(1)">the Attorney General and the Commission for purposes consistent with this subtitle; and</section><section prefix="(2)">the Comptroller for the purpose of ensuring compliance with this section.</section></section><section prefix="(d)"><section prefix="(1)">Each cigarette certified under this section shall be recertified every 3 years.</section><section prefix="(2)">If a manufacturer of a cigarette that has been certified under this section makes a change that is likely to  alter the cigarette's compliance with the performance standard under &#xA7; 16-602(e) of this subtitle, that cigarette may not be sold in this State until the manufacturer, in accordance with &#xA7; 16-602 of this subtitle, retests and maintains the proper records of the testing.</section></section></text>
</law>
