<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gbr" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="14-103" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gbr-14-103</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">This subtitle applies to an offer to sell or sale of a business opportunity if:<section prefix="(1)">the offeree or buyer is a resident of the State;</section><section prefix="(2)">the business opportunity will be or is operated in the State;</section><section prefix="(3)">the offer to sell is made in the State; or</section><section prefix="(4)">the offer to buy is accepted in the State.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">For purposes of this section, an offer to sell is made in the State, whether or not either party is then present in the State, if the offer:<section prefix="(i)">originates from the State; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">is directed by the offeror to the State and is received at:</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">For purposes of this section, an offer to sell is not made in the State only because the publisher circulates or there is circulated on the publisher's behalf in the State:<section prefix="(i)">a newspaper or other publication of general, regular, and paid circulation that:</section><section prefix="(ii)">a radio or television program that originates outside the State and is received in the State.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">For purposes of this section, an offer to buy is accepted in the State if acceptance:<section prefix="(i)">is communicated to the offeror in the State; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">has not been communicated previously to the offeror, orally or in writing, outside the State.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">For purposes of this section, acceptance is communicated to the offeror in the State, whether or not either party is then present in the State, if:<section prefix="(i)">the offeree directs acceptance to the offeror in the State reasonably believing the offeror to be in the State; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">the acceptance is received at:</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
