<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gbr" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="11-525" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gbr-11-525</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">On all races the State Fair Society holds each year, the State Fair Society may keep:<section prefix="(1)">10.25% of each regular mutuel pool;</section><section prefix="(2)">10.25% of each multiple mutuel pool on 2 horses;</section><section prefix="(3)">10.25% of the money bet in the first race of the day with a multiple mutuel pool on 3 or more horses;</section><section prefix="(4)">14% of the money bet in every other race with a multiple mutuel pool on 3 or more horses; and</section><section prefix="(5)">50% of the breakage.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Within 5 days after the end of a race meeting the State Fair Society each year shall pay to the Commission, from the State Fair Society's share of the takeout, a 3.5% State tax on the handle for the race meeting.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">However, the State Fair Society is exempt from paying the tax on the handle for all racing days held at Timonium Race Course during the State Fair.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Commission promptly shall pay the tax collected under this subsection to the Comptroller.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">For each race that the State Fair Society holds, the State Fair Society shall allocate to purses:<section prefix="(1)">5% of each regular mutuel pool;</section><section prefix="(2)">7% of each multiple mutuel pool on 2 horses;</section><section prefix="(3)">13% of the money bet in the first race of the day with a multiple mutuel pool on 3 or more horses;</section><section prefix="(4)">9.25% of the money bet in every other race with a multiple mutuel pool on 3 or more horses; and</section><section prefix="(5)">45% of the breakage.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The State Fair Society shall allocate to the Maryland-Bred Race Fund:<section prefix="(1)">5% of the breakage; and</section><section prefix="(2)">1.50% of the mutuel pools.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The State Fair Society shall allocate 0.25% of the mutuel pools to the Maryland Race Track Employees Pension Fund.</section>
  </text>
</law>
