<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gbr" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="19-103" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gbr-19-103</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, "truck stop" means a facility:<section prefix="(1)">the primary purpose of which is to provide services to long-haul truck drivers; and</section><section prefix="(2)">that provides:<section prefix="(i)">shower facilities to the truck drivers for a fee; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">parking for the truck drivers' vehicles.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The owner of a privately owned bus station or truck stop shall post the National Human Trafficking Resource Center Hotline information sign described in &#xA7; 15-207 of this article in each restroom of the bus station or truck stop.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A sign required under this section shall be posted:<section prefix="(i)">on the inside of each stall door in the restroom; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">on the back of the door at the entrance to the restroom.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">An agency that enforces this section and determines that a violation of this section has occurred shall notify the business owner of the bus station or truck stop, or the business owner's agent, of the violation.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If the business owner of the bus station or truck stop does not post signs as required under this section within 24 hours after receiving the notice required under paragraph (1) of this subsection, the business owner is subject to a civil penalty not exceeding $1,000.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">For each restroom in which a business owner fails to post a sign in accordance with this section, the business owner is subject to a separate civil penalty.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
