<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gbr" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="8-301" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gbr-8-301</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Except as otherwise provided in this title, a person must have a contractor license whenever the person acts as a contractor in the State.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Except as otherwise provided in this title, a person must have a subcontractor license or contractor license whenever the person acts as a subcontractor in the State.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Except as otherwise provided in this title, a person must have a salesperson license or contractor license whenever the person sells a home improvement in the State.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">This section does not apply to:<section prefix="(1)">an individual who works for a contractor or subcontractor for a salary or wages but who is not a salesperson for the contractor;</section><section prefix="(2)">a clerical employee, retail clerk, or other employee of a licensed contractor who is not a salesperson, as to a transaction on the premises of the licensed contractor;</section><section prefix="(3)">a solicitor for a contractor who calls an owner by telephone only;</section><section prefix="(4)">an architect, electrician, plumber, heating, ventilation, air-conditioning, or refrigeration contractor, or other person who:<section prefix="(i)">is required by State or local law to meet standards of competency or experience before engaging in an occupation or profession;</section><section prefix="(ii)">currently is licensed in that occupation or profession under State or local law; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">is:</section></section><section prefix="(5)">a security systems technician licensed under Title 18 of the Business Occupations and Professions Article;</section><section prefix="(6)">a marine contractor licensed under Title 17, Subtitle 3 of the Environment Article; or</section><section prefix="(7)">a person who is selling a home improvement to be performed by a person described in item (4) of this subsection.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
