<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gbr" order_by="gbr" level="1">Business Regulation</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gbr-5-606</section_number>
  <catch_line>Each sole proprietor registered cemeterian, permit holder, or any other person subject to the trust ...</catch_line>
  <order_by>606</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Each sole proprietor registered cemeterian, permit holder, or any other person subject to the trust requirements of this subtitle shall keep detailed records of all sales of burial lots or burial rights in a cemetery and money received.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The records of each sole proprietor registered cemeterian, permit holder, or any other person subject to the trust requirements of this subtitle and of each trustee appointed by the sole proprietor registered cemeterian, permit holder, or any other person subject to the trust requirements of this subtitle are subject to examination by:<section prefix="(i)">the Director;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the Attorney General or an authorized representative of the Attorney General; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">the State's Attorney for the county where the cemetery owner does business or where the cemetery is located.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Each sole proprietor registered cemeterian, permit holder, or any other person subject to the trust requirements of this subtitle shall submit a report to the Director within 120 days after the close of each calendar or other fiscal year chosen by the sole proprietor registered cemeterian, permit holder, or any other person subject to the trust requirements of this subtitle.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The report shall:<section prefix="(i)">be on the form that the Director requires;</section><section prefix="(ii)">be certified as to correctness by a certified public accountant retained by the cemetery;</section><section prefix="(iii)">be accompanied by a trustee's annual summary statement of assets for the reporting period that includes:<section prefix="1.">the amount of money in the perpetual care trust fund at the beginning of the reporting period;</section><section prefix="2.">an investment portfolio summary describing the asset and the market value for each investment class;</section><section prefix="3.">a transaction summary of the perpetual care trust fund containing:</section><section prefix="4.">the amount of money in the perpetual care trust fund at the end of the reporting period;</section></section><section prefix="(iv)">be accompanied by a fee of $25; and</section><section prefix="(v)">include:<section prefix="1.">the name of the sole proprietor registered cemeterian, permit holder, or any other person subject to the trust requirements of this subtitle;</section><section prefix="2.">each location of the sole proprietor registered cemeterian, permit holder, or any other person subject to the trust requirements of this subtitle;</section><section prefix="3.">the amount of money in each perpetual care trust fund at the beginning of the calendar or other fiscal year chosen by the sole proprietor registered cemeterian, permit holder, or any other person subject to the trust requirements of this subtitle;</section><section prefix="4.">the amount of money that the sole proprietor registered cemeterian, permit holder, or any other person subject to the trust requirements of this subtitle received during that year that is subject to the trust requirements of this subtitle;</section><section prefix="5.">the amount of money actually deposited into each perpetual care trust fund in that year;</section><section prefix="6.">the amount of money spent during that year to provide care, maintenance, administration, and embellishment of each cemetery, except for money used for the care of monuments and memorials; and</section><section prefix="7.">the name and address of each trustee.</section></section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">If the Director determines, after a review of the report and annual summary statement of assets required by this subsection, that additional documentation is required, a sole proprietor registered cemeterian, permit holder, or any other person subject to the trust requirements of this subtitle shall provide the additional documentation to the Director.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">A sole proprietor registered cemeterian, permit holder, or any other person subject to the trust requirements of this subtitle who stops selling burial lots or burial rights in a cemetery as to which perpetual care is stated or implied shall notify the Director in the required report for the year in which sales stop.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">The Director may require a sole proprietor registered cemeterian, permit holder, or any other person subject to the trust requirements of this subtitle to correct any underfunding, including interest, due to the perpetual care trust fund.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Director may adopt regulations:<section prefix="(1)">to administer subsection (b) of this section; and</section><section prefix="(2)">for determining whether registered cemeterians, permit holders, or any other person subject to the trust requirements of this subtitle are complying with this subtitle.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
