<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gbr" order_by="" level="1">Business Regulation</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gbr-16.5-210</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>210</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Subject to the notice requirement of subsection (c) of this section, if a licensee engages in an act or omission that is a ground for discipline under &#xA7; 16.5-208 of this subtitle, the Comptroller may suspend the license for a consecutive period that:<section prefix="(1)">for a first offense, is not less than 5 nor more than 20 business days; or</section><section prefix="(2)">for a subsequent offense, is not less than 20 business days nor more than 6 months.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Subject to the notice requirement under subsection (c) of this section, the Comptroller may revoke a license if a licensee:<section prefix="(1)">willfully and persistently engages in an act or omission that is a ground for discipline under &#xA7; 16.5-208(a) of this subtitle; or</section><section prefix="(2)">violates this title or Title 12 of the Tax - General Article or regulations adopted under these titles.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">If a license is suspended or revoked under this section:<section prefix="(1)">the Comptroller shall give the licensee notice of the suspension or revocation; and</section><section prefix="(2)">the suspension or revocation may not take effect until at least 5 business days following notice of the suspension or revocation.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The transfer, renewal, or expiration of a license will not bar or abate a disciplinary action under this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except for a violation of &#xA7; 10-107 of the Criminal Law Article, whenever any license issued under the provisions of this subtitle is suspended or revoked by the Comptroller, the licensee may, before the effective date of the suspension or revocation, petition the Comptroller for permission to make an offer of compromise consisting of a sum of money in lieu of serving the suspension or revocation.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Money paid in lieu of suspension or revocation shall be paid into the General Fund of the State.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">An offer of compromise may not exceed $2,000 in the case of retail licensees and may not exceed $50,000 for other licensees.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The Comptroller may accept the offer of compromise if:<section prefix="(i)">the public welfare and morals would not be impaired by allowing the licensee to operate during the period set for the suspension or revocation; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">the payment of the sum of money will achieve the desired disciplinary purposes.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(5)">The Comptroller may adopt regulations to carry out this subsection.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
