<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gbr" order_by="gbr" level="1">Business Regulation</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gbr-9A-306</section_number>
  <catch_line>The Board shall issue without examination a master, master restricted, or limited heating, ventilati...</catch_line>
  <order_by>306</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Board shall issue without examination a master, master restricted, or limited heating, ventilation, air-conditioning, and refrigeration contractor license to any licensee holding a current, active or inactive master, master restricted, or limited heating, ventilation, air-conditioning, and refrigeration contractor license, or a similar license issued by a subdivision of the State, if the licensee:<section prefix="(1)">files an application for a license under this title by 1 year after the date that the members of the Board are appointed; and</section><section prefix="(2)">submits with the application the prescribed fee and proof of eligibility required by the Board.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Board shall issue without examination a master, master restricted, or limited heating, ventilation, air-conditioning, and refrigeration contractor license, whether a subdivision of the State requires a local license or not, to an individual who:<section prefix="(1)">has lawfully provided heating, ventilation, air-conditioning, or refrigeration services in a subdivision of the State for at least 5 years immediately prior to 1 year after the date the members of the Board are appointed;</section><section prefix="(2)">files an application for a license under this title prior to 1 year after the date the members of the Board are appointed; and</section><section prefix="(3)">submits with the application the prescribed fee and proof of eligibility required by the Board.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Board shall issue without examination a journeyman license to an individual holding a current, active or inactive, journeyman license, or a similar license issued by a subdivision of the State, if the individual:<section prefix="(1)">files an application for a license under this title prior to December 31, 1994; and</section><section prefix="(2)">submits with the application the prescribed fee and proof of eligibility required by the Board.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Board shall issue without examination a journeyman license, whether a subdivision of the State requires a local license or not, to an individual who:<section prefix="(1)">has lawfully provided heating, ventilation, air-conditioning, or refrigeration services in a subdivision of the State:<section prefix="(i)">under the direction and control of one or more individuals who meet the requirements for a master license under subsection (a) or (b) of this section; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">for at least 3 years prior to December 31, 1994;</section></section><section prefix="(2)">holds an apprentice license at the time of the application;</section><section prefix="(3)">files an application for a license under this title prior to December 31, 1994; and</section><section prefix="(4)">submits with the application the prescribed fee and proof of eligibility required by the Board.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Board shall issue without examination a journeyman license to an individual who has successfully completed an apprentice program in heating, ventilation, air-conditioning, and refrigeration approved by the Apprenticeship and Training Council.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Board shall issue without examination a journeyman restricted license to an individual who has successfully completed an apprentice program in heating, ventilation, air-conditioning, or refrigeration approved by the Apprenticeship and Training Council.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">All applicants for a master, master restricted, or limited heating, ventilation, air-conditioning, and refrigeration contractor license on or after 1 year after the date the members of the Board are appointed shall submit to examination under this title.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The application shall include all information required by the Board regarding proof of eligibility.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in subsection (e) of this section, all applicants for a journeyman license on or after January 1, 1995 shall submit to examination under this title.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The application shall include all information required by the Board regarding proof of eligibility.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(h)">An applicant who qualifies for a license under subsection (a) or (b) of this section but fails to apply for the license within the 1-year period:<section prefix="(1)">may take an examination under this title to be licensed;</section><section prefix="(2)">may not be required to obtain a journeyman license or an apprentice license; and</section><section prefix="(3)">may provide services as a master, master restricted, or limited license holder after obtaining the appropriate license.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(i)">An individual who holds a limited license or a master restricted license issued under subsection (a) or (b) of this section may take an examination administered by the Board to qualify for a master license or an additional master restricted license without meeting the requirements of &#xA7; 9A-302 of this subtitle, if the individual:<section prefix="(1)">submits to the Board on or before December 31, 1996 an application on the form that the Board provides; and</section><section prefix="(2)">pays to the Board an application fee established by the Board.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
