<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gbr" order_by="gbr" level="1">Business Regulation</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gbr-6-509</section_number>
  <catch_line>The only persons liable under this section are:...</catch_line>
  <order_by>509</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The only persons liable under this section are:<section prefix="(1)">charitable organizations;</section><section prefix="(2)">charitable representatives; and</section><section prefix="(3)">officers, directors, partners, or trustees of charitable organizations or charitable representatives.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Except as provided in subsection (d) of this section, a person who willfully fails to comply with a requirement of this title as to a charitable contribution made because of a charitable solicitation is liable to the donor of the charitable contribution for:<section prefix="(1)">actual damages that the donor sustains because of the failure;</section><section prefix="(2)">punitive damages that the court allows, not exceeding 3 times the actual damages; and</section><section prefix="(3)">reasonable attorney's fees and costs of the action, if damages are awarded.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Except as provided in subsection (d) of this section, a person who is grossly negligent in failing to comply with a requirement of this title as to a charitable contribution made because of a charitable solicitation is liable to the donor of the charitable contribution for:<section prefix="(1)">actual damages that the donor sustains because of the failure; and</section><section prefix="(2)">reasonable attorney's fees and costs of the action, if damages are awarded.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A person is not liable under this section if the person establishes by a preponderance of the evidence that, at the time of the failure to comply with a requirement under this title, the person followed reasonable procedures to comply.</section>
  </text>
</law>
