<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gbr" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="4.5-706" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gbr-4.5-706</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">To begin a proceeding to recover from the Guaranty Fund, a claimant shall submit to the Division's mediation unit a written complaint that states:<section prefix="(1)">the amount claimed based on the actual loss;</section><section prefix="(2)">the facts giving rise to the claim;</section><section prefix="(3)">whether there is other evidence that supports the claim, including expert reports, photographs, or videotapes and that the evidence is included with the complaint;</section><section prefix="(4)">what documents are related to the claim and that copies of the documents are attached, including the contract of sale; and</section><section prefix="(5)">any other information that the Division requires.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Division's mediation unit shall:<section prefix="(1)">send a copy of the complaint to the registrant alleged to be responsible for the actual loss;</section><section prefix="(2)">require a written response to the complaint within 30 days that includes:<section prefix="(i)">any evidence the registrant has concerning the claim, including expert reports, photographs, or videotapes; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">any other information that the Division requires;</section></section><section prefix="(3)">attempt to resolve the complaint through mediation, taking into consideration applicable laws, including express and implied warranties and the provisions of &#xA7; 4.5-401 of this title; and</section><section prefix="(4)">refer the complaint to the Division as a claim against the Guaranty Fund if:<section prefix="(i)"/><section prefix="(ii)">the claimant executes a claim form prepared by the Division stating under oath that the claimant wishes to seek recovery from the Guaranty Fund.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If a claimant's new home contract includes a written agreement with a registrant to submit a dispute to arbitration and the agreement authorizes:<section prefix="(i)">the registrant to select the arbitrator or the arbitration service, the claimant may elect whether to first seek recovery from the Guaranty Fund or submit the dispute to arbitration; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">if the claimant's new home contract provides for mutual selection of the arbitration service and the claimant and registrant have mutually agreed on an arbitration service, the claimant must submit the dispute to arbitration prior to seeking recovery from the Guaranty Fund.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If the claimant and the registrant submit the dispute to arbitration under the written agreement in the contract and the arbitrator makes a final judgment or final award in favor of the claimant:<section prefix="(i)">the claimant may make a claim against the Guaranty Fund; but</section><section prefix="(ii)">if the registrant pays the award amount to the claimant within 90 days of the final award, the Division shall dismiss the claim against the Guaranty Fund.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
