<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gbr" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="6-302" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gbr-6-302</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">An applicant for registration as a professional solicitor or fund-raising counsel shall:<section prefix="(1)">submit to the Secretary of State an application under oath on the form that the Secretary of State provides;</section><section prefix="(2)">consent in writing to the jurisdiction and venue of the Circuit Court for Anne Arundel County in actions brought under this title;</section><section prefix="(3)">pay to the Secretary of State an application fee of:<section prefix="(i)">$200 for registration as a fund-raising counsel; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">$300 for registration as a professional solicitor; and</section></section><section prefix="(4)"><section prefix="(i)">certify that all taxes due from the applicant to the State or to Baltimore City or a county of the State during the preceding fiscal year have been paid, and all taxes the applicant was required to collect and pay over to the State or to Baltimore City or a county of the State during the preceding fiscal year have been collected and paid over; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">certify that the taxes due from the applicant to the State or to Baltimore City or a county are under dispute and the dispute has not been finally resolved.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">An applicant for registration as a fund-raising counsel may register and pay a single application fee of $200 to cover all of the applicant's officers, agents, members, and employees who work in fund-raising, if the applicant lists in the application the name and address of each of them.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">An applicant for registration as a professional solicitor may register and pay a single application fee of $300 to cover all of the applicant's officers, agents, members, associate solicitors, and employees who work in fund-raising, if the applicant:<section prefix="(i)">lists in the application the name of each current officer, agent, member, associate solicitor, and employee who works in fund-raising; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">submits to the Secretary of State the name of each person within 10 days after the person starts employment.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
