<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gbr" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="6-201" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gbr-6-201</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, "Program" means the Charitable Giving Information Program.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">There is a Charitable Giving Information Program in the Office of the Secretary of State.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The purpose of the Program is to educate the public about charitable organizations and charitable solicitations so that members of the public can:<section prefix="(1)">recognize unlawful or misleading charitable solicitations; and</section><section prefix="(2)">make informed decisions about charitable contributions to charitable organizations.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Program shall inform the public of:<section prefix="(1)">the laws and regulations about charitable organizations and charitable solicitations, including registration requirements, prohibited acts and penalties, and the availability of information through the Office of the Secretary of State;</section><section prefix="(2)">the importance of reporting alleged unlawful or misleading charitable solicitations to the Office of the Secretary of State;</section><section prefix="(3)">an address and toll-free telephone number through which the public can get information about charitable organizations and charitable solicitations and can report alleged violations of this title;</section><section prefix="(4)">precautions an individual may take before making a charitable contribution to a charitable organization; and</section><section prefix="(5)">any other information the Secretary of State believes will help the public make informed decisions about charitable contributions to charitable organizations.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The Program shall make available:<section prefix="(1)">written materials, in places easily accessible to the public, including libraries, schools, and other public buildings;</section><section prefix="(2)">on request, individuals to speak to community groups or other groups; and</section><section prefix="(3)">material for broad distribution to the public or for use by the news media.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Program may make available a disk containing computerized data if:<section prefix="(i)">the Secretary of State determines that making the disk available serves the purposes of the Program; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">the person agrees in writing to use the disk only for purposes approved by the Secretary of State, and not to copy the disk, or permit the disk to be copied, without the prior written consent of the Secretary of State.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The Secretary of State may charge a reasonable fee for a disk under this section.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The fee may not exceed the actual cost of purchasing and preparing the disk.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
