<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gbr" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="16-210" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gbr-16-210</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Subject to the hearing provisions of &#xA7; 16-211 of this subtitle, the Comptroller may deny a license to an applicant, reprimand a licensee, or suspend or revoke a license if the applicant or licensee:<section prefix="(1)">fraudulently or deceptively obtains or attempts to obtain a license for the applicant or licensee or for another person;</section><section prefix="(2)">fraudulently or deceptively uses a license;</section><section prefix="(3)">fails to comply with the Maryland Cigarette Sales Below Cost Act or regulations adopted under that Act;</section><section prefix="(4)">fails to comply with the provisions of Title 11, Subtitle 5A of the Commercial Law Article;</section><section prefix="(5)">buys cigarettes for resale:<section prefix="(i)">in violation of a license; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">from a person who is not a licensed cigarette manufacturer, licensed subwholesaler, licensed vending machine operator, or licensed wholesaler;</section></section><section prefix="(6)">is convicted, under the laws of the United States or of any other state, of:<section prefix="(i)">a felony; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">a misdemeanor that is a crime of moral turpitude and is directly related to the fitness and qualification of the applicant or licensee; or</section></section><section prefix="(7)">has not paid a tax due before October 1 of the year after the tax became due.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Subject to the hearing provisions of &#xA7; 16-211 of this subtitle, the Comptroller may suspend or revoke a license if the licensee violates:<section prefix="(1)">Title 12 of the Tax - General Article, or regulations adopted under that title; or</section><section prefix="(2)">this title or regulations adopted under this title.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Subject to the hearing provisions of &#xA7; 16-211 of this subtitle, the Comptroller shall deny a license to any applicant who has had a license revoked under this section until:<section prefix="(1)">1 year has passed since the license was revoked; and</section><section prefix="(2)">it satisfactorily appears to the Comptroller that the applicant will comply with this title and any regulations adopted under this title.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Prior to the issuance or renewal of any license, the Comptroller shall conduct an investigation with regard to:<section prefix="(1)">the applicant;</section><section prefix="(2)">the business to be operated; and</section><section prefix="(3)">the facts set forth in the application.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
