<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gbr" order_by="" level="1">Business Regulation</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gbr-17-302</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>302</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Except as otherwise provided in this title, an applicant for a license under this title shall:<section prefix="(1)">submit to the clerk, in duplicate, an application on the form that the clerk provides;</section><section prefix="(2)">submit to the clerk a receipt or certificate for taxes in accordance with subsection (c) of this section; and</section><section prefix="(3)">pay to the clerk the appropriate license fee required by this title.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Each application for a license shall be verified in the way and contain the information that the Comptroller requires by regulation.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this subsection, "county treasurer" includes the Director of Finance or other chief fiscal officer of a county that does not have a county treasurer.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">This subsection does not apply to a domestic corporation that has shares subject to taxation under State law.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">An applicant for a license shall submit to the clerk:<section prefix="(i)">a certification by the State Department of Assessments and Taxation of the value of the goods, fixtures, and stock in trade in each county where the business is located for the applicant's business for the valuation year;</section><section prefix="(ii)">a certification by the county treasurer of that county that there are no unpaid taxes due to the State or county on the goods, fixtures, or stock in trade; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">a certification by the municipal corporation, if any, where the business is located that there are no unpaid taxes due to the municipal corporation on the goods, fixtures, or stock in trade.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">In this subsection, the valuation year:<section prefix="(i)">in Washington County, is the fiscal year that includes May 1 of the calendar year when the license is issued; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">in each other county, is the last calendar year before the year for which the license is sought.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">In Washington County, the clerk may not issue a license under this title for the first time unless the applicant submits to the clerk a certification that the location of the business for which the license is sought has proper zoning. The  certification must be from the county planning commission or, if the business is located in a municipal corporation, from the municipal corporation.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This subsection applies only in Calvert County.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The clerk may not issue a license under this title for the first time to a business that will be located in Calvert County unless the applicant submits to the clerk a certification that the location of the business for which the license is sought is zoned for the type of business for which the applicant is seeking a license.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The certification must be issued from:<section prefix="(i)">the Calvert County Department of Planning and Zoning; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">the appropriate municipal corporation, if the location of the proposed business is within the boundaries of a municipal corporation.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
