<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gbr" order_by="" level="1">Business Regulation</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gbr-2-106.1</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>106.1</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">This section applies to the following occupational and professional licensing boards:<section prefix="(1)">the State Board of Architects established under Title 3 of the Business Occupations and Professions Article;</section><section prefix="(2)">the State Board of Certified Interior Designers established under Title 8 of the Business Occupations and Professions Article;</section><section prefix="(3)">the State Board of Examiners of Landscape Architects established under Title 9 of the Business Occupations and Professions Article;</section><section prefix="(4)">the State Board for Professional Engineers established under Title 14 of the Business Occupations and Professions Article; and</section><section prefix="(5)">the State Board for Professional Land Surveyors established under Title 15 of the Business Occupations and Professions Article.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">There is a State Occupational and Professional Licensing Design Boards' Fund in the Department, which shall be a continuing, nonlapsing special fund.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as otherwise provided by law, each occupational and professional licensing board described in subsection (a) of this section shall pay all fees collected to the Comptroller of the State.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Comptroller shall distribute the fees to the Fund.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Fund shall be used to cover the actual documented direct and indirect costs of fulfilling the statutory and regulatory duties of each occupational and professional licensing board described in subsection (a) of this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The Secretary or a designee of the Secretary shall administer the Fund.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The Legislative Auditor shall audit the accounts and transactions of the Fund as provided in &#xA7; 2-1220 of the State Government Article.</section>
  </text>
</law>
