<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gbr" order_by="" level="1">Business Regulation</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gbr-11-513</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>513</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Except as otherwise provided in this section, the Commission shall hold a public hearing before the Commission awards, for racing at a particular track, racing days that:<section prefix="(1)">total at least 3 more than those awarded for racing at that track in the previous calendar year; or</section><section prefix="(2)">result from the transfer of racing days to that track from another track in the same year.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Commission shall:<section prefix="(1)">hold the hearing not more than 10 miles from the track where the racing is to be held; and</section><section prefix="(2)">allow any person to testify.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Commission:<section prefix="(1)">at least 15 days before the hearing, shall have notice of the hearing published in at least 1 newspaper with a substantial circulation in the county where the track is located; and</section><section prefix="(2)">shall try to give notice of the hearing to any public unit or private organization that has made a written request for notice.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If the transfer of racing days from one track to another becomes necessary due to fire, flood, mechanical failure, or any other similar circumstance deemed by the Commission to constitute an emergency:<section prefix="(i)">the racing days may be transferred immediately; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">as soon as practicable, the Commission shall provide notice of a hearing and conduct a hearing pursuant to subsection (c) of this section.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">As soon as the track and the facilities of the licensee from which race days were transferred under paragraph (1) of this section are in a condition to continue racing and pari-mutuel betting, any remaining days of the meet that was being conducted when the days were transferred shall be held at the track from which the days were transferred.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
