<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gbr" order_by="gbr" level="1">Business Regulation</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gbr-17-206</section_number>
  <catch_line>This section does not apply to:...</catch_line>
  <order_by>206</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">This section does not apply to:<section prefix="(1)">a console machine license, pinball machine license, Wicomico County pinball machine license, or Garrett County amusement device license issued under Subtitle 4 of this title;</section><section prefix="(2)">a Calvert County peddler license or magazine seller license issued under Subtitle 9 of this title;</section><section prefix="(3)">a junk dealer or scrap metal processor license, agent license, or Calvert County junk dealer or scrap metal processor license issued under Subtitle 10 of this title;</section><section prefix="(4)">a license to keep a storage warehouse issued under Subtitle 12 of this title;</section><section prefix="(5)">a State juke box license or Harford County juke box license issued under Subtitle 13 of this title;</section><section prefix="(6)">a promoter license issued under Subtitle 14 of this title;</section><section prefix="(7)">a vending machine license issued under Subtitle 19 of this title; or</section><section prefix="(8)">a license to do business as a trading stamp issuer issued under Subtitle 20 of this title.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Except as provided in subsection (a) of this section or otherwise in this title, each clerk shall account for and distribute the fees received for licenses issued under this title as follows:<section prefix="(1)">the clerk shall pay into the General Fund of the State:<section prefix="(i)">the percentage of license fees authorized by law as a fee of the office;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the additional issuance fee now allowed; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">3% of license fees to defray the expenses of the State License Bureau; and</section></section><section prefix="(2)">except as provided in subsection (c) of this section, the clerk shall distribute the remaining license fees:<section prefix="(i)">to the municipal corporation where the licensed business or activity is located, if the licensed business or activity is located in a municipal corporation; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">to the county where the licensed business or activity is located, if the licensed business or activity is not located in a municipal corporation.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">For purposes of this subsection, per capita revenue shall be computed by using the population figures from the later of:<section prefix="(i)">the most recent federal census; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">an official local census.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The clerk may not distribute license fees to a county or municipal corporation unless the county or municipal corporation:<section prefix="(i)">levies, in its current fiscal year, taxes sufficient to collect at least $1.00 per capita in revenue; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">certifies to the Comptroller a copy of the levy.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The clerk shall pay into the General Fund of the State any money that is not distributed at the end of the fiscal year of a county or municipal corporation because the county or municipal corporation failed to make the levy and certification required by paragraph (2) of this subsection.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
