<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gbr" order_by="" level="1">Business Regulation</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gbr-8-407</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>407</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The procedures for notice, hearings, and judicial review that apply to proceedings under Subtitle 3 of this title also apply to proceedings to recover from the Fund.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">On receipt of a claim, the Commission shall:<section prefix="(1)">send a copy of the claim to the contractor alleged to be responsible for the actual loss; and</section><section prefix="(2)">require a written response to the claim within 10 days.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Commission:<section prefix="(i)">shall review the claim and any response to it; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">may investigate the claim.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">On the basis of its review and any investigation, the Commission may:<section prefix="(i)">set the matter for a hearing;</section><section prefix="(ii)">dismiss the claim, if the claim is frivolous, legally insufficient, or made in bad faith; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">issue a proposed order to pay all or part of the claim or deny the claim if the total claim against a particular contractor does not exceed $5,000.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Commission shall send the proposed order to the claimant and the contractor, at the most recent address on record with the Commission, by:<section prefix="(i)">personal delivery; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">both regular mail and certified mail, return receipt requested.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Within 21 days after service, receipt, or attempted delivery of the proposed order, the claimant or contractor may submit to the Commission:<section prefix="(i)">a written request for a hearing before the Commission; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">a written exception to the proposed order.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">If the claimant or contractor submits a timely exception to the proposed order, the Commission may:<section prefix="(i)">issue a revised proposed order;</section><section prefix="(ii)">set a hearing on the claim; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">dismiss the claim.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">Unless the claimant or contractor submits a timely request for a hearing or a timely exception, the proposed order is final.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">At a hearing on a claim, the claimant has the burden of proof.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If a subcontractor or salesperson is necessary to adjudicate a claim fairly, the Commission shall issue a subpoena for that person to appear at the hearing.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
