<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gbr" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="4.5-202" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gbr-4.5-202</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Unit shall maintain a list of all registrants and registered sales representatives.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Unit shall make available to each applicant for registration as a home builder or home builder sales representative a copy of this title and other applicable laws and regulations.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Unit shall make available to each registrant and each registered sales representative any amendments to this title or other applicable laws or regulations at least 30 days before the effective date of the amendments.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In consultation with the home building industry, the Unit shall develop a consumer information pamphlet written in plain English that describes:<section prefix="(i)">the rights and remedies of consumers in the purchase of a new home; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">any other information that the Division considers reasonably necessary to assist consumers.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Division shall provide each registered home builder with a sufficient number of copies of the consumer information pamphlets as needed by the home builder.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A home builder shall provide each contract purchaser with the consumer information pamphlet before entering into a contract for the initial sale of a new home.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The contract purchaser shall acknowledge in writing the receipt of the consumer information pamphlet.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">The failure of a home builder to provide a copy of the consumer information pamphlet to a contract purchaser may not be used as a basis for invalidation of the contract for the initial sale of a new home.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Unit shall collect and maintain information on the resolution of consumer complaints involving new home builders or home builder sales representatives.</section>
  </text>
</law>
