<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gbr" order_by="" level="1">Business Regulation</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gbr-12-207</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>207</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Unless a license is renewed for a 2-year term as provided in this section, the license expires on the first April 30 that comes:<section prefix="(1)">after the effective date of the license; and</section><section prefix="(2)">in an even-numbered year.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">At least 1 month before a license expires, the Secretary shall mail to the licensee, at the last known address of the licensee:<section prefix="(1)">a renewal application form; and</section><section prefix="(2)">a notice that states:<section prefix="(i)">the date on which the current license expires;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the date by which the Secretary must receive the renewal application for the renewal to be issued and mailed before the license expires; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">the amount of the renewal fee.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Before a license expires, the licensee periodically may renew it for an additional 2-year term, if the licensee:<section prefix="(1)">submits to the Secretary a renewal application on the form that the Secretary provides;</section><section prefix="(2)">signs the renewal application under oath;</section><section prefix="(3)">updates the information submitted in the original application and states that the information is current;</section><section prefix="(4)">except as provided in subsection (d) of this section, agrees to comply with each requirement applicable to the original application;</section><section prefix="(5)">states that the licensee:<section prefix="(i)">has not violated this title;</section><section prefix="(ii)">has not been convicted of an offense specified in &#xA7; 12-209 of this subtitle; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">has not had a similar license denied, suspended, or revoked in another jurisdiction;</section></section><section prefix="(6)">otherwise is entitled to be licensed; and</section><section prefix="(7)">pays to the Secretary a renewal fee of $265.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Secretary may require a licensee to submit a national and State criminal history records check with the renewal application.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The Secretary shall renew the license of each licensee who meets the requirements of this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">A license is not transferable and may be used only to benefit the licensee.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A licensee may change the place of business for which a license is issued only if the licensee:<section prefix="(i)">submits to the Secretary an application to transfer the license to a new business location on a form that the Secretary provides; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">receives the written approval of the Secretary.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Within 45 days after the application is filed with the Secretary, the Secretary shall approve or disapprove the application and notify the licensee of the approval or disapproval, in writing.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">If the Secretary approves a proposed change of place of business, the licensee shall:<section prefix="(i)">submit to the Secretary a current list of names of each employee to be employed at the new location; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">attach the written approval of the Secretary to the license until an amended license is received by the licensee.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(h)">The Secretary may determine that licenses issued under this subtitle shall expire on a staggered basis.</section>
  </text>
</law>
