<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gbr" order_by="gbr" level="1">Business Regulation</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gbr-12.5-204</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this section, "Central Repository" means the Criminal Justice Information System Central Reposito...</catch_line>
  <order_by>204</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, "Central Repository" means the Criminal Justice Information System Central Repository of the Department of Public Safety and Correctional Services.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The owner of a business that is an applicant for a license under &#xA7; 12.5-202 of this subtitle and an individual whose name is required to be submitted to the Secretary under &#xA7; 12.5-203 of this subtitle shall apply to the Central Repository for a national and State criminal history records check on a form approved by the Director of the Central Repository.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">As a part of an application to the Central Repository for a national and State criminal history records check, the owner of a business that is an applicant and an individual whose name is required to be submitted to the Secretary under &#xA7; 12.5-203 of this subtitle shall submit to the Central Repository:<section prefix="(i)">two complete sets of legible fingerprints taken on forms approved by the Director of the Central Repository and the Director of the Federal Bureau of Investigation;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the fee authorized under &#xA7; 10-221(b)(7) of the Criminal Procedure Article for access to the State criminal history records; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">the mandatory processing fee required by the Federal Bureau of Investigation for a national criminal history records check.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A licensee or applicant may pay for the costs borne by the employee or other individual requiring a criminal history records check under subsection (b) of this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Central Repository shall provide to the Secretary:<section prefix="(1)">the national and State criminal history records of each individual requiring a criminal history records check under subsection (b) of this section and issue a printed statement listing any convictions and pleas of guilty or nolo contendere to any criminal charge;</section><section prefix="(2)">an update of the initial criminal history records check for an individual requiring a criminal history records check and issue a revised printed statement listing any convictions and pleas of guilty or nolo contendere to any criminal charge occurring in the State after the date of the initial criminal history records check; and</section><section prefix="(3)">an acknowledged receipt of the application for a criminal history records check by an individual requiring a criminal history records check.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Information obtained by the Secretary from the Central Repository under this section:<section prefix="(i)">is confidential;</section><section prefix="(ii)">may not be redisseminated; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">may be used only for the license purpose authorized by this title.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Paragraph (1) of this subsection does not preclude the Secretary from notifying a licensee or an applicant of the approval or disqualification of the employee for employment based on information obtained by the Secretary under this section.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The subject of a criminal history records check under this section may contest the contents of the printed statement issued by the Central Repository as provided in &#xA7; 10-223 of the Criminal Procedure Article.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">The Secretary shall verify periodically the continued employment or licensure of individuals requiring criminal history records checks in accordance with regulations adopted by the Secretary of Public Safety and Correctional Services.</section>
  </text>
</law>
