<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gbr" order_by="" level="1">Business Regulation</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gbr-11-403</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>403</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Comptroller shall pay from the Special Fund an annual grant of:<section prefix="(1)">$825,000 to the Maryland Agricultural Fair Board to promote State and county agricultural fairs and exhibits;</section><section prefix="(2)">$100,000 to Prince George's County to replace money formerly received from the admissions and amusement tax;</section><section prefix="(3)">$40,000 to the Great Frederick Fair to support exhibition harness racing with money for construction and maintenance of new stalls, track maintenance, and purses;</section><section prefix="(4)">$50 to the City of Bowie for each day that the training facilities are open at the Bowie Race Course Training Center;</section><section prefix="(5)">$75,000 to the Maryland Agricultural Education Foundation, Inc., to promote and enhance statewide agricultural education;</section><section prefix="(6)">an amount not to exceed $30,000 in fiscal year 1998 and $20,000 in each fiscal year thereafter to the Great Pocomoke Fair, Inc. to support exhibition harness racing with money for construction and maintenance of new stalls, track maintenance, and purses;</section><section prefix="(7)">$500,000 to the Maryland Million, Ltd. to support and promote the running of Maryland Million races; and</section><section prefix="(8)">$350,000 to the Maryland Standardbred Race Fund for the Sire Stakes Program.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">If the Maryland State Fair remains at the Timonium Fair Grounds, the Comptroller shall pay from the Special Fund an annual grant of:<section prefix="(1)">$500,000 to the Maryland State Fair and Agricultural Society, Inc., to:<section prefix="(i)">promote and enhance the Maryland State Fair; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">maintain and develop youth programs, with premium money provided to organizations, such as 4-H Clubs and the Future Farmers of America, for recognition and awards; and</section></section><section prefix="(2)">$50,000 to Baltimore County to replace the money formerly received by the county under this subtitle.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
