<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gbr" order_by="gbr" level="1">Business Regulation</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gbr-8-620</section_number>
  <catch_line>The Commission may impose on a person who violates this title, including &#xA7; 8-607(4) of this subtitl...</catch_line>
  <order_by>620</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Commission may impose on a person who violates this title, including &#xA7; 8-607(4) of this subtitle, a civil penalty not exceeding $5,000 for each violation, whether or not the person is licensed under this title.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">In setting the amount of a civil penalty, the Commission shall consider:<section prefix="(1)">the seriousness of the violation;</section><section prefix="(2)">the good faith of the violator;</section><section prefix="(3)">any previous violations;</section><section prefix="(4)">the harmful effect of the violation on the complainant, the public, and the business of home improvement;</section><section prefix="(5)">the assets of the violator; and</section><section prefix="(6)">any other relevant factors.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Commission may establish by regulation a schedule of violations and fines to be used for civil citations issued under this title.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A citation issued by the Commission shall include:<section prefix="(i)">the name and address of the person charged;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the nature of the violation;</section><section prefix="(iii)">the location and time of the violation;</section><section prefix="(iv)">the amount of the fine;</section><section prefix="(v)">the manner, location, and time in which the fine may be paid;</section><section prefix="(vi)">the cited person's right to a hearing for the violation; and</section><section prefix="(vii)">a warning that failure to pay the fine or to contest liability in a timely manner in accordance with the citation:<section prefix="1.">is an admission of liability; and</section><section prefix="2.">may result in an entry of a default judgment that may include the fine, court costs, and administrative expenses.</section></section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Commission shall retain a copy of the citation.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">All money collected under this subsection shall be paid in accordance with &#xA7; 8-403(b) of this title.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
