<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gbr" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="16-206" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gbr-16-206</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">A manufacturer license authorizes the licensee to:<section prefix="(1)">sell unstamped cigarettes to:<section prefix="(i)">a licensed cigarette wholesaler located in Maryland; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">a licensed cigarette wholesaler located outside of Maryland if the unstamped cigarettes may lawfully be sold in Maryland;</section></section><section prefix="(2)">except as otherwise prohibited or restricted under local law, this article, or the Criminal Law Article, distribute sample cigarettes to consumers located in Maryland;</section><section prefix="(3)">store unstamped cigarettes in a licensed cigarette storage warehouse for subsequent shipment to licensed wholesalers, federal reservations, or persons out of state; and</section><section prefix="(4)">upon approval of the Comptroller, act as an agent of a Maryland licensed wholesaler for stamping and distribution of cigarettes.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A retailer license authorizes the licensee to:<section prefix="(1)">act as a retailer; and</section><section prefix="(2)">buy stamped cigarettes from a subwholesaler or wholesaler.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A storage warehouse license authorizes the licensee to operate a storage facility in Maryland for the purpose of storing unstamped cigarettes on behalf of a licensed cigarette manufacturer.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If a storage warehouse licensee is a licensed cigarette wholesaler or licensed cigarette subwholesaler, the storage warehouse license authorizes the holder to store stamped cigarettes and cigarettes with another state's tax stamp.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A subwholesaler license authorizes the licensee to:<section prefix="(1)">act as a subwholesaler;</section><section prefix="(2)">buy stamped cigarettes from a wholesaler or another subwholesaler; and</section><section prefix="(3)">store stamped cigarettes and cigarettes with another state's tax stamp at a licensed cigarette storage facility.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">A vending machine operator license authorizes the licensee to:<section prefix="(1)">act as a vending machine operator; and</section><section prefix="(2)">buy stamped cigarettes from a subwholesaler or wholesaler.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">A wholesaler license authorizes the licensee to:<section prefix="(1)">act as a wholesaler;</section><section prefix="(2)">buy unstamped cigarettes directly from a cigarette manufacturer;</section><section prefix="(3)">hold unstamped cigarettes;</section><section prefix="(4)">buy tobacco tax stamps as authorized by &#xA7; 12-303 of the Tax - General Article;</section><section prefix="(5)">transport unstamped cigarettes in the State;</section><section prefix="(6)">sell unstamped cigarettes to another licensed wholesaler if the Comptroller specifically authorizes;</section><section prefix="(7)">upon approval of the Comptroller, designate a licensed manufacturer to act as its agent for the stamping and distribution of cigarettes; and</section><section prefix="(8)">store stamped cigarettes and cigarettes with another state's tax stamp at a licensed cigarette storage facility.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
