<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gbr" order_by="gbr" level="1">Business Regulation</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gbr-8-405</section_number>
  <catch_line>Subject to this subtitle, an owner may recover compensation from the Fund for an actual loss that re...</catch_line>
  <order_by>405</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Subject to this subtitle, an owner may recover compensation from the Fund for an actual loss that results from an act or omission by a licensed contractor or a violation of &#xA7; 8-607(4) of this title as found by the Commission or a court of competent jurisdiction.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">For purposes of recovery from the Fund, the act or omission of a licensed contractor includes the act or omission of a subcontractor, salesperson, or employee of the licensed contractor, whether or not an express agency relationship exists.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A claimant shall comply with a written agreement to submit a dispute to arbitration before seeking recovery from the Fund.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Commission may deny a claim if the Commission finds that the claimant unreasonably rejected good faith efforts by the contractor to resolve the claim.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The Commission may not award from the Fund:<section prefix="(1)">more than $20,000 to one claimant for acts or omissions of one contractor;</section><section prefix="(2)">more than $100,000 to all claimants for acts or omissions of one contractor unless, after the Commission has paid out $100,000 on account of acts or omissions of the contractor, the contractor reimburses $100,000 to the Fund;</section><section prefix="(3)">an amount for attorney fees, consequential damages, court costs, interest, personal injury damages, or punitive damages;</section><section prefix="(4)">an amount as a result of a default judgment in court; or</section><section prefix="(5)">an amount in excess of the amount paid by or on behalf of the claimant to the contractor against whom the claim is filed.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A claim against the Fund based on the act or omission of a particular contractor may not be made by:<section prefix="(i)">a spouse or other immediate relative of the contractor;</section><section prefix="(ii)">an employee, officer, or partner of the contractor; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">an immediate relative of an employee, officer, or partner of the contractor.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">An owner may make a claim against the Fund only if the owner:<section prefix="(i)">resides in the home as to which the claim is made; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">does not own more than three residences or dwelling places.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">A claim shall be brought against the Fund within 3 years after the claimant discovered or, by use of ordinary diligence, should have discovered the loss or damage.</section>
  </text>
</law>
