<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gbr" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="9A-101" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gbr-9A-101</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this title the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Board" means the State Board of Heating, Ventilation, Air-Conditioning, and Refrigeration Contractors.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Contractor" means a heating, ventilation, air-conditioning, and refrigeration contractor.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Cooling system" means a system in which heat is removed from air, surrounding surfaces, or both.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Cooling system" includes an air-conditioning system.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"Forced air system" means a heating system that uses air being moved by mechanical means to transmit heat.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Heating system" means a system in which heat is transmitted by radiation, conduction, or convection, or a combination of any of these methods, to the air, surrounding surfaces, or both.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Heating system" does not include a fireplace or woodburning stove not incorporated into or used as a primary heating system.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">"Heating, ventilation, air-conditioning, and refrigeration contractor" means an individual who provides heating, ventilation, air-conditioning, or refrigeration services.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">"Hydronic system" means a heating and cooling system using liquids or steam to transmit or remove heat.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">"Independent agency" means an office, commission, board, department, or agency established as an independent unit of government that may receive budgetary or administrative support from the federal, State, or local government.</section>
    <section prefix="(j)">"Journeyman license" means a license issued by the Board to provide heating, ventilation, air-conditioning, and refrigeration services while under the direction and control of a licensed contractor.</section>
    <section prefix="(k)">"Journeyman restricted license" means a license issued by the Board to provide heating, ventilation, air-conditioning, and refrigeration services while under the direction and control of a licensed contractor, in only one of the following areas:<section prefix="(1)">heating - forced air systems;</section><section prefix="(2)">heating - hydronic systems;</section><section prefix="(3)">ventilation;</section><section prefix="(4)">air-conditioning; or</section><section prefix="(5)">refrigeration.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(l)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"License" means, unless the context requires otherwise, a license issued by the Board to provide or to assist in providing heating, ventilation, air-conditioning, or refrigeration services.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"License" includes, unless the context requires otherwise:<section prefix="(i)">a master license;</section><section prefix="(ii)">a master restricted license;</section><section prefix="(iii)">a limited license;</section><section prefix="(iv)">a journeyman license;</section><section prefix="(v)">a journeyman restricted license; and</section><section prefix="(vi)">an apprentice license.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(m)">"Licensed apprentice" means an individual who is licensed by the Board to assist in providing heating, ventilation, air-conditioning, or refrigeration services while:<section prefix="(1)">under the direction and control of a licensed contractor; and</section><section prefix="(2)">in training to become a journeyman.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(n)">"Licensed contractor" means a contractor who is licensed by the Board to provide heating, ventilation, air-conditioning, or refrigeration services, but does not include a licensed apprentice or licensed journeyman.</section>
    <section prefix="(o)">"Limited license" means a license issued by the Board exclusively to maintain or repair one or more of the following: heating systems, cooling systems, refrigeration systems, ventilation systems, or hydronic systems.</section>
    <section prefix="(p)">"Master license" means a license issued by the Board to provide heating, ventilation, air-conditioning, or refrigeration services.</section>
    <section prefix="(q)">"Master restricted license" means a license issued by the Board to provide services in only one of the following areas:<section prefix="(1)">heating - forced air systems;</section><section prefix="(2)">heating - hydronic systems;</section><section prefix="(3)">ventilation;</section><section prefix="(4)">air-conditioning; or</section><section prefix="(5)">refrigeration.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(r)">"Provide heating, ventilation, air-conditioning, or refrigeration services" means to install, maintain, alter, remodel, or repair heating systems, cooling systems, refrigeration systems, ventilation systems, or hydronic systems.</section>
    <section prefix="(s)">"Refrigeration system" means a system used to cool a surface or area below 55 degrees Fahrenheit or 12.9 degrees Celsius.</section>
    <section prefix="(t)">"Self-contained appliance" means a heating, ventilation, air-conditioning, or refrigeration device that is designed and manufactured:<section prefix="(1)">with its component parts contained within a single chassis;</section><section prefix="(2)">with a standard factory-installed electrical line cord that requires a plug-in device;</section><section prefix="(3)">with no additional external fuel source; and</section><section prefix="(4)">independent of an air distribution system.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(u)">"Subdivision of the State" means any of the 23 counties in Maryland, the City of Baltimore, and any municipal corporation.</section>
    <section prefix="(v)">"Ventilation system" means the natural or mechanical process of supplying air to, or removing air from, any space:<section prefix="(1)">whether the air is conditioned or is not conditioned; and</section><section prefix="(2)">at a rate of airflow of more than 250 cubic feet per minute.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
