<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gbr" order_by="" level="1">Business Regulation</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gbr-4.5-101</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>101</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this title the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Consumer" means an owner or a contract purchaser.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Contract purchaser" means a person who has entered into a contract with a home builder to purchase a new home, but who has not yet settled on the purchase of the new home.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">"Division" means the Consumer Protection Division of the Office of the Attorney General.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"Exempt lender" means a lender exempt from the requirements of registration as provided in &#xA7; 4.5-501(c) of this title.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">"Guaranty Fund" means the Home Builder Guaranty Fund.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Home builder" means a person that undertakes to erect or otherwise construct a new home.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Home builder" includes:<section prefix="(i)">a custom home builder as defined in &#xA7; 10-501 of the Real Property Article;</section><section prefix="(ii)">a new home builder subject to &#xA7; 10-301 of the Real Property Article;</section><section prefix="(iii)">the installer or retailer of a mobile home or an industrialized building intended for residential use; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">a person that enters into a contract with a consumer under which the person agrees to provide the consumer with a new home.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Home builder" does not include:<section prefix="(i)">an employee of a registrant who does not hold himself or herself out for hire in home building except as an employee of a registrant;</section><section prefix="(ii)">subcontractors or other vendors hired by the registrant to perform services or supply materials for the construction of a new home who do not otherwise meet the requirements of this title;</section><section prefix="(iii)">the manufacturer of industrialized buildings intended for residential use or of mobile homes, unless the manufacturer also installs the industrialized buildings or mobile homes;</section><section prefix="(iv)">a real estate developer who does not construct, or enter into contracts with consumers to provide or construct, homes;</section><section prefix="(v)">a financial institution that lends funds for the construction or purchase of residential dwellings in the State;</section><section prefix="(vi)">except as otherwise provided in this title, a person who erects or constructs new homes solely in Montgomery County; or</section><section prefix="(vii)">a buyer's agent, as defined in &#xA7; 17-530 of the Business Occupations and Professions Article, when representing a prospective buyer in the purchase of a new home.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(h)">"Home builder registration number" means a registration number issued by the Unit to a registrant under this title.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Home builder sales representative" means an individual employed by a home builder as the home builder's representative to consumers regarding the purchase of a new home from the home builder.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Home builder sales representative" includes individuals employed by a person who erects or constructs new homes solely in Montgomery County and is not required to register under this title.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Home builder sales representative" does not include:<section prefix="(i)">an individual employed by an installer or retailer of mobile homes or industrialized buildings intended for residential use; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">an employee or officer agent for a nonprofit organization, with at least a 2-year record in the State as a developer of affordable housing for persons with low to moderate incomes, in the initial sale of a home if:<section prefix="1.">the home is constructed or rehabilitated by the nonprofit organization; and</section><section prefix="2.">the purchaser of the home is using federal, State, or local government or other subsidized financing administered by the nonprofit organization for the purpose of assisting individuals with low to moderate incomes to purchase homes.</section></section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(j)">"Industrialized building" has the meaning stated in &#xA7; 12-301 of the Public Safety Article.</section>
    <section prefix="(k)">"Install" has the meaning stated in &#xA7; 12-301 of the Public Safety Article.</section>
    <section prefix="(l)">"Mobile home" means a manufactured home as defined in &#xA7; 12-301 of the Public Safety Article.</section>
    <section prefix="(m)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"New home" means each newly constructed residential dwelling unit in the State and the fixtures and structure that are made a part of a newly constructed private dwelling unit at the time of construction.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"New home" includes:<section prefix="(i)">a custom home as defined in &#xA7; 10-501(c) of the Real Property Article;</section><section prefix="(ii)">a new home to which &#xA7; 10-301 of the Real Property Article applies;</section><section prefix="(iii)">an industrialized building intended for residential use; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">a mobile home.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(n)">"New home contract" means an agreement between a home builder and a consumer for the sale or construction of a new home.</section>
    <section prefix="(o)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Owner" means a person for whom a new home is built or to whom a new home is sold for occupation by:<section prefix="(i)">that person or the family of that person as a home; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">the successors of that person in title to the home or a mortgagor in possession.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Owner" includes a contract purchaser who contracts with a registrant for the construction and purchase of a new home.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Owner" does not include:<section prefix="(i)">a development company, association, or subsidiary company of a registrant; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">a person or organization to whom the home may be conveyed by the registrant for a purpose other than residential occupation by that person or organization.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(p)">"Principal" means:<section prefix="(1)">a sole proprietor, officer, director, general partner, or limited liability company manager of an applicant or registrant;</section><section prefix="(2)">a person with at least 10 percent ownership in an applicant or registrant or a subsidiary of an applicant or registrant; and</section><section prefix="(3)">parents, spouses, and children with a combined 10 percent ownership in an applicant or registrant or a subsidiary of an applicant or registrant.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(q)">"Registered sales representative" means a person registered to be a home builder sales representative under this title.</section>
    <section prefix="(r)">"Registrant" means a person registered to build new homes.</section>
    <section prefix="(s)">"Registration certificate" means a certificate issued to a registered sales representative by the Unit.</section>
    <section prefix="(t)">"Registration Fund" means the Home Builder Registration Fund.</section>
  </text>
</law>
