<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gbr" order_by="" level="1">Business Regulation</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gbr-19-303</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>303</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A person may register:<section prefix="(i)">a class of returnable containers if:<section prefix="1.">the person owns or deals in goods handled or delivered in a returnable container; and</section><section prefix="2.">the returnable container has an identifying name, mark, or device securely attached, impressed, or imprinted; or</section></section><section prefix="(ii)">a class of returnable textiles, if the person:<section prefix="1.">is in the business of regularly supplying clean laundered returnable textiles; and</section><section prefix="2.">periodically exchanges the clean returnable textiles for soiled returnable textiles.</section></section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A person who has registered a returnable container or returnable textile under State law is not required to reregister the returnable container or returnable textile.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">To register a returnable container or returnable textile a person shall:<section prefix="(1)"><section prefix="(i)">prepare a clear statement of the character of the returnable container or returnable textile; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">prepare a comprehensive description of the identifying name, mark, or device attached, impressed, imprinted, woven, or produced;</section></section><section prefix="(2)">sign and acknowledge the comprehensive description before an officer qualified to take an acknowledgment to deeds in the State;</section><section prefix="(3)">publish the signed and acknowledged comprehensive description:<section prefix="(i)">in two successive issues, in different weeks, of a newspaper published in the county in which the principal office, place of business, or agency of the person is located; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">twice a week for 2 successive weeks in a daily newspaper published in Baltimore City if the principal office, place of business, or agency of the person is located in Baltimore City; and</section></section><section prefix="(4)">file with the Secretary of State the comprehensive description and a certificate of publication, certified by the owner or manager of the newspaper in which the comprehensive description was published.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A person may transfer a registration by filing a copy of the assignment or transfer with the Secretary of State.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Secretary of State shall record each:<section prefix="(i)">comprehensive description filed under subsection (b) of this section;</section><section prefix="(ii)">certificate of publication filed under subsection (b) of this section; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">transfer filed under subsection (c) of this section.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">On application, the Secretary of State shall provide to the applicant a certified copy of a recorded filing.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Secretary of State shall establish reasonable fees:<section prefix="(i)">for recording under this section; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">for providing copies of records filed under this section.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">A certified copy of a comprehensive description and a certificate of publication or of a transfer with the seal of the Secretary of State attached is:<section prefix="(1)">evidence that the person complied with this subtitle; and</section><section prefix="(2)">prima facie evidence of:<section prefix="(i)">title to or right to use, collect, or deliver the corresponding returnable containers; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">title to the corresponding returnable textiles.</section></section></section>
  </text>
</law>
