<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gbr" order_by="gbr" level="1">Business Regulation</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gbr-14-119</section_number>
  <catch_line>The Commissioner may pass an order denying effectiveness to, or suspending or revoking the effective...</catch_line>
  <order_by>119</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Commissioner may pass an order denying effectiveness to, or suspending or revoking the effectiveness of, any registration if the Commissioner finds that the order is in the public interest and that:<section prefix="(1)"><section prefix="(i)">the registration as of its effective date, or as of any earlier date in the case of an order denying effectiveness, is incomplete in any material respect or contains any statement made that was, in light of the circumstances under which it was made, false or misleading with respect to any material fact;</section><section prefix="(ii)">an amendment as of its effective date is incomplete in any material respect or contains any statement made that was, in light of the circumstances under which it was made, false or misleading with respect to any material fact; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">a report is incomplete in any material respect or contains any statement made that was, in light of the circumstances under which it was made, false or misleading with respect to any material fact;</section></section><section prefix="(2)">any provision of this subtitle or any order or condition lawfully imposed under this subtitle has been violated, in connection with the business opportunity by:<section prefix="(i)">the person filing the registration;</section><section prefix="(ii)">a seller, any partner, officer, or director of the seller, or any person occupying a similar status or performing similar functions as the seller; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">a person that directly or indirectly controls or is controlled by the seller if the person filing the registration is directly or indirectly controlled by or acting for the seller;</section></section><section prefix="(3)">except as provided in paragraph (4) of this subsection, the business opportunity registered or sought to be registered is the subject of an order denying, suspending, or revoking a registration or a permanent or temporary injunction of any court of competent jurisdiction;</section><section prefix="(4)">the seller's enterprise or method of business, or that of the business opportunity, includes or would include activities that are illegal where performed;</section><section prefix="(5)">the business opportunity or the offering of a business opportunity has worked or tended to work a fraud upon purchasers or would so operate;</section><section prefix="(6)">there has been a failure to file any documents or information required by &#xA7; 14-113.1 of this subtitle; or</section><section prefix="(7)">the seller's literature or advertising is misleading, incorrect, incomplete, or deceptive.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Commissioner may enter a denial order if the Commissioner finds that the order is in the public interest and the seller has failed to pay the proper registration fee.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Commissioner shall vacate any such order when the deficiency has been corrected.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Commissioner may not:<section prefix="(1)">institute a proceeding against an effective registration under subsection (a)(3) of this section more than 1 year after the date of the order or injunction relied on; or</section><section prefix="(2)">pass an order under subsection (a)(3) of this section on the basis of an order or injunction entered under any other state act unless that order or injunction was based on facts which would currently constitute grounds for an order under this section.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">By order, the Commissioner summarily may postpone or suspend the effectiveness of the registration pending final determination of any proceeding under this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">Upon the entry of the order, the Commissioner shall promptly notify the seller:<section prefix="(1)">that the order has been entered;</section><section prefix="(2)">the basis for the order; and</section><section prefix="(3)">that within 15 days after the day on which the Commissioner receives a written request by the seller, the matter will be set down for a hearing.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">If the seller fails to request a hearing and the Commissioner fails to order a hearing, the order shall remain in effect until the Commissioner modifies or vacates the order.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">If the seller requests a hearing or the Commissioner orders a hearing, the Commissioner, after providing notice of an opportunity for hearing to the seller, may modify or vacate the order or extend it until final determination.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">The Commissioner may not enter an order described under subsection (b) of this section without first providing to the seller notice in accordance with subsection (e) of this section, an opportunity for hearing, and written findings of fact and conclusions of law.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">If the Commissioner finds that the conditions which prompted its entry have changed or that it is otherwise in the public interest, the Commissioner may vacate or modify an order passed under this section.</section>
  </text>
</law>
