<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gbr" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="10-101" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gbr-10-101</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this title the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Conveyance" means a carrying or transporting device that has a capacity that exceeds 1,749 gallons exclusive of the fuel supply tank for its own propulsion.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Conveyance" includes a pipeline, tank car, vehicle, and vessel.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Dyed diesel fuel" means diesel fuel that is dyed under U.S. Environmental Protection Agency rules for high sulfur diesel fuel or is dyed under Internal Revenue Service rules for nontaxable use.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Gasoline" means a product that:<section prefix="(i)">is used as fuel in a spark ignited, internal combustion engine; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">is designated as gasoline by the Comptroller.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Gasoline" includes:<section prefix="(i)">casing head gasoline;</section><section prefix="(ii)">absorption gasoline;</section><section prefix="(iii)">other natural gasoline; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">aviation gasoline, as defined in &#xA7; 9-101(c) of the Tax - General Article.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"Motor fuel" means:<section prefix="(1)">gasoline; or</section><section prefix="(2)">special fuel.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">"Motor vehicle" means a vehicle that:<section prefix="(1)">is self-propelled;</section><section prefix="(2)">is designed to be operated on a public highway; and</section><section prefix="(3)">is not operated only on rails.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(g)">"Petroleum transporter" means a person who transports motor fuel in interstate or intrastate commerce in a conveyance, whether or not the person owns the conveyance.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">"Producer" means a company, or agent, parent company, subsidiary, or joint venture of a company, that extracts crude oil from the earth.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Propulsion tank" means a receptacle on a motor vehicle from which motor fuel is supplied for the propulsion of the vehicle.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Propulsion tank" includes a fuel supply tank of a motor vehicle.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(j)">"Refiner" means a person who makes motor fuel from crude oil by changing the physical or chemical characteristics of the crude oil.</section>
    <section prefix="(k)">"Retail service station dealer" means a person who operates a retail place of business where motor fuel is sold and delivered into the fuel supply tanks of motor vehicles.</section>
    <section prefix="(l)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Special fuel" means a product that is usable as fuel in an internal combustion engine.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Special fuel" does not include gasoline.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(m)">"Vehicle" means a conveyance for transporting motor fuel on a public highway.</section>
  </text>
</law>
