<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gbr" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="12.5-209" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gbr-12.5-209</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">A license is issued for a term of 2 years.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Unless a licensee meets the insurance requirements of &#xA7; 12.5-205 of this subtitle, the Secretary may not renew the license of the licensee.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Unless a license is renewed for a 2-year term as provided in this section, the license expires on the second anniversary of the effective date of the license.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A licensee that meets the requirements of this section may obtain a renewal of a license before the license expires for an additional 2-year term.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Once expired, a license may not be renewed.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">At least 60 days before a license expires, the Secretary shall mail to the licensee, at the last known address of the licensee:<section prefix="(1)">a renewal application form;</section><section prefix="(2)">a form that allows a licensee to update the information submitted in the original application or state that the information is current and accurate;</section><section prefix="(3)">except as provided in subsection (e) of this section, a form that requires the licensee to agree to continue to comply with each requirement applicable to the original application; and</section><section prefix="(4)">a notice that states:<section prefix="(i)">the date on which the current license expires;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the date by which the Secretary must receive the renewal application for the renewal to be issued and mailed before the license expires; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">the amount of the renewal fee.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The Secretary may require a licensee to submit a national and State criminal history records check with the renewal application.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The Secretary shall renew the license of each licensee who meets the requirements of this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A licensee may change the fixed business address for which a license is issued only if the licensee:<section prefix="(i)">submits to the Secretary an application to transfer the license to a new business location on a form that the Secretary provides; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">receives the written approval of the Secretary.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Within 45 days after the application is filed with the Secretary, the Secretary shall approve or disapprove the application and notify the licensee of the approval or disapproval, in writing.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">If the Secretary approves a proposed change of fixed business address, the licensee shall:<section prefix="(i)">submit to the Secretary a current list of names of each employee to be employed at the new location; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">attach the written approval of the Secretary to the license until an amended license is received by the licensee.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(h)">The Secretary may determine that licenses issued under this subtitle shall expire on a staggered basis.</section>
  </text>
</law>
