<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gbr" order_by="gbr" level="1">Business Regulation</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gbr-12-401</section_number>
  <catch_line>This section applies to all dealers and all pawnbrokers wherever located in the State....</catch_line>
  <order_by>401</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">This section applies to all dealers and all pawnbrokers wherever located in the State.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A dealer or pawnbroker shall release to the primary law enforcement unit an item of personal property, other than a security or printed evidence of indebtedness, located at the place of business of the dealer or pawnbroker if:<section prefix="(1)">the item is established to have been stolen;</section><section prefix="(2)">the owner of the item or victim of the theft has positively identified the item;</section><section prefix="(3)">the owner of the item or the agent or designee of the owner has provided an affidavit of ownership;</section><section prefix="(4)">the stolen property report describes the item by:<section prefix="(i)">a date;</section><section prefix="(ii)">initials;</section><section prefix="(iii)">an insurance record;</section><section prefix="(iv)">a photograph;</section><section prefix="(v)">a sales receipt;</section><section prefix="(vi)">a serial number;</section><section prefix="(vii)">specific damage;</section><section prefix="(viii)">a statement of the facts that show that the item is one of a kind; or</section><section prefix="(ix)">a unique engraving; and</section></section><section prefix="(5)">the primary law enforcement unit provides to the dealer or pawnbroker a receipt that describes the item and that notifies the dealer or pawnbroker of the dealer's or pawnbroker's right to file an application for a statement of charges against the individual who sold the item to the dealer or pawnbroker, or other alleged thief for theft under &#xA7; 7-104 of the Criminal Law Article.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A dealer shall retain in the dealer's place of business, for an additional period of 12 days, any item of personal property or other valuable thing, other than securities or printed evidence of indebtedness, if:<section prefix="(1)">the primary law enforcement unit requests that the dealer retain the item;</section><section prefix="(2)">the primary law enforcement unit has reasonable cause to believe the item has been stolen; and</section><section prefix="(3)">the item has not been identified under subsection (b)(2) of this section.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">When a primary law enforcement unit no longer needs an item for evidence, the primary law enforcement unit shall give the item to its owner.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">A dealer or pawnbroker who is required to release an item under this section is not entitled to reimbursement for any pledge or purchase price paid for the item from:<section prefix="(1)">the primary law enforcement unit to which the dealer released the item;</section><section prefix="(2)">the owner of the item; or</section><section prefix="(3)">the victim of the theft.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">If the owner of the item or the victim of the theft chooses to participate in the prosecution of the alleged identified thief, then the charges of theft from the owner or the victim of the theft and the charges of theft from the dealer or pawnbroker may be heard in a joint trial.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">The Secretary shall distribute to licensed dealers or post on the Department's website the name of the primary law enforcement unit responsible for enforcing this title in each jurisdiction, including municipalities.</section>
  </text>
</law>
