<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gbr" order_by="gbr" level="1">Business Regulation</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gbr-5-310</section_number>
  <catch_line>Subject to the hearing provisions of &#xA7; 5-312 of this subtitle, the Director may deny a registration...</catch_line>
  <order_by>310</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Subject to the hearing provisions of &#xA7; 5-312 of this subtitle, the Director may deny a registration or permit to an applicant, reprimand a person subject to the registration or permit provisions of this title, or suspend or revoke a registration or permit if an applicant, registrant, or permit holder, or an agent, employee, officer, director, or partner of the applicant, registrant, or permit holder:<section prefix="(1)">fraudulently or deceptively obtains or attempts to obtain a registration or permit;</section><section prefix="(2)">fraudulently or deceptively uses a registration or permit;</section><section prefix="(3)">under the laws of the United States or of any state, is convicted of a:<section prefix="(i)">felony; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">misdemeanor that is directly related to the fitness and qualifications of the applicant, registrant, or permit holder to own or operate a cemetery or crematory or provide burial goods;</section></section><section prefix="(4)">fails to provide or misrepresents any information required to be provided under this title;</section><section prefix="(5)">violates this title;</section><section prefix="(6)">violates the code of ethics adopted by the Director;</section><section prefix="(7)">violates a regulation adopted under this title;</section><section prefix="(8)">fails to provide reasonable and adequate supervision of the operation of the cemetery or crematory or the provision of burial goods by agents, employees, officers, directors, or partners affiliated with a cemetery, crematory, or burial goods business;</section><section prefix="(9)">refuses to allow an inspection required by this title;</section><section prefix="(10)">fails to comply with an order of the Director;</section><section prefix="(11)">fails to comply with any terms of settlement under a binding arbitration agreement;</section><section prefix="(12)">is found guilty by a court in this State of violating an unfair or deceptive trade practices provision under Title 13 of the Commercial Law Article; or</section><section prefix="(13)">fails to comply with &#xA7; 5-513 of the Health - General Article.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If a person is charged with a violation of this title that could result in suspension or revocation of a registration or permit, the Director may seek an immediate restraining order in a circuit court in this State to prohibit the person from engaging in the operation of any cemetery, crematory, or burial goods business.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The restraining order is in effect until:<section prefix="(i)">the court lifts the order; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">the charges are adjudicated or dismissed.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">If a person is charged with a violation of this title that could result in suspension or revocation of a registration or permit, the Director may petition a court to:<section prefix="(1)">appoint a receiver or trustee to take charge of the assets and operate the business of the person in the event that the registration or permit is suspended or revoked; and</section><section prefix="(2)">take any actions as are appropriate to protect the public interest.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Instead of or in addition to reprimanding a person, or suspending or revoking a registration or permit, the Director may impose a civil penalty:<section prefix="(1)">not to exceed $5,000 for each violation of this title or an order of the Director under this title; and</section><section prefix="(2)">not to exceed $500 for each day a violation continues past the time set for its correction.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">To determine the amount of the penalty imposed under this subsection, the Director shall consider:<section prefix="(1)">the seriousness of the violation;</section><section prefix="(2)">the harm caused by the violation;</section><section prefix="(3)">the good faith efforts of the person; and</section><section prefix="(4)">any history of previous violations by the person.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">Any civil penalties collected under this section shall be paid into the General Fund of the State.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">The Director shall consider the following facts in the granting, denial, renewal, suspension, or revocation of a registration or permit or the reprimand of a registrant or permit holder when an applicant, registrant, or permit holder, or an agent, employee, officer, director, or partner of an applicant, registrant, or permit holder is convicted of a felony or misdemeanor described in subsection (a)(3) of this section:<section prefix="(1)">the nature of the crime;</section><section prefix="(2)">the relationship of the crime to the activities authorized by this title;</section><section prefix="(3)">with respect to a felony, the relevance of the conviction to the fitness and qualifications of the applicant, registrant, or permit holder, or agent, employee, officer, director, or partner to operate a cemetery or provide burial goods;</section><section prefix="(4)">the length of time since the conviction; and</section><section prefix="(5)">the behavior and activities of the applicant, registrant, or permit holder, or any agent, employee, officer, director, or partner before and after the conviction.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
