<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gbr" order_by="gbr" level="1">Business Regulation</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gbr-11-308</section_number>
  <catch_line>Subject to the hearing provisions of &#xA7;&#xA7; 11-309 and 11-310 of this subtitle, the Commission may den...</catch_line>
  <order_by>308</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Subject to the hearing provisions of &#xA7;&#xA7; 11-309 and 11-310 of this subtitle, the Commission may deny a license to an applicant or discipline a licensee in accordance with this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Commission may deny a license to any applicant for any reason that the Commission considers sufficient.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Commission may reprimand any licensee or suspend or revoke a license if the licensee violates:<section prefix="(i)">this title;</section><section prefix="(ii)">a regulation adopted under this title; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">a condition set by the Commission.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Commission shall suspend or revoke a license if the applicant or licensee fails to:<section prefix="(i)">keep records and make reports of ownership of stock that are required under &#xA7; 11-314 of this subtitle; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">make a reasonable effort to get affidavits required under &#xA7; 11-314(b) and (c) of this subtitle.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Commission may impose a penalty not exceeding $5,000 for each racing day that the licensee is in violation of subsection (c) of this section:<section prefix="(i)">instead of suspending or revoking a license under subsection (c)(1) of this section; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">in addition to suspending or revoking a license under subsection (c)(2) of this section.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">To determine the amount of the penalty imposed under paragraph (1) of this subsection, the Commission shall consider:<section prefix="(i)">the seriousness of the violation;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the harm caused by the violation; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">the good faith or lack of good faith of the licensee.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A penalty imposed on a licensee shall be paid from the licensee's share of the takeout.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
