<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gbr" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="17-1405" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gbr-17-1405</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In St. Mary's County, this section does not apply if the promoter owns the property where the outdoor musical festival will be held.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in paragraph (3) of this subsection, each promoter shall post a cash bond with the application for a health permit.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The amount of the bond:<section prefix="(i)">shall be determined by the health officer; but</section><section prefix="(ii)">may not exceed:</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">In St. Mary's County, a promoter may pledge real or personal property instead of posting a cash bond if the promoter submits to the health officer a verified financial statement confirming that the fair market value of the pledged property equals or exceeds the amount of the bond required.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The health officer:<section prefix="(1)">shall keep the bond until 30 days after the end of the outdoor musical festival; and</section><section prefix="(2)">after that time, shall return to the promoter any money that has not been used and is not needed to satisfy pending claims.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">If, within 72 hours after an outdoor musical festival ends, the promoter fails to remove all trash, and to begin repair of any damage to property, including crops and livestock, that the outdoor musical festival or its spectators caused or created, the health officer may use as much of the bond as necessary to remove the trash and repair the damage.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This subsection does not affect any common law remedy that the person has against the promoter.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Any person who has a claim against the bond shall submit the claim to the health officer within 30 days after the outdoor musical festival ends.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">If a claim is submitted, the health officer shall determine and keep the amount necessary to cover the claim.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
