<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gca" order_by="gca" level="1">Corporations and Associations</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gca-9A-106</section_number>
  <catch_line>Except as provided in subsection (b) of this section, the law of the jurisdiction in which a partner...</catch_line>
  <order_by>106</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Except as provided in subsection (b) of this section, the law of the jurisdiction in which a partnership has its chief executive office governs relations among the partners and between the partners and the partnership.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The law of the state under which a foreign limited liability partnership is formed and registered as a limited liability partnership governs relations among the partners and the foreign limited liability partnership and the liability of a partner for any debts, obligations, or liabilities of or chargeable to the foreign limited liability partnership or another partner.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A partnership, including a limited liability partnership, may conduct its business, carry on its operations, and have and exercise the powers granted by this title in any state, territory, district, or possession of the United States or in any foreign country.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">It is the policy of this State that the internal affairs of partnerships, including limited liability partnerships, formed and existing under this title, including the liability of partners for debts, obligations, and liabilities of or chargeable to partnerships, shall be subject to and governed by the laws of this State.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">It is the intent of the legislature that the legal existence of limited liability partnerships formed and existing under this title or a predecessor statute be recognized outside the boundaries of this State and that the laws of this State governing such limited liability partnerships transacting business outside this State be granted the protection of full faith and credit under the Constitution of the United States.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">A foreign limited liability partnership may not be denied registration under Subtitle 11 of this title by reason of any difference between those laws and the laws of this State.</section>
  </text>
</law>
