<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gca" order_by="" level="1">Corporations and Associations</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gca-4A-707</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>707</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Department shall require a limited liability company, limited partnership, partnership, corporation, or business trust to submit with the articles of merger a property certificate for each county where a merging limited liability company, partnership, limited partnership, corporation, or business trust other than the successor owns an interest in land.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The property certificate is not required with respect to any property in which the only interest owned by the merging limited liability company, partnership, limited partnership, corporation, or business trust is a security interest.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The property certificate:<section prefix="(1)">Shall be in the form and number of copies that the Department requires; and</section><section prefix="(2)">May include the certificate of the Department required by &#xA7; 4A-706 of this subtitle.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The property certificate shall provide a deed reference or other description sufficient to identify the property.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Department shall:<section prefix="(i)">Indicate on the property certificate the time the articles of merger are accepted for record; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Send a copy of the property certificate to the chief assessor of the county where the property is located.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">A transfer, vesting, or devolution of title to the property is not invalidated or otherwise affected by any error or defect in the property certificate, failure to file the property certificate, or failure by the Department to act on the property certificate.</section>
  </text>
</law>
