<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gca" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="11-701" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gca-11-701</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In his discretion, the Commissioner may:<section prefix="(1)">Make public or private investigations within or outside of this State as he considers necessary to:<section prefix="(i)">Determine whether any person has violated or is about to violate any provision of this title or any rule or order under this title; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">Aid in the enforcement of this title or in the prescribing of rules and forms under this title;</section></section><section prefix="(2)">Require or permit any person to file a statement in writing, under oath or otherwise as the Commissioner determines, as to all the facts and circumstances concerning the matter to be investigated; and</section><section prefix="(3)">Publish information concerning any violation of this title or any rule or order under this title.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">For the purpose of any investigation or proceeding under this title, the Commissioner or any officer designated by him may administer oaths and affirmations, subpoena witnesses, compel their attendance, take evidence, and require the production of any books, papers, correspondence, memoranda, agreements, or other documents or records which the Commissioner considers relevant or material to the inquiry.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In case of contumacy by or refusal to obey a subpoena issued to any person, the circuit court of the county in which the person resides or transacts business, on application by the Commissioner, may issue to the person an order requiring him to appear before the Commissioner or the officer designated by him to produce documentary evidence if so ordered or to give evidence touching the matter under investigation or in question.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Failure to obey the order of the court may be punished by the court as a contempt of court.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A person is not excused from attending and testifying or from producing any document or record before the Commissioner, or in obedience to the subpoena of the Commissioner or any officer designated by him, or in any proceeding instituted by the Commissioner, on the ground that the testimony or evidence, documentary or otherwise, required of him may tend to incriminate him or subject him to a penalty or forfeiture. However, an individual may not be prosecuted or subjected to any penalty or forfeiture for or on account of any specific subject concerning which he is compelled, after claiming his privilege against self-incrimination as to that specific subject, to testify or produce evidence, documentary or otherwise, except that the individual testifying is not exempt from prosecution and punishment for perjury or contempt committed in testifying.</section>
  </text>
</law>
