<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gca" order_by="gca" level="1">Corporations and Associations</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gca-10-1105</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this section, "limited partnership" means a limited partnership that:...</catch_line>
  <order_by>1105</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, "limited partnership" means a limited partnership that:<section prefix="(1)">Was formed under the Maryland Uniform Limited Partnership Act before July 1, 1982; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Did not exercise the election authorized by &#xA7; 10-1104(4) of this subtitle before July 1, 1985.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">As provided in &#xA7; 10-1104(2) of this subtitle, a limited partnership shall be governed by the Maryland Revised Uniform Limited Partnership Act as of July 1, 1985. However, except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, a limited partnership is not required to file with the Department a certificate that would cause its certificate of limited partnership to comply with this title until the occurrence of an event which requires the filing of a certificate of amendment under &#xA7; 10-202(b) of this title at which time the limited partnership shall:<section prefix="(i)">File with the Department a certificate setting forth the information required by &#xA7; 10-201(a) of this title; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Pay the penalty specified in subsection (e) of this section.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A limited partnership or a person claiming under the limited partnership may not convey or accept title to real or personal property or maintain a suit in any court of the State unless it shows to the satisfaction of the court that the limited partnership has:<section prefix="(i)">Filed with the Department a certificate setting forth the information required by &#xA7; 10-201(a) of this title; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Paid the penalty under subsection (e) of this section.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The failure of a limited partnership to file with the Department a certificate setting forth the information required by &#xA7; 10-201(a) of this title does not of itself:<section prefix="(1)">Impair the validity of any contract or act of the limited partnership or prevent the limited partnership from defending any action, suit, or proceeding;</section><section prefix="(2)">Impose or permit the imposition of liability on a limited partner of the limited partnership as a general partner of the limited partnership; or</section><section prefix="(3)">Cause the limited partnership to dissolve or have its existence otherwise affected.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Until a limited partnership files with the Department a certificate setting forth the information required by &#xA7; 10-201(a) of this title:<section prefix="(1)">The limited partnership appoints the Department as its resident agent; and</section><section prefix="(2)">The principal office of the limited partnership is the principal place of business in this State of the limited partnership.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">When a limited partnership files with the Department a certificate setting forth the information required by &#xA7; 10-201(a) of this title, the Department shall impose a penalty of $200 on the limited partnership.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The penalty under this subsection shall be collected and may be reduced or abated under the procedures of &#xA7; 14-704 of the Tax - Property Article that relate to the penalty for failure to file reports with the Department.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
