<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gca" order_by="gca" level="1">Corporations and Associations</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gca-3-501</section_number>
  <catch_line>If the period of existence of a corporation has expired under the terms of its charter and if the co...</catch_line>
  <order_by>501</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">If the period of existence of a corporation has expired under the terms of its charter and if the corporation has been in continuous operation since before the date of expiration, the corporation, at any time within three years after the date of expiration, may reinstate its charter and extend its existence for an additional period or in perpetuity, by filing articles of extension as provided in this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The board of directors of a corporation proposing to reinstate its charter and extend its existence shall:<section prefix="(1)">Adopt a resolution which declares that the reinstatement and extension are advisable; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Direct that the proposed reinstatement and extension be submitted for consideration at either an annual or a special meeting of the stockholders.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Notice which states that a purpose of the meeting will be to act on the proposed reinstatement and extension shall be given by the corporation in the manner required by Title 2 of this article to:<section prefix="(1)">Each stockholder entitled to vote on the proposed reinstatement and extension; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Each stockholder not entitled to vote if the contract rights of his stock, as expressly set forth in the charter, would be altered by the reinstatement and extension.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The proposed reinstatement and extension shall be approved by the stockholders of the corporation by the affirmative vote of two thirds of all the votes entitled to be cast on the matter.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">Articles of extension shall be filed for record with the Department.</section>
  </text>
</law>
