<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gca" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="11-503.1" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gca-11-503.1</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">A person may not offer or sell a federal covered security in this State unless the documents required by this section are filed and the fees required by &#xA7; 11-506 or &#xA7; 11-510.1 of this subtitle are paid.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">With respect to a federal covered security specified in &#xA7; 18(b)(2) of the Securities Act of 1933, the Commissioner may require, by rule, order, or otherwise, the filing of the following documents:<section prefix="(1)">Before the initial offer of the federal covered security in this State:<section prefix="(i)">A notice in a form that the Commissioner requires or the documents filed with the Securities and Exchange Commission under the Securities Act of 1933;</section><section prefix="(ii)">A consent to service of process signed by the issuer; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">The fee required under &#xA7; 11-510.1 of this subtitle; and</section></section><section prefix="(2)">After the initial offer of the federal covered security in this State:<section prefix="(i)">Any document that is part of an amendment filed with the Securities and Exchange Commission under the Securities Act of 1933; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">As necessary to compute fees, an annual or periodic report of the value of the federal covered securities offered or sold in this State together with any fee required under &#xA7; 11-510.1(b) and (c) of this subtitle.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">With respect to a security that is a federal covered security specified in &#xA7; 18(b)(3) or (4) of the Securities Act of 1933, the Commissioner may require, by rule, order, or otherwise, the issuer to file:<section prefix="(1)">A consent to service of process signed by the issuer;</section><section prefix="(2)">The fee required under &#xA7; 11-506 of this subtitle; and</section><section prefix="(3)">Any document filed with the Securities and Exchange Commission under the Securities Act of 1933.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Except for a federal covered security specified in &#xA7; 18(b)(1) of the Securities Act of 1933, the Commissioner may issue a stop order suspending the offer and sale of a federal covered security, if the Commissioner finds that:<section prefix="(1)">The order is in the public interest; and</section><section prefix="(2)">There is a failure to comply with any condition established under this section.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The Commissioner may waive, by rule, order, or otherwise, the filing of any document required under this section.</section>
  </text>
</law>
