<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gca" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="2-506" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gca-2-506</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Unless this article or the charter of a corporation provides otherwise, at a meeting of stockholders:<section prefix="(1)">The presence in person or by proxy of stockholders entitled to cast a majority of all the votes entitled to be cast at the meeting constitutes a quorum; and</section><section prefix="(2)">A majority of all the votes cast at a meeting at which a quorum is present is sufficient to approve any matter which properly comes before the meeting.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Subject to other provisions of this article, unless the charter of a corporation provides otherwise, if two or more classes of stock are entitled to vote separately on any matter for which this article requires approval by two-thirds of all the votes entitled to be cast, the matter shall be approved by two-thirds of all the votes of each class.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This subsection applies to a corporation that:<section prefix="(i)">Has a class of equity securities registered under the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 and at least three directors who are not officers or employees of the corporation; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">Is registered as an open-end investment company under the Investment Company Act of 1940.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Unless the charter or bylaws of a corporation provide otherwise, at a meeting of stockholders the presence, in person or by proxy, of a majority of all votes entitled to be cast at the meeting constitutes a quorum.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">For purposes of this subsection, a quorum provision in the bylaws of a corporation may not be less than one-third of the votes entitled to be cast at the meeting.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
