<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gca" order_by="" level="1">Corporations and Associations</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gca-11-101</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>101</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this title, unless the context requires otherwise, the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Agent" means an individual other than a broker-dealer who represents a broker-dealer or issuer in effecting or attempting to effect the purchase or sale of securities.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Agent" includes a partner, officer, or director of a broker-dealer or issuer, or a person occupying a similar status or performing similar functions, only if the person otherwise comes within this definition.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Agent" does not include an individual who represents:<section prefix="(i)">An issuer in:<section prefix="1.">Effecting a transaction in a security exempted by &#xA7; 11-601(1), (2), (3), (9)(i), (10), (11), or (14)(i) of this title;</section><section prefix="2.">Effecting a transaction exempted by &#xA7; 11-602 of this title;</section><section prefix="3.">Effecting a transaction with an existing employee, partner, or director of the issuer if no commission or other remuneration is paid or given directly or indirectly for soliciting a person in this State; or</section><section prefix="4.">Effecting a transaction in a federal covered security under &#xA7; 18(b)(3) or &#xA7; 18(b)(4)(D) of the Securities Act of 1933 if no commission or other remuneration is paid or given directly or indirectly for soliciting a person in this State; or</section></section><section prefix="(ii)">A broker-dealer in effecting a transaction described in &#xA7; 15(h)(2) of the Securities Exchange Act of 1934.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Broker-dealer" means a person engaged in the business of effecting transactions in securities for the account of others or for his own account.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Broker-dealer" does not include:<section prefix="(i)">An agent;</section><section prefix="(ii)">An issuer;</section><section prefix="(iii)">A bank, savings institution, or trust company; or</section><section prefix="(iv)">A person who has no place of business in this State if:<section prefix="1.">He effects transactions in this State exclusively with or through the issuer of the securities involved in the transactions, another broker-dealer, or a bank, savings institution, trust company, insurance company, investment company as defined in the Investment Company Act of 1940, pension or profit-sharing trust, or other financial institution or institutional buyer, whether acting for itself or as trustee; or</section><section prefix="2.">During any period of 12 consecutive months, he does not direct more than 15 offers to sell or buy into the State in any manner, other than to the persons specified in paragraph (2)(iv)1 of this subsection, whether or not the offeror or any offeree is then present in the State.</section></section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">"Commissioner" means the Securities Commissioner of the Division of Securities.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"Federal covered adviser" means a person who is registered under &#xA7; 203 of the Investment Advisers Act of 1940.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">"Federal covered security" means a covered security under &#xA7; 18(b) of the Securities Act of 1933.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">"Guaranteed" means guaranteed as to payment of principal, interest, or dividends.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Investment adviser" means a person who, for compensation:<section prefix="(i)">Engages in the business of advising others, either directly or through publications or writings, as to the value of securities or as to the advisability of investing in, purchasing, or selling securities, or who, for compensation and as a part of a regular business, issues or promulgates analyses or reports concerning securities; or</section><section prefix="(ii)"><section prefix="1.">Provides or offers to provide, directly or indirectly, financial and investment counseling or advice, on a group or individual basis;</section><section prefix="2.">Gathers information relating to investments, establishes financial goals and objectives, processes and analyzes the information gathered, and recommends a financial plan; or</section><section prefix="3.">Holds out as an investment adviser in any way, including indicating by advertisement, card, or letterhead, or in any other manner indicates that the person is, a financial or investment "planner", "counselor", "consultant", or any other similar type of adviser or consultant.</section></section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Investment adviser" does not include:<section prefix="(i)">An investment adviser representative;</section><section prefix="(ii)">A bank, savings institution, or trust company;</section><section prefix="(iii)">A lawyer, certified public accountant, engineer, insurance producer, or teacher whose performance of investment advisory services is solely incidental to the practice of the profession, provided that the performance of such services is not solely incidental unless:<section prefix="1.">The investment advisory services rendered are connected with and reasonably related to the other professional services rendered;</section><section prefix="2.">The fee charged for the investment advisory services is based on the same factors as those used to determine the fee for other professional services; and</section><section prefix="3.">The lawyer, certified public accountant, engineer, insurance producer, or teacher does not hold out as an investment adviser;</section></section><section prefix="(iv)">A broker-dealer or its agent whose performance of these services is solely incidental to the conduct of business as a broker-dealer and who receives no special compensation for them;</section><section prefix="(v)">A publisher of any bona fide newspaper, news column, newsletter, news magazine, or business or financial publication or service, whether communicated in hard copy form, or by electronic means, or otherwise, that does not consist of the rendering of advice on the basis of the specific investment situation of each client;</section><section prefix="(vi)">A federal covered adviser; or</section><section prefix="(vii)">Any other person not within the intent of this subsection as the Commissioner by rule or order designates.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(i)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Investment adviser representative" or "representative" means any partner, officer, director of (or a person occupying a similar status or performing similar functions) or other individual who is employed by or associated with an investment adviser, or who has a place of business located in this State and is employed by or associated with a federal covered adviser, and who:<section prefix="(i)">Makes any recommendations or otherwise renders investment advice to clients;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Represents an investment adviser in rendering the services described under subsection (h)(1) of this section;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Manages accounts or portfolios of clients;</section><section prefix="(iv)">Determines which recommendation or investment advice should be given with respect to a particular client account;</section><section prefix="(v)">Solicits, offers or negotiates for the sale of or sells investment advisory services;</section><section prefix="(vi)">Directly supervises employees who perform any of the foregoing; or</section><section prefix="(vii)">Holds out as an investment adviser.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Investment adviser representative" or "representative" does not include:<section prefix="(i)">Any other person not within the intent of this subsection as the Commissioner designates by rule or order; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">Clerical or ministerial personnel.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(j)">"Investment Company Act of 1940" and "Investment Advisers Act of 1940" mean the federal statutes of those names, as amended.</section>
    <section prefix="(k)">"Issuer" means any person who issues or proposes to issue a security, except that:<section prefix="(1)">With respect to certificates of deposit, voting-trust certificates, or collateral-trust certificates or with respect to certificates of interest or shares in an unincorporated investment trust not having a board of directors or persons performing similar functions or of the fixed, restricted management, or unit type, the term "issuer" means the person performing the acts and assuming the duties of depositor or manager under the provisions of the trust or other agreement or instrument under which the security is issued; and</section><section prefix="(2)">With respect to certificates of interest or participation in oil, gas, or mining titles or leases or in payments out of production under the titles or leases, there is not considered to be any "issuer".</section></section>
    <section prefix="(l)">"Nonissuer distribution" and "nonissuer transaction" mean a distribution or transaction, as the case may be, not directly or indirectly for the benefit of the issuer.</section>
    <section prefix="(m)">"Offer" or "offer to sell", except as provided in &#xA7; 11-102(a) of this subtitle, includes every attempt or offer to dispose of or solicitation of an offer to buy, a security or interest in a security for value.</section>
    <section prefix="(n)">"Person" means an individual, a corporation, a partnership, an association, a joint-stock company, a trust where the interests of the beneficiaries are evidenced by a security, an unincorporated organization, a government, or a political subdivision of a government.</section>
    <section prefix="(o)">"Public Utility Holding Company Act of 1935" means the federal statute of that name, as amended.</section>
    <section prefix="(p)">"Sale" or "sell", except as provided in &#xA7; 11-102(a) of this subtitle, includes every contract of sale of, contract to sell, or disposition of a security or interest in a security for value.</section>
    <section prefix="(q)">"Securities Act of 1933" and "Securities Exchange Act of 1934" mean the federal statutes of those names, as amended.</section>
    <section prefix="(r)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Security" means any:<section prefix="(i)">Note;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Stock;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Treasury stock;</section><section prefix="(iv)">Bond;</section><section prefix="(v)">Debenture;</section><section prefix="(vi)">Evidence of indebtedness;</section><section prefix="(vii)">Certificate of interest or participation in any profit-sharing agreement;</section><section prefix="(viii)">Collateral-trust certificate;</section><section prefix="(ix)">Preorganization certificate or subscription;</section><section prefix="(x)">Transferable share;</section><section prefix="(xi)">Investment contract;</section><section prefix="(xii)">Voting-trust certificate;</section><section prefix="(xiii)">Certificate of deposit for a security;</section><section prefix="(xiv)">Certificate of interest or participation in an oil, gas, or mining title or lease or in payments out of production under the title or lease;</section><section prefix="(xv)">In general, any interest or instrument commonly known as a "security"; or</section><section prefix="(xvi)">Certificate of interest or participation in, temporary or interim certificate for, receipt for, guarantee of, or warrant or right to subscribe to or purchase any of the preceding.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Security" does not include any insurance or endowment policy or annuity contract under which an insurance company promises to pay money either in a lump sum, periodically for life, or some other specified period.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(s)">"State" means any state, territory, or possession of the United States, the District of Columbia, and Puerto Rico.</section>
  </text>
</law>
