<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gca" order_by="" level="1">Corporations and Associations</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gca-2-309</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>309</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, "reverse stock split" means a combination of outstanding shares of stock of a corporation into a lesser number of shares of stock of the same class without any change in the aggregate amount of stated capital of the corporation, except for a change resulting from the elimination of fractional shares in accordance with &#xA7; 2-214 of this title.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">If authorized by its board of directors, a corporation may make distributions to its stockholders, subject to any restriction in its charter and the limitations in &#xA7; 2-311 of this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A division of issued shares into a greater number of shares of the same class without any change in the aggregate amount of stated capital is a stock split, and a division with a change in the aggregate amount of stated capital is a stock dividend within the meaning of this subsection.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If authorized by its board of directors and unless the charter provides otherwise, shares may be issued by a corporation, without consideration to the holders of one or more classes or series of stock, as a stock split or a stock dividend.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">If a stock dividend is payable in a corporation's own stock with par value, the shares shall be issued at par value and, at the time the stock dividend is paid, the corporation shall transfer from surplus to stated capital an amount at least equal to the aggregate par value of the shares to be issued.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">If a stock dividend is payable in a corporation's own stock without par value, the board of directors shall adopt at the time the stock dividend is declared a resolution which sets the aggregate amount to be attributed to stated capital with respect to the shares that constitute the stock dividend and, at the time the stock dividend is paid, the corporation shall transfer at least that amount from surplus to stated capital.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">A dividend payable in shares of one class of a corporation's stock may not be declared or paid to the holders of shares of another class of stock unless the payment has been:<section prefix="(i)">Approved by the board of directors in accordance with specific authority in the charter; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">Approved at a meeting of stockholders by the affirmative vote of a majority of all the votes entitled to be cast on the matter of each class entitled to vote on it.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">If the board of directors of a corporation has given general authorization for a distribution and provides for or establishes a method or procedure for determining the maximum amount of the distribution, the board may delegate to an officer of the corporation the power, in accordance with the general authorization, to fix the amount and other terms of the distribution.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This subsection applies to a corporation:<section prefix="(i)">With a class of equity securities registered under the Securities Exchange Act of 1934; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">Registered as an open-end investment company under the Investment Company Act of 1940.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Unless prohibited by the charter of a corporation by reference to this subsection or the subject matter of this subsection, the board of directors of the corporation may amend the charter, with the approval of a majority of the board of directors and without stockholder action, to effect a reverse stock split that results in a combination of shares of stock at a ratio of not more than 10 shares of stock into one share of stock in any 12-month period.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Within 20 days after the effective date of the reverse stock split, the corporation shall give written notice of the reverse stock split to each holder of record of the combined shares of stock as of the effective date.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
