<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gca" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="11-503" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gca-11-503</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Any security for which a registration statement has been filed under the Securities Act of 1933 in connection with the same offering may be registered by coordination.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A registration statement under this section shall contain the following information and be accompanied by the following documents, in addition to the information specified in &#xA7; 11-507(a) of this subtitle and the consent to service of process required by &#xA7; 11-802(a) of this title:<section prefix="(1)">Two copies of the latest form of prospectus filed under the Securities Act of 1933;</section><section prefix="(2)">If the Commissioner by rule or otherwise requires:<section prefix="(i)">A copy of the articles of incorporation and bylaws or their substantial equivalents, as currently in effect;</section><section prefix="(ii)">A copy of any agreements with or among underwriters;</section><section prefix="(iii)">A copy of any indenture or other instrument governing the issuance of the security to be registered; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">A specimen or copy of the security;</section></section><section prefix="(3)">If the Commissioner requests, any other information or copies of any other documents filed under the Securities Act of 1933; and</section><section prefix="(4)">An undertaking to forward all future amendments to the federal prospectus, other than an amendment which merely delays the effective date of the registration statement, promptly and in any event not later than the first business day after the day they are forwarded to or filed with the Securities and Exchange Commission, whichever first occurs.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A registration statement under this section automatically becomes effective at the moment the federal registration statement becomes effective, if all the following conditions are satisfied:<section prefix="(i)">A stop order is not in effect and a proceeding is not pending under &#xA7;&#xA7; 11-511 through 11-513 of this subtitle;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The registration statement has been on file with the Commissioner for at least ten business days; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">A statement of the maximum and minimum proposed offering prices and the maximum underwriting discounts and commissions has been on file for two full business days or any shorter period which the Commissioner permits by rule or otherwise, and the offering is made within those limitations.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The registrant promptly shall notify the Commissioner in writing, by facsimile transmission, telegram, or by any other means that the Commissioner by rule or order may deem appropriate, of the date and time when the federal registration statement became effective and the content of the price amendment, if any, and promptly shall file a post-effective amendment containing the information and documents in the price amendment.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Price amendment" means the final federal amendment which includes a statement of the offering price, underwriting and selling discounts or commissions, amount of proceeds, conversion rates, call prices, and other matters dependent on the offering price.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">On failure to receive the required notification and post-effective amendment with respect to the price amendment, the Commissioner may enter a stop order without notice or hearing, retroactively denying effectiveness to the registration statement or suspending its effectiveness until compliance with this subsection, if he promptly notifies the registrant by telephone or telegram, and promptly confirms by letter, facsimile transmission, or telegram when he notifies by telephone, of the issuance of the order. If the registrant proves compliance with the requirements of this subsection as to notice and post-effective amendment, the stop order is void as of the time of its entry.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">The Commissioner by rule or otherwise may waive either or both of the conditions specified in paragraphs (1)(ii) and (iii) of this subsection.</section>
      <section prefix="(6)">If the federal registration statement becomes effective before all the conditions in this subsection are satisfied and they are not waived, the registration statement automatically becomes effective as soon as all the conditions are satisfied. If the registrant advises the Commissioner of the date when the federal registration statement is expected to become effective, the Commissioner promptly shall advise the registrant by telephone, facsimile transmission, or telegram, at the expense of the registrant, whether all the conditions are satisfied and whether he then contemplates the institution of a proceeding under &#xA7;&#xA7; 11-511 through 11-513 of this subtitle, but this advice by the Commissioner does not preclude the institution of the proceeding at any time.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Any security for which the documents required by any regulation adopted by the Securities and Exchange Commission under &#xA7; 3(b) or &#xA7; 3(c) of the Securities Act of 1933 have been filed with the Commission in connection with the same offering may be registered by coordination on compliance with subsections (b) and (c) of this section in the manner the Commissioner by rule or order may prescribe.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">For purposes of this subsection, the terms "federal registration statement" and "federal prospectus" include the documents, including the offering circular, if any, which may be filed with the Securities and Exchange Commission in accordance with any such regulation.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The Commissioner by rule or order may waive or modify the application of a requirement of this section if a provision or an amendment, repeal or other alteration of the provisions of the Securities Act of 1933, or the regulations adopted under that act, render the waiver or modification appropriate for further coordination of State and federal law.</section>
  </text>
</law>
