<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gca" order_by="" level="1">Corporations and Associations</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gca-3-112</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>112</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In order to keep the land assessment records current in each county, the Department shall require a corporation, limited partnership, limited liability company, or business trust to submit with the articles a property certificate for each county where a merging corporation, partnership, limited partnership, limited liability company, or business trust other than the successor, a consolidating corporation, or a transferor corporation owns an interest in land.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A property certificate is not required with respect to any property in which the only interest owned by the merging corporation, partnership, limited partnership, limited liability company, or business trust or by the consolidating or transferor corporation is a security interest.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The property certificate shall be in the form and number of copies which the Department requires and may include the certificate of the Department required by &#xA7; 3-111 of this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The property certificate shall:<section prefix="(i)">Provide a deed reference or other description sufficient to identify the property; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">State the actual consideration paid or to be paid for the property.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Department shall indicate on the certificate the time the articles are accepted for record and send a copy of it to the chief assessor of the county where the property is located.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">A transfer, vesting, or devolution of title to the property is not invalidated or otherwise affected by any error or defect in the property certificate, failure to file it, or failure of the Department to act on it.</section>
  </text>
</law>
