<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gca" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="5-632" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gca-5-632</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">A cooperative that has begun doing business may be dissolved as provided in this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A proposed dissolution shall be approved by the affirmative vote of not less than two-thirds of the members voting on the matter at an annual or special meeting of the members.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">On approval of the proposed dissolution by the members of the cooperative as provided in subsection (b) of this section:<section prefix="(i)">A certificate of election to dissolve shall be signed and acknowledged for the cooperative by its chairman or vice-chairman and attested by its secretary; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">The seal of the cooperative shall be affixed to the certificate.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The certificate shall state:<section prefix="(i)">The name of the cooperative and the address of its principal office; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">That the members of the cooperative have approved the dissolution in accordance with subsection (b) of this section.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The chairman or vice-chairman who signs the certificate for the cooperative shall make and attach to the certificate an affidavit stating that the statements made in the certificate are true.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The certificate and affidavit shall be filed for record with the Department.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">On the Department's acceptance for record of the certificate of election to dissolve and affidavit, the cooperative shall cease doing business except to the extent necessary to wind up its business and affairs.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The corporate existence of the cooperative shall continue until articles of dissolution have been accepted for record by the Department.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The board of directors immediately shall cause notice of the dissolution proceedings to be:<section prefix="(i)">Mailed to each known creditor of and claimant against the cooperative; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Published once a week for 2 successive weeks in a newspaper of general circulation published in the county in which the principal office of the cooperative is located.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The board shall collect money owing to the cooperative, liquidate its assets, discharge its debts, obligations, and liabilities, and do all other acts required to wind up the business and affairs of the cooperative.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">
        <section prefix="(i)">After discharging, or adequately providing for the discharge of, all of the debts, obligations, and liabilities of the cooperative, the board shall distribute any remaining money among the current and former members of the cooperative.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The money shall be distributed in proportion to the patronage of each current or former member:</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">After winding up the business and affairs of the cooperative as provided in subsection (d) of this section, the board of directors shall authorize the execution of articles of dissolution.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The articles of dissolution shall be signed and acknowledged for the cooperative by its chairman or vice-chairman and attested by its secretary, and the seal of the cooperative shall be affixed to the articles.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The articles of dissolution shall state:<section prefix="(1)">The name of the cooperative and the address of its principal office;</section><section prefix="(2)">The date on which the certificate of election to dissolve was accepted for record by the Department;</section><section prefix="(3)">That there are no actions pending against the cooperative;</section><section prefix="(4)">That all debts, obligations, and liabilities of the cooperative have been discharged, or that adequate provision has been made for their discharge;</section><section prefix="(5)">That the articles are executed in accordance with this subtitle; and</section><section prefix="(6)">That the provisions of this section have been complied with.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(g)">The chairman or vice-chairman who signs the articles of dissolution for the cooperative shall make and attach to the articles an affidavit stating that the statements made in the articles are true.</section>
  </text>
</law>
