<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gca" order_by="" level="1">Corporations and Associations</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gca-4A-406</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>406</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">A member may inspect and copy, in person or by agent, from time to time on reasonable written demand, for any purpose reasonably related to the member's membership interest:<section prefix="(1)">True and full information regarding the state of the business and financial condition of the limited liability company;</section><section prefix="(2)">A copy of the articles of organization and operating agreement and all amendments to the articles of organization and operating agreement;</section><section prefix="(3)">A current list of the names and last known business, residence, or mailing addresses of all members; and</section><section prefix="(4)">Other information regarding the affairs of the limited liability company as is just and reasonable for any purpose reasonably related to the member's membership interest.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Any member may inspect and copy, in person or by agent, a copy of the limited liability company's federal, state, or local income tax returns.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The rights to inspect and copy records of a limited liability company may be subject to reasonable standards that may be set forth in the articles of organization or the operating agreement, including standards governing what information and documents are to be furnished, at what time and location, and at whose expense.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Unless a member seeking information executes a confidentiality or nondisclosure agreement reasonably acceptable to the limited liability company restricting the use and disclosure of the information, a limited liability company shall have the right to keep confidential from members, for a reasonable period of time:<section prefix="(1)">Any information that the limited liability company reasonably believes to be in the nature of trade secrets;</section><section prefix="(2)">Information the disclosure of which the limited liability company in good faith believes:<section prefix="(i)">Is not in the best interest of the limited liability company; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">Could damage the limited liability company or its business; or</section></section><section prefix="(3)">Information the limited liability company is required by law or by agreement with a third party to keep confidential.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">Any demand by a member under this section shall be in writing and shall state the purpose of the demand.</section>
  </text>
</law>
