<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gca" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="11-510.1" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gca-11-510.1</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">A face-amount certificate company, an open-end management company, a closed-end management company that is not a federal covered security under &#xA7; 18(b)(1) of the Securities Act of 1933, or a unit investment trust, as those terms are defined in the Investment Company Act of 1940, shall comply with the requirements of this section, if the company or trust files:<section prefix="(1)">A notice under &#xA7; 11-503.1 of this subtitle of the offer or sale in this State of an indefinite amount of federal covered securities specified in &#xA7; 18(b)(2) of the Securities Act of 1933; or</section><section prefix="(2)">An application to register under &#xA7; 11-503 of this subtitle the offer and sale in this State of an indefinite amount of securities.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A face-amount certificate company or an open-end management company, at the time of filing, shall pay an initial fee of $500 and within 60 days after the issuer's fiscal year end during which its registration statement is effective or notice required by &#xA7; 11-503.1(b) of this subtitle is filed:<section prefix="(i)">Pay a fee of $1,300; or</section><section prefix="(ii)"/></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">When calculating the fee in accordance with paragraph (1)(ii)2 of this subsection, the initial fee of $500 shall be deducted from the aggregate fee due.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">Except as provided in subsection (d) of this section, the aggregate fee due under this paragraph may not exceed $1,500.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">If the amount due under paragraph (1)(ii)2 of this subsection is less than $500, no additional amount may be payable, and no credit or refund may be allowed or returned.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">At the time of filing, a unit investment trust, or a closed-end management company that is not a federal covered security under &#xA7; 18(b)(1) of the Securities Act of 1933, shall pay an initial fee of $500.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Within 60 days after the anniversary of the date on which the issuer's offer became effective or its notice filed under &#xA7; 11-503(b) of this subtitle was accepted, a unit investment trust, or a closed-end management company that is not a federal covered security under &#xA7; 18(b)(1) of the Securities Act of 1933, shall:<section prefix="(i)">Pay a fee of $1,300; or</section><section prefix="(ii)"/></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">When calculating the fee in accordance with paragraph (1)(ii)2 of this subsection, the initial $500 fee shall be deducted from the aggregate fee due.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">Except as provided in subsection (d) of this section, the aggregate fee due under this paragraph may not exceed $1,500.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">Except as provided in subsection (d) of this section, if the amount due under paragraph (1)(ii)2 of this subsection is less than $500, no additional amount may be payable, and no credit or refund may be allowed or returned.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Commissioner, by rule, order, or otherwise, may extend the length of the renewal period to a period not exceeding 2 years for the effectiveness of a registered offering or for a notice filed under &#xA7; 11-503.1 of this subtitle.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If the Commissioner extends a renewal period in excess of 1 year, the fee shall be prorated to the extended renewal period.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
