<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gca" order_by="" level="1">Corporations and Associations</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gca-5-6B-05</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>05</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">At least 180 days before a tenant is required to vacate a portion of a residential rental facility used as a residence that is acquired or is to be acquired by a cooperative housing corporation or that is owned by or is to be owned by a corporation that may become a cooperative housing corporation, the owner and the landlord of each tenant in possession of a portion of the residential rental facility shall give the tenant a notice in substantially the form specified in subsection (f) of this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">For effective notice, the owner and the landlord, at least 15 days before giving the notice required by this section, shall file with the Secretary of State a copy of the notice, a list of the tenants to whom the owner and the landlord anticipate giving notice, and an affidavit in substantially the following form:</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">If a tenant first leases a portion of the premises as a residence after the notice required by this subsection has been given, the owner and the landlord, if other than the owner, shall inform the tenant in writing that the notice has been given. The tenant shall be so informed on or before signing the lease or taking possession, whichever occurs first.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The notice shall be considered to have been given to each tenant if delivered by hand or mailed, postage prepaid, to the tenant's last known address.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A tenant leasing a portion of a residential rental facility as a residence at the time the notice referred to in subsection (a) of this section is given to the tenant may not be required to vacate the premises prior to the expiration of 180 days from the giving of the notice except for:<section prefix="(1)">Breach of a covenant in the lease occurring before or after the notice is given;</section><section prefix="(2)">Nonpayment of rent occurring before or after the notice is given; or</section><section prefix="(3)">Failure of the tenant to vacate the premises at the time that is indicated by the tenant in a notice given to the landlord under subsection (e) of this section.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If the lease term of a tenant who leases a portion of a residential rental facility as a residence at the time the notice referred to in subsection (a) of this section is given would ordinarily terminate during the 180-day period, the lease term shall be extended, at the option of the tenant, until the expiration of the 180-day period.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The extended term shall be at the same rent and on the same terms and conditions as were applicable on the last day of the lease term.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">A tenant who leases a portion of a residential rental facility as a residence at the time the notice referred to in subsection (a) of this section is given may terminate the lease, without penalty for termination, upon at least 30 days' written notice to the landlord.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The notice referred to in subsection (a) of this section shall be sufficient for the purposes of this section if it is in substantially the following form. As to rental facilities containing fewer than 10 units, "Section 2" of the notice is not required to be given.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">The failure of a landlord or owner to give notice as required by this section is a defense to an action for possession.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">This section does not apply to a tenant whose lease term expires during the 180-day period and who has given written notice of intent not to renew the lease before the notice required by subsection (a) of this section is given.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">A tenant may not waive the rights under this section except as otherwise provided under this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(j)">At the expiration of the 180-day period a tenant shall become a tenant from month-to-month subject to the same rent, terms, and conditions as those existing at the giving of the notice required by subsection (a) of this section, if the tenant's initial lease has expired and the tenant has not:<section prefix="(1)">Entered into a new lease;</section><section prefix="(2)">Vacated under subsection (e) of this section; or</section><section prefix="(3)">Been notified in accordance with applicable law prior to the expiration of the 180-day period that the tenant must vacate at the end of that period.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
