<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gca" order_by="gca" level="1">Corporations and Associations</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gca-11-102</section_number>
  <catch_line>The terms "offer", "offer to sell", "sale", and "sell", as defined in &#xA7; 11-101(m) and (p) of this s...</catch_line>
  <order_by>102</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The terms "offer", "offer to sell", "sale", and "sell", as defined in &#xA7; 11-101(m) and (p) of this subtitle, do not include:<section prefix="(1)">Any bona fide pledge or loan;</section><section prefix="(2)">Any stock dividend, whether the corporation distributing the dividend is the issuer of the stock or not, if nothing of value is given by stockholders for the dividend other than the surrender of a right to a cash or property dividend when each stockholder may elect to take the dividend in cash, property, or stock;</section><section prefix="(3)">Any act incident to a class vote by stockholders, under the certificate of incorporation or the applicable corporation statute, on a merger, consolidation, split-up, spin-off, share exchange, reclassification of securities, or transfer of corporate assets in consideration of the issuance, in whole or in part, of securities of another corporation;</section><section prefix="(4)">Any act incident to a judicially approved reorganization in which a security is issued:<section prefix="(i)">In exchange for one or more outstanding securities, claims, or property interests; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">Partly in such exchange and partly for cash; or</section></section><section prefix="(5)">Any act as to which the Commissioner by rule or order finds that:<section prefix="(i)">Application of &#xA7; 11-101(m) and (p) of this subtitle is not necessary or appropriate for the protection of investors; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">The finding is consistent with the public interest and within the purposes fairly intended by the policy and provisions of this title.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">As used in this title, "fraud", "deceit", and "defraud" are not limited to common-law deceit.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Any security given or delivered with or as a bonus on account of any purchase of securities or any other thing is considered to constitute part of the subject of the purchase and to have been offered and sold for value.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A purported gift of assessable stock is considered to involve an offer and sale.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">Every sale or offer of a warrant or right to purchase or subscribe to another security of the same or another issuer and every sale or offer of a security which gives the holder a present or future right or privilege to convert into another security of the same or another issuer is considered to include an offer of the other security.</section>
  </text>
</law>
