<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gca" order_by="gca" level="1">Corporations and Associations</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gca-2-608</section_number>
  <catch_line>If authorized by a majority of the entire board of directors, a corporation may restate its charter ...</catch_line>
  <order_by>608</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">If authorized by a majority of the entire board of directors, a corporation may restate its charter as provided in this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Articles of restatement shall include every charter provision currently in effect, omitting only provisions which this section specifically permits to be omitted, and shall state:<section prefix="(1)">That the corporation desires to restate its charter as currently in effect;</section><section prefix="(2)">That the provisions set forth in the articles of restatement are all the provisions of the charter currently in effect;</section><section prefix="(3)">That the restatement of the charter has been approved by a majority of the entire board of directors;</section><section prefix="(4)">That the charter is not amended by the articles of restatement;</section><section prefix="(5)">The current address of the principal office of the corporation;</section><section prefix="(6)">The name and address of the corporation's current resident agent; and</section><section prefix="(7)">The number of directors of the corporation and the names of those currently in office.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Articles of restatement may omit all provisions which relate solely to a class of stock if, at the time:<section prefix="(1)">There are no shares of the class outstanding; and</section><section prefix="(2)">The corporation has no authority to issue any shares of the class.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Articles of restatement may not contain:<section prefix="(1)">Any provisions of the charter which have been eliminated from it by amendment;</section><section prefix="(2)">The original charter provisions which contained the information required by subsection (b) (5), (6), and (7) of this section, if they are no longer current; or</section><section prefix="(3)">Any amendment to the charter of the corporation.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
