<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gca" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="5-6C-01" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gca-5-6C-01</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Benefit corporation" means a Maryland corporation that elects to be a benefit corporation in accordance with &#xA7; 5-6C-03 of this subtitle and has not ceased to be a benefit corporation through the operation of &#xA7; 5-6C-04 of this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"General public benefit" means a material, positive impact on society and the environment, as measured by a third-party standard, through activities that promote a combination of specific public benefits.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">"Specific public benefit" includes:<section prefix="(1)">Providing individuals or communities with beneficial products or services;</section><section prefix="(2)">Promoting economic opportunity for individuals or communities beyond the creation of jobs in the normal course of business;</section><section prefix="(3)">Preserving the environment;</section><section prefix="(4)">Improving human health;</section><section prefix="(5)">Promoting the arts, sciences, or advancement of knowledge;</section><section prefix="(6)">Increasing the flow of capital to entities with a public benefit purpose; or</section><section prefix="(7)">The accomplishment of any other particular benefit for society or the environment.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"Third-party standard" means a standard for defining, reporting, and assessing best practices in corporate social and environmental performance that:<section prefix="(1)">Is developed by a person or entity that is independent of the benefit corporation; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Is transparent because the following information about the standard is publicly available or accessible:<section prefix="(i)">The factors considered when measuring the performance of a business;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The relative weightings of those factors; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">The identity of the persons who developed and control changes to the standard and the process by which those changes were made.</section></section></section>
  </text>
</law>
