<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gca" order_by="gca" level="1">Corporations and Associations</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gca-1-403</section_number>
  <catch_line>Unless a lack of power or capacity is asserted in a proceeding described in this section, an act of ...</catch_line>
  <order_by>403</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Unless a lack of power or capacity is asserted in a proceeding described in this section, an act of a corporation or a transfer of real or personal property by or to the corporation is not invalid or unenforceable solely because the corporation lacked the power or capacity to take the action.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Lack of corporate power or capacity may be asserted by a stockholder in a proceeding to enjoin the corporation from doing an act or from transferring or acquiring real or personal property.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If the act or transfer sought to be enjoined is based on a contract to which the corporation is a party and if all parties to the contract are parties to the proceeding, the court may set the contract aside and enjoin its performance.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The court may award compensatory damages to any party to the contract who suffers a loss because of the action of the court. However, the court may not award compensatory damages for loss of anticipated profits to be derived from performance of the contract.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Lack of corporate power or capacity may be asserted by the corporation in a suit brought in its name by the corporation or its receiver, trustee, other legal representative, or in a representative suit brought by a stockholder against its present or former officers or directors.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Lack of corporate power or capacity may be asserted by the Attorney General in a proceeding for the forfeiture of the charter of the corporation or to enjoin it from transacting unauthorized business.</section>
  </text>
</law>
