<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gca" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="5-101" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gca-5-101</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Disqualified person" means an individual or entity that for any reason is or becomes ineligible under this subtitle to be issued stock by a professional corporation.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Foreign professional corporation" means a professional corporation organized under the laws of another state or a territory, possession, or district of the United States.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">"License" means any license, certification, certificate, registration, or other legal authorization required by statute as a condition precedent to the performance of a professional service in the State.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"Licensing unit" means the board, agency, court, or other entity that licenses or otherwise legally authorizes the rendition of a professional service.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">"Professional corporation" means a corporation organized under this subtitle for the purpose of rendering professional services.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Professional service" means a service that may lawfully be rendered only by a person licensed or otherwise authorized by a licensing unit in the State to render the service and that may not lawfully be rendered by a corporation under the Maryland General Corporation Law.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Professional service" includes, but is not limited to, a service provided by:<section prefix="(i)">An architect;</section><section prefix="(ii)">An attorney;</section><section prefix="(iii)">A certified public accountant;</section><section prefix="(iv)">A chiropractor;</section><section prefix="(v)">A dentist;</section><section prefix="(vi)">An osteopath;</section><section prefix="(vii)">A podiatrist;</section><section prefix="(viii)">A physician;</section><section prefix="(ix)">A professional engineer;</section><section prefix="(x)">A licensed real estate broker, licensed real estate salesperson, and licensed associate real estate broker;</section><section prefix="(xi)">A veterinarian;</section><section prefix="(xii)">A psychologist; and</section><section prefix="(xiii)">A physical therapist.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(h)">"Qualified person" means an individual, professional corporation, or general partnership that is eligible under this Act to be issued stock by a professional corporation.</section>
  </text>
</law>
