<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gca" order_by="gca" level="1">Corporations and Associations</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gca-4A-210</section_number>
  <catch_line>Each limited liability company shall have:...</catch_line>
  <order_by>210</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Each limited liability company shall have:<section prefix="(1)">A principal office in this State; and</section><section prefix="(2)">A resident agent.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A limited liability company may designate or change its resident agent or principal office by filing for record with the Department a statement signed by an authorized person which authorizes the designation or change.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A limited liability company may change the address of its resident agent by filing for record with the Department a statement of the change signed by an authorized person.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A designation or change of a principal office or resident agent or address of the resident agent for a limited liability company under this subsection is effective when the Department accepts the statement for record.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A resident agent who changes addresses in this State may notify the Department of the change by filing for record with the Department a statement of the change signed by or on behalf of the resident agent.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The statement shall include:<section prefix="(i)">The name of the limited liability company for which the change is effective;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The old and new addresses of the resident agent; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">The date on which the change is effective.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">If the old and new addresses of the resident agent are the same as the old and new addresses of the principal office of the limited liability company, the statement may include a change of address of the principal office if:<section prefix="(i)">The resident agent notifies the limited liability company in writing; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">The statement recites that notice has been sent.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The change of address of the resident agent or principal office is effective when the Department accepts the statement for record.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A resident agent may resign by filing with the Department a counterpart or photocopy of the signed resignation.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Unless a later time is specified in the resignation, it is effective:<section prefix="(i)">At the time it is filed with the Department, if the limited liability company has more than 1 resident agent; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">10 days after it is filed with the Department, if the limited liability company has only 1 resident agent.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
