<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gca" order_by="gca" level="1">Corporations and Associations</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gca-2-206</section_number>
  <catch_line>The consideration for the issuance of stock, convertible securities, warrants, or options may consis...</catch_line>
  <order_by>206</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The consideration for the issuance of stock, convertible securities, warrants, or options may consist in whole or in part of:<section prefix="(1)">Money;</section><section prefix="(2)">Tangible or intangible property;</section><section prefix="(3)">Labor or services actually performed for the corporation;</section><section prefix="(4)">A promissory note or other obligation for future payment in money; or</section><section prefix="(5)">Contracts for labor or services to be performed.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The corporation may place in escrow shares issued for a contract for future labor or services or a promissory note or other obligation for future payment in money, or make other arrangements to restrict the transfer of the shares, and may credit distributions in respect of the shares against their purchase price, until the labor or services are performed or the note or other obligation for future payment in money is paid. If the labor or services are not performed or the note or other obligation for future payment in money is not paid, the shares escrowed or restricted and the distributions credited may be canceled in whole or in part.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">When the corporation receives the consideration for which stock or convertible securities are to be issued, the stock or convertible securities are fully paid and nonassessable.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Notwithstanding any other provision of the Maryland General Corporation Law, a corporation may issue shares of its stock without consideration for the purpose of qualifying the corporation as a real estate investment trust under the Internal Revenue Code.</section>
  </text>
</law>
