<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gca" order_by="gca" level="1">Corporations and Associations</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gca-4-401</section_number>
  <catch_line>Under a unanimous stockholders' agreement, the stockholders of a close corporation may regulate any ...</catch_line>
  <order_by>401</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Under a unanimous stockholders' agreement, the stockholders of a close corporation may regulate any aspect of the affairs of the corporation or the relations of the stockholders, including:<section prefix="(1)">The management of the business and affairs of the corporation;</section><section prefix="(2)">Restrictions on the transfer of stock;</section><section prefix="(3)">The right of one or more stockholders to dissolve the corporation at will or on the occurrence of a specified event or contingency;</section><section prefix="(4)">The exercise or division of voting power;</section><section prefix="(5)">The terms and conditions of employment of an officer or employee of the corporation, without regard to the period of his employment;</section><section prefix="(6)">The individuals who are to be directors and officers of the corporation; and</section><section prefix="(7)">The payment of dividends or the division of profits.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A unanimous stockholders' agreement may be amended, but only by the unanimous written consent of the stockholders then parties to the agreement.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A stockholder who acquires his stock after a unanimous stockholders' agreement becomes effective is considered to have actually assented to the agreement and is a party to it:<section prefix="(1)">Whether or not he has actual knowledge of the existence of the agreement at the time he acquires the stock, if acquired by gift or bequest from a person who was a party to the agreement; and</section><section prefix="(2)">If he has actual knowledge of the existence of the agreement at the time he acquires the stock, if acquired in any other manner.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A court of equity may enforce a unanimous stockholders' agreement by injunction or by any other relief which the court in its discretion determines to be fair and appropriate in the circumstances.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">As an alternative to the granting of an injunction or other equitable relief, on motion of a party to the proceeding, the court may order dissolution of the corporation under the provisions of Subtitle 6 of this title.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">This section does not affect any otherwise valid agreement among stockholders of a close corporation or of any other corporation.</section>
  </text>
</law>
