<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gca" order_by="" level="1">Corporations and Associations</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gca-3-101</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>101</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Domestic business trust" or "business trust" means a business trust formed under the laws of the State.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Domestic limited liability company" or "limited liability company" means a limited liability company formed under the laws of the State.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">"Domestic limited partnership" or "limited partnership" means a partnership formed by 2 or more persons under the laws of the State and having one or more general partners and one or more limited partners.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"Domestic partnership" or "partnership" means a partnership formed under the laws of the State.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">"Foreign business trust" means a business trust organized under the laws of the United States, another state of the United States, or a territory, possession, or district of the United States, or under the laws of a foreign country.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">"Foreign limited liability company" means a limited liability company formed under the laws of any state, other than the State of Maryland, or under the laws of a foreign country.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">"Foreign limited partnership" means a partnership formed under the laws of any state other than the State of Maryland or under the laws of a foreign country and having as partners one or more general partners and one or more limited partners.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">"Foreign partnership" means a partnership formed under the laws of any state, other than this State, or under the laws of a foreign country.</section>
    <section prefix="(j)">"Interest in land" means any interest in real property, the title to which could be affected by recording an instrument in the land records.</section>
  </text>
</law>
