<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gca" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="2-303" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gca-2-303</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The entire consideration received by a corporation for issuing stock with par value constitutes stated capital to the extent of the aggregate par value of the stock.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Any consideration received in excess of the aggregate par value constitutes capital surplus.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as permitted by paragraph (2) of this subsection, the entire consideration received by a corporation for issuing stock without par value constitutes stated capital.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Before issuing stock without par value, the board of directors may allocate any portion of the consideration to capital surplus. However, if the stock has a preference in the assets of the corporation in the event of involuntary liquidation, the board may allocate to capital surplus only a portion which does not exceed the amount by which the consideration exceeds the aggregate amount of the preference.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Subsections (a)(2) and (b) of this section do not affect a good faith allocation of amounts to retained earnings, earned surplus, or a similar account if:<section prefix="(1)">Stock is issued in a consolidation, merger, or acquisition of all or substantially all of the stock or assets of another corporation; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Immediately after the transaction, the aggregate retained earnings, earned surplus, or similar account of the corporation which issued the stock does not exceed the aggregate of the corresponding accounts of the corporations parties to the transaction as they existed immediately before the transaction.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
