<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gca" order_by="" level="1">Corporations and Associations</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gca-2-405.1</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>405.1</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">A director shall perform his duties as a director, including his duties as a member of a committee of the board on which he serves:<section prefix="(1)">In good faith;</section><section prefix="(2)">In a manner he reasonably believes to be in the best interests of the corporation; and</section><section prefix="(3)">With the care that an ordinarily prudent person in a like position would use under similar circumstances.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In performing his duties, a director is entitled to rely on any information, opinion, report, or statement, including any financial statement or other financial data, prepared or presented by:<section prefix="(i)">An officer or employee of the corporation whom the director reasonably believes to be reliable and competent in the matters presented;</section><section prefix="(ii)">A lawyer, certified public accountant, or other person, as to a matter which the director reasonably believes to be within the person's professional or expert competence; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">A committee of the board on which the director does not serve, as to a matter within its designated authority, if the director reasonably believes the committee to merit confidence.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A director is not acting in good faith if he has any knowledge concerning the matter in question which would cause such reliance to be unwarranted.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A person who performs his duties in accordance with the standard provided in this section shall have the immunity from liability described under &#xA7; 5-417 of the Courts and Judicial Proceedings Article.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The duty of the directors of a corporation does not require them to:<section prefix="(1)">Accept, recommend, or respond on behalf of the corporation to any proposal by an acquiring person as defined in &#xA7; 3-801 of this article;</section><section prefix="(2)">Authorize the corporation to redeem any rights under, modify, or render inapplicable, a stockholder rights plan;</section><section prefix="(3)">Elect on behalf of the corporation to be subject to or refrain from electing on behalf of the corporation to be subject to any or all of the provisions of Title 3, Subtitle 8 of this article;</section><section prefix="(4)">Make a determination under the provisions of Title 3, Subtitle 6 or Subtitle 7 of this article; or</section><section prefix="(5)">Act or fail to act solely because of:<section prefix="(i)">The effect the act or failure to act may have on an acquisition or potential acquisition of control of the corporation; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">The amount or type of any consideration that may be offered or paid to stockholders in an acquisition.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">An act of a director of a corporation is presumed to satisfy the standards of subsection (a) of this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">An act of a director relating to or affecting an acquisition or a potential acquisition of control of a corporation may not be subject to a higher duty or greater scrutiny than is applied to any other act of a director.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">Nothing in this section creates a duty of any director of a corporation enforceable otherwise than by the corporation or in the right of the corporation.</section>
  </text>
</law>
