<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gca" order_by="" level="1">Corporations and Associations</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gca-5-6B-10</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>10</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The intent of the General Assembly of Maryland is to facilitate the orderly development of cooperative housing corporations in Maryland. The General Assembly recognizes, however, that the conversion of residential rental facilities to cooperative housing corporations or condominiums can have an adverse impact on the availability of rental units, resulting in the displacement of tenants.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A county or incorporated municipality may, by legislative finding, recognize and declare that a rental housing emergency exists in all or a part of its jurisdiction and has been caused by the conversion of residential rental facilities. Any legislative finding shall exist for one year, subject to any extensions for periods of one year at a time. The jurisdiction shall consider and make findings as to:<section prefix="(1)">The nature and incidence of conversions of residential rental facilities;</section><section prefix="(2)">The resulting hardship to and displacement of tenants; and</section><section prefix="(3)">The scarcity of rental housing.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Upon the finding and declaration of a rental housing emergency caused by the conversion of rental housing, a county or an incorporated municipality may by the enactment of laws, ordinances, and regulations, take the following actions to meet the emergency:<section prefix="(1)">Grant to a designated family as defined in &#xA7; 5-6B-07 of this subtitle a right to an extended lease for a period in addition to that period provided for in &#xA7; 5-6B-07 of this subtitle. The right to an extended lease may not, in any event, result in a requirement that a developer set aside for an extended lease more than 20 percent of the total number of units.</section><section prefix="(2)">Otherwise extend the provisions of &#xA7; 5-6B-07 of this subtitle except that:<section prefix="(i)">More than 20 percent of the total number of units may not be required to be set aside; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">The term of an extended lease for a family made a designated family by a county or an incorporated municipality may not exceed 3 years.</section></section><section prefix="(3)">Require that the notice required to be given under &#xA7; 5-6B-05 of this subtitle be altered to disclose the effects of any actions taken under this section.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Within 10 days after the enactment of a law, ordinance, or regulation under this section, a county or incorporated municipality shall forward a copy of the law, ordinance, or regulation to the Secretary of State.</section>
  </text>
</law>
