<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gca" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="1-101" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gca-1-101</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this article, unless the context clearly requires otherwise, the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Address" means the post office address, and includes street and number, if any, county or municipal area, and state and, if outside the United States, country.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Articles of transfer" means articles of sale, articles of lease, articles of asset exchange, or articles of transfer.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">"Assets" means any tangible, intangible, real, or personal property or other assets, including goodwill and franchises.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"Business trust" means an unincorporated trust or association, including a common-law trust, a Massachusetts trust, a real estate investment trust as defined in &#xA7; 8-101 of this article, a statutory trust as defined in &#xA7; 12-101 of this article, and a foreign statutory trust as defined in &#xA7; 12-101 of this article, that is engaged in business and in which property is acquired, held, managed, administered, controlled, invested, or disposed of by trustees or the trust for the benefit and profit of any person who may become a holder of a transferable unit of beneficial interest in the trust.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Charter" includes:<section prefix="(i)">A charter granted by special act of the General Assembly;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Articles or certificate of incorporation;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Amended articles or certificate of incorporation;</section><section prefix="(iv)">Articles of restatement, if approved as described in &#xA7; 2-609 of this article;</section><section prefix="(v)">Articles of amendment and restatement; and</section><section prefix="(vi)">Articles or agreements of consolidation.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Charter" includes the documents referred to in paragraph (1) of this subsection, either as:<section prefix="(i)">Originally passed or accepted for record; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">As amended, corrected, or supplemented by special act of the General Assembly, articles of amendment, articles of amendment and reduction, articles of extension, articles supplementary, articles or agreements of merger, articles of revival, or a certificate of correction.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">"Charter document" means any:<section prefix="(1)">Document enumerated in subsection (f) of this section; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Articles of reduction, articles or agreements of transfer, articles of merger, articles of share exchange, articles of dissolution, and stock issuance statements.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(h)">"Clerk of the court" means clerk of the circuit court for any county.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">"Convertible securities" includes:<section prefix="(1)">Shares of stock which by their terms are convertible into shares of stock of one or more classes; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Obligations which by their terms are convertible into shares of stock of one or more classes.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(j)">"County" includes Baltimore City.</section>
    <section prefix="(k)">"Department" means the State Department of Assessments and Taxation.</section>
    <section prefix="(l)">"Director" means a member of the governing body of a corporation, whether designated as a director, trustee, or manager or by any other title.</section>
    <section prefix="(m)">"Electronic transmission" means any form of communication, not directly involving the physical transmission of paper, that creates a record that:<section prefix="(1)">May be retained, retrieved, and reviewed by a recipient of the communication; and</section><section prefix="(2)">May be reproduced directly in paper form by a recipient through an automated process.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(n)">"Foreign corporation" means a corporation, association, or joint-stock company organized under the laws of the United States, another state of the United States, a territory, possession, or district of the United States, or a foreign country.</section>
    <section prefix="(o)">"Mail" means to deposit in the United States mails postage prepaid.</section>
    <section prefix="(p)">"Maryland corporation" means a corporation organized and existing under the laws of the State.</section>
    <section prefix="(q)">"Municipal area" means any incorporated or unincorporated city, town, or village.</section>
    <section prefix="(r)">"Person" includes an individual, corporation, business trust, statutory trust, estate, trust, partnership, limited partnership, limited liability company, association, two or more persons having a joint or common interest, or any other legal or commercial entity.</section>
    <section prefix="(s)">"Principal office" means:<section prefix="(1)">The place in this State filed or recorded with the Department as the principal office of a corporation or domestic limited partnership; or</section><section prefix="(2)">If there is no principal office designated, the main office of the corporation or domestic limited partnership in this State for the transaction of business.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(t)">"Resident agent" means an individual residing in this State or a Maryland corporation or limited liability company whose name, address, and designation as a resident agent are filed or recorded with the Department in accordance with the provisions of this article.</section>
    <section prefix="(u)">"Share exchange" means a transaction:<section prefix="(1)">In which a corporation acquires all the issued or all the outstanding shares of stock of one or more classes of another corporation by a stockholder vote under this article; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Which does not affect the corporate existence of either corporation.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(v)">"Stated capital" means the amount of stated capital determined in accordance with Title 2, Subtitle 3 of this article.</section>
    <section prefix="(w)">"Stockholder" means a person who is a record holder of shares of stock in a corporation and includes a member of a corporation organized without stock.</section>
    <section prefix="(x)">"Stockholder rights plan" means an agreement or other instrument under which a corporation issues rights to its stockholders that:<section prefix="(1)">May be exercised under specified circumstances to purchase stock or other securities of a corporation or any other person; and</section><section prefix="(2)">May become void if owned by a designated person or classes of persons under specified circumstances.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(y)">"Successor" means:<section prefix="(1)">A new corporation formed by consolidation;</section><section prefix="(2)">A corporation or other entity surviving a merger;</section><section prefix="(3)">A corporation acquiring stock in a share exchange; or</section><section prefix="(4)">A vendee, lessee, or other transferee in a transfer of assets.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(z)">"Transfer assets", "transfer its assets", and "transfer of assets" mean to sell, lease, exchange, or otherwise transfer all or substantially all of the assets of a corporation.</section>
  </text>
</law>
