<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gca" order_by="gca" level="1">Corporations and Associations</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gca-3-406</section_number>
  <catch_line>In the case of voluntary dissolution, the articles of dissolution shall include:...</catch_line>
  <order_by>406</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In the case of voluntary dissolution, the articles of dissolution shall include:<section prefix="(1)">The name of the corporation and the address of its principal office;</section><section prefix="(2)">The name and address of a resident agent of the corporation who shall serve for one year after dissolution and until the affairs of the corporation are wound up;</section><section prefix="(3)">The name and address of each director of the corporation;</section><section prefix="(4)">The name, title, and address of each officer of the corporation;</section><section prefix="(5)">A statement that dissolution of the corporation was approved in the manner and by the vote required by law and by the charter of the corporation, and a statement of the manner of approval;</section><section prefix="(6)">A statement that notice of the approved dissolution was mailed to all known creditors of the corporation and the date of the mailing, or a statement that the corporation has no known creditors;</section><section prefix="(7)">All other provisions which the corporation considers necessary to dissolve; and</section><section prefix="(8)">A statement that the corporation is dissolved.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If the dissolution is authorized under &#xA7; 3-402 of this subtitle, a majority of the incorporators or a majority of the entire board of directors, as the case may be, shall execute articles of dissolution for the corporation in the manner required by Title 1 of this article.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">In all other cases, articles of dissolution shall be executed by the persons and in the manner required by Title 1 of this article.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
