<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gca" order_by="" level="1">Corporations and Associations</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gca-3-803</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>803</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in subsection (f) of this section, notwithstanding any provision in the charter or the bylaws of a corporation, before the first annual meeting of stockholders after a corporation elects to be subject to this subtitle, the board of directors shall designate by resolution, from among its members, directors to serve as class I directors, class II directors, and class III directors.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">To the extent possible, the classes shall have the same number of directors.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The term of office of the class I directors shall continue until the first annual meeting of stockholders after the date on which the corporation becomes subject to this subtitle and until their successors are elected and qualify.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The term of office of the class II directors shall continue until the second annual meeting of stockholders after the date on which the corporation becomes subject to this subtitle and until their successors are elected and qualify.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The term of office of the class III directors shall continue until the third annual meeting of stockholders following the date on which the corporation becomes subject to this subtitle and until their successors are elected and qualify.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">At each annual meeting of the stockholders of a corporation, the successors to the class of directors whose term expires at that meeting shall be elected to hold office for a term continuing until:<section prefix="(1)">The annual meeting of stockholders held in the third year following the year of their election; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Their successors are elected and qualify.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">This subtitle does not limit the power of a corporation by provision in its charter to:<section prefix="(1)">Confer on the holders of any class or series of preference or preferred stock the right to elect one or more directors; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Designate the terms and voting powers of the directors, which may vary among the directors.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
