<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gca" order_by="" level="1">Corporations and Associations</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gca-2-406</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>406</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The stockholders of a corporation may remove any director, with or without cause, by the affirmative vote of a majority of all the votes entitled to be cast generally for the election of directors, except:<section prefix="(1)">As provided in subsection (b) of this section;</section><section prefix="(2)">As otherwise provided in the charter of the corporation; or</section><section prefix="(3)">For a corporation that has elected to be subject to &#xA7; 3-804(a) of this article.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Unless the charter of the corporation provides otherwise:<section prefix="(1)">If the stockholders of any class or series are entitled separately to elect one or more directors, a director elected by a class or series may not be removed without cause except by the affirmative vote of a majority of all the votes of that class or series;</section><section prefix="(2)">If a corporation has cumulative voting for the election of directors and less than the entire board is to be removed, a director may not be removed without cause if the votes cast against the director's removal would be sufficient to elect the director if then cumulatively voted at an election of the entire board of directors, or, if there is more than one class of directors, at an election of the class of directors of which the director is a member; and</section><section prefix="(3)">If the directors have been divided into classes, a director may not be removed without cause.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A resignation of a director given in writing or by electronic transmission may provide that:<section prefix="(1)">The resignation will be effective at a later time or on the occurrence of an event;</section><section prefix="(2)">The resignation is irrevocable on the occurrence of the event; and</section><section prefix="(3)">If the resignation will be effective on the failure of the director to receive a specified vote for reelection, the resignation is irrevocable.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
