<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gca" order_by="" level="1">Corporations and Associations</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gca-5-623</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>623</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The directors of a cooperative named in any articles of incorporation, consolidation, merger, or conversion shall hold office until the next annual meeting of the members and until their successors are elected and qualified.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Except as otherwise provided in this subtitle, at each annual meeting or, if the cooperative fails to hold an annual meeting as specified in the bylaws, at a special meeting called for that purpose, the members shall elect directors to hold office until the next annual meeting of the members.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Each director shall hold office for the term for which the director is elected and until a successor is elected and qualifies.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Instead of electing all the directors annually, the bylaws may require that the directors be divided into three classes.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">Each class shall be as nearly equal in number as possible.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">If the bylaws require that the directors be divided into three classes, the terms of the directors shall be staggered in accordance with subparagraph (ii) of this paragraph.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">
          <section prefix="1.">The initial term of office of the directors of the first class shall expire at the next succeeding annual meeting.</section>
          <section prefix="2.">The initial term of the second class shall expire at the second succeeding annual meeting.</section>
          <section prefix="3.">The initial term of the third class shall expire at the third succeeding annual meeting.</section>
        </section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">At each annual meeting after the initial classification of the directors, a number of directors equal to the number of the class whose term expires at that meeting shall be elected to hold office for 3 years or until the third succeeding annual meeting.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">If a vacancy occurs on the board of directors, the remaining directors shall elect a director to fill the vacancy for the remainder of the term for which the vacating director was elected.</section>
  </text>
</law>
