<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gca" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="5-113" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gca-5-113</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">A professional corporation shall acquire, or cause to be acquired by a qualified person, the stock of a stockholder, at a price that represents the fair value of the stock as of the date of death or disqualification of the stockholder or transfer of the stock if:<section prefix="(1)">The stockholder dies;</section><section prefix="(2)">Except as provided in subsection (c) of this section, the stockholder becomes a disqualified person; or</section><section prefix="(3)">Except as provided in subsection (c) of this section, the stock is transferred by operation of law or court judgment to a disqualified person.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If the price for stock is determinable in accordance with the articles of incorporation or bylaws of the corporation, or by private agreement, that price controls.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If the price is not determinable, under paragraph (1) of this subsection, the corporation shall acquire the stock in accordance with the provisions of &#xA7; 5-114 of this subtitle.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">If the disqualified person rejects the corporation's purchase offer, either the disqualified stockholder, personal representative, transferee, or the corporation may commence a proceeding under &#xA7; 5-115 of this subtitle to determine the fair value of the stock.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">This section does not require the acquisition of stock in the event of disqualification if the disqualification lasts less than 5 months from the date the disqualification or transfer occurs.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">This section and &#xA7; 5-114 of this subtitle do not prevent or relieve a professional corporation from paying pension benefits or other deferred compensation to a former stockholder if otherwise permitted by law, including amounts payable pursuant to an agreement between a judge and his former law firm as provided in &#xA7; 1-203 of the Courts Article.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">A provision for the acquisition of stock contained in a professional corporation's articles of incorporation or bylaws, or in a private agreement, is specifically enforceable.</section>
  </text>
</law>
