<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gca" order_by="gca" level="1">Corporations and Associations</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gca-5-609</section_number>
  <catch_line>A cooperative may amend its articles of incorporation as provided in this section....</catch_line>
  <order_by>609</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">A cooperative may amend its articles of incorporation as provided in this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A proposed amendment shall be submitted for consideration at an annual or special meeting of the members of the cooperative.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The proposed amendment shall be included in or attached to the notice of the meeting.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The proposed amendment and any change to the proposed amendment shall be approved by the affirmative vote of not less than two-thirds of the members voting on the matter.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">If the proposed amendment and any change to the proposed amendment are approved by the members as provided in subsection (b) of this section:<section prefix="(1)">Articles of amendment shall be signed and acknowledged for the cooperative by its chairman or vice-chairman and attested by its secretary; and</section><section prefix="(2)">The seal of the cooperative shall be affixed to the articles.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The articles of amendment shall contain:<section prefix="(1)">The name of the cooperative;</section><section prefix="(2)">The address of the principal office of the cooperative;</section><section prefix="(3)">The amendment to the articles of incorporation; and</section><section prefix="(4)">A statement that the articles are executed in accordance with this subtitle.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The chairman or vice-chairman who signs the articles of amendment for the cooperative shall make and attach to the articles an affidavit stating that the cooperative has complied with the provisions of this section that relate to the articles.</section>
  </text>
</law>
