<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gca" order_by="gca" level="1">Corporations and Associations</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gca-5-6B-01</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this subtitle the following terms have the meanings indicated....</catch_line>
  <order_by>01</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this subtitle the following terms have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Articles of incorporation" means the charter by which a cooperative housing corporation becomes incorporated under this article.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Blanket encumbrance" means any contract binding on a cooperative housing corporation and creating a lien or security interest or other encumbrance or imposing restrictions on any real or personal property owned by the cooperative housing corporation.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">"Bylaws" means the document which details and governs the internal organization and operation of the cooperative housing corporation.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"Conversion" means the creation of a cooperative housing corporation from a property which was immediately previously a residential rental facility.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">"Cooperative housing corporation" means a domestic or foreign corporation qualified in this State, either stock or nonstock, having only one class of stock or membership, in which each stockholder or member, by virtue of such ownership or membership, has a cooperative interest in the corporation.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">"Cooperative interest" means the ownership interest in a cooperative housing corporation which is coupled with a possessory interest in real or personal property or both and evidenced by a membership certificate.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">"Cooperative project" means all the real and personal property in this State owned or leased by the cooperative housing corporation for the primary purpose of residential use.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Developer" means a person who:<section prefix="(i)">Owns an equitable interest, including a cooperative interest, in a unit prior to its initial sale to a member of the public;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Exercises control over cooperative interests before they are transferred to initial purchasers, excluding management agents and sales agents acting in their capacities as such; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">Receives a material portion of the sales proceeds, not including customary brokerage commissions or payment for indebtedness to an institutional banker, from the initial sale of a cooperative interest to a member of the public.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Developer" does not include a cooperative housing corporation.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(j)">"Electronic transmission" means any form of communication, not directly involving the physical transmission of paper, that creates a record that:<section prefix="(1)">May be retained, retrieved, and reviewed by a recipient of the communication; and</section><section prefix="(2)">May be reproduced directly in paper form by a recipient through an automated process.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(k)">"Initial purchaser" means a member of the public, not an affiliate of or a successor to the developer, who, for value, acquires a cooperative interest as part of the initial sale of a cooperative interest which is used for residential purposes.</section>
    <section prefix="(l)">"Initial sale" means the first transfer of a cooperative interest to an initial purchaser.</section>
    <section prefix="(m)">"Member" means a person who owns a cooperative interest.</section>
    <section prefix="(n)">"Membership certificate" means:<section prefix="(1)">A document, including a stock certificate issued by a cooperative housing corporation, evidencing ownership of a cooperative interest; or</section><section prefix="(2)">If there is no other document which satisfies paragraph (1) of this subsection, a proprietary lease.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(o)">"Moving expenses" means costs incurred to:<section prefix="(1)">Hire contractors, labor, trucks, or equipment for the transportation of personal property;</section><section prefix="(2)">Pack and unpack personal property;</section><section prefix="(3)">Disconnect and install personal property;</section><section prefix="(4)">Insure personal property to be moved; and</section><section prefix="(5)">Disconnect and reconnect utilities such as telephone service, gas, water, and electricity.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(p)">"No-impact home-based business" means a business that:<section prefix="(1)">Is consistent with the residential character of the dwelling unit;</section><section prefix="(2)">Is subordinate to the use of the dwelling unit for residential purposes and requires no external modifications that detract from the residential appearance of the dwelling unit;</section><section prefix="(3)">Uses no equipment or process that creates noise, vibration, glare, fumes, odors, or electrical or electronic interference detectable by neighbors; and</section><section prefix="(4)">Does not involve use, storage, or disposal of any grouping or classification of materials that the United States Secretary of Transportation or the State or any local governing body designates as a hazardous material.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(q)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Proprietary lease" means an agreement with the cooperative housing corporation under which a member has an exclusive possessory interest in a unit and a possessory interest in common with other members in that portion of a cooperative project not constituting units and which creates a legal relationship of landlord and tenant between the cooperative housing corporation and the member, respectively.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Proprietary lease" includes, if there is no other document that satisfies paragraph (1) of this subsection, a membership certificate.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(r)">"Residential rental facility" means property containing at least 10 dwelling units leased for residential purposes.</section>
    <section prefix="(s)">"Unit" means a portion of the cooperative project leased for exclusive occupancy by a member under a proprietary lease.</section>
  </text>
</law>
