<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gca" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="3-211" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gca-3-211</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The court shall consider the report and, on motion of any party to the proceeding, enter an order which:<section prefix="(1)">Confirms, modifies, or rejects it; and</section><section prefix="(2)">If appropriate, sets the time for payment to the stockholder.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If the appraisers' report is confirmed or modified by the order, judgment shall be entered against the successor and in favor of each objecting stockholder party to the proceeding for the appraised fair value of his stock.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If the appraisers' report is rejected, the court may:<section prefix="(i)">Determine the fair value of the stock and enter judgment for the stockholder; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">Remit the proceedings to the same or other appraisers on terms and conditions it considers proper.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, a judgment for the stockholder shall award the value of the stock and interest from the date as at which fair value is to be determined under &#xA7; 3-202 of this subtitle.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The court may not allow interest if it finds that the failure of the stockholder to accept an offer for the stock made under &#xA7; 3-207 of this subtitle was arbitrary and vexatious or not in good faith. In making this finding, the court shall consider:<section prefix="(i)">The price which the successor offered for the stock;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The financial statements and other information furnished to the stockholder; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Any other circumstances it considers relevant.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The costs of the proceedings, including reasonable compensation and expenses of the appraisers, shall be set by the court and assessed against the successor. However, the court may direct the costs to be apportioned and assessed against any objecting stockholder if the court finds that the failure of the stockholder to accept an offer for the stock made under &#xA7; 3-207 of this subtitle was arbitrary and vexatious or not in good faith. In making this finding, the court shall consider:<section prefix="(i)">The price which the successor offered for the stock;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The financial statements and other information furnished to the stockholder; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Any other circumstances it considers relevant.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Costs may not include attorney's fees or expenses. The reasonable fees and expenses of experts may be included only if:<section prefix="(i)">The successor did not make an offer for the stock under &#xA7; 3-207 of this subtitle; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">The value of the stock determined in the proceeding materially exceeds the amount offered by the successor.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The judgment is final and conclusive on all parties and has the same force and effect as other decrees in equity. The judgment constitutes a lien on the assets of the successor with priority over any mortgage or other lien attaching on or after the effective date of the consolidation, merger, transfer, or charter amendment.</section>
  </text>
</law>
