<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gca" order_by="" level="1">Corporations and Associations</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gca-7-205</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>205</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">As long as it is subject to suit in this State, a foreign corporation which has registered or qualified to do business in this State shall maintain:<section prefix="(1)">A resident agent in this State whose name and address is certified to the Department; and</section><section prefix="(2)">An address which is certified to the Department.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A foreign corporation registered or qualified to do business in this State:<section prefix="(1)">At any time may certify to the Department the address of a principal office in this State, which may be a business office of the corporation; and</section><section prefix="(2)">With respect to an address so certified, shall certify to the Department:<section prefix="(i)">Any subsequent change in the address of the principal office; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">The fact that it no longer has the principal office in this State.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Except as provided in subsection (d) of this section, each certification by a foreign corporation which relates to its resident agent, address, or principal office shall be executed for the corporation by its president or one of its vice-presidents.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A foreign corporation and its resident agent may change the resident agent, his address, or the address of a principal office of the corporation in the same manner as provided for a Maryland corporation under &#xA7; 2-108 of this article.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A resident agent of a foreign corporation may resign by filing with the Department a counterpart or photocopy of his signed resignation.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Unless a later time is specified in the resignation, it is effective:<section prefix="(i)">At the time it is filed with the Department, if the corporation has more than one resident agent; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">Ten days after it is filed with the Department, if the corporation has only one resident agent.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
