<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gca" order_by="gca" level="1">Corporations and Associations</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gca-4A-601</section_number>
  <catch_line>A person becomes a member of a limited liability company at:...</catch_line>
  <order_by>601</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">A person becomes a member of a limited liability company at:<section prefix="(1)">The time the limited liability company is formed;</section><section prefix="(2)">A later time specified in the operating agreement; or</section><section prefix="(3)">The time specified in &#xA7; 4A-902(b)(1) of this title relating to continuation of the limited liability company after there are no remaining members.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">After the formation of a limited liability company, a person may be admitted as a member:<section prefix="(1)">In the case of a person acquiring a membership interest directly from the limited liability company, upon compliance with the operating agreement or, if the operating agreement does not so provide, upon the unanimous consent of the members;</section><section prefix="(2)">In the case of an assignee of the economic interest of a member, only as provided in &#xA7; 4A-604 of this subtitle; or</section><section prefix="(3)">In the case of a personal representative or successor to the last remaining member who is not an assignee of the last remaining member, as provided in &#xA7; 4A-902(b)(1) of this title.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Unless otherwise agreed, a person may be admitted as a member of a limited liability company and may be the sole member of a limited liability company without:<section prefix="(1)">Making a capital contribution to the limited liability company;</section><section prefix="(2)">Being obligated to make a capital contribution to the limited liability company; or</section><section prefix="(3)">Acquiring an economic interest in the limited liability company.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
