<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gca" order_by="gca" level="1">Corporations and Associations</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gca-1-203</section_number>
  <catch_line>In addition to any organization and capitalization fee required under &#xA7; 1-204 of this subtitle, sub...</catch_line>
  <order_by>203</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In addition to any organization and capitalization fee required under &#xA7; 1-204 of this subtitle, subject to subsection (c) of this section, the Department shall collect the fees specified in subsection (b) of this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in paragraph (11) of this subsection, for each of the following documents, the nonrefundable processing fee is $100:</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">For each of the following documents, the nonrefundable processing fee is as indicated:<section prefix="(i)">Notice of change of address of principal office $25</section><section prefix="(ii)">Notice of change of name or address of resident agent $25,up to a maximum of $30,000 for a bulk filing</section><section prefix="(iii)">Certificate of correction $25</section><section prefix="(iv)">Any other documents $25</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">For each of the following documents which are filed but not recorded, the nonrefundable processing fee is as indicated:</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">For each of the following documents which are filed but not recorded, the filing fee is as indicated:</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(4)">For each of the following documents recorded or filed the nonrefundable processing fee is $100:<section prefix="(i)">Certificate of limited partnership, certificate of limited liability partnership, articles of organization of a limited liability company, certificate of trust of a business trust, including certificates of amendment and certificates of cancellation, certificates of reinstatement, and articles of reinstatement; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Any statement filed by a partnership under Title 9A of this article.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(5)">For issuing each of the following certificates, the nonrefundable processing fee is as indicated:</section>
      <section prefix="(6)">For a duplicate of a certificate mentioned in paragraph (5) of this subsection which is issued at the same time as the original, the fee is $1, and for a copy of any other paper recorded or filed with the Department, the fee is $1 per page.</section>
      <section prefix="(7)">
        <section prefix="(i)">For acceptance of service of process or notice on the Department, the Department shall charge a fee of $50.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">Each county and Baltimore City is exempt from the fee under subparagraph (i) of this paragraph.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(8)">For processing each of the following documents on an expedited basis, the additional fee is as indicated:</section>
      <section prefix="(9)">A nonrefundable processing fee for a request by paper document for an extension of the date for submitting an annual report under &#xA7; 14-704 of  the Tax - Property Article is $20.</section>
      <section prefix="(10)">A nonrefundable processing fee for return of an original document is $5.</section>
      <section prefix="(11)">A nonrefundable processing fee for articles of incorporation of a nonstock corporation that is organized to operate as a not-for-profit entity under &#xA7; 501(c)(3), (4), or (6) of the Internal Revenue Code is $150.</section>
      <section prefix="(12)">A fee for the nonpayment of a check or other negotiable instrument that was presented to the Department as payment for any of the other fees imposed under this section is $30.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">For each fee identified under subsection (b) of this section as nonrefundable, the Department shall adopt regulations to specify the conditions under which the fee shall be nonrefundable and the conditions under which the fee may be applied to a resubmission of a document for filing, recording, or processing.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The fee collected under subsection (b)(10) of this section shall be credited to the fund established under &#xA7; 1-203.3 of this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">Of the $150 collected under subsection (b)(11) of this section, $50 shall be credited to the Maryland Not-For-Profit Development Center Program Fund established under &#xA7; 5-1204 of the Economic Development Article.</section>
  </text>
</law>
