<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gca" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="5-5A-07" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gca-5-5A-07</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Within the limitations of this subtitle, the articles of incorporation or bylaws of a consumer cooperative shall contain:<section prefix="(1)">The name of the cooperative, which shall include the word "cooperative" or the abbreviation "co-op";</section><section prefix="(2)">The name, address, and state of residence of each incorporator;</section><section prefix="(3)">A statement of the purposes of the cooperative;</section><section prefix="(4)">The address of its principal office in the State; and</section><section prefix="(5)">The name and address of its resident agent in the State.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If the cooperative is organized with capital stock, the articles of incorporation shall state:<section prefix="(i)">The number of authorized shares of stock;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The par value of each share of stock; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">The aggregate par value of all authorized shares of stock.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A cooperative may not issue stock without par value.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">If the cooperative is organized without capital stock, the articles of incorporation shall state whether the property rights of its members are equal or unequal, and, if unequal, the rule by which the property rights of members, including members admitted after the original organization, are to be determined.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The articles shall state the method by which any surplus existing upon dissolution of the cooperative may be distributed as a gift to another cooperative or to a nonprofit, tax-exempt enterprise.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The articles may also contain any other provisions not inconsistent with the law of this State or with this subtitle for the conduct of the cooperative's affairs.</section>
  </text>
</law>
