<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gca" order_by="gca" level="1">Corporations and Associations</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gca-7-208</section_number>
  <catch_line>A foreign corporation registered or qualified under this subtitle may terminate its registration or ...</catch_line>
  <order_by>208</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">A foreign corporation registered or qualified under this subtitle may terminate its registration or qualification as provided in this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">To terminate, the corporation shall file with the Department an application for termination.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The application for termination shall be executed for the corporation by its president or one of its vice-presidents. The application shall include:<section prefix="(1)">The name of the corporation, and the address of any principal office in this State;</section><section prefix="(2)">The name and address of its resident agent in this State;</section><section prefix="(3)">A statement that the corporation:<section prefix="(i)">In the case of termination of qualification, no longer transacts any intrastate business in this State; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">In the case of termination of registration, no longer transacts any interstate or foreign business in this State; and</section></section><section prefix="(4)">A statement that the corporation:<section prefix="(i)">Wishes to terminate its registration or qualification to do business in this State; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Has filed all reports required by law and has paid all taxes due by it to the State and any of its political subdivisions as of the date of the application for termination.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Department shall issue a certificate of termination to the corporation if all reports required by Title 11 of the Tax - Property Article have been filed.</section>
  </text>
</law>
