<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gca" order_by="" level="1">Corporations and Associations</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gca-5-6B-08</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>08</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A county or an incorporated municipality may provide, by local law or ordinance, that a residential rental facility may not be granted to a purchaser for the purpose of conversion unless the county, incorporated municipality, or housing agency has first been offered in writing the right to purchase the rental facility on substantially the same terms and conditions offered by the owner to the purchaser. The local law or ordinance shall designate the title and mailing address of the person to whom the offer to the county, incorporated municipality, or housing agency shall be delivered.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The offer shall contain a contingency entitling the county, incorporated municipality, or housing agency, to secure financing within 180 days from the date of the offer, provided that the county, incorporated municipality, or housing agency shall use its best efforts to secure financing as soon as possible.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Unless written acceptance of the offer is first delivered to the owner by the county, incorporated municipality, or housing agency, the offer shall terminate, without further act, 60 days after it is delivered to the county, incorporated municipality, or housing agency. If the offer terminates, the owner may grant the residential rental facility to any person for any purpose on terms and conditions not more favorable to a buyer than those offered by the owner to the county, incorporated municipality, or housing agency.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">If the county, incorporated municipality, or housing agency purchases the residential rental facility, it shall retain or provide for the retention of the property as a residential rental facility for at least 3 years from the date of acquisition.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A local law or ordinance adopted under subsection (a) of this section may provide that the owner of a residential rental facility is exempt from the provisions of this section if the purchaser of the rental facility enters into an agreement with the county, incorporated municipality, or housing agency to retain the property as a residential rental facility for a period not to exceed 3 years after the date of acquisition of the property.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The provisions of any local law or ordinance adopted under this section shall not apply to the following transfers of a residential rental facility:<section prefix="(1)">A transfer as a result of a foreclosure made under the terms of a mortgage or deed of trust;</section><section prefix="(2)">A transfer to a mortgagee in lieu of foreclosure or a transfer under other proceedings, arrangement or deed in lieu of foreclosure;</section><section prefix="(3)">A transfer made under a judicial sale or other judicial proceeding brought to secure payment of a debt or for the purpose of securing the performance of an obligation;</section><section prefix="(4)">A transfer of the interest of one co-tenant to another co-tenant by operation of law or otherwise;</section><section prefix="(5)">A transfer made by will or descent or by intestate distribution;</section><section prefix="(6)">A transfer made to a municipal or county government, to the State government, or to an agency, instrumentality, or political subdivision of government;</section><section prefix="(7)">A transfer to a spouse, son, or daughter;</section><section prefix="(8)">A transfer made under the liquidation of a partnership or corporation; or</section><section prefix="(9)">A transfer into a partnership or corporation wholly owned by the person(s) so contributing.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A county, incorporated municipality, or housing agency, by execution and delivery by the appropriate official to the grantor of an instrument in recordable form, may waive its right to purchase a particular residential rental facility under this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">Within 30 days after the enactment of a law or ordinance under this section, the county or incorporated municipality shall forward a copy of the law or ordinance to the Secretary of State.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">If a deed for a residential rental facility contains an affidavit by the grantor that the provisions of this section have been fulfilled, then the grantee in that deed takes title to the residential rental facility free and clear of all claims and rights of a county, incorporated municipality, or housing agency arising under this section.</section>
  </text>
</law>
