<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gca" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="2-507" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gca-2-507</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Unless the charter provides for a greater or lesser number of votes per share or limits or denies voting rights, each outstanding share of stock, regardless of class, is entitled to one vote on each matter submitted to a vote at a meeting of stockholders. However, a share is not entitled to be voted if any installment payable on it is overdue and unpaid.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A stockholder may vote the stock the stockholder owns of record either:<section prefix="(i)">In person; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">By proxy as provided in subsection (c) of this section.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Unless a proxy provides otherwise, it is not valid more than 11 months after its date.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Unless otherwise agreed in writing, the holder of record of stock which actually belongs to another shall issue a proxy to vote the stock to the actual owner on the owner's demand.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A stockholder may authorize another person to act as proxy for the stockholder as provided in this subsection.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">A stockholder may sign a writing authorizing another person to act as proxy.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">Signing may be accomplished by the stockholder or the stockholder's authorized agent signing the writing or causing the stockholder's signature to be affixed to the writing by any reasonable means, including facsimile signature.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Subject to subparagraph (ii) of this paragraph, a stockholder may authorize another person to act as proxy by transmitting, or authorizing the transmission of, an authorization for the person to act as proxy to:</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The authorization may be transmitted by a telegram, cablegram, datagram, electronic mail, or any other electronic or telephonic means.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(4)">A copy, facsimile telecommunication, or other reliable reproduction of the writing or transmission authorized under paragraphs (2) and (3) of this subsection may be substituted for the original writing or transmission for any purpose for which the original writing or transmission could be used.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A proxy is revocable by a stockholder at any time without condition or qualification unless:<section prefix="(i)">The proxy states that it is irrevocable; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">The proxy is coupled with an interest.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A proxy may be made irrevocable for as long as it is coupled with an interest.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The interest with which a proxy may be coupled includes an interest in the stock to be voted under the proxy or another general interest in the corporation or its assets or liabilities.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
