<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gca" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="2-311" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gca-2-311</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">No distribution may be made if, after giving effect to the distribution:</section>
      <section prefix="(i)">The corporation would not be able to pay indebtedness of the corporation as the indebtedness becomes due in the usual course of business; or</section>
      <section prefix="(ii)">Except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, the corporation's total assets would be less than the sum of the corporation's total liabilities plus, unless the charter permits otherwise, the amount that would be needed, if the corporation were to be dissolved at the time of the distribution, to satisfy the preferential rights upon dissolution of stockholders whose preferential rights on dissolution are superior to those receiving the distribution.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A corporation may make a distribution from:<section prefix="(i)">The net earnings of the corporation for the fiscal year in which the distribution is made;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The net earnings of the corporation for the preceding fiscal year; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">The sum of the net earnings of the corporation for the preceding eight fiscal quarters.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The board of directors may base a determination that a distribution is not prohibited under subsection (a) of this section either on:<section prefix="(1)">Financial statements prepared on the basis of accounting practices and principles that are reasonable in the circumstances; or</section><section prefix="(2)">A fair valuation or other method that is reasonable in the circumstances.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Except as provided in subsection (e) of this section, the effect of a distribution under subsection (a) of this section is measured:<section prefix="(1)">In the case of distribution by purchase, redemption, or other acquisition of the corporation's shares, as of the earlier of:<section prefix="(i)">The date money or other property is transferred or the indebtedness is incurred by the corporation; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">The date the stockholder ceases to be a stockholder with respect to the acquired shares;</section></section><section prefix="(2)">In the case of any other distribution of indebtedness, as of the date the indebtedness is distributed; and</section><section prefix="(3)">In all other cases, as of:<section prefix="(i)">The date the distribution is authorized if the payment occurs within 120 days after the date of authorization; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">The date the payment is made if it occurs more than 120 days after the date of authorization.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A corporation's indebtedness to a stockholder, incurred by reason of a distribution made in accordance with this section, is at parity with the corporation's indebtedness to the corporation's general, unsecured creditors, except to the extent subordinated by agreement.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If terms of the indebtedness provide that payment of principal and interest is to be made only if and to the extent that payment of a distribution to stockholders could then be made under this section, indebtedness of a corporation, including indebtedness issued as a distribution, is not a liability for purposes of determinations made under subsection (a) of this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If the indebtedness referred to in paragraph (1) of this subsection is issued as a distribution, each payment of principal or interest on the indebtedness is treated as a distribution, the effect of which is measured on the date the payment is actually made.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
