<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gca" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="2-502" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gca-2-502</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">A special meeting of the stockholders of a corporation may be called by:<section prefix="(1)">The president;</section><section prefix="(2)">The board of directors; or</section><section prefix="(3)">Any other person specified in the charter or the bylaws.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in subsections (c) and (d) of this section, and except for a corporation that has elected to be subject to &#xA7; 3-805 of this article, the secretary of a corporation shall call a special meeting of the stockholders on the written request of stockholders entitled to cast at least 25 percent of all the votes entitled to be cast at the meeting.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A request for a special meeting shall state the purpose of the meeting and the matters proposed to be acted on at the meeting.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The secretary shall:<section prefix="(i)">Inform the stockholders who make the request of the reasonably estimated cost of preparing and mailing a notice of the meeting; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">On payment of these costs to the corporation, notify each stockholder entitled to notice of the meeting.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Unless requested by stockholders entitled to cast a majority of all the votes entitled to be cast at the meeting, a special meeting need not be called to consider any matter which is substantially the same as a matter voted on at any special meeting of the stockholders held during the preceding 12 months.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Subject to paragraph (2) of this subsection, a corporation may include in its charter or bylaws a provision that requires the written request of stockholders entitled to cast a greater or lesser percentage of all votes entitled to be cast at the meeting than that required by subsection (b)(1) of this section in order to call a special meeting of the stockholders.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The percentage provided for in the charter or bylaws may not be greater than a majority of all the votes entitled to be cast at the meeting.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The board of directors has the sole power to fix:<section prefix="(1)">The record date for determining stockholders entitled to request a special meeting of the stockholders and the record date for determining stockholders entitled to notice of and to vote at the special meeting; and</section><section prefix="(2)">The date, time, and place, if any, and the means of remote communication, if any, by which stockholders and proxy holders may be considered present in person and may vote at the special meeting.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
