<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gca" order_by="gca" level="1">Corporations and Associations</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gca-4A-403</section_number>
  <catch_line>The provisions of this section apply unless otherwise provided in this title or unless otherwise agr...</catch_line>
  <order_by>403</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The provisions of this section apply unless otherwise provided in this title or unless otherwise agreed.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Members shall vote in proportion to their respective interests in profits of the limited liability company, as determined under &#xA7; 4A-503 of this title.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Decisions concerning the affairs of the limited liability company shall require the consent of members holding at least a majority of the interests in profits of the limited liability company as determined under &#xA7; 4A-503 of this title.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A meeting of the members may be called by the written request of members holding at least 25% of the interests in profits of the limited liability company as determined under &#xA7; 4A-503 of this title.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Members of a limited liability company may participate in a meeting by means of conference telephone or other communications equipment or by means of remote communication, if all persons participating in the meeting:<section prefix="1.">Can either hear or read the proceedings of the meeting substantially concurrent with the proceedings; and</section><section prefix="2.">Have the opportunity to participate in the meeting and vote on matters submitted to the members.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">Participation in a meeting by the means authorized by subparagraph (i) of this paragraph constitutes presence in person at the meeting.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A member may not take any of the following actions without the consent of members holding at least two-thirds of the interest in profits of the limited liability company as determined under &#xA7; 4A-503 of this title:<section prefix="(i)">Dispose of all or substantially all of the business or property of the limited liability company; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">Approve a merger as provided in &#xA7; 4A-702 of this title.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A member may not  take any of the following actions without the unanimous consent of the members:<section prefix="(i)">Institute a voluntary proceeding under the federal bankruptcy code;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Assign the property of the limited liability company in trust for creditors or on the assignee's promise to pay the debts of the limited liability company;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Alter the allocation of profit or loss to members of the limited liability company;</section><section prefix="(iv)">Alter the allocation of or the manner of computing distributions payable to members of the limited liability company; or</section><section prefix="(v)">Do any other act that would make it impossible to carry on the ordinary business of the limited liability company.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
