<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gca" order_by="" level="1">Corporations and Associations</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gca-2-504</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>504</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Not less than 10 nor more than 90 days before each stockholders' meeting, the secretary of the corporation shall give notice in writing or by electronic transmission of the meeting to:<section prefix="(1)">Each stockholder entitled to vote at the meeting; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Each other stockholder entitled to notice of the meeting.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The notice shall state:<section prefix="(1)">The time of the meeting, the place of the meeting, if any, and the means of remote communication, if any, by which stockholders and proxy holders may be deemed to be present in person and may vote at the meeting; and</section><section prefix="(2)">The purpose of the meeting, if:<section prefix="(i)">The meeting is a special meeting; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">Notice of the purpose is required by any other provision of this article.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">For purposes of this section, notice is given to a stockholder when it is:<section prefix="(i)">Personally delivered to the stockholder;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Left at the stockholder's residence or usual place of business;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Mailed to the stockholder at the stockholder's address as it appears on the records of the corporation; or</section><section prefix="(iv)">Transmitted to the stockholder by an electronic transmission to any address or number of the stockholder at which the stockholder receives electronic transmissions.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If a corporation has received a request from a stockholder that notice not be sent by electronic transmission, the corporation may not provide notice to the stockholder by electronic transmission.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">An affidavit of the secretary, an assistant secretary, the transfer agent, or other agent of the corporation that notice has been given by a form of electronic transmission, in the absence of actual fraud, shall be prima facie evidence of the facts stated in the affidavit.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Notice given by electronic transmission shall be considered ineffective if:<section prefix="(i)">The corporation is unable to deliver two consecutive notices; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">The inability to deliver the notices becomes known to the secretary, an assistant secretary, the transfer agent, or other person responsible for the giving of notice.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The inadvertent failure to deliver notice under paragraph (2) of this subsection does not invalidate any meeting or other action.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">Whenever this article or the charter or bylaws of a corporation require notice of a meeting of the stockholders, each person who is entitled to the notice waives notice if the person:<section prefix="(1)">Before or after the meeting delivers a written waiver or a waiver by electronic transmission which is filed with the records of stockholders meetings; or</section><section prefix="(2)">Is present at the meeting in person or by proxy.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The charter or bylaws may require any stockholder proposing a nominee for election as a director or any other matter for consideration at a meeting of the stockholders to provide advance notice of the nomination or proposal to the corporation before a date or within a period of time specified in the charter or bylaws.</section>
  </text>
</law>
