<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gca" order_by="gca" level="1">Corporations and Associations</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gca-5-525</section_number>
  <catch_line>At the time and in the manner which its bylaws provide, each cooperative shall apportion and distrib...</catch_line>
  <order_by>525</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">At the time and in the manner which its bylaws provide, each cooperative shall apportion and distribute its net proceeds or savings to the persons entitled to receive them on the basis of their patronage.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The bylaws may provide:<section prefix="(1)">That the apportionment and distribution of the net proceeds or savings may be restricted to members or be made at the same or different rates for members and nonmember patrons;</section><section prefix="(2)">For any reasonable apportionment and charging of net losses;</section><section prefix="(3)">That any distribution to a nonmember eligible for membership may be credited to him until the amount credited equals the value of a membership certificate or a share of the common stock of the cooperatives; and</section><section prefix="(4)">The minimum amount of any single patronage transaction which will be considered for the purpose of participation in an allocation or distribution of net proceeds, savings, or losses under this section.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">An apportionment and distribution of net proceeds or savings may be in cash, credits, capital stock, certificates of interest, certificates of equity, revolving fund certificates, letters of advice, or other securities or certificates issued by the cooperative or by any affiliated Maryland or foreign cooperative.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Apportionment and distribution of net proceeds, savings, or losses may be separately determined and based on:<section prefix="(1)">The patronage of single or multiple pools or particular departments of the cooperative;</section><section prefix="(2)">The patronage as to particular commodities, supplies, or services; or</section><section prefix="(3)">The classification of patronage according to its type.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">For purposes of this section, net proceeds, savings, or losses shall be computed in accordance with generally accepted accounting principles applicable to cooperatives, after deducting from gross proceeds or savings all costs and expenses of operation and any dividends paid on capital stock and interest paid on certificates or other evidence of equity in any fund, capital investment, or other assets of the cooperative.</section>
  </text>
</law>
