<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gca" order_by="gca" level="1">Corporations and Associations</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gca-5-6C-07</section_number>
  <catch_line>A director of a benefit corporation, in performing the duties of a director, including the director'...</catch_line>
  <order_by>07</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">A director of a benefit corporation, in performing the duties of a director, including the director's duties as a member of a committee and in addition to the duties described in &#xA7; 2-405.1 of this article:<section prefix="(1)">In determining what the director reasonably believes to be in the best interests of the benefit corporation, shall consider the effects of any action or decision not to act on:<section prefix="(i)">The stockholders of the benefit corporation;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The employees and workforce of the benefit corporation and the subsidiaries and suppliers of the benefit corporation;</section><section prefix="(iii)">The interests of customers as beneficiaries of the general or specific public benefit purposes of the benefit corporation;</section><section prefix="(iv)">Community and societal considerations, including those of any community in which offices or facilities of the benefit corporation or the subsidiaries or suppliers of the benefit corporation are located; and</section><section prefix="(v)">The local and global environment; and</section></section><section prefix="(2)">May consider any other pertinent factors or the interests of any other group that the director determines are appropriate to consider.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A director of a benefit corporation, in the performance of duties in that capacity, does not have any duty to a person that is a beneficiary of the public benefit purposes of the benefit corporation.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A director of a benefit corporation, in the reasonable performance of duties in accordance with the standard provided in this subtitle, shall have the immunity from liability described in &#xA7; 5-417 of the Courts Article.</section>
  </text>
</law>
