<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gca" order_by="gca" level="1">Corporations and Associations</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gca-5-703</section_number>
  <catch_line>As used in this section, "aliens" means the following and their representatives:...</catch_line>
  <order_by>703</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">As used in this section, "aliens" means the following and their representatives:<section prefix="(1)">An alien;</section><section prefix="(2)">A foreign government;</section><section prefix="(3)">A corporation, joint-stock company, or association organized under the laws of a foreign country; and</section><section prefix="(4)">Any other corporation, joint-stock company, or association controlled directly or indirectly by one or more aliens.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Any Maryland corporation which conducts business under a license or grant of authority issued pursuant to a statute or regulation of the United States government, this State, or any agency of either, which statute or regulation provides that the license or grant of authority may not be granted to or held by, or the business may not be conducted by, a corporation of which more than a specified percentage of the capital stock or voting interests is owned of record or controlled by aliens, or which license or grant of authority permits an agency to restrict, limit or revoke the license or grant of authority or the right to conduct the business in such circumstances, or any Maryland corporation controlling directly or indirectly any corporation, joint-stock company or association which conducts its business or any portion of its business under the license or grant of authority, may, by its bylaws, restrict or limit the transferability to, ownership by, or voting rights of shares of its stock, whether issued or to be issued in the hands of aliens to the extent appropriate to comply with the applicable statute or regulation. Any requirements of &#xA7; 8-204 of the Commercial Law Article and of &#xA7; 2-211 of this article with respect to limitations or restrictions need only be complied with as to certificates for such shares issued after the adoption of such bylaws.</section>
  </text>
</law>
