<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gca" order_by="gca" level="1">Corporations and Associations</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gca-10-101</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this title, unless the context requires otherwise, the following words have the meanings indicate...</catch_line>
  <order_by>101</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this title, unless the context requires otherwise, the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Certificate" means the certificate referred to in &#xA7; 10-201 of this title, the certificate as amended, and the certificate of cancellation.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Consent" means a writing consenting to a specified act or event.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">"Contribution" means any cash, property, services rendered, or a promissory note or other binding obligation to contribute cash or property or to perform services, which a partner contributes as capital to a limited partnership in that individual's capacity as a partner.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"Event of withdrawal of a general partner" means an event that causes a person to cease to be a general partner as provided in &#xA7; 10-402 of this title.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">"Foreign limited partnership" means a partnership formed under the laws of any state other than the State of Maryland or under the laws of a foreign country and having as partners one or more general partners and one or more limited partners.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">"General partner" means a person who has been admitted to a limited partnership as a general partner in accordance with the partnership agreement and has been named as a general partner in the certificate or similar instrument of the state or foreign country under which the limited partnership is organized if so required.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">"Limited partner" means a person who has been admitted to a limited partnership as a limited partner in accordance with the partnership agreement and has been named as a limited partner in the certificate or similar instrument of the state or foreign country under which the limited partnership is organized if so required.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">"Limited partnership" and "domestic limited partnership" mean a partnership formed by two or more persons under the laws of the State and having one or more general partners and one or more limited partners.</section>
    <section prefix="(j)">"Partner" means a limited or general partner.</section>
    <section prefix="(k)">"Partnership" means a partnership formed under &#xA7; 9A-202 of this article, or any predecessor law, but not including a domestic or foreign limited partnership.</section>
    <section prefix="(l)">"Partnership agreement" means any valid agreement, written or oral, of the partners as to the affairs of a limited partnership and the conduct of its business.</section>
    <section prefix="(m)">"Partnership interest" means a partner's share of the profits and losses of a limited partnership and the right to receive distributions of partnership assets.</section>
    <section prefix="(n)">"Person" means a natural person, partnership, limited partnership (domestic or foreign), trust, estate, association, limited liability company (domestic or foreign), or corporation.</section>
    <section prefix="(o)">"State" means a state, territory, possession, or district of the United States.</section>
  </text>
</law>
