<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gca" order_by="gca" level="1">Corporations and Associations</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gca-2-512</section_number>
  <catch_line>Any stockholder, holder of a voting trust certificate in a corporation, or his agent, on written req...</catch_line>
  <order_by>512</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Any stockholder, holder of a voting trust certificate in a corporation, or his agent, on written request, may inspect and copy during usual business hours any of the following corporate documents:<section prefix="(1)">Bylaws;</section><section prefix="(2)">Minutes of the proceedings of the stockholders;</section><section prefix="(3)">Annual statements of affairs; and</section><section prefix="(4)">Voting trust agreements deposited with the corporation at the corporation's principal office in accordance with &#xA7; 2-510(2) of this subtitle.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Within 7 days after a request for documents made under subsection (a) of this section is presented to an officer or the resident agent of a corporation, the corporation shall have the requested documents available on file at its principal office.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Any stockholder or holder of a voting trust certificate in a corporation other than an open-ended investment company may present to any officer or resident agent of the corporation a written request for a statement showing all stock and securities issued by the corporation during a specified period of not more than 12 months before the date of the request.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Within 20 days after a request is made under this subsection, the corporation shall prepare and have available on file at its principal office a sworn statement of its president or treasurer or one of its vice-presidents or assistant treasurers which states:<section prefix="(i)">The number of shares or amounts of each class of stock or other securities issued during the specified period;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The consideration received per share or unit, which may be aggregated as to all issuances for the same consideration per share or unit; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">The value of any consideration other than money as set in a resolution of the board of directors.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
