<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gca" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="2-409" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gca-2-409</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Unless the bylaws of the corporation provide otherwise, a regular or special meeting of the board of directors may be held at any place in or out of the State or by means of remote communication.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Notice of each meeting of the board of directors shall be given as provided in the bylaws.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Unless the bylaws provide otherwise, the notice:<section prefix="(i)">Shall be in writing or delivered by electronic transmission; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Need not state the business to be transacted at or the purpose of any regular or special meeting of the board of directors.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Whenever this article or the charter or bylaws of a corporation require notice of the time, place, or purpose of a meeting of the board of directors or a committee of the board, a person who is entitled to the notice waives notice if the person:<section prefix="(1)">Before or after the meeting delivers a written waiver or a waiver by electronic transmission which is filed with the records of the meeting; or</section><section prefix="(2)">Is present at the meeting.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Unless restricted by the charter or bylaws of the corporation, members of the board of directors or a committee of the board may participate in a meeting by means of a conference telephone or other communications equipment if all persons participating in the meeting can hear each other at the same time.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Participation in a meeting by these means constitutes presence in person at the meeting.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
