<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gca" order_by="" level="1">Corporations and Associations</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gca-2-211</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>211</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Each stock certificate shall include on its face:<section prefix="(1)">The name of the corporation that issues it;</section><section prefix="(2)">The name of the stockholder or other person to whom it is issued; and</section><section prefix="(3)">The class of stock and number of shares it represents.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">If the corporation has authority to issue stock of more than one class, the stock certificate shall contain on its face or back a full statement or summary of:<section prefix="(1)">The designations and any preferences, conversion and other rights, voting powers, restrictions, limitations as to dividends, qualifications, and terms and conditions of redemption of the stock of each class which the corporation is authorized to issue; and</section><section prefix="(2)">If the corporation is authorized to issue any preferred or special class in series:<section prefix="(i)">The differences in the relative rights and preferences between the shares of each series to the extent they have been set; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">The authority of the board of directors to set the relative rights and preferences of subsequent series.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Instead of a full statement or summary of the information required by subsection (b) of this section, the certificate may state that the corporation will furnish a full statement of the required information to any stockholder on request and without charge.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Without affecting &#xA7; 8-204 of the Commercial Law Article, if the corporation which issues the stock imposes a restriction on its transferability, the stock certificate shall:<section prefix="(1)">Contain a full statement of the restriction; or</section><section prefix="(2)">State that the corporation will furnish information about the restriction to the stockholder on request and without charge.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">Except as otherwise provided by &#xA7; 8-204 of the Commercial Law Article, the fact that a stock certificate does not contain or refer to a restriction on transferability that is adopted after the date of issuance of the stock certificate does not mean that the restriction is invalid or unenforceable.</section>
  </text>
</law>
