<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gca" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="12-101" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gca-12-101</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this title the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Beneficial owner" means any owner of record of a beneficial interest in a statutory trust, the fact of ownership to be determined and evidenced, whether by means of registration, the issuance of certificates or otherwise, in conformity to the applicable provisions of the governing instrument of the statutory trust.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Foreign business entity" means:<section prefix="(1)">A foreign statutory trust; or</section><section prefix="(2)">A corporation, general or limited partnership, common-law trust, limited liability company, real estate investment trust, limited liability company, or any other unincorporated business formed, organized, or existing under the laws of another state, the United States, a foreign country, or other foreign jurisdiction.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">"Foreign statutory trust" means a trust that is:<section prefix="(1)">Formed under the laws of another state, the United States, a foreign country, or other foreign jurisdiction; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Required by the laws of the jurisdiction in which it is formed to file a record with a public official in that jurisdiction.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"Governing instrument" means a declaration of trust or other trust instrument which provides for the governance of the affairs of a statutory trust and the conduct of its business.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Other business entity" means a corporation, a general or limited partnership, a common-law trust, a limited liability company, a real estate investment trust, or any other unincorporated business.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Other business entity" does not include a statutory trust.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">"Person" means a natural person, partnership, limited partnership, limited liability company, trust, estate, association, corporation, custodian, nominee, or any other individual or entity in its own or any representative capacity.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Statutory trust" means an unincorporated business, trust, or association that is:<section prefix="(i)">Formed by filing an initial certificate of trust under &#xA7; 12-204 of this title; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Governed by a governing instrument.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Statutory trust" includes a trust formed under this title on or before May 31, 2010, as a business trust, as the term business trust was then defined in this title.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(i)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Trustee" means the person appointed as a trustee in accordance with the governing instrument of a statutory trust.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Trustee" may include a beneficial owner of a statutory trust.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
