<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gca" order_by="gca" level="1">Corporations and Associations</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gca-12-609</section_number>
  <catch_line>In order to keep the land assessment records current in each county, the Department shall require a ...</catch_line>
  <order_by>609</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In order to keep the land assessment records current in each county, the Department shall require a statutory trust, corporation, partnership, limited partnership, or limited liability company to submit with the articles of merger or consolidation a property certificate for each county where a merging or consolidating statutory trust, corporation, partnership, limited partnership, or limited liability company other than the successor owns an interest in land.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A property certificate is not required with respect to any property in which the only interest owned by the merging or consolidating statutory trust, corporation, partnership, limited partnership, or limited liability company is a security interest.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The property certificate shall be in the form and number of copies which the Department requires and may include the certificate of the Department required by subsection (a) of this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The property certificate shall provide a deed reference or other description sufficient to identify the property.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Department shall indicate on the certificate the time the articles of merger or consolidation are accepted for record and send a copy of it to the chief assessor of the county where the property is located.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">A transfer, vesting, or devolution of title to the property is not invalidated or otherwise affected by any error or defect in the property certificate, failure to file it, or failure by the Department to act on it.</section>
  </text>
</law>
