<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gca" order_by="gca" level="1">Corporations and Associations</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gca-10-303</section_number>
  <catch_line>Except as provided in &#xA7; 10-207(a) of this title and subsection (c) of this section, a limited partn...</catch_line>
  <order_by>303</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Except as provided in &#xA7; 10-207(a) of this title and subsection (c) of this section, a limited partner is not liable for the obligations of a limited partnership unless the limited partner is also a general partner or, in addition to the exercise of his rights and powers as a limited partner, he takes part in the control of the business. However, if the limited partner takes part in the control of the business and is not also a general partner, the limited partner is liable only to persons who transact business with the limited partnership and who reasonably believe, based upon the limited partner's conduct, that the limited partner is a general partner.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A limited partner does not take part in the control of the business within the meaning of subsection (a) of this section solely by doing one or more of the following:<section prefix="(i)">Being a contractor for or an agent or employee of the limited partnership or of a general partner or being an officer, director, or stockholder of a corporate general partner, or any combination of these roles, whether solely or jointly with other officers, directors, or stockholders, and irrespective of whether that corporate general partner is the sole general partner of the limited partnership or is a general partner of one or more limited partnerships;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Consulting with or advising a general partner with respect to the business of the limited partnership;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Acting as surety for the limited partnership;</section><section prefix="(iv)">Approving or disapproving an amendment to the partnership agreement; or</section><section prefix="(v)">Voting on one or more of the following matters:<section prefix="1.">The dissolution and winding up of the limited partnership;</section><section prefix="2.">The sale, exchange, lease, mortgage, pledge, or other transfer of a material portion of the assets of the limited partnership;</section><section prefix="3.">The incurrence of indebtedness by the limited partnership other than in the ordinary course of its business;</section><section prefix="4.">A change in the nature of its business;</section><section prefix="5.">The removal of a general partner;</section><section prefix="6.">The admission of a general or limited partner;</section><section prefix="7.">The merger of the limited partnership with or into any other entity; or</section><section prefix="8.">Any matter related to the business of the limited partnership not otherwise enumerated in this subsection which the partnership agreement states in writing may be subject to the approval or disapproval of limited partners.</section></section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The enumeration in subsection (b)(1) of this subsection does not necessarily mean that the possession or exercise of any other powers by a limited partner constitutes participation by the limited partner in the business of the limited partnership.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A limited partner who knowingly permits his name to be used in the name of the limited partnership, except under circumstances permitted by Title 1, Subtitle 5 of this article, is liable to creditors who extend credit to the limited partnership without actual knowledge that the limited partner is not a general partner.</section>
  </text>
</law>
