<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gca" order_by="gca" level="1">Corporations and Associations</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gca-9A-101</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this title the following words have the meanings indicated....</catch_line>
  <order_by>101</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this title the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Business" includes every trade, occupation, and profession.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Debtor in bankruptcy" means a person who is the subject of:<section prefix="(1)">An order for relief under Title 11 of the United States Code or a comparable order under a successor statute of general application; or</section><section prefix="(2)">A comparable order under federal, State, or foreign law governing insolvency.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">"Distribution" means a transfer of money or other property from a partnership to a partner in the partner's capacity as a partner or to the partner's transferee.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"Foreign limited liability partnership" means a partnership that is formed in accordance with an agreement governed by the laws of a state other than this State and registered or denominated as a limited liability partnership or registered limited liability partnership under the laws of such other state, but does not include a foreign limited partnership registered or denominated as a limited liability limited partnership under the laws of a state other than this State.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">"Foreign limited partnership" means a partnership, including a foreign limited partnership registered or denominated as a limited liability partnership under the laws of a state other than this State, formed under the laws of any state other than this State or under the laws of a foreign country and having as partners one or more general partners and one or more limited partners.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">"Limited liability partnership" means a partnership that:<section prefix="(1)">Is formed in accordance with the laws of this State; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Is registered under &#xA7; 9A-1001 of this title.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(h)">"Limited partnership" and "domestic limited partnership" means a limited partnership formed by two or more persons under the laws of this State and having one or more general partners and one or more limited partners.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">"Partnership" means an association of two or more persons to carry on as co-owners a business for profit formed under &#xA7; 9A-202 of this title, predecessor law, or comparable law of another jurisdiction and includes, for all purposes of the laws of this State, a limited liability partnership and a foreign limited liability partnership.</section>
    <section prefix="(j)">"Partnership agreement" means the agreement, whether written, oral, or implied, among the partners concerning the partnership, including amendments to the partnership agreement.</section>
    <section prefix="(k)">"Partnership at will" means a partnership in which the partners have not agreed to remain partners until the expiration of a definite term or the completion of a particular undertaking.</section>
    <section prefix="(l)">"Partnership interest" or "partner's interest in the partnership" means all of a partner's interests in the partnership, including the partner's transferable interest and all management and other rights.</section>
    <section prefix="(m)">"Property" means all property, real, personal, or mixed, tangible or intangible, or any interest therein.</section>
    <section prefix="(n)">"Real estate investment trust" means a Maryland real estate investment trust as defined in &#xA7; 8-101 of this article.</section>
    <section prefix="(o)">"State" means a state of the United States, the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, or any territory or insular possession subject to the jurisdiction of the United States.</section>
    <section prefix="(p)">"Statement" means a statement of partnership authority under &#xA7; 9A-303 of this title, a statement of denial under &#xA7; 9A-304 of this title, a statement of dissociation under &#xA7; 9A-704 of this title, a statement of dissolution under &#xA7; 9A-805 of this title, or an amendment or cancellation of any of the foregoing.</section>
    <section prefix="(q)">"Statutory trust" means a Maryland statutory trust as defined in &#xA7; 12-101 of this article.</section>
    <section prefix="(r)">"Transfer" includes an assignment, conveyance, lease, mortgage, deed, and encumbrance.</section>
  </text>
</law>
