<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gca" order_by="gca" level="1">Corporations and Associations</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gca-12-801</section_number>
  <catch_line>Except with respect to a tax collectible locally, the State Comptroller shall certify to the Departm...</catch_line>
  <order_by>801</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except with respect to a tax collectible locally, the State Comptroller shall certify to the Department, as soon as practicable after October 1 of each year, a list of every Maryland statutory trust that has not paid a tax that was due before October 1 of the year.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">When the Comptroller certifies the list to the Department, the Comptroller shall mail to each listed statutory trust, at the statutory trust's address as it appears on the Comptroller's records, a notice that the statutory trust's right to do business in the State and the right to the use of its name will be forfeited unless the statutory trust pays all taxes, interest, and penalties due.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The failure of a statutory trust to receive the notice mailed in accordance with paragraph (2) of this subsection does not affect the forfeiture of the statutory trust's right to do business in the State or to use its name.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">As soon as practicable after October 1 of each year, the Secretary of Labor, Licensing, and Regulation shall certify to the Department a list of every Maryland statutory trust that has not paid an unemployment insurance contribution or made a reimbursement payment that was due before October 1 of the year.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">When the Secretary certifies the list to the Department, the Secretary shall mail to each listed statutory trust, at the statutory trust's address as it appears on the Secretary's records, a notice that the statutory trust's right to do business in the State and the right to the use of its name will be forfeited unless the statutory trust pays all contributions, reimbursement payments, interest, and penalties due.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The failure of a statutory trust to receive the notice mailed in accordance with paragraph (2) of this subsection does not affect the forfeiture of the statutory trust's right to do business in the State or to use its name.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">As soon as practicable after October 1 of each year, the Department shall certify a list of every Maryland statutory trust that has not filed an annual report with the Department as required by law or has not paid a tax that was due before October 1 of the year.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">After the lists are certified, the Department shall issue a proclamation declaring, for each statutory trust included on a list, that, subject to &#xA7; 12-810 of this subtitle, the right to do business in the State and to use the name of the statutory trust is forfeited as of the date of the proclamation, without proceedings of any kind at law or at equity.</section>
  </text>
</law>
