<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gca" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="9A-1001" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gca-9A-1001</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">A partnership formed in accordance with an agreement governed by the laws of this State may register as a limited liability partnership by filing with the Department a certificate of limited liability partnership which sets forth:<section prefix="(1)">The name of the limited liability partnership;</section><section prefix="(2)">The purpose for which the limited liability partnership exists; and</section><section prefix="(3)">The address of its principal office in this State and the name and address of its resident agent.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A partnership qualifies as a limited liability partnership at the time of the filing of the certificate with the Department or at any later time specified in the certificate.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">An amendment to the certificate of limited liability partnership shall be:<section prefix="(1)">In writing; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Filed for record with the Department.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A certificate or amendment shall be executed by a person authorized by the limited liability partnership to execute such certificate and amendment.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">Registration of a partnership as a limited liability partnership may be voluntarily withdrawn at any time by filing with the Department a written withdrawal notice executed by one or more partners authorized by the limited liability partnership to execute the withdrawal.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The status of a partnership as a limited liability partnership shall not be affected by the admission of one or more partners to the partnership or by the death, retirement, or withdrawal of any partner or any other event causing any partner to be dissociated from the partnership.</section>
  </text>
</law>
