<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gca" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="2-408" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gca-2-408</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Unless this article or the charter or bylaws of the corporation require a greater proportion, the action of a majority of the directors present at a meeting at which a quorum is present is the action of the board of directors.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Unless the bylaws of the corporation provide otherwise, a majority of the entire board of directors constitutes a quorum for the transaction of business.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The bylaws may provide that less than a majority, but not less than one-third of the entire board of directors, may constitute a quorum unless:<section prefix="(i)">There are only two or three directors, in which case not less than two may constitute a quorum; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">There is only one director, in which case that one will constitute a quorum.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Any action required or permitted to be taken at a meeting of the board of directors or of a committee of the board may be taken without a meeting if a unanimous consent which sets forth the action is:<section prefix="(1)">Given in writing or by electronic transmission by each member of the board or committee; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Filed in paper or electronic form with the minutes of proceedings of the board or committee.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The charter may provide that one or more directors or a class of directors shall have more or less than one vote per director on any matter.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If the charter provides that one or more directors shall have more or less than one vote per director on any matter, every reference in this article to a majority or other proportion of directors shall refer to a majority or other proportion of votes of the directors.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
