<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gca" order_by="" level="1">Corporations and Associations</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gca-3-413</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>413</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Except as provided in subsection (d) of this section, stockholders entitled to cast at least 25 percent of all the votes entitled to be cast in the election of directors of a corporation may petition a court of equity to dissolve the corporation on grounds that:<section prefix="(1)">The directors are so divided respecting the management of the corporation's affairs that the votes required for action by the board cannot be obtained; or</section><section prefix="(2)">The stockholders are so divided that directors cannot be elected.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Except as provided in subsection (d) of this section, any stockholder entitled to vote in the election of directors of a corporation may petition a court of equity to dissolve the corporation on grounds that:<section prefix="(1)">The stockholders are so divided that they have failed, for a period which includes at least two consecutive annual meeting dates, to elect successors to directors whose terms would have expired on the election and qualification of their successors; or</section><section prefix="(2)">The acts of the directors or those in control of the corporation are illegal, oppressive, or fraudulent.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Any stockholder or creditor of a corporation other than a railroad corporation may petition a court of equity to dissolve the corporation on grounds that it is unable to meet its debts as they mature in the ordinary course of its business.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Subsections (a)(2) and (b)(1) of this section do not apply to any corporation that has a class of equity securities registered under the federal Securities Exchange Act of 1934.</section>
  </text>
</law>
