<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gca" order_by="gca" level="1">Corporations and Associations</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gca-11-406</section_number>
  <catch_line>A broker-dealer or investment adviser may obtain a renewal registration by filing with the Commissio...</catch_line>
  <order_by>406</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">A broker-dealer or investment adviser may obtain a renewal registration by filing with the Commissioner or any entity the Commissioner designates by rule or order an application containing whatever information the Commissioner by rule requires to keep current the information contained in the application for initial registration.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A broker-dealer or issuer may obtain a renewal registration for the agents associated with it by filing with the Commissioner or any entity the Commissioner designates by rule or order an application containing the names of the agents associated with it and a certification that, to the best knowledge, information, and belief of the broker-dealer or issuer:<section prefix="(1)">There has been no change in the information contained in the agents' applications for the registration then currently in effect; or</section><section prefix="(2)">If there has been any such change, specifying the change.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A federal covered adviser who has filed a notice under &#xA7; 11-405(b) of this subtitle or an investment adviser may obtain a renewal registration for the investment adviser representatives associated with it by filing with the Commissioner or any entity the Commissioner designates by rule or order an application containing the names of the representatives associated with it and a certification that, to the best knowledge, information, and belief of the federal covered adviser or the investment adviser:<section prefix="(1)">There has been no change in the information contained in the investment adviser representatives' applications for the registration currently in effect; or</section><section prefix="(2)">If there has been any such change, specifying the change.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">An application for renewal registration is effective on receipt by the Commissioner of the proper application and fee or on the expiration of the previous registration, whichever date is later.</section>
  </text>
</law>
