<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gca" order_by="gca" level="1">Corporations and Associations</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gca-4A-1007</section_number>
  <catch_line>If a foreign limited liability company is doing or has done any intrastate, interstate, or foreign b...</catch_line>
  <order_by>1007</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">If a foreign limited liability company is doing or has done any intrastate, interstate, or foreign business in this State without complying with the requirements of this subtitle, the foreign limited liability company and any person claiming under it may not maintain suit in any court of this State, unless the limited liability company shows to the satisfaction of the court that:<section prefix="(1)">The foreign limited liability company or the person claiming under it has paid the penalty specified in subsection (d)(1) of this section; and</section><section prefix="(2)"><section prefix="(i)">The foreign limited liability company or a successor to it has complied with the requirements of this title; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">The foreign limited liability company and any foreign limited liability company successor to it are no longer doing intrastate, interstate, or foreign business in this State.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The failure of a foreign limited liability company to register in this State does not impair the validity of a contract or act of the foreign limited liability company or prevent the foreign limited liability company from defending any action, suit, or proceeding in a court of this State.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A foreign limited liability company, by doing business in this State without registration, appoints the Department as its agent for service of process with respect to causes of action arising out of doing business in this State.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">If a foreign limited liability company does any intrastate, interstate, or foreign business in this State without registering, the Department shall impose a penalty of $200 on the limited liability company.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The penalty under this subsection shall be collected and may be reduced or abated under &#xA7; 14-704 of the Tax - Property Article.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Each member of a foreign limited liability company that does intrastate, interstate, or foreign business in this State without registering, and each agent of the foreign limited liability company who transacts intrastate, interstate, or foreign business in this State for it is guilty of a misdemeanor and on conviction is subject to a fine of not more than $1,000.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
