<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gca" order_by="gca" level="1">Corporations and Associations</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gca-9A-307</section_number>
  <catch_line>A partnership may sue and be sued in the name of the partnership....</catch_line>
  <order_by>307</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">A partnership may sue and be sued in the name of the partnership.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">An action may be brought against the partnership and, except as provided in &#xA7; 9A-306 of this subtitle and subsection (f) of this section, any or all of the partners in the same action or in separate actions.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A judgment against a partnership is not by itself a judgment against a partner. A judgment against a partnership may not be satisfied from a partner's assets unless there is also a judgment against the partner.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A judgment creditor of a partner may not levy execution against the assets of the partner to satisfy a judgment based on a claim against the partnership unless the claim is for a debt, obligation, or liability for which the partner is liable under &#xA7; 9A-306 of this subtitle and either:<section prefix="(1)">A judgment based on the same claim has been obtained against the partnership and a writ of execution on the judgment has been returned unsatisfied in whole or in part;</section><section prefix="(2)">The partnership is a debtor in bankruptcy;</section><section prefix="(3)">The partner has agreed that the creditor need not exhaust partnership assets;</section><section prefix="(4)">A court grants permission to the judgment creditor to levy execution against the assets of a partner based on a finding that partnership assets subject to execution are clearly insufficient to satisfy the judgment, that exhaustion of partnership assets is excessively burdensome, or that the grant of permission is an appropriate exercise of the court's equitable powers; or</section><section prefix="(5)">Liability is imposed on the partner by law or contract independent of the existence of the partnership.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">This section applies to any partnership liability or obligation resulting from a representation by a partner or purported partner under &#xA7; 9A-308 of this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">A partner of a limited liability partnership is not a proper party to a proceeding by or against a limited liability partnership solely by reason of being a partner of the limited liability partnership, except where the object of the proceeding is:<section prefix="(1)">To enforce a partner's right against or liability to the limited liability partnership; or</section><section prefix="(2)">To recover damages, or enforce partnership obligations, for which the partner is personally liable under &#xA7; 9A-306 of this subtitle.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
