<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gca" order_by="gca" level="1">Corporations and Associations</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gca-3-802</section_number>
  <catch_line>Notwithstanding any other provision in this article except subsection (b) of this section, this subt...</catch_line>
  <order_by>802</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Notwithstanding any other provision in this article except subsection (b) of this section, this subtitle applies to each corporation that:<section prefix="(1)">Has a class of equity securities registered under the Securities Exchange Act of 1934; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Elects to be subject to any or all provisions, in whole or in part, of this subtitle by provision in:<section prefix="(i)">Its charter or bylaws; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">A resolution of its board of directors.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This subtitle applies only to a corporation that has at least three directors who, at the time of any election to become subject to the provisions of this subtitle:<section prefix="(i)">Are not officers or employees of the corporation;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Are not acquiring persons;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Are not directors, officers, affiliates, or associates of an acquiring person; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">Were not nominated or designated as directors by an acquiring person.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A director does not fail to satisfy paragraph (1) of this subsection because the director:<section prefix="(i)">Owns securities issued by the corporation;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Is entitled to compensation, retirement, severance, or other benefits as a director of the corporation; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">Might continue to serve as a director of the corporation or become a director of an acquiring person.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">This subtitle does not apply to a corporation to the extent that the corporation elects not to be subject to any provision of this subtitle to which it has previously elected to be subject, if the corporation elects not to be subject to the provision in the same manner in which it elected to become subject to the provision, including the satisfaction of subsection (d)(1) of this section, if applicable.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The charter of a corporation may contain a provision or the board of directors may adopt a resolution that prohibits the corporation from electing to be subject to any or all provisions of this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A corporation shall file articles supplementary with the Department if:<section prefix="(i)">The corporation elects to be subject to any or all provisions of this subtitle by resolution of the board of directors or bylaw amendment; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">The board of directors adopts a resolution in accordance with subsection (c) of this section that prohibits the corporation from electing to be subject to any or all provisions of this subtitle.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The articles supplementary shall describe any provision of this subtitle to which the corporation:<section prefix="(i)">Has elected to become subject; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">May not elect to become subject in accordance with the resolution of the board.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Stockholder approval is not required for the filing of articles supplementary in accordance with paragraph (1) of this subsection.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
