<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gca" order_by="gca" level="1">Corporations and Associations</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gca-3-801</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated....</catch_line>
  <order_by>801</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Acquiring person" means a person who is seeking to acquire control of a corporation.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Act" includes an omission or failure to act.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">"Affiliate" means a person that directly, or indirectly through one or more intermediaries, controls, is controlled by, or is under common control with, a specified person.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"Associate", when used to indicate a relationship with any person, means:<section prefix="(1)">Any corporation or organization (other than the corporation or a subsidiary of the corporation) of which such person is an officer, director, or partner or is, directly or indirectly, the beneficial owner of 10 percent or more of any class of equity securities;</section><section prefix="(2)">Any trust or other estate in which such person has a substantial beneficial interest or as to which such person serves as trustee or in a similar fiduciary capacity; and</section><section prefix="(3)">Any relative or spouse of such person, or any relative of such spouse, who has the same principal residence as such person or who is a director or officer of the corporation or any of its affiliates.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">"Beneficial owner", when used with respect to any stock, means a person:<section prefix="(1)">That, individually or with any of its affiliates or associates, beneficially owns stock, directly or indirectly; or</section><section prefix="(2)">That, individually or with any of its affiliates or associates, has:<section prefix="(i)">The right to acquire stock (whether such right is exercisable immediately or only after the passage of time), pursuant to any agreement, arrangement, or understanding or upon the exercise of conversion rights, exchange rights, warrants or options, or otherwise; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">The right to vote stock pursuant to any agreement, arrangement, or understanding; or</section></section><section prefix="(3)">That has any agreement, arrangement, or understanding for the purpose of acquiring, holding, voting, or disposing of stock with any other person that beneficially owns, or whose affiliates or associates beneficially own, directly or indirectly, such shares of stock.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(g)">"Charter" includes the declaration of trust of a real estate investment trust.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">"Control", including the terms "controlling", "controlled by", and "under common control with", means the possession, directly or indirectly, of the power to direct or cause the direction of the management and policies of a person, whether through the ownership of voting securities, by contract, or otherwise, and the beneficial ownership of 10 percent or more of the votes entitled to be cast by a corporation's stock creates a presumption of control.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">"Corporation" includes a real estate investment trust as defined in Title 8 of this article.</section>
    <section prefix="(j)">"Director" includes a trustee of a real estate investment trust.</section>
    <section prefix="(k)">"Equity security" means:<section prefix="(1)">Any stock or similar security, certificate of interest, or participation in any profit sharing agreement, voting trust certificate, or certificate of deposit for an equity security;</section><section prefix="(2)">Any security convertible, with or without consideration, into an equity security, or any warrant or other security carrying any right to subscribe to or purchase an equity security; or</section><section prefix="(3)">Any put, call, straddle, or other option or privilege of buying an equity security from or selling an equity security to another without being bound to do so.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(l)">"Real estate investment trust" has the meaning stated in Title 8 of this article.</section>
    <section prefix="(m)">"Stockholder" includes a shareholder of a real estate investment trust.</section>
    <section prefix="(n)">"Subsidiary" means any corporation of which stock having a majority of the votes entitled to be cast is owned, directly or indirectly, by the corporation.</section>
  </text>
</law>
