<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gca" order_by="" level="1">Corporations and Associations</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gca-11-405</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>405</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">A broker-dealer, agent, investment adviser, or investment adviser representative may obtain an initial registration by filing with the Commissioner, or any entity the Commissioner designates by rule or order, an application together with a consent to service of process under &#xA7; 11-802(a) of this title. The application shall contain whatever information the Commissioner by rule or order requires.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This subsection does not apply to a federal covered adviser who conducts advisory business in accordance with &#xA7; 11-401(b)(2) or (3) of this subtitle.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Before acting as a federal covered adviser in this State, a person shall pay the fee required by &#xA7; 11-407 of this subtitle and shall file the following documents as the Commissioner may require by rule or order:<section prefix="(i)">The documents that the person filed with the Securities and Exchange Commission; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">A consent to service of process under &#xA7; 11-802(a) of this title.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Notwithstanding the provisions of subsection (a) of this section, a registered broker-dealer who is also a registered investment adviser in this State may effect the initial registration of any or all of its registered agents in this State as investment adviser representatives by the filing of:<section prefix="(1)">A notice with the Commissioner designating the registered agents as representatives of the investment adviser;</section><section prefix="(2)">A consent to service of process under &#xA7; 11-802(a) of this title; and</section><section prefix="(3)">Such other information as the Commissioner by rule or order may require.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Notwithstanding the provisions of subsection (a) of this section, a registered broker-dealer who is also a federal covered adviser that has filed a notice under subsection (b) of this section may effect the initial registration of its registered agents with a place of business in this State as investment adviser representatives by the filing of:<section prefix="(1)">A notice with the Commissioner designating the registered agents as representatives of the federal covered adviser;</section><section prefix="(2)">A consent to service of process under &#xA7; 11-802(a) of this title; and</section><section prefix="(3)">Such other information as the Commissioner by rule or order may require.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The Commissioner in the Commissioner's discretion may publish an announcement of the applicants for registration in the newspapers the Commissioner determines.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">If a denial order is not in effect and a proceeding is not pending under &#xA7;&#xA7; 11-412 through 11-414 of this subtitle, registration becomes effective at noon of the 30th day after an application is filed. The Commissioner by rule or order may specify an earlier effective date, and the Commissioner by order may defer the effective date until noon of the 30th day after the filing of any amendment.</section>
  </text>
</law>
