<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gca" order_by="gca" level="1">Corporations and Associations</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gca-1-207.1</section_number>
  <catch_line>A corporation may file a certificate of notice for record with the Department....</catch_line>
  <order_by>207.1</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">A corporation may file a certificate of notice for record with the Department.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A certificate of notice may describe:<section prefix="(1)">An action by the corporation, its board of directors, or its stockholders;</section><section prefix="(2)">The occurrence of or change to facts ascertainable outside of the charter, as defined in &#xA7; 2-105(b) of this article;</section><section prefix="(3)">The expiration of the period of existence of the corporation in accordance with &#xA7; 3-519 of this article; or</section><section prefix="(4)">Any other information that the corporation determines should be disclosed.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A certificate of notice may not:<section prefix="(1)">Amend, supplement, or correct the charter of the corporation in any manner; or</section><section prefix="(2)">Affect any rights or liabilities of stockholders, whether or not accrued or incurred before the certificate of notice is filed.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A certificate of notice is not a part of the charter of a corporation.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">A director of a corporation is not required to authorize or direct the filing of a certificate of notice.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">A corporation is not required to file a certificate of notice for any purpose, including to indicate that there has been a change to the facts or information contained in a previously filed certificate of notice.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">A certificate of notice shall be executed in the manner required for charter documents by &#xA7; 1-301 of this title.</section>
  </text>
</law>
