<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gca" order_by="gca" level="1">Corporations and Associations</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gca-12-205</section_number>
  <catch_line>Articles of merger or consolidation, a restated certificate of trust, a certificate of amendment, a ...</catch_line>
  <order_by>205</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Articles of merger or consolidation, a restated certificate of trust, a certificate of amendment, a certificate of cancellation, or an amendment of a certificate or articles shall be executed:<section prefix="(i)">In the manner required by &#xA7; 1-301 of this article; or</section><section prefix="(ii)"><section prefix="1.">By a person duly authorized by one or more of the trustees; or</section><section prefix="2.">If there is no trustee, as provided in the governing instrument of the statutory trust.</section></section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If articles of merger or consolidation or a certificate of termination or amendment of articles of merger or consolidation is being filed by another business entity or a foreign business entity, the articles of merger or consolidation or the certificate of termination or amendment of articles of merger or consolidation shall be executed by a person authorized to execute the articles or certificate on behalf of the other business entity or foreign business entity.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">An executed copy of each certificate required by this subtitle shall be filed with the Department.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Department may not accept for record any certificate that does not meet the requirements of this subtitle.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Department may not accept for record or filing any certificate or other document until all required fees have been paid to the Department.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">When the Department accepts for record any certificate or any document designating or changing the name or address of a resident agent or principal office of a Maryland statutory trust, the Department shall promptly record the document.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The fact that a certificate of trust is on file in the office of the Department is notice:<section prefix="(1)">That the entity formed in connection with the filing of the certificate of trust is a statutory trust formed under the laws of the State;</section><section prefix="(2)">Of all other facts which are required to be set forth in a certificate of trust by &#xA7; 12-204 of this subtitle; and</section><section prefix="(3)">Of the limitation on liability of a series of a statutory trust which is permitted to be set forth in a certificate of trust by &#xA7; 12-501(d) of this title.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
