<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gcj" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="9-109.1" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcj-9-109.1</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Client" means an individual who communicates to or receives services from a psychiatric-mental health nursing specialist or a professional counselor regarding the diagnosis or treatment of the individual's mental or emotional disorder.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Professional counselor" means an individual who is certified, licensed, or exempted from licensure as a counselor under Title 17 of the Health Occupations Article.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">"Psychiatric-mental health nursing specialist" means a registered nurse who:<section prefix="(i)">Has a master's degree in psychiatric-mental health nursing; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">Has a baccalaureate degree in nursing and a master's degree in a mental health field; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">Is certified as a clinical specialist in psychiatric and mental health nursing by the American Nurses' Association or by a body approved by the Board of Nursing.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Unless otherwise provided, in any judicial, legislative, or administrative proceeding, a client or a client's authorized representative has a privilege to refuse to disclose, and to prevent a witness from disclosing, communications relating to:<section prefix="(1)">Diagnosis or treatment of the client; or</section><section prefix="(2)">Any information that by its nature would show a medical record of the diagnosis or treatment exists.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If a client is incompetent to assert or waive this privilege, a guardian shall be appointed and shall act for the client.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A guardian appointed before the proceeding has the authority to act for the client.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">There is no privilege if:<section prefix="(1)">A disclosure is necessary for the purpose of placing the client in a facility for mental illness;</section><section prefix="(2)">A judge finds that the client, after being informed that there will be no privilege, makes communications in the course of an examination ordered by the court and the issue at trial involves the client's mental or emotional disorder;</section><section prefix="(3)">In a civil or criminal proceeding:<section prefix="(i)">The client introduces the client's mental condition as an element of the claim or defense; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">After the client's death, the client's mental condition is introduced by any party claiming or defending through or as a beneficiary of the client;</section></section><section prefix="(4)">The client, the authorized representative of the client, or the personal representative of the client makes a claim against the psychiatric-mental health nursing specialist or the professional counselor for malpractice; or</section><section prefix="(5)">The client expressly consents to waive the privilege or, in the case of death or disability, the client's personal representative waives the privilege for the purpose of making a claim or bringing suit on a policy of insurance on life, health, or physical condition.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">There is no privilege in:<section prefix="(1)">Any administrative or judicial nondelinquent juvenile proceeding;</section><section prefix="(2)">Any guardianship and adoption proceeding initiated by a child placement agency;</section><section prefix="(3)">Any guardianship and protective services proceeding concerning a disabled person; or</section><section prefix="(4)">Any criminal or delinquency proceeding in which there is a charge of child abuse or neglect or that arises out of an investigation of suspected child abuse or neglect.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
