<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcj" order_by="" level="1">Courts and Judicial Proceedings</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcj-3-813</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>813</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Except as provided in subsections (b) and (c) of this section, a party is entitled to the assistance of counsel at every stage of any proceeding under this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Except for the local department and the child who is the subject of the petition, a party is not entitled to the assistance of counsel at State expense unless the party is:<section prefix="(1)">Indigent; or</section><section prefix="(2)">Otherwise not represented and:<section prefix="(i)">Under the age of 18 years; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">Incompetent by reason of mental disability.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Office of the Public Defender may not represent a party in a CINA proceeding unless the party:<section prefix="(1)">Is the parent or guardian of the alleged CINA;</section><section prefix="(2)">Applies to the Office of the Public Defender requesting legal representation by the Public Defender in the proceeding; and</section><section prefix="(3)">Is financially eligible for the services of the Public Defender.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A child who is the subject of a CINA petition shall be represented by counsel.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Unless the court finds that it would not be in the best interests of the child, the court shall:<section prefix="(i)">Appoint an attorney with whom the Department of Human Resources has contracted to provide those services, in accordance with the terms of the contract; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">If another attorney has previously been appointed, strike the appearance of that attorney.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">In addition to, but not instead of, the appointment of an attorney under this section, the court, in any action, may appoint an individual provided by a Court-Appointed Special Advocate Program created under &#xA7; 3-830 of this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The court may assess against any party reasonable compensation for the services of an attorney appointed to represent a child in an action under this subtitle.</section>
  </text>
</law>
