<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gcj" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="9-110" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcj-9-110</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">"Firm" means a proprietorship, partnership, or professional corporation engaged in the practice of public accountancy.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">"Firm" includes an employee of the firm.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">"Licensed certified public accountant" has the meaning stated in &#xA7; 2-101(i) of the Business Occupations and Professions Article.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">"Licensed certified public accountant" includes an employee of the licensed certified public accountant.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(4)">"Permit" has the meaning stated in &#xA7; 2-101(j) of the Business Occupations and Professions Article.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">"Practice of certified public accountancy" has the meaning stated for "practice certified public accountancy" in &#xA7; 2-101(l) of the Business Occupations and Professions Article.</section>
      <section prefix="(6)">
        <section prefix="(i)">"Practice of public accountancy" means the performance or the offering to perform by a licensed certified public accountant or a firm, while holding out to the public, services for a client or a potential client that involve:</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">"Practice of public accountancy" includes the practice of certified public accountancy.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(7)">"Quality review" means an independent appraisal, review, or study of the professional work of a licensed certified public accountant or firm in the practice of public accountancy that is made by a licensed certified public accountant or firm that is not affiliated with the licensed certified public accountant or firm undergoing a quality review.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Except as provided in subsections (c) and (d) of this section or unless expressly permitted by a client or the personal representative or successor in interest of the client, a licensed certified public accountant or firm may not disclose:<section prefix="(1)">The contents of any communication made to the licensed certified public accountant or firm by a client who employs the licensed certified public accountant or firm to audit, examine, or report on any account, book, record, or statement of the client;</section><section prefix="(2)">Any information that the licensed certified public accountant or firm, in rendering professional service, derives from:<section prefix="(i)">A client who employs the licensed certified public accountant or firm; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">The material of the client.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A licensed certified public accountant or firm may disclose any data to another certified public accountant or firm that conducts a quality review.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The disclosure permitted by paragraph (1) of this subsection:<section prefix="(i)">Does not waive the privilege required by subsection (b) of this section; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Subjects a licensed certified public accountant or firm that conducts a quality review to the same duty of confidentiality applicable to the licensed certified public accountant or firm undergoing the quality review.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The privilege against disclosure required by subsection (b) of this section does not affect:<section prefix="(1)">The bankruptcy laws;</section><section prefix="(2)">The criminal laws of the State; or</section><section prefix="(3)">A regulatory proceeding by the State Board of Public Accountancy under &#xA7;&#xA7; 2-317 and 2-412 of the Business Occupations and Professions Article.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
