<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gcj" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="2-213" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcj-2-213</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Except as otherwise provided in this section, the clerk of a circuit court is entitled to 5% of all public money that the clerk receives, collects, and pays over.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Clerk of the Circuit Court for Anne Arundel County is entitled to receive:<section prefix="(1)">3% of the amount collected for the tax applicable to instruments recorded with the Clerk under Title 12 of the Tax - Property Article; and</section><section prefix="(2)">5% of all other public money that the Clerk receives, collects, and pays over.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Clerk of the Circuit Court for Baltimore City is entitled to receive:<section prefix="(1)">2.5% of the amount collected from the tax applicable to instruments recorded with the Clerk under Title 12 of the Tax - Property Article; and</section><section prefix="(2)">5% of all other public money that the Clerk receives, collects, and pays over.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Clerk of the Circuit Court for Baltimore County is entitled to receive:<section prefix="(1)">3% of the amount collected from the tax applicable to instruments recorded with the Clerk under Title 12 of the Tax - Property Article; and</section><section prefix="(2)">5% of all other public money that the Clerk receives, collects, and pays over.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Notwithstanding subsection (a) of this section, the Clerk of the Circuit Court for Charles County shall:<section prefix="(i)">Deduct from collection fees for the tax collected under Title 12 of the Tax - Property Article the cost of two-thirds of the salaries and benefits of the court reporters for the Circuit Court of Charles County; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Pay the amount deducted to the Charles County Treasurer.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Clerk shall make the payment promptly after receipt of a voucher from the Charles County Treasurer stating the amount of the salaries and benefits paid to the court reporters.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The Clerk of the Circuit Court for Harford County is entitled to:<section prefix="(1)">3% of the amount collected from the tax applicable to instruments recorded with the Clerk under Title 12 of the Tax - Property Article; and</section><section prefix="(2)">5% of all other public money that the Clerk receives, collects, and pays over.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(g)">The Clerk of the Circuit Court for Montgomery County is entitled to 3% of all public money that the Clerk receives, collects, and pays over.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">Notwithstanding subsection (a) of this section, the Clerk of the Circuit Court for St. Mary's County is not entitled to a collection fee for collecting the county transfer tax under Chapter 138 of the Public Local Laws of St. Mary's County when the Clerk collects both the recordation tax under Title 12 of the Tax - Property Article and the county transfer tax for the filing of a single instrument.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">Notwithstanding subsection (a) of this section, the Clerk of the Circuit Court for Washington County is not entitled to a collection fee for collecting the county transfer tax under &#xA7; 2-702 of the Public Local Laws of Washington County when the Clerk collects both the recordation tax under Title 12 of the Tax - Property Article and the county transfer tax for the filing of a single instrument.</section>
  </text>
</law>
