<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gcj" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="10-306" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcj-10-306</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Subject to the provisions of paragraph (2) of this subsection, in any criminal trial in which a violation of &#xA7; 16-113, &#xA7; 16-813, or &#xA7; 21-902 of the Transportation Article, or a violation of Title 2, Subtitle 5, &#xA7; 2-209, or &#xA7; 3-211 of the Criminal Law Article is charged or is an issue, a copy of a report of the results of a test of breath or blood to determine alcohol concentration signed by the technician or analyst who performed the test, is admissible as substantive evidence without the presence or testimony of the technician or analyst who performed the test.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">Subject to the provisions of &#xA7; 10-308(b) of this subtitle and paragraph (2) of this subsection, in any criminal trial in which a violation of &#xA7; 21-902 of the Transportation Article or a violation of Title 2, Subtitle 5, &#xA7; 2-209, or &#xA7; 3-211 of the Criminal Law Article is charged, a copy of a report of the results of a test or tests of blood to determine drug or controlled dangerous substance content signed by the technician or analyst who performed the test, is admissible as substantive evidence without the presence or testimony of the technician or analyst who performed the test.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">To be admissible under paragraph (1) of this subsection, the report shall:<section prefix="(i)">Identify the technician or analyst as a "qualified person", as defined in &#xA7; 10-304 of this subtitle;</section><section prefix="(ii)">State that the test was performed with equipment approved by the toxicologist under the Postmortem Examiners Commission at the direction of a police officer; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">State that the result of the test is as stated in the report.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Test results which comply with the requirements of subsection (a) of this section are admissible as substantive evidence without the presence or testimony of the technician or analyst who administered the test.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">However, if the State decides to offer the test results without the testimony of the technician or analyst, it shall, at least 30 days before trial, notify the defendant or his attorney in writing of its intention and deliver to the defendant or his attorney a copy of the test results to be offered.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">If the District Court is deprived of jurisdiction under circumstances in which a defendant is entitled to and demands a jury trial, or appeals from the District Court to the circuit court, the State is not required to file a second notice.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">If the defendant desires the technician or analyst to be present and testify at trial, the defendant shall notify the court and the State in writing no later than 20 days before trial.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">If the District Court is deprived of jurisdiction under circumstances in which a defendant is entitled to and demands a jury trial, or appeals from the District Court to a circuit court, the defendant shall notify the circuit court and the State in writing no later than 20 days before trial.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">If the timely and proper notice required under this paragraph is provided by the defendant, the test results are inadmissible without the testimony of the technician or analyst.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Failure to give timely and proper notice constitutes a waiver of the defendant's right to the presence and testimony of the technician or analyst.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
