<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gcj" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="11-108" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcj-11-108</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">"Noneconomic damages" means:</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">"Noneconomic damages" does not include punitive damages.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Primary claimant" means a claimant in an action for the death of a person described under &#xA7; 3-904(d) of this article.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">"Secondary claimant" means a claimant in an action for the death of a person described under &#xA7; 3-904(e) of this article.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In any action for damages for personal injury in which the cause of action arises on or after July 1, 1986, an award for noneconomic damages may not exceed $350,000.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Except as provided in paragraph (3)(ii) of this subsection, in any action for damages for personal injury or wrongful death in which the cause of action arises on or after October 1, 1994, an award for noneconomic damages may not exceed $500,000.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The limitation on noneconomic damages provided under subparagraph (i) of this paragraph shall increase by $15,000 on October 1 of each year beginning on October 1, 1995. The increased amount shall apply to causes of action arising between October 1 of that year and September 30 of the following year, inclusive.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The limitation established under paragraph (2) of this subsection shall apply in a personal injury action to each direct victim of tortious conduct and all persons who claim injury by or through that victim.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">In a wrongful death action in which there are two or more claimants or beneficiaries, an award for noneconomic damages may not exceed 150% of the limitation established under paragraph (2) of this subsection, regardless of the number of claimants or beneficiaries who share in the award.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">An award by the health claims arbitration panel in accordance with &#xA7; 3-2A-05 of this article for damages in which the cause of action arose before January 1, 2005, shall be considered an award for purposes of this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In a jury trial, the jury may not be informed of the limitation established under subsection (b) of this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">If the jury awards an amount for noneconomic damages that exceeds the limitation established under subsection (b) of this section, the court shall reduce the amount to conform to the limitation.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">In a wrongful death action in which there are two or more claimants or beneficiaries, if the jury awards an amount for noneconomic damages that exceeds the limitation established under subsection (b)(3)(ii) of this section, the court shall:</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The provisions of this section do not apply to a verdict under Title 3, Subtitle 2A of this article for damages in which the cause of action arises on or after January 1, 2005.</section>
  </text>
</law>
