<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcj" order_by="gcj" level="1">Courts and Judicial Proceedings</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcj-3-803</section_number>
  <catch_line>In addition to the jurisdiction specified in Subtitle 8A of this title, the court has exclusive orig...</catch_line>
  <order_by>803</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In addition to the jurisdiction specified in Subtitle 8A of this title, the court has exclusive original jurisdiction over:<section prefix="(1)">Voluntary placement hearings;</section><section prefix="(2)">Proceedings arising from a petition alleging that a child is a CINA;</section><section prefix="(3)">Proceedings arising under the Interstate Compact on the Placement of Children;</section><section prefix="(4)">Proceedings to terminate parental rights after a CINA proceeding;</section><section prefix="(5)">Guardianship review proceedings after a TPR proceeding; and</section><section prefix="(6)">Adoption proceedings, if any, after a TPR proceeding.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The court has concurrent jurisdiction over:<section prefix="(i)">Custody, visitation, support, and paternity of a child whom the court finds to be a CINA; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Custody of a child alleged to be a CINA under the circumstances described in &#xA7; 3-819(d) of this subtitle.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">During pendency of an action under this subtitle, a party has a continuing duty to advise the court and any other court considering custody, support, visitation, or paternity of a child, of the pendency of any other action concerning the child, whether the action is in this or another state.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The court may decline to exercise jurisdiction under this subsection if there is a proceeding pending in another court of competent jurisdiction.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">If the court and another court both have pending actions involving a child described in paragraph (1) of this subsection, the court shall communicate with the other court expeditiously to determine the more appropriate court to take further action, consistent with the best interest of the child.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">The court shall advise the parties of the decision and the basis for the decision.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The court has concurrent jurisdiction over proceedings against an adult for a violation of &#xA7; 3-828 of this subtitle.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The court may waive its jurisdiction under this subsection on its own motion or on the motion of any party to the proceeding, if charges against the adult arising from the same incident are pending in the criminal court.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">On motion by the State's Attorney or the adult charged under &#xA7; 3-828 of this subtitle, the court shall waive its jurisdiction and the adult shall be tried in the criminal court according to the usual criminal procedure.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The age of the child at the time a petition is filed under &#xA7; 3-828 of this subtitle controls the determination of jurisdiction under this subsection.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
