<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcj" order_by="gcj" level="1">Courts and Judicial Proceedings</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcj-5-803</section_number>
  <catch_line>Whether or not an individual receives compensation for the individual's services, an employee of a c...</catch_line>
  <order_by>803</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Whether or not an individual receives compensation for the individual's services, an employee of a county health department or other local department or agency functioning as a school nurse or school health aide or a member of the administrative, educational, or support staff of, or an individual who serves under a contract for services to, any public, private, or parochial school is immune from liability for:<section prefix="(i)">Making a report required by law, if the individual acts on reasonable grounds;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Participating in a judicial proceeding that results from the individual's report; and<section prefix="1.">Under the influence of alcoholic beverages or a controlled dangerous substance;</section><section prefix="2.">In possession of alcoholic beverages or a controlled dangerous substance; or</section><section prefix="3.">Involved in the illegal sale or distribution of alcoholic beverages or a controlled dangerous substance.</section></section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Paragraph (1)(iii) of this subsection is effective only to the extent that its provisions do not conflict with federal or State confidentiality laws and regulations.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A county superintendent or any employee of a county school system who presents or enters findings of fact, recommendations, or reports or who participates in an employee dismissal, disciplinary, administrative, or judicial proceeding relating to a school system employee that results from these actions is immune from any civil liability if the action is:<section prefix="(1)">In the performance of duties;</section><section prefix="(2)">Within the scope of employment; and</section><section prefix="(3)">Without malice.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
