<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcj" order_by="" level="1">Courts and Judicial Proceedings</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcj-3-904</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>904</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in paragraphs (2) and (3) of this subsection, an action under this subtitle shall be for the benefit of the wife, husband, parent, and child of the deceased person.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A parent may not be a beneficiary in a wrongful death action for the death of a child of the parent if:<section prefix="(i)"><section prefix="1.">The parent is convicted under &#xA7;&#xA7; 3-303 through 3-308, &#xA7; 3-323, &#xA7; 3-601, or &#xA7; 3-602 of the Criminal Law Article; or</section><section prefix="2.">The parent committed an act prohibited under &#xA7;&#xA7; 3-303 through 3-308, &#xA7; 3-323, &#xA7; 3-601, or &#xA7; 3-602 of the Criminal Law Article;</section></section><section prefix="(ii)">The other parent of the child is the victim of the crime or act described under item (i) of this paragraph; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">The other parent of the child is a child of the parent.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">An action under this subtitle for the wrongful death of a child caused by the parent of the child allowed under the provisions of &#xA7; 5-806 of this article may not be for the benefit of that parent of the deceased child.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">An action under this subtitle for the wrongful death of a parent caused by a child of the parent allowed under the provisions of &#xA7; 5-806 of this article may not be for the benefit of that child of the deceased parent.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">If there are no persons who qualify under subsection (a), an action shall be for the benefit of any person related to the deceased person by blood or marriage who was substantially dependent upon the deceased.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In an action under this subtitle, damages may be awarded to the beneficiaries proportioned to the injury resulting from the wrongful death.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Subject to &#xA7; 11-108(d)(2) of this article, the amount recovered shall be divided among the beneficiaries in shares directed by the verdict.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The damages awarded under subsection (c) of this section are not limited or restricted by the "pecuniary loss" or "pecuniary benefit" rule but may include damages for mental anguish, emotional pain and suffering, loss of society, companionship, comfort, protection, marital care, parental care, filial care, attention, advice, counsel, training, guidance, or education where applicable for the death of:<section prefix="(1)">A spouse;</section><section prefix="(2)">A minor child;</section><section prefix="(3)">A parent of a minor child; or</section><section prefix="(4)">An unmarried child who is not a minor child if:<section prefix="(i)">The child is 21 years old or younger; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">A parent contributed 50 percent or more of the child's support within the 12-month period immediately before the date of death of the child.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">For the death of a child, who is not described under subsection (d) of this section, or a parent of a child, who is not a minor child, the damages awarded under subsection (c) of this section are not limited or restricted by the "pecuniary loss" or "pecuniary benefit" rule but may include damages for mental anguish, emotional pain and suffering, loss of society, companionship, comfort, protection, care, attention, advice, counsel, training, education, or guidance where applicable.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">Only one action under this subtitle lies in respect to the death of a person.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in paragraph (2) or (3) of this subsection, an action under this subtitle shall be filed within three years after the death of the injured person.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">In this paragraph, "occupational disease" means a disease caused by exposure to any toxic substance in the person's workplace and contracted by a person in the course of the person's employment.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">If an occupational disease was a cause of a person's death, an action shall be filed:<section prefix="1.">Within 10 years of the time of death; or</section><section prefix="2.">Within 3 years of the date when the cause of death was discovered, whichever is the shorter.</section></section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">This paragraph applies only to a wrongful death cause of action arising from conduct that would constitute a criminal homicide under State or federal law.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">If knowledge of a cause of action or the identity of a person whose wrongful act contributed to a homicide is kept from a party by the conduct of an adverse party or an accessory or accomplice of an adverse party:<section prefix="1.">The cause of action shall be deemed to accrue at the time the party discovered or should have discovered by the exercise of ordinary diligence the homicide and the identity of the person who contributed to the homicide;</section><section prefix="2.">A presumption shall exist that the party should have discovered by the exercise of ordinary diligence the identity of the person who contributed to the homicide after:</section><section prefix="3.">An action under this subtitle shall be filed within 3 years after the date that the cause of action accrues.</section></section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(h)">For the purposes of this section, a person born to parents who have not participated in a marriage ceremony with each other is considered to be the child of the mother. The person is considered to be the child of the father only if the father:<section prefix="(1)">Has been judicially determined to be the father in a proceeding brought under &#xA7; 5-1010 of the Family Law Article or &#xA7; 1-208 of the Estates and Trusts Article; or</section><section prefix="(2)">Prior to the death of the child:<section prefix="(i)">Has acknowledged himself, in writing, to be the father;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Has openly and notoriously recognized the person to be his child; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">Has subsequently married the mother and has acknowledged himself, orally or in writing, to be the father.</section></section></section>
  </text>
</law>
