<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcj" order_by="gcj" level="1">Courts and Judicial Proceedings</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcj-3-8A-14</section_number>
  <catch_line>A child may be taken into custody under this subtitle by any of the following methods:...</catch_line>
  <order_by>14</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">A child may be taken into custody under this subtitle by any of the following methods:<section prefix="(1)">Pursuant to an order of the court;</section><section prefix="(2)">By a law enforcement officer pursuant to the law of arrest;</section><section prefix="(3)">By a law enforcement officer or other person authorized by the court if the officer or other person has reasonable grounds to believe that the child is in immediate danger from the child's surroundings and that the child's removal is necessary for the child's protection;</section><section prefix="(4)">By a law enforcement officer or other person authorized by the court if the officer or other person has reasonable grounds to believe that the child has run away from the child's parents, guardian, or legal custodian; or</section><section prefix="(5)">In accordance with &#xA7; 3-8A-14.1 of this subtitle.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">If a law enforcement officer takes a child into custody, the officer shall immediately notify, or cause to be notified, the child's parents, guardian, or custodian of the action. After making every reasonable effort to give notice, the law enforcement officer shall with all reasonable speed:<section prefix="(1)">Release the child to the child's parents, guardian, or custodian or to any other person designated by the court, upon their written promise to bring the child before the court when requested by the court, and such security for the child's appearance as the court may reasonably require, unless the child's placement in detention or shelter care is permitted and appears required by &#xA7; 3-8A-15 of this subtitle; or</section><section prefix="(2)">Deliver the child to the court or a place of detention or shelter care designated by the court.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">If a parent, guardian, or custodian fails to bring the child before the court when requested, the court may issue a writ of attachment directing that the child be taken into custody and brought before the court. The court may proceed against the parent, guardian, or custodian for contempt.</section>
  </text>
</law>
