<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcj" order_by="" level="1">Courts and Judicial Proceedings</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcj-9-112</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>112</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, "news media" means:<section prefix="(1)">Newspapers;</section><section prefix="(2)">Magazines;</section><section prefix="(3)">Journals;</section><section prefix="(4)">Press associations;</section><section prefix="(5)">News agencies;</section><section prefix="(6)">Wire services;</section><section prefix="(7)">Radio;</section><section prefix="(8)">Television; and</section><section prefix="(9)">Any printed, photographic, mechanical, or electronic means of disseminating news and information to the public.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The provisions of this section apply to any person who is, or has been:<section prefix="(1)">Employed by the news media in any news gathering or news disseminating capacity; or</section><section prefix="(2)">Enrolled as a student in an institution of postsecondary education and engaged in any news gathering or news disseminating capacity recognized by the institution as a scholastic activity or in conjunction with an activity sponsored, funded, managed, or supervised by school staff or faculty.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Except as provided in subsection (d) of this section, any judicial, legislative, or administrative body, or anybody that has the power to issue subpoenas may not compel any person described in subsection (b) of this section to disclose:<section prefix="(1)">The source of any news or information procured by the person while employed by the news media or while enrolled as a student, whether or not the source has been promised confidentiality; or</section><section prefix="(2)">Any news or information procured by the person while employed by the news media, in the course of pursuing a professional activity, or any news or information procured by the person while enrolled as a student, in the course of pursuing a scholastic activity or in conjunction with an activity sponsored, funded, managed, or supervised by school staff or faculty, for communication to the public but which is not so communicated, in whole or in part, including:<section prefix="(i)">Notes;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Outtakes;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Photographs or photographic negatives;</section><section prefix="(iv)">Video and sound tapes;</section><section prefix="(v)">Film; and</section><section prefix="(vi)">Other data, irrespective of its nature, not itself disseminated in any manner to the public.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A court may compel disclosure of news or information, if the court finds that the party seeking news or information protected under subsection (c)(2) of this section has established by clear and convincing evidence that:<section prefix="(i)">The news or information is relevant to a significant legal issue before any judicial, legislative, or administrative body, or anybody that has the power to issue subpoenas;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The news or information could not, with due diligence, be obtained by any alternate means; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">There is an overriding public interest in disclosure.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A court may not compel disclosure under this subsection of the source of any news or information protected under subsection (c)(1) of this section.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">If any person described in subsection (b) of this section disseminates a source of any news or information, or any portion of the news or information procured while pursuing an activity described in subsection (b) of this section, the protection from compelled disclosure under this section is not waived by the person.</section>
  </text>
</law>
