<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gcj" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="3-8A-33" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcj-3-8A-33</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">A law enforcement officer authorized to make arrests shall issue a citation to a child if the officer has probable cause to believe that the child is violating:<section prefix="(1)">&#xA7; 10-113, &#xA7; 10-114, &#xA7; 10-115, or &#xA7; 10-116 of the Criminal Law Article;</section><section prefix="(2)">&#xA7; 10-108 of the Criminal Law Article;</section><section prefix="(3)">&#xA7; 10-132 of the Criminal Law Article; or</section><section prefix="(4)">&#xA7; 26-103 of the Education Article.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A citation issued under this section shall be in a format prescribed by the State Court Administrator after consultation with police administrators and the Motor Vehicle Administrator. Each citation shall be signed by the issuing officer and shall contain:<section prefix="(1)">The name, address, and birth date of the child being charged with the violation;</section><section prefix="(2)">The name and address of the child's parent or legal guardian;</section><section prefix="(3)">The statute allegedly violated;</section><section prefix="(4)">The time, place, and date of the violation;</section><section prefix="(5)">The driver's license number of the child, if the child possesses a driver's license;</section><section prefix="(6)">The registration number of the motor vehicle, motorcycle, or other vehicle, if applicable;</section><section prefix="(7)">The signature of the child; and</section><section prefix="(8)">The penalties which may be imposed under &#xA7; 3-8A-19 of this subtitle.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A copy of the citation issued under this section shall be:<section prefix="(1)">Given to the child being charged;</section><section prefix="(2)">Retained by the officer issuing the citation;</section><section prefix="(3)">Mailed within 7 days to the child's parent or legal guardian; and</section><section prefix="(4)">Filed with the intake officer of the court having jurisdiction under this subtitle.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
