<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcj" order_by="gcj" level="1">Courts and Judicial Proceedings</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcj-5-1001</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated....</catch_line>
  <order_by>1001</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Administrative remedy" means any procedure for review of a prisoner's complaint or grievance, including judicial review, if available, that is provided by the Department, the Division of Correction, or any county or other municipality or political subdivision, and results in a written determination or disposition.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Administrative remedy" includes a proceeding under Title 10, Subtitle 2 of the State Government Article or Title 10, Subtitle 2 of the Correctional Services Article.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Civil action" means a legal action seeking money damages, injunctive relief, declaratory relief, or any appeal filed in any court in the State that relates to or involves a prisoner's conditions of confinement.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Civil action" includes:<section prefix="(i)">An appeal of an administrative remedy to any court;</section><section prefix="(ii)">A petition for mandamus against the prisoner's custodian, its officers or employees, or any official or employee of the Department;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Any tort claim against a custodian, the custodian's officers or employees, or any employee or official of the Department;</section><section prefix="(iv)">Any action alleging a violation of civil rights against a custodian, the custodian's officers and employees, or any official or employee of the Department; or</section><section prefix="(v)">Any appeal, application for leave to appeal, or petition for certiorari.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Civil action" does not include a postconviction petition or petition for habeas corpus relief.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">"Conditions of confinement" means any circumstance, situation or event that involves a prisoner's custody, transportation, incarceration, or supervision.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"Custodian" means the institution or agency that has custody of the prisoner.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">"Department" means the Department of Public Safety and Correctional Services.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Prisoner" means a person who is in the custody of the Department or a local detention center.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Prisoner" includes pretrial detainees.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
