<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcj" order_by="" level="1">Courts and Judicial Proceedings</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcj-3-1503</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>1503</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">A petitioner may seek relief under this subtitle by filing with the court, or with a commissioner under the circumstances specified in &#xA7; 3-1503.1(a) of this subtitle, a petition that alleges the commission of any of the following acts against the petitioner by the respondent, if the act occurred within 30 days before the filing of the petition:<section prefix="(1)">An act that causes serious bodily harm;</section><section prefix="(2)">An act that places the petitioner in fear of imminent serious bodily harm;</section><section prefix="(3)">Assault in any degree;</section><section prefix="(4)">Rape or sexual offense under &#xA7;&#xA7; 3-303 through 3-308 of the Criminal Law Article or attempted rape or sexual offense in any degree;</section><section prefix="(5)">False imprisonment;</section><section prefix="(6)">Harassment under &#xA7; 3-803 of the Criminal Law Article;</section><section prefix="(7)">Stalking under &#xA7; 3-802 of the Criminal Law Article;</section><section prefix="(8)">Trespass under Title 6, Subtitle 4 of the Criminal Law Article; or</section><section prefix="(9)">Malicious destruction of property under &#xA7; 6-301 of the Criminal Law Article.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The petition shall:<section prefix="(i)">Be under oath and provide notice to the petitioner that an individual who knowingly provides false information in the petition is guilty of a misdemeanor and on conviction is subject to the penalties specified in subsection (d) of this section;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Subject to the provisions of subsection (c) of this section, contain the address of the petitioner; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Include all information known to the petitioner of:<section prefix="1.">The nature and extent of the act specified in subsection (a) of this section for which the relief is being sought, including information known to the petitioner concerning previous harm or injury resulting from an act specified in subsection (a) of this section by the respondent;</section><section prefix="2.">Each previous and pending action between the parties in any court; and</section><section prefix="3.">The whereabouts of the respondent.</section></section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">If, in a proceeding under this subtitle, a petitioner alleges, and the commissioner or judge finds, that the disclosure of the address of the petitioner would risk further harm to the petitioner, that address may be stricken from the petition and omitted from all other documents filed with the commissioner or filed with, or transferred to, a court.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">An individual who knowingly provides false information in a petition filed under this section is guilty of a misdemeanor and on conviction is subject to a fine not exceeding $1,000 or imprisonment not exceeding 90 days or both.</section>
  </text>
</law>
