<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcj" order_by="" level="1">Courts and Judicial Proceedings</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcj-3-1103</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>1103</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A motor carrier that is at fault and causes a traffic accident that results in a spill or discharge of hazardous materials shall negotiate in good faith to reimburse a volunteer fire company for the expense of an emergency response, containment, cleanup, and abatement involving the hazardous materials in the traffic accident.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A person in control of a fixed facility who is at fault and who is involved in a release or threatened release of hazardous materials shall negotiate in good faith to reimburse a volunteer fire company for the expense of an emergency response, containment, cleanup, and abatement involving the hazardous materials in the release or threatened release.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If the negotiations under subsection (a)(1) of this section do not resolve the dispute to the satisfaction of the parties, a volunteer fire company may file suit against the motor carrier in a court of competent jurisdiction in the State.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If the negotiations under subsection (a)(2) of this section do not resolve the dispute to the satisfaction of the parties, a volunteer fire company may file suit against the person in control in a court of competent jurisdiction in the State.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">At the request of a volunteer fire company, a local jurisdiction may file suit under this subtitle on behalf of the volunteer fire company.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">If a volunteer fire company is awarded damages under this subtitle, the court may also award reasonable attorney's fees.</section>
  </text>
</law>
