<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcj" order_by="gcj" level="1">Courts and Judicial Proceedings</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcj-3-830</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this section the following words have the meanings indicated....</catch_line>
  <order_by>830</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Advocate" or "C.A.S.A." means a Court-Appointed Special Advocate.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Program" means a Court-Appointed Special Advocate service that is created in a county with the support of the court for that county to provide trained volunteers whom the court may appoint to:<section prefix="(i)">Provide the court with background information to aid it in making decisions in the child's best interest; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Ensure that the child is provided appropriate case planning and services.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">There is a Court-Appointed Special Advocate Program.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The purpose of the Program is to provide volunteers whose primary purpose is to ensure the provision of appropriate service and case planning consistent with the best interests of a child who is the subject of:<section prefix="(i)">A CINA proceeding;</section><section prefix="(ii)">A custody and guardianship proceeding under &#xA7; 3-819.2 of this subtitle; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">A guardianship review proceeding under Title 5, Subtitle 3 of the Family Law Article.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Administrative Office of the Courts:<section prefix="(i)">Shall administer the Program;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Shall report annually to the Chief Judge of the Court of Appeals and, subject to &#xA7; 2-1246 of the State Government Article, to the General Assembly regarding the operation of the Program; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">May adopt rules governing the implementation and operation of the Program including funding, training, selection, and supervision of volunteers.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Governor may include funds in the budget to carry out the provisions of this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">An advocate or a member of the administrative staff of the Program is not liable for an act or omission in providing services or performing a duty on behalf of the Program, unless the act or omission constitutes reckless, willful, or wanton misconduct or intentionally tortious conduct.</section>
  </text>
</law>
