<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcj" order_by="" level="1">Courts and Judicial Proceedings</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcj-3-8A-19.2</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>19.2</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, "residence" includes the yard, grounds, outbuildings, and common areas surrounding the residence.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If a peace order request is filed under &#xA7; 3-8A-19.1(b) of this subtitle, the respondent shall have an opportunity to be heard on the question of whether the court should issue a peace order.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If the court finds by clear and convincing evidence that the respondent has committed, and is likely to commit in the future, an act specified in &#xA7; 3-8A-19.1(b) of this subtitle against the victim, or if the respondent consents to the entry of a peace order, the court may issue a peace order to protect the victim.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The peace order may include any or all of the following relief:<section prefix="(i)">Order the respondent to refrain from committing or threatening to commit an act specified in &#xA7; 3-8A-19.1(b) of this subtitle against the victim;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Order the respondent to refrain from contacting, attempting to contact, or harassing the victim;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Order the respondent to refrain from entering the residence of the victim;</section><section prefix="(iv)">Order the respondent to remain away from the place of employment, school, or temporary residence of the victim; and</section><section prefix="(v)">Direct the respondent or the victim to participate in professionally supervised counseling.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If the court issues an order under this section, the order shall contain only the relief that is minimally necessary to protect the victim.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">All relief granted in a peace order shall be effective for the period stated in the order, not to exceed 6 months.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">If the court issues an order under this section, the court may impose reasonable court costs against a respondent, or the respondent's parent, guardian, or custodian.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
