<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcj" order_by="" level="1">Courts and Judicial Proceedings</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcj-7-202</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>202</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The State Court Administrator shall determine the amount of all court costs and charges for the circuit courts of the counties with the approval of the Board of Public Works. The fees and charges shall be uniform throughout the State.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Comptroller of the State shall require clerks of court to collect all fees required to be collected by law.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The clerk may not charge the State, any county, municipality, or Baltimore City any fee provided by this subtitle, unless the State, county, municipality, or Baltimore City first gives its consent.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The clerk is entitled to a reasonable fee for performing any other service that is not enumerated in this subtitle or in &#xA7;&#xA7; 3-601 through 3-603 of the Real Property Article.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The State Court Administrator, as part of the Administrator's determination of the amount of court costs and charges in civil cases, shall assess a surcharge that:<section prefix="(1)">May not be more than $25 per case; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Shall be deposited into the Maryland Legal Services Corporation Fund established under &#xA7; 11-402 of the Human Services Article.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The State Court Administrator shall:<section prefix="(1)">Assess a $100 fee for the special admission of an out-of-state attorney under &#xA7; 10-215 of the Business Occupations and Professions Article; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Pay $75 of the fee to the Janet L. Hoffman Loan Assistance Repayment Program established under &#xA7; 18-1502 of the Education Article.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">If a party in a proceeding feels aggrieved by any fee permitted under this subtitle or by &#xA7;&#xA7; 3-601 through 3-603 of the Real Property Article, the party may request a judge of that circuit court to determine the reasonableness of the fee.</section>
  </text>
</law>
