<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcj" order_by="" level="1">Courts and Judicial Proceedings</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcj-6-203</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>203</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The general rule of &#xA7; 6-201 of this subtitle does not apply to actions enumerated in this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The venue of the following actions is in the county where all or any portion of the subject matter of the action is located:<section prefix="(i)">Partition of real estate;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Enforcement of a charge or lien on land;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Eminent domain;</section><section prefix="(iv)">Trespass to land; and</section><section prefix="(v)">Waste.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If the property lies in more than one county, the court where proceedings are first brought has jurisdiction over the entire property.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The venue of an action to recover damages against a railroad company for injury to livestock is the county where the injury occurred.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The venue of an action for guardianship under Title 5, Subtitle 3 of the Family Law Article is in the county where the court has jurisdiction over the child in need of assistance case under Title 3, Subtitle 8 of this article.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in paragraphs (2) and (3) of this subsection, the venue for a proceeding for adoption of an individual who is physically within this State or subject to the jurisdiction of an equity court is in a county where:<section prefix="(i)">The petitioner is domiciled;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The petitioner has resided for at least 90 days next preceding the filing of the petition;</section><section prefix="(iii)">A licensed child placement agency having legal or physical custody of the individual is located;</section><section prefix="(iv)">The individual is domiciled, if the individual is related to the petitioner by blood or marriage or is an adult; or</section><section prefix="(v)">An equity court has continuing jurisdiction over the custody of the individual.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The venue in an adoption of an individual under Title 5, Subtitle 3, Part III of the Family Law Article is in the court with jurisdiction over the individual under Title 3, Subtitle 8 of this article.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The venue in an adoption of an individual under Title 5, Subtitle 3, Part IV of the Family Law Article is in the court where the individual's guardianship case is pending.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
