<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcj" order_by="gcj" level="1">Courts and Judicial Proceedings</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcj-3-816</section_number>
  <catch_line>After a petition is filed under this subtitle, the court may order the local department or another q...</catch_line>
  <order_by>816</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">After a petition is filed under this subtitle, the court may order the local department or another qualified agency to make or arrange for a study concerning the child, the child's family, the child's environment, and other matters relevant to the disposition of the case.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">As part of a study under this section, the court may order that the child or any parent, guardian, or custodian be examined at a suitable place by a physician, psychiatrist, psychologist, or other professionally qualified person.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The court may not order an inpatient evaluation unless, after a hearing, the court finds that an inpatient evaluation is necessary and there are no less restrictive means to obtain an evaluation.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">Placement in an inpatient facility may not exceed 21 days unless the court finds good cause.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The report of a study under this section is admissible as evidence at a disposition hearing but not at an adjudicatory hearing.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The attorney for each party has the right to receive the report at least 5 days before its presentation to the court, to challenge or impeach its findings and to present appropriate evidence with respect to it.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The time requirement specified in paragraph (2) of this subsection does not apply to an emergency dispositional review hearing held in accordance with &#xA7; 3-820 of this subtitle.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
