<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcj" order_by="gcj" level="1">Courts and Judicial Proceedings</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcj-3-8A-17.6</section_number>
  <catch_line>At a competency hearing, if the court determines that the child is incompetent to proceed, but that ...</catch_line>
  <order_by>17.6</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">At a competency hearing, if the court determines that the child is incompetent to proceed, but that there is a substantial probability that the child may be able to attain competency in the foreseeable future and that services are necessary to attain competency, the court may order the Department of Health and Mental Hygiene to provide competency attainment services for the child for an initial period of not more than 90 days.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Any competency attainment services shall be provided in the least restrictive environment.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Subject to subsection (d) of this section, the court may order a child to be placed in a facility for children if:<section prefix="(1)">The child is detained under &#xA7; 3-8A-15 of this subtitle at the time of the competency hearing; and</section><section prefix="(2)">The court finds after a hearing on the issue that:<section prefix="(i)">Placement in a facility is necessary to protect the child or others, or the child is likely to leave the jurisdiction of the court; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">No less restrictive alternative placement is available that will protect the child or the community or prevent the child from leaving the jurisdiction of the court.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A child may not be:<section prefix="(1)">Unless the child's individualized treatment plan developed under &#xA7; 10-706 of the Health - General Article otherwise indicates, provided services in any group with persons who are at least 18 years old;</section><section prefix="(2)">Placed in a detention facility; or</section><section prefix="(3)">Placed in a psychiatric hospital, except in accordance with Title 10, Subtitle 6 of the Health - General Article.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
