<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcj" order_by="" level="1">Courts and Judicial Proceedings</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcj-6-311</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>311</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, "person" has the meaning stated in Rule 1-202 of the Maryland Rules.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This section applies to an action against a person who had applicable insurance coverage under an insurance policy or self-insurance plan at the time the alleged liability that is the subject of the action was incurred.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Subject to paragraph (1) of this subsection, this section applies to a person who is a defendant subject to a complaint, counterclaim, cross-claim, or third-party complaint.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Subject to subsections (d) and (e) of this section, on written request of a plaintiff to the action, an insurer or a person that has a self-insurance plan shall provide to the plaintiff the defendant's last known home and business addresses if known.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">An insurer or a person that has a self-insurance plan, and their employees and agents, may not be civilly or criminally liable for the disclosure of information required under this subsection.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Subsection (c)(1) of this section applies only if the plaintiff files a certification that states that the defendant:<section prefix="(1)">Had applicable insurance coverage at the time the alleged liability was incurred; and</section><section prefix="(2)">	Is evading service of process or the whereabouts of the defendant are unknown to the plaintiff.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">A plaintiff shall file a certification described under subsection (d) of this section with the clerk of the court in which the case is filed and serve the certification on the insurer or the person that has the self-insurance plan, as provided in the Maryland Rules.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">A defendant who is subject to the provisions of this section is deemed to have consented to the disclosure of the information described in this section.</section>
  </text>
</law>
