<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcj" order_by="gcj" level="1">Courts and Judicial Proceedings</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcj-5-301</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated....</catch_line>
  <order_by>301</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Actual malice" means ill will or improper motivation.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Employee" means any person who was employed by a local government at the time of the act or omission giving rise to potential liability against that person.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Employee" includes:<section prefix="(i)">Any employee, either within or without a classified service or merit system;</section><section prefix="(ii)">An appointed or elected official; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">A volunteer who, at the request of the local government, and under its control and direction, was providing services or performing duties.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">"Local government" means:<section prefix="(1)">A chartered county established under Article 25A of the Code;</section><section prefix="(2)">A code county established under Article 25B of the Code;</section><section prefix="(3)">A board of county commissioners established or operating under Article 25 of the Code;</section><section prefix="(4)">Baltimore City;</section><section prefix="(5)">A municipal corporation established or operating under Article 23A of the Code;</section><section prefix="(6)">The Maryland-National Capital Park and Planning Commission;</section><section prefix="(7)">The Washington Suburban Sanitary Commission;</section><section prefix="(8)">The Northeast Maryland Waste Disposal Authority;</section><section prefix="(9)">A community college or board of trustees for a community college established or operating under Title 16 of the Education Article, not including Baltimore City Community College;</section><section prefix="(10)">A county public library or board of trustees of a county public library established or operating under Title 23, Subtitle 4 of the Education Article;</section><section prefix="(11)">The Enoch Pratt Free Library or Board of Trustees of the Enoch Pratt Free Library;</section><section prefix="(12)">The Washington County Free Library or the Board of Trustees of the Washington County Free Library;</section><section prefix="(13)">A special taxing district;</section><section prefix="(14)">A nonprofit community service corporation incorporated under State law that is authorized to collect charges or assessments;</section><section prefix="(15)">Housing authorities created under Division II of the Housing and Community Development Article;</section><section prefix="(16)">A sanitary district, sanitary commission, metropolitan commission, or other sewer or water authority established or operating under public local law or public general law;</section><section prefix="(17)">The Baltimore Metropolitan Council;</section><section prefix="(18)">The Howard County Economic Development Authority;</section><section prefix="(19)">The Howard County Mental Health Authority;</section><section prefix="(20)">A commercial district management authority established by a county or municipal corporation if provided under local law;</section><section prefix="(21)">The Baltimore City Police Department;</section><section prefix="(22)">A regional library resource center or a cooperative library corporation established under Title 23, Subtitle 2 of the Education Article;</section><section prefix="(23)">Lexington Market, Inc., in Baltimore City;</section><section prefix="(24)">The Baltimore Public Markets Corporation, in Baltimore City;</section><section prefix="(25)">The nonprofit corporation serving as the local public transportation authority for Carroll County pursuant to a contract or memorandum of understanding with Carroll County (Carroll County Senior Overland Service, Inc., t/a Carroll Area Transit System);</section><section prefix="(26)">The nonprofit corporation serving as the animal control and licensing authority for Carroll County pursuant to a contract or memorandum of understanding with Carroll County (the Humane Society of Carroll County, Inc.);</section><section prefix="(27)">Garrett County Municipalities, Inc., in Garrett County; and</section><section prefix="(28)">The nonprofit corporation serving as the local public transportation authority for Garrett County pursuant to a contract or memorandum of understanding with Garrett County (Garrett County Community Action Committee, Inc.).</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
