<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcj" order_by="" level="1">Courts and Judicial Proceedings</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcj-4-302</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>302</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Except as provided in &#xA7; 4-301(b)(2), (6), (7), (8), (9), (10), (11), (12), (13), (14), (15), (16), (17), (18), (19), (20), (21), (22), (23), (24), and (25) of this subtitle, the District Court does not have jurisdiction to try a criminal case charging the commission of a felony.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Except as provided in &#xA7; 4-303 of this subtitle, the District Court does not have criminal jurisdiction to try a case in which a juvenile court has exclusive original jurisdiction.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The jurisdiction of the District Court is concurrent with that of the juvenile court in any criminal case arising under the compulsory public school attendance laws of this State.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, the jurisdiction of the District Court is concurrent with that of the circuit court in a criminal case:<section prefix="(i)">In which the penalty may be confinement for 3 years or more or a fine of $2,500 or more; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">That is a felony, as provided in &#xA7; 4-301(b)(2), (6), (7), (8), (9), (10), (11), (12), (13), (14), (15), (16), (17), (18), (19), (20), (21), (22), (23), (24), and (25) of this subtitle.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Except as provided in subparagraph (ii) of this paragraph, a circuit court does not have jurisdiction to try a case charging a violation of &#xA7; 5-601 or &#xA7; 5-620 of the Criminal Law Article.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">A circuit court does have jurisdiction to try a case charging a violation of &#xA7; 5-601 or &#xA7; 5-620 of the Criminal Law Article if the defendant:<section prefix="1.">Properly demands a jury trial;</section><section prefix="2.">Appeals as provided by law from a final judgment entered in the District Court; or</section><section prefix="3.">Is charged with another offense arising out of the same circumstances that is within a circuit court's jurisdiction.</section></section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The District Court is deprived of jurisdiction if a defendant is entitled to and demands a jury trial at any time prior to trial in the District Court.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Except as provided in subparagraph (ii) of this paragraph, unless the penalty for the offense with which the defendant is charged permits imprisonment for a period in excess of 90 days, a defendant is not entitled to a jury trial in a criminal case.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">Notwithstanding the provisions of subparagraph (i) of this paragraph, the presiding judge of the District Court may deny a defendant a jury trial if:<section prefix="1.">The prosecutor recommends in open court that the judge not impose a penalty of imprisonment for a period in excess of 90 days, regardless of the permissible statutory or common law maximum;</section><section prefix="2.">The judge agrees not to impose a penalty of imprisonment for a period in excess of 90 days; and</section><section prefix="3.">The judge agrees not to increase the defendant's bond if an appeal is noted.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">The State may not demand a jury trial.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in Title 4, Subtitle 5 of the Family Law Article, the District Court does not have jurisdiction of an offense otherwise within the District Court's jurisdiction if a person is charged:<section prefix="(i)">With another offense arising out of the same circumstances but not within the District Court's jurisdiction; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">In the circuit court with an offense arising out of the same circumstances and within the concurrent jurisdictions of the District Court and the circuit court described under subsection (d) of this section.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">In the cases described under paragraph (1) of this subsection, the circuit court for the county has exclusive original jurisdiction over all the offenses.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
