<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gcj" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="10-914" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcj-10-914</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">A laboratory test, performed by a laboratory certified by the Department of Health and Mental Hygiene and approved by the Division of Parole and Probation of the Department of Public Safety and Correctional Services, indicating that the defendant has used a controlled dangerous substance as defined in &#xA7; 5-101 of the Criminal Law Article or alcohol in violation of a condition of the defendant's probation or work release, is sufficiently reliable to justify revocation of the defendant's probation or work release, without an expert witness from the laboratory testifying in court to support the contents of a report of the laboratory test.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A report of a laboratory test described under this section shall:<section prefix="(1)">Identify the chemist or analyst who performed the laboratory test as an individual qualified, under standards approved by the Department of Health and Mental Hygiene, to perform the laboratory test;</section><section prefix="(2)">Be signed by the chemist or analyst who performed the laboratory test; and</section><section prefix="(3)">Contain a statement that:<section prefix="(i)">The material delivered to the chemist or analyst who performed the laboratory test was properly tested under procedures and equipment approved by the Department of Health and Mental Hygiene;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The procedures of the laboratory test are reliable; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">The laboratory test indicates that the defendant used a controlled dangerous substance or alcohol.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A report of a laboratory test is prima facie evidence of the results of the laboratory test.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Nothing in this section precludes the right of any party to introduce any evidence that supports or contradicts the evidence contained in or the presumptions raised by the report of the laboratory test described under subsection (b) of this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">Subject to the provisions of subsection (f) of this section, if a laboratory report or statement is admitted in evidence, the chemist or analyst who performed the laboratory test is subject to cross-examination by any party to the proceeding.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">On written demand of a defendant filed in the proceeding at least 5 days before the hearing to revoke a defendant's probation or work release, the prosecution shall require the presence of the chemist or analyst who performed the test or any individual in the chain of custody or control as a prosecution witness.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The provisions of subsections (a), (b), and (c) of this section concerning prima facie evidence do not apply to the testimony of a witness whose presence is required under this subsection.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Subsections (a), (b), and (c) of this section apply in a proceeding to revoke a defendant's probation or work release only when a copy of the report of the laboratory test or the statement to be introduced is mailed, delivered, or made available to counsel for the defendant or to the defendant personally when the defendant is not represented by counsel, at least 10 days prior to the introduction of the report of the laboratory test or the statement at the hearing.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
