<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gcj" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="3-8A-13" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcj-3-8A-13</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">A petition shall allege that a child is either delinquent or in need of supervision. If it alleges delinquency, it shall set forth in clear and simple language the alleged facts which constitute the delinquency, and shall also specify the laws allegedly violated by the child. If it alleges that the child is in need of supervision, the petition shall set forth in clear and simple language the alleged facts supporting that allegation.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Petitions alleging delinquency or violation of &#xA7; 3-8A-30 of this subtitle shall be prepared and filed by the State's Attorney. A petition alleging delinquency shall be filed within 30 days after the receipt of a referral from the intake officer, unless that time is extended by the court for good cause shown. Petitions alleging that a child is in need of supervision shall be filed by the intake officer.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A peace order request shall be filed by the intake officer in accordance with &#xA7; 3-8A-19.1(b)(1) of this subtitle or the State's Attorney in accordance with &#xA7; 3-8A-19.1(b)(2) of this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The form of petitions, peace order requests, and all other pleadings under this subtitle, and except as otherwise provided in this subtitle, the procedures to be followed by the court under this subtitle, shall be as specified in the Maryland Rules.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The State's Attorney, upon assigning the reasons, may dismiss in open court a petition alleging delinquency.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The court shall conduct all hearings under this subtitle in an informal manner.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">In any proceeding in which a child is alleged to be in need of supervision or to have committed a delinquent act that would be a misdemeanor if committed by an adult or in a peace order proceeding, the court may exclude the general public from a hearing, and admit only the victim and those persons having a direct interest in the proceeding and their representatives.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Except as provided in subparagraph (ii) of this paragraph, in a case in which a child is alleged to have committed a delinquent act that would be a felony if committed by an adult, the court shall conduct in open court any hearing or other proceeding at which the child has a right to appear.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">For good cause shown, the court may exclude the general public from a hearing or other proceeding in a case in which a child is alleged to have committed a delinquent act that would be a felony if committed by an adult and admit only the victim and those persons having a direct interest in the proceeding and their representatives.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(4)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Except as provided in subparagraph (ii) of this paragraph, the court shall announce in open court adjudications and dispositions in cases where a child is alleged to have committed a delinquent act which would be a felony if committed by an adult.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">For good cause shown, the court may exclude the general public from a proceeding at which an adjudication or disposition is announced and admit only the victim and those persons having a direct interest in the proceeding and their representatives.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(5)">Notwithstanding the provisions of this subsection, in a case in which the victim of an alleged delinquent act is a child, on petition of the State's Attorney, the court shall exclude the general public from the testimony of the victim during a hearing or other proceeding, including a proceeding at which an adjudication or disposition is announced, and admit during the testimony of the victim only the victim and those persons having a direct interest in the proceeding and their representatives, unless the court finds good cause to receive the testimony of the victim in open court.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">The court shall try cases without a jury.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">The court shall hear and rule on a petition seeking an order for emergency medical treatment on an expedited basis.</section>
  </text>
</law>
