<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcj" order_by="" level="1">Courts and Judicial Proceedings</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcj-3-823</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>823</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, "out-of-home placement" has the meaning stated in &#xA7; 5-501 of the Family Law Article.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The court shall hold a permanency planning hearing to determine the permanency plan for a child:<section prefix="(i)">No later than 11 months after a child committed under &#xA7; 3-819 of this subtitle or continued in a voluntary placement under &#xA7; 3-819.1(b) of this subtitle enters an out-of-home placement; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">Within 30 days after the court finds that reasonable efforts to reunify a child with the child's parent or guardian are not required based on a finding that a circumstance enumerated in &#xA7; 3-812 of this subtitle has occurred.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">For purposes of this section, a child shall be considered to have entered an out-of-home placement 30 days after the child is placed into an out-of-home placement.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">If all parties agree, a permanency planning hearing may be held on the same day as the reasonable efforts hearing.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">On the written request of a party or on its own motion, the court may schedule a hearing at any earlier time to determine a permanency plan or to review the implementation of a permanency plan for any child committed under &#xA7; 3-819 of this subtitle.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A written request for review shall state the reason for the request and each issue to be raised.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">At least 10 days before the permanency planning hearing, the local department shall provide all parties and the court with a copy of the local department's permanency plan for the child.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">At a permanency planning hearing, the court shall:<section prefix="(i)">Determine the child's permanency plan, which, to the extent consistent with the best interests of the child, may be, in descending order of priority:<section prefix="1.">Reunification with the parent or guardian;</section><section prefix="2.">Placement with a relative for:</section><section prefix="3.">Adoption by a nonrelative;</section><section prefix="4.">Custody and guardianship by a nonrelative under &#xA7; 3-819.2 of this subtitle; or</section><section prefix="5.">Another planned permanent living arrangement that:</section></section><section prefix="(ii)">For a child who has attained the age of 16 years, determine the services needed to assist the child to make the transition from placement to independent living.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">In determining the child's permanency plan, the court shall consider the factors specified in &#xA7; 5-525(f)(1) of the Family Law Article.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The court may not order a child to be continued in a placement under subsection (e)(1)(i)5 of this section unless the court finds that the person or agency to which the child is committed has documented a compelling reason for determining that it would not be in the best interest of the child to:<section prefix="(1)">Return home;</section><section prefix="(2)">Be referred for termination of parental rights; or</section><section prefix="(3)">Be placed for adoption or guardianship with a specified and appropriate relative or legal guardian willing to care for the child.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(g)">In the case of a child for whom the court determines that the plan should be changed to adoption under subsection (e)(1)(i)3 of this section, the court shall:<section prefix="(1)">Order the local department to file a petition for guardianship in accordance with Title 5, Subtitle 3 of the Family Law Article within 30 days or, if the local department does not support the plan, within 60 days; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Schedule a TPR hearing instead of the next 6-month review hearing.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(h)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Except as provided in subparagraphs (ii) and (iii) of this paragraph, the court shall conduct a hearing to review the permanency plan at least every 6 months until commitment is rescinded or a voluntary placement is terminated.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The court shall conduct a review hearing every 12 months after the court determines that the child shall be continued in out-of-home placement with a specific caregiver who agrees to care for the child on a permanent basis.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">
          <section prefix="1.">Unless the court finds good cause, a case shall be terminated after the court grants custody and guardianship of the child to a relative or other individual.</section>
          <section prefix="2.">If the court finds good cause not to terminate a case, the court shall conduct a review hearing every 12 months until the case is terminated.</section>
          <section prefix="3.">The court may not conclude a review hearing under subsubparagraph 2 of this subparagraph unless the court has seen the child in person.</section>
        </section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">At the review hearing, the court shall:<section prefix="(i)">Determine the continuing necessity for and appropriateness of the commitment;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Determine and document in its order whether reasonable efforts have been made to finalize the permanency plan that is in effect;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Determine the extent of progress that has been made toward alleviating or mitigating the causes necessitating commitment;</section><section prefix="(iv)">Project a reasonable date by which a child in placement may be returned home, placed in a preadoptive home, or placed under a legal guardianship;</section><section prefix="(v)">Evaluate the safety of the child and take necessary measures to protect the child; and</section><section prefix="(vi)">Change the permanency plan if a change in the permanency plan would be in the child's best interest.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Every reasonable effort shall be made to effectuate a permanent placement for the child within 24 months after the date of initial placement.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(i)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this subsection, "preadoptive parent" means an individual whom a child placement agency, as defined in &#xA7; 5-101 of the Family Law Article, approves to adopt a child who has been placed in the individual's home for adoption before the order of adoption.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">If practicable, before any hearing conducted under this section, the local department shall give at least 10 days' notice to the child's foster parent, preadoptive parent, or relative providing care for the child of the date, time, and place of the hearing and of the right to be heard.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">Unless waived for good cause, the notice shall be in writing.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The foster parent, preadoptive parent, relative, or an attorney for the foster parent, preadoptive parent, or relative shall be given the right to be heard at the hearing.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The foster parent, preadoptive parent, relative, or attorney may not be considered to be a party solely on the basis of the right to notice and the right to be heard provided under this subsection.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(j)">At a review hearing under this section, the court shall consider any written report of a local out-of-home care review board required under &#xA7; 5-545 of the Family Law Article.</section>
    <section prefix="(k)">
      <section prefix="(1)">At least every 12 months at a hearing under this section, the court shall consult on the record with the child in an age-appropriate manner to obtain the child's views on permanency.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">If, after a hearing or with the agreement of all parties, the court determines that the child is medically fragile and that it is detrimental to the child's physical or mental health to be transported to the courthouse, the court may, subject to subparagraph (ii) of this paragraph:<section prefix="1.">Visit the child at the child's placement and use appropriate technology to document the consultation for the record; or</section><section prefix="2.">Use video conferencing to consult with the child on the record during the hearing.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">If the court visits the child at the child's placement under subparagraph (i)1 of this paragraph or uses video conferencing under subparagraph (i)2 of this paragraph, the court shall give each party notice and an opportunity to attend the visit or the video conferencing, unless the court determines that it is not in the best interest of the child for a party to attend the visit or the video conferencing.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Subject to the provisions of paragraph (2)(ii) of this subsection, if the child's placement is outside the State and, after a hearing or with the agreement of all parties, the court determines that it is not in the best interest of the child to be transported to the court, the court may use video conferencing to consult with the child on the record during the hearing.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
