<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gcj" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="10-304" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcj-10-304</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Qualified medical person" means any person permitted by law to withdraw blood from humans.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Qualified person" means a person who has received training in the use of the equipment in a training program approved by the toxicologist under the Postmortem Examiners Commission and who is either a police officer, a police employee, an employee of the office of the Chief Medical Examiner, or a person authorized by the toxicologist under the Postmortem Examiners Commission.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The test of breath shall be administered by a qualified person with equipment approved by the toxicologist under the Postmortem Examiners Commission at the direction of a police officer.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The officer arresting the individual may not administer the test of breath.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The blood shall be obtained by a qualified medical person using equipment approved by the toxicologist under the Postmortem Examiners Commission acting at the request of a police officer.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">A certified statement by the qualified medical person who obtained the blood shall be prima facie evidence of that person's qualifications and that the blood was obtained in compliance with this section.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)"/>
        <section prefix="(iv)"/>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The test of blood shall be conducted by a qualified person using equipment approved by the toxicologist under the Postmortem Examiners Commission in a laboratory approved by the toxicologist.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">For the purpose of establishing that the test of breath or blood was administered with equipment approved by the toxicologist under the Postmortem Examiners Commission, a statement signed by the toxicologist certifying that the equipment used in the test has been approved by him shall be prima facie evidence of the approval, and the statement is admissible in evidence without the necessity of the toxicologist personally appearing in court.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">If a defendant desires the toxicologist to be present and testify at trial as a witness, the defendant shall file a request for a subpoena for the toxicologist at least 20 days before the trial in the appropriate court.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">If the District Court is deprived of jurisdiction under circumstances in which a defendant is entitled to and demands a jury trial, or appeals from the District Court to the circuit court, another subpoena must be filed at least 20 days before the trial in the circuit court.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">If a trial date is postponed for any reason beyond 30 days from the trial date for which the subpoena was issued, the defendant shall file a new subpoena for the toxicologist.</section>
        <section prefix="(iv)">In addition to the requirements of Maryland Rules 4-265 and 4-266, the subpoena shall contain the name, address, and telephone number of the defendant or the defendant's attorney.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A subpoena for the toxicologist may be quashed if a defendant fails to comply with the requirements of this subsection.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">A motion to quash a defendant's subpoena may be filed by any party or by the Attorney General.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The person tested is permitted to have a physician of the person's own choosing administer tests in addition to the one administered at the direction of the police officer, and in the event no test is offered or requested by the police officer, the person may request, and the officer shall have administered, one or more of the tests provided for in this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">Nothing in this section precludes the right to introduce any other competent evidence bearing upon the date of the certificate or change in the equipment since the date of the certificate.</section>
  </text>
</law>
