<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcj" order_by="" level="1">Courts and Judicial Proceedings</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcj-13-101</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>101</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">There is an Administrative Office of the Courts, headed by the State Court Administrator. The Administrator is appointed by and holds office during the pleasure of the Chief Judge of the Court of Appeals of Maryland. The Administrator shall have the compensation provided in the State budget. The Administrative Office of the Courts shall have a seal in the form the Chief Judge of the Court of Appeals approves. The courts of the State shall take judicial notice of the seal.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Subject to the approval of the Chief Judge of the Court of Appeals, the Administrator may appoint employees necessary to carry out his duties. The persons appointed shall have the compensation provided in the State budget.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Neither the Administrator nor any employee of the Administrative Office of the Courts may engage directly or indirectly in the practice of law.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The State Court Administrator, under the supervision and direction of the Chief Judge of the Court of Appeals of Maryland, shall:<section prefix="(1)">Examine the state of the dockets of the courts and determine the need for assistance by any court;</section><section prefix="(2)">Make recommendations to the Chief Judge relating to assignment of judges to courts in need of assistance and carry out the directions of the Chief Judge as to assignment of judges;</section><section prefix="(3)">Collect and compile statistical and other data, make reports of the business transacted by the courts, and transmit this information to the Chief Judge in order that action may be taken in respect to it;</section><section prefix="(4)">Prepare and submit budget estimates of State appropriations necessary for maintenance and operation of the judicial system and make recommendations in respect to it;</section><section prefix="(5)">Draw any requisition for payment of State money appropriated for maintenance and operation of the judicial system;</section><section prefix="(6)">Collect statistical and other data and make reports relating to expenditure of State and local public money for maintenance and operation of the judicial system and the offices connected to it;</section><section prefix="(7)">Obtain reports in accordance with law or rules the Court of Appeals or the Chief Judge adopts on cases and other judicial business in which action is delayed beyond periods of time specified by law or rules of court, and report the information to the Chief Judge;</section><section prefix="(8)">Formulate and submit to the Chief Judge recommendations for improvement of the judicial system;</section><section prefix="(9)">Make and publish an annual report of the affairs of the Administrator's Office;</section><section prefix="(10)">Design a citation form for citations to be issued under &#xA7; 3-8A-33 of this article and citations to be issued to a minor under &#xA7; 10-119 of the Criminal Law Article; and</section><section prefix="(11)">Perform other duties the Chief Judge assigns.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The Administrative Office of the Courts shall:<section prefix="(1)">Keep a current list of alcoholism education or treatment programs that the Department of Health and Mental Hygiene approves for use under &#xA7; 6-219(c) or &#xA7; 6-220(c) of the Criminal Procedure Article; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Notify promptly the appropriate judges whenever the Department of Health and Mental Hygiene approves a new alcoholism education or treatment program or withdraws approval for a program.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">Every judge, clerk of court, and any other State or local officer shall comply with any request approved by the Chief Judge of the Court of Appeals and made by the Administrator or any of his assistants for information and statistical data bearing on the state of the dockets of the courts, the business transacted by them, and the expenditure of public money for maintenance and operation of the judicial system.</section>
  </text>
</law>
