<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcj" order_by="" level="1">Courts and Judicial Proceedings</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcj-3-8A-23</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>23</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">An adjudication of a child pursuant to this subtitle is not a criminal conviction for any purpose and does not impose any of the civil disabilities ordinarily imposed by a criminal conviction.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">An adjudication and disposition of a child in which the child's driving privileges have been suspended may not affect the child's driving record or result in a point assessment. The State Motor Vehicle Administration may not disclose information concerning or relating to a suspension under this subtitle to any insurance company or person other than the child, the child's parent or guardian, the court, the child's attorney, a State's Attorney, or law enforcement agency.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Subject to paragraph (4) of this subsection, an adjudication of a child as delinquent by reason of the child's violation of the State vehicle laws, including a violation involving an unlawful taking or unauthorized use of a motor vehicle under &#xA7; 7-105 or &#xA7; 7-203 of the Criminal Law Article or &#xA7; 14-102 of the Transportation Article shall be reported by the clerk of the court to the Motor Vehicle Administration, which shall assess points against the child under Title 16, Subtitle 4 of the Transportation Article, in the same manner and to the same effect as if the child had been convicted of the offense.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">
        <section prefix="(i)">An adjudication of a child as delinquent by reason of the child's violation of &#xA7; 21-902 of the Transportation Article or a finding that a child has committed a delinquent act by reason of the child's violation of &#xA7; 21-902 of the Transportation Article, without an adjudication of the child as delinquent, shall be reported by the clerk of the court to the Motor Vehicle Administration which shall suspend the child's license to drive as provided in &#xA7; 16-206(b) of the Transportation Article:<section prefix="1.">For 1 year for a first adjudication as delinquent or finding of a delinquent act for a violation of &#xA7; 21-902 of the Transportation Article; and</section><section prefix="2.">For 2 years for a second or subsequent adjudication as delinquent or finding of a delinquent act for a violation of &#xA7; 21-902 of the Transportation Article.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">In the case of a finding, without an adjudication, that a child has violated &#xA7; 21-902 of the Transportation Article, the Motor Vehicle Administration shall retain the report in accordance with &#xA7; 16-117(b)(2) of the Transportation Article pertaining to records of licensees who receive a disposition of probation before judgment.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(5)">
        <section prefix="(i)">An adjudication of a child as delinquent by reason of the child's violation of &#xA7; 20-102, &#xA7; 20-103, or &#xA7; 21-904 of the Transportation Article or a finding that a child has committed a delinquent act by reason of the child's violation of &#xA7; 20-102, &#xA7; 20-103, or &#xA7; 21-904 of the Transportation Article, without an adjudication of the child as delinquent, shall be reported by the clerk of the court to the Motor Vehicle Administration that shall suspend the child's license to drive as provided in &#xA7; 16-206(b) of the Transportation Article:<section prefix="1.">For 6 months for a first adjudication as delinquent or finding of a delinquent act for a violation of &#xA7; 20-102, &#xA7; 20-103, or &#xA7; 21-904 of the Transportation Article; and</section><section prefix="2.">For 1 year for a second or subsequent adjudication as delinquent or finding of a delinquent act for a violation of &#xA7; 20-102, &#xA7; 20-103, or &#xA7; 21-904 of the Transportation Article.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">In the case of a finding, without an adjudication, that a child has violated &#xA7; 20-102, &#xA7; 20-103, or &#xA7; 21-904 of the Transportation Article, the Motor Vehicle Administration shall retain the report in accordance with &#xA7; 16-117(b)(2) of the Transportation Article pertaining to records of licensees who receive a disposition of probation before judgment.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">An adjudication and disposition of a child pursuant to this subtitle are not admissible as evidence against the child:<section prefix="(1)">In any criminal proceeding prior to conviction; or</section><section prefix="(2)">In any adjudicatory hearing on a petition alleging delinquency; or</section><section prefix="(3)">In any civil proceeding not conducted under this subtitle.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Evidence given in a proceeding under this subtitle is not admissible against the child in any other proceeding in another court, except in a criminal proceeding where the child is charged with perjury and the evidence is relevant to that charge and is otherwise admissible.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">An adjudication or disposition of a child under this subtitle shall not disqualify the child with respect to employment in the civil service of the State or any subdivision of the State.</section>
  </text>
</law>
