<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcj" order_by="gcj" level="1">Courts and Judicial Proceedings</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcj-3-812</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this section the following words have the meanings indicated, unless the context of their use ind...</catch_line>
  <order_by>812</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated, unless the context of their use indicates otherwise.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Crime of violence":<section prefix="(i)">Has the meaning stated in &#xA7; 14-101 of the Criminal Law Article; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">As to a crime committed in another state, means a crime that, if committed in this State, would be a crime of violence as defined in &#xA7; 14-101 of the Criminal Law Article.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Torture" means to cause intense pain to body or mind for purposes of punishment or extraction of information or for sadistic purposes.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">In a petition under this subtitle, a local department may ask the court to find that reasonable efforts to reunify a child with the child's parent or guardian are not required if the local department concludes that a parent or guardian has:<section prefix="(1)">Subjected the child to:<section prefix="(i)">Chronic abuse;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Chronic and life-threatening neglect;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Sexual abuse; or</section><section prefix="(iv)">Torture;</section></section><section prefix="(2)">Been convicted, in any state or any court of the United States, of:<section prefix="(i)">A crime of violence against:<section prefix="1.">A minor offspring of the parent or guardian;</section><section prefix="2.">The child; or</section><section prefix="3.">Another parent or guardian of the child; or</section></section><section prefix="(ii)">Aiding or abetting, conspiring, or soliciting to commit a crime described in subitem (i) of this item; or</section></section><section prefix="(3)">Involuntarily lost parental rights of a sibling of a child.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">If the local department determines after the initial petition is filed that any of the circumstances specified in subsection (b) of this section exists, the local department may immediately request the court to find that reasonable efforts to reunify the child with the child's parent or guardian are not required.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">If the court finds by clear and convincing evidence that any of the circumstances specified in subsection (b) of this section exists, the court shall waive the requirement that reasonable efforts be made to reunify the child with the child's parent or guardian.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">If the court finds that reasonable efforts are not required, the local department shall:<section prefix="(1)">Request that a permanency planning hearing be held in accordance with &#xA7; 3-823 of this subtitle within 30 days after the court makes the finding; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Make reasonable efforts to place the child in a timely manner in accordance with the permanency plan and complete the steps necessary to finalize the permanent placement of the child.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">If a parent consents to guardianship or adoption in accordance with &#xA7; 5-320 or &#xA7; 5-338 of the Family Law Article, loss of parental rights shall be considered voluntary.</section>
  </text>
</law>
