<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcj" order_by="" level="1">Courts and Judicial Proceedings</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcj-3-805</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>805</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A petition alleging that a child is a CINA shall be filed in the county where:<section prefix="(i)">The child is residing when the petition is filed; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">The act on which the petition is based allegedly occurred.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A voluntary placement petition shall be filed in the county where the parent or legal guardian resides.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Whenever a petition is filed other than in the county where the child resides, the court, on its own motion or on motion of a party, may transfer the case at any time to any appropriate county, including a county where:<section prefix="(i)">Another case involving custody, visitation, or support of the child is pending;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The child resides;</section><section prefix="(iii)">A parent of the child resides; or</section><section prefix="(iv)">The court determines it is in the child's best interests for further proceedings concerning the child to take place.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Before the court transfers a case to another court in the State, the court shall communicate with the juvenile judge of the other court or the judge's designee.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The court shall advise the parties of the decision made to transfer the case and the basis for the decision.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Before the court transfers a case to a court outside the State, the court shall communicate with the other court in accordance with the Maryland Uniform Child Custody Jurisdiction Act.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Within 15 days after the court orders a transfer, the clerk of the sending court shall forward to the receiving court every document on file with the sending court.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">If a case is transferred to another court in this State, the receiving court shall treat the case as if it had been filed with that court initially and shall set hearing dates as close as practicable to those set forth in any pending orders issued by the sending court.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">If information about a child is alleged to be available in another jurisdiction in or outside of this State, the court, on its own motion or on motion of a party, may use the provisions of the Maryland Uniform Child Custody Jurisdiction Act to obtain that information.</section>
  </text>
</law>
