<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcj" order_by="gcj" level="1">Courts and Judicial Proceedings</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcj-5-109</section_number>
  <catch_line>An action for damages for an injury arising out of the rendering of or failure to render professiona...</catch_line>
  <order_by>109</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">An action for damages for an injury arising out of the rendering of or failure to render professional services by a health care provider, as defined in &#xA7; 3-2A-01 of this article, shall be filed within the earlier of:<section prefix="(1)">Five years of the time the injury was committed; or</section><section prefix="(2)">Three years of the date the injury was discovered.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Except as provided in subsection (c) of this section, if the claimant was under the age of 11 years at the time the injury was committed, the time limitations prescribed in subsection (a) of this section shall commence when the claimant reaches the age of 11 years.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The provisions of subsection (b) of this section may not be applied to an action for damages for an injury:<section prefix="(i)">To the reproductive system of the claimant; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">Caused by a foreign object negligently left in the claimant's body.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">In an action for damages for an injury described in this subsection, if the claimant was under the age of 16 years at the time the injury was committed, the time limitations prescribed in subsection (a) of this section shall commence when the claimant reaches the age of 16 years.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">For the purposes of this section, the filing of a claim with the Health Care Alternative Dispute Resolution Office in accordance with &#xA7; 3-2A-04 of this article shall be deemed the filing of an action.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The provisions of &#xA7; 5-201 of this title that relate to a cause of action of a minor may not be construed as limiting the application of subsection (b) or (c) of this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">Nothing contained in this section may be construed as limiting the application of the provisions of:<section prefix="(1)">&#xA7; 5-201 of this title that relate to a cause of action of a mental incompetent; or</section><section prefix="(2)">&#xA7; 5-203 of this title.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
