<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gcj" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="2-309" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcj-2-309</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The sheriff of a county and his deputies shall receive the annual salaries provided by this section for performing the duties required of them by the Constitution and the laws of this State. They shall be reimbursed for expenses as provided by law.</section>
    <section prefix="(a-1)">The government of each county shall furnish an office for the sheriff and pay the necessary expenses for telephones, stationery and for other purposes, and unless otherwise provided by law, shall provide for the necessary traveling expenses of the sheriff for conveying prisoners to any penal institution in the State and other necessary traveling expenses.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Sheriff of Allegany County shall receive the salary set by the County Commissioners in accordance with Article 24, Title 12, Subtitle 1 of the Code.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Sheriff shall appoint not less than five deputies at salaries of at least $2,400 each who are under the county classified service; one of these deputies shall be assigned by the Sheriff to execute process, orders, and directions for the juvenile court, and to perform the other duties the Sheriff assigns.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A deputy sheriff is entitled to free meals while on duty in addition to the salary provided in this subsection.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">If authorized by the County Commissioners, the Sheriff may employ a clerk-bookkeeper under the county classified service at a salary agreed upon by the Sheriff and the County Commissioners. The clerk-bookkeeper shall perform the duties assigned by the Sheriff, including the preparation of reports submitted by the Sheriff's Office to the grand jury or the County Commissioners.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">If the Sheriff of Allegany County approves after considering personnel needs, the County Commissioners may authorize a deputy sheriff to perform off-duty services for any person who agrees to pay a fee, including but not limited to, hourly rates for off-duty service, any necessary insurance to be determined by the Commissioners, including any fringe benefits and the reasonable rental cost of uniforms or other equipment used by any off-duty personnel.</section>
      <section prefix="(6)">The Sheriff, with the approval of the County Commissioners, may appoint a chief deputy sheriff who shall perform all legal functions of the Sheriff during any temporary absence, sickness, vacation, or vacancy of Office of the Sheriff. The Sheriff may appoint as chief deputy a person who has not served as a deputy sheriff. The chief deputy sheriff shall serve at the Sheriff's pleasure, and is not under the county classified service.</section>
      <section prefix="(7)">
        <section prefix="(i)">This subsection does not apply to officers in the Sheriff's Office at a rank of lieutenant or above.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">Deputies, officers, and civilian employees of the Sheriff's Office, including the Allegany County jail, have the right to organize and bargain collectively with the Sheriff concerning wages and benefits, hours, working conditions, discipline procedures, and job security issues through a labor organization selected by the majority of the deputies, officers, and civilian employees.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">The Sheriff shall meet with the labor organization and engage in good faith negotiations to reach a written agreement on wages and benefits, hours, working conditions, discipline procedures, and job security issues.</section>
        <section prefix="(iv)">If the labor organization and the Sheriff are unable to reach an agreement during the collective bargaining process, either the labor organization or the Sheriff may seek nonbinding mediation through the Federal Mediation and Conciliation Service by giving at least 15 days notice to the other party and to the Federal Mediation and Conciliation Service.</section>
        <section prefix="(v)"/>
        <section prefix="(vi)">This subsection may not be construed to authorize an employee of the Sheriff's Office or of the Allegany County jail to engage in a strike.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Sheriff of Anne Arundel County shall receive a salary equal to the salary of a captain in the Anne Arundel County Police Department at the highest rate in the pay scale.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The Sheriff of Anne Arundel County shall appoint deputies at a salary as provided by the County Council.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The Sheriff may appoint a chief deputy who shall serve at the pleasure of the Sheriff.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Employees in the Sheriff's Office shall be in the county merit system.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">In case of emergency, the Sheriff may temporarily deputize any able-bodied citizen to assist the Sheriff in carrying out the duties of the Sheriff's Office.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">The Sheriff and the deputies whose duties require the use of automobiles shall be furnished at no expense with suitable automobiles and any necessary maintenance, repairs or upkeep by the County Council.</section>
      <section prefix="(6)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The Sheriff may appoint part-time deputies as provided in the county budget.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">A part-time deputy appointed under this paragraph may not work more than 24 hours per week.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">The Sheriff may set the rate of pay for a part-time deputy.</section>
        <section prefix="(iv)">A part-time deputy appointed under this paragraph is not eligible for any benefits that are provided to county employees, including pension benefits, unless approved by the County Council.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">In Baltimore City, the Sheriff shall receive an expense allowance of $750 two times per year and a salary of:</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The Sheriff:</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)"/>
        <section prefix="(iv)">In addition to any other compensation received, each deputy sheriff shall receive an expense allowance of $200 annually for:</section>
        <section prefix="(v)">A deputy sheriff who uses a personal automobile is entitled to a monthly automobile allowance at the same rate paid to other State employees. Any Sheriff who is assigned a city-owned automobile may not receive the monthly automobile expense allowance.</section>
        <section prefix="(vi)">The Sheriff's Office shall also have assistants at the compensation provided for in the annual ordinance of estimates of Baltimore City. Provisions shall also be made in the ordinance for the expenses of the Office of the Sheriff, including the purchase and maintenance of motor vehicles.</section>
        <section prefix="(vii)">The Mayor and City Council of Baltimore have the same power with respect to the salaries of the Office of the Sheriff as they have under the city charter with respect to the salaries of all municipal departments.</section>
        <section prefix="(viii)">Employees of the Sheriff's Office, except the Sheriff, shall be selected according to the provisions of the State Personnel and Pensions Article.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Mayor and City Council shall pay monthly to the Sheriff of Baltimore City one twelfth of the amount provided in the ordinance of estimates for the expenses of the Sheriff's Office. Within 30 days after June 30th in each and every year the Sheriff of Baltimore City shall pay to the Mayor and City Council of Baltimore any of the unexpended expense funds advanced during the preceding year and render a detailed account to the Mayor and City Council of Baltimore of all expense funds received and expended by him. The Mayor and City Council of Baltimore shall reimburse the State of Maryland for the administrative costs incurred because the employees of the Sheriff's Office of Baltimore City are in the State Personnel Management System.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">During the course of his employment, any deputy sheriff of Baltimore City may ride in Baltimore City on public transportation of the Maryland Transit Administration without paying any fare if he shows proper identification regarding his position as a deputy sheriff.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Sheriff of Baltimore County shall receive an annual salary of:<section prefix="(i)">$75,000 for calendar year 2007;</section><section prefix="(ii)">$80,000 for calendar year 2008;</section><section prefix="(iii)">$85,000 for calendar year 2009; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">$90,000 for calendar year 2010 and each subsequent calendar year.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Sheriff shall appoint an under-sheriff and any number of deputies and any clerical assistant required by the duties of the office. The Sheriff may also appoint a number of deputies to the ranks of chief deputy, captain, lieutenant, and sergeant as his duties and responsibilities require. The cost and expense of these supervisory, administrative, and clerical positions, including salaries, shall be as provided in the budget of the county by the County Executive and as approved by the County Council. All full-time employees under this subsection are subject to the provisions of the county merit system and the rules and regulations passed by the County Council pursuant to the charter, as to qualifications, compensation, and other regulations. Part-time deputies may not be employed by the Sheriff's Office. However, the Sheriff may appoint as part-time deputies persons employed in specific plants, institutions, colleges, and hospitals situated within Baltimore County who are limited to service only within the particular facility where they are employed, and who may not be compensated by Baltimore County for their services.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">This paragraph applies to all full-time deputy sheriffs in the Baltimore County Sheriff's Office at the rank of lieutenant and below.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)"/>
        <section prefix="(iii)"/>
        <section prefix="(iv)"/>
        <section prefix="(v)"/>
        <section prefix="(vi)">Nothing in this paragraph may be construed as authorizing or otherwise allowing a deputy sheriff to engage in a strike as defined in &#xA7; 3-303 of the State Personnel and Pensions Article.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The Sheriff of Calvert County shall receive an annual salary of:</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)"/>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Sheriff may appoint deputy sheriffs in the number and at the salary approved by the County Commissioners. The deputy sheriffs shall serve under the direction of the Sheriff. Within one year of their appointment, they shall complete the course prescribed for police officers by the Maryland Police Training Commission. The deputy sheriffs funded by the County Commissioners will become merit system employees of the Calvert County Sheriff's Office upon completion of their initial probation period and may not be dismissed without cause, except the deputy sheriffs funded through grants or other sources may be dismissed without cause when the funding source is depleted. There may be no honorary deputy sheriffs of Calvert County and no one is authorized to carry badges, certificates, or other materials for the purpose of identifying the bearer as an honorary deputy sheriff. However, the Sheriff may appoint as special deputy sheriffs any members of the police force of the towns of North Beach or Chesapeake Beach who shall have all of the powers and authority of the deputy sheriffs. The County Commissioners are authorized to reimburse the towns of North Beach and Chesapeake Beach in whole or in part for services performed by the special deputy sheriffs outside the town limits.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The Sheriff may appoint 1 full-time assistant sheriff who shall:</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The Sheriff shall appoint an individual to serve as the assistant sheriff who:</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)"/>
        <section prefix="(iv)"/>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(4)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Except as provided in subparagraph (ii) of this paragraph, any Sheriff of Calvert County who, since 1948, has served for three or more terms shall receive a pension when he leaves office in the annual amount of $150 for each year served. This pension shall be paid not less frequently than once a month.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">This paragraph does not apply to a term of office that begins on or after July 1, 1988.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(5)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The County Commissioners of Calvert County may provide in their annual budget for a pension to be paid to the surviving spouse, if any, of any Sheriff of Calvert County who was in office as of October 1970.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The pension shall be in the amount of $250 a month and shall be paid to the surviving spouse, if any, for the life of that surviving spouse.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(6)">
        <section prefix="(i)">This paragraph applies to an individual who:</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">An individual described in subparagraph (i) of this paragraph may participate in the Calvert County Employees' Savings Plan.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Sheriff of Caroline County shall receive an annual salary of $80,000.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The sheriff may appoint:</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The sheriff may not refuse to reappoint a deputy sheriff without just cause.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(h)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Sheriff of Carroll County shall receive an annual salary as follows:<section prefix="(i)">$71,532 beginning December 5, 2006;</section><section prefix="(ii)">$72,963 beginning December 4, 2007;</section><section prefix="(iii)">$74,422 beginning December 9, 2008; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">$75,910 beginning December 8, 2009, and thereafter.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Sheriff may employ the number of personnel necessary for the proper execution of the duties of office. Personnel shall receive the compensation set by the County Commissioners.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Personnel employed by the Sheriff shall be placed on a probationary status and may be dismissed by the Sheriff for any reason. After the probationary period, personnel may only be disciplined or dismissed for just cause:<section prefix="(i)">In accordance with the Law Enforcement Officers' Bill of Rights, if the employee's rights are covered under this bill of rights; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">In accordance with the personnel rules and regulations of the Carroll County Sheriff's Office, if the employee's rights are not covered under the Law Enforcement Officers' Bill of Rights.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">Except for an appeal taken pursuant to the Law Enforcement Officers' Bill of Rights, an appeal by an aggrieved party shall be taken to the Circuit Court for Carroll County.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">The Sheriff may also appoint a chief deputy and a warden who shall serve at the pleasure of the Sheriff.</section>
      <section prefix="(6)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Subject to subparagraph (ii) of this paragraph, the Sheriff of Carroll County may appoint special deputy sheriffs who are:</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The appointment of special deputy sheriffs under subparagraph (i) of this paragraph is subject to the following conditions:</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(i)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The Sheriff of Cecil County shall receive an annual salary of:</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">In addition, the Sheriff shall receive the benefits and reimbursements for reasonable expenses in the performance of duties as provided in the Cecil County budget or by law, including, where appropriate:</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)"/>
        <section prefix="(iv)">The Sheriff shall appoint full-time or part-time employees, as provided in the county budget, to perform the duties of the Sheriff's department. These employees shall include:</section>
        <section prefix="(v)">Except for the chief deputy sheriff, each employee of the Sheriff's department shall serve a probationary period of 12 months. The Sheriff may extend the probationary period for cause.</section>
        <section prefix="(vi)">During the probationary period of an employee in the Sheriff's department:</section>
        <section prefix="(vii)">Except for the chief deputy sheriff, community adult rehabilitation center administrator, detention center director, detention center deputy director, law enforcement director, law enforcement personnel, and personal secretary to the Sheriff, all employees of the Sheriff's department:</section>
        <section prefix="(viii)">Law enforcement officers and correctional officers of the Sheriff's department may be terminated only for just cause.</section>
        <section prefix="(ix)">Nothing in this subsection shall affect the rights and protections accorded an employee under any other provision of law.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The County Commissioners shall pay the cost of all necessary expenses incurred by the Sheriff and his staff.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Sheriff of Cecil County shall have the authority to formulate and administer a plan that includes the method of supervision to use inmates the Sheriff deems eligible and selects to perform, under the supervision of State, county, or municipal employees, tasks the Sheriff assigns within the county or any incorporated municipality within the county.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">
        <section prefix="(i)">This paragraph applies only to all full-time sworn law enforcement deputy sheriffs in the Office of the Sheriff of Cecil County at the rank of Sergeant and below.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">A full-time sworn law enforcement deputy sheriff at the rank of Sergeant and below may:</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)"/>
        <section prefix="(iv)"/>
        <section prefix="(v)"/>
        <section prefix="(vi)">Nothing in this paragraph may be construed to:</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(j)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The salary for the Sheriff of Charles County is equal to the salary of a Department of State Police lieutenant colonel, at the highest available step for a lieutenant colonel under the Department of State Police pay plan in effect on the day prior to the day that the Sheriff begins a term of office.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Any change in the salary paid under the Department of State Police pay plan during the term of Office of the Sheriff may not apply to the incumbent Sheriff, but the changed rate shall take effect at the beginning of the next following term of office.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Sheriff, in accordance with rules and regulations developed by the Board of County Commissioners and the Sheriff, shall appoint the number of deputy sheriffs that the Board of County Commissioners of Charles County and the Sheriff consider necessary.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The books of the Sheriff shall be audited annually, and copies of the audit published by the County Commissioners in local newspapers.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">
        <section prefix="(i)">This paragraph applies to all full-time, merit system sworn law enforcement officers and correctional officers in the Charles County Sheriff's Office at a rank of sergeant or below.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">This paragraph does not apply to the following employees in the Charles County Sheriff's Office:</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)"/>
        <section prefix="(iv)">The Sheriff and the Office of the Sheriff for Charles County, through their appropriate officers and employees, may:</section>
        <section prefix="(v)"/>
        <section prefix="(vi)"/>
        <section prefix="(vii)">To the extent that any matters negotiated between the Sheriff and the collective bargaining unit require legislative approval or the appropriation of funds, the matters shall be recommended to the General Assembly for the approval of legislation or to the County Commissioners for the appropriation of funds.</section>
        <section prefix="(viii)">An agreement is not valid if it extends for less than 1 year or for more than 2 years.</section>
        <section prefix="(ix)"/>
        <section prefix="(x)">This paragraph does not authorize a sworn law enforcement officer or correctional officer to engage in a strike as defined in &#xA7; 3-303 of the State Personnel and Pensions Article.</section>
        <section prefix="(xi)">Nothing in this paragraph shall be construed as subjecting disciplinary matters or the disciplinary process to negotiation as part of the collective bargaining process.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(k)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The Sheriff of Dorchester County shall receive an annual salary of:</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">For calendar year 2015 and thereafter, the Sheriff of Dorchester County shall receive the same annual salary as paid in 2014.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">The Sheriff of Dorchester County shall be allowed the actual operating costs of the Sheriff's Office, including the maintenance of automobiles.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The Sheriff shall appoint a chief deputy sheriff, or the managerial equivalent, who shall serve at the pleasure of the Sheriff.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">If an employee of the Sheriff's Office is appointed as chief deputy sheriff and is subsequently removed from the chief deputy sheriff's position for other than cause, the person may resume the employment status held prior to the appointment to the chief deputy sheriff's position.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">The chief deputy sheriff shall:</section>
        <section prefix="(iv)">If the Sheriff becomes incapacitated and the position of chief deputy sheriff is vacant, the County Council shall appoint an acting chief deputy sheriff to serve until the Sheriff is reactivated or replaced.</section>
        <section prefix="(v)">The County Council shall approve the salary of the chief deputy sheriff.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The Sheriff may appoint probationary deputy sheriffs, deputy sheriffs, investigators, communications officers, secretaries, supervisors, administrators, and other staff as approved in the county budget.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The County Council shall approve the salaries for all staff appointed by the Sheriff.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">The Sheriff may not refuse to reappoint a deputy sheriff without just cause.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(l)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Sheriff of Frederick County shall receive a salary of $100,000. The Sheriff shall appoint deputies as necessary, at salaries of at least $2,400, and jail wardens as necessary, at salaries of at least $1,320 each. The Sheriff also may appoint additional temporary deputy sheriffs as the Sheriff considers necessary for the public safety, with the approval of the Board of County Commissioners. The County Commissioners shall allow reasonable compensation for the temporary additional deputy sheriffs and the temporary deputies may not serve longer than the occasion requires. The Sheriff may appoint a chief deputy who shall serve at the pleasure of the Sheriff.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Any deputy sheriff, with the exception of the chief deputy, appointed according to this section shall be placed on a probationary status for at least 18 months of continuous employment and may be dismissed by the Sheriff for any reason during the probationary period.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">All full-time civilian employees are subject to the county personnel regulations with regard to qualifications for hiring, promotion, compensation and disciplinary action. All deputy sheriffs, except the chief deputy, are subject to the county personnel regulations with regard to qualifications for hiring, promotion and compensation with regard to matters not covered by the Law Enforcement Officers' Bill of Rights.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The Sheriff of Frederick County may appoint special deputy sheriffs who are:</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The appointment of special deputy sheriffs under this paragraph is subject to the following conditions:</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(5)">
        <section prefix="(i)">This paragraph applies to all full-time deputy sheriffs in the Frederick County Sheriff's Office at the rank of sergeant and below.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)"/>
        <section prefix="(iii)"/>
        <section prefix="(iv)"/>
        <section prefix="(v)"/>
        <section prefix="(vi)">Nothing in this paragraph may be construed as authorizing or otherwise allowing a deputy sheriff to engage in a strike as defined in &#xA7; 3-303 of the State Personnel and Pensions Article.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(6)">
        <section prefix="(i)">This paragraph applies to all full-time correctional officers in the Frederick County Sheriff's Office at the rank of sergeant and below.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)"/>
        <section prefix="(iii)"/>
        <section prefix="(iv)"/>
        <section prefix="(v)"/>
        <section prefix="(vi)">Nothing in this paragraph may be construed as authorizing or otherwise allowing a correctional officer to engage in a strike as defined in &#xA7; 3-303 of the State Personnel and Pensions Article.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(m)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The Sheriff of Garrett County shall receive:</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The Sheriff is entitled to a sum set by the County Commissioners, for expenses.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Sheriff shall employ deputies as needed, within the budgetary limits, at salaries of at least $5,200 each, one of whom shall act as warden of the jail, and a matron for the jail who shall also perform clerical duties at the salary set by the Sheriff. The Sheriff may employ additional special deputies whose compensation shall be approved by the County Commissioners.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Sheriff and the deputy sheriffs shall be allowed extra car mileage and out-of-county mileage at the rate of 14 cents per mile. This mileage allowance shall not be payable if the Sheriff's Office is furnished with automobiles.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The Sheriff shall be reimbursed for the expenses of boarding prisoners committed to the county jail, to be paid monthly upon vouchers submitted by him to the County Commissioners of Garrett County. He shall also submit with these vouchers an affidavit sworn to by him upon personal knowledge showing for each day of the month just passed the number of prisoners boarded by him. The Sheriff may appoint a cook for the jail who shall receive a salary of at least $2,400. The Sheriff, deputies, and cook shall each receive an additional allowance of $200 per year for uniforms and cleaning.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">
        <section prefix="(i)">This paragraph does not apply to the Sheriff or chief deputy sheriff.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">Deputy sheriffs and other employees of the Sheriff's Office are included in the Garrett County classified service system.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(n)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The Sheriff of Harford County shall receive a salary of:</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)"/>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Sheriff may not have employment outside of that position unless:<section prefix="(i)">The employment is a part-time teaching position; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">The total maximum yearly income from the outside employment under this paragraph is $2,500 or less.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Sheriff shall appoint the number of deputies at the compensation provided in the county budget.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The Sheriff may appoint as a special deputy sheriff:<section prefix="(i)">The chief of police of a Harford County municipality; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">A member of the police force of a Harford County municipality who is certified by the Maryland Police Training Commission.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(5)">A special deputy sheriff appointed under this subsection is not an employee of the Sheriff or of Harford County.</section>
      <section prefix="(6)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Except as provided in subparagraph (ii) of this paragraph, an employee of the Harford County Sheriff's Office may not be terminated without just cause.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">Subparagraph (i) of this paragraph does not apply to:</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(7)">
        <section prefix="(i)">A lieutenant colonel or major serves at the pleasure of the Sheriff.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">A lieutenant colonel, major, or captain may not be reduced below the rank of lieutenant without just cause.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(8)">The Sheriff of Harford County shall have the authority to formulate and administer a plan that includes the method of supervision to use inmates from the Harford County Detention Center the Sheriff deems eligible and selects to perform, under the supervision of State, county, or municipal employees, tasks the Sheriff assigns within the county or any incorporated municipality within the county.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(o)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The Sheriff of Howard County shall receive an annual salary as follows:</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The Sheriff shall appoint the number of deputies authorized by the county government. The compensation of the deputies shall be set by the county government.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Each full-time deputy sheriff at the rank of lieutenant or below appointed by the Sheriff on or after October 1, 2005:</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The Sheriff may extend the probationary period for reasonable cause.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">During the probationary period, the Sheriff has exclusive discretion to determine whether a probationary deputy sheriff has the qualifications and ability to serve in the position of a permanent nonprobationary employee.</section>
        <section prefix="(iv)">Each probationary deputy sheriff shall be required to complete the minimum number of hours mandated for law enforcement agencies established by the Maryland Police Training Commission.</section>
        <section prefix="(v)">After the probationary period, a full-time deputy sheriff at a rank of lieutenant or below may be disciplined or dismissed only for just cause:</section>
        <section prefix="(vi)">Except for an appeal taken pursuant to the Law Enforcement Officers' Bill of Rights, an appeal by an aggrieved party shall be taken to the Circuit Court for Howard County.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Sheriff may appoint additional temporary deputy sheriffs when necessary for the public safety and the county government shall allow them reasonable compensation. These deputies may not serve longer than the case actually requires.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The primary duties of the Sheriff are the following:<section prefix="(i)">The security of the circuit court, and the performance of such duties as may be required of the Sheriff by that court;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The service of process of writs, summonses, orders, petitions, subpoenas, warrants, orders to show cause, and other legal papers; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Additional duties, including law enforcement as may be requested by law enforcement or other criminal justice agencies, the circuit court, or the county government, when necessary for the public safety.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(5)">
        <section prefix="(i)">This paragraph applies only to full-time deputy sheriffs in the Office of the Sheriff of Howard County at the rank of corporal and below.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">A deputy sheriff may:</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)"/>
        <section prefix="(iv)"/>
        <section prefix="(v)"/>
        <section prefix="(vi)">Nothing in this paragraph may be construed to:</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(p)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Sheriff of Kent County shall receive a salary of:<section prefix="(i)">$67,000 for the calendar year 2009;</section><section prefix="(ii)">$68,000 for the calendar year 2010;</section><section prefix="(iii)">$82,000 for the calendar year 2011;</section><section prefix="(iv)">$83,000 for the calendar year 2012;</section><section prefix="(v)">$84,000 for the calendar year 2013; and</section><section prefix="(vi)">$85,000 for the calendar year 2014 and each calendar year thereafter.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">At the discretion of the County Commissioners, the Sheriff shall receive county-owned automobiles as may be necessary to operate the Sheriff's department.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The Sheriff shall appoint a chief deputy sheriff, or the managerial equivalent, who shall:</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The Sheriff may not refuse to reappoint a deputy sheriff without just cause.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The Sheriff and the Sheriff's deputies shall be paid allowances as the Commissioners may deem necessary.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">The County Commissioners may authorize additional deputies as necessary and shall set their compensation at the time of their appointment.</section>
      <section prefix="(6)">The County Commissioners may authorize the Sheriff to appoint as part-time deputies individuals employed in specific plants, schools, hospitals, institutions, business enterprises, and land development tracts situated within Kent County who are limited to service only within the particular facility where they are employed, and who may not be compensated by Kent County for their services.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(q)">
      <section prefix="(1)">It is the intent of the General Assembly to:<section prefix="(i)">Protect the right to bargain of the Montgomery County Executive and the Montgomery County Sheriff;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Preserve a single master collective bargaining agreement to the extent that a single exclusive bargaining representative represents multiple units of employees covered under the Montgomery County Collective Bargaining Law; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Streamline, facilitate, and make more effective the collective bargaining process by ensuring that there shall be a single collective bargaining agreement with both the Montgomery County government and the Montgomery County Sheriff's Office if a single exclusive bargaining representative represents both Montgomery County government employees and Montgomery County Sheriff employees.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Sheriff of Montgomery County shall receive a salary, subject to &#xA7; 35 of Article III of the Maryland Constitution, and an allowance for expenses, as the County Council provides in its annual budget. The County Council shall provide an automobile for the use of the Sheriff and his deputies for the general public work of the office and the expense of operating the automobile shall be paid by the county.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The Sheriff may appoint 2 full-time assistant sheriffs and the number of deputies provided in the county budget.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The Sheriff shall also appoint the other clerical and administrative employees provided in the county budget, all of whom shall be paid by the county.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)"/>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(4)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The Sheriff shall fix the compensation of, and may discharge, the deputy sheriffs, and other employees appointed, subject to budget limitations, the Montgomery County merit system law, personnel regulations, or applicable collective bargaining agreement. The Sheriff shall fix the compensation of the assistant sheriffs subject to budget limitations.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">Except for the assistant sheriffs, personnel appointed by the Sheriff shall be considered for all purposes as Montgomery County merit system employees and subject to the Montgomery County merit system law, personnel regulations, and applicable collective bargaining agreement. Assistant sheriffs shall serve at the pleasure of the Sheriff and shall meet the qualifications of the Maryland Police Training Commission standards for law enforcement officers.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)"/>
        <section prefix="(iv)">Any required funding for the terms of an agreement negotiated by the Sheriff under subparagraph (iii) of this paragraph is subject to the budget and fiscal policies of Montgomery County.</section>
        <section prefix="(v)">Except as provided in the Montgomery County merit system law and personnel regulations, the provisions of subparagraph (iii) of this paragraph and any agreement made under it may not impair the right and responsibility of the Sheriff to:</section>
        <section prefix="(vi)"/>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(5)">Deputy sheriffs are not entitled to any additional compensation for rendering services incident to their office. The County Council shall levy and collect annual taxes on the assessable property in the county in an amount sufficient to pay the salaries and allowances of the Sheriff and the Sheriff's deputies.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(r)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Sheriff of Prince George's County shall:<section prefix="(i)">Receive an annual salary of:</section><section prefix="(ii)">Be provided with an automobile during the term as Sheriff for the use and work of the Sheriff's Office, with adequate maintenance and insurance for the automobile to be at the cost of the county; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Receive not more than $5,000 per year for expenses incurred in performing the duties of Sheriff, including training and education, an accounting of which shall be submitted to the County Director of Finance for approval.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The Sheriff of Prince George's County shall be provided with 4 full-time assistant sheriffs, and all assistant sheriffs shall be selected and appointed by the Sheriff and serve at the Sheriff's pleasure. One of the assistant sheriffs shall be appointed as the chief assistant sheriff. The assistant sheriffs shall be considered line officers, if so designated by the Sheriff.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">Each assistant sheriff shall:</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">Each assistant sheriff may participate in the supplemental retirement program provided to deputy sheriffs by the county.</section>
        <section prefix="(iv)">The assistant sheriffs shall devote their full time and attention to the Office of Sheriff.</section>
        <section prefix="(v)">Except as provided in subparagraph (vi) of this paragraph, the chief assistant sheriff shall receive an annual salary of $71,091.</section>
        <section prefix="(vi)">The salary of a commissioned deputy sheriff appointed to the position of chief assistant sheriff shall be provided for by the Sheriff in the budget of the county.</section>
        <section prefix="(vii)">The Sheriff and the assistant sheriffs shall be provided with an annual clothing allowance equal to that which is provided to deputy sheriffs of all ranks for the procurement, care, and upkeep of clothing and leather goods, and administered for that purpose.</section>
        <section prefix="(viii)"/>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">In addition to the assistant sheriffs, the Sheriff of Prince George's County shall be provided with the number of full-time employees, including civilian employees and commissioned deputy sheriffs, as is deemed necessary and appropriate to carry out the duties and discharge of the Sheriff's Office. The cost and expense of the positions of the full-time employees, including the salaries, shall be provided for in the budget of the county.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">All full-time civilian employees shall be subject to the county personnel law. Civilian employees shall have the right to organize and bargain collectively. Civilian employees shall be subject to the Prince George's County Labor Code with regard to collective bargaining for compensation, including pension and fringe benefits, hours, and terms and conditions of employment. The County Executive shall be considered the employer of the civilian employees only for the purpose of collective bargaining for compensation, including pension and fringe benefits, and hours. The Sheriff shall be considered the employer for purposes of collective bargaining for other terms and conditions of employment. However, any required funding for a collective bargaining agreement negotiated by the Sheriff shall be subject to the approval of the County Executive.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">With the exception of the assistant sheriffs, all full-time deputy sheriffs of all ranks, provided for the Sheriff in the budget of the county, upon commencement of any position in the Sheriff's department may be required by the Sheriff to serve a probationary period of 12 months. The probationary period may be extended by the Sheriff for reasonable cause. During the probationary period, the determination of the employee's qualifications and ability to serve in the position of a permanent, nonprobationary employee shall be within the exclusive discretion of the Sheriff. All probationary commissioned deputy sheriffs shall be required to complete the minimum number of hours as mandated to other law enforcement agencies, as set by the Maryland Police Training Commission.</section>
      <section prefix="(6)">
        <section prefix="(i)">With the exception of the assistant sheriffs, all commissioned full-time employees, including deputy sheriffs of all ranks and court security officers, that are provided for by the Sheriff in the budget of the county, shall be subject to the county personnel law.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">Except as provided in subparagraph (iii) of this paragraph, the assistant sheriffs shall receive an annual salary of $69,888.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">The salary of commissioned deputy sheriffs serving as assistant sheriffs shall be provided for by the Sheriff in the budget of the county.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(7)">All nonprobationary commissioned full-time employees, including deputy sheriffs of all ranks, are subject to the Law Enforcement Officers' Bill of Rights. All commissioned full-time employees, including deputy sheriffs of all ranks and court security officers, are also subject to the Labor Code of the county with regard to collective bargaining for compensation, including pension and other fringe benefits, hours, and terms and conditions of employment. The County Executive shall be considered the "employer" of the deputy sheriffs and court security officers only for the purpose of collective bargaining for compensation, including pension and fringe benefits, and hours. The Sheriff shall be considered the employer for purposes of collective bargaining for other terms and conditions of employment. However, any required funding for a collective bargaining agreement negotiated by the Sheriff shall be subject to the approval of the County Executive.</section>
      <section prefix="(8)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The Sheriff and the Sheriff's deputies shall be limited in their duties as law enforcement officers, as follows:</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)"/>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(9)">Neither the Sheriff of Prince George's County nor any of the Sheriff's deputies shall conduct criminal investigations, except:<section prefix="(i)">In matters concerning the Sheriff's department;</section><section prefix="(ii)">On request of the courts;</section><section prefix="(iii)">As necessary for the administration and enforcement of casino night permits as authorized by the county governing body; or</section><section prefix="(iv)">In investigations arising out of or incident to normally assigned duties, including those duties authorized by the county governing body under paragraph (8)(i)6 of this subsection.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(10)">When a Sheriff or Sheriff's deputy has commenced an investigation under paragraph (9)(iv) of this subsection, the Sheriff or the Sheriff's deputy:<section prefix="(i)">Shall immediately notify the appropriate law enforcement agency that has jurisdiction over the matter; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Shall transfer the investigation to an appropriate law enforcement agency that has jurisdiction over the matter on request of the agency.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(s)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The Sheriff of Queen Anne's County shall receive a salary set by the County Commissioners of at least $10,000.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The Sheriff shall appoint a chief deputy sheriff or the managerial equivalent, who shall:</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)"/>
        <section prefix="(iv)">The Commissioners may appoint an assistant deputy sheriff, at a salary set by the County Commissioners of at least $4,200.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The salaries are in lieu of all expenses, fees, costs, and charges, except for the board and keeping of prisoners in the county jail and other necessary operating expenses allowed by law or practice, including all expenses for transferring persons to and from penal institutions, places of confinement and State institutions in the State under sentence or order of an authority.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(t)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The annual salary of the Sheriff of St. Mary's County shall be:<section prefix="(i)">$76,000 for the calendar year 2007;</section><section prefix="(ii)">$78,000 for the calendar year 2008;</section><section prefix="(iii)">$80,000 for the calendar year 2009; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">$82,000 for the calendar year 2010.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Sheriff shall devote full time to the duties of office.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(u)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The Sheriff of Somerset County shall receive a salary of not less than $60,000 and no expense allowance.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">He shall appoint a chief deputy who shall receive a salary of not less than $7,500.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">Subject to the approval of the County Commissioners, the Sheriff may appoint additional deputies at the compensation set by the County Commissioners prior to any appointment.</section>
        <section prefix="(iv)">Deputy sheriffs serve under the direction of the Sheriff.</section>
        <section prefix="(v)">Deputy sheriffs are required, within 1 year after their appointment, to complete successfully the course that the Maryland Police Training Commission prescribes for police officers.</section>
        <section prefix="(vi)"/>
        <section prefix="(vii)">The County Commissioners may appoint a jail warden as the county jailer. Prior to the appointment of any individual, the County Commissioners shall establish an annual rate of compensation for the county jailer.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Sheriff and his deputies may wear uniforms when performing their official duties, and the automobiles used by the Sheriff's Office shall be equipped with a two-way radio.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The County Commissioners may pay for the uniforms, radios, automobiles, and operating expenses of the automobiles of the Sheriff's Office.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(v)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Sheriff of Talbot County shall receive a salary as set by the County Council.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Sheriff may appoint, subject to the approval of the County Council, the number of deputies the Sheriff deems necessary at the compensation fixed by the County Council prior to the appointment.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Sheriff may appoint a chief deputy sheriff, or the managerial equivalent, who shall serve at the pleasure of the Sheriff.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The Sheriff may not refuse to reappoint a deputy sheriff without just cause.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">The Sheriff's Office shall be operated on a 24-hour daily basis.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(w)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The Sheriff of Washington County shall receive a salary of $88,000.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The Sheriff shall appoint a chief deputy at a salary level set by the County Commissioners.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">The Sheriff may appoint deputy sheriffs and other personnel necessary to perform the duties of office at salary levels set by the County Commissioners in accordance with the county's budgetary process.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Any deputy sheriff appointed according to this subsection shall be placed on a probationary status for the first two years of his employment, and may be dismissed by the Sheriff for any reason during that probationary period.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">At the conclusion of continuous employment for two years, a deputy sheriff having the rank of major or below has tenure, and may be discharged by the Sheriff only for misfeasance, malfeasance, nonfeasance, or insubordination in office.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">If the Sheriff of Washington County approves after considering personnel needs, the County Commissioners may authorize a deputy sheriff to perform off-duty services for any person who agrees to pay a fee, including but not limited to, hourly rates for off-duty service, any necessary insurance to be determined by the Commissioners, including any fringe benefits and the reasonable rental cost of uniforms or other equipment used by any off-duty personnel.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The Sheriff of Washington County may appoint special deputy sheriffs, including members of the police force of a Washington County municipality who are:</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The appointment of special deputy sheriffs is subject to the following conditions:</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(x)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The Sheriff of Wicomico County shall receive a salary of the greater of:</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The Sheriff shall appoint a chief deputy at a salary set by the Wicomico County Council, payable in equal monthly installments. The chief deputy's term of office coincides with the Sheriff's and he may be removed by the Sheriff at any time. The Sheriff may appoint additional deputies as he and the County Council of Wicomico County deem necessary, each of whom shall receive the compensation prescribed by the personnel rules and regulations of the county.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Sheriff of Wicomico County shall be allowed an additional amount to defray all expenses of his office, including necessary automobile mileage allowance at the rate of at least 6 cents per mile for automobiles used by him and his deputies in performing their official duties. However, mileage shall not be allowed if automobiles are furnished to the Sheriff by the County Council. Necessary expenses for telephone and telegraph, and clerical assistants will be allowed if approved by the County Council.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Sheriff shall submit properly authenticated requisitions containing a full and complete statement under oath setting forth all of the expenses for a month, including the names of all deputies and assistants, the amounts allowed to each and all other items of expense. These sums are in lieu of all expenses, fees and costs now or heretofore allowed the Sheriff for expense in carrying out the duties of his office, including the expenses of transferring prisoners to and from penal institutions and places of confinement in the State under the sentence or order of any authority. The County Council shall not pay the Sheriff additional compensation for any services he renders in discharging his official duties. The County Council is not liable for any other fee or compensation to the Sheriff.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The County Council shall levy each year sufficient funds to pay the salaries and expenses of the Sheriff's Office.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">All deputies, except the chief deputy, clerical assistant, and other employees employed are subject to the "personnel provisions" of the charter of Wicomico County and subsequent rules and regulations passed by the County Council. If a deputy subject to the personnel provisions is promoted to chief deputy, then on his removal from the office of chief deputy for other than cause, he shall revert to a deputy with the same status which he had prior to his appointment as chief deputy. A chief deputy who is not a deputy subject to the personnel provisions prior to his appointment as chief deputy, if removed from office for any reason shall not automatically revert to a deputy.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(y)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The Sheriff of Worcester County shall receive an annual salary as set by the County Commissioners of at least $85,000.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The Sheriff shall appoint at least one chief deputy sheriff and as many deputy sheriffs and other personnel as are necessary to perform the duties of the office and are provided for in the county budget.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The County Commissioners of Worcester County shall pay all necessary expenses of the operation of the Sheriff's Office through the county budget adopted in accordance with all applicable laws and budget procedures and subject to all applicable budget reviews.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The chief deputy sheriff shall serve at the pleasure of the Sheriff.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">If a chief deputy sheriff who was a Worcester County deputy sheriff prior to being appointed as chief deputy is removed from the office of chief deputy for other than cause, that person shall revert to a deputy sheriff with the same status that the person had prior to the person's appointment as chief deputy.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">If a chief deputy sheriff who was not a Worcester County deputy sheriff prior to being appointed as chief deputy is removed from the office of chief deputy for any reason, that person may not automatically revert to a deputy sheriff after being removed as chief deputy.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(4)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Except as provided in this subsection, the personnel rules and regulations of Worcester County as adopted by the County Commissioners shall apply to all employees of the Sheriff of Worcester County other than the chief deputy sheriff, including deputy sheriffs, clerks, typists, animal control officers, and other necessary personnel.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The appointment, disciplinary, and managerial functions of the County Commissioners as provided for in the personnel rules and regulations of Worcester County shall be performed by the Sheriff in the case of all employees of the Sheriff's Office.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(5)">The Sheriff may adopt Sheriff's Office manuals,  additional rules of conduct, dress, and decorum, and other procedures that shall apply to all employees and shall be conditions of employment with the Sheriff's Office.</section>
      <section prefix="(6)">An employee of the Sheriff's Office other than the chief deputy sheriff or a probationary employee may be disciplined or terminated for cause only in accordance with the provisions of this subsection, the regulations referred to in this subsection, or the Law Enforcement Officers' Bill of Rights.</section>
      <section prefix="(7)">When a new Sheriff takes office, or at the beginning of a new term of office of a Sheriff, all deputies other than the chief deputy and all other employees in good standing shall remain in their positions and shall be considered reappointed or redeputized, subject to the provisions of this subsection and to the extent required. A Sheriff may not refuse to reappoint and redeputize a deputy sheriff without cause.</section>
      <section prefix="(8)">At the request of the Sheriff, the County Commissioners may provide in-kind support to the Sheriff relating to personnel matters.</section>
      <section prefix="(9)">The Sheriff shall have complete control over the employees of the Sheriff's Office, subject only to the provisions of this subsection and the reasonable application of the personnel rules and regulations of Worcester County and the protections and benefits those policies provide.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(z)">A deputy sheriff shall perform the duties incidental to the office as are assigned to him by the Sheriff. All salaries shall be paid at least once each month.</section>
  </text>
</law>
