<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcj" order_by="gcj" level="1">Courts and Judicial Proceedings</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcj-3-2A-06D</section_number>
  <catch_line>This section applies only to an initial complaint filed on or after January 1, 2005, for which a cer...</catch_line>
  <order_by>06D</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This section applies only to an initial complaint filed on or after January 1, 2005, for which a certificate of a qualified expert is required to be filed in accordance with &#xA7; 3-2A-04 of this subtitle.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">This section does not apply if the defendant admits liability.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Within 15 days after the date that discovery is required to be completed, a party shall file with the court a supplemental certificate of a qualified expert, for each defendant, that attests to:<section prefix="(i)">The certifying expert's basis for alleging what is the specific standard of care;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The certifying expert's qualifications to testify to the specific standard of care;</section><section prefix="(iii)">The specific standard of care;</section><section prefix="(iv)">For the plaintiff:<section prefix="1.">The specific injury complained of;</section><section prefix="2.">How the specific standard of care was breached;</section><section prefix="3.">What specifically the defendant should have done to meet the specific standard of care; and</section><section prefix="4.">The inference that the breach of the standard of care proximately caused the plaintiff's injury; and</section></section><section prefix="(v)">For the defendant:<section prefix="1.">How the defendant complied with the specific standard of care;</section><section prefix="2.">What the defendant did to meet the specific standard of care; and</section><section prefix="3.">If applicable, that the breach of the standard of care did not proximately cause the plaintiff's injury.</section></section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">An extension of the time allowed for filing a supplemental certificate under this section shall be granted for good cause shown.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The facts required to be included in the supplemental certificate of a qualified expert shall be considered necessary to show entitlement to relief sought by a plaintiff or to raise a defense by a defendant.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Subject to the provisions of this section:<section prefix="(1)">If a plaintiff fails to file a supplemental certificate of a qualified expert for a defendant, on motion of the defendant the court may dismiss, without prejudice, the action as to that defendant; or</section><section prefix="(2)">If the defendant fails to file a supplemental certificate of a qualified expert, on motion of the plaintiff the court may adjudicate in favor of the plaintiff on the issue of liability as to that defendant.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Maryland Rules apply to filing and serving a copy of a certificate required under this section and in motions relating to a violation of this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Nothing contained in this section prohibits or limits a party from moving for summary judgment in accordance with the Maryland Rules.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">For purposes of the certification requirements of this section:<section prefix="(1)">A party may not serve as a party's expert; and</section><section prefix="(2)">The certificate may not be signed by:<section prefix="(i)">A party;</section><section prefix="(ii)">An employee or partner of a party; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">An employee or stockholder of any professional corporation of which the party is a stockholder.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The clerk of the court shall forward to the Department of Health and Mental Hygiene copies of the certificates filed under this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">In the case of a complaint against a physician, the Department of Health and Mental Hygiene shall forward to the State Board of Physicians copies of the supplemental certificate of a qualified expert filed under this section.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
