<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcj" order_by="gcj" level="1">Courts and Judicial Proceedings</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcj-5-518</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this section the following words have the meanings indicated....</catch_line>
  <order_by>518</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Compensation" does not include actual and necessary expenses that are incurred by a volunteer in connection with the services provided or duties performed by the volunteer for a county board of education, and that are reimbursed to the volunteer or otherwise paid.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"County board employee" means:<section prefix="(i)">Any employee whose compensation is paid in whole or in part by a county board of education; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">A student teacher.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">"County board member" means a duly elected or appointed member of a county board of education.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">"Volunteer" means an individual who, at the request of the county board and under its control and direction, provides services or performs duties for the county board without compensation.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A county board of education, described under Title 4, Subtitle 1 of the Education Article, may raise the defense of sovereign immunity to any amount claimed above the limit of its insurance policy or, if self-insured or a member of a pool described under &#xA7; 4-105(c)(1)(ii) of the Education Article, above $100,000.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A county board of education may not raise the defense of sovereign immunity to any claim of $100,000 or less.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The county board shall be joined as a party to an action against a county board employee, county board member, or volunteer that alleges damages resulting from a tortious act or omission committed by the employee in the scope of employment, by the county board member within the scope of the member's authority, or by the volunteer within the scope of the volunteer's services or duties.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The issue of whether the county board employee acted within the scope of employment may be litigated separately.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The issue of whether the county board member acted within the scope of the member's authority may be litigated separately.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The issue of whether the volunteer acted within the scope of the volunteer's services or duties may be litigated separately.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">A county board employee acting within the scope of employment, without malice and gross negligence, is not personally liable for damages resulting from a tortious act or omission for which a limitation of liability is provided for the county board under subsection (b) of this section, including damages that exceed the limitation on the county board's liability.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A county board member, acting within the scope of the member's authority, without malice and gross negligence, is not personally liable for damages resulting from a tortious act or omission for which a limitation of liability is provided for the county board under subsection (b) of this section, including damages that exceed the limitation on the county board's liability.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">In addition to the immunity provided under paragraph (1) of this subsection, a county board member is immune as an individual from civil liability for any act or omission if the member is acting:<section prefix="(i)">Within the scope of the member's authority;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Without malice; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">In a discretionary capacity.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The provisions of this subsection apply only to a volunteer.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A volunteer who acts within the scope of the volunteer's services or duties is not personally liable for damages resulting from a tortious act or omission beyond the limits of any personal insurance the volunteer may have unless:<section prefix="(i)">The damages were the result of the volunteer's negligent operation of a motor vehicle; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">The damages were the result of the volunteer's willful, wanton, malicious, reckless, or grossly negligent act or omission.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The limitations on liability contained in this subsection may not be construed or applied to affect any immunities from civil liability or defenses established by any other provision of the Code or available at common law to which the volunteer may be entitled.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(h)">Except as provided in subsection (e), (f), or (g) of this section, a judgment in tort for damages against a county board employee acting within the scope of employment, a county board member acting within the scope of the member's authority, or a volunteer acting within the scope of the volunteer's services or duties shall be levied against the county board only and may not be executed against the county board employee, the county board member, or the volunteer personally.</section>
  </text>
</law>
