<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcj" order_by="gcj" level="1">Courts and Judicial Proceedings</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcj-3-822</section_number>
  <catch_line>At each CINA hearing, the court shall inquire into, and make findings of fact on the record as to, t...</catch_line>
  <order_by>822</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">At each CINA hearing, the court shall inquire into, and make findings of fact on the record as to, the identity and current address of each parent of each child before the court.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">In carrying out paragraph (1) of this subsection, the court shall:<section prefix="(i)">Inform all parties present of their continuing obligation to assist the court in identifying and locating each parent of each child;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Inform the parents present of their continuing obligation to keep the clerk of the court apprised of their current address;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Inform the parents present of available means to establish paternity, if not yet established; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">If appropriate, refer the parents to the appropriate support enforcement agency to establish paternity and support.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Each parent of a child who is the subject of a CINA proceeding shall notify the court and the local department of all changes in the parent's address.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The clerk of the court shall keep a listing of every address provided by a parent of a child who is the subject of a CINA proceeding.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">On request of a local department, the clerk's office shall disclose to the local department all addresses listed by a parent of a CINA within the preceding 270 days.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The court may:<section prefix="(1)">Order a parent or putative parent to:<section prefix="(i)">Apply for child support services with the appropriate support enforcement agency; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Cooperate with the appropriate support enforcement agency to establish paternity and child support; and</section></section><section prefix="(2)">Make a finding of paternity in accordance with Title 5, Subtitle 10, Part VI of the Family Law Article.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">Any court may consider evidence taken and findings made on the record in a CINA hearing and in a paternity, custody, child support, or guardianship proceeding regarding that child or a sibling of a child.</section>
  </text>
</law>
