<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcj" order_by="" level="1">Courts and Judicial Proceedings</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcj-3-2A-01</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>01</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this subtitle the following terms have the meanings indicated unless the context of their use requires otherwise.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Arbitration panel" means the arbitrators selected to determine a health care malpractice claim in accordance with this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Court" means a circuit court for a county.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">"Director" means the Director of the Health Care Alternative Dispute Resolution Office.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"Economic damages" retains its judicially determined meaning.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Health care provider" means a hospital, a related institution as defined in &#xA7; 19-301 of the Health - General Article, a medical day care center, a hospice care program, an assisted living program, a freestanding ambulatory care facility as defined in &#xA7; 19-3B-01 of the Health - General Article, a physician, an osteopath, an optometrist, a chiropractor, a registered or licensed practical nurse, a dentist, a podiatrist, a psychologist, a licensed certified social worker-clinical, and a physical therapist, licensed or authorized to provide one or more health care services in Maryland.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Health care provider" does not include any nursing institution conducted by and for those who rely upon treatment by spiritual means through prayer alone in accordance with the tenets and practices of a recognized church or religious denomination.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">"Medical injury" means injury arising or resulting from the rendering or failure to render health care.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">"Noneconomic damages" means:<section prefix="(1)">In a claim for personal injury, pain, suffering, inconvenience, physical impairment, disfigurement, loss of consortium, or other nonpecuniary injury; or</section><section prefix="(2)">In a claim for wrongful death, mental anguish, emotional pain and suffering, loss of society, companionship, comfort, protection, care, marital care, parental care, filial care, attention, advice, counsel, training, guidance, or education, or other noneconomic damages authorized under Subtitle 9 of this title.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
