<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcj" order_by="" level="1">Courts and Judicial Proceedings</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcj-10-4A-06</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>06</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Supervisory official" means:<section prefix="(i)">The Secretary or Deputy Secretary of State Police;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The chief of police, deputy chief of police, or equivalent official of a law enforcement agency of any political subdivision of the State;</section><section prefix="(iii)">The Attorney General of the State or a Deputy Attorney General;</section><section prefix="(iv)">The State Prosecutor or Deputy State Prosecutor; or</section><section prefix="(v)">A State's Attorney or Deputy State's Attorney.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Adverse result" means:<section prefix="(i)">Endangering the life or physical safety of an individual;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Flight from prosecution;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Destruction of or tampering with evidence;</section><section prefix="(iv)">Intimidation of potential witnesses; or</section><section prefix="(v)">Otherwise seriously jeopardizing an investigation or unduly delaying a trial.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">An investigative or law enforcement officer acting under &#xA7; 10-4A-04 of this subtitle may:<section prefix="(1)">If a court order is sought, include in the application a request for an order delaying the notification required under &#xA7; 10-4A-05 of this subtitle for a period not to exceed 90 days, which the court shall grant, if the court determines that there is reason to believe that notification of the existence of the court order may have an adverse result; or</section><section prefix="(2)">If a subpoena issued by a court of competent jurisdiction or a grand jury subpoena is obtained, delay the notification required under &#xA7; 10-4A-05 of this subtitle for a period not to exceed 90 days, upon the execution of a written certification to a court of competent jurisdiction by a supervisory official that there is reason to believe that notification of the existence of the subpoena may have an adverse result.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The investigative or law enforcement officer shall maintain a true copy of a certification executed under subsection (b)(2) of this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Extensions of a delay in notification may be granted by the court upon application or by certification by a supervisory official under subsection (b) of this section. An extension may not exceed 90 days.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">Upon expiration of the period of a delay of notification under subsection (b) or (d) of this section, the investigative or law enforcement officer shall serve upon, or deliver by registered or first-class mail, to the customer or subscriber a copy of the process or request together with a notice that:<section prefix="(1)">States with reasonable specificity the nature of the law enforcement inquiry; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Informs the customer or subscriber:<section prefix="(i)">That information maintained for the customer or subscriber by the service provider named in the process or request was supplied to or requested by that investigative or law enforcement officer and the date on which the information was supplied or the request was made;</section><section prefix="(ii)">That notification of the customer or subscriber was delayed;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Of the identity of the investigative or law enforcement officer or court that made the certification or determination authorizing the delay; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">Of the statutory authority for the delay.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">If notice to the subscriber is not required under &#xA7; 10-4A-04(b)(1) of this subtitle or if notice is delayed under subsection (b) or (d) of this section, an investigative or law enforcement officer acting under &#xA7; 10-4A-04 of this subtitle may apply to a court for an order requiring a provider of electronic communications service or remote computing service to whom a warrant, subpoena, or court order is directed, for such period as the court deems appropriate, not to notify any other person of the existence of the warrant, subpoena, or court order. The court shall enter an order under this subsection if the court determines that there is reason to believe that notification of the existence of the warrant, subpoena, or court order will have an adverse result.</section>
  </text>
</law>
