<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcj" order_by="gcj" level="1">Courts and Judicial Proceedings</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcj-12-401</section_number>
  <catch_line>A party in a civil case may appeal from a final judgment entered in the District Court....</catch_line>
  <order_by>401</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">A party in a civil case may appeal from a final judgment entered in the District Court.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">In a criminal case:<section prefix="(1)">The State may appeal from a final judgment entered in the District Court:<section prefix="(i)">If the State alleges that the trial judge failed to impose the sentence specifically mandated by the Code; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">Granting a motion to dismiss, or quashing or dismissing a charging document.</section></section><section prefix="(2)">The defendant may appeal even from a final judgment entered in the District Court though imposition or execution of sentence has been suspended.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, an appeal taken under subsection (b)(1)(ii) of this section shall be:<section prefix="(1)">To the circuit court solely for the purpose of reviewing the judgment of the District Court; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Heard on the record made in the District Court.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A defendant who has been found guilty of a municipal infraction, as defined in Article 23A, &#xA7; 3(b)(1) of the Code or a Code violation under &#xA7; 10-119 of the Criminal Law Article, may appeal from the final judgment entered in the District Court.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The costs and procedures for taking the appeal shall be as provided for appeals from criminal cases in the District Court.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Except, however, as provided in subsection (f) of this section, the appellate court shall docket and hear the appeal as a civil appeal from the District Court.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, an appeal shall be taken by filing an order for appeal with the clerk of the District Court within 30 days from the date of the final judgment from which appealed.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If the final judgment was entered in a case filed under &#xA7; 8-332, &#xA7; 8-401, &#xA7; 8-402, &#xA7; 14-109, or &#xA7; 14-120 of the Real Property Article, the order for appeal shall be filed within the time prescribed by the particular section.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">In a civil case in which the amount in controversy exceeds $5,000 exclusive of interest, costs, and attorney's fees if attorney's fees are recoverable by law or contract, in any matter arising under &#xA7; 4-401(7)(ii) of this article, and in any case in which the parties so agree, an appeal shall be heard on the record made in the District Court. In every other case, including a criminal case in which sentence has been imposed or suspended following a plea of nolo contendere or guilty, and an appeal in a municipal infraction or Code violation case, an appeal shall be tried de novo.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">In a criminal appeal that is tried de novo:<section prefix="(1)">There is no right to a jury trial unless the offense charged is subject to a penalty of imprisonment or unless there is a constitutional right to a jury trial for that offense; and</section><section prefix="(2)">On the filing of a notice of appeal, the circuit court may stay a sentence of imprisonment imposed by the District Court and release the defendant pending trial in the circuit court.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
