<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcj" order_by="" level="1">Courts and Judicial Proceedings</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcj-9-124</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>124</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Employee" means an individual represented by a labor organization regardless of whether the individual is a member of the labor organization.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Labor organization" means an organization that represents or seeks to represent workers for the purposes of collective bargaining.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in subsection (c) or (d) of this section, a labor organization or an agent of a labor organization may not be compelled to disclose any communication or information the labor organization or agent received or acquired in confidence from an employee while the labor organization or agent was acting in a representative capacity concerning an employee grievance.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Paragraph (1) of this subsection does not apply to a criminal proceeding.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">An employee's privilege under this subsection applies only to the extent that:<section prefix="(i)">A communication or information is germane to a grievance of the employee; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">The grievance of the employee is a subject matter of an investigation, a grievance proceeding, or a civil court, administrative, arbitration, or other civil proceeding.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">An employee's privilege under this subsection continues after termination of:<section prefix="(i)">The employee's employment; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">The representative relationship of the labor organization or its agent with the employee.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(5)">An employee's privilege under this subsection protects the communication or information received or acquired by the labor organization or its agent, but does not protect the employee from being compelled to disclose, to the extent provided by law, the facts underlying the communication or information.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A labor organization or its agent shall disclose to the employer as soon as possible a communication or information described in subsection (b)(1) of this section to the extent the labor organization or its agent reasonably believes necessary to prevent certain death or substantial bodily harm.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A labor organization or its agent may disclose a communication or information described in subsection (b) of this section:<section prefix="(1)">To the extent the labor organization or its agent reasonably believes necessary to:<section prefix="(i)">Prevent the employee from committing a crime, fraud, or any act in violation of a collective bargaining agreement or contractual agreement that is reasonably certain to result in substantial injury to the financial interests or property of another and in furtherance of which the employee has used or is using the services of the labor organization or its agent;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Prevent, mitigate, or rectify substantial injury to the financial interests or property of another that is reasonably certain to result or has resulted from the employee's commission of a crime, fraud, or any act in violation of a collective bargaining agreement or contractual agreement in furtherance of which the employee has used the services of the labor organization or its agent;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Secure legal advice about the compliance of the labor organization or its agent with a court order or other law or the terms of a collective bargaining agreement or contractual agreement;</section><section prefix="(iv)">Establish a claim or defense on behalf of the labor organization or its agent in a controversy between the employee and the labor organization or its agent, to establish a defense to a criminal charge or civil claim against the labor organization or its agent based on conduct in which the employee was involved, or to respond to allegations in any proceeding concerning the performance of professional duties by the labor organization or its agent on behalf of the employee; or</section><section prefix="(v)">Comply with a court order or other law or the terms of a collective bargaining agreement or contractual agreement;</section></section><section prefix="(2)">To the extent the communication or information constitutes an admission that the employee has committed a crime;</section><section prefix="(3)">In any court, administrative, arbitration, or other proceeding against:<section prefix="(i)">The agent of the labor organization in the agent's personal or official representative capacity; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">The labor organization, any affiliated or subordinate body of the labor organization, or any agent of the labor organization or its affiliated or subordinate body;</section></section><section prefix="(4)">If the labor organization has obtained the written or oral consent of the employee;</section><section prefix="(5)">If the employee is deceased or has been adjudicated incompetent by a court of competent jurisdiction and the labor organization has obtained the written or oral consent of the personal representative of the employee's estate or of the employee's guardian;</section><section prefix="(6)">When required by court order; or</section><section prefix="(7)">To the extent that the employee waives the confidentiality of the communication or information.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">An adverse inference may not be drawn based on the refusal of a labor organization or an agent of a labor organization to disclose a communication or any information under subsection (d)(3) of this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">In the event of a conflict between the application of this section and any federal or State labor law, the provisions of the federal or State law shall control.</section>
  </text>
</law>
