<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gcj" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="5-406" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcj-5-406</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">"Agent of an association or organization" means a director, officer, trustee, employee, or volunteer of an association or organization who provides services or performs duties on behalf of the association or organization.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">"Agent of an association or organization" does not include an independent contractor who provides services or performs duties on behalf of the association or organization on a contractual basis.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Association or organization" means:<section prefix="(i)">An athletic club;</section><section prefix="(ii)">A charitable organization;</section><section prefix="(iii)">A civic league or organization;</section><section prefix="(iv)">A community association;</section><section prefix="(v)">A cooperative housing corporation as that term is defined under &#xA7; 5-6B-01 of the Corporations and Associations Article;</section><section prefix="(vi)">A council of unit owners of a condominium as that term is defined in &#xA7; 11-101 of the Real Property Article; or</section><section prefix="(vii)">A homeowners' association.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">"Athletic club" means a club organized and operated exclusively for recreational purposes that is exempt from taxation under &#xA7; 501(c)(7) of the Internal Revenue Code.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">"Charitable organization" means an organization, institution, association, society, or corporation that is exempt from taxation under &#xA7; 501(c)(3) of the Internal Revenue Code.</section>
      <section prefix="(6)">"Civic league or organization" means an organization, operated exclusively for the promotion of social welfare, that is exempt from taxation under &#xA7; 501(c)(4) of the Internal Revenue Code.</section>
      <section prefix="(7)">"Community association" means a nonprofit association, corporation, or other organization that registers with the Secretary of State under &#xA7; 7-108 of the State Government Article and:<section prefix="(i)"/><section prefix="(ii)"/><section prefix="(iii)"/></section>
      <section prefix="(8)">"Compensation" does not include actual and necessary expenses that are incurred by a volunteer in connection with the services provided or duties performed by the volunteer on behalf of an association or organization, and that are reimbursed to the volunteer or otherwise paid.</section>
      <section prefix="(9)">"Homeowners' association" means a nonprofit association, corporation, or other organization comprised of property owners in a subdivision or group of subdivisions whose purpose is to represent the mutual interests of the property owners regarding the construction, protection, and maintenance of the commonly owned or used property and improvements.</section>
      <section prefix="(10)">"Suit" means any civil action, except any health care malpractice action, brought against an agent of an association or organization or against the association or organization by virtue of the agent's act or omission in providing services or performing duties on behalf of the association or organization.</section>
      <section prefix="(11)">"Volunteer" means an officer, director, trustee, or other person who provides services or performs duties on behalf of an association or organization without receiving compensation.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Except as provided in subsection (d) of this section, an agent of an association or organization is not personally liable for damages in any suit if:<section prefix="(1)">The association or organization maintains insurance covering liability incurred by the association or organization or its agents, or both, as a result of the acts or omissions of its agents in providing services or performing duties on behalf of the association or organization;</section><section prefix="(2)">The terms of the insurance policy under which the insurance is maintained provide coverage for the act or omission which is the subject matter of the suit and no meritorious basis exists for the denial of the coverage by the insurance carrier; and</section><section prefix="(3)">The insurance has:<section prefix="(i)">A limit of coverage of not less than:</section><section prefix="(ii)"/></section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">In suits to which the provisions of subsection (b) of this section apply, the plaintiff may recover damages from the association or organization only to the extent of the applicable limit of insurance coverage including any amount for which the association or organization is responsible as a result of any deductible or coinsurance provisions of such insurance coverage.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">An agent of an association or organization shall be liable for damages in any suit in which it is found that the agent acted with malice or gross negligence, to the extent that the judgment for damages exceeds the limits on liability under subsection (c) of this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The provisions of this section do not apply to suits brought by the Attorney General upon referral by the Secretary of State in which willful violations of Title 6 of the Business Regulation Article are alleged and proven.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This section does not create, and may not be construed as creating, a new cause of action or substantive legal right against an association or organization or an agent of an association or organization.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">This section does not affect, and may not be construed as affecting, any immunities from civil liability or defenses established by any other provision of the Code or available at common law, to which an association or organization or an agent of an association or organization may be entitled.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">This section may be cited as the Maryland Associations, Organizations, and Agents Act.</section>
  </text>
</law>
