<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcj" order_by="gcj" level="1">Courts and Judicial Proceedings</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcj-12-702</section_number>
  <catch_line>If an appellate court remands a criminal case to a lower court in order that the lower court may pro...</catch_line>
  <order_by>702</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">If an appellate court remands a criminal case to a lower court in order that the lower court may pronounce the proper judgment or sentence, the lower court shall deduct from the term of the new sentence the time served by the defendant under the previous sentence from the date of his conviction. If the previous sentence was a statutory maximum sentence, the lower court also shall give credit for any period of incarceration prior to the previous sentence, if the incarceration was related to the offense for which the sentence was imposed.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">If an appellate court remands a criminal case to a lower court in order that the lower court may pronounce the proper judgment or sentence, or conduct a new trial, and if there is a conviction following this new trial, the lower court may impose any sentence authorized by law to be imposed as punishment for the offense. However, it may not impose a sentence more severe than the sentence previously imposed for the offense unless:<section prefix="(1)">The reasons for the increased sentence affirmatively appear;</section><section prefix="(2)">The reasons are based upon additional objective information concerning identifiable conduct on the part of the defendant; and</section><section prefix="(3)">The factual data upon which the increased sentence is based appears as part of the record.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">If a defendant who appeals from a conviction in the District Court is convicted after a trial de novo on appeal, the appellate court may impose a more severe sentence than that imposed in the District Court, but if the case is one in which the defendant was denied a jury trial under &#xA7; 4-302(e)(2) of this article, the sentence may not be for more than 90 days except under the conditions prescribed in subsection (b) of this section. Except as provided above, the appellate court may impose any sentence authorized by law to be imposed as punishment for the offense.</section>
  </text>
</law>
