<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcj" order_by="gcj" level="1">Courts and Judicial Proceedings</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcj-10-4A-08</section_number>
  <catch_line>Except as provided in &#xA7; 10-4A-04(e) of this subtitle, a provider of electronic communication servic...</catch_line>
  <order_by>08</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Except as provided in &#xA7; 10-4A-04(e) of this subtitle, a provider of electronic communication service, subscriber, or customer aggrieved by a knowing or intentional violation of this subtitle may recover appropriate relief in a civil action against the person or entity that engaged in the violation.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">In a civil action under this section, appropriate relief includes:<section prefix="(1)">Appropriate preliminary and other equitable or declaratory relief;</section><section prefix="(2)">Damages under subsection (c) of this section; and</section><section prefix="(3)">A reasonable attorney's fee and other litigation costs reasonably incurred.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The court may assess as damages in a civil action under this section the sum of the actual damages suffered by the plaintiff and any profits made by the violator as a result of the violation, but in no case shall a person entitled to recover receive less than $1,000.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A good faith reliance on any of the following is a complete defense to any civil or criminal action brought under this subtitle or any other State law:<section prefix="(1)">A court warrant or order, a grand jury subpoena, a legislative authorization, or a statutory authorization; or</section><section prefix="(2)">A good faith determination that &#xA7; 10-402(d) of this title permitted the conduct that is the subject of the action.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">A civil action under this section shall be filed within 2 years after the day on which the claimant first discovered or had a reasonable opportunity to discover the violation.</section>
  </text>
</law>
