<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcj" order_by="gcj" level="1">Courts and Judicial Proceedings</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcj-10-4A-02</section_number>
  <catch_line>Except as provided in subsection (c) of this section, a person may not obtain, alter, or prevent aut...</catch_line>
  <order_by>02</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Except as provided in subsection (c) of this section, a person may not obtain, alter, or prevent authorized access to a wire or electronic communication while it is in electronic storage in an electronic communications system by:<section prefix="(1)">Intentionally accessing without authorization a facility through which an electronic communication service is provided; or</section><section prefix="(2)">Intentionally exceeding an authorization to access a facility through which an electronic communication service is provided.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A person who violates the provisions of subsection (a) of this section is subject to the following penalties:<section prefix="(1)">If the offense is committed for purposes of commercial advantage, malicious destruction or damage, or private commercial gain:<section prefix="(i)">For a first offense, a fine of not more than $250,000 or imprisonment for not more than 1 year, or both; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">For a second or subsequent offense, a fine of not more than $250,000 or imprisonment for not more than 2 years, or both; or</section></section><section prefix="(2)">In any other case, a fine of not more than $5,000 or imprisonment for not more than 6 months, or both.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Subsection (a) of this section does not apply to conduct authorized:<section prefix="(1)">By the person or entity providing a wire or electronic communications service;</section><section prefix="(2)">By a user of a wire or electronic communications service with respect to a communication of or intended for that user; or</section><section prefix="(3)">Under the provisions of this subtitle.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
