<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gcj" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="10-704" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcj-10-704</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">A foreign judgment is not conclusive if:<section prefix="(1)">The judgment was rendered under a system which does not provide impartial tribunals or procedures compatible with the requirements of due process of law;</section><section prefix="(2)">The foreign court did not have personal jurisdiction over the defendant;</section><section prefix="(3)">The foreign court did not have jurisdiction over the subject matter; or</section><section prefix="(4)">The judgment was obtained by fraud.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A foreign judgment need not be recognized if:<section prefix="(1)">The defendant in the proceedings in the foreign court did not receive notice of the proceedings in sufficient time to enable him to defend;</section><section prefix="(2)">The cause of action on which the judgment is based is repugnant to the public policy of the State;</section><section prefix="(3)">The judgment conflicts with another final and conclusive judgment;</section><section prefix="(4)">The proceeding in the foreign court was contrary to an agreement between the parties under which the dispute was to be settled out of court; or</section><section prefix="(5)">In the case of jurisdiction based only on personal service, the foreign court was a seriously inconvenient forum for the trial of the action.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this subsection, "defamation" includes invasion of privacy by false facts.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A foreign judgment against any person who is a resident of this State or who has assets in this State may not be recognized if:<section prefix="(i)">The cause of action resulted in a defamation judgment obtained in a jurisdiction outside the United States, unless the court before which the matter is brought in this State first determines that the defamation law as applied in the foreign jurisdiction provides for at least as much protection for freedom of speech and the press as is provided by both the United States Constitution and the Maryland Constitution; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">The cause of action resulted in a defamation judgment entered against the provider of an interactive computer service, as defined in 47 U.S.C. &#xA7; 230, unless the court before which the matter is brought in this State determines that the judgment is consistent with 47 U.S.C. &#xA7; 230.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
