<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcj" order_by="gcj" level="1">Courts and Judicial Proceedings</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcj-6-313</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this section the following words have the meanings indicated....</catch_line>
  <order_by>313</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Motor vehicle" has the meaning stated in &#xA7; 11-135 of the Transportation Article.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Nonresident" has the meaning stated in &#xA7; 11-139 of the Transportation Article.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">"Nonresident's privilege to drive" has the meaning stated in &#xA7; 11-140 of the Transportation Article.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">By exercising a nonresident's privilege to drive a motor vehicle in the State, a nonresident irrevocably appoints the Motor Vehicle Administration as agent to receive a subpoena, a summons, or other process that is:<section prefix="(1)">Issued in an action that is related to an accident or collision involving a motor vehicle driven by the nonresident driver and in which the nonresident driver is named as a party; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Directed to the nonresident driver.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Service of process is sufficient service on a nonresident driver if:<section prefix="(1)">Service is made by the personal delivery and leaving of a copy of the process, with a certification of the last known address of the nonresident driver, with the Motor Vehicle Administration;</section><section prefix="(2)">A fee for service of process is paid to the Motor Vehicle Administration;</section><section prefix="(3)">The Motor Vehicle Administration sends a copy of the process by certified mail, return receipt requested, to the nonresident driver at the nonresident driver's last known address; and</section><section prefix="(4)">The Motor Vehicle Administration files an affidavit of compliance with the provisions of this section with the clerk of the court in which the action is pending.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Motor Vehicle Administration shall provide a copy of the affidavit of compliance to the party seeking service.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The party seeking service shall send by certified mail, return receipt requested, a copy of the affidavit of compliance to the motor vehicle insurer of the nonresident driver.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Motor Vehicle Administration shall keep a record of all process served under this section that shows the date and hour of service on the Administration by the party seeking service.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">When the certified return receipt is returned to the Motor Vehicle Administration, the Administration shall:<section prefix="(i)">Deliver it to the party seeking service; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Keep a record of the date of its receipt and the date of its delivery to the party seeking service.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">The Motor Vehicle Administration is authorized to establish and collect a reasonable fee to recover the Administration's costs under this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">The Motor Vehicle Administration shall report to the General Assembly on or before January 1 of each year, in accordance with &#xA7; 2-1246 of the State Government Article, the following information for the preceding calendar year:<section prefix="(1)">The total number of subpoenas, summonses, and other service of process issued in accordance with the provisions of this section;</section><section prefix="(2)">The number of instances in which the Motor Vehicle Administration failed to reach the individual being served and the reasons that those attempts failed;</section><section prefix="(3)">A breakdown of all direct and indirect costs incurred by the Motor Vehicle Administration in carrying out the requirements of this section; and</section><section prefix="(4)">The total fees collected by the Motor Vehicle Administration from persons requesting service of process under this section.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
