<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcj" order_by="" level="1">Courts and Judicial Proceedings</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcj-10-201</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>201</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The 1957 Edition of the Annotated Code of Maryland, prepared and published by the Editorial Staff of The Michie Company, Charlottesville, Virginia, is adopted and made evidence of the Public General Laws of the State of Maryland as contained in the Code of Public General Laws of Maryland of 1888, as amended, modified and changed from time to time, through and including the regular session of the General Assembly of Maryland held in 1957. It shall be considered as the evidence of the law in all courts of the State and by all public offices and officers of the State and its political subdivisions.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A replacement volume to the Annotated Code of the Public General Laws of Maryland (1957 Edition), prepared and published by the Editorial Staff of The Michie Company, Charlottesville, Virginia, is adopted and made evidence of the Public General Laws in the volume at the time of publication. It shall be considered as evidence of the law in all courts of the State and by all public offices and officers of the State and its political subdivisions.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Any pocket or other supplement to a volume of the Annotated Code of the Public General Laws of Maryland (1957 Edition or subsequent replacement volume), prepared and published by the Editorial Staff of The Michie Company, Charlottesville, Virginia, is adopted and made evidence of changes in the Public General Laws which are supplementary or in addition to the laws in the main volume. It shall be considered as evidence of the law in all the courts of the State and by all public offices and officers of the State and its political subdivisions.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The 2002 Edition of West's Annotated Code of Maryland, prepared and published by the editorial staff of West, Eagan, Minnesota, is adopted and made evidence of the Public General Laws of Maryland as contained in the Code of Public General Laws of Maryland of 1888, as amended, modified, and changed from time to time, through and including the regular session of the General Assembly of Maryland held in 2001. It shall be considered as the evidence of the law in all courts of the State and by all public offices and officers of the State and its political subdivisions.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A replacement volume to West's Annotated Code of Maryland (2002 Edition), prepared and published by the editorial staff of West, Eagan, Minnesota, is adopted and made evidence of the Public General Laws in the volume at the time of publication. It shall be considered as evidence of the law in all the courts of the State and by all public offices and officers of the State and its political subdivisions.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Any pocket or other supplement to a volume of West's Annotated Code of Maryland (2002 Edition or subsequent replacement volume), prepared and published by the editorial staff of West, Eagan, Minnesota, is adopted and made evidence of changes in the Public General Laws which are supplementary or in addition to the laws in the main volume. It shall be considered as evidence of the law in all the courts of the State and by all public offices and officers of the State and its political subdivisions.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Code of Public General Laws, as compiled, updated, and maintained by the Department of Legislative Services in accordance with &#xA7; 2-1243(c) of the State Government Article, is adopted and made evidence of the Public General Laws of Maryland as contained in the Code of Public General Laws of Maryland of 1888, as amended, modified, and changed from time to time, through and including the most recently completed regular session of the General Assembly. It shall be considered as the evidence of the law in all courts of the State and by all public offices and officers of the State and its political subdivisions.</section>
  </text>
</law>
