<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcj" order_by="gcj" level="1">Courts and Judicial Proceedings</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcj-3-303</section_number>
  <catch_line>An attachment before judgment may issue in any of the instances in this section....</catch_line>
  <order_by>303</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">An attachment before judgment may issue in any of the instances in this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">If the debtor is a nonresident individual, or a corporation which has no resident agent in this State, and:<section prefix="(1)">The debtor is a person over whom the court could exercise personal jurisdiction pursuant to &#xA7;&#xA7; 6-102, 6-103 and 6-104 of this article; or</section><section prefix="(2)">The action involves claims to property in this State which property is to be attached; or</section><section prefix="(3)">The action is any other in which the attachment is constitutionally permitted.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">If a resident individual defendant or an agent authorized to accept process for a corporation has acted to evade service.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">If the debtor has absconded or is about to abscond from the State; or if an individual has removed, or is about to remove, from his place of abode in the State with intent to defraud his creditors.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If the debtor is about to assign, dispose of, conceal, or remove his property or a portion of it from the State with intent to defraud his creditors; or</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If the debtor has done any of these acts, or fraudulently contracted the debt or incurred the obligation which is the subject of the pending action.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">If the debtor is deceased and an adult nonresident is entitled by descent or devise from the debtor to any land or interest in land in the State, an attachment may issue against that land or interest held by descent or devise from the person indebted.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">If any person who is required to be but is not licensed under the provisions of the Maryland Home Improvement Law, in an action against that person arising out of a home improvement transaction.</section>
  </text>
</law>
