<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcj" order_by="gcj" level="1">Courts and Judicial Proceedings</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcj-7-507</section_number>
  <catch_line>This section does not apply to Anne Arundel, Howard, and Somerset counties....</catch_line>
  <order_by>507</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This section does not apply to Anne Arundel, Howard, and Somerset counties.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">This section does not apply to fines imposed in gambling cases in Baltimore County.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Except as provided in subsection (c) of this section, the fines imposed by and recognizances forfeited to each circuit court shall be distributed as follows:<section prefix="(1)">50% to the clerk of the circuit court, to be used under the direction of the judges of the circuit court to augment the court library; and</section><section prefix="(2)">5% to the clerk of the circuit court as a commission.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In Calvert County, if the County Administrative Circuit Court Judge determines that the amount under subsection (b)(1) of this section exceeds the needs of the library, excess amounts may be used for other needs of the Circuit Court for Calvert County if the Judge provides the County Commissioners with an annual report documenting how the excess amount is used.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">In Carroll County, in addition to the amount under subsection (b) of this section, the County Commissioners shall appropriate and pay to the Clerk of the Circuit Court for Carroll County $1,800, plus any additional amount that the County Commissioners determine, for library support and maintenance, including books and library equipment, to be used under the direction of the judges of the Circuit Court for Carroll County.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">In Cecil County:<section prefix="(i)">In any year in which the amount provided to the court library under subsection (b) of this section and the attorney appearance fees under &#xA7; 7-204 of this title:<section prefix="1.">Is less than $10,000, the County Commissioners shall pay to the clerk of the court the amount necessary to bring the total to $10,000, plus any amount the County Commissioners determine is reasonable for the library maintenance, to be used under the direction of the judges of the Circuit Court for Cecil County; or</section><section prefix="2.">Exceeds the amount necessary for library maintenance, the Cecil County Bar and Library Association, Inc., may transfer the excess money to the Cecil County Bar Foundation, Inc., to be used for charitable and educational purposes in accordance with the bylaws of the Foundation; and</section></section><section prefix="(ii)">All amounts paid under this section shall be used under the direction of the judges of the Circuit Court for Cecil County in consultation with the Law Library Committee of the Cecil County Bar and Library Association, Inc.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">In Charles County, in any year in which the amount under subsection (b) of this section is less than $3,000, the County Commissioners shall pay to the Clerk of the Circuit Court for Charles County the amount necessary to bring the total to $3,000, plus any amount the County Commissioners determine is reasonable for library maintenance, to be used under the direction of the judges of the Circuit Court for Charles County, who reside in the county.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">In Harford County, the local governing body shall appropriate and pay to the Clerk of the Circuit Court for Harford County, to be used under the direction of the judges of the court:<section prefix="(i)">The amount under subsection (b) of this section; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Any amount the local governing body determines is appropriate, but not less than $1,500, for library support and maintenance, including books, library equipment, and the services of a librarian.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(6)">
        <section prefix="(i)">In St. Mary's County, the Clerk of the Circuit Court for St. Mary's County shall transmit monthly the amount under subsection (b)(1) of this section to a special account known as the St. Mary's County Law Library Fund maintained by the county.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">As determined by the County Administrative Judge, the St. Mary's County Law Library Fund may only be used for the general purposes of the court library, including to acquire books, other publications, and library equipment, and for other necessary expenses.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(7)">In Worcester County, in addition to the amount under subsection (b) of this section, the County Commissioners shall appropriate and pay to the Clerk of the Circuit Court for Worcester County $2,000 and any additional amount that the Commissioners set for library support and maintenance to be used under the direction of the judges of the Circuit Court for Worcester County.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
