<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gcj" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="2-104" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcj-2-104</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Every auditor, clerk, sheriff, constable, commissioner, surveyor, or other officer before he assumes the duties of his office, shall take and sign the oath or affirmation prescribed by the Constitution.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Except as provided in subsection (d) of this section, every deputy clerk or sheriff shall take and subscribe the following oath or affirmation: "I, A.B., do swear (or affirm) that I will not for lucre or malice delay any person applying to me for any business belonging to the office I officiate in, and that I will not directly or indirectly ask, take, exact, demand, or receive from or charge to any such person to my own use any fee or reward whatsoever for any services I may do as deputy of the said office, and that in making out the office fees I will not wittingly or willingly charge other or higher fees than are allowed by law."</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In addition to the oath or affirmation required under subsection (b) of this section, in St. Mary's County, every deputy sheriff shall take and subscribe the following oath or affirmation: "I, A.B., do solemnly swear (or affirm) that I will bear true faith and allegiance to the United States of America and to the State of Maryland; that I will serve honestly and faithfully to uphold and defend the Constitution of the United States and the Constitution of Maryland; that I will enforce the laws of St. Mary's County, and the State of Maryland; and that I will obey the orders of the Sheriff and of my superior officers according to the rules and regulations of the Sheriff's Office, St. Mary's County and the State of Maryland."</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">In addition to the oath or affirmation required under subsection (b) of this section, in Charles County, every deputy sheriff shall take and subscribe the following oath or affirmation: "I, A.B., do solemnly swear (or affirm) that I will bear true faith and allegiance to the United States of America and to the State of Maryland; that I will serve honestly and faithfully to uphold and defend the Constitution of the United States and the Constitution of Maryland; that I will enforce the laws of Charles County, and the State of Maryland; and that I will obey the orders of the Sheriff and of my superior officers according to the rules and regulations of the Sheriff's Office, Charles County and the State of Maryland."</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">In Montgomery County and Washington County, every deputy clerk or deputy sheriff shall take and sign the oath or affirmation prescribed by Article I, &#xA7; 9 of the Maryland Constitution.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as authorized by Article I, &#xA7; 10 of the Maryland Constitution, every officer, except the clerk of the circuit court of a county or an appellate court, shall take the oath before the clerk of the circuit court.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Except as provided in Article I, &#xA7; 10 of the Maryland Constitution, the clerk of a circuit court shall take the oath before a judge of the court.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The clerk of an appellate court shall take the oath before the Governor.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
