<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gcj" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="7-402" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcj-7-402</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Except as provided in subsections (b) and (e) of this section, a sheriff shall collect the following fees:<section prefix="(1)">$5 for service of summary ejectment papers.</section><section prefix="(2)">$40 for service of a paper not including an execution or attachment.</section><section prefix="(3)">$40 for service including an execution or attachment by taking into custody a person or seizing real or personal property.</section><section prefix="(4)">$40 for service of process papers arising out of administrative agency proceedings where the party requesting the service is a nongovernmental entity.</section><section prefix="(5)">For the sale following the execution or attachment of personal property: Three percent of the first $5,000; two percent of the second $5,000; and one percent of any amount in excess of $10,000. The sheriff shall collect a minimum of $15 and a maximum of $500 under the provisions of this paragraph.</section><section prefix="(6)">For the sale following the execution or attachment of real property: One and one-half percent of the first $5,000; one percent of the second $5,000; and one-half of one percent of any amount in excess of $10,000. The sheriff shall collect a minimum of $1.50 and a maximum of $250 under the provisions of this paragraph.</section><section prefix="(7)">$60 for service of a paper originating from a foreign court.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">For service including an execution or attachment by taking into custody a person or seizing real or personal property, a sheriff may collect the amount specified in a cooperative agreement with the Child Support Enforcement Administration under &#xA7; 10-111 of the Family Law Article.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">As part of the costs awarded to a party under &#xA7; 12-103 of the Family Law Article, a court may not award an amount greater than the amount specified in subsection (a) of this section for the cost of service including an execution or attachment by taking into custody a person or seizing real or personal property.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If the sheriff incurs expenses for the purpose of conserving or protecting the seized property, the sheriff shall be reimbursed for the expense.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If the Sheriff of Washington County incurs expenses for seizing property, the Sheriff shall be reimbursed by the judgment debtor for reasonable expenses.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, if the sheriff is unable to serve a paper, 50% of the fee shall be refunded to the party requesting the service.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If the sheriff is unable to serve summary ejectment papers, the full fee shall be refunded to the party requesting the service.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">A sheriff may not collect a fee for the service of:<section prefix="(1)">A paper from a housing authority created under Division II of the Housing and Community Development Article; or</section><section prefix="(2)">A summons for a law enforcement officer to appear as a witness in a criminal case.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
