<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcj" order_by="gcj" level="1">Courts and Judicial Proceedings</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcj-5-1002</section_number>
  <catch_line>Except as provided in subsection (c) of this section, a prisoner who maintains a civil action shall ...</catch_line>
  <order_by>1002</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Except as provided in subsection (c) of this section, a prisoner who maintains a civil action shall pay all or a portion of the applicable filing fee, as determined by the court.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">Unless a waiver is granted under subsection (c) of this section, a fee determined by the court under subparagraph (i) of this paragraph shall be at least 25 percent of the entire filing fee otherwise required for a civil action.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The court may:<section prefix="(i)">Authorize any fee to be paid over a specific period of time; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Establish a payment schedule.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Until any applicable filing fee is paid, service of the complaint shall be withheld, discovery may not commence, and other proceedings may not be convened.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">In establishing the amount of the filing fee to be paid under subsection (a) of this section, the court shall consider, based on information in the complaint and provided by the prisoner:<section prefix="(1)">The seriousness of the claim;</section><section prefix="(2)">The likelihood of success;</section><section prefix="(3)">The urgency of consideration;</section><section prefix="(4)">The amount of funds available in any institutional account and any account outside of the institution;</section><section prefix="(5)">The employment status of the prisoner in the institution and income from the employment;</section><section prefix="(6)">Any financial obligations of the prisoner; and</section><section prefix="(7)">The length of time that is likely to pass before the filing fee that is imposed is able to be paid.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A court may waive payment of the entire required filing fee for a civil action filed by a prisoner only on a written showing under oath by the prisoner that:<section prefix="(1)">The prisoner is indigent;</section><section prefix="(2)">The issue presented is of serious concern;</section><section prefix="(3)">Delay in the consideration of the issues presented will prejudice the consideration of the claim;</section><section prefix="(4)">The prisoner is not likely to accumulate sufficient funds to pay the required filing fee within a reasonable period of time; and</section><section prefix="(5)">The prisoner possesses a reasonable likelihood of success on the merits of the claim.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">If a prisoner prevails in an action, the filing fee that is paid by the prisoner shall be reimbursed to the prisoner by the defendant through costs awarded by the court.</section>
  </text>
</law>
