<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gcj" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="3-2C-01" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcj-3-2C-01</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Claim" means a civil action, including an original claim, counterclaim, cross-claim, or third-party claim, originally filed in a circuit court or United States District Court against a licensed professional or the employer, partnership, or other entity through which the licensed professional performed professional services that is based on the licensed professional's alleged negligent act or omission in rendering professional services, within the scope of the professional's license, permit, or certificate, for others.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Licensed professional" means:<section prefix="(1)">An architect licensed under Title 3 of the Business Occupations and Professions Article;</section><section prefix="(2)">An interior designer certified under Title 8 of the Business Occupations and Professions Article;</section><section prefix="(3)">A landscape architect licensed under Title 9 of the Business Occupations and Professions Article;</section><section prefix="(4)">A professional engineer licensed under Title 14 of the Business Occupations and Professions Article; or</section><section prefix="(5)">A professional land surveyor or property line surveyor licensed under Title 15 of the Business Occupations and Professions Article.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Qualified expert" means an individual who is a licensed professional, or comparably licensed or certified professional under the laws of another jurisdiction, knowledgeable in the accepted standard of care in the same discipline as the licensed professional against whom a claim is filed.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Qualified expert" does not include:<section prefix="(i)">A party to the claim;</section><section prefix="(ii)">An employee or partner of a party;</section><section prefix="(iii)">An employee or stockholder of a professional corporation of which a party is a stockholder; or</section><section prefix="(iv)">A person having a financial interest in the outcome of the claim.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
