<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcj" order_by="" level="1">Courts and Judicial Proceedings</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcj-5-404</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>404</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Agent of a charitable organization" means a person who:<section prefix="(i)">Is or was a director, officer, or employee of a charitable organization; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">On a volunteer basis, is or was providing services or performing duties on behalf of a charitable organization.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Charitable organization" means an organization, institution, association, society, or corporation that is exempt from taxation under &#xA7; 501(c)(3) of the Internal Revenue Code.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">"Farmer" means a person, including a corporation, who engages in an activity conducted solely or primarily for the production of a farm product.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">"Farm product" has the meaning stated in &#xA7; 10-601 of the Agriculture Article.</section>
      <section prefix="(6)">"Glean" means:<section prefix="(i)">To harvest or collect farm products from the fields of a farmer who grants access to the fields without charging a fee; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">To distribute the farm products to needy individuals, including unemployed and low-income individuals.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Except as provided in subsection (c) of this section, a farmer is not personally liable for damages in a civil action brought against the farmer for injury to a person or property by a charitable organization or an agent of a charitable organization that the farmer permitted to glean on the farmer's property.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">This section does not limit any liability that otherwise exists for willful or malicious failure to guard or warn against any dangerous condition, use, structure, or activity.</section>
  </text>
</law>
