<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gcj" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="3-2A-06C" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcj-3-2A-06C</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Alternative dispute resolution" means mediation, neutral case evaluation, neutral fact-finding, or a settlement conference.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Mediation" has the meaning stated in Title 17 of the Maryland Rules.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">"Mediator" means an individual who conducts mediation.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">"Neutral case evaluation" has the meaning stated in Title 17 of the Maryland Rules.</section>
      <section prefix="(6)">"Neutral fact-finding" has the meaning stated in Title 17 of the Maryland Rules.</section>
      <section prefix="(7)">"Neutral provider" means an individual who conducts neutral case evaluation or neutral fact-finding.</section>
      <section prefix="(8)">"Settlement conference" has the meaning stated in Title 17 of the Maryland Rules.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This section does not apply if:<section prefix="(i)">All parties file with the court an agreement not to engage in alternative dispute resolution; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">The court finds that alternative dispute resolution under this section would not be productive.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">In determining whether alternative dispute resolution would not be productive under paragraph (1)(ii) of this subsection, the court may consider whether the parties have already engaged in alternative dispute resolution.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">In addition to the qualifications and requirements of Title 17 of the Maryland Rules, the Court of Appeals may adopt rules requiring a mediator, neutral provider, or individual conducting a settlement conference to have experience with health care malpractice claims.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Within 30 days of the later of the filing of the defendant's answer to the complaint or the defendant's certificate of a qualified expert under &#xA7; 3-2A-04 of this subtitle, the court shall order the parties to engage in alternative dispute resolution at the earliest possible date.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Within 30 days of the later of the filing of the defendant's answer to the complaint or the defendant's certificate of a qualified expert under &#xA7; 3-2A-04 of this subtitle, the parties may choose a mediator, neutral provider, or individual to conduct a settlement conference.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If the parties choose a mediator, neutral provider, or individual to conduct a settlement conference, the parties shall notify the court of the name of the individual.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If the parties do not notify the court that they have chosen a mediator, neutral provider, or individual to conduct a settlement conference within the time required under subsection (e) of this section, the court shall assign a mediator, neutral provider, or individual to conduct a settlement conference to the claim within 30 days.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Within 15 days after the parties are notified of the identity of the mediator, neutral provider, or individual conducting a settlement conference, a party may object in writing to the selection, stating the reasons for the objection.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">If the court sustains the objection, the court shall appoint a different mediator, neutral provider, or individual to conduct a settlement conference.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A mediator, neutral provider, or individual conducting a settlement conference shall follow the "Maryland Standards of Practice for Mediators, Arbitrators, and Other ADR Practitioners" adopted by the Court of Appeals.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">The mediator, neutral provider, or individual conducting a settlement conference shall schedule an initial conference with the parties as soon as practicable.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">
      <section prefix="(1)">At least 15 days before the initial conference, the parties shall send to the mediator, neutral provider, or individual conducting a settlement conference a brief written outline of the strengths and weaknesses of the party's case.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A party may not be required to provide to another party the written outline described in paragraph (1) of this subsection.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(i)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Alternative dispute resolution under this section may not operate to delay discovery in the action.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If the mediator, neutral provider, or individual conducting a settlement conference finds that the parties need to engage in discovery for a limited period of time in order to facilitate the alternative dispute resolution, the mediator, neutral provider, or individual conducting a settlement conference may mediate the scope and schedule of discovery needed to proceed with the alternative dispute resolution, adjourn the initial conference, and reschedule an additional conference for a later date.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(j)">A neutral expert may be employed in alternative dispute resolution under this section as provided in Title 17 of the Maryland Rules.</section>
    <section prefix="(k)">In accordance with Maryland Rule 17-109, the outline described in subsection (h) of this section and any written or oral communication made in the course of a conference under this section:<section prefix="(1)">Are confidential;</section><section prefix="(2)">Do not constitute an admission; and</section><section prefix="(3)">Are not discoverable.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(l)">Unless excused by the mediator, neutral provider, or individual conducting a settlement conference, the parties and the claims representative for each defendant shall appear at all conferences held under this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(m)">A party who fails to comply with the provisions of subsection (h), (k), or (l) of this section is subject to the sanctions provided in Maryland Rule 2-433.</section>
    <section prefix="(n)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If a case is settled, the parties shall notify the court that the case has been settled.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If the parties agree to settle some but not all of the issues in dispute, the mediator, neutral provider, or individual conducting a settlement conference shall file a written notice of partial settlement with the court.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">If the parties have not agreed to a settlement the mediator, neutral provider, or individual conducting a settlement conference shall file a written notice with the court that the case was not settled.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(o)">Unless otherwise agreed by the parties, the costs of alternative dispute resolution shall be divided equally between the parties.</section>
    <section prefix="(p)">An individual who conducts alternative dispute resolution shall have the immunity from suit described under &#xA7; 5-615 of this article.</section>
  </text>
</law>
