<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcj" order_by="" level="1">Courts and Judicial Proceedings</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcj-6-103</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>103</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">If jurisdiction over a person is based solely upon this section, he may be sued only on a cause of action arising from any act enumerated in this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A court may exercise personal jurisdiction over a person, who directly or by an agent:<section prefix="(1)">Transacts any business or performs any character of work or service in the State;</section><section prefix="(2)">Contracts to supply goods, food, services, or manufactured products in the State;</section><section prefix="(3)">Causes tortious injury in the State by an act or omission in the State;</section><section prefix="(4)">Causes tortious injury in the State or outside of the State by an act or omission outside the State if he regularly does or solicits business, engages in any other persistent course of conduct in the State or derives substantial revenue from goods, food, services, or manufactured products used or consumed in the State;</section><section prefix="(5)">Has an interest in, uses, or possesses real property in the State; or</section><section prefix="(6)">Contracts to insure or act as surety for, or on, any person, property, risk, contract, obligation, or agreement located, executed, or to be performed within the State at the time the contract is made, unless the parties otherwise provide in writing.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">In this subsection the following terms have the meanings indicated.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">"Computer information" has the meaning stated in &#xA7; 22-102 of the Commercial Law Article.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">"Computer program" has the meaning stated in &#xA7; 22-102 of the Commercial Law Article.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The provisions of this section apply to computer information and computer programs in the same manner as they apply to goods and services.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
