<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gcj" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="9-123" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcj-9-123</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Other information" includes any book, paper, document, record, recording, or other material.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Prosecutor" means:<section prefix="(i)">The State's Attorney for a county;</section><section prefix="(ii)">A Deputy State's Attorney;</section><section prefix="(iii)">The Attorney General of the State; or</section><section prefix="(iv)">A Deputy Attorney General or designated Assistant Attorney General.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If a witness refuses, on the basis of the privilege against self-incrimination, to testify or provide other information in a criminal prosecution or a proceeding before a grand jury of the State, and the court issues an order to testify or provide other information under subsection (c) of this section, the witness may not refuse to comply with the order on the basis of the privilege against self-incrimination.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">No testimony or other information compelled under the order, and no information directly or indirectly derived from the testimony or other information, may be used against the witness in any criminal case, except in a prosecution for perjury, obstruction of justice, or otherwise failing to comply with the order.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">If an individual has been, or may be, called to testify or provide other information in a criminal prosecution or a proceeding before a grand jury of the State, the court in which the proceeding is or may be held shall issue, on the request of the prosecutor made in accordance with subsection (d) of this section, an order requiring the individual to give testimony or provide other information which the individual has refused to give or provide on the basis of the individual's privilege against self-incrimination. The order shall have the effect provided under subsection (b) of this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">If a prosecutor seeks to compel an individual to testify or provide other information, the prosecutor shall request, by written motion, the court to issue an order under subsection (c) of this section when the prosecutor determines that:<section prefix="(1)">The testimony or other information from the individual may be necessary to the public interest; and</section><section prefix="(2)">The individual has refused or is likely to refuse to testify or provide other information on the basis of the individual's privilege against self-incrimination.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">If a witness refuses to comply with an order issued under subsection (c) of this section, on written motion of the prosecutor and on admission into evidence of the transcript of the refusal, if the refusal was before a grand jury, the court shall treat the refusal as a direct contempt, notwithstanding any law to the contrary, and proceed in accordance with Title 15, Chapter 200 of the Maryland Rules.</section>
  </text>
</law>
