<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcj" order_by="gcj" level="1">Courts and Judicial Proceedings</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcj-11-504</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this section the following terms have the meanings indicated....</catch_line>
  <order_by>504</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following terms have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Value" means fair market value as of the date upon which the execution or other judicial process becomes effective against the property of the debtor, or the date of filing the petition under the federal Bankruptcy Code.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The following items are exempt from execution on a judgment:<section prefix="(1)">Wearing apparel, books, tools, instruments, or appliances, in an amount not to exceed $5,000 in value necessary for the practice of any trade or profession except those kept for sale, lease, or barter.</section><section prefix="(2)">Except as provided in subsection (i) of this section, money payable in the event of sickness, accident, injury, or death of any person, including compensation for loss of future earnings. This exemption includes but is not limited to money payable on account of judgments, arbitrations, compromises, insurance, benefits, compensation, and relief. Disability income benefits are not exempt if the judgment is for necessities contracted for after the disability is incurred.</section><section prefix="(3)">Professionally prescribed health aids for the debtor or any dependent of the debtor.</section><section prefix="(4)">The debtor's interest, not to exceed $1,000 in value, in household furnishings, household goods, wearing apparel, appliances, books, animals kept as pets, and other items that are held primarily for the personal, family, or household use of the debtor or any dependent of the debtor.</section><section prefix="(5)">Cash or property of any kind equivalent in value to $6,000 is exempt, if within 30 days from the date of the attachment or the levy by the sheriff, the debtor elects to exempt cash or selected items of property in an amount not to exceed a cumulative value of $6,000.</section><section prefix="(6)">Money payable or paid in accordance with an agreement or court order for child support.</section><section prefix="(7)">Money payable or paid in accordance with an agreement or court order for alimony to the same extent that wages are exempt from attachment under &#xA7; 15-601.1(b)(1)(ii) or (2)(i) of the Commercial Law Article.</section><section prefix="(8)">The debtor's beneficial interest in any trust property that is immune from the claims of the debtor's creditors under &#xA7; 14-113 of the Estates and Trusts Article.</section><section prefix="(9)">With respect to claims by a separate creditor of a husband or wife, trust property that is immune from the claims of the separate creditors of the husband or wife under &#xA7; 14-113 of the Estates and Trusts Article.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In order to determine whether the property listed in subsection (b)(4) and (5) of this section is subject to execution, the sheriff shall appraise the property at the time of levy. The sheriff shall return the appraisal with the writ.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">An appraisal made by the sheriff under this subsection is subject to review by the court on motion of the debtor.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Procedures will be as prescribed by rules issued by the Court of Appeals.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The debtor may not waive, by cognovit note or otherwise, the provisions of subsections (b) and (h) of this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The exemptions in this section do not apply to wage attachments.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">In addition to the exemptions provided in subsection (b) of this section, and in other statutes of this State, in any proceeding under Title 11 of the United States Code, entitled "Bankruptcy", any individual debtor domiciled in this State may exempt the debtor's aggregate interest in:<section prefix="1.">Personal property, up to $5,000; and</section><section prefix="2.">Subject to subparagraph (ii) of this paragraph:</section></section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The exemption allowed under subparagraph(i)2 of this paragraph may not exceed the amount under 11 U.S.C. &#xA7; 522(d)(1), adjusted in accordance with 11 U.S.C. &#xA7; 104, subject to the provisions of paragraphs (2) and (3) of this subsection.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">An individual may not claim the exemption under paragraph (1)(i)2 of this subsection on a particular property if:<section prefix="(i)">The individual has claimed successfully the exemption on the property within 8 years prior to the filing of the bankruptcy proceeding in which the exemption under this subsection is claimed; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">The individual's spouse, child, child's spouse, parent, sibling, grandparent, or grandchild has claimed successfully the exemption on the property within 8 years prior to the filing of the bankruptcy proceeding in which the exemption under this subsection is claimed.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The exemption under paragraph (1)(i)2 of this subsection may not be claimed by both a husband and wife in the same bankruptcy proceeding.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">In any bankruptcy proceeding, a debtor is not entitled to the federal exemptions provided by &#xA7; 522(d) of the federal Bankruptcy Code.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In addition to the exemptions provided in subsections (b) and (f) of this section and any other provisions of law, any money or other assets payable to a participant or beneficiary from, or any interest of any participant or beneficiary in, a retirement plan qualified under &#xA7; 401(a), &#xA7; 403(a), &#xA7; 403(b), &#xA7; 408, &#xA7; 408A, &#xA7; 414(d), or &#xA7; 414(e) of the United States Internal Revenue Code of 1986, as amended, or &#xA7; 409 (as in effect prior to January 1984) of the United States Internal Revenue Code of 1954, as amended, shall be exempt from any and all claims of the creditors of the beneficiary or participant, other than claims by the Department of Health and Mental Hygiene.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Paragraph (1) of this subsection does not apply to:<section prefix="(i)">An alternate payee under a qualified domestic relations order, as defined in &#xA7; 414(p) of the United States Internal Revenue Code of 1986, as amended;</section><section prefix="(ii)">A retirement plan, qualified under &#xA7; 401(a) of the United States Internal Revenue Code of 1986, as amended, as a creditor of an individual retirement account qualified under &#xA7; 408 of the United States Internal Revenue Code of 1986, as amended; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">The assets of a bankruptcy case filed before January 1, 1988.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The interest of an alternate payee in a plan described in subsection (h)(1) of this section shall be exempt from any and all claims of any creditor of the alternate payee, except claims by the Department of Health and Mental Hygiene.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">If a contribution to a retirement plan described under paragraph (1) of this subsection exceeds the amount deductible or, in the case of contribution under &#xA7; 408A of the Internal Revenue Code, the maximum contribution allowed under the applicable provisions of the United States Internal Revenue Code of 1986, as amended, the portion of that contribution that exceeds the amount deductible or, in the case of contribution under &#xA7; 408A of the Internal Revenue Code, the maximum contribution allowed, and any accrued earnings on such a portion, are not exempt under paragraph (1) of this subsection.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(i)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this subsection, "net recovery" means the sum of money to be distributed to the debtor after deduction of attorney's fees, expenses, medical bills, and satisfaction of any liens or subrogation claims arising out of the claims for personal injury, including those arising under:<section prefix="(i)">The Medicare Secondary Payer Act, 42 U.S.C. &#xA7; 1395y;</section><section prefix="(ii)">A program of the Department of Health and Mental Hygiene for which a right of subrogation exists under &#xA7;&#xA7; 15-120 and 15-121.1 of the Health - General Article;</section><section prefix="(iii)">An employee benefit plan subject to the federal Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974; or</section><section prefix="(iv)">A health insurance contract.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Twenty-five percent of the net recovery by the debtor on a claim for personal injury is subject to execution on a judgment for a child support arrearage.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
