<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gcj" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="7-301" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcj-7-301</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in paragraphs (2) and (3) of this subsection, the court costs in a traffic case, including parking and impounding cases, cases under &#xA7; 21-202.1, &#xA7; 21-809, &#xA7; 21-810, or &#xA7; 24-111.3 of the Transportation Article in which costs are imposed, and cases under &#xA7; 10-112 of the Criminal Law Article in which costs are imposed:<section prefix="(i)">Are $22.50 plus the surcharge under subsection (f) of this section; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Shall also be applicable to those cases in which the defendant elects to waive the defendant's right to trial and pay the fine or penalty deposit established by the Chief Judge of the District Court by administrative regulation.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">In an uncontested case under &#xA7; 21-202.1, &#xA7; 21-809, &#xA7; 21-810, or &#xA7; 24-111.3 of the Transportation Article, an uncontested case under &#xA7; 10-112 of the Criminal Law Article, or an uncontested parking or impounding case in which the fines are paid directly to a political subdivision or municipality, costs are $2.00, which costs shall be paid to and retained by the political subdivision or municipality.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">In an uncontested case in which the fine is paid directly to an agency of State government authorized by law to regulate parking of motor vehicles, the court costs are $2.00.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The fine and the costs under this paragraph shall be paid to the agency, which shall receive and account for these funds as in all other cases involving sums due the State through a State agency.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The court costs in a criminal case in which costs are imposed are $22.50.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The costs shall be in addition to any costs imposed in a criminal case under the Criminal Injuries Compensation Act.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The filing fees and costs in a civil case are those prescribed by law subject to modification by law, rule, or administrative regulation.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Chief Judge of the District Court shall assess a surcharge that:<section prefix="(i)">May not be more than:</section><section prefix="(ii)">Shall be deposited into the Maryland Legal Services Corporation Fund established under &#xA7; 11-402 of the Human Services Article.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Court of Appeals may provide by rule for waiver of prepayment of filing fees and other costs in cases of indigency.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">When a person pays court costs or a fine with a check in any motor vehicle, criminal, or civil case in the District Court, and the check is returned to the court by the financial institution on which it is drawn because of insufficient funds in the account, or because the account has been closed or never existed, then the court may impose additional costs of $10 against the party issuing the check. These costs shall be in addition to any other penalty now prescribed by law.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The Comptroller shall annually pay from the court costs collected by the District Court under subsections (a) and (b)(1) of this section:<section prefix="(1)">$500,000 into the Criminal Injuries Compensation Fund established under &#xA7; 11-819 of the Criminal Procedure Article; and</section><section prefix="(2)">$125,000 into the Victim and Witness Protection and Relocation Fund established under &#xA7; 11-905 of the Criminal Procedure Article.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This subsection does not apply to a traffic case under &#xA7; 21-202.1, &#xA7; 21-809, or &#xA7; 21-810 of the Transportation Article or to a parking or impounding case.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">In a traffic case under subsection (a)(1) of this section the court shall add a $7.50 surcharge to the court costs imposed by the court.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The Comptroller annually shall credit the surcharges collected under this subsection as provided in this paragraph.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">An amount annually as set forth in the State budget shall be distributed for the Charles W. Riley Fire and Emergency Medical Services Tuition Reimbursement Program as established in &#xA7; 18-603 of the Education Article.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">After the distribution under subparagraph (ii) of this paragraph, $200,000 shall be distributed to the Maryland State Firemen's Association.</section>
        <section prefix="(iv)">After the distribution under subparagraphs (ii) and (iii) of this paragraph and until a total of $20,000,000 has been distributed to the Volunteer Company Assistance Fund since the establishment of the surcharge under this subsection, the remainder shall be credited to the Volunteer Company Assistance  Fund to be used in accordance with the provisions of Title 8, Subtitle 2 of the Public Safety Article.</section>
        <section prefix="(v)">After a total of $20,000,000 has been distributed to the Volunteer Company Assistance Fund, 100% of the remainder shall be credited to the Maryland Emergency Medical Systems Operation Fund established under &#xA7; 13-955 of the Transportation Article.</section>
        <section prefix="(vi)">On or before September 1 of each year until $20,000,000 has been distributed to the Volunteer Company Assistance Fund, the State Court Administrator shall submit a report to the Senate Budget and Taxation Committee and the House Appropriations Committee, in accordance with &#xA7; 2-1246 of the State Government Article, on the amount of revenue distributed to the Volunteer Company Assistance Fund under this paragraph.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
