<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcj" order_by="gcj" level="1">Courts and Judicial Proceedings</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcj-5-522</section_number>
  <catch_line>Immunity of the State is not waived under &#xA7; 12-104 of the State Government Article for:...</catch_line>
  <order_by>522</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Immunity of the State is not waived under &#xA7; 12-104 of the State Government Article for:<section prefix="(1)">Punitive damages;</section><section prefix="(2)">Interest before judgment;</section><section prefix="(3)">A claim that arises from the combatant activities of the State Militia during a state of emergency;</section><section prefix="(4)">Any tortious act or omission of State personnel that:<section prefix="(i)">Is not within the scope of the public duties of the State personnel; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">Is made with malice or gross negligence;</section></section><section prefix="(5)">A claim by an individual arising from a single incident or occurrence that exceeds $200,000; or</section><section prefix="(6)">A cause of action that law specifically prohibits.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">State personnel, as defined in &#xA7; 12-101 of the State Government Article, are immune from suit in courts of the State and from liability in tort for a tortious act or omission that is within the scope of the public duties of the State personnel and is made without malice or gross negligence, and for which the State or its units have waived immunity under Title 12, Subtitle 1 of the State Government Article, even if the damages exceed the limits of that waiver.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The scope of public duties of State personnel shall include, but not be limited to:<section prefix="(1)">Any authorized use of a State-owned vehicle by State personnel, including, but not limited to, commuting to and from the place of employment; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Services to third parties performed by State personnel, as defined by &#xA7; 12-101 of the State Government Article, in the course of participation in an approved clinical training or academic program.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">In a contract action under Title 12, Subtitle 2 of the State Government Article, the State and its officers and units are not liable for punitive damages.</section>
  </text>
</law>
