<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcj" order_by="gcj" level="1">Courts and Judicial Proceedings</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcj-3-1001</section_number>
  <catch_line>There shall be provided protection and advocacy services to persons with developmental disabilities....</catch_line>
  <order_by>1001</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">There shall be provided protection and advocacy services to persons with developmental disabilities.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The term "developmental disabilities" shall mean a severe, chronic disability of a person which:<section prefix="(1)">Is attributable to a mental or physical impairment or combination of mental and physical impairments;</section><section prefix="(2)">Is manifested before the person attains age 22;</section><section prefix="(3)">Is likely to continue indefinitely;</section><section prefix="(4)">Results in substantial functional limitations in three or more of the following areas of major life activity:<section prefix="(i)">Self-care;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Receptive and expressive language;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Learning;</section><section prefix="(iv)">Mobility;</section><section prefix="(v)">Self-direction;</section><section prefix="(vi)">Capacity for independent living; and</section><section prefix="(vii)">Economic self-sufficiency; and</section></section><section prefix="(5)">Reflects the person's need for a combination and sequence of special, interdisciplinary, or generic care, treatment, or other services which are of lifelong or extended duration and are individually planned and coordinated.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The term "protection and advocacy services" includes the pursuit of legal, administrative, and other appropriate remedies to protect the rights of persons with developmental disabilities.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Protection and advocacy services shall be provided by an entity or entities, which may include private, nonprofit corporations, with the authority to pursue legal, administrative, and other appropriate remedies to insure the protection of the rights of persons with developmental disabilities who are receiving treatment, services, or habilitation within this State.</section>
  </text>
</law>
