<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcj" order_by="gcj" level="1">Courts and Judicial Proceedings</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcj-6-402</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this section the following words have the meanings indicated....</catch_line>
  <order_by>402</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Proceeding" includes:<section prefix="(i)">An arbitration proceeding;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Any part of an action; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Any part of an appellate proceeding.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Session" includes an extraordinary session.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Subject to subsection (d) of this section, if a member or desk officer of the General Assembly is an attorney of record in a proceeding, the proceeding shall be continued from 5 days before the legislative session convenes until at least 10 days after it is adjourned.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">If a member of the Legislative Policy Committee or of any committee or subcommittee thereof or a committee or subcommittee of the State legislature functioning during the legislative interim is an attorney of record in a proceeding, the proceeding shall be continued while the committee or subcommittee is holding a meeting.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">If a brief, a memorandum of law, or another document is required to be filed in a proceeding continued under this section:<section prefix="(1)">The proceeding shall be continued for a time sufficient to allow it to be prepared and filed; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Any time prescribed by the Maryland Rules, by rule or order of court, or by any statute applicable to the filing of the document shall begin to run 10 days after the General Assembly adjourns.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The attorney may waive the benefit of this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The attorney may exercise any right under this section after filing a motion or letter with the appropriate court or administrative agency without the attorney personally appearing.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">This section applies to a proceeding in a federal, State, or local court or administrative agency.</section>
  </text>
</law>
