<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcj" order_by="gcj" level="1">Courts and Judicial Proceedings</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcj-3-2A-03A</section_number>
  <catch_line>There is a Health Claims Arbitration Fund....</catch_line>
  <order_by>03A</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">There is a Health Claims Arbitration Fund.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">At the time of the filing of any claim or a response to a claim, the Director shall collect a fee of:<section prefix="(1)">$40 for the filing of the claim, including any third-party claim; and</section><section prefix="(2)">$25 for the filing of the response to the claim.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Director shall pay all filing fees collected under this subtitle to the Comptroller of the State.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Comptroller shall distribute:<section prefix="(i)">20% of the filing fees received from the Director to the General Fund of the State; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">The balance of the filing fees to the Health Care Alternative Dispute Resolution Office.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Fund shall be used exclusively to pay the fees of arbitrators and other operating expenses of the Health Care Alternative Dispute Resolution Office.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">In accordance with the assessment of costs under &#xA7; 3-2A-05(f) of this subtitle, the parties to an arbitration shall reimburse the Fund for all fees paid to the arbitrators from the Fund.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Fund is a continuing, nonlapsing fund and is not subject to &#xA7; 7-302 of the State Finance and Procurement Article.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Subject to subparagraph (ii) of this paragraph, any unspent portions of the Fund may not be transferred or revert to the General Fund of the State, but shall remain in the Fund to be used for the purposes specified under this subtitle.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">Unspent portions of the Fund that exceed $100,000 at the end of any fiscal year shall revert to the General Fund.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Director shall administer the Fund.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Moneys in the Fund may be expended only for any lawful purpose authorized by this subtitle.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">The Legislative Auditor shall audit the accounts and transactions of the Fund as provided in &#xA7; 2-1220 of the State Government Article.</section>
  </text>
</law>
