<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gcj" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="10-915" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcj-10-915</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Deoxyribonucleic acid (DNA)" means the molecules in all cellular forms that contain genetic information in a chemical structure of each individual.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"DNA profile" means an analysis of genetic loci that have been validated according to standards established by:<section prefix="(i)">The Technical Working Group on DNA Analysis Methods (TWGDAM); or</section><section prefix="(ii)">The DNA Advisory Board of the Federal Bureau of Investigation.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A statement from the testing laboratory setting forth that the analysis of genetic loci has been validated by standards established by TWGDAM or the DNA Advisory Board is sufficient to admit a DNA profile under this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">In any criminal proceeding, the evidence of a DNA profile is admissible to prove or disprove the identity of any person, if the party seeking to introduce the evidence of a DNA profile:<section prefix="(1)">Notifies in writing the other party or parties by mail at least 45 days before any criminal proceeding; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Provides, if applicable and requested in writing, the other party or parties at least 30 days before any criminal proceeding with:<section prefix="(i)">First generation film copy or suitable reproductions of autoradiographs, dot blots, slot blots, silver stained gels, test strips, control strips, and any other results generated in the course of the analysis;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Copies of laboratory notes generated in connection with the analysis, including chain of custody documents, sizing and hybridization information, statistical calculations, and worksheets;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Laboratory protocols and procedures utilized in the analysis;</section><section prefix="(iv)">The identification of each genetic locus analyzed; and</section><section prefix="(v)">A statement setting forth the genotype data and the profile frequencies for the databases utilized.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">If a party is unable to provide the information required under subsection (c) of this section at least 30 days prior to the criminal proceedings, the court may grant a continuance to permit such timely disclosures.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">Except as to the issue of admissibility under this section, subsection (c) of this section does not preclude discovery under the Maryland Rules relating to discovery, upon a showing of scientific relevance to a material issue regarding the DNA profile.</section>
  </text>
</law>
