<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcj" order_by="" level="1">Courts and Judicial Proceedings</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcj-3-802</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>802</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The purposes of this subtitle are:<section prefix="(1)">To provide for the care, protection, safety, and mental and physical development of any child coming within the provisions of this subtitle;</section><section prefix="(2)">To provide for a program of services and treatment consistent with the child's best interests and the promotion of the public interest;</section><section prefix="(3)">To conserve and strengthen the child's family ties and to separate a child from the child's parents only when necessary for the child's welfare;</section><section prefix="(4)">To hold parents of children found to be in need of assistance responsible for remedying the circumstances that required the court's intervention;</section><section prefix="(5)">Except as otherwise provided by law, to hold the local department responsible for providing services to assist the parents with remedying the circumstances that required the court's intervention;</section><section prefix="(6)">If necessary to remove a child from the child's home, to secure for the child custody, care, and discipline as nearly as possible equivalent to that which the child's parents should have given;</section><section prefix="(7)">To achieve a timely, permanent placement for the child consistent with the child's best interests; and</section><section prefix="(8)">To provide judicial procedures for carrying out the provisions of this subtitle.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">This subtitle shall be construed liberally to effectuate these purposes.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In all judicial proceedings conducted in accordance with this subtitle or &#xA7; 5-326 of the Family Law Article, the court may direct the local department to provide services to a child, the child's family, or the child's caregiver to the extent that the local department is authorized under State law.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The court shall exercise the authority described in paragraph (1) of this subsection to protect and advance a child's best interests.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
