<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcj" order_by="" level="1">Courts and Judicial Proceedings</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcj-5-1101</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>1101</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Discounted present value" means the fair present value of future payments, as determined by discounting payments to the present using the most recently published applicable federal rate for determining the present value of an annuity, as issued by the United States Internal Revenue Service.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Independent professional advice" means advice of an attorney, certified public accountant, actuary, or other licensed professional adviser:<section prefix="(1)">Who is engaged by a payee to render advice concerning the legal, tax, and financial implications of a transfer of structured settlement payment rights;</section><section prefix="(2)">Who is not affiliated with or compensated by the transferee of the transfer; and</section><section prefix="(3)">Whose compensation is not affected by whether a transfer occurs.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">"Interested parties" means the payee, each beneficiary designated under the annuity contract to receive payments following the payee's death, the annuity issuer, the structured settlement obligor, and any other party that has continuing rights or obligations under a structured settlement.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"Payee" means an individual who receives damage payments that are not subject to income taxation under a structured settlement and proposes to make a transfer of payment rights.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">"Responsible administrative authority" means a government authority vested with exclusive jurisdiction over the settled claim resolved by a structured settlement.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Structured settlement" means an arrangement for periodic payment of damages for personal injury established by a settlement or judgment in resolution of a tort claim.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Structured settlement" does not include an arrangement for periodic payment of damages for personal injury established by a judgment by confession.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(h)">"Structured settlement agreement" means an agreement, judgment, stipulation, or release embodying the terms of a structured settlement.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">"Structured settlement obligor" means a party who has the continuing periodic payment obligation to the payee under a structured settlement agreement or a qualified assignment agreement.</section>
    <section prefix="(j)">"Structured settlement payment rights" means the rights to receive periodic payments, including lump-sum payments under a structured settlement, whether from the settlement obligor or the annuity issuer, if:<section prefix="(1)">An interested party is domiciled in this State;</section><section prefix="(2)">The structured settlement agreement was approved by a court or responsible administrative authority in this State; or</section><section prefix="(3)">The settled claim was pending before a court of this State when the parties entered into the structured settlement agreement.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(k)">"Terms of the structured settlement" includes the terms of the structured settlement agreement, the annuity contract, a qualified assignment, and an order or approval of a court or responsible administrative authority authorizing or approving a structured settlement.</section>
    <section prefix="(l)">"Transfer" means a sale, assignment, pledge, hypothecation, or other form of alienation or encumbrance made by a payee for consideration.</section>
    <section prefix="(m)">"Transfer agreement" means the agreement providing for the transfer of structured settlement payment rights from a payee to a transferee.</section>
  </text>
</law>
