<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcj" order_by="" level="1">Courts and Judicial Proceedings</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcj-5-609</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>609</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Mental health care provider" means:<section prefix="(i)">A mental health care provider licensed under the Health Occupations Article; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Any facility, corporation, partnership, association, or other entity that provides treatment or services to individuals who have mental disorders.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Administrator" means an administrator of a facility as defined in &#xA7; 10-101 of the Health - General Article.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A cause of action or disciplinary action may not arise against any mental health care provider or administrator for failing to predict, warn of, or take precautions to provide protection from a patient's violent behavior unless the mental health care provider or administrator knew of the patient's propensity for violence and the patient indicated to the mental health care provider or administrator, by speech, conduct, or writing, of the patient's intention to inflict imminent physical injury upon a specified victim or group of victims.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The duty to take the actions under paragraph (2) of this subsection arises only under the limited circumstances described under subsection (b) of this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The duty described under this section is deemed to have been discharged if the mental health care provider or administrator makes reasonable and timely efforts to:<section prefix="(i)">Seek civil commitment of the patient;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Formulate a diagnostic impression and establish and undertake a documented treatment plan calculated to eliminate the possibility that the patient will carry out the threat; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">Inform the appropriate law enforcement agency and, if feasible, the specified victim or victims of:<section prefix="1.">The nature of the threat;</section><section prefix="2.">The identity of the patient making the threat; and</section><section prefix="3.">The identity of the specified victim or victims.</section></section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">No cause of action or disciplinary action may arise under any patient confidentiality act against a mental health care provider or administrator for confidences disclosed or not disclosed in good faith to third parties in an effort to discharge a duty arising under this section according to the provisions of subsection (c) of this section.</section>
  </text>
</law>
