<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcj" order_by="gcj" level="1">Courts and Judicial Proceedings</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcj-8-404</section_number>
  <catch_line>Notwithstanding &#xA7; 8-103(a) of this title, a trial judge may strike an individual who is party in a ...</catch_line>
  <order_by>404</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Notwithstanding &#xA7; 8-103(a) of this title, a trial judge may strike an individual who is party in a civil case while the individual is entitled to a jury trial in the county.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Whenever more individuals than are needed to impanel a jury have been summoned, an individual may be excused but only in accordance with rule or other law.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">An individual who is summoned for jury service may be struck from a particular jury only:<section prefix="(i)">In accordance with rule or other law, by a party on peremptory challenge;</section><section prefix="(ii)">For good cause shown, by a trial judge on a challenge by a party; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">Subject to paragraph (3) of this subsection, by a trial judge who finds that:<section prefix="1.">The individual may be unable to render impartial jury service;</section><section prefix="2.">The individual's service likely would disrupt the proceeding; or</section><section prefix="3.">The individual's service may threaten the secrecy of a proceeding or otherwise affect the integrity of the jury deliberations adversely.</section></section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A trial judge may not strike an individual under paragraph (2)(iii)3 of this subsection, unless the judge states on the record:<section prefix="(i)">Each reason for the strike; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">A finding that the strike is warranted and not inconsistent with &#xA7;&#xA7; 8-102(a) and (b) and 8-104 of this title.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">An individual struck under this subsection may serve on another jury for which the basis for the strike is irrelevant.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A trial judge may strike an individual on the basis of the individual's belief for or against capital punishment only if the judge finds that the belief would prevent or substantially impair the individual from returning an impartial verdict according to law.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">An individual struck under this subsection may serve on another jury for which the basis for the strike is irrelevant.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
