<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gcj" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="8-416" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcj-8-416</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">A court reporter ordered to take testimony given before a grand jury shall take and transcribe the testimony.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A court reporter shall provide, as requested, a transcript of testimony given before a grand jury for a county to the grand jury and State's Attorney for the county.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Each transcript of testimony given before a grand jury for a county shall be kept in the custody of the State's Attorney for the county.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Unless the circuit court for a county orders otherwise after hearing the State's Attorney for the county, neither the original nor a copy of the transcript of testimony given before a grand jury may be taken from the office of the State's Attorney for the county, other than for use of the grand jury or for production in court.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">On written order of the circuit court for a county, granted on written motion of the State's Attorney for the county, the State's Attorney may have the notes as to, and transcript of, grand jury testimony destroyed.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Except on written order of the circuit court for a county after hearing the State's Attorney for the county:<section prefix="(1)">A record of testimony given before a grand jury is for the exclusive use and benefit of the grand jury and the State's Attorney; and</section><section prefix="(2)">A court reporter may not:<section prefix="(i)">Allow any other governmental unit or person to read or have a copy of all or any part of the record; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">Disclose wholly or partly the character of the contents of the record to any other governmental unit or person.</section></section></section>
  </text>
</law>
