<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gcj" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="3-8A-15" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcj-3-8A-15</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Only the court or an intake officer may authorize detention, community detention, or shelter care for a child who may be in need of supervision or delinquent.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">If a child is taken into custody under this subtitle, the child may be placed in detention or community detention prior to a hearing if:<section prefix="(1)">Such action is required to protect the child or others; or</section><section prefix="(2)">The child is likely to leave the jurisdiction of the court.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A child taken into custody under this subtitle may be placed in emergency shelter care or community detention prior to a hearing if:<section prefix="(1)"><section prefix="(i)">Such action is required to protect the child or person and property of others;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The child is likely to leave the jurisdiction of the court; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">There is no parent, guardian, or custodian or other person able to provide supervision and care for the child and return the child to the court when required; and</section></section><section prefix="(2)"><section prefix="(i)"/><section prefix="(ii)"/></section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If the child is not released, the intake officer or the official who authorized detention, community detention, or shelter care under this section shall immediately file a petition to authorize continued detention, community detention, or shelter care.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A hearing on the petition shall be held not later than the next court day, unless extended for no more than 5 days by the court upon good cause shown.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Reasonable notice, oral or written, stating the time, place, and purpose of the hearing, shall be given to the child and, if they can be found, the child's parents, guardian, or custodian.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">Except as provided in paragraph (5) of this subsection, shelter care may not be ordered for a period of more than 30 days unless an adjudicatory or waiver hearing is held.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">For a child in need of supervision or a delinquent child, shelter care may be extended for an additional period of not more than 30 days if the court finds after a hearing held as part of the adjudication that continued shelter care is consistent with the circumstances stated in subsections (b) and (c) of this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(6)">
        <section prefix="(i)">An adjudicatory or waiver hearing shall be held no later than 30 days after the date a petition for detention or community detention is granted.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">If a child is detained or placed in community detention after an adjudicatory hearing, a disposition hearing shall be held no later than 14 days after the adjudicatory hearing.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">Detention or community detention time may be extended in increments of not more than 14 days where the petition charges the child with a delinquent act and where the court finds, after a subsequent hearing, that extended detention or community detention is necessary either:</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Detention or community detention may not be continued beyond emergency detention or community detention unless, upon an order of court after a hearing, the court has found that one or more of the circumstances stated in subsection (b) of this section exist.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A court order under this paragraph shall:<section prefix="(i)">Contain a written determination of whether or not the criteria contained in subsection (c)(1) and (2) of this section have been met; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Specify which of the circumstances stated in subsection (b) of this section exist.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">If the court has not specifically prohibited community detention, the Department of Juvenile Services may release the child from detention into community detention and place the child in:</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">If a child who has been released by the Department of Juvenile Services or the court into community detention violates the conditions of community detention, and it is necessary to protect the child or others, an intake officer may authorize the detention of the child.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">The Department of Juvenile Services shall promptly notify the court of:</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">Shelter care may only be continued beyond emergency shelter care if the court has found that:<section prefix="(1)">Continuation of the child in the child's home is contrary to the welfare of the child; and</section><section prefix="(2)"><section prefix="(i)">Removal of the child from the child's home is necessary due to an alleged emergency situation and in order to provide for the safety of the child; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">Reasonable but unsuccessful efforts were made to prevent or eliminate the need for removal of the child from the home.</section></section><section prefix="(3)"><section prefix="(i)">If the court continues shelter care on the basis of an alleged emergency, the court shall assess whether the absence of efforts to prevent removal was reasonable.</section><section prefix="(ii)">If the court finds that the absence of efforts to prevent removal was not reasonable, the court shall make a written determination so stating.</section></section><section prefix="(4)">The court shall make a determination as to whether reasonable efforts are being made to make it possible to return the child to the child's home or whether the absence of such efforts is reasonable.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(g)">A child alleged to be delinquent may not be detained in a jail or other facility for the detention of adults.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A child alleged to be in need of supervision may not be placed in:<section prefix="(i)">Detention or community detention;</section><section prefix="(ii)">A State mental health facility; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">A shelter care facility that is not operating in compliance with applicable State licensing laws.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Subject to paragraph (1)(iii) of this subsection, a child alleged to be in need of supervision may be placed in shelter care facilities maintained or approved by the Social Services Administration or the Department of Juvenile Services or in a private home or shelter care facility approved by the court.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Secretary of Human Resources and the Secretary of Juvenile Services together, when appropriate, with the Secretary of Health and Mental Hygiene shall jointly adopt regulations to ensure that any child placed in shelter care pursuant to a petition filed under subsection (d) of this section be provided appropriate services, including:<section prefix="(i)">Health care services;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Counseling services;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Education services;</section><section prefix="(iv)">Social work services; and</section><section prefix="(v)">Drug and alcohol abuse assessment or treatment services.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">In addition to any other provision, the regulations shall require:<section prefix="(i)">The Department of Juvenile Services to develop a plan within 45 days of placement of a child in a shelter care facility to assess the child's treatment needs; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">The plan to be submitted to all parties to the petition and their counsel.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(i)">The intake officer or the official who authorized detention, community detention, or shelter care under this subtitle shall immediately give written notice of the authorization for detention, community detention, or shelter care to the child's parent, guardian, or custodian and to the court. The notice shall be accompanied by a statement of the reasons for taking the child into custody and placing him in detention, community detention, or shelter care. This notice may be combined with the notice required under subsection (d) of this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(j)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If a child is alleged to have committed a delinquent act, the court or a juvenile intake officer shall consider including, as a condition of releasing the child pending an adjudicatory or disposition hearing, reasonable protections for the safety of the alleged victim.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If a victim has requested reasonable protections for safety, the court or juvenile intake officer shall consider including, as a condition of releasing the child pending an adjudicatory or disposition hearing, provisions regarding no contact with the alleged victim or the alleged victim's premises or place of employment.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(k)">If a child remains in a facility used for detention for the specific act for which the child has been adjudicated delinquent for more than 25 days after the court has made a disposition on a petition under &#xA7; 3-8A-19 of this subtitle, the Department of Juvenile Services shall:<section prefix="(1)">On the first available court date after the 25th day that the child remains in a facility used for detention, appear at a hearing before the court with the child to explain the reasons for continued detention; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Every 25 days thereafter, appear at another hearing before the court with the child to explain the reasons for continued detention.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
