<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcj" order_by="gcj" level="1">Courts and Judicial Proceedings</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcj-3-8A-01</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated, unless the context of their use in...</catch_line>
  <order_by>01</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated, unless the context of their use indicates otherwise.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Adjudicatory hearing" means a hearing under this subtitle to determine whether the allegations in the petition, other than allegations that the child requires treatment, guidance, or rehabilitation, are true.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Adult" means an individual who is at least 18 years old.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">"Child" means an individual under the age of 18 years.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"Child in need of supervision" is a child who requires guidance, treatment, or rehabilitation and:<section prefix="(1)">Is required by law to attend school and is habitually truant;</section><section prefix="(2)">Is habitually disobedient, ungovernable, and beyond the control of the person having custody of him;</section><section prefix="(3)">Deports himself so as to injure or endanger himself or others; or</section><section prefix="(4)">Has committed an offense applicable only to children.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">"Citation" means the written form issued by a police officer which serves as the initial pleading against a child for a violation and which is adequate process to give the court jurisdiction over the person cited.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">"Commit" means to transfer legal custody.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Community detention" means a program monitored by the Department of Juvenile Services in which a delinquent child or a child alleged to be delinquent is placed in the home of a parent, guardian, custodian, or other fit person, or in shelter care, as a condition of probation or as an alternative to detention.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Community detention" includes electronic monitoring.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(i)">"Competency hearing" means a hearing under this subtitle to determine whether a child alleged to be delinquent is mentally competent to participate in a waiver hearing under &#xA7; 3-8A-06 of this subtitle, an adjudicatory hearing under &#xA7; 3-8A-18 of this subtitle, a disposition hearing under &#xA7; 3-8A-19 of this subtitle, or a violation of probation hearing.</section>
    <section prefix="(j)">"Court" means the circuit court for a county sitting as the juvenile court.</section>
    <section prefix="(k)">"Custodian" means a person or agency to whom legal custody of a child has been given by order of the court, other than the child's parent or legal guardian.</section>
    <section prefix="(l)">"Delinquent act" means an act which would be a crime if committed by an adult.</section>
    <section prefix="(m)">"Delinquent child" is a child who has committed a delinquent act and requires guidance, treatment, or rehabilitation.</section>
    <section prefix="(n)">"Detention" means the temporary care of children who, pending court disposition, require secure custody for the protection of themselves or the community, in physically restricting facilities.</section>
    <section prefix="(o)">"Developmental disability" means a severe chronic disability of a child that:<section prefix="(1)">Is attributable to a physical or mental impairment, other than the sole diagnosis of mental illness, or to a combination of mental and physical impairments;</section><section prefix="(2)">Is likely to continue indefinitely;</section><section prefix="(3)">Results in an inability to live independently without external support or continuing and regular assistance; and</section><section prefix="(4)">Reflects the need for a combination and sequence of special interdisciplinary or generic care, treatment, or other services that are individually planned and coordinated for the child.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(p)">"Disposition hearing" means a hearing under this subtitle to determine:<section prefix="(1)">Whether a child needs or requires guidance, treatment, or rehabilitation; and, if so</section><section prefix="(2)">The nature of the guidance, treatment, or rehabilitation.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(q)">"Incompetent to proceed" means that a child is not able to:<section prefix="(1)">Understand the nature or object of the proceeding; or</section><section prefix="(2)">Assist in the child's defense.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(r)">"Intake officer" means the person assigned to the court by the Department of Juvenile Services to provide the intake services set forth in this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(s)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Mental disorder" means a behavioral or emotional illness that results from a psychiatric or neurological disorder.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Mental disorder" includes a mental illness that so substantially impairs the mental or emotional functioning of a child as to make care or treatment necessary or advisable for the welfare of the child or for the safety of the child or property of another.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Mental disorder" does not include mental retardation.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(t)">"Mental retardation" means a developmental disability that is evidenced by intellectual functioning that is significantly below average and impairment in the adaptive behavior of a child.</section>
    <section prefix="(u)">"Mentally handicapped child" means a child who is or may be mentally retarded or mentally ill.</section>
    <section prefix="(v)">"Party" includes a child who is the subject of a petition or a peace order request, the child's parent, guardian, or custodian, the petitioner and an adult who is charged under &#xA7; 3-8A-30 of this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(w)">"Peace order proceeding" means a proceeding under &#xA7; 3-8A-19.2 or &#xA7; 3-8A-19.4 of this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(x)">"Peace order request" means the initial pleading filed with the court under &#xA7; 3-8A-19.1 of this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(y)">"Petition" means the pleading filed with the court under &#xA7; 3-8A-13 of this subtitle alleging that a child is a delinquent child or a child in need of supervision or that an adult violated &#xA7; 3-8A-30 of this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(z)">"Qualified expert" means a licensed psychologist or licensed psychiatrist who:<section prefix="(1)">Has expertise in child development, with training in the forensic evaluation of children, as approved by the Secretary of Health and Mental Hygiene;</section><section prefix="(2)">Is familiar with the competency standards contained in this subtitle; and</section><section prefix="(3)">Is familiar with the treatment, training, and restoration programs for children that are available in this State.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(aa)">"Respondent" means the individual against whom a petition or a peace order request is filed.</section>
    <section prefix="(bb)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Shelter care" means the temporary care of children in physically unrestricting facilities.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Shelter care" does not mean care in a State mental health facility.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(cc)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Victim" means:<section prefix="(i)">A person who suffers direct or threatened physical, emotional, or financial harm as a result of a delinquent act; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">An individual against whom an act specified in &#xA7; 3-8A-19.1(b) of this subtitle is committed or alleged to have been committed.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Victim" includes a family member of a minor, disabled, or a deceased victim.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Victim" includes, if the victim is not an individual, the victim's agent or designee.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(dd)">"Violation" means a violation for which a citation is issued under:<section prefix="(1)">&#xA7; 10-113, &#xA7; 10-114, &#xA7; 10-115, or &#xA7; 10-116 of the Criminal Law Article;</section><section prefix="(2)">&#xA7; 10-108 of the Criminal Law Article;</section><section prefix="(3)">&#xA7; 10-132 of the Criminal Law Article; or</section><section prefix="(4)">&#xA7; 26-103 of the Education Article.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(ee)">"Witness" means any person who is or expects to be a State's witness.</section>
  </text>
</law>
