<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcj" order_by="gcj" level="1">Courts and Judicial Proceedings</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcj-3-1701</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated....</catch_line>
  <order_by>1701</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Casualty insurance" has the meaning stated in &#xA7; 1-101 of the Insurance Article.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Commercial insurance" has the meaning stated in &#xA7; 27-601 of the Insurance Article.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">"Good faith" means an informed judgment based on honesty and diligence supported by evidence the insurer knew or should have known at the time the insurer made a decision on a claim.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">"Insurer" has the meaning stated in &#xA7; 1-101 of the Insurance Article.</section>
      <section prefix="(6)">"Property insurance" has the meaning stated in &#xA7; 1-101 of the Insurance Article.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">This subtitle applies only to first-party claims under property and casualty insurance policies issued, sold, or delivered in the State.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, a party may not file an action under this subtitle before the date of a final decision under &#xA7; 27-1001 of the Insurance Article.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Paragraph (1) of this subsection does not apply to an action:<section prefix="(i)">Within the small claim jurisdiction of the District Court under &#xA7; 4-405 of this article;</section><section prefix="(ii)">If the insured and the insurer agree to waive the requirement under paragraph (1) of this subsection; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">Under a commercial insurance policy on a claim with respect to which the applicable limit of liability exceeds $1,000,000.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">This section applies only in a civil action:<section prefix="(1)"><section prefix="(i)">To determine the coverage that exists under the insurer's insurance policy; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">To determine the extent to which the insured is entitled to receive payment from the insurer for a covered loss;</section></section><section prefix="(2)">That alleges that the insurer failed to act in good faith; and</section><section prefix="(3)">That seeks, in addition to the actual damages under the policy, to recover expenses and litigation costs, and interest on those expenses or costs, under subsection (e) of this section.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, if the trier of fact in an action under this section finds in favor of the insured and finds that the insurer failed to act in good faith, the insured may recover from the insurer:<section prefix="(1)">Actual damages, which actual damages may not exceed the limits of the applicable policy;</section><section prefix="(2)">Expenses and litigation costs incurred by the insured in an action under this section or under &#xA7; 27-1001 of the Insurance Article or both, including reasonable attorney's fees; and</section><section prefix="(3)">Interest on all actual damages, expenses, and litigation costs incurred by the insured, computed:<section prefix="(i)">At the rate allowed under &#xA7; 11-107(a) of this article; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">From the date on which the insured's claim would have been paid if the insurer acted in good faith.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">An insurer may not be found to have failed to act in good faith under this section solely on the basis of delay in determining coverage or the extent of payment to which the insured is entitled if the insurer acted within the time period specified by statute or regulation for investigation of a claim by an insurer.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">The amount of attorney's fees recovered from an insurer under subsection (e) of this section may not exceed one-third of the actual damages recovered.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">The clerk of the court shall file a copy of the verdict or any other final disposition of an action under this section with the Maryland Insurance Administration.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">This section does not limit the right of any person to maintain a civil action for damages or other remedies otherwise available under any other provision of law.</section>
    <section prefix="(j)">If a party to the proceeding elects to have the case tried by a jury in accordance with the Maryland Rules, the case shall be tried by a jury.</section>
  </text>
</law>
