<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gcj" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="2-507" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcj-2-507</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">A bailiff shall receive the compensation provided in this section. Unless otherwise provided, the amount is a per diem sum for each day he attends the circuit court.<section prefix="(1)">Allegany County -- As set by the court and approved by the county government.</section><section prefix="(2)">Anne Arundel County -- As set by the court and approved by the county government.</section><section prefix="(3)">Baltimore City -- As set by the city government.</section><section prefix="(4)">Baltimore County -- As set by the court.</section><section prefix="(5)">Calvert County -- As set by the county government and approved by the court.</section><section prefix="(6)">Caroline County -- $15.</section><section prefix="(7)">Carroll County -- As set by the county government.</section><section prefix="(8)">Cecil County -- $17.50.</section><section prefix="(9)">Charles County -- As set by county government.</section><section prefix="(10)">Dorchester County -- As set by the court and confirmed by the County Commissioners.</section><section prefix="(11)">Frederick County -- As set by the County Commissioners.</section><section prefix="(12)">Garrett County -- As set by the court and approved by the County Commissioners.</section><section prefix="(13)">Harford County -- As set by the court.</section><section prefix="(14)">Howard County -- As set by the county government.</section><section prefix="(15)">Kent County -- $25.</section><section prefix="(16)">Montgomery County -- As set by the county government.</section><section prefix="(17)">Prince George's County -- As set by the county government and approved by the court.</section><section prefix="(18)">Queen Anne's County --  As set by the court and approved by the county government.</section><section prefix="(19)">St. Mary's County -- As set by the county government.</section><section prefix="(20)">Somerset County -- $10.</section><section prefix="(21)">Talbot County -- As set by the county government.</section><section prefix="(22)">Washington County -- As set by the court and approved by the County Commissioners.</section><section prefix="(23)">Wicomico County -- As set by the county government.</section><section prefix="(24)">Worcester County -- As set by the county government but not more than $35.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A court crier shall receive the per diem compensation provided by this section for attending the circuit court:<section prefix="(1)">Caroline -- $15;</section><section prefix="(2)">Cecil -- As set by the County Commissioners;</section><section prefix="(3)">Kent -- $17.50;</section><section prefix="(4)">Queen Anne's --  As set by the court and approved by the county government;</section><section prefix="(5)">Somerset -- As set by the County Commissioners;</section><section prefix="(6)">Talbot -- As set by the County Commissioners;</section><section prefix="(7)">Wicomico -- As set by the County Commissioners.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
