<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcj" order_by="" level="1">Courts and Judicial Proceedings</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcj-10-104</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>104</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following terms have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Health care provider" means:<section prefix="(i)">A health care provider, as defined in &#xA7; 3-2A-01 of this article;</section><section prefix="(ii)">An ambulatory surgical facility;</section><section prefix="(iii)">An inpatient facility that is organized primarily in the rehabilitation of disabled persons, through an integrated program of medical and other service provided under competent professional supervision;</section><section prefix="(iv)">A home health agency, as defined in &#xA7; 19-401 of the Health - General Article;</section><section prefix="(v)">Any health institution, service, or program for which a certificate of need is required under Title 19 of the Health - General Article; or</section><section prefix="(vi)">A person who is:<section prefix="1.">Substantially similar to a health care provider described in items (i) through (v) of this paragraph; and</section><section prefix="2.">Regulated by another state to provide health care services.</section></section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"State" means a state of the United States or the District of Columbia.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The provisions of this section apply only to a claim for:<section prefix="(i)">Damages for personal injury;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Medical, hospital, or disability benefits under &#xA7;&#xA7; 19-505 and 19-506 of the Insurance Article;</section><section prefix="(iii)">First party motor vehicle benefits under &#xA7;&#xA7; 19-509 and 19-510 of the Insurance Article; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">First party health insurance benefits.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">This section does not apply to an action for damages filed under Title 3, Subtitle 2A of this article.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Subject to the provisions of paragraphs (1) and (2) of this subsection, the provisions of this section apply to a proceeding in:<section prefix="(i)">The District Court; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">A circuit court if the amount in controversy in the action in the circuit court does not exceed the amount specified in &#xA7; 4-401 of this article for that type of action.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A writing or record of a health care provider described in this section is admissible under this section if:<section prefix="(i)">The writing or record is offered in the trial of a civil action in the District Court or a circuit court;</section><section prefix="(ii)">At least 60 days, except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, before the beginning of the trial, the party who intends to introduce the writing or record:<section prefix="1.">Serves notice of the party's intent to introduce the writing or record without the support of a health care provider's testimony, a list that identifies each writing or record, and a copy of the writing or record on all other parties as provided under Maryland Rule 1-321; and</section><section prefix="2.">Files notice of service and the list that identifies each writing or record with the court; and</section></section><section prefix="(iii)">The writing or record is otherwise admissible.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A party who receives a notice under paragraph (1) of this subsection and intends to introduce another writing or record of a health care provider without a health care provider's testimony shall:<section prefix="(i)">Serve a notice of intent, a list that identifies each writing or record, and a copy of the writing or record at least 30 days before the beginning of the trial; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">File notice of service and the list that identifies each writing or record with the court.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The list required under paragraphs (1) and (2) of this subsection shall include:<section prefix="(i)">The name of the health care provider for each writing or record; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">The date of each writing or record of the health care provider or each date of treatment by the health care provider.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A writing or record of a health care provider made to document a medical, dental, or other health condition, a health care provider's opinion, or the providing of health care is admissible without the support of the testimony of a health care provider as the maker or the custodian of the writing or record as evidence of the existence of a medical, dental, or health condition, the opinion, and the necessity and the providing of health care.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A finder of fact may attach whatever weight to a writing or record that the finder of fact deems appropriate.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A written statement or bill for health care expenses is admissible without the support of the testimony of a health care provider as the maker or the custodian of the statement or bill as evidence of the amount, fairness, and reasonableness of the charges for the services or materials provided.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A finder of fact may attach whatever weight to a writing or record that the finder of fact deems appropriate.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">Nothing contained in this section may be construed to limit the right of a party to:<section prefix="(1)">Request a summons to compel the attendance of a witness;</section><section prefix="(2)">Examine a witness who appears at trial; or</section><section prefix="(3)">Engage in discovery as provided under the Maryland Rules.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
