<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcj" order_by="gcj" level="1">Courts and Judicial Proceedings</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcj-3-1804</section_number>
  <catch_line>A document signed by the parties that records points of agreement expressed by the parties or that c...</catch_line>
  <order_by>1804</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">A document signed by the parties that records points of agreement expressed by the parties or that constitutes an agreement reached by the parties as a result of mediation is not confidential unless the parties agree otherwise in writing.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">In addition to any other disclosure required by law, a mediator, a party, or a person who was present or who otherwise participated in a mediation at the request of the mediator or a party may disclose mediation communications:<section prefix="(1)">To a potential victim or to the appropriate law enforcement authority to the extent that the mediator, party, or person reasonably believes the disclosure is necessary to prevent bodily harm or death to the potential victim;</section><section prefix="(2)">To the extent necessary to assert or defend against allegations of mediator misconduct or negligence;</section><section prefix="(3)">To the extent necessary to assert or defend against allegations of professional misconduct or malpractice by a party or any person who was present or who otherwise participated in the mediation at the request of a party, except that a mediator may not be compelled to participate in a proceeding arising out of the disclosure; or</section><section prefix="(4)">To the extent necessary to assert or defend against a claim or defense that, because of fraud, duress, or misrepresentation, a contract arising out of a mediation should be rescinded or damages should be awarded.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A court may order mediation communications to be disclosed only to the extent that the court determines that the disclosure is necessary to prevent an injustice or harm to the public interest that is of sufficient magnitude in the particular case to outweigh the integrity of mediation proceedings.</section>
  </text>
</law>
