<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcj" order_by="gcj" level="1">Courts and Judicial Proceedings</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcj-3-801</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated....</catch_line>
  <order_by>801</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Abuse" means:<section prefix="(1)">Sexual abuse of a child, whether a physical injury is sustained or not; or</section><section prefix="(2)">Physical or mental injury of a child under circumstances that indicate that the child's health or welfare is harmed or is at substantial risk of being harmed by:<section prefix="(i)">A parent or other individual who has permanent or temporary care or custody or responsibility for supervision of the child; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">A household or family member.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Adjudicatory hearing" means a hearing under this subtitle to determine whether the allegations in the petition, other than the allegation that the child requires the court's intervention, are true.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">"Adult" means an individual who is at least 18 years old.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"Child" means an individual under the age of 18 years.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">"Child in need of assistance" means a child who requires court intervention because:<section prefix="(1)">The child has been abused, has been neglected, has a developmental disability, or has a mental disorder; and</section><section prefix="(2)">The child's parents, guardian, or custodian are unable or unwilling to give proper care and attention to the child and the child's needs.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(g)">"CINA" means a child in need of assistance.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">"Commit" means to transfer custody.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">"Court" means the circuit court for a county sitting as the juvenile court.</section>
    <section prefix="(j)">"Custodian" means a person or governmental agency to whom custody of a child has been given by order of court, including a court other than the juvenile court.</section>
    <section prefix="(k)">"Custody" means the right and obligation, unless otherwise determined by the court, to provide ordinary care for a child and determine placement.</section>
    <section prefix="(l)">"Developmental disability" means a severe chronic disability of an individual that:<section prefix="(1)">Is attributable to a physical or mental impairment, other than the sole diagnosis of mental illness, or to a combination of mental and physical impairments;</section><section prefix="(2)">Is likely to continue indefinitely;</section><section prefix="(3)">Results in an inability to live independently without external support or continuing and regular assistance; and</section><section prefix="(4)">Reflects the need for a combination and sequence of special, interdisciplinary, or generic care, treatment, or other services that are individually planned and coordinated for the individual.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(m)">"Disposition hearing" means a hearing under this subtitle to determine:<section prefix="(1)">Whether a child is in need of assistance; and</section><section prefix="(2)">If so, the nature of the court's intervention to protect the child's health, safety, and well-being.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(n)">"Guardian" means a person to whom guardianship of a child has been given by order of court, including a court other than the juvenile court.</section>
    <section prefix="(o)">"Guardianship" means an award by a court, including a court other than the juvenile court, of the authority to make ordinary and emergency decisions as to the child's care, welfare, education, physical and mental health, and the right to pursue support.</section>
    <section prefix="(p)">"Local department" means:<section prefix="(1)">The local department of social services for the county in which the court is located; or</section><section prefix="(2)">In Montgomery County, the county department of health and human services.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(q)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Mental disorder" means a behavioral or emotional illness that results from a psychiatric or neurological disorder.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Mental disorder" includes a mental illness that so substantially impairs the mental or emotional functioning of an individual as to make care or treatment necessary or advisable for the welfare of the individual or for the safety of the person or property of another.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Mental disorder" does not include mental retardation.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(r)">"Mental injury" means the observable, identifiable, and substantial impairment of a child's mental or psychological ability to function.</section>
    <section prefix="(s)">"Neglect" means the leaving of a child unattended or other failure to give proper care and attention to a child by any parent or individual who has permanent or temporary care or custody or responsibility for supervision of the child under circumstances that indicate:<section prefix="(1)">That the child's health or welfare is harmed or placed at substantial risk of harm; or</section><section prefix="(2)">That the child has suffered mental injury or been placed at substantial risk of mental injury.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(t)">"Parent" means a natural or adoptive parent whose parental rights have not been terminated.</section>
    <section prefix="(u)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Party" means:<section prefix="(i)">A child who is the subject of a petition;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The child's parent, guardian, or custodian;</section><section prefix="(iii)">The petitioner; or</section><section prefix="(iv)">An adult who is charged under &#xA7; 3-828 of this subtitle.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Party" does not include a foster parent.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(v)">"Reasonable efforts" means efforts that are reasonably likely to achieve the objectives set forth in &#xA7; 3-816.1(b)(1) and (2) of this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(w)">"Relative" means an individual who is:<section prefix="(1)">Related to the child by blood or marriage within five degrees of consanguinity or affinity under the civil law; and</section><section prefix="(2)"><section prefix="(i)">At least 21 years old; or</section><section prefix="(ii)"><section prefix="1.">At least 18 years old; and</section><section prefix="2.">Lives with a spouse who is at least 21 years old.</section></section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(x)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Sexual abuse" means an act that involves sexual molestation or sexual exploitation of a child by:<section prefix="(i)">A parent or other individual who has permanent or temporary care or custody or responsibility for supervision of the child; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">A household or family member.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Sexual abuse" includes:<section prefix="(i)">Allowing or encouraging a child to engage in:<section prefix="1.">Obscene photography, films, poses, or similar activity;</section><section prefix="2.">Pornographic photography, films, poses, or similar activity; or</section><section prefix="3.">Prostitution;</section></section><section prefix="(ii)">Human trafficking;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Incest;</section><section prefix="(iv)">Rape;</section><section prefix="(v)">Sexual offense in any degree;</section><section prefix="(vi)">Sodomy; and</section><section prefix="(vii)">Unnatural or perverted sexual practices.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(y)">"Shelter care" means a temporary placement of a child outside of the home at any time before disposition.</section>
    <section prefix="(z)">"Shelter care hearing" means a hearing held before disposition to determine whether the temporary placement of the child outside of the home is warranted.</section>
    <section prefix="(aa)">"TPR proceeding" means a proceeding to terminate parental rights.</section>
    <section prefix="(bb)">"Voluntary placement" means a placement in accordance with &#xA7; 5-525(b)(1)(i) or (iii) of the Family Law Article.</section>
    <section prefix="(cc)">"Voluntary placement hearing" means a hearing to obtain a judicial determination as to whether continuing a voluntary placement is in the best interests of the child.</section>
  </text>
</law>
