<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gcj" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="3-1101" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcj-3-1101</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Expense of an emergency response, containment, cleanup, and abatement" means the reasonable costs associated with the repair or replacement of personal protective equipment:<section prefix="(i)">Owned by:</section><section prefix="(ii)">Damaged through proper use during an emergency response, containment, cleanup, and abatement of a release of hazardous materials resulting from a traffic accident involving a motor vehicle operated by a motor carrier that is transporting hazardous materials or from a release or threatened release of hazardous materials at a fixed facility.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Expense of an emergency response, containment, cleanup, and abatement" includes the costs of replacing the chemicals that are used or damaged during an emergency response, containment, cleanup, and abatement.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Fixed facility" means any installation, structure, or premises, above ground or underground, in which hazardous materials are stored with a capacity to store more than 1,000 pounds of hazardous materials.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Fixed facility" does not include a farm or any building or structure associated with a farm.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Hazardous materials" means a substance or material in a quantity or form that the United States Secretary of Transportation designates may pose an unreasonable risk to health and safety of individuals or to property when transported in commerce.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Hazardous materials" includes any grouping or classification of materials, that the United States Secretary of Transportation designates as a hazardous material, including:<section prefix="(i)">Explosives;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Radioactive materials;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Etiologic agents;</section><section prefix="(iv)">Flammable liquids or solids;</section><section prefix="(v)">Combustible liquids or solids;</section><section prefix="(vi)">Poisons;</section><section prefix="(vii)">Oxidizing or corrosive materials; and</section><section prefix="(viii)">Compressed gases.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"Highway" has the same meaning as provided in &#xA7; 11-127 of the Transportation Article.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">"Motor carrier" means a common carrier by motor vehicle, contract carrier by motor vehicle, and private carrier by motor vehicle that carries a hazardous material in commerce.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">"Person in control", with respect to a release or threatened release of hazardous materials at a fixed facility, means:<section prefix="(1)">The owner of the hazardous materials; and</section><section prefix="(2)">The owner or operator of the fixed facility involved in the release or threatened release of hazardous materials at the time of or immediately before the release or threatened release.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(h)">"Volunteer fire company" includes a volunteer fire company, a volunteer hazardous material response team, a volunteer rescue squad, a volunteer ambulance squad, or any other volunteer organization designated by a local jurisdiction as a responder to a release or threatened release of hazardous materials.</section>
  </text>
</law>
