<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcj" order_by="" level="1">Courts and Judicial Proceedings</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcj-3-1503.1</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>1503.1</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">A petition under this subtitle may be filed with a commissioner when the Office of the District Court Clerk is not open for business.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">If a petition is filed with a commissioner and the commissioner finds that there are reasonable grounds to believe that the respondent has committed, and is likely to commit in the future, an act specified in &#xA7; 3-1503(a) of this subtitle against the petitioner, the commissioner may issue an interim peace order to protect the petitioner.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">An interim peace order:<section prefix="(1)">Shall contain only the relief that is minimally necessary to protect the petitioner; and</section><section prefix="(2)">May order the respondent to:<section prefix="(i)">Refrain from committing or threatening to commit an act specified in &#xA7; 3-1503(a) of this subtitle against the petitioner;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Refrain from contacting, attempting to contact, or harassing the petitioner;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Refrain from entering the residence of the petitioner; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">Remain away from the place of employment, school, or temporary residence of the petitioner.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">An interim peace order shall state the date, time, and location for the temporary peace order hearing and a tentative date, time, and location for a final peace order hearing.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">Except as provided in subsection (g) of this section, or unless the court continues the hearing for good cause, a temporary peace order hearing shall be held on the first or second day on which a District Court judge is sitting after issuance of the interim peace order.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">An interim peace order shall include in at least 10-point bold type:<section prefix="(i)">Notice to the respondent that:<section prefix="1.">The respondent must give the court written notice of each change of address;</section><section prefix="2.">If the respondent fails to appear at the temporary peace order hearing or any later hearing, the respondent may be served with any other orders or notices in the case by first-class mail at the respondent's last known address;</section><section prefix="3.">The date, time, and location of the final peace order hearing is tentative only, and subject to change; and</section><section prefix="4.">If the respondent does not attend the temporary peace order hearing, the respondent may call the Office of the Clerk of the District Court at the number provided in the order to find out the actual date, time, and location of any final peace order hearing;</section></section><section prefix="(ii)">A statement of all possible forms and duration of relief that a temporary peace order or final peace order may contain;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Notice to the petitioner and respondent that, at the hearing, a judge may issue a temporary peace order that grants any or all of the relief requested in the petition or may deny the petition, whether or not the respondent is in court;</section><section prefix="(iv)">A warning to the respondent that violation of an interim peace order is a crime and that a law enforcement officer shall arrest the respondent, with or without a warrant, and take the respondent into custody if the officer has probable cause to believe that the respondent has violated any provision of the interim peace order; and</section><section prefix="(v)">The phone number of the Office of the District Court Clerk.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">Whenever a commissioner issues an interim peace order, the commissioner shall:<section prefix="(1)">Immediately forward a copy of the petition and interim peace order to the appropriate law enforcement agency for service on the respondent; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Before the hearing scheduled in the interim peace order, transfer the case file and the return of service, if any, to the Office of the District Court Clerk.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">A law enforcement officer shall:<section prefix="(1)">Immediately on receipt of a petition and interim peace order, serve them on the respondent named in the order; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Immediately after service, make a return of service to the commissioner's office or, if the Office of the District Court Clerk is open for business, to the clerk.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as otherwise provided in this subsection, an interim peace order shall be effective until the earlier of:<section prefix="(i)">The temporary peace order hearing under &#xA7; 3-1504 of this subtitle; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">The end of the second business day the Office of the Clerk of the District Court is open following the issuance of an interim peace order.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If the court is closed on the day on which the interim peace order is due to expire, the interim peace order shall be effective until the next day on which the court is open, at which time the court shall hold a temporary peace order hearing.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(h)">A decision of a commissioner to grant or deny relief under this section is not binding on, and does not affect any power granted to or duty imposed on, a judge of a circuit court or the District Court under any law, including any power to grant or deny a petition for a temporary peace order or final peace order.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">An individual who knowingly provides false information in a petition filed under this section is guilty of a misdemeanor and on conviction is subject to a fine not exceeding $1,000 or imprisonment not exceeding 90 days or both.</section>
  </text>
</law>
