<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gcj" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="1-603" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcj-1-603</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The court is composed of a Chief Judge and the number of associate judges provided for in subsection (b) of this section. If the Chief Judge is relieved of the Judge's duties as Chief Judge but not removed from office as a judge of the District Court, the Chief Judge shall serve for the remainder of the Judge's term of office as a District Court judge, as a resident judge of the Judge's district and county of residence, without reference to the maximum number of judges for that district prescribed in subsection (b) of this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">In each of the districts provided for in &#xA7; 1-602 of this subtitle, there shall be the following number of associate judges of the District Court:<section prefix="(1)">District 1 -- 27</section><section prefix="(2)">District 2 -- 6, two to be appointed from Wicomico County and two to be appointed from Worcester County</section><section prefix="(3)">District 3 -- 6, two to be appointed from Cecil County</section><section prefix="(4)">District 4 -- 5, two to be appointed from Calvert County and two to be appointed from Charles County</section><section prefix="(5)">District 5 -- 15</section><section prefix="(6)">District 6 -- 11</section><section prefix="(7)">District 7 -- 9</section><section prefix="(8)">District 8 -- 13</section><section prefix="(9)">District 9 -- 4</section><section prefix="(10)">District 10 -- 7, two to be appointed from Carroll County and five to be appointed from Howard County</section><section prefix="(11)">District 11 -- 5, three to be appointed from Frederick County and two to be appointed from Washington County</section><section prefix="(12)">District 12 -- 3, two to be appointed from Allegany County</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">In each district comprising more than one county, there shall be at least one District Court judge resident and holding court in each county in the district.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">To assure that the services of the District Court are readily and practicably available in all areas of District 8 and to assure that these services are provided to all citizens of District 8 with a minimum of inconvenience and a maximum of availability, there shall be a court facility physically located in each of the following areas of that district, and at least one judge shall sit regularly in each location:<section prefix="(1)">The Towson area;</section><section prefix="(2)">The Catonsville area; and</section><section prefix="(3)">The Essex area.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
