<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcj" order_by="gcj" level="1">Courts and Judicial Proceedings</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcj-9-121</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this section the following words have the meanings indicated....</catch_line>
  <order_by>121</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Client" means a person who communicates to or receives services from a licensed certified social worker regarding his mental or emotional condition, or from any other person participating directly or vitally with a licensed certified social worker in rendering those services, in consultation with or under direct supervision of a licensed certified social worker.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Licensed certified social worker" means any person licensed as a certified social worker under Title 19 of the Health Occupations Article.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">"Witness" means a licensed certified social worker or any other person participating directly or vitally with a licensed certified social worker in rendering services to a client, in consultation with or under direct supervision of a licensed certified social worker.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Unless otherwise provided, in all judicial or administrative proceedings, a client has a privilege to refuse to disclose, and to prevent a witness from disclosing, communications made while the client was receiving counseling or any information that by its nature would show that such counseling occurred.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">If a client is incompetent to assert or waive this privilege, a guardian shall be appointed and shall act for the client. A previously appointed guardian has the same authority.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">There is no privilege if:<section prefix="(1)">A disclosure is necessary for the purpose of placing the client in a facility for mental illness;</section><section prefix="(2)">A judge finds that the client, after being informed there will be no privilege, makes communications in the course of an examination ordered by the court;</section><section prefix="(3)">In a civil or criminal proceeding:<section prefix="(i)">The client introduces the client's mental condition as an element of the claim or defense; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">After the client's death, the client's mental condition is introduced by any party claiming or defending through or as a beneficiary of the client;</section></section><section prefix="(4)">The client or the personal representative of the client makes a claim against the licensed certified social worker for malpractice; or</section><section prefix="(5)">The client expressly consents to waive the privilege, or in the case of death or disability, the client's personal representative waives the privilege for purpose of making a claim or bringing suit on a policy of insurance on life, health, or physical condition.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">There is no privilege in:<section prefix="(1)">Any administrative or judicial nondelinquent juvenile proceeding;</section><section prefix="(2)">Any guardianship and adoption proceeding initiated by a child placement agency;</section><section prefix="(3)">Any guardianship and protective services proceeding concerning disabled persons; or</section><section prefix="(4)">Any criminal or delinquency proceeding in which there is a charge of child abuse or neglect or which arises out of an investigation of suspected child abuse or neglect.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
