<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gcj" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="1-302" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcj-1-302</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, "former judge" means a judge who previously served in a court.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Except as provided in subsection (c) of this section, the Chief Judge of the Court of Appeals may assign any former judge to sit temporarily in any court if the temporary assignment is approved by the administrative judge of the circuit in which the former judge is to be assigned and if the former judge:<section prefix="(1)">Has served in the aggregate at least 2 years as a judge, except that:<section prefix="(i)">In Baltimore City and Charles, Prince George's, and Harford counties the former judge shall have served in the aggregate at least 3 years as a judge; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">In Talbot County, the former judge shall have served in the aggregate at least 1 year as a judge;</section></section><section prefix="(2)">Has been approved for assignment by a majority of the judges of the Court of Appeals;</section><section prefix="(3)">Meets the standards established by this section as well as any additional standards established by rule of the Court of Appeals; and</section><section prefix="(4)">Has consented to the assignment.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A former judge may not be recalled for temporary assignment if the judge:<section prefix="(1)">Was removed or involuntarily retired from judicial office pursuant to the Constitution or laws of this State;</section><section prefix="(2)">Voluntarily retired by reason of disability;</section><section prefix="(3)">Had the most recent service as a judge terminated by reason of defeat for election to judicial office or by rejection of confirmation by the Senate;</section><section prefix="(4)">Was censured by the Court of Appeals upon recommendation of the Commission on Judicial Disabilities; or</section><section prefix="(5)">Is engaged in the practice of law.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A former judge recalled under this section may not be temporarily assigned for more than 180 working days in any calendar year. However, if the case which the former judge is hearing at the end of the 180-day period is not concluded, the time may be extended until that case is concluded.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">A former judge temporarily assigned under this section has all the power and authority of a judge of the court to which he is assigned.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Whether or not he is receiving a retirement allowance, a former judge temporarily assigned under this section shall receive a per diem compensation for each day he is actually engaged in the discharge of judicial duties based on the current annual salary of the court in which he served immediately prior to his resignation or retirement. The per diem shall be computed on the basis of 246 working days a year. If the sum of the per diem payments received by a former judge in any one calendar year, when added to the retirement allowance he is entitled to receive during that calendar year, equals the annual salary of a judge of the court in which the former judge served immediately prior to the termination of his active service, no further per diem is payable to the former judge in that calendar year.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A deduction may not be withheld for health benefits or retirement purposes from the compensation paid to a former judge during temporary judicial service. The performance of temporary judicial service does not provide additional service for retirement credit purposes.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">In addition to the per diem compensation provided for in paragraph (1), he shall be reimbursed for reasonable expenses actually incurred by reason of the assignment, in accordance with State joint travel regulations.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">Preference for temporary assignment shall be given to retired judges from the circuit in which the temporary assignment is to take place.</section>
  </text>
</law>
