<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcl" order_by="gcl" level="1">Commercial Law</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcl-14-1320</section_number>
  <catch_line>This section applies to a gift card that:...</catch_line>
  <order_by>1320</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">This section applies to a gift card that:<section prefix="(1)">Is processed through a national credit or debit card service; and</section><section prefix="(2)">May be used to purchase goods or services from multiple unaffiliated sellers of goods and services.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A gift card may be subject to expiration or a postsale fee, including a service fee, dormancy fee, account maintenance fee, cash-out fee, gift card replacement fee, activation fee, or reactivation fee, if the following disclosures are printed clearly in a visible place on the front or back of the gift card in at least 10 point type:<section prefix="(1)">With respect to the expiration date, the date on which the gift card expires; and</section><section prefix="(2)">With respect to a postsale fee:<section prefix="(i)">The amount of the fee;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The circumstances under which the fee will be imposed;</section><section prefix="(iii)">The frequency with which the fee will be imposed; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">Whether the fee is triggered by inactivity.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">If the disclosures required under subsection (b) of this section are hidden by the packaging of the gift card, the seller or issuer shall give the purchaser a written statement of the disclosures before the gift card is sold or issued.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">In addition to printing the information required under subsection (b) of this section on a gift card:<section prefix="(1)">If a gift card is sold or issued by electronic means, the seller or issuer shall include a conspicuous written statement of the information in the electronic message offering the gift card; and</section><section prefix="(2)">If a gift card is sold or issued by telephonic means, the seller or issuer, before the gift card is sold, shall state the information to the purchaser.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">Unless the change benefits the consumer, a term or condition disclosed under subsection (b) of this section may not be changed after the date of purchase or issuance.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">A violation of any provision of this section:<section prefix="(1)">Is an unfair or deceptive trade practice within the meaning of Title 13 of this article; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Is subject to the enforcement and penalty provisions contained in Title 13 of this article, except &#xA7; 13-411 of this article.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
