<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gcl" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="12-409.1" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcl-12-409.1</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Covered loan" means a mortgage loan made under this subtitle that meets the criteria for a loan subject to the federal Home Ownership Equity Protection Act set forth in 15 U.S.C. &#xA7; 1602(aa), as modified from time to time by Regulation Z, 12 C.F.R. Part 226, except that the comparison percentages for the mortgage loan shall be one percentage point less than those specified in 15 U.S.C. &#xA7; 1602(aa), as modified from time to time by Regulation Z, 12 C.F.R. Part 226.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Fully indexed rate" means the index rate, as defined in the secondary mortgage loan documents, prevailing at the time the secondary mortgage loan is approved by the lender, plus the margin that will apply after the expiration of an introductory interest rate.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">"Home buyer education or housing counseling" means instruction on preparing for home ownership, shopping for a home, obtaining a mortgage, loan closing, and life as a homeowner.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A lender may not make a secondary mortgage loan without giving due regard to the borrower's ability to repay the secondary mortgage loan in accordance with its terms, including the fully indexed rate of the secondary mortgage loan, if applicable, and property taxes and homeowner's insurance whether or not an escrow account is established for the collection and payment of these expenses.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Due regard to a borrower's ability to repay a secondary mortgage loan must include:<section prefix="(i)">Consideration of the borrower's debt to income ratio, including existing debts and other obligations; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Verification of the borrower's gross monthly income and assets by review of third-party written documentation reasonably believed by the lender to be accurate and complete.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Acceptable third-party written documentation includes:<section prefix="(i)">The borrower's Internal Revenue Service form W-2;</section><section prefix="(ii)">A copy of the borrower's income tax return;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Payroll receipts;</section><section prefix="(iv)">The records of a financial institution; or</section><section prefix="(v)">Other third-party documents that provide reasonably reliable evidence of the borrower's income or assets.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">This subsection does not apply to a secondary mortgage loan:<section prefix="(i)">Approved for government guaranty by the Federal Housing Administration, the Veterans Administration, the United States Department of Agriculture, the Maryland Department of Housing and Community Development, or the Community Development Administration; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">That refinances an existing mortgage loan if the refinance mortgage loan is:</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this subsection, "loan application" has the meaning stated in &#xA7; 12-125 of this title.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">At the time a borrower completes a loan application for a covered loan, the lender shall provide the borrower with:<section prefix="(i)">A written recommendation that the borrower seek home buyer education or housing counseling; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">A list of agencies and organizations approved by the county in which the residential real property securing the covered loan is located to provide home buyer education or housing counseling.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
