<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gcl" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="14-12B-01" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcl-14-12B-01</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Business day" means Monday through Friday.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Business day" includes Saturday if:<section prefix="(i)">The seller of health club services is open to members on Saturday; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">The health club services contract specifically identifies Saturday as a business day for purposes of the cancellation provisions of this subtitle.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Business day" does not include legal holidays.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Division" means the Consumer Protection Division of the Office of the Attorney General.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Health club services agreement" means an agreement under which:<section prefix="(i)">The buyer of a health club service purchases, or becomes obligated to purchase, health club services to be rendered over a period longer than 3 months; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">The seller of a health club services agreement collects more than 3 months' payment in advance; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">The service to be rendered under the agreement is for personal, family, or household use.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Health club services" includes health spa, figure salon, weight reduction center, self defense school, or other physical culture service enterprises offering facilities for the preservation, maintenance, encouragement, or development of physical fitness or physical well-being.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Health club services" does not include agreements for services rendered by:<section prefix="(i)">Any nonprofit public or private school, college, or university;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The State, or any of its political subdivisions; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">Any nonprofit religious, ethnic, community, or service organization.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
