<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gcl" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="14-3103" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcl-14-3103</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, "excess charges" means an amount, in excess of the estimate provided to a consumer, charged by a household goods mover for additional services that:<section prefix="(1)">Are provided before or during an intrastate move; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Are necessary because of circumstances that:<section prefix="(i)">Are beyond the control of the household goods mover; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Could not have been reasonably anticipated by the household goods mover.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Subject to subsection (e) of this section, a household goods mover shall provide a written estimate to a consumer before providing household goods moving services for an intrastate move.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The written estimate shall:<section prefix="(1)">Separately identify each household goods moving service that the household goods mover will provide and the price of each service;</section><section prefix="(2)">Separately identify each fee that the consumer will or may be required to pay;</section><section prefix="(3)">State the estimated total price;</section><section prefix="(4)">State the time and method of payment for the household goods moving services; and</section><section prefix="(5)">Indicate clearly whether the estimate is binding on the consumer and household goods mover.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A consumer who receives a binding estimate from a household goods mover may not be required to pay more than the estimated total price stated in the estimate for the household goods moving services described in the estimate.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A consumer who receives a nonbinding estimate from a household goods mover may not be required to pay more than 125% of the estimated total price stated in the estimate for the household goods moving services described in the estimate, plus any applicable excess charges.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">A consumer may waive the right to receive a written estimate under subsection (a) of this section if the waiver is made voluntarily and without coercion by the household goods mover.</section>
  </text>
</law>
