<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcl" order_by="" level="1">Commercial Law</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcl-12-511</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>511</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, "billing error" means the initial occurrence of an error in a billing statement given to a buyer by the holder of an account, which error results from:<section prefix="(1)">An omission or commission by the holder in posting any debit or credit;</section><section prefix="(2)">The computation of any amount; or</section><section prefix="(3)">Any similar error of an accounting nature.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The provisions of this section do not apply to a status inquiry made under &#xA7; 12-510 of this subtitle if a billing error is not asserted by the buyer.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">If, on receipt of a billing statement from a holder, a buyer believes the billing is in error, he may inquire as to the computation of the statement. The inquiry by the buyer shall:<section prefix="(1)">Be made within 60 days of receipt of the billing statement which contains the claimed error;</section><section prefix="(2)">Be in writing and sent to the holder by mail at the address designated on the statement pursuant to &#xA7; 12-503(i) of this subtitle; and</section><section prefix="(3)">Set forth sufficient information to enable the holder to identify:<section prefix="(i)">The buyer and the account;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The amount and transaction shown in the billing statement which the buyer in good faith believes to be a billing error; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">The facts providing the basis for the buyer's belief that the billing statement is in error.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">On receipt of an inquiry under this section, the holder shall:<section prefix="(1)">Within 30 days after its receipt, mail a written acknowledgement to the buyer; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Within 60 days after its receipt, before taking any action to collect the amount believed by the buyer to be a billing error:<section prefix="(i)">Make appropriate corrections in the account and mail to the buyer a written notice which states that the amount believed to be in error has been corrected and will be so shown on the next billing statement mailed to him; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">Send to the buyer a written notice which sets forth in a clear and definitive manner the reasons why the holder believes that the account was correctly shown in the statement.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">Notwithstanding the receipt of an inquiry, the holder may:<section prefix="(1)">Transmit to the buyer regular periodic billing statements which include the amount believed by the buyer to be a billing error; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Undertake collection of any amount which the buyer does not dispute under this section.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">On or before the first billing statement for a new account, the holder shall send to the buyer a written notice which describes the procedures to be followed by a buyer under this section to claim a billing error.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">On receipt of an inquiry under this section, until the holder has complied with the provisions of this section, he may not communicate to any person, including any credit bureau or credit reporting agency, unfavorable credit information concerning the buyer and based on the buyer's failure to pay the amount believed by him to be a billing error.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">If a holder of an account receives a written inquiry from a buyer under this section and fails to comply with the requirements of this section, then:<section prefix="(1)">If the disputed amount is not a billing error, the holder:<section prefix="(i)">May proceed to collect the disputed amount; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Shall forfeit the right to collect any finance charge assessed on the account in connection with the disputed amount from the date of the mailing of the written inquiry to the date the holder complies with this section; or</section></section><section prefix="(2)">If the disputed amount is a billing error, the holder:<section prefix="(i)">May not collect the amount of the error or any finance charge on that amount; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Is liable to the buyer for his actual damages sustained as a result of the failure of the holder to comply with this section.</section></section></section>
  </text>
</law>
