<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcl" order_by="gcl" level="1">Commercial Law</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcl-21-102</section_number>
  <catch_line>Except as otherwise provided in subsections (b) and (c) of this section, this title applies to elect...</catch_line>
  <order_by>102</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Except as otherwise provided in subsections (b) and (c) of this section, this title applies to electronic records and electronic signatures relating to a transaction.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">This title does not apply to a transaction to the extent it is governed by:<section prefix="(1)">A law governing the creation and execution of wills, codicils, or testamentary trusts;</section><section prefix="(2)">The Maryland Uniform Commercial Code, other than &#xA7;&#xA7; 1-107 and 1-206 and Titles 2 and 2A;</section><section prefix="(3)">The Uniform Computer Information Transactions Act;</section><section prefix="(4)">A law or regulation governing notice of:<section prefix="(i)">The cancellation or termination of utility services, including water, heat, and power;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Default, acceleration, repossession, foreclosure, eviction, or the right to cure, under a credit agreement, mortgage, or a rental agreement for a primary residence of an individual;</section><section prefix="(iii)">The cancellation or termination of health insurance, health insurance benefits, or life insurance benefits, excluding annuities; or</section><section prefix="(iv)">Recall of a product, or material failure of a product, that risks endangering health or safety; and</section></section><section prefix="(5)">A law governing adoption, divorce, or other family law matters.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">This title does not apply to:<section prefix="(1)">Court orders, notices, or official court documents, except as provided in the Maryland Rules; or</section><section prefix="(2)">Documents required to accompany transportation or handling of hazardous materials, pesticides, or other toxic or dangerous materials.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">This title applies to an electronic record or electronic signature otherwise excluded from the application of this title under subsection (b) of this section to the extent it is governed by a law other than those specified in subsection (b) of this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">A transaction subject to this title is also subject to other applicable substantive law.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The provisions of this title may not modify, limit, or supersede the provisions of the federal Electronic Signatures in Global and National Commerce Act as it relates to use of an electronic record to provide or make available information that is required to be provided or made available in writing to a consumer.</section>
  </text>
</law>
