<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcl" order_by="gcl" level="1">Commercial Law</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcl-9-807</section_number>
  <catch_line>** TAKES EFFECT JULY 1, 2013 PER CHAPTER 674 OF 2012 **...</catch_line>
  <order_by>807</order_by>
  <text>** TAKES EFFECT JULY 1, 2013 PER CHAPTER 674 OF 2012 **<section prefix="(a)">The filing of an initial financing statement in the office specified in &#xA7; 9-501 continues the effectiveness of a pre-effective-date financing statement if:<section prefix="(1)">The filing of an initial financing statement in that office would be effective to perfect a security interest under this title, as amended by the Act;</section><section prefix="(2)">The pre-effective-date financing statement was filed in an office in another state; and</section><section prefix="(3)">The initial financing statement satisfies subsection (c).</section></section><section prefix="(b)">The filing of an initial financing statement under subsection (a) continues the effectiveness of the pre-effective-date financing statement:<section prefix="(1)">If the initial financing statement is filed before the Act takes effect, for the period provided in &#xA7; 9-515, as it existed before the Act takes effect, with respect to an initial financing statement; and</section><section prefix="(2)">If the initial financing statement is filed after the Act takes effect, for the period provided in &#xA7; 9-515, as amended by the Act, with respect to an initial financing statement.</section></section><section prefix="(c)">To be effective for purposes of subsection (a), an initial financing statement must:<section prefix="(1)">Satisfy the requirements of Subtitle 5, as amended by the Act, for an initial financing statement;</section><section prefix="(2)">Identify the pre-effective-date financing statement by indicating the office in which the financing statement was filed and providing the dates of filing and file numbers, if any, of the financing statement and of the most recent continuation statement filed with respect to the financing statement; and</section><section prefix="(3)">Indicate that the pre-effective-date financing statement remains effective.</section></section></text>
</law>
