<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcl" order_by="gcl" level="1">Commercial Law</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcl-14-1905</section_number>
  <catch_line>The information statement required under &#xA7; 14-1904 of this subtitle shall include:...</catch_line>
  <order_by>1905</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The information statement required under &#xA7; 14-1904 of this subtitle shall include:<section prefix="(1)">An accurate statement of the consumer's right to review any file on the consumer maintained by any consumer reporting agency, and the right of the consumer to receive a copy of a consumer report containing all information in that file as provided under the federal Fair Credit Reporting Act (15 U.S.C. &#xA7; 1681g) and under &#xA7; 14-1206 of this title;</section><section prefix="(2)">A statement that a copy of the consumer report containing all information in the consumer's file will be furnished free of charge by the consumer reporting agency if requested by the consumer within 30 days of receiving a notice of a denial of credit as provided under the federal Fair Credit Reporting Act (15 U.S.C. &#xA7; 1681j) and under &#xA7; 14-1209 of this title;</section><section prefix="(3)">A statement that a nominal charge not to exceed $5 may be imposed on the consumer by the consumer reporting agency for a copy of the consumer report containing all the information in the consumer's file, if the consumer has not been denied credit within 30 days from receipt of the consumer's request;</section><section prefix="(4)">A complete and accurate statement of the consumer's right to dispute the completeness or accuracy of any item on the consumer contained in any file that is maintained by any consumer reporting agency, as provided under the federal Fair Credit Reporting Act (15 U.S.C. &#xA7; 1681i) and under &#xA7; 14-1208 of this title;</section><section prefix="(5)">A complete and detailed description of the services to be performed by the credit services business for or on behalf of the consumer, and the total amount the consumer will have to pay for the services; and</section><section prefix="(6)">A statement that accurately reported information may not be permanently removed from the file of a consumer reporting agency.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A credit services business required to obtain a license pursuant to &#xA7; 14-1902 of this subtitle shall include in the information statement required under &#xA7; 14-1904 of this subtitle:<section prefix="(1)">A statement of the consumer's right to file a complaint pursuant to &#xA7; 14-1911 of this subtitle;</section><section prefix="(2)">The address of the Commissioner where such complaints should be filed; and</section><section prefix="(3)">A statement that a bond exists and the consumer's right to proceed against the bond under the circumstances and in the manner set forth in &#xA7; 14-1910 of this subtitle.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
