<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcl" order_by="" level="1">Commercial Law</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcl-12-308</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>308</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">At the time a loan is made, the lender shall deliver to the borrower a statement in the English language which:<section prefix="(i)">Quotes &#xA7;&#xA7; 12-306, 12-307, 12-312, and 12-313 of this subtitle, in their entireties; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Complies with &#xA7; 12-106(b) of this title.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If there are two or more borrowers, the lender:<section prefix="(i)">May deliver the statement to any one of the borrowers; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">At the request of any other borrower, shall deliver a copy of the statement to that borrower within 10 days after the request.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in paragraphs (2), (3), and (4) of this subsection, at the time a lender receives a payment on account of a loan, the lender shall deliver to the person making the payment a receipt which specifies:<section prefix="(i)">The amount applied to principal;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The amount applied to interest and other charges; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">The unpaid principal balance of the loan.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The lender may deliver an unitemized receipt at the time of payment if he delivers the required itemized receipt within 10 days after the payment.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The lender is not required to issue a receipt if, before the due date of each payment, he regularly delivers to the borrower a billing statement which specifies:<section prefix="(i)">The previous unpaid principal balance of the loan;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The amount and date of each payment made during the billing period;</section><section prefix="(iii)">The amount of each of these payments applied to interest;</section><section prefix="(iv)">The amount of each of these payments applied to principal;</section><section prefix="(v)">The current unpaid principal balance; and</section><section prefix="(vi)">The amount and due date of the next maturing installment.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The lender is not required to issue a receipt if the lender issues to the borrower a payment book or coupon book and payment is made by check or money order.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A lender shall permit a borrower to prepay a loan in full or in part at any time, without penalty.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Each partial prepayment shall be applied:<section prefix="(i)">First, to any interest accrued on the unpaid principal balance to the date of the payment; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Then, to the unpaid principal balance.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">After full repayment of a loan, the lender shall:<section prefix="(1)"><section prefix="(i)">Indelibly mark with the word "paid" or "canceled" and return each note, contract, or other evidence of obligation of the borrower in the possession of the lender; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">Furnish the borrower with a written statement that identifies the loan transaction and states that the loan has been paid in full;</section></section><section prefix="(2)">Release any mortgage, security agreement, or other form of security instrument which no longer secures any indebtedness to the lender; and</section><section prefix="(3)">Restore any pledge or certificate of title.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">At the request of the borrower, the lender shall furnish the borrower with a written statement of the account. However, the lender is not required to do so more than once in any 30-day period.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">A lender making or offering to make a loan secured by residential real property shall comply with &#xA7; 12-125 of this title, as applicable.</section>
  </text>
</law>
