<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcl" order_by="" level="1">Commercial Law</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcl-12-503</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>503</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">A retail credit account may be established by a seller or financial institution only on the request of a buyer or with his consent.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A seller or financial institution may not discriminate solely on the basis of sex, marital status, geographic area of residence, neighborhood of residence, or age against a buyer who wishes to establish an account. Refusal to establish an account for a buyer who is under the age of 18 is not discrimination solely on the basis of age.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">An application, questionnaire, or other written document used to establish credit for an applicant may not contain any reference to the race, creed, color, or national origin of the applicant.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">An investigation made for the purpose of establishing credit for an applicant may not contain any information pertaining to the race, creed, color, or national origin of the applicant.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">For the purpose of considering the eligibility of a buyer for an extension of credit, a seller or financial institution shall consider alimony or child support awarded by a court and received by the buyer as income to the buyer.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If a seller or financial institution establishes an account for the use of a buyer, the seller or financial institution shall confirm the fact to the buyer in writing. The confirmation shall be in type no smaller than elite typewriter characters and shall contain:<section prefix="(i)">A clear and understandable statement of the amount or the rate of the finance charge;</section><section prefix="(ii)">A legend that the buyer may pay at any time the entire balance without incurring any additional charge for prepayment;</section><section prefix="(iii)">A statement which advises the buyer of his right under &#xA7; 12-510 of this subtitle to an answer to a written inquiry concerning the status of his account; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">Unless set out in a copy of the application form delivered to the buyer, the legend required by subsection (e)(2) of this section.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If no copy of the confirmation is retained by the seller or financial institution, a notation in the permanent records of the seller or financial institution which shows that the confirmation was mailed and the date of mailing is admissible as evidence of the mailing.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A retail credit account agreement shall be in writing and either:<section prefix="(i)">Signed by the buyer; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">The seller or financial institution shall have made a reasonable attempt to obtain the signature of the buyer to the agreement.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A legend stating that finance charges will be made in amounts or at rates not in excess of those permitted by law shall be printed in type no smaller than elite typewriter characters in both:<section prefix="(i)">The application form used by the seller or financial institution; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">A copy of either the application form or the confirmation delivered or mailed to the buyer when the retail credit account is established.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">Before the first payment on an account is due, other than any down payment, and within 40 days after each purchase, the holder of a retail credit account shall inform the buyer in writing of:<section prefix="(1)">The cash sale price of the goods or services purchased;</section><section prefix="(2)">The amount of any down payment;</section><section prefix="(3)">A general description of the type of goods or services and the date of each purchase;</section><section prefix="(4)">If the account is a closed end account:<section prefix="(i)">The amount of the finance charge;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The time sale price;</section><section prefix="(iii)">The amount of each installment due, expressed in dollars; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">The time or period of the payment of each installment; and</section></section><section prefix="(5)">If the account is an open end account:<section prefix="(i)">The amount or the rate of the finance charge on the outstanding balance; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">The method of determining the outstanding balance pursuant to &#xA7; 12-506(c) of this subtitle.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(g)">Unless the buyer previously received written notice by coupon, book, or otherwise of the amount of the payment and the amount of the unpaid balance after the payment, the holder of a retail credit account shall inform the buyer in writing, within 40 days after each payment, of:<section prefix="(1)">The total amount remaining due to the seller; and</section><section prefix="(2)">The total amount paid by the buyer since the last written notice.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(h)">The buyer under an open end retail credit account may request in writing, not more frequently than once each year, that the holder of the account inform the buyer of the total amount of finance charges assessed on the account during the preceding calendar year and the holder shall so advise the buyer in writing within 30 days of the request.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">The holder of a retail credit account shall disclose his address and telephone number on each billing statement for the use of the buyer for status and billing inquiries under &#xA7;&#xA7; 12-510 and 12-511 of this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(j)">Except as otherwise provided in this section, the information required by this section may be stated in any sequence, order, or form and in one or more documents. Additional items may be included with the information to explain the computations made in determining the amount to be paid by the buyer.</section>
  </text>
</law>
