<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcl" order_by="" level="1">Commercial Law</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcl-14-3601</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>3601</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Advertisement" has the meaning stated in &#xA7; 13-101 of this article.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Disclosure statement" means the form provided by the Attorney General for the purpose of disclosing to consumers practices relating to the preparation, handling, and sale of any unpackaged food represented to be halal.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">"Division" means the Division of Consumer Protection of the Office of the Attorney General.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Food" or "food product" means any food, food product, or food preparation, whether:<section prefix="(i)">Raw, solid, or liquid; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">Prepared for human consumption.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Food" or "food product" includes:<section prefix="(i)">Any meat, meat product, or meat preparation; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Any poultry or poultry product.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">"Halal" means prepared or processed in accordance with Islamic religious requirements.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">"Meat" includes any meat product or meat preparation.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">"Person" includes an individual, corporation, business trust, statutory trust, estate, trust, partnership, association, two or more persons having a joint or common interest, or any other legal or commercial entity.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Represents to the public" means any direct or indirect statement, oral or written, and any letter, word, sign, emblem, insignia, or mark which could reasonably lead a consumer to believe that a representation is being made that the final food product sold to the consumer is halal.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Represents to the public" includes an advertisement.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
