<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcl" order_by="gcl" level="1">Commercial Law</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcl-14-901</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated....</catch_line>
  <order_by>901</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Advertisement" has the meaning stated in &#xA7; 13-101(b) of this article.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Disclosure statement" means the form provided by the Attorney General for the purpose of disclosing to consumers practices relating to the preparation, handling, and sale of any unpackaged food represented to be kosher, kosher for Passover, or prepared or maintained under rabbinical or other kosher supervision.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">"Division" means the Division of Consumer Protection of the Office of the Attorney General.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Food" or "food product" means any food, food product, or food preparation, whether:<section prefix="(i)">Raw, solid or liquid; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">Prepared for human consumption.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Food" or "food product" includes:<section prefix="(i)">Any meat, meat product, or meat preparation;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Any milk, milk product, or milk preparation;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Any poultry or poultry product; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">Any alcoholic or nonalcoholic beverage.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">"Kosher" includes foods prepared for the festival of Passover and termed as "kosher for Passover".</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">"Meat" includes any meat product or meat preparation.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Mezuzah" means the Jewish religious article that, according to Jewish law, is designed to be attached to the doorpost of a room in a home.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Mezuzah" includes:<section prefix="(i)">The parchment or other material on which passages from the Bible are to be written; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">The writing on that parchment or other material.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(i)">"Person" includes an individual, corporation, business trust, statutory trust, estate, trust, partnership, association, two or more persons having a joint or common interest, or any other legal or commercial entity.</section>
    <section prefix="(j)">"Poultry" includes any poultry product or poultry preparation.</section>
    <section prefix="(k)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Represents to the public" means any direct or indirect statement, orally or written, and any letter, word, sign, emblem, insignia, or mark which could reasonably lead a consumer to believe that a representation is being made that the final food product sold to the consumer is kosher, kosher for Passover, or prepared or maintained under rabbinical or other kosher supervision.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Represents to the public" includes any advertisement.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(l)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Tefillin" means the Jewish religious article, also known as "phylacteries", that, according to Jewish law, is designed to be worn on the upper arm and head during morning prayers.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Tefillin" includes:<section prefix="(i)">The parchment or other material on which passages from the Bible are to be written;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The writing on that parchment or other material;</section><section prefix="(iii)">The capsules in which the parchment or other material is contained; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">The straps attached to the capsules.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
