<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gcl" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="12-1026" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcl-12-1026</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Escrow account" means an expense or escrow account which tends to protect the security of a loan by the accumulation of funds for the payment of taxes, insurance premiums, or other expenses.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Lending institution" means a bank, savings bank, or savings and loan association doing business in Maryland.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A lending institution that makes a loan to a consumer borrower secured by a first mortgage or first deed of trust on residential real property and creates or is the assignee of an escrow account in connection with that loan shall pay interest to the consumer borrower on the funds in the escrow account at an annual rate not less than the 6-month average dealer bid rate on nationally traded certificates of deposit, as published by the Federal Reserve in "Selected Interest Rates (Daily) - H.15", as of the first business day of the calendar year.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Interest on these funds shall be:<section prefix="(i)">Adjusted, if applicable, as of the first day of each calendar year to reflect the rate to be paid during that year, as determined under paragraph (1) of this subsection;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Computed on the average monthly balance in the escrow account; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Paid annually to the borrower by crediting the escrow account with the amount of interest due.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The lending institution shall annually provide the consumer borrower with a statement of the escrow balance.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The provisions of this subsection do not apply to a lending institution that provides for the payment of taxes, insurance, or other expenses under the direct reduction method by which these expenses, when paid by the lending institution, are added to the outstanding principal balance of the loan.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">
        <section prefix="(i)">This subsection does not apply if the loan:</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">Notwithstanding subparagraph (i) of this paragraph, this subsection shall apply if the out-of-state lender:</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except upon foreclosure, release, or as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, funds in any escrow account maintained by a credit grantor on behalf of a consumer borrower for use in paying taxes, insurance premiums, and ground rents may not be used:<section prefix="(i)">To reduce the principal; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">To pay interest or other loan charges.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If there is periodically a balance in the escrow account maintained by a credit grantor on behalf of a consumer borrower which exceeds the amount stated in the agreement, note, or other evidence of the loan, the consumer borrower shall be given at least annually the option of:<section prefix="(i)">Receiving a refund of the excess amount;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Applying the excess amount to the payment of principal and interest; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">Leaving the excess amount in the escrow account.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A refund of any excess amount shall be made:<section prefix="(i)">Within 60 days after the receipt by the credit grantor of the consumer borrower's request for a refund; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">If the consumer borrower has not notified the credit grantor of the option chosen by the consumer borrower, within 60 days after the date the credit grantor mailed notice of an excess amount.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Subject to subparagraph (iii) of this paragraph, if, after recalculating the amount that is required to be maintained in escrow under a first mortgage or first deed of trust on residential real property, a credit grantor or a servicer of a loan determines that the amount that a consumer borrower is required to pay must increase, the credit grantor or servicer may not include, for a 1-year period after the determination is made, the amount of the increase in escrow payments in any calculation of the amount of interest or any fee due under the loan.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">This paragraph may not be construed to limit the ability of a credit grantor or a servicer of a loan to impose a late fee for any escrow payment that is due and not timely paid.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)"/>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Funds in any escrow account shall be kept separate from and may not be commingled with the funds of the credit grantor.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A credit grantor may place escrow funds received in connection with more than one loan into a single escrow account.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">In the event of the bankruptcy of the credit grantor, any escrow funds placed in any escrow account may not be considered to be part of the bankrupt estate of the credit grantor.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">A credit grantor may not impose a collection fee or service charge on the maintenance of an escrow account on a first mortgage or first deed of trust.</section>
  </text>
</law>
