<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gcl" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="12-124" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcl-12-124</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">"Flood insurance coverage" means flood insurance against losses caused by flooding that are covered under a policy issued by:</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">"Improvements" means buildings or structures erected upon or affixed to real property that enhance the value of the real property.</section>
        <section prefix="(iv)">"Property insurance coverage" means property insurance against losses caused by perils that commonly are covered in insurance policies described with terms similar to "standard fire" or "standard fire with extended coverage".</section>
        <section prefix="(v)"/>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A lender may not require a borrower, as a condition to receiving or maintaining a loan secured by a first mortgage or first deed of trust, to provide or purchase property insurance coverage against risks to any improvements on any real property in an amount exceeding the replacement cost of the improvements on the real property.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A lender may not require a borrower, as a condition to receiving or maintaining a loan secured by a first mortgage or first deed of trust, to provide or purchase flood insurance coverage in an amount exceeding the replacement cost of the improvements on the real property.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">In determining the replacement cost of the improvements on any real property, the lender may:<section prefix="(i)">Accept the value placed on the improvements by the insurer; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">Use the value placed on the improvements by the lender's appraisal of the improvements.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(5)">A lender may not require that the insurance be purchased through a particular insurance producer or insurance company.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A violation of this section shall entitle the borrower to:<section prefix="(i)">Seek an injunction to prohibit the lender who has engaged or is engaging in the violation from continuing or engaging in the violation;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Reasonable attorney's fees; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Damages directly resulting from the violation.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A violation of this section does not affect the validity of the first mortgage or first deed of trust securing the loan.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
