<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcl" order_by="gcl" level="1">Commercial Law</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcl-22-605</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this section, "automatic restraint" means a program, code, device, or similar electronic or physi...</catch_line>
  <order_by>605</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, "automatic restraint" means a program, code, device, or similar electronic or physical limitation the intended purpose of which is to restrict use of information.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A party entitled to enforce a limitation on use of information may include an automatic restraint in the information or a copy of it and use that restraint if:<section prefix="(1)">A conspicuous term of the agreement authorizes use of the restraint;</section><section prefix="(2)">The restraint prevents a use that is inconsistent with the agreement;</section><section prefix="(3)">The restraint prevents use after expiration of the stated duration of the contract or a stated number of uses; or</section><section prefix="(4)">The restraint prevents use after the contract terminates, other than on expiration of a stated duration or number of uses, and the licensor gives reasonable notice to the licensee before further use is prevented.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">This section does not authorize an automatic restraint that affirmatively prevents or makes impracticable a licensee's access to its own information or information of a third party, other than the licensor, if that information is in the possession of the licensee or a third party and accessed without use of the licensor's information or informational rights.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A party that includes or uses an automatic restraint consistent with subsection (b) or (c) of this section is not liable for any loss caused by the use of the restraint.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">This section does not preclude electronic replacement or disabling of an earlier copy of information by the licensor in connection with delivery of a new copy or version under an agreement to replace or disable the earlier copy by electronic means with an upgrade or other new information.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">This section does not authorize use of an automatic restraint to enforce remedies in the event of breach of contract or of cancellation for breach.</section>
  </text>
</law>
