<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcl" order_by="" level="1">Commercial Law</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcl-14-3501</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>3501</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Business" means a sole proprietorship, partnership, corporation, association, or any other business entity, whether or not organized to operate at a profit.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Business" includes a financial institution organized, chartered, licensed, or otherwise authorized under the laws of this State, any other state, the United States, or any other country, and the parent or subsidiary of a financial institution.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Encrypted" means the transformation of data through  the use of an algorithmic process into a form in which there is a low  probability of assigning meaning without use of a confidential  process or key.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Personal information" means an individual's first name or first initial and last name in combination with any one or more of the following data elements, when the name or the data elements are not encrypted, redacted, or otherwise protected by another method that renders the information unreadable or unusable:<section prefix="(i)">A Social Security number;</section><section prefix="(ii)">A driver's license number;</section><section prefix="(iii)">A financial account number, including a credit card number or debit card number, that in combination with any required security code, access code, or password, would permit access to an individual's financial account; or</section><section prefix="(iv)">An Individual Taxpayer Identification Number.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Personal information" does not include:<section prefix="(i)">Publicly available information that is lawfully made available to the general public from federal, State, or local government records;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Information that an individual has consented to have publicly disseminated or listed; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">Information that is disseminated or listed in accordance with the federal Health Insurance Portability and Accountability Act.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"Records" means information that is inscribed on a tangible medium or that is stored in an electronic or other medium and is retrievable in perceivable form.</section>
  </text>
</law>
