<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gcl" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="8-510" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcl-8-510</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In a case not covered by the priority rules in Title 9 of this article or the rules stated in subsection (c) of this section, an action based on an adverse claim to a financial asset or security entitlement, whether framed in conversion, replevin, constructive trust, equitable lien, or other theory, may not be asserted against a person who purchases a security entitlement, or an interest in a security entitlement, from an entitlement holder if the purchaser gives value, does not have notice of the adverse claim, and obtains control.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">If an adverse claim could not have been asserted against an entitlement holder under &#xA7; 8-502 of this subtitle, the adverse claim cannot be asserted against a person who purchases a security entitlement, or an interest in a security entitlement, from the entitlement holder.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In a case not covered by the priority rules in Title 9 of this article, a purchaser for value of a security entitlement, or an interest in a security entitlement, who obtains control has priority over a purchaser of a security entitlement, or an interest in a security entitlement, who does not obtain control.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Except as otherwise provided in subsection (d) of this section, purchasers who have control rank according to priority in time of:<section prefix="(i)">The purchaser's becoming the person for whom the securities account, in which the security entitlement is carried, is maintained, if the purchaser obtained control under &#xA7; 8-106(d)(1);</section><section prefix="(ii)">The securities intermediary's agreement to comply with the purchaser's entitlement orders with respect to security entitlements carried or to be carried in the securities account in which the security entitlement is carried, if the purchaser obtained control under &#xA7; 8-106(d)(2); or</section><section prefix="(iii)">If the purchaser obtained control through another person under &#xA7; 8-106(d)(3), the time on which priority would be based under this subsection if the other person were the secured party.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A securities intermediary as purchaser has priority over a conflicting purchaser who has control unless otherwise agreed by the securities intermediary.</section>
  </text>
</law>
