<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcl" order_by="" level="1">Commercial Law</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcl-14-3903</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>3903</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">An arbitration organization subject to this subtitle shall collect, publish, and make available to the public the following information regarding each consumer arbitration for which it performed an arbitration activity during the preceding 5-year period:<section prefix="(1)">If the nonconsumer party is a corporation or other business entity, the name of that party;</section><section prefix="(2)">Whether the dispute involved goods, services, real property, or credit;</section><section prefix="(3)">The type of claim or cause of action alleged;</section><section prefix="(4)">Whether the consumer or nonconsumer party was the prevailing party;</section><section prefix="(5)">The number of times during the reporting period that the nonconsumer party has been a party in a consumer arbitration for which the arbitration organization performed an arbitration activity;</section><section prefix="(6)">Whether the consumer party was represented by an attorney and, if so, the name of the attorney;</section><section prefix="(7)">The date the arbitration organization received the demand for the consumer arbitration, the date the arbitrator was appointed, and the date of disposition by the arbitrator or arbitration organization;</section><section prefix="(8)">If known, the type of disposition of the dispute, including withdrawal, abandonment, settlement, award after hearing, award without hearing, default, or dismissal without hearing;</section><section prefix="(9)">The amount of the claim, the amount of the award, and any other relief granted;</section><section prefix="(10)">The name of the arbitrator, the arbitrator's total fee for conducting the consumer arbitration, and the percentage of the arbitrator's fee allocated to each party; and</section><section prefix="(11)">The address of the premises where the consumer arbitration was conducted.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The information required under subsection (a) of this section:<section prefix="(i)">Shall be reported beginning on the first day of the month immediately following the month an arbitration organization becomes subject to this subtitle; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Shall be updated at least quarterly thereafter.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">An arbitration organization that becomes subject to this subtitle before July 1, 2016, shall report the information required under subsection (a) of this section to the extent it is available.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The information required under subsection (a) of this section shall be made available to the public:<section prefix="(1)">In a computer-searchable format that:<section prefix="(i)">Is accessible at the Internet Web site of the arbitration organization; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">May be downloaded without a fee; and</section></section><section prefix="(2)">In writing:<section prefix="(i)">On request; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">At a fee that does not exceed the actual cost to the arbitration organization of copying the information.</section></section></section>
  </text>
</law>
