<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gcl" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="14-1310" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcl-14-1310</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>1. This unit must be used in an area which has proper ventilation. Consult owner's manual for details and instructions.<section prefix="(a)">With the written consent of the property owner, a person may use unvented portable kerosene-fired heaters in single family dwelling units and in commercial establishments in this State if the heaters otherwise comply with the State Fire Prevention Code regulations in effect on January 1, 1982.</section><section prefix="(b)"><section prefix="(1)">"Commercial establishment" does not include:<section prefix="(i)">Places of public assembly capable of accommodating more than 50 persons;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Child care centers;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Educational occupancies;</section><section prefix="(iv)">Health care occupancies;</section><section prefix="(v)">Hotels and motels; or</section><section prefix="(vi)">Buildings (other than office facilities) where open flame devices would readily ignite flammable liquid vapor, explosives, or dust, or buildings over 3 stories in height.</section></section><section prefix="(2)">In commercial establishments, portable kerosene heaters may not be located in such a manner as to obstruct exits.</section><section prefix="(3)">This section shall not be construed to prohibit or allow the prohibition of the demonstration or repair of unvented portable kerosene-fired heaters in any commercial establishment.</section></section><section prefix="(c)">The manufacturer shall affix to each portable kerosene heater, in a safe and prominent place, a nondetachable warning label which states:</section><section prefix="(d)">In Baltimore City, this section does not affect or supersede any local law or ordinance which is more stringent or imposes a higher standard regarding the use or sale of portable kerosene heaters.</section></text>
</law>
