<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcl" order_by="gcl" level="1">Commercial Law</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcl-14-2503</section_number>
  <catch_line>Within 30 days of the date of delivery, a purchaser of a hearing aid may cancel the purchase for any...</catch_line>
  <order_by>2503</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Within 30 days of the date of delivery, a purchaser of a hearing aid may cancel the purchase for any reason, by mailing or delivering a notice of cancellation to the seller of the hearing aid at the address specified in the contract.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Cancellation of the purchase entitles the purchaser to a refund of the entire consideration paid, less 10 percent for services and payments made for diagnostic tests.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If the actual documented expenses incurred by the seller for the fitting, delivery, and return of the hearing aid to the manufacturer are in excess of 10 percent of the purchase price, the seller may retain an amount equal to these expenses only if:<section prefix="(i)">The amount is conspicuously identified as "nonrefundable" on the contract or bill of sale for the hearing aid; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">The total amount retained does not exceed 20 percent of the purchase price of the hearing aid.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The seller shall deliver the refund to the purchaser if:<section prefix="(i)">The purchase is made at a place other than the place of business of the seller, within 30 days after the receipt of the notice of cancellation; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">The purchase agreement is made at the place of business of the seller, within 30 days after the return of the hearing aid.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">If a hearing aid is sold in a hospital or related institution, the seller must initiate a refund request with the accounting department of the selling hospital or related institution within 10 days after receiving the notice of cancellation from the purchaser.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">After cancellation of the purchase, if the hearing aid has been delivered to the purchaser, the purchaser must make the hearing aid available to the seller in substantially as good condition as when received.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The right of cancellation may not be waived or otherwise surrendered.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The contract or bill of sale for the purchase of a hearing aid shall contain the following statement:</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The statement required under this subsection shall:<section prefix="(i)">Be in bold and conspicuous type of at least 10-point type; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Appear on the same page as and above the space for the purchaser's signature.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The seller shall provide to the purchaser at the time of delivery of the hearing aid a notice of cancellation that states the total refundable amount and contains the following information:</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If the hearing aid is sold at the seller's place of business and the seller is not located within a hospital or other related institution, the notice shall contain the following statement:</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">If the hearing aid is sold by a seller affiliated with a hospital or other related institution, the notice shall contain the following statement:</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">If the hearing aid is sold at a place other than the seller's place of business the notice shall contain the following statement:</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">The notice of cancellation shall be in 10 point type.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">At the time of delivery, the seller shall complete the notice of cancellation by including the date of delivery and the date by which cancellation must be made.</section>
  </text>
</law>
