<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcl" order_by="" level="1">Commercial Law</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcl-12-311</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>311</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Fully indexed rate" means the index rate, as defined in the mortgage loan documents, prevailing at the time the mortgage loan is approved by the lender, plus the margin that will apply after the expiration of an introductory interest rate.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">"Mortgage loan" has the meaning stated in &#xA7; 11-501 of the Financial Institutions Article.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">"Mortgage loan" does not include a reverse mortgage loan.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A lender may not take as security for a loan any:<section prefix="(1)">Confession of judgment or power of attorney to him or to a third person to confess judgment or appear for the borrower in a judicial proceeding;</section><section prefix="(2)">Assignment or order for payment of wages;</section><section prefix="(3)">Instrument in which blanks are left to be filled after execution; or</section><section prefix="(4)">Note, promise to pay, or security instrument which does not state:<section prefix="(i)">The principal amount of the loan;</section><section prefix="(ii)">A schedule of payments or a description of the schedule; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">The agreed amount and rate of interest, charges, and fees.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A lender may not take any security interest in:<section prefix="(i)">Real property for any loan under $2,000 in value or amount; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">Personal property for any loan under $700 in value or amount.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Any lien taken in violation of this subsection is void.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">This subsection does not apply to or affect a lien on an interest in real property which results from a judgment obtained by the lender based on a loan otherwise secured or unsecured.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A lender may not make a mortgage loan without giving due regard to the borrower's ability to repay the mortgage loan in accordance with its terms, including the fully indexed rate of the mortgage loan, if applicable, and property taxes and homeowner's insurance whether or not an escrow account is established for the collection and payment of these expenses.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Due regard to a borrower's ability to repay a mortgage loan must include:<section prefix="(i)">Consideration of the borrower's debt to income ratio, including existing debts and other obligations; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Verification of the borrower's gross monthly income and assets by review of third-party written documentation reasonably believed by the lender to be accurate and complete.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Acceptable third-party written documentation includes:<section prefix="(i)">The borrower's Internal Revenue Service form W-2;</section><section prefix="(ii)">A copy of the borrower's income tax return;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Payroll receipts;</section><section prefix="(iv)">The records of a financial institution; or</section><section prefix="(v)">Other third-party documents that provide reasonably reliable evidence of the borrower's income or assets.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">This subsection does not apply to a mortgage loan:<section prefix="(i)">Approved for government guaranty by the Federal Housing Administration, the Veterans Administration, the United States Department of Agriculture, the Maryland Department of Housing and Community Development, or the Community Development Administration; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">That refinances an existing mortgage loan if the refinance mortgage loan is:<section prefix="1.">Offered under the federal Homeowner Affordability and Stability Plan; and</section><section prefix="2.">Made available by the Federal Home Loan Mortgage Corporation or the Federal National Mortgage Association.</section></section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
