<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gcl" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="14-1322" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcl-14-1322</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Billing agent" means a person that submits charges for products or services to a telephone company or reseller on behalf of the person submitting the charges or on behalf of a third-party vendor.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Customer" means a customer of a telephone company or reseller.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">"Express authorization" means an express, affirmative act by an ordering customer in the form of:<section prefix="(i)">A written authorization;</section><section prefix="(ii)">An oral authorization verified and recorded by an independent party; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">A recorded electronic authorization.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(5)">"Ordering customer" means a customer or another person ordering services that will appear on the customer's telephone bill.</section>
      <section prefix="(6)">"Reseller" means a person that provides wireline telephone voice service by using the transmission facilities of another person.</section>
      <section prefix="(7)">"Telephone company" means a person that provides wireline telephone voice services.</section>
      <section prefix="(8)">"Third-party vendor" means an entity not affiliated with a telephone company or reseller that:<section prefix="(i)">Provides products or services to a customer; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Seeks to charge the customer through third-party vendor billing.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(9)">
        <section prefix="(i)">"Third-party vendor billing" means the use of a telephone company's or reseller's billing system, either directly or through a billing agent, to charge a customer for products or services provided by a third-party vendor.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">"Third-party vendor billing" does not include billing for:</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Unless the third-party vendor or billing agent first obtains an ordering customer's express authorization, a third-party vendor or billing agent may not submit charges to a telephone company or reseller.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The express authorization required under subsection (b) of this section shall:<section prefix="(1)">Be separate from any solicitation material or entry forms for sweepstakes or contests; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Include:<section prefix="(i)">The name and telephone number of the ordering customer;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The date of authorization;</section><section prefix="(iii)">An explanation of:</section><section prefix="(iv)">An affirmation by the ordering customer that:</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A third-party vendor or billing agent shall retain a copy of the express authorization required under subsection (b) of this section for 2 years after the date of authorization.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">A customer is not liable for third-party vendor billing charges unless:<section prefix="(1)">The customer has been given notice that the telephone company or reseller may allow third-party vendor billing and that free blocking of certain third-party vendor billing may be available to the customer; and</section><section prefix="(2)">The customer is provided access to:<section prefix="(i)">An itemization of the third-party vendor billing charges identifying them separately from other charges; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">The name and telephone number of the third-party vendor or its billing agent.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">Unless the third-party vendor or billing agent provides a copy of the authorization required under subsection (b) of this section to the customer and to the telephone company or reseller, a customer is not liable for third-party vendor billing charges if the customer, in good faith and in a reasonably timely manner, but not outside the time period specified in subsection (d) of this section, disputes that the charges were authorized.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">An agreement for third-party vendor billing entered into by a telephone company or reseller and a third-party vendor or billing agent on or after October 1, 2010, is void and unenforceable to the extent that it does not require the third-party vendor to comply with subsection (b) of this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">A violation of this section by a third-party vendor or billing agent:<section prefix="(1)">Is an unfair or deceptive trade practice under Title 13 of this article; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Except for the provisions of &#xA7; 13-411 of this article, is subject to the enforcement and penalty provisions contained in Title 13 of this article.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
