<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcl" order_by="" level="1">Commercial Law</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcl-14-1312</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>1312</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following terms have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Acceptor" means a seller, lender, or credit grantor to whom a discharged check was originally issued.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Discharged check" means a check or other instrument that has been:<section prefix="(i)">Issued to a seller, lender, or credit grantor by a buyer or borrower in full or partial satisfaction of an underlying obligation; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Reacquired by the buyer or borrower in his own right.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Notwithstanding any other provision of this article, if an acceptor requires a buyer or borrower to submit to the acceptor a discharged check, rather than a facsimile thereof, for the purpose of verifying the full or partial payment of the obligation for which the check was issued, the acceptor shall return the discharged check directly to the buyer or borrower when payment or nonpayment has been verified.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">An acceptor may not return the discharged check directly to the financial institution on which the discharged check was drawn if the check was submitted to the acceptor under the circumstances outlined in paragraph (1) of this subsection.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The failure of an acceptor to return a discharged check directly to a buyer or borrower as provided in subsection (b) of this section shall make the acceptor liable to the buyer or borrower for:<section prefix="(1)">The amount of the check; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Any charges made against the buyer's or borrower's account by the financial institution on which the check was drawn if those charges are a direct result of the acceptor's noncompliance with subsection (b) of this section.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
