<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gcl" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="21-118.1" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcl-21-118.1</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Electronic postmark certificate" means evidentiary proof, provided to the sender or recipient of an electronic record, that the electronic record:<section prefix="(i)">Was postmarked by a postal authority with a valid electronic postmark on the date and time indicated;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Was transmitted in a certain form on a specific date and time; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Was sent by the person indicated, to the person indicated, and on the date and time indicated.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Postal authority" means:<section prefix="(i)">The United States Postal Service or other national public or private mail delivery service that provides electronic postmarks; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">A public or private entity that has the regulatory authority or legal responsibility for providing electronic postmarks.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Subject to &#xA7; 21-117 of this title, a requirement under a law other than this title to send, communicate, or transmit a record by registered or certified mail, postage prepaid, or by regular mail is satisfied by an electronic record that:<section prefix="(1)">Is addressed properly or otherwise directed properly to an information processing system that the recipient has designated;</section><section prefix="(2)"><section prefix="(i)">Enters an information processing system that is outside the control of the sender; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">Enters a region of an information processing system that is under the control of the recipient;</section></section><section prefix="(3)">Is postmarked by a postal authority with an electronic postmark; and</section><section prefix="(4)">Is authenticated by an electronic postmark certificate.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">An electronic record is subject to the same legal protections as the United States mail if:<section prefix="(1)">The electronic record meets the requirements of subsection (b) of this section; and</section><section prefix="(2)">The postal authority that postmarked the electronic record under subsection (b)(3) of this section is the United States Postal Service.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">This section does not authorize the use of an electronic postmark or electronic postmark certificate for the service of a summons, complaint, or other papers for the purpose of obtaining jurisdiction over a defendant in a lawsuit.</section>
  </text>
</law>
