<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcl" order_by="gcl" level="1">Commercial Law</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcl-14-3701</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated....</catch_line>
  <order_by>3701</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Child" means an individual under the age of 18 years.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Computer network" means the computer network commonly known as the Internet and any other local, regional, or global computer network that is similar to or is a predecessor of or successor to the Internet.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">"Internet" means the international computer network of both federal and nonfederal interoperable packet-switched data networks.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Internet access provider" means a provider that offers directly to residential customers an interactive computer service to obtain access to the Internet in exchange for consideration, such as through a paid subscription or through an agreement to view specific advertising or other content.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Internet access provider" does not include a library or educational institution that operates or offers an interactive computer service to obtain access to the Internet.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Interactive computer service" means an information service, system, or access software provider that provides or enables computer access by multiple users to a computer service.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Interactive computer service" includes a service or system that provides access to the Internet and systems operated or services offered by a library or educational institution.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">"Parental control" means a product or service to control the access of a child to the Internet.</section>
  </text>
</law>
