<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcl" order_by="" level="1">Commercial Law</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcl-14-1315</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>1315</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Consumer contract" means a contract involving the sale, lease, or provision of goods or services which are for personal, family, or household purposes.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Contract", unless specifically provided otherwise, includes consumer, commercial, and business contracts, covenants, leases of any kind, and tariffs on file with any regulatory authority.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">
        <section prefix="(i)">"Late fee" means any charge or fee imposed because a payment is not made when the payment is due under the terms of a contract.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">"Late fee" includes a fee imposed under subparagraph (i) of this paragraph that is described:<section prefix="1.">As a flat rate;</section><section prefix="2.">As a percentage of the amount due; or</section><section prefix="3.">In any other terms.</section></section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The parties to a contract may agree to require the payment of a late fee when a party fails to make a payment when the payment is due.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A contract that requires the payment of a late fee shall disclose, by its terms or by notice:<section prefix="(1)">The amount of the late fee;</section><section prefix="(2)">The conditions under which the late fee will be imposed; and</section><section prefix="(3)">The timing for the imposition of the late fee.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A late fee imposed under this section is not:<section prefix="(1)">Interest;</section><section prefix="(2)">A finance charge;</section><section prefix="(3)">Liquidated damages; or</section><section prefix="(4)">A penalty.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">This section does not affect a late fee, a finance charge, interest, or any other fee or charge otherwise allowed under applicable law.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A late fee included in a consumer contract pursuant to this section is subject to one of the following limitations:<section prefix="(i)"><section prefix="1.">The amount of the late fee may be up to $5 per month, or up to 10% per month of the payment amount that is past due, whichever is greater; and</section><section prefix="2.">No more than 3 monthly late fees may be imposed for any single payment amount that is past due, regardless of the period during which the payment remains past due; or</section></section><section prefix="(ii)">The amount of the late fee may be up to 1.5% per month of the payment amount that is past due.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The amount of the late fee under paragraph (1) of this subsection shall be disclosed, in the consumer contract or by notice, in size equal to at least 10-point bold type.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Except as provided in subparagraph (ii) of this paragraph, a late fee included in a consumer contract pursuant to this section may not be imposed until 15 days after the date the bill was rendered for the goods or services provided.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">If a bill is not rendered, a late fee included in a consumer contract pursuant to this section may not be imposed until 15 days after the payment amount becomes due.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">A late fee imposed under this section is subject to any additional limitations or conditions prescribed by any federal, State, or local regulatory agency or authority having jurisdiction over entities imposing late fees regulated by this section.</section>
  </text>
</law>
