<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gcl" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="9-614" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcl-9-614</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>In a consumer-goods transaction, the following rules apply:<section prefix=""><section prefix="(1)">A notification of disposition must provide the following information:<section prefix="(A)">The information specified in &#xA7; 9-613(1);</section><section prefix="(B)">A description of any liability for a deficiency of the person to which the notification is sent;</section><section prefix="(C)">A telephone number from which the amount that must be paid to the secured party to redeem the collateral under &#xA7; 9-623 is available; and</section><section prefix="(D)">A telephone number or mailing address from which additional information concerning the disposition and the obligation secured is available.</section></section><section prefix="(2)">A particular phrasing of the notification is not required.</section><section prefix="(3)">The following form of notification, when completed, provides sufficient information:</section><section prefix="(4)">A notification in the form of paragraph (3) is sufficient, even if additional information appears at the end of the form.</section><section prefix="(5)">A notification in the form of paragraph (3) is sufficient, even if it includes errors in information not required by paragraph (1), unless the error is misleading with respect to rights arising under this article.</section><section prefix="(6)">If a notification under this section is not in the form of paragraph (3), law other than this article determines the effect of including information not required by paragraph (1).</section><section prefix="(7)">Secured parties subject to &#xA7;&#xA7; 12-115, 12-624 through 12-627, &#xA7; 12-921, or &#xA7; 12-1021 of this article are not subject to the provisions of this section.</section></section></text>
</law>
