<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcl" order_by="" level="1">Commercial Law</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcl-12-625</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>625</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">For 15 days after the holder gives the notice required by &#xA7; 12-624(d) of this subtitle, the holder shall retain any repossessed goods in the county where the goods were sold to the buyer or were repossessed.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">During the period provided for in subsection (a) of this section, the buyer may:<section prefix="(1)">Redeem and take possession of the goods; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Resume the performance of the agreement.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">To redeem the goods, the buyer shall:<section prefix="(1)">Tender the amount due under the agreement at the time of redemption, without giving effect to any provision which allows acceleration of any installment otherwise payable after that time;</section><section prefix="(2)">Tender performance of any other promise for the breach of which the goods were repossessed; and</section><section prefix="(3)">If the discretionary notice provided for in &#xA7; 12-624(c) of this subtitle was given, pay the actual and reasonable expenses of retaking and storing the goods.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">This section does not apply if the goods were seized by a police department, bureau, or force and the goods were repossessed because of that seizure, in which event, the buyer shall have no right to redeem or take possession, even if the buyer tenders payment of the entire balance due under the agreement.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">Notwithstanding subsections (b) and (c) of this section:<section prefix="(1)">The holder shall have the right to require the buyer to tender payment of the entire balance due under the agreement if:<section prefix="(i)">The date of the default in the payments due under the agreement that led to the present repossession occurred within 18 months after the last repossession; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">The buyer was guilty of fraudulent conduct, intentionally and wrongfully concealed, removed, damaged, or destroyed the goods, or attempted to do so, and the goods were repossessed because of that conduct.</section></section><section prefix="(2)">Under paragraph (1) of this subsection, the payment by the buyer of the entire balance due under the agreement shall:<section prefix="(i)">Constitute redemption by the buyer; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Entitle the buyer to take possession of the goods.</section></section></section>
  </text>
</law>
