<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gcl" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="6-106" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcl-6-106</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>In addition to the requirements of the two preceding sections:<section prefix="(1)">Upon every bulk transfer subject to this title for which new consideration becomes payable except those made by sale at auction it is the duty of the transferee to assure that such consideration is applied so far as necessary to pay those debts of the transferor which are either shown on the list furnished by the transferor (&#xA7; 6-104) or filed in writing in the place stated in the notice (&#xA7; 6-107) within thirty days after the mailing of such notice. This duty of the transferee runs to all the holders of such debts, and may be enforced by any of them for the benefit of all.</section><section prefix="(2)">If any of said debts are in dispute the necessary sum may be withheld from distribution until the dispute is settled or adjudicated.</section><section prefix="(3)">If the consideration payable is not enough to pay all of the said debts in full, distribution shall be made pro rata.</section><section prefix="(4)">The transferee may within ten days after he takes possession of the goods file a petition in the circuit court for the county in which the place of business of the transferor is situated and pay the consideration into such court asking that a receiver or receivers be appointed by said court to take charge of the distribution of the agreed purchase price and the transferee may discharge his duty under this section by giving notice by registered or certified mail to all the persons to whom the duty runs that the consideration has been paid into that court and that they should file their claims there. If said receivership is granted then said receiver or receivers, upon qualification by filing an approved bond in the amount fixed by the court, shall be entitled to the custody and distribution of the agreed purchase price under orders of the court as in other receiverships.</section></text>
</law>
