<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcl" order_by="gcl" level="1">Commercial Law</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcl-14-12A-02</section_number>
  <catch_line>It is an unfair or deceptive trade practice within the meaning of Title 13 of this article for a sel...</catch_line>
  <order_by>02</order_by>
  <text>It is an unfair or deceptive trade practice within the meaning of Title 13 of this article for a seller to:<section prefix=""><section prefix="(1)">Sell or offer to sell any basement waterproofing service that uses the soil injection/pressure pumping technique either alone or with any other waterproofing technique unless the need for, effectiveness of, and appropriateness of the method is established in a written seller's analysis. The written seller analysis shall be separate from the service contract and verified by a signed engineer's or architect's analysis furnished to the buyer prior to the sale;</section><section prefix="(2)">Fail to describe separately and conspicuously on the seller's analysis and the service contract the cost of a soil injection/pressure pumping procedure;</section><section prefix="(3)">Submit a seller's analysis to the buyer that the seller knows or has reason to know is founded on incorrect facts or conclusions;</section><section prefix="(4)">Misrepresent directly or through an agent the need for, or the effectiveness of the soil injection/pressure pumping technique alone or in conjunction with other waterproofing techniques. This section also applies to misrepresentation by an engineer in connection with the sale of waterproofing services;</section><section prefix="(5)">Advertise basement waterproofing services using the soil injection/pressure pumping technique without disclosing in the advertisement that an engineer's analysis recommending this process is required as a condition of its use and that the analysis must be furnished to the buyer before a contract is signed. This disclosure shall be in 10 point boldface type; or</section><section prefix="(6)">Fail to itemize on the service contract the individual cost of each waterproofing technique used.</section></section></text>
</law>
