<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcl" order_by="" level="1">Commercial Law</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcl-11-301</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>301</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Controlled outlet" means an outlet which is operated by a distributor or operated by company employees, a subsidiary company, commissioned agent, or by any person who manages the outlet on a fee arrangement with the distributor.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The distributor may not:<section prefix="(1)">Require the dealer to refuse credit card purchases of gasohol; or</section><section prefix="(2)">Provide that any credit card it issues may not be used for the purchase of gasohol.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Dealer" means a person engaged in the retail sale of gasohol or gasoline products under a marketing agreement, at least 30 percent of whose gross revenue is derived from the retail sale of gasoline products.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Dealer" does not include an employee of a distributor.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Distributor" means a person who:<section prefix="(i)">Engages in the sale, consignment, or distribution of gasohol or gasoline products through retail outlets which he owns or leases; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Maintains an oral or written contractual relationship with a dealer for the sale of the products.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Distributor" includes any subsidiary or affiliated corporation in which a distributor holds at least 30 percent voting control.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">"Farm cooperative" means a cooperative organized under Subtitle 5 of Title 5 of the Corporations and Associations Article.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">"Gasoline products" includes gasohol.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">"Independent jobber" means an individual or corporation who purchases gasohol or gasoline products from a wholesaler for resale to a dealer.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">"Marketing agreement" means an oral or written agreement between a distributor and a dealer under which the dealer is granted the right, for the purpose of engaging in the retail sale of gasohol or gasoline products supplied by the distributor, to:<section prefix="(1)">Use a trademark, trade name, service mark, or other identifying symbol or name owned by the distributor; or</section><section prefix="(2)">Occupy premises owned, leased, or controlled by the distributor.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(j)">"Person" includes an individual, corporation, business trust, statutory trust, estate, trust, partnership, association, two or more persons having a joint or common interest, or any other legal or commercial entity.</section>
    <section prefix="(k)">"Retail sale" means the sale of a product for purposes other than resale.</section>
  </text>
</law>
