<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcl" order_by="gcl" level="1">Commercial Law</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcl-22-209</section_number>
  <catch_line>A party adopts the terms of a mass-market license for purposes of &#xA7; 22-208 of this subtitle only if...</catch_line>
  <order_by>209</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">A party adopts the terms of a mass-market license for purposes of &#xA7; 22-208 of this subtitle only if the party agrees to the license, such as by manifesting assent, before or during the party's initial performance or use of or access to the information. A term is not part of the license if:<section prefix="(1)">The term is unconscionable;</section><section prefix="(2)">The term is unenforceable, after weighing fundamental public policies, including fundamental public policies concerning competition or innovation, under &#xA7; 22-105(a) or (b) of this title;</section><section prefix="(3)">Subject to &#xA7; 22-301 of this title, the term conflicts with a term to which the parties to the license have expressly agreed; or</section><section prefix="(4)">The term is not available for viewing before and after assent:<section prefix="(A)">In a printed license; or</section><section prefix="(B)">In electronic form that:<section prefix="(i)">Can be printed or stored for archival and review purposes by the licensee; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">Is made available by a licensor to a licensee, at no cost to the licensee, in a printed form on the request of a licensee that is unable to print or store the license for archival and review purposes.</section></section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">If a mass-market license or a copy of the license is not available in a manner permitting an opportunity to review by the licensee before the licensee becomes obligated to pay and the licensee does not agree, such as by manifesting assent, to the license after having an opportunity to review, the licensee is entitled to a return under &#xA7; 22-112 of this title and, in addition, to:<section prefix="(1)">Reimbursement of any reasonable expenses incurred in complying with the licensor's instructions for returning or destroying the computer information or, in the absence of instructions, expenses incurred for return postage or similar reasonable expense in returning the computer information; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Compensation for any reasonable and foreseeable costs of restoring the licensee's information processing system to reverse changes in the system caused by the installation, if:<section prefix="(A)">The installation occurs because information must be installed to enable review of the license; and</section><section prefix="(B)">The installation alters the system or information in it but does not restore the system or information after removal of the installed information because the licensee rejected the license.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">In a mass-market transaction, if the licensor does not have an opportunity to review a record containing proposed terms from the licensee before the licensor delivers or becomes obligated to deliver the information, and if the licensor does not agree, such as by manifesting assent, to those terms after having that opportunity, the licensor is entitled to a return.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A term in a mass-market license that limits the duration of the license shall be conspicuous.</section>
  </text>
</law>
