<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gcl" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="14-1401" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcl-14-1401</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Adjustment program" means a program or policy:<section prefix="(i)">That expands or extends a warranty beyond its stated limit; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">Under which a manufacturer undertakes or offers to pay or reimburse a consumer, whether directly or indirectly, for all or a part of the cost of repairing a condition that may substantially affect the durability, reliability, or performance of a motor vehicle.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Adjustment program" does not include:<section prefix="(i)">Service provided under a safety or emissions related recall campaign; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">Adjustments made by a manufacturer on a case-by-case basis.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Consumer" means:<section prefix="(1)">The purchaser, other than for purposes of resale, of a new motor vehicle;</section><section prefix="(2)">A lessee of a motor vehicle;</section><section prefix="(3)">A person to whom a new motor vehicle is transferred during the duration of the warranty applicable to the motor vehicle; or</section><section prefix="(4)">A person who is entitled under the terms of the warranty to enforce its obligations.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">"Dealer" means a person who sells or leases motor vehicles under a retail agreement with a manufacturer or distributor, or an agent of a manufacturer or distributor.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"Lessee" means a consumer who leases a motor vehicle under a written lease that provides that the lessee is responsible for repairs to the motor vehicle.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">"Manufacturer" means a person who:<section prefix="(1)">Manufactures or assembles new motor vehicles for sale or distribution; or</section><section prefix="(2)">Is engaged in the business of importing new motor vehicles for sale or distribution to dealers or through distributors or factory branches.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(g)">"Motor vehicle" means a vehicle that:<section prefix="(1)">Is used for the private transportation of individuals and their personal belongings; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Has a maximum capacity of 10 individuals, including the driver.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
