<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcl" order_by="gcl" level="1">Commercial Law</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcl-14-1901</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated....</catch_line>
  <order_by>1901</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Commissioner" means the Commissioner of Financial Regulation of the Department of Labor, Licensing, and Regulation.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Consumer" means any individual who is solicited to purchase or who purchases for personal, family, or household purposes the services of a credit services business.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">"Consumer reporting agency", "consumer report", "investigative consumer report", and "file" shall have the meaning ascribed to each under &#xA7; 14-1201 of this title.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Credit services business" means any person who, with respect to the extension of credit by others, sells, provides, or performs, or represents that such person can or will sell, provide, or perform, any of the following services in return for the payment of money or other valuable consideration:<section prefix="(i)">Improving a consumer's credit record, history, or rating or establishing a new credit file or record;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Obtaining an extension of credit for a consumer; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">Providing advice or assistance to a consumer with regard to either subparagraph (i) or (ii) of this paragraph.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Credit services business" includes a person who sells or attempts to sell written materials containing information that the person represents will enable a consumer to establish a new credit file or record.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Credit services business" does not include:<section prefix="(i)">Any person authorized to make loans or extensions of credit under the laws of this State or the United States who is actively engaged in the business of making loans or other extensions of credit to residents of this State;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Any bank, trust company, savings bank, or savings and loan association whose deposits or accounts are eligible for insurance by the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation or any credit union organized and chartered under the laws of this State or the United States;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Any nonprofit organization exempt from taxation under &#xA7; 501(c)(3) of the Internal Revenue Code (26 U.S.C. &#xA7; 501(c)(3));</section><section prefix="(iv)">Any person licensed as a real estate broker by this State where the person is acting within the course and scope of that license;</section><section prefix="(v)">Any person licensed as a mortgage lender by this State;</section><section prefix="(vi)">An individual admitted to the Bar of the Court of Appeals of Maryland when the individual renders services within the course and scope of practice by the individual as a lawyer and does not engage in the credit services business on a regular and continuing basis;</section><section prefix="(vii)">Any broker-dealer registered with the Securities and Exchange Commission or the Commodity Futures Trading Commission where the broker-dealer is acting within the course and scope of that regulation;</section><section prefix="(viii)">Any consumer reporting agency as defined in the federal Fair Credit Reporting Act (15 U.S.C. &#xA7;&#xA7; 1681 - 1681t) or in &#xA7; 14-1201(e) of this title; or</section><section prefix="(ix)">An individual licensed by the Maryland Board of Public Accountancy when the individual renders services within the course and scope of practice by the individual as a certified public accountant and does not engage in the credit services business on a regular and continuing basis.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">"Extension of credit" means the right to defer payment of debt or to incur debt and defer its payment, offered or granted primarily for personal, family, or household purposes.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">"Person" includes an individual, corporation, government or governmental subdivision or agency, business trust, statutory trust, estate, trust, partnership, association, 2 or more persons having a joint or common interest, and any other legal or commercial entity.</section>
  </text>
</law>
