<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcl" order_by="gcl" level="1">Commercial Law</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcl-14-902</section_number>
  <catch_line>A person that represents to the public that any unpackaged food that is sold or served is kosher, ko...</catch_line>
  <order_by>902</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A person that represents to the public that any unpackaged food that is sold or served is kosher, kosher for Passover, or under rabbinical or other kosher supervision shall prominently and conspicuously display on the premises on which the food is sold or served a complete disclosure statement.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Division shall develop a form for disclosure statements and shall make the form available to any person upon request.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The disclosure statement shall:<section prefix="(i)">Be understandable and written in simple and readable plain language;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Disclose to the public the basis for a representation that any unpackaged food sold or served is kosher, kosher for Passover, or under rabbinical or other supervision, including a specification of practices relating to the preparation, handling, and sale of the food; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Contain any additional information or conform to any additional requirements that the Division considers reasonable and necessary to carry out the provisions of this subtitle.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">
        <section prefix="(i)">A person that displays a disclosure statement in accordance with this section shall retain a copy of the statement for at least:<section prefix="1.">3 years after the date of the initial display of the disclosure statement; or</section><section prefix="2.">3 years after the date of any amendment to the disclosure, whichever is longer.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">A person that displays a disclosure statement in accordance with this section shall provide a copy of the statement to the Division within 2 business days of the person's receipt from the Division of a request for a copy of the disclosure statement.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(5)">A person shall conform its practices with respect to the sale or serving of unpackaged food that is represented to the public as kosher, kosher for Passover, or under rabbinical or other kosher supervision.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A person may not sell or offer for sale any unpackaged food represented to the public as kosher, whether for consumption in the person's place of business or elsewhere, if, in the same place of business, the person also offers for sale any unpackaged food, not represented to the public as kosher, unless the person includes on each window sign and each display advertisement in block letters at least 4 inches high the words "kosher and nonkosher food sold here" or, as to the sale of meat alone, "kosher and nonkosher meat and poultry sold here".</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A person may not display for sale any food represented to the public as kosher, whether for consumption in the person's place of business or elsewhere, if, in the same show window or other location on or in the place of business, the person also displays any unpackaged food not represented to the public as kosher, unless the person displays over the kosher and nonkosher food signs that read, in block letters at least 4 inches high, "kosher food" and "nonkosher food", respectively, or, as to the display of meat alone, "kosher meat" and "nonkosher meat", or "kosher poultry" or "nonkosher poultry", respectively.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A person may not prepare or serve any food represented to the public as kosher, whether for consumption in the person's place of business or elsewhere, if, in the same place of business, the person also prepares or serves food not represented to the public as kosher, unless the person includes on each sign and display advertisement in or about the person's premises in block letters at least 4 inches high the words "kosher and nonkosher food prepared and sold here".</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this subsection, "Hebrew" symbol means:<section prefix="(i)">Any Hebrew word or letter; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">Any symbol, emblem, sign, insignia, or other mark that simulates a Hebrew word or letter.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">In connection with any place of business that sells or offers for sale any food, a person may not display, whether in a window, door, or other location on or in the place of business, in any handbill or other printed matter distributed in or outside of the place of business, or otherwise in any advertisement, any Hebrew symbol, or any other representation to the public that the place of business is kosher, kosher for Passover, or under rabbinical or other kosher supervision, unless the person also displays in conjunction with the Hebrew symbol or such other representation, in English letters of at least the same size as the characters used in the Hebrew symbol, the words "we sell kosher meat and food only", "we sell nonkosher meat and food only", or "we sell both kosher and nonkosher meat and food", as the appropriate representation may be.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this subsection, "fresh" means unprocessed other than by salting or soaking.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A person may not sell or offer for sale, as kosher, any fresh meat or poultry unless the words "soaked and salted" or "not soaked and salted", as the appropriate case may be, is marked:<section prefix="(i)">On the package label; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">If the product is not packaged, on a sign prominently displayed in conjunction with the product.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
