<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcl" order_by="gcl" level="1">Commercial Law</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcl-14-2201</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated....</catch_line>
  <order_by>2201</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Consumer" means an actual or prospective purchaser, lessee, or recipient of consumer goods, consumer services, or consumer realty.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Consumer goods", "consumer realty", and "consumer services" mean, respectively, goods, real property, and services which are primarily for personal, household, family, or agricultural purposes.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Subject to subparagraph (ii) of this paragraph, "consumer services" does not include financial services or securities sales.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">"Consumer services" includes any solicitation offering credit services where:<section prefix="1.">The consumer is required to call a telephone number;</section><section prefix="2.">The consumer is charged a separate toll fee for the call; and</section><section prefix="3.">The person making the solicitation receives any portion of the separate telephone toll fee paid by the consumer.</section></section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">"Credit services" means providing or offering to provide any service in return for the payment of money or other consideration, where the service is held out to provide assistance to a consumer with regard to:<section prefix="(1)">Improving the consumer's credit history, credit rating, or credit record; or</section><section prefix="(2)">Obtaining an extension of credit for the consumer.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Merchant" means a person who, directly or indirectly, offers or makes available to consumers any consumer goods, consumer services, or consumer realty.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Merchant" does not include a person who is exempt under &#xA7; 13-104 of this article.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">"Telephone solicitation" means the attempt by a merchant to sell or lease consumer goods, services, or realty to a consumer located in this State that is:<section prefix="(1)">Made entirely by telephone; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Initiated by the merchant.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
