<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcl" order_by="gcl" level="1">Commercial Law</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcl-9-201</section_number>
  <catch_line>Except as otherwise provided by Titles 1 through 10 of this article, a security agreement is effecti...</catch_line>
  <order_by>201</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Except as otherwise provided by Titles 1 through 10 of this article, a security agreement is effective according to its terms between the parties, against purchasers of the collateral, and against creditors.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A transaction subject to this title may also be subject to other statutes or regulations which establish different rules for consumers, including other statutes or regulations that regulate the rates, charges, agreements, and practices for loans, credit sales, or other extensions of credit and consumer protection statutes or regulations.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In case of conflict between this title and a statute or regulation described in subsection (b), the statute or regulation controls.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Failure to comply with a statute or regulation described in subsection (b) has only the effect the statute specifies and no recovery for such a failure is permitted under this title.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Without limiting the generality of paragraph (1) or (2) of this subsection, Subtitle 6 of this title does not impose additional duties, obligations, or responsibilities on secured parties subject to &#xA7; 12-115, &#xA7;&#xA7; 12-624 through 12-627, &#xA7; 12-921, or &#xA7; 12-1021 of this article and no recovery under &#xA7; 9-625 of this title is permitted for any failure to comply with those statutes.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">This title does not:<section prefix="(1)">Validate any rate, charge, agreement, or practice that violates a statute identified or described in subsection (b);</section><section prefix="(2)">Extend the application of any rule of law, statute, or regulation to a transaction not otherwise subject to it; or</section><section prefix="(3)">Authorize or permit the application of any provision of this title which is applicable to a consumer transaction, or to any other transaction with a consumer obligor, to any transaction other than a consumer transaction.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
