<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcl" order_by="" level="1">Commercial Law</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcl-14-1319</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>1319</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section, "gift certificate" means a device constructed of paper, plastic, or any other material that is:<section prefix="(i)">Sold or issued by a person for a cash value that can be used to purchase goods or services; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">Issued as a store credit for returned goods.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Gift certificate" does not include:<section prefix="(i)">A prepaid telephone calling card;</section><section prefix="(ii)">A prepaid technical support card;</section><section prefix="(iii)">A prepaid card for Internet services;</section><section prefix="(iv)">A coupon for discounted goods or services;</section><section prefix="(v)">A gift certificate that is distributed to an individual under an awards, loyalty, or promotional program in which the recipient does not give money or value for the gift certificate; or</section><section prefix="(vi)">A gift card that:<section prefix="1.">Is processed through a national credit or debit card service; and</section><section prefix="2.">May be used to purchase goods or services from multiple unaffiliated sellers of goods or services.</section></section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A person may not sell or issue a gift certificate that, within 4 years after the date of purchase, is subject to expiration or a fee or charge of any kind.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Any term or condition concerning expiration or a fee or charge that takes effect more than 4 years after the date of purchase must be printed clearly in at least 10 point type in a visible place on:<section prefix="(1)">The front or back of the gift certificate;</section><section prefix="(2)">A sticker permanently affixed to the gift certificate; or</section><section prefix="(3)">An envelope containing the gift certificate.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Unless the change benefits the consumer, a term or condition disclosed under subsection (c) of this section may not be changed after the date of purchase or issuance.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">A gift certificate that is sold or issued in violation of this section shall be considered valid and may not be subject to expiration or any fee or charge.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">A violation of any provision of this section:<section prefix="(1)">Is an unfair or deceptive trade practice within the meaning of Title 13 of this article; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Is subject to the enforcement and penalty provisions contained in Title 13 of this article, except &#xA7; 13-411 of this article.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
