<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcl" order_by="gcl" level="1">Commercial Law</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcl-12-312</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this section the following words have the meanings indicated....</catch_line>
  <order_by>312</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Covered loan" means a mortgage loan made under this subtitle that meets the criteria for a loan subject to the federal Home Ownership Equity Protection Act set forth in 15 U.S.C. &#xA7; 1602(aa), as modified from time to time by Regulation Z, 12 C.F.R. Part 226, except that the comparison percentages for the mortgage loan shall be one percentage point less than those specified in 15 U.S.C. &#xA7; 1602(aa), as modified from time to time by Regulation Z, 12 C.F.R. Part 226.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Credit health insurance" has the meaning stated in &#xA7; 13-101 of the Insurance Article.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">"Credit involuntary unemployment benefit insurance" has the meaning stated in &#xA7; 13-101 of the Insurance Article.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">
        <section prefix="(i)">"Credit life insurance" means insurance on the life of a borrower that provides indemnity for repayment of a specific loan or credit transaction on the death of the borrower.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">"Credit life insurance" does not include life insurance payable to a beneficiary designated by the borrower other than the obligee of a specific loan or credit transaction.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(6)">"Mortgage loan" has the meaning stated in &#xA7; 11-501 of the Financial Institutions Article.</section>
      <section prefix="(7)">"Premium" has the meaning stated in &#xA7; 1-101 of the Insurance Article.</section>
      <section prefix="(8)">"Single premium coverage" means insurance for which the total premium is payable in one lump sum at or before the time coverage commences.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Subject to the provisions of this section, a lender may collect from the borrower, at the option of the borrower, the premiums paid for:<section prefix="(1)">Insurance covering any real or personal property pledged as security for the loan;</section><section prefix="(2)">Credit health insurance covering any one or more borrowers, if the insurance does not provide for benefits exceeding the actual period of disability;</section><section prefix="(3)">Credit life insurance:<section prefix="(i)">Covering any one borrower for any loan under $700 in value or amount; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">Covering any one or more borrowers for any loan of $700 or more in value or amount; and</section></section><section prefix="(4)">Credit involuntary unemployment benefit insurance covering any one borrower, if the insurance:<section prefix="(i)">Does not provide for benefits exceeding the actual period of unemployment; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Is not contingent upon the purchase of any other type of insurance permitted under this subtitle.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A lender may not require that the insurance be purchased through a particular insurance producer or insurance company.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The lender may:<section prefix="(i)">Assist an applicant or act with the applicant in forwarding an application to an insurance producer; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Receive and transmit premiums or other identifiable charges for the insurance.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Subject to subsection (e) of this section, at the option of the borrower, a lender may be coinsured or protected to the extent of his interest by a mortgagee clause.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Subject to subsection (e) of this section, the amount of property insurance may not exceed either the reasonable value of the property insured or the originally scheduled total of payments under the loan contract.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The terms and conditions of the property insurance policy shall be filed with and approved by the Insurance Commissioner.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">Property insurance may be provided by the lender if the borrower, at the time the loan is made, fails to furnish a loss payable endorsement for the protection of the lender in an amount sufficient to cover the amount of the loan or the value of the property securing the loan, whichever is less.</section>
        <section prefix="(iv)">If, however, within 30 days of the inception date of the loan, the borrower does provide a loss payable endorsement for the protection of the lender, and no claim has been filed under the coverage purchased, the lender shall cancel the property insurance on the loan and shall refund the entire original property insurance premium to the borrower.</section>
        <section prefix="(v)">A lender providing property insurance under this section shall give the borrower, at the time the loan is made, a written notice of the borrower's right to provide a loss payable endorsement for the protection of the lender and the borrower's right to a refund of the entire property insurance premium.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Credit health insurance shall provide for:<section prefix="(i)">Benefits not exceeding the then scheduled unpaid total of payments of the loan;</section><section prefix="(ii)">A waiting period of at least 14 days; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Periodic benefits, the amount of each of which may not exceed the originally scheduled total of payments under the loan contract, divided by the number of installments.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The amount of credit life insurance in force may not exceed the unpaid principal but shall include all accrued interest under the loan contract.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">Credit involuntary unemployment benefit insurance shall provide that, in the event of involuntary loss of employment, the aggregate amount of periodic benefits payable in the event of involuntary loss of employment, as defined in the policy, may not exceed the then scheduled unpaid total of payments of the loan.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Except as provided in this paragraph, a person making a covered loan may not finance as a part of the covered loan transaction single premium coverage for:<section prefix="1.">Credit health insurance;</section><section prefix="2.">Credit involuntary unemployment benefit insurance; or</section><section prefix="3.">Credit life insurance.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">Nothing in this paragraph shall prohibit the financing of any insurance coverage in connection with a mobile home or its premises, as those terms are defined in &#xA7; 8A-101 of the Real Property Article.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this subsection, "property insurance coverage" means property insurance against losses caused by perils that commonly are covered in insurance policies described with terms similar to "standard fire" or "standard fire with extended coverage".</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">A lender may not require a borrower, as a condition to receiving or maintaining a loan secured by a first mortgage or first deed of trust, to provide or purchase property insurance coverage against risks to any improvements on any real property in an amount exceeding the replacement value of improvements on the real property.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">In determining the replacement value of the improvements on any real property, the lender may:<section prefix="1.">Accept the value placed on the improvements by the insurer; or</section><section prefix="2.">Use the value placed on the improvements that is determined by the lender's appraisal of the real property.</section></section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A violation of this subsection or of subsection (c)(1) of this section shall entitle the borrower to seek:<section prefix="(i)">An injunction to prohibit the lender who has engaged or is engaging in the violation from continuing or engaging in the violation;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Reasonable attorney's fees; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Damages directly resulting from the violation.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">A violation of this subsection or of subsection (c)(1) of this section does not affect the validity of the first mortgage or first deed of trust securing the loan.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">Under this subtitle, insurance may be obtained only:<section prefix="(1)">From an insurance company qualified to do business in the State; and</section><section prefix="(2)">At rates not exceeding those approved by the Insurance Administration.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(g)">Within 25 days after a lender has charged for any insurance in connection with a loan, he shall deliver a copy of the appropriate policy or certificate to the borrower.</section>
  </text>
</law>
