<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gcl" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="11-1201" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcl-11-1201</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Improper means" includes theft, bribery, misrepresentation, breach or inducement of a breach of a duty to maintain secrecy, or espionage through electronic or other means.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Misappropriation" means the:<section prefix="(1)">Acquisition of a trade secret of another by a person who knows or has reason to know that the trade secret was acquired by improper means; or</section><section prefix="(2)">Disclosure or use of a trade secret of another without express or implied consent by a person who:<section prefix="(i)">Used improper means to acquire knowledge of the trade secret; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">At the time of disclosure or use, knew or had reason to know that the person's knowledge of the trade secret was:</section><section prefix="(iii)">Before a material change of the person's position, knew or had reason to know that it was a trade secret and that knowledge of it had been acquired by accident or mistake.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">"Person" means an individual, corporation, business trust, statutory trust, estate, trust, partnership, association, joint venture, government, governmental subdivision or agency, or any other legal or commercial entity.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"Trade secret" means information, including a formula, pattern, compilation, program, device, method, technique, or process, that:<section prefix="(1)">Derives independent economic value, actual or potential, from not being generally known to, and not being readily ascertainable by proper means by, other persons who can obtain economic value from its disclosure or use; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Is the subject of efforts that are reasonable under the circumstances to maintain its secrecy.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
