<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcl" order_by="gcl" level="1">Commercial Law</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcl-14-2601</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated....</catch_line>
  <order_by>2601</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Consumer" means a natural person.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Disclosure statement" means a written statement that includes the following information:<section prefix="(1)">A statement that a copy of the current financial statement of the individual or organization on whose behalf the solicitation is made is available on request; and</section><section prefix="(2)">The name of the individual or organization on whose behalf the solicitation is made and the address and telephone number where requests for a copy of the financial statement should be directed.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Door-to-door solicitation" means a single or multiple request, directly or indirectly, for money or other valuable consideration or for a pledge or subsequent contribution of money or other valuable consideration, whether or not it is made in exchange for any tangible or intangible item:<section prefix="(i)">That promotes the programs or goals of the organization on whose behalf the solicitation is made;</section><section prefix="(ii)">That is made in person by the solicitor; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Where the consumer's payment, pledge, or promise is made at the consumer's home or residence.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Door-to-door solicitation" does not include a transaction that:<section prefix="(i)">Is subject to:<section prefix="1.">The consumer debt collection law, Subtitle 2 of this title;</section><section prefix="2.">The Door-to-Door Sales Act, Subtitle 3 of this title; or</section><section prefix="3.">The Telephone Solicitation Act, Subtitle 22 of this title;</section></section><section prefix="(ii)">Is made in the regular course of business by any person licensed or regulated under:<section prefix="1.">The Insurance Article;</section><section prefix="2.">Title 11 of this article; or</section><section prefix="3.">The Business Occupations and Professions Article;</section></section><section prefix="(iii)">Is made in the regular course of business by:<section prefix="1.">Any person defined as a financial institution under the Financial Institutions Article;</section><section prefix="2.">A corporation regulated by the Maryland Public Service Commission; or</section><section prefix="3.">A broker-dealer or investment advisor registered with the Securities and Exchange Commission or the Maryland Securities Commissioner; or</section></section><section prefix="(iv)">Is a solicitation by or on behalf of:<section prefix="1.">A charitable organization, as defined in &#xA7; 6-101 of the Business Regulation Article, that is exempt from federal income taxation; or</section><section prefix="2.">A fraternal organization of fire fighters, rescue or ambulance personnel, or police or other law enforcement organization soliciting for charitable purposes.</section></section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"Organization" means any group, trust fund, foundation, association, corporation, society, or any combination of entities and includes an entity that is affiliated with an organization that is organized or has its principal place of business outside the State.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">"Solicitor" means the individual making a door-to-door solicitation.</section>
  </text>
</law>
