<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcl" order_by="gcl" level="1">Commercial Law</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcl-12-123</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this section, "binder" means a binder or other temporary contract of insurance as provided under ...</catch_line>
  <order_by>123</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, "binder" means a binder or other temporary contract of insurance as provided under &#xA7; 12-106 of the Insurance Article.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A lender shall comply with this section if the lender:<section prefix="(1)">Makes any loan secured by a first mortgage or a first deed of trust on any interest in owner-occupied residential real property; and</section><section prefix="(2)">As a condition of making the loan, requires the borrower to purchase property insurance or credit loss insurance.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A lender who makes a loan subject to this section shall accept as evidence of insurance a written binder issued by any authorized insurer or its insurance producer if the binder includes or is accompanied by:<section prefix="(1)">The name and address of the insured borrower;</section><section prefix="(2)">The name and address of the lender;</section><section prefix="(3)">A description of the insured residential real property;</section><section prefix="(4)">A provision that the binder may not be canceled within the term of the binder unless the lender and the insured borrower receive written notice of the cancellation at least 10 days prior to the cancellation;</section><section prefix="(5)">Except in the case of the renewal of a policy subsequent to the closing of the loan, a paid receipt for the full amount of the applicable premium; and</section><section prefix="(6)">The amount of coverage.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">This section does not prohibit a lender from refusing to honor a binder in cases where:<section prefix="(1)">The lender receives notice of the cancellation of the binder by the insurer; or</section><section prefix="(2)">At the expiration of 30 days of the date the binder was given, the insurer has failed to issue the policy of insurance.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
