<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gcl" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="14-1204" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcl-14-1204</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">A person may not procure or cause to be prepared an investigative consumer report on any consumer unless:<section prefix="(1)">It is clearly and accurately disclosed to the consumer that an investigative consumer report including information as to his character, general reputation, personal characteristics, and mode of living, whichever are applicable, may be made, and the disclosure:<section prefix="(i)">Is made in a writing mailed, or otherwise delivered, to the consumer, not later than three days after the date on which the report was first requested; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Includes a statement informing the consumer of his right to request the additional disclosures provided for under subsection (b) of this section; or</section></section><section prefix="(2)">The report is to be used for employment purposes for which the consumer has not specifically applied.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Any person who procures or causes to be prepared an investigative consumer report on any consumer shall make, upon written request made by the consumer within a reasonable period of time after the receipt by him of the disclosure required by subsection (a)(1) of this section, a complete and accurate disclosure of the nature and scope of the investigation requested. This disclosure shall be made in a writing mailed, or otherwise delivered, to the consumer not later than five days after the date on which the request for the disclosure was received from the consumer or the report was first requested, whichever is the later.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">No person may be held liable for any violation of subsection (a) or (b) of this section if he shows by a preponderance of the evidence that at the time of the violation he maintained reasonable procedures to assure compliance with subsection (a) or (b) of this section.</section>
  </text>
</law>
