<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcl" order_by="gcl" level="1">Commercial Law</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcl-14-1501</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated....</catch_line>
  <order_by>1501</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Consumer" means:<section prefix="(1)">The purchaser, other than for purposes of resale, of a new motor vehicle;</section><section prefix="(2)">Any person to whom a new motor vehicle is transferred during the duration of the warranty applicable to such motor vehicle; or</section><section prefix="(3)">Any other person who is entitled to enforce the obligations of the warranty.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Dealer" has the meaning provided in &#xA7; 15-101(c) of the Transportation Article.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">"Manufacturer, factory branch, or distributor" means a person, partnership, association, corporation, or entity engaged in the business of manufacturing or assembling motor vehicles or of distributing motor vehicles to motor vehicle dealers as defined in &#xA7; 15-201(b), (c), and (e) of the Transportation Article.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Manufacturer's warranty period" means the earlier of:<section prefix="(i)">The period of the motor vehicle's first 18,000 miles of operation; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">24 months following the date of original delivery of the motor vehicle to the consumer.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">This subsection does not extend any manufacturer's express warranty.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Motor vehicle" means a vehicle that is registered in this State as a:<section prefix="(i)">Class A (passenger) vehicle;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Class D (motorcycle) vehicle;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Class E (truck) vehicle with a 3/4 ton or less manufacturer's rated capacity; or</section><section prefix="(iv)">Class M (multipurpose) vehicle.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Motor vehicle" does not include a motor home. For the purpose of administering this subtitle, the Motor Vehicle Administration shall promulgate a regulation defining a motor home.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">"Warranty" means warranties as defined in &#xA7;&#xA7; 2-312, 2-313, 2-314, and 2-315 of this article.</section>
  </text>
</law>
