<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcl" order_by="" level="1">Commercial Law</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcl-14-1008</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>1008</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Except as provided in subsection (c) of this section, before beginning any repair work on a motor vehicle, an automotive repair facility shall give the customer a copy of a form used for authorization of repairs which shall inform the customer of the following rights:<section prefix="(1)">That a customer:<section prefix="(i)">May request a written estimate for repairs which cost in excess of $50; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">May not be charged any amount ten percent in excess of the written estimate without the customer's consent;</section></section><section prefix="(2)">That the customer is entitled to the return of any replaced parts except when parts are required to be returned to the manufacturer under a warranty agreement; and</section><section prefix="(3)">That repairs not originally authorized by the customer may not be charged to the customer without the customer's consent.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The customer's rights provided in subsection (a) of this section shall be:<section prefix="(1)">Displayed immediately before the space for the signature of the customer conspicuously in easily readable type;</section><section prefix="(2)">Physically separated from the other terms of the form used for authorization of repairs; and</section><section prefix="(3)">Listed under the printed heading "Customer's Rights".</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">An automotive repair facility may inform the customer orally of the customer's rights if:<section prefix="(i)">The customer's motor vehicle is towed to the automotive repair facility for repair; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">The customer leaves the vehicle for repair at the repair facility when the facility is not open.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Under this subsection, if any automotive repair facility informs a customer orally of the customer's rights, the facility shall record in writing:<section prefix="(i)">The name of the persons notified;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The date and time of the notification; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">The signature of the person who made the notification.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The authorization form shall include the following notice:</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The authorization form shall include a clear statement that while the customer's motor vehicle is on the premises of the automotive repair facility, the automotive repair facility may not be responsible for damage to the customer's motor vehicle under certain circumstances, and that the customer should ask a representative of the automotive repair facility about the extent of its responsibility, including the extent of the insurance coverage of the automotive repair facility.</section>
  </text>
</law>
