<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcl" order_by="gcl" level="1">Commercial Law</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcl-11-503</section_number>
  <catch_line>In a wholesale sale of cigarettes, the presumptive wholesale markup of 5 percent provided for in &#xA7; ...</catch_line>
  <order_by>503</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In a wholesale sale of cigarettes, the presumptive wholesale markup of 5 percent provided for in &#xA7; 11-501(e) of this subtitle may be reduced by 2 cents for each carton of 200 cigarettes, if:<section prefix="(1)">The cigarettes are not delivered unless their full price is received by the wholesaler at or before delivery; and</section><section prefix="(2)">The purchaser performs or pays for the cartage cost of the cigarettes to the place of business of the purchaser.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In the absence of satisfactory proof of a lesser aggregate cost of doing business, a vending machine operator or retailer who purchases cigarettes at prices ordinarily invoiced to a wholesaler and who receives the wholesaler's discounts on them shall:<section prefix="(i)">First, add to his basic cost of cigarettes the wholesale markup of 5 percent provided for in &#xA7; 11-501(e) of this subtitle to cover the cost of doing business as a wholesaler; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Then, on the resultant sum, add the retail markup of 8 percent provided for in &#xA7; 11-501(d) of this subtitle.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If the discount received by the vending machine operator or retailer is less than that ordinarily allowed to wholesalers, the wholesale markup of 5 percent may be reduced by the difference between the discount ordinarily allowed to wholesalers and the discount received by the retailer or vending machine operator.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A wholesaler who sells cigarettes to another wholesaler or to a vending machine operator is not required to include in his selling price the cost to the wholesaler. However, in the absence of satisfactory proof of a lesser cost for the service rendered, the wholesaler shall include in the selling price his basic cost of cigarettes, plus a charge of 1 percent of his basic cost of cigarettes.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If a wholesaler purchases cigarettes from another wholesaler, then, on resale of the cigarettes to a retailer, he is the wholesaler for the purposes of this subtitle.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
