<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcl" order_by="" level="1">Commercial Law</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcl-12-1101</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>1101</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Advertisement" means a commercial message in any medium that aids, promotes, or assists, directly or indirectly, a rental-purchase agreement.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Advertisement" does not include in-store merchandising ads.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Cash price" means the price at which the lessor would have sold rental property covered by a rental-purchase agreement to the consumer unconditionally for cash on the date of consummation.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">"Consumer" means an individual who rents personal property under a rental-purchase agreement primarily for personal, family, or household purposes.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"Consummation" means the time at which a consumer enters into a rental-purchase agreement.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">"Lessor" means a person who regularly provides the use of personal property through rental-purchase agreements to consumers and to whom rental payments are initially payable on the face of a rental-purchase agreement.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">"Rental property" means personal property that is the subject of a rental-purchase agreement.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">"Rental-purchase agreement" means an agreement that:<section prefix="(1)">Is for the use of personal property by an individual primarily for personal, family, or household purposes;</section><section prefix="(2)">Is for an initial period of 4 months or less;</section><section prefix="(3)">Is automatically renewable for a weekly or monthly period with each rental payment after the initial period; and</section><section prefix="(4)">Allows but does not obligate the consumer to become the owner of the property.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
