<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcl" order_by="" level="1">Commercial Law</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcl-17-311</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>311</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Within 365 days from the filing of the report required by &#xA7; 17-310 of this subtitle, the Administrator shall cause notice to be published in a newspaper of general circulation in the county in the State within which is located the last known address of any person to be named in the notice.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If an address is not listed or if the address is outside the State, the notice shall be published in the county within which the person who held the abandoned property has the principal place of business in this State.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The published notice shall be entitled "Notice of Names of Persons Appearing to Be Owners of Abandoned Property" and shall contain:<section prefix="(1)">The names in alphabetical order and last known addresses, if any, of persons listed in the report and entitled to notice in the county specified in this section;</section><section prefix="(2)">A statement that information concerning the amount or description of the property and the name and address of the person who held the property may be obtained by any person who possesses an interest in the property, by addressing an inquiry to the Administrator; and</section><section prefix="(3)">A statement that a proof of claim may be presented by the owner to the Administrator.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Administrator is not required to publish in the notice any item valued at less than $100 unless the Administrator considers the publication to be in the public interest.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Within 120 days from the receipt of the report required by &#xA7; 17-310 of this subtitle, the Administrator shall mail a notice to each person who has an address listed in the report who appears entitled to property valued at $100 or more and presumed abandoned under this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The mailed notice shall contain:<section prefix="(1)">A statement that, according to a report filed with the Administrator, property is being held to which the addressee appears entitled;</section><section prefix="(2)">The name and address of the person who held the property and any necessary information regarding any change of the name or address of the holder; and</section><section prefix="(3)">A statement that a proof of claim may be presented by the owner to the Administrator.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
