<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcl" order_by="" level="1">Commercial Law</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcl-11-704.1</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>704.1</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">"Local telephone classified advertising directory" means a telephone directory that:<section prefix="1.">Contains classified advertisements; and</section><section prefix="2.">Is distributed free of charge to residents in the State.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">"Local telephone classified advertising directory" includes a directory distributed by a person other than a telephone company.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">"Local telephone directory" means a telephone directory that is:<section prefix="1.">Available free of charge to telephone subscribers in an area of the State; and</section><section prefix="2.">Does not contain classified advertisements.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">"Local telephone directory" includes a directory distributed by a person other than a telephone company.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(4)">"Location" means any part of the address of a person, including the street, the city, or the state.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This section applies only to business telephone listings and advertisements.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">This section does not apply to any bank, trust company, savings bank, savings and loan association, or credit union incorporated or chartered under the laws of this State or the United States or any other state bank having a branch in this State.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A person is in violation of &#xA7; 11-703 of this subtitle if the person:<section prefix="(i)">Causes to be published in a local telephone classified advertising directory an advertisement that misrepresents the location of the person; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">Causes to be listed in a local telephone directory a telephone listing that misrepresents the location of the person.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">For purposes of this subsection, a person commits a separate violation for each edition of a local telephone directory or local telephone advertising directory in which the advertisement or telephone listing is published.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
