<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcl" order_by="gcl" level="1">Commercial Law</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcl-17-101</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this title the following words have the meanings indicated....</catch_line>
  <order_by>101</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this title the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Abandoned property" means personal property that is considered abandoned under this title.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Abandoned property" includes property in the custody of the federal government that is classified as "unclaimed property" under federal law.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Administrator" means the State Comptroller.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">"Banking organization" means any bank, trust company, savings bank, land bank, and any other similar organization engaged in business in the State.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"Business association" means any corporation, joint stock company, business trust, statutory trust, partnership, or any association for business purposes of two or more individuals.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">"County" includes Baltimore City.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">"Federal government" includes any of its agencies or instrumentalities.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">"Financial organization" means any savings and loan association or credit union engaged in business in the State.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">"Holder" means any person who is:<section prefix="(1)">In possession of property subject to this title belonging to another;</section><section prefix="(2)">A trustee, in the case of a trust; or</section><section prefix="(3)">Indebted to another on an obligation subject to this title.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(j)">"Insurance corporation" means any association or corporation transacting in the State the business of insurance on the lives of persons or insurance pertaining to life insurance, including endowments and annuities, disability, accident and health insurance, and property, casualty, and surety insurance, as these terms are defined in the Insurance Article.</section>
    <section prefix="(k)">"Owner" means:<section prefix="(1)">In the case of a deposit, a depositor or a person entitled to receive the funds as reflected on the records of the bank or financial organization;</section><section prefix="(2)">In the case of a trust, a beneficiary;</section><section prefix="(3)">In the case of other choses in action, a creditor, claimant, or payee;</section><section prefix="(4)">In the case of abandoned property in federal custody, the person who is defined as the owner by any applicable federal law; or</section><section prefix="(5)">Any person who has a legal or equitable interest in property subject to this title, or the legal representative of that person.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(l)">"Person" includes the State, any county, municipal corporation, or other political subdivision of the State, or any of their units, an individual, business association, corporation, business trust, statutory trust, estate, trust, partnership, association, two or more persons having a joint or common interest, or any other legal or commercial entity.</section>
    <section prefix="(m)">"Personal property" does not include:<section prefix="(1)">A gift certificate;</section><section prefix="(2)">Credits in connection with the sale of consumer goods to a wholesaler or retailer in the ordinary course of business;</section><section prefix="(3)">Outstanding checks or credits issued to vendors or commercial customers in the ordinary course of business, other than property described in &#xA7; 17-301(a) of this title held by a banking organization or financial organization;</section><section prefix="(4)">Credit balances in vendor or commercial customer accounts that occur in the ordinary course of business, other than property described in &#xA7; 17-301(a) of this title held by a banking organization or financial organization; or</section><section prefix="(5)">Purchase price rebates issued to customers in the ordinary course of business.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(n)">"Service charge" means any type of deduction or charge made by a holder on property presumed abandoned under this title.</section>
    <section prefix="(o)">"Utility" means any person who owns or operates in the State, for public use, any plant, equipment, property, franchise, or license for the transmission of communications, for the production, storage, transmission, sale, delivery, or furnishing of electricity, water, steam, or gas, or for the transportation of persons or property.</section>
  </text>
</law>
