<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcl" order_by="" level="1">Commercial Law</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcl-4A-105</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>105</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this title:<section prefix="(1)">"Authorized account" means a deposit account of a customer in a bank designated by the customer as a source of payment of payment orders issued by the customer to the bank. If a customer does not so designate an account, any account of the customer is an authorized account if payment of a payment order from that account is not inconsistent with a restriction on the use of that account.</section><section prefix="(2)">"Bank" means a person engaged in the business of banking and includes a savings bank, savings and loan association, credit union, and trust company. A branch or separate office of a bank is a separate bank for purposes of this title.</section><section prefix="(3)">"Customer" means a person, including a bank, having an account with a bank or from whom a bank has agreed to receive payment orders.</section><section prefix="(4)">"Funds-transfer business day" of a receiving bank means the part of a day during which the receiving bank is open for the receipt, processing, and transmittal of payment orders and cancellations and amendments of payment orders.</section><section prefix="(5)">"Funds-transfer system" means a wire transfer network, automated clearing house, or other communication system of a clearing house or other association of banks through which a payment order by a bank may be transmitted to the bank to which the order is addressed.</section><section prefix="(6)">Reserved.</section><section prefix="(7)">"Prove" with respect to a fact means to meet the burden of establishing the fact (&#xA7; 1-208(b)(8)).</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Other definitions applying to this title and the sections in which they appear are:</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The following definitions in Title 4 of this article apply to this title:</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">In addition, Title 1 of this article contains general definitions and principles of construction and interpretation applicable throughout this title.</section>
  </text>
</law>
