<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcl" order_by="gcl" level="1">Commercial Law</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcl-12-922</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this section the following words have the meanings indicated....</catch_line>
  <order_by>922</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Borrower" means a consumer borrower who makes an application for a loan secured by a first mortgage or first deed of trust on residential real property to be occupied by the borrower as the borrower's primary residence.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Commitment" means a written, specific, binding agreement between a borrower and a lender which sets forth the terms of a loan being extended to the borrower.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">"Financing agreement" means a written agreement between a borrower and a lender which sets forth the terms of a purchase money loan or a refinancing of an existing loan that:<section prefix="(i)">Results in or is secured by a first mortgage or a first deed of trust on residential real property to be occupied by the borrower; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Is offered or extended to the borrower.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(5)">
        <section prefix="(i)">"Lender" means a credit grantor subject to the licensing requirements of Title 11, Subtitle 5 of the Financial Institutions Article.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">"Lender" does not include a credit grantor exempt from licensing under &#xA7; 11-502 of the Financial Institutions Article.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(6)">
        <section prefix="(i)">"Loan application" means any oral or written request for an extension of credit that is made in accordance with procedures established by a lender for the purpose of inducing the lender to seek to procure or make a mortgage loan.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">"Loan application" does not include the use of an account or line of credit to obtain a loan within a previously established credit limit.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A lender who offers to make or procure a loan secured by a first mortgage or first deed of trust on residential real property to be occupied by the borrower shall provide the borrower with a financing agreement executed by the lender within 10 business days after the date the loan application is completed.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The financing agreement shall provide:<section prefix="(i)">The term and principal amount of the loan;</section><section prefix="(ii)">An explanation of the type of mortgage loan being offered;</section><section prefix="(iii)">The rate of interest that will apply to the loan and, if the rate is subject to change or is a variable rate or is subject to final determination at a future date based on some objective standard, a specific statement of those facts;</section><section prefix="(iv)">The points, if any, to be paid by the borrower or the seller, or both; and</section><section prefix="(v)">The term during which the financing agreement remains in effect.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">If all the provisions of the financing agreement are not subject to future determination, change, or alteration during its term, the financing agreement shall constitute the final binding agreement between the parties as to the items covered by the financing agreement.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If any of the provisions of the financing agreement are subject to change or determination after its execution, the lender shall provide the borrower with a commitment, executed by the lender, at least 72 hours before the time of settlement agreed to by the parties, providing:<section prefix="(i)">The effective fixed interest rate or initial interest rate that will be applied to the loan; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">A restatement of all the remaining unchanged provisions of the financing agreement.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Subsequent to execution of the financing agreement, the borrower may waive in writing the 72-hour advance presentation requirement and accept the commitment at settlement only if compliance with the 72-hour requirement is shown by the lender to be infeasible.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A borrower aggrieved by any violation of this section shall be entitled to bring a civil suit for damages, including reasonable attorney's fees, against the lender.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The penalties set out under &#xA7; 12-918 of this subtitle do not apply to any violation of this section.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
