<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcl" order_by="gcl" level="1">Commercial Law</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcl-22-113</section_number>
  <catch_line>The effect of any provision of this title, including an allocation of risk or imposition of a burden...</catch_line>
  <order_by>113</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The effect of any provision of this title, including an allocation of risk or imposition of a burden, may be varied by agreement of the parties. However, the following rules apply:<section prefix="(1)">Obligations of good faith, diligence, reasonableness, and care imposed by this title may not be disclaimed by agreement, but the parties by agreement may determine the standards by which the performance of the obligation is to be measured if the standards are not manifestly unreasonable.</section><section prefix="(2)">The limitations on enforceability imposed by unconscionability under &#xA7; 22-111 of this subtitle and fundamental public policy under &#xA7; 22-105(b) of this subtitle may not be varied by agreement.</section><section prefix="(3)">Limitations on enforceability of, or agreement to, a contract, term, or right expressly stated in the sections of this title listed in the following subparagraphs may not be varied by agreement except to the extent provided in each section:<section prefix="(A)">The limitations on agreed choice of law in &#xA7; 22-109(a);</section><section prefix="(B)">The limitations on agreed choice of forum in &#xA7; 22-110;</section><section prefix="(C)">The requirements for manifesting assent and opportunity for review in &#xA7; 22-112;</section><section prefix="(D)">The limitations on enforceability in &#xA7; 22-201;</section><section prefix="(E)">The limitations on a mass-market license in &#xA7; 22-209;</section><section prefix="(F)">The consumer defense arising from an electronic error in &#xA7; 22-214;</section><section prefix="(G)">The requirements for an enforceable term in &#xA7;&#xA7; 22-303(b), 22-307(g), 22-406(b) and (c), and 22-804(a);</section><section prefix="(H)">The limitations on a financier in &#xA7;&#xA7; 22-507 through 22-511;</section><section prefix="(I)">The restrictions on altering the period of limitations in &#xA7; 22-805(a) and (b); and</section><section prefix="(J)">The limitations on self-help repossession in &#xA7;&#xA7; 22-815(b) and 22-816.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Any usage of trade of which the parties are or should be aware and any course of dealing or course of performance between the parties are relevant to determining the existence or meaning of an agreement.</section>
  </text>
</law>
