<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcl" order_by="gcl" level="1">Commercial Law</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcl-16-203</section_number>
  <catch_line>The lienor may retain possession of the property subject to the lien until:...</catch_line>
  <order_by>203</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The lienor may retain possession of the property subject to the lien until:<section prefix="(1)">The charges which give rise to the lien are paid; or</section><section prefix="(2)">The lien is otherwise discharged in accordance with this subtitle.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Except as provided in subparagraph (ii) of this paragraph, within 30 days after the creation of a lien under this subtitle, including a lien created under &#xA7; 16-207(c) of this subtitle, the lienor shall send notice of the lien by registered or certified mail to all holders of perfected security interests in the property who:<section prefix="1.">Are known to the lienor; or</section><section prefix="2.">Can be identified through a search of the public records where filings are made to perfect security interests in the property.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">For a lien created under &#xA7; 16-202(b) of this subtitle, the lienor shall send the notice required under subparagraph (i) of this paragraph within 45 days after the creation of the lien.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Subject to subparagraph (ii) of this paragraph, the notice required under paragraph (1) of this subsection shall be sent to the address shown on the document that creates or otherwise gives notice of the perfected security interest.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">For a lien created under this subtitle in a motor vehicle registered in this State, the notice required under paragraph (1) of this subsection may be sent to the addresses of all holders of perfected security interests in the motor vehicle that are listed in the certified records issued to the lienor by the Motor Vehicle Administration.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The lienor shall send the notice required under paragraph (1) of this subsection prior to publishing and sending the notice required under &#xA7; 16-207(b) of this subtitle.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
