<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gcl" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="12-924" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcl-12-924</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, this section applies only to a plan between a credit grantor and a consumer borrower under which a credit grantor has taken any property as security for credit extended under the plan.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">This section does not apply to a loan to which &#xA7; 3-105.1 of the Real Property Article applies.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A credit grantor shall release any recorded mortgage, deed of trust, security agreement, or other lien securing the extension of credit within a reasonable time after:<section prefix="(1)">The outstanding unpaid indebtedness under a plan has been paid in full;</section><section prefix="(2)">There are no further obligations of the credit grantor or the consumer borrower under the plan; and</section><section prefix="(3)">The account under the plan is closed.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The release shall be:<section prefix="(1)">In writing; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Prepared at the expense of the credit grantor.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If the credit grantor does not record the release, the credit grantor shall furnish the consumer borrower with the release in a recordable form.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If the credit grantor records the release, the credit grantor shall furnish the consumer borrower with a copy of the release.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If a fee is collected by a credit grantor for the recording of a release:<section prefix="(i)">The release shall be recorded by the credit grantor; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Any portion of the fee not paid to a governmental entity for recording the release shall be refunded to the borrower.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If a fee is not collected by a credit grantor for the recording of a release, the credit grantor is not obligated to record the release.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
