<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcl" order_by="gcl" level="1">Commercial Law</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcl-14-2902</section_number>
  <catch_line>For the purpose of purchasing, selling, or disposing of property or a service, a person may not adve...</catch_line>
  <order_by>2902</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">For the purpose of purchasing, selling, or disposing of property or a service, a person may not advertise a statement containing a representation of fact that the person knows, or by the exercise of reasonable care should know, to be untrue, deceptive, or misleading.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A person may not offer for sale repossessed, reconditioned, rebuilt, or secondhand property, knowing the property to be repossessed, reconditioned, rebuilt, or secondhand, unless:<section prefix="(1)">The property is identified clearly as repossessed, reconditioned, rebuilt, or secondhand; or</section><section prefix="(2)">The circumstances of the sale make it clear to a reasonable purchaser that the property is repossessed, reconditioned, rebuilt, or secondhand.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A person may not knowingly advertise for sale property or a service that the person does not possess or control for the purpose of inducing or increasing the sale of other property or service that the person possesses or controls.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A person who issues, sells, or offers to sell a passenger ticket to board a vessel may not omit reference to the country of registry of the vessel in any advertisement or any other similar printed paper or notice, written or oral, regarding:<section prefix="(i)">The voyage or the ticket that entitles or purports to entitle its owner, purchaser, or holder to the voyage;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The vessel for which the voyage is sold or offered;</section><section prefix="(iii)">The line that the vessel is part of; or</section><section prefix="(iv)">If applicable, that the person is an agent for the line or vessel.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Reference in a printed advertisement to the country of registry of the vessel shall be no less prominently displayed than the balance of the material appearing in the advertisement.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">A person may not advertise for sale property subject to a ground rent at a stated price or on terms stating the amount of any installment payments without also stating the amount of the annual ground rent for the property.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">A person who violates this section is guilty of a misdemeanor and on conviction is subject to imprisonment not exceeding 1 year or a fine not exceeding $1,000 or both.</section>
  </text>
</law>
