<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gcl" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="4-104" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcl-4-104</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this title, unless the context otherwise requires:<section prefix="(1)">"Account" means any deposit or credit account with a bank, including a demand, time, savings, passbook, share draft, or like account, other than an account evidenced by a certificate of deposit;</section><section prefix="(2)">"Afternoon" means the period of a day between noon and midnight;</section><section prefix="(3)">"Banking day" means the part of a day, excluding Saturday, Sunday, or a legal holiday, on which a bank is open to the public for carrying on substantially all of its banking functions;</section><section prefix="(4)">"Clearing-house" means an association of banks or other payors regularly clearing items;</section><section prefix="(5)">"Customer" means a person having an account with a bank or for whom a bank has agreed to collect items, including a bank that maintains an account at another bank;</section><section prefix="(6)">"Documentary draft" means a draft to be presented for acceptance or payment if specified documents, certificated securities (&#xA7; 8-102) or instructions for uncertificated securities (&#xA7; 8-102), or other certificates, statements, or the like are to be received by the drawee or other payor before acceptance or payment of the draft;</section><section prefix="(7)">"Draft" means a draft as defined in &#xA7; 3-104 or an item, other than an instrument, that is an order;</section><section prefix="(8)">"Drawee" means a person ordered in a draft to make payment;</section><section prefix="(9)">"Item" means an instrument or a promise or order to pay money handled by a bank for collection or payment. The term does not include a payment order governed by Title 4A or a credit or debit card slip;</section><section prefix="(10)">"Midnight deadline" with respect to a bank is midnight on its next banking day following the banking day on which it receives the relevant item or notice or from which the time for taking action commences to run, whichever is later;</section><section prefix="(11)">"Settle" means to pay in cash, by clearing-house settlement, in a charge or credit or by remittance, or otherwise as agreed. A settlement may be either provisional or final;</section><section prefix="(12)">"Suspends payments" with respect to a bank means that it has been closed by order of the supervisory authorities, that a public officer has been appointed to take it over; or that it ceases or refuses to make payments in the ordinary course of business.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Other definitions applying to this title and the sections in which they appear are:</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The following definitions in other titles apply to this title:</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">In addition Title 1 contains general definitions and principles of construction and interpretation applicable throughout this title.</section>
  </text>
</law>
