<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcl" order_by="gcl" level="1">Commercial Law</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcl-11-101</section_number>
  <catch_line>It is the policy of the State of Maryland to oppose restraints of trade and unfair trade practices i...</catch_line>
  <order_by>101</order_by>
  <text>It is the policy of the State of Maryland to oppose restraints of trade and unfair trade practices in the form of foreign discriminatory boycotts not specifically authorized by the law of the United States which are fostered or imposed by foreign persons, foreign governments or international organizations against any domestic individual on the basis of race, color, creed, religion, sex or national origin. It is also the policy of the State of Maryland to oppose those actions, including the formation of agreements, understandings or contractual arrangements, expressed or implied, which have the effect of furthering or supporting these discriminatory boycotts, in order that the peace, health, safety, prosperity and general welfare of all the inhabitants of the State may be protected and ensured. It is the further policy of the State of Maryland not to impede domestic or foreign commerce, the free flow of goods in commerce, or actions reasonably necessary to protect goods moving in commerce. The State of Maryland recognizes the right of Maryland firms to decide whether to enter into commercial agreements with foreign firms, provided the agreement does not contravene U.S. foreign policy or any federal or Maryland laws and the agreement does not discriminate against domestic individuals entitled to the benefit of the laws of Maryland on the basis of race, color, creed, religion, sex or national origin, and the right of Maryland firms to decide whether to enter into a commercial agreement with a foreign firm that would advance the political and economic interests of a foreign country provided that agreement does not contravene U.S. foreign policy or federal or Maryland laws and does not discriminate against domestic individuals entitled to the benefits of the laws of Maryland on the basis of race, color, creed, religion, sex, or national origin. This subtitle shall be deemed an exercise of the police power of the State of Maryland for the protection of the people of this State, and shall be administered and principally enforced by the Attorney General of the State of Maryland. The provisions of this subtitle shall be construed liberally so as to effectuate this declaration of policy and the laws and Constitution of the United States, but nothing in this subtitle shall be construed to infringe upon the right of the United States government to regulate interstate and foreign commerce.</text>
</law>
