<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcl" order_by="" level="1">Commercial Law</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcl-12-905</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>905</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">With respect to an unsecured open end credit plan, fees or charges may not be imposed on a consumer borrower in addition to interest or finance charges as permitted by this subtitle, except as follows:<section prefix="(1)">If the plan is offered by a seller of goods or services, or both, and may be used only for the purchase or lease of the seller's goods and services, the seller may charge one of the following fees:<section prefix="(i)">An annual charge in any amount the agreement provides for the privileges made available to the consumer borrower under the plan;</section><section prefix="(ii)">A transaction charge or charges in such amount or amounts as the agreement may provide for each separate purchase under the plan; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">A minimum charge for each scheduled billing period under the plan during any portion of which there is an outstanding unpaid indebtedness under the plan.</section></section><section prefix="(2)">If the plan is offered by any other credit grantor, the credit grantor may impose any or all of the following fees:<section prefix="(i)">An annual charge in any amount the agreement provides for the privileges made available to the consumer borrower under the plan;</section><section prefix="(ii)">A transaction charge or charges in such amount or amounts as the agreement may provide for each separate purchase or loan under the plan; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">A minimum charge for each scheduled billing period under the plan during any portion of which there is an outstanding unpaid indebtedness under the plan.</section></section><section prefix="(3)">Notwithstanding the provisions of paragraph (2) of this subsection, if the credit agreement provides, a credit union may make loans or extend credit to its members incorporating the same terms and conditions as a federal credit union is permitted under federal law and regulations relating to:<section prefix="(i)">An over the limit fee assessed on a credit card account; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Fees for ancillary and administrative services requested by the member, including:<section prefix="1.">Researching account records;</section><section prefix="2.">Providing duplicate statements and other documents; and</section><section prefix="3.">Expedited issuance of a duplicate or original credit card or device.</section></section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in subsection (f) of this section, with respect to a secured open end credit plan, fees or charges may not be imposed on a consumer borrower in addition to interest or finance charges except for actual and verifiable fees incurred by the credit grantor and not retained by the credit grantor for the following:<section prefix="(i)">Attorney's fees for services rendered in connection with the preparation, closing, or disbursement of the loan;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Any expense, tax, or charge paid to a governmental agency;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Examination of title, appraisal, or other costs necessary or appropriate to the security of the loan; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">Premiums for any insurance coverage permitted under this subtitle.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The additional fees or charges permitted under this subsection may be imposed, charged, and collected at any time.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">If a plan is established for a consumer borrower, a fee or charge may not be charged or collected unless the agreement concerning the plan permits the fee to be charged.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">If a plan is established for a nonconsumer borrower, the nonconsumer borrower and credit grantor may agree upon any terms concerning charges and fees.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">For purposes of this section, the additional charges listed in subsections (a), (b), and (f) of this section are not interest or finance charges with respect to a plan.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Subject to the provisions of paragraphs (2) through (8) of this subsection, a credit grantor of an open end credit plan that is secured by a deposit, savings, passbook, or other similar account or certificate of deposit may impose:<section prefix="(i)">An application fee not to exceed $35; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">An annual charge not to exceed $35 for the privileges made available to the consumer borrower under the plan.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If an application to the plan is approved, the credit grantor shall credit the application fee:<section prefix="(i)">To the initial annual charge; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">If there is no annual charge, to the interest or finance charges under the plan.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">If an application to the plan is rejected, the credit grantor shall return the application fee to the applicant.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">Within 45 days after the receipt of the application, the credit grantor shall:<section prefix="(i)">Accept the application; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">Reject the application and return the application fee to the applicant.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(5)">Any such plan shall have a credit limit of no less than the amount of the deposit, savings, passbook, or other similar account or certificate of deposit required as security.</section>
      <section prefix="(6)">The application shall state the amount of:<section prefix="(i)">The minimum required security; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">The application fee.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(7)">The agreement shall state the amount of the annual charge.</section>
      <section prefix="(8)">If an annual charge is imposed, the credit grantor shall pay interest on the deposit, savings, passbook, or other similar account or certificate of deposit required as security in the greater of:<section prefix="(i)">A rate of 4 percent per annum simple interest; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">The rate of interest regularly paid on regular passbook savings accounts by the lending institution that issued the deposit, savings, passbook, or other similar account or certificate of deposit required as security.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
