<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcl" order_by="" level="1">Commercial Law</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcl-19-103</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>103</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">A supplier may not directly or through an officer, agent, or employee terminate, cancel, fail to renew, or substantially change the competitive circumstances of a contract without good cause.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, a supplier who terminates, cancels, fails to renew, or substantially changes the competitive circumstances of a contract with good cause is not required to provide any notice or the right to cure a deficiency to a dealer.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If a supplier terminates, cancels, fails to renew, or substantially changes the competitive circumstances of a contract based upon the dealer's failure to capture the share of the market required in the contract and the supplier has worked with the dealer for a minimum of 12 months to gain the desired market share, the supplier shall provide a dealer with at least 90 days' written notice of the termination of the agreement and a 60 day right to cure.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Notwithstanding any agreement to the contrary, a dealer who terminates a contract with a supplier shall notify the supplier of the termination within 90 days prior to the effective date of the termination.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Each notification required under this section shall:<section prefix="(1)">Be in writing;</section><section prefix="(2)">Contain:<section prefix="(i)">A statement of intention to terminate the contract;</section><section prefix="(ii)">A statement of the reasons for the termination; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">The date on which the termination takes effect; and</section></section><section prefix="(3)">Be delivered to the supplier or dealer by:<section prefix="(i)">Certified mail; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">Personal delivery.</section></section></section>
  </text>
</law>
