<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gcl" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="13-101" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcl-13-101</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this title the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Advertisement" means the publication, dissemination, or circulation of any oral or written matter, including labeling, which directly or indirectly tends to induce a person to enter into an obligation, sign a contract, or acquire title or interest in any merchandise, real property, intangibles, or service.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Advertisement" includes every device to disguise any form of business solicitation by using:<section prefix="(i)">A word such as "renewal", "invoice", "bill", "statement", or "reminder" to create an impression of an existing obligation if there is none; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">Other language to mislead a person in relation to a proposed commercial transaction.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Consumer" means an actual or prospective purchaser, lessee, or recipient of consumer goods, consumer services, consumer realty, or consumer credit.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Consumer" includes:<section prefix="(i)">A co-obligor or surety for a consumer;</section><section prefix="(ii)">A licensee or recipient of computer information or computer programs under a consumer contract as defined in &#xA7; 22-102 of this article; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">An individual who sells or offers for sale to a merchant consumer goods or consumer realty that the individual acquired primarily for personal, household, family, or agricultural purposes.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">"Consumer credit", "consumer debts", "consumer goods", "consumer realty", and "consumer services" mean, respectively, credit, debts or obligations, goods, real property, and services which are primarily for personal, household, family, or agricultural purposes.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"Division" means the Division of Consumer Protection of the Office of the Attorney General.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">"Merchandise" means any commodity, object, wares, or goods.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Merchant" means a person who directly or indirectly either offers or makes available to consumers any consumer goods, consumer services, consumer realty, or consumer credit.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Merchant" includes a person:<section prefix="(i)">Who directly or indirectly purchases or offers to purchase any consumer goods or consumer realty from a consumer; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Whose business includes paying off consumer debt in connection with the purchase of any consumer goods or consumer realty from a consumer.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(h)">"Person" includes an individual, corporation, business trust, statutory trust, estate, trust, partnership, association, two or more persons having a joint or common interest, or any other legal or commercial entity.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">"Sale" includes any:<section prefix="(1)">Sale of or offer or attempt to sell merchandise, real property, or intangibles for cash or credit; or</section><section prefix="(2)">Service or offer for service which relates to any person, building, or equipment.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(j)">"Service" means any:<section prefix="(1)">Building repair or improvement service;</section><section prefix="(2)">Subprofessional service;</section><section prefix="(3)">Repair of a motor vehicle, home appliance, or other similar commodity; or</section><section prefix="(4)">Repair, installation, or other servicing of any plumbing, heating, electrical, or mechanical device.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(k)">"Unfair or deceptive trade practice" has the meaning stated in Subtitle 3 of this title.</section>
  </text>
</law>
