<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcl" order_by="gcl" level="1">Commercial Law</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcl-12-624</section_number>
  <catch_line>The holder may repossess goods sold under an agreement if:...</catch_line>
  <order_by>624</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The holder may repossess goods sold under an agreement if:<section prefix="(1)">The buyer is in default in:<section prefix="(i)">The payment of any sum due under the agreement;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The performance of any other condition which the agreement lawfully requires him to perform in order to obtain unencumbered title to the goods; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">The performance of any promise the breach of which is expressly made a ground for repossessing the goods; or</section></section><section prefix="(2)">The goods were seized by a police department, bureau, or force.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The holder may repossess goods only by:<section prefix="(i)">Legal process; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">Self-help, without use of force.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Nothing in this section authorizes a violation of criminal law.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">At least 10 days before he repossesses any goods, the holder may serve a written notice on the buyer of his intention to repossess the goods.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The notice shall:<section prefix="(i)">State the default and any period at the end of which the goods will be repossessed; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Briefly state the rights of the buyer in case the goods are repossessed.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The notice may be delivered to the buyer personally or sent to him at his last known address by registered or certified mail.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Within five days after he repossesses the goods, the holder shall deliver to the buyer personally or send to him at his last known address by registered or certified mail, a written notice which briefly states:<section prefix="(1)">The right of the buyer to redeem the goods, and the amount payable for them;</section><section prefix="(2)">The rights of the buyer as to a resale, and his liability for a deficiency; and</section><section prefix="(3)">The exact location where the goods are stored and the address where any payment is to be made or notice delivered.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
