<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcl" order_by="" level="1">Commercial Law</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcl-14-2806</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>2806</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Each person that is engaged in the State in the business of telephone solicitation or door-to-door sales of products made by the blind shall:<section prefix="(1)">Register with Blind Industries and Services of Maryland; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Obtain a permit for each person selling or soliciting the sale of products made by the blind.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A product made by the blind may not be sold in the State unless the seller holds a valid permit issued under this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Unless earlier revoked for good cause shown, a permit issued under this section is valid for 1 year.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The fee for each permit and each renewal of a permit shall be:<section prefix="(1)">50 cents for a person that resides or has its main office in the State; and</section><section prefix="(2)">$5.00 for a person that does not reside or have its main office in the State.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Blind Industries and Services of Maryland shall investigate, under rules and regulations that it adopts for the administration of this subtitle, each application filed under this section to ensure that the applicant actually is engaged in the manufacture or distribution of products made by the blind.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Blind Industries and Services of Maryland may register, without investigation, nonresident persons and out-of-state associations and corporations on proof that the persons, associations, or corporations are recognized and approved by the state of their residence or organization under a law of that state that imposes requirements substantially similar to those prescribed under this subtitle.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">A person that violates this section is guilty of a misdemeanor and on conviction is subject to a fine not exceeding $100 or imprisonment not exceeding 30 days or both.</section>
  </text>
</law>
