<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcl" order_by="gcl" level="1">Commercial Law</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcl-9-707</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this section, "pre-effective-date financing statement" means a financing statement filed before t...</catch_line>
  <order_by>707</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, "pre-effective-date financing statement" means a financing statement filed before this title takes effect.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">After this title takes effect, a person may add or delete collateral covered by, continue or terminate the effectiveness of, or otherwise amend the information provided in, a pre-effective-date financing statement only in accordance with the law of the jurisdiction governing perfection as provided in Subtitle 3 of this title. However, the effectiveness of a pre-effective-date financing statement also may be terminated in accordance with the law of the jurisdiction in which the financing statement is filed.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Except as otherwise provided in subsection (d), if the law of this State governs perfection of a security interest, the information in a pre-effective-date financing statement may be amended after this title takes effect only if:<section prefix="(1)">The pre-effective-date financing statement and an amendment are filed in the office specified in &#xA7; 9-501;</section><section prefix="(2)">An amendment is filed in the office specified in &#xA7; 9-501 concurrently with, or after the filing in that office of, an initial financing statement that satisfies &#xA7; 9-706(c); or</section><section prefix="(3)">An initial financing statement that provides the information as amended and satisfies &#xA7; 9-706(c) is filed in the office specified in &#xA7; 9-501.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">If the law of this State governs perfection of a security interest, the effectiveness of a pre-effective-date financing statement may be continued only under &#xA7; 9-705(e) and (g) or &#xA7; 9-706.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">Whether or not the law of this State governs the perfection of a security interest, the effectiveness of a pre-effective-date financing statement filed in this State may be terminated after this title takes effect by filing a termination statement in the office in which the pre-effective-date financing statement is filed, unless an initial financing statement that satisfies &#xA7; 9-706(c) has been filed in the office specified by the law of the jurisdiction governing perfection as provided in Subtitle 3 of this title as the office in which to file a financing statement.</section>
  </text>
</law>
