<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcl" order_by="" level="1">Commercial Law</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcl-14-1218</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>1218</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Commissioner may:<section prefix="(1)">Hold a hearing on the complaint at a time and place in this State reasonably convenient to the parties involved;</section><section prefix="(2)">Subpoena witnesses;</section><section prefix="(3)">Take depositions of witnesses residing without the State, in the manner provided for witnesses in civil actions in courts of record;</section><section prefix="(4)">Administer oaths;</section><section prefix="(5)">Issue orders for compliance with this subtitle;</section><section prefix="(6)">Issue cease and desist orders, if after a hearing the Commissioner finds a pattern and practice of violation of this subtitle; and</section><section prefix="(7)">If a consumer reporting agency that has violated any law regulating consumer credit reporting fails to comply with a lawful order of the Commissioner, impose a civil penalty of up to $100 for each violation from which the violator failed to cease and desist or for which the violator failed to take action ordered by the Commissioner for compliance with the law. In determining the amount of civil penalty to be imposed under this paragraph, the Commissioner shall consider:<section prefix="(i)">The seriousness of the violation;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The good faith of the violator;</section><section prefix="(iii)">The violator's history of previous violations;</section><section prefix="(iv)">The deleterious effect of the violation upon the public and the credit granting industry;</section><section prefix="(v)">The assets and financial status of the violator; and</section><section prefix="(vi)">Any other factors relevant to the determination of the financial penalty.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">If a person fails to comply with any lawful order of the Commissioner pursuant to this subtitle or if any witness fails to appear and testify to any matter regarding which the witness may be lawfully interrogated, on petition of the Commissioner setting forth the facts, the circuit court of any county shall:<section prefix="(1)">Compel obedience to the requirements of the subpoena or order;</section><section prefix="(2)">Compel the production of contracts, forms, files, and other evidence; and</section><section prefix="(3)">Order compliance with any lawful order issued by the Commissioner under the provisions of subsection (a)(5) or subsection (a)(6) of this section.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">If a person fails, refuses, or neglects to comply with the order of the court, the court may punish that person for contempt of court.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Administrative Procedure Act, including its provisions for judicial review of a final decision in a contested case, applies to proceedings before the Commissioner pursuant to this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Commissioner shall adopt regulations necessary to administer the provisions of this subtitle.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The regulations shall include procedures for:<section prefix="(i)">Achieving accuracy in information collected and maintained in consumer files;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Developing a system to facilitate correction of information in a consumer file at each credit reporting agency on correction at one consumer reporting agency; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Periodically distributing to the public a current listing of the names, addresses, and telephone numbers of consumer reporting agencies that maintain information or provide consumer reports on residents of the State.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
