<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcl" order_by="gcl" level="1">Commercial Law</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcl-2-314</section_number>
  <catch_line>Unless excluded or modified (&#xA7; 2-316), a warranty that the goods shall be merchantable is implied i...</catch_line>
  <order_by>314</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(1)">Unless excluded or modified (&#xA7; 2-316), a warranty that the goods shall be merchantable is implied in a contract for their sale if the seller is a merchant with respect to goods of that kind. Under this section the serving for value of food or drink to be consumed either on the premises or elsewhere is a sale. Notwithstanding any other provisions of this title<section prefix="(a)">In &#xA7;&#xA7; 2-314 through 2-318 of this title, "seller" includes the manufacturer, distributor, dealer, wholesaler or other middleman or the retailer; and</section><section prefix="(b)">Any previous requirement of privity is abolished as between the buyer and the seller in any action brought by the buyer.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(2)">Goods to be merchantable must be at least such as<section prefix="(a)">Pass without objection in the trade under the contract description; and</section><section prefix="(b)">In the case of fungible goods, are of fair average quality within the description; and</section><section prefix="(c)">Are fit for the ordinary purposes for which such goods are used; and</section><section prefix="(d)">Run, within the variations permitted by the agreement, of even kind, quality and quantity within each unit and among all units involved; and</section><section prefix="(e)">Are adequately contained, packaged, and labeled as the agreement may require; and</section><section prefix="(f)">Conform to the promises or affirmations of fact made on the container or label if any.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(3)">Unless excluded or modified (&#xA7; 2-316) other implied warranties may arise from course of dealing or usage of trade.</section>
    <section prefix="(4)">Subsections (1) and (2) of this section apply to a lease of goods and a bailment for hire of goods that pass through the physical possession of and are maintained by the lessor, sublessor, or bailor.</section>
  </text>
</law>
