<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcl" order_by="" level="1">Commercial Law</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcl-14-101</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>101</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Consumer commodity" means any food, drug, cosmetic, or other article, product, or commodity of any kind or class which is:<section prefix="(1)">Customarily produced for sale at retail for consumption by individuals for purposes of personal care or in the performance of services ordinarily performed in or around the household; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Usually consumed or expended in the course of that use or performance other than by wear or deterioration from use.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Division" means the Division of Consumer Protection of the Office of the Attorney General.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">"Person" includes an individual, corporation, business trust, statutory trust, estate, trust, partnership, association, two or more persons having a joint or common interest, or any other legal or commercial entity.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"Unit price" means the retail price of an item expressed in dollars and cents per unit. In addition to any units commonly in use in the United States, the following units may be used if appropriate:<section prefix="(1)">Per pound for an item the net quantity of which is expressed in pounds, ounces, or both;</section><section prefix="(2)">Per kilogram (1000 grams) for an item the net quantity of which is expressed in kilograms, grams, or both;</section><section prefix="(3)">Per meter (100 centimeters) for an item the net quantity of which is expressed in meters, centimeters, millimeters, or a combination of them;</section><section prefix="(4)">Per quart for an item the net quantity of which is expressed in quarts, pints, fluid ounces, or a combination of them;</section><section prefix="(5)">Per liter for an item the net quantity of which is expressed in liters and milliliters, or a combination of them;</section><section prefix="(6)">Per 100 feet for an item the net quantity of which is expressed in yards, feet, inches, or a combination of them;</section><section prefix="(7)">Per 100 square feet for an item the net quantity of which is expressed in square yards, square feet, square inches, or a combination of them; or</section><section prefix="(8)">Per 100 units for an item the net quantity of which is expressed in terms of a numerical count.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
