<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcl" order_by="" level="1">Commercial Law</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcl-12-1005</section_number>
  <catch_line>In addition to interest at a periodic percentage rate or rates permitted by &#xA7;&#xA7; 12-1003 and 12-1004...</catch_line>
  <order_by>1005</order_by>
  <text>In addition to interest at a periodic percentage rate or rates permitted by &#xA7;&#xA7; 12-1003 and 12-1004 of this subtitle, a credit grantor may charge and collect:<section prefix="(a)"><section prefix="(1)">Subject to the limitations in this section, loan fees, points, finder's fees, and other charges; however, all such charges, when combined with any finder's fee imposed by a mortgage broker under &#xA7; 12-804 of this title, may not exceed 10 percent of the original extension of credit;</section><section prefix="(2)">In the case of a loan to a consumer borrower, no loan fees, points, finder's fees, or other charges may be charged and collected unless:<section prefix="(i)">The agreement, note, or other evidence of the loan so provides and the borrower agrees in writing to pay those charges;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The loan is secured by a lien on residential real property; however, all such charges, when combined with any finder's fee imposed by a mortgage broker under &#xA7; 12-804 of this title, may not exceed 10 percent of the original extension of credit; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">The charges are disclosed to the borrower in accordance with the federal Truth in Lending Act; and</section></section><section prefix="(3)">The limitations imposed by paragraphs (1) and (2) of this subsection do not apply to a credit extension:<section prefix="(i)">Secured by a first lien on residential real property; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">Made for a bona fide commercial purpose in excess of $75,000.</section></section></section><section prefix="(b)">Reasonable fees for services rendered or for reimbursement of expenses incurred in good faith by the credit grantor or its agents in connection with the loan, including:<section prefix="(1)">Commitment fees;</section><section prefix="(2)">Official fees and taxes;</section><section prefix="(3)">Premiums or other charges for any guarantee or insurance protecting the credit grantor against the borrower's default or other credit loss;</section><section prefix="(4)">Costs incurred by reason of examination of title, inspection, recording, and other formal acts necessary or appropriate to the security of the loan;</section><section prefix="(5)">Filing fees;</section><section prefix="(6)">Attorney's fees; and</section><section prefix="(7)">Travel expenses.</section></section><section prefix="(c)"><section prefix="(1)">The cost to the borrower of an optional debt cancellation agreement, provided that the cost of the debt cancellation agreement is separately itemized in the financing agreement.</section><section prefix="(2)">This cost is in addition to the charges permitted under subsections (a), (b), and (d) of this section.</section></section><section prefix="(d)"><section prefix="(1)">In the case of a loan to a consumer borrower, a fee permitted under subsection (b) of this section may not be charged and collected unless:<section prefix="(i)">The agreement, note, or other evidence of the loan permits;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The fee is an actual and verifiable expense of the credit grantor not retained by him; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Limited to charges for:<section prefix="1.">Attorney's fees for services rendered in connection with the preparation, closing, or disbursement of the loan;</section><section prefix="2.">Any expense, tax, or charge paid to a governmental agency;</section><section prefix="3.">Examination of title, appraisal, or other costs necessary or appropriate to the security of the loan; and</section><section prefix="4.">Premiums for any insurance coverage permitted under this subtitle.</section></section></section><section prefix="(2)">Notwithstanding &#xA7; 12-1009(e) of this subtitle, fees and charges permitted under this subsection may be imposed, charged, and collected at any time.</section></section><section prefix="(e)">For purposes of this subtitle, fees and charges permitted under this section are not interest with respect to a loan.</section></text>
</law>
