<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gcl" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="14-409" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcl-14-409</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Except for Title 13 of this article, this subtitle provides the exclusive remedy by which a person guaranteed may recover damages for a breach of a service contract or may enforce a service contract.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Providers, administrators, and other persons marketing, selling, or offering to enter into service contracts that comply with the terms of this subtitle need not comply with any provision of the Insurance Article.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Guarantors, administrators, and other persons marketing, selling, or offering to issue guarantees that comply with the terms of this subtitle need not comply with any provision of the Insurance Article.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this subsection, "licensee" means a person who:<section prefix="(i)">Is licensed as a master plumber and meets the qualifications to engage in the business of providing plumbing services under Title 12 of the Business Occupations and Professions Article;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Provides heating, ventilation, air-conditioning, or refrigeration services in accordance with a master license or a master restricted license issued under Title 9A of the Business Regulation Article; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">Is a licensed contractor under Title 8 of the Business Regulation Article.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A licensee is not subject to:<section prefix="(i)">This subtitle if the services provided or to be provided under the service contract are within the scope of the licensee's license; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">Any provision of the Insurance Article applicable to service contracts.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
