<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gcl" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="6-104" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcl-6-104</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided with respect to auction sales (&#xA7; 6-108), a bulk transfer subject to this title is ineffective against any creditor of the transferor unless:<section prefix="(a)">The transferee requires the transferor to furnish a list of his existing creditors prepared as stated in this section; and</section><section prefix="(b)">The parties prepare a schedule of the property transferred sufficient to identify it; and</section><section prefix="(c)">The transferee preserves the list and schedule for six months next following the transfer and permits inspection of either or both and copying therefrom at all reasonable hours by any creditor of the transferor, or files the list and schedule in the office of the clerk of the circuit court in the county in which the property was located at the time of transfer.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(2)">The list of creditors must be signed and sworn to or affirmed by the transferor or his agent. It must contain the names and business addresses of all creditors of the transferor, with the amounts when known, and also the names of all persons who are known to the transferor to assert claims against him even though such claims are disputed. If the transferor is the obligor of an outstanding issue of bonds, debentures or the like as to which there is an indenture trustee, the list of creditors need include only the name and address of the indenture trustee and the aggregate outstanding principal amount of the issue.</section>
    <section prefix="(3)">Responsibility for the completeness and accuracy of the list of creditors rests on the transferor, and the transfer is not rendered ineffective by errors or omissions therein unless the transferee is shown to have had knowledge.</section>
  </text>
</law>
