<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcl" order_by="gcl" level="1">Commercial Law</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcl-9-311</section_number>
  <catch_line>Except as otherwise provided in subsection (d), the filing of a financing statement is not necessary...</catch_line>
  <order_by>311</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Except as otherwise provided in subsection (d), the filing of a financing statement is not necessary or effective to perfect a security interest in property subject to:<section prefix="(1)">A statute, regulation, or treaty of the United States whose requirements for a security interest's obtaining priority over the rights of a lien creditor with respect to the property preempt &#xA7; 9-310(a);</section><section prefix="(2)">Any statute of this State which provides for a security interest to be indicated on a certificate of title as a condition or result of perfection; or</section><section prefix="(3)">A statute of another jurisdiction which provides for a security interest to be indicated on a certificate of title as a condition or result of the security interest's obtaining priority over the rights of a lien creditor with respect to the property.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Compliance with the requirements of a statute, regulation, or treaty described in subsection (a) for obtaining priority over the rights of a lien creditor is equivalent to the filing of a financing statement under this title, provided that the time for perfection will be governed by that statute, regulation, or treaty. Except as otherwise provided in subsection (d) and &#xA7;&#xA7; 9-313 and 9-316(d) and (e) for goods covered by a certificate of title, a security interest in property subject to a statute, regulation, or treaty described in subsection (a) may be perfected only by compliance with those requirements, and a security interest so perfected remains perfected notwithstanding a change in the use or transfer of possession of the collateral.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Except as otherwise provided in subsection (d) and &#xA7; 9-316(d) and (e), duration and renewal of perfection of a security interest perfected by compliance with the requirements prescribed by a statute, regulation, or treaty described in subsection (a) are governed by the statute, regulation, or treaty. In other respects, the security interest is subject to this article.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">During any period in which collateral subject to a statute specified in subsection (a)(2) is inventory held for sale or lease by a person or leased by that person as lessor and that person is in the business of selling goods of that kind, this section does not apply to a security interest in that collateral created by that person.</section>
  </text>
</law>
