<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcl" order_by="gcl" level="1">Commercial Law</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcl-13-316</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this section the following terms have the meanings indicated....</catch_line>
  <order_by>316</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following terms have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Mortgage" includes a mortgage, deed of trust, security agreement, or other lien on 1 to 4 family residential real estate located in this State.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Servicer" means a person responsible for collection and payment of principal, interest, escrow, and other moneys under an original mortgage.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Within 7 days of acquiring mortgage servicing, a servicer shall send to the mortgagor a written notice containing the following information regarding the mortgage on the date of transfer:<section prefix="(1)">The name, address, and telephone number of the new servicer and the address where mortgage payments are to be forwarded;</section><section prefix="(2)">The principal balance and escrow balance;</section><section prefix="(3)">The telephone number of the contact designated under subsection (c) of this section;</section><section prefix="(4)">The responsibilities of the contact under subsection (c) of this section; and</section><section prefix="(5)">A statement that the servicer's violation of this section will result in the servicer being held liable under subsection (e) of this section.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A servicer shall designate a contact to whom mortgagors may direct complaints and inquiries.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The contact shall respond in writing to each written complaint or inquiry within 15 days if requested.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A servicer shall make timely payments of the taxes or insurance premiums due under the mortgage so long as the mortgagor has paid an amount sufficient to pay the tax or insurance premium due and, with regard to the taxes, so long as the servicer is in possession of either the tax bill or notice from the taxing authority.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If a servicer fails to comply with any provision of this section, the servicer is liable for any economic damages caused by the violation.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The penalties provided in this section are in addition to any other applicable remedies.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">A servicer shall provide a toll-free telephone number through which any borrower residing in this State may direct telephone inquiries on outstanding loans during regular business hours.</section>
  </text>
</law>
