<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcl" order_by="" level="1">Commercial Law</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcl-23-101</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>101</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Hotel" means a hotel or motel with more than 30 rooms for rent that is primarily used by transients who are lodged with or without meals.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Operating agreement" means a written contract, agreement, instrument, or other document between at least two persons that relates to the management, operation, or franchise of a hotel or a retirement community.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">"Person" does not include an individual, a not for profit entity, or a public instrumentality.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Retirement community" means a senior living community, retirement community, assisted living community, continuing care retirement community, independent living community, or similar community that offers a combination of independent living, assisted living, or nursing.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Retirement community" does not include:<section prefix="(i)">A freestanding nursing home, as defined in &#xA7; 19-1401 of the Health - General Article, that is licensed by the Department of Health and Mental Hygiene;</section><section prefix="(ii)">A State facility, as defined in &#xA7; 10-101 of the Health - General Article;</section><section prefix="(iii)">A program licensed by the Department of Health and Mental Hygiene under Title 7 or Title 10 of the Health - General Article;</section><section prefix="(iv)">A freestanding hospice care program regulated by the Department of Health and Mental Hygiene under Title 19, Subtitle 9 of the Health - General Article;</section><section prefix="(v)">A freestanding day care center for the elderly regulated by the Department of Health and Mental Hygiene under Title 14, Subtitle 2 of the Health - General Article;</section><section prefix="(vi)">A retirement community that is owned by or affiliated with a church or religious organization;</section><section prefix="(vii)">A cooperative housing corporation organized under Title 5, Subtitle 6B of the Corporations and Associations Article and certified as a continuing care provider under Title 10, Subtitle 4 of the Human Services Article and separate entities certified as continuing care providers under Title 10, Subtitle 4 of the Human Services Article that provide services to residents of a cooperative housing corporation; or</section><section prefix="(viii)">A condominium organized under Title 11 of the Real Property Article and certified as a continuing care provider under Title 10, Subtitle 4 of the Human Services Article and separate entities certified as continuing care providers under Title 10, Subtitle 4 of the Human Services Article that provide services to residents of a condominium.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
