<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcl" order_by="gcl" level="1">Commercial Law</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcl-14-1402</section_number>
  <catch_line>A manufacturer of motor vehicles sold in the State shall establish procedures under which each consu...</catch_line>
  <order_by>1402</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">A manufacturer of motor vehicles sold in the State shall establish procedures under which each consumer in the State who owns or leases a motor vehicle to which an adjustment program of the manufacturer applies:<section prefix="(1)">Is notified of the adjustment program;</section><section prefix="(2)">On request, is provided with a copy of any service bulletin or any other document issued by the manufacturer pertaining to an adjustment program or to a condition that may substantially affect motor vehicle durability, reliability, or performance; and</section><section prefix="(3)">Within 90 days after the establishment of a new adjustment program, is sent written notice by first-class mail of the terms and conditions of the adjustment program.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A manufacturer of motor vehicles sold in the State shall ensure that the purchaser of a new motor vehicle receives, at the time of purchase, a written notice describing the rights and remedies provided under this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The written notice shall be considered sufficient if stated in substantially the following form:</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A manufacturer shall provide to its dealers information about each adjustment program of the manufacturer in a format that facilitates the disclosure of the terms and conditions of the adjustment program to a consumer seeking repairs at the dealer's repair facility.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A manufacturer that establishes an adjustment program shall implement procedures to ensure reimbursement of each consumer who:<section prefix="(i)">Is eligible under the adjustment program; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Incurs expenses for the repair of a condition subject to the adjustment program before the consumer knows about the adjustment program.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Reimbursement under this subsection shall be consistent with the terms and conditions of the particular adjustment program.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">A consumer shall make a claim for reimbursement under this subsection in writing to the manufacturer within the later of:<section prefix="1.">2 years after the date of the consumer's payment for the repair of the condition; or</section><section prefix="2.">1 year after the date the manufacturer sends the notice required under subsection (a)(3) of this section.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The manufacturer shall notify the consumer within 21 business days after receiving a claim for reimbursement whether the claim will be approved or denied.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">If the claim is denied, the manufacturer shall state in writing the specific reasons for the denial.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
