<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gcl" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="11-202" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcl-11-202</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The General Assembly of Maryland declares that the purpose of this subtitle is to complement the body of federal law governing restraints of trade, unfair competition, and unfair, deceptive, and fraudulent acts or practices in order to protect the public and foster fair and honest intrastate competition.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">It is the intent of the General Assembly that, in construing this subtitle, the courts be guided by the interpretation given by the federal courts to the various federal statutes dealing with the same or similar matters, including:<section prefix="(i)">Act of July 2, 1890, ch. 647, 26 U.S. Stat. 209, 15 U.S.C. &#xA7;&#xA7; 1 through 7;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Act of Oct. 15, 1914, ch. 323, 38 U.S. Stat. 730, 15 U.S.C. &#xA7;&#xA7; 12 through 27, 44;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Act of August 17, 1937, ch. 690, Title VIII, 50 U.S. Stat. 693, 15 U.S.C. &#xA7; 1;</section><section prefix="(iv)">Act of July 7, 1955, ch. 281, 69 U.S. Stat. 282, 15 U.S.C. &#xA7;&#xA7; 1 through 3;</section><section prefix="(v)">Act of May 26, 1938, ch. 283, 52 U.S. Stat. 446, 15 U.S.C. &#xA7; 13c; and</section><section prefix="(vi)">Any similar act passed in the future.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">It is also the intent of the General Assembly that, in deciding whether conduct restrains or monopolizes trade or commerce or may substantially lessen competition within the State, determination of the relevant market or effective area of competition may not be limited by the boundaries of the State.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">For the purpose and intent stated in subsection (a) of this section, this subtitle shall be liberally construed to serve its beneficial purposes.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">It is also the intent of the General Assembly that this subtitle may not be construed to prohibit acts or practices which are reasonable in relation to the development and preservation of business or which are not injurious to the public interest.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
