<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcl" order_by="" level="1">Commercial Law</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcl-14-401</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>401</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Consumer product" means goods or services used for personal, family, or household purposes, the actual cash sales price of which to the person guaranteed was in excess of $10.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Guarantor" means a person who is engaged in the business of making consumer products available to consumers and who makes a guaranty.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Guaranty" means any of the following which is made at the time of the sale of a consumer product by a guarantor to a person guaranteed and which is part of the basis of the bargain between them:<section prefix="(i)">A written affirmation of fact or written promise which relates to the nature of the material or workmanship and affirms or promises that the material or workmanship is defect-free or meets a specified level of performance; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">A written undertaking to refund, repair, replace, or take other remedial action with respect to the consumer product if it proves defective in material or workmanship or fails to meet a specified level of performance.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Guaranty" includes warranty.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Guaranty" does not include:<section prefix="(i)">A written statement or expression of general policy concerning customer satisfaction which is not subject to specified limitations; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">A service contract.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"Mechanical breakdown insurance" means a policy, contract, or agreement issued by an authorized insurer that provides for the repair, replacement, or maintenance of property or indemnification for repair, replacement, or services, for the operational or structural failure of a product due to a defect in the materials or workmanship or due to normal wear and tear.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">"Person" includes an individual, corporation, business trust, statutory trust, estate, trust, partnership, association, two or more persons having a joint or common interest, or any other legal or commercial entity.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">"Person guaranteed" means:<section prefix="(1)">The person who is the first buyer at retail of a consumer product which is the subject of a guaranty;</section><section prefix="(2)">A person who is entitled to enforce the obligations of a guaranty against the guarantor; or</section><section prefix="(3)">The person who is entitled to enforce the obligations of the provider under a service contract.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(h)">"Provider" means a person or persons acting in concert who are contractually obligated under the terms of a service contract to provide services to the owner of a product covered by the service contract.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">"Reasonable and necessary maintenance" means those operations which the person guaranteed reasonably can be expected to perform or have performed and which are necessary to keep the product performing its intended function.</section>
    <section prefix="(j)">"Replace" means:<section prefix="(1)">To replace a product or its component with a new and identical or equivalent product or component; or</section><section prefix="(2)">To refund the price of the product or its component less reasonable depreciation if:<section prefix="(i)">Neither replacement nor repair is commercially practicable; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">The person guaranteed is willing to accept the refund in place of the replacement or repair.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(k)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Service contract" means a contract or agreement for a separately stated consideration for a specific duration to perform the repair, replacement, or maintenance of a product, or to indemnify for the repair, replacement, or maintenance, because of an operational or structural failure due to a defect in materials, workmanship, or normal wear and tear, with or without additional provisions for incidental payment of indemnity under limited circumstances.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Service contract" includes a contract or agreement for repair, replacement, or maintenance of a product for damage resulting from power surges and accidental damage from handling.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Service contract" does not include:<section prefix="(i)">A guaranty;</section><section prefix="(ii)">A maintenance agreement that does not include a provision for the repair, replacement, or maintenance of a product because of an operational or structural failure due to a defect in materials, workmanship, or normal wear and tear;</section><section prefix="(iii)">A warranty, service contract, or maintenance agreement offered by a public utility on its transmission devices to the extent it is regulated by the Public Service Commission;</section><section prefix="(iv)">A mechanical repair contract under &#xA7; 15-311.2 of the Transportation Article; or</section><section prefix="(v)">Mechanical breakdown insurance.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(l)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Services" means work, labor, or any other kind of activity furnished or agreed to be furnished to a person guaranteed.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Services" includes services for home improvement, repair of a motor vehicle and other products, and the repair or installation of plumbing, heating, electrical, or mechanical devices.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Services" does not include the professional services of an accountant, architect, clergyman, engineer, lawyer, or medical or dental practitioner.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(m)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Without charge" means that the guarantor cannot charge the person guaranteed for any costs which the guarantor or the guarantor's representative incurs in connection with the required repair or replacement of a consumer product.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Without charge" does not mean that the guarantor must compensate the person guaranteed for incidental expenses unless the expenses were incurred because the repair or replacement was not made within a reasonable time.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(n)">"Wrongful breach of a guaranty" means the failure of a guarantor to perform the duties imposed by &#xA7; 14-404(a), (b), and (c) of this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(o)">"Wrongful breach of a service contract" means the failure of a provider to perform the duties imposed by &#xA7; 14-404(a), (b), and (c) of this subtitle.</section>
  </text>
</law>
