<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcl" order_by="gcl" level="1">Commercial Law</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcl-14-3901</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated....</catch_line>
  <order_by>3901</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Arbitration activity" means the initiation, conduct, sponsorship, or administration of, or the appointment of an arbitrator in, a consumer arbitration.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Arbitration organization" means a nongovernmental association, agency, board, commission, corporation, or other entity that performs arbitration activities.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">"Consumer" means an individual who is:<section prefix="(1)">A resident of the State; and</section><section prefix="(2)">An actual or prospective purchaser or lessee of any goods, services, real property, or credit primarily for personal, family, or household purposes.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Consumer arbitration" means a binding arbitration conducted in accordance with a consumer arbitration agreement.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Consumer arbitration" does not include:<section prefix="(i)">A binding arbitration conducted in accordance with the provisions of a policy of property insurance, casualty insurance, or surety insurance, as those terms are defined in &#xA7; 1-101 of the Insurance Article;</section><section prefix="(ii)">An arbitration governed by rules adopted by a securities self-regulatory organization and approved by the United States Securities and Exchange Commission under federal law; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">An arbitration between a consumer and a related institution that is licensed by the Department of Health and Mental Hygiene, if the consumer arbitration agreement between the consumer and the related institution is not mandated as a condition of admission of the consumer to the related institution.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Consumer arbitration agreement" means a standardized contract that:<section prefix="(i)">Is between a consumer and another person who is not a consumer;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Provides for the sale or lease of any goods, services, real property, or credit primarily for personal, family, or household purposes; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Requires that disputes arising under the contract be submitted to binding arbitration.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Consumer arbitration agreement" does not include a public or private sector collective bargaining agreement.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">"Related institution" has the meaning stated in &#xA7; 19-301 of the Health - General Article.</section>
  </text>
</law>
