<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcl" order_by="" level="1">Commercial Law</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcl-14-1002</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>1002</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Before beginning any repair work on a motor vehicle for which a customer is charged more than $50, an automotive repair facility shall give the customer on the customer's request a written statement which contains:<section prefix="(i)">The estimated completion date;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The estimated price for labor and parts necessary to complete the work;</section><section prefix="(iii)">A clear statement that while the customer's motor vehicle is on the premises of the automotive repair facility, the automotive repair facility may not be responsible for damage to the customer's motor vehicle under certain circumstances, and that the customer should ask a representative of the automotive repair facility about the extent of its responsibility, including the extent of the insurance coverage of the automotive repair facility; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">The estimated surcharge, if any.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If the fee is disclosed to the customer before the estimate is made, the automotive repair facility may charge a reasonable fee for making the estimate.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">An automotive repair facility may not charge a customer without his consent any amount which exceeds the written estimate by 10 percent.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">An automotive repair facility is not liable for breach of the written estimated completion date for a repair if the delay is caused by:<section prefix="(1)">An act of God;</section><section prefix="(2)">Strike;</section><section prefix="(3)">Unexpected illness; or</section><section prefix="(4)">Unexpected shortage of labor or parts.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">This section does not require an automotive repair facility to give a written estimate if the facility does not agree to perform the requested repair work.</section>
  </text>
</law>
