<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gcl" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="11-1301" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcl-11-1301</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Agreement" means a contract or other agreement between a grantor and a distributor.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Cancel" means to terminate an agreement prior to the natural expiration date of its term.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Cancel" includes a de facto cancellation.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">"Commercial goods" means, as those terms are defined in the wholesale trade section of the 1987 edition of the federal Office of Management and Budget's Standard Industrial Classification Manual, durable goods, except for:<section prefix="(1)">Motor vehicles and motor vehicle parts and supplies;</section><section prefix="(2)">Furniture;</section><section prefix="(3)">Office equipment, computers, computer peripheral equipment, and software; and</section><section prefix="(4)">Prerecorded tapes, cassettes, film, and videos and books or other similar items for which copyright protection might be available.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"De facto cancellation" means actions taken by the grantor that:<section prefix="(1)">Materially alter the competitive business and economic conditions of a distributor;</section><section prefix="(2)">Are not applicable to similarly situated distributors of that grantor's products; and</section><section prefix="(3)">Are intended to be discriminatory and detrimental to the distributor.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">"Deficiency" means the failure of a distributor to comply substantially with the fair, reasonable, and material requirements imposed or sought to be imposed on the distributor by the grantor.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Distributor" means a person:<section prefix="(i)">Whose primary business is the wholesale distribution of commercial goods for resale;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Who maintains an inventory of commercial goods for resale;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Who has been granted either expressly or implicitly the right to sell or distribute a grantor's commercial goods in Maryland for resale to retailers or other resellers or to an industrial or commercial manufacturer; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">Who conducts a substantial business in Maryland.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Distributor" does not include:<section prefix="(i)">A sales representative that does not maintain an inventory of commercial goods; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">A direct seller whose work is exempt from covered employment under &#xA7; 8-206(b) of the Labor and Employment Article.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(h)">"Grantor" means a person, including a manufacturer, that grants distribution and sales rights to a distributor.</section>
  </text>
</law>
