<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcl" order_by="" level="1">Commercial Law</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcl-14-1311</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>1311</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following terms have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Consumer goods" means any new goods used for personal, family, or household purposes where:<section prefix="(i)">The purchaser of the goods has entered into an agreement to purchase an extended warranty on the goods purchased; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">The actual cash sales price of the goods paid by the purchaser is in excess of $50.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Consumer goods" includes household appliances.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">"Extended warranty" means a written warranty that:<section prefix="(i)">Covers consumer goods offered for sale by a guarantor or manufacturer;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Includes terms or conditions beyond those offered in any express warranty originally included as part of the contract of sale for the consumer goods; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Is purchased at the time of the sale of the consumer goods.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(5)">"Guarantor" means a person who:<section prefix="(i)">Is engaged in the business of making consumer products available to consumers; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Makes a warranty.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(6)">"Manufacturer" includes a manufacturer, its agent, or its authorized dealer.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Any extended warranty sold by a guarantor or manufacturer to a purchaser of consumer goods may not supersede any original express warranty and shall be offered in addition to the original express warranty.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">This section applies only to an agreement to purchase an extended warranty which is executed on or after July 1, 1984.</section>
  </text>
</law>
