<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcl" order_by="" level="1">Commercial Law</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcl-14-2009</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>2009</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">This section applies if the lease provides that the motor vehicle is to be sold after repossession and the lessee is to be responsible for any deficiency arising from the sale of the motor vehicle.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The lessor shall sell the motor vehicle that was repossessed at:<section prefix="(i)">Subject to subsection (c) of this section, a private sale; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">A public auction.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">At least 10 days before the sale, the lessor shall notify the lessee in writing of the time and place of the sale, by certified mail, return receipt requested, sent to the lessee's last known address.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Any sale of a repossessed motor vehicle must be accomplished in a commercially reasonable manner.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">In all cases of a private sale of a repossessed motor vehicle under this section, a full accounting shall be made to the lessee in writing. This accounting shall contain the following information:<section prefix="(1)">The unpaid balance at the time the motor vehicle was repossessed;</section><section prefix="(2)">The refund credit of unearned insurance premiums, if any;</section><section prefix="(3)">The remaining net balance;</section><section prefix="(4)">The proceeds of the sale of the motor vehicle;</section><section prefix="(5)">The remaining deficiency balance, if any, or the amount due to the lessee; and</section><section prefix="(6)">All expenses incurred as a result of the sale.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Commissioner of Financial Regulation may make a determination concerning any private sale that the sale was not accomplished in a commercially reasonable manner. Upon that determination, the Commissioner may enter an order disallowing any claim for a deficiency balance.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The proceeds of a sale to which this section applies shall be applied, in the following order, to:<section prefix="(i)">The actual and reasonable costs of the sale;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The actual and reasonable costs of retaking and storing the property; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">The unpaid balance owing under the lease agreement at the time the property was repossessed.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The lessor shall furnish to the lessee a written statement which shows the distribution of the proceeds.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">If the provisions of this subtitle, including the requirement of furnishing a notice following repossession, are not followed, the lessor shall not be entitled to any deficiency judgment to which it would be entitled under the lease agreement.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
