<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gcl" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="12-921" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcl-12-921</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A credit grantor may repossess tangible personal property securing a plan under an agreement if the consumer borrower is in default.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The credit grantor may repossess tangible personal property from a consumer borrower only by:<section prefix="(i)">Legal process; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">Self-help, without use of force.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Nothing in this section authorizes a violation of criminal law.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">At least 10 days before a credit grantor repossesses any tangible personal property, the credit grantor may serve a written notice on the consumer borrower of the intention to repossess the tangible personal property.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The notice shall:<section prefix="(i)">State the default and any period at the end of which the tangible personal property will be repossessed; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Briefly state the rights of the consumer borrower in case the tangible personal property is repossessed.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The notice may be delivered to the consumer borrower personally or sent to him at his last known address by registered or certified mail.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">Within 5 days after the credit grantor repossesses the tangible personal property the credit grantor shall deliver to the consumer borrower personally or send to him at his last known address by registered or certified mail, a written notice which briefly states:<section prefix="(1)">The right of the consumer borrower to redeem the tangible personal property, and the amount payable for it;</section><section prefix="(2)">The rights of the consumer borrower as to a resale, and his liability for a deficiency; and</section><section prefix="(3)">The exact location where the tangible personal property is stored and the address where any payment is to be made.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">For 15 days after the credit grantor gives the notice required by subsection (e) of this section, the credit grantor shall retain any repossessed property.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">During the period provided for in subsection (f) of this section, the consumer borrower may:<section prefix="(1)">Redeem and take possession of the property; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Resume the performance of the agreement.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(h)">To redeem the property, the consumer borrower shall:<section prefix="(1)">Tender the amount due under the agreement at the time of redemption, without giving effect to any provision which allows acceleration of any installment otherwise payable after that time;</section><section prefix="(2)">Tender performance of any other promise for the breach of which the property was repossessed; and</section><section prefix="(3)">If the discretionary notice provided for in subsection (c) of this section was given, pay the actual and reasonable expenses of retaking and storing the property.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(i)">This section does not apply if the consumer borrower was guilty of fraudulent conduct, intentionally and wrongfully concealed, removed, damaged, or destroyed the property, or attempted to do so, and the property was repossessed because of that conduct, or if the property has been previously repossessed from the consumer borrower and redeemed by the consumer borrower.</section>
    <section prefix="(j)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Subject to subsection (l) of this section, the credit grantor shall sell the property that was repossessed at:</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">At least 10 days before the sale, the credit grantor shall notify the consumer borrower in writing of the time and place of the sale, by certified mail, return receipt requested, sent to the consumer borrower's last known address.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">Any sale of repossessed property must be accomplished in a commercially reasonable manner.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">In all cases of a private sale of repossessed goods under this section, a full accounting shall be made to the borrower in writing and the seller shall retain a copy of this accounting for at least 24 months. This accounting shall contain the following information:<section prefix="(i)">The unpaid balance at the time the goods were repossessed;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The refund credit of unearned finance charges and insurance premiums, if any;</section><section prefix="(iii)">The remaining net balance;</section><section prefix="(iv)">The proceeds of the sale of the goods;</section><section prefix="(v)">The remaining deficiency balance, if any, or the amount due the buyer;</section><section prefix="(vi)">All expenses incurred as a result of the sale;</section><section prefix="(vii)">The purchaser's name, address, and business;</section><section prefix="(viii)">The number of bids sought and received; and</section><section prefix="(ix)">Any statement as to the condition of the goods at the time of repossession which would cause their value to be increased or decreased above or below the market value for goods of like kind and quality.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Commissioner of Financial Regulation may make a determination concerning any private sale that the sale was not accomplished in a commercially reasonable manner. Upon that determination, the Commissioner may enter an order disallowing any claim for a deficiency balance.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(k)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The provisions of this subsection apply to a public sale of property which secured a plan in excess of $2,000 at the time the plan was made.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The proceeds of a sale to which this subsection applies shall be applied, in the following order, to:<section prefix="(i)">The actual and reasonable cost of the sale;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The actual and reasonable cost of retaking and storing the property; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">The unpaid balance owing under the agreement at the time the property was repossessed.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The credit grantor shall furnish to the consumer borrower a written statement which shows the distribution of the proceeds.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">If the provisions of this section, including the requirement of furnishing a notice following repossession, are not followed, the credit grantor shall not be entitled to any deficiency judgment to which he would be entitled under the plan.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(l)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">In this subsection, "consumer goods" means tangible personal property used or bought for use primarily for personal, family, or household purposes that is:</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">"Consumer goods" does not include money, documents, instruments, accounts, chattel paper, or general intangibles.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">This subsection applies to tangible personal property securing a plan that:<section prefix="(i)">Has been repossessed by the credit grantor; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">Is in actual or constructive possession of the credit grantor where the perfection of the security interest in the property depends on the possession of the property.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">In the case of a purchase money security interest in consumer goods, if a consumer borrower has paid 60 percent of the cash price and, after default, has not signed a statement renouncing or modifying the consumer borrower's rights under this subsection, a credit grantor who has repossessed the consumer goods must take reasonable action within 90 days after the repossession to commence disposal of them in the manner provided under subsection (j) of this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">
        <section prefix="(i)">In any other case involving tangible personal property securing a plan, a credit grantor may, after default, propose to retain the property in full satisfaction of the obligations of the borrower under the plan.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">If, as authorized by subparagraph (i) of this paragraph, a credit grantor proposes to retain property in full satisfaction of the obligations of the borrower under the plan, the credit grantor shall send written notice of the proposal to:</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)"/>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(5)">If despite complying with the requirements of this section there is no sale of tangible personal property securing a plan under subsection (j) of this section:<section prefix="(i)">The credit grantor may retain the property without obligation to account to the borrower; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">If the property is retained, all obligations of the borrower under the plan shall be discharged.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
