<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcl" order_by="gcl" level="1">Commercial Law</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcl-16-207</section_number>
  <catch_line>If the charges which give rise to a lien are due and unpaid for 30 days and the lienor is in possess...</catch_line>
  <order_by>207</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">If the charges which give rise to a lien are due and unpaid for 30 days and the lienor is in possession of the property subject to the lien, the lienor may sell the property to which the lien attaches at public sale. The sale shall be in a location convenient and accessible to the public and shall be held between the hours of 10 a.m. and 6 p.m.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The lienor shall publish notice of the time, place, and terms of the sale and a full description of the property to be sold once a week for the two weeks immediately preceding the sale in one or more newspapers of general circulation in the county where the sale is to be held.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">In addition, the lienor shall send the notice by registered or certified mail at least 10 days before the sale to:<section prefix="(i)">The owner of the property, all holders of perfected security interests in the property and, in the case of a sale of a motor vehicle or mobile home, the Motor Vehicle Administration;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The person who incurred the charges which give rise to the lien, if the address of the owner is unknown and cannot be ascertained by the exercise of reasonable diligence; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">"General delivery" at the post office of the city or county where the business of the lienor is located, if the address of both the owner and the person who incurred the charges is unknown and cannot be ascertained by the exercise of reasonable diligence.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">If a motor vehicle or mobile home which is subject to a lien is delivered by the lienor to the possession of a third party for storage, and the charges for storage are due and unpaid for 30 days or more, the third party holder is deemed to hold a perfected security interest in the motor vehicle or mobile home notwithstanding &#xA7; 13-202 of the Transportation Article and may sell the motor vehicle or mobile home in the same manner as the lienor under this section if he has first published and sent notice as required of the lienor under this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in &#xA7; 13-110 of the Transportation Article, the Motor Vehicle Administration shall issue a title, free and clear of any lien, to the purchaser of any motor vehicle or mobile home sold under this section, if the holder of the lien on the motor vehicle or mobile home submits to the Motor Vehicle Administration a completed application for a certificate of title with:<section prefix="(i)">A copy of the newspaper publication required by subsection (b) of this section;</section><section prefix="(ii)">A copy of the registered or certified letter required under subsection (b) of this section to be sent to holders of perfected security interests in the motor vehicle or mobile home and the Motor Vehicle Administration, and the return card;</section><section prefix="(iii)">A copy of the registered or certified letters required by subsection (b) of this section to be sent to the owner of the motor vehicle or mobile home, and the return card;</section><section prefix="(iv)">If applicable, a written statement from the lienor that the lienor stored the vehicle in accordance with an agreement with an insurer;</section><section prefix="(v)">An auctioneer's receipt;</section><section prefix="(vi)">If applicable, certification by holders of perfected security interests;</section><section prefix="(vii)">In the case of mobile homes manufactured after 1976 and motor vehicles, a pencil tracing of the vehicle identification number or a statement certifying the vehicle identification number; and</section><section prefix="(viii)">Any other reasonable information required in accordance with regulations adopted by the Administration.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Department of Natural Resources shall issue a title, free and clear of any liens, to the purchaser of any boat sold under this section.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If the notice required under &#xA7; 16-203(b) of this subtitle was sent, the proceeds of a sale under this section shall be applied, in the following order, to:<section prefix="(i)">The expenses of giving notice and holding the sale, including reasonable attorney's fees;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Subject to subsection (f) of this section, storage fees of the third party holder;</section><section prefix="(iii)">The amount of the lien claimed exclusive of any storage fees except as provided in subsection (f)(2) of this section;</section><section prefix="(iv)">A purchase money security interest; and</section><section prefix="(v)">Any remaining secured parties of record who shall divide the remaining balance equally if there are insufficient funds to completely satisfy their respective interests, but not to exceed the amount of a security interest.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Except as provided in paragraph (3) of this subsection, if the notice required under &#xA7; 16-203(b) of this subtitle was not sent, the proceeds of a sale under this section shall be applied, in the following order, to:<section prefix="(i)">A purchase money security interest;</section><section prefix="(ii)">All additional holders of perfected security interests in the property;</section><section prefix="(iii)">The expenses of giving notice and holding the sale, including reasonable attorney's fees;</section><section prefix="(iv)">Subject to subsection (f) of this section, storage fees of the third party holder;</section><section prefix="(v)">The amount of the lien claimed exclusive of any storage fees except as provided in subsection (f)(2) of this section;</section><section prefix="(vi)">Any remaining secured parties of record who shall divide the remaining balance equally if there are insufficient funds to completely satisfy their respective interest, but not to exceed the amount of a security interest.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">For a motor vehicle lien created under this subtitle, if the notice required under &#xA7; 16-203(b) of this subtitle was not sent:<section prefix="(i)">The proceeds of a sale under this section shall be applied in the order described in paragraph (1) of this subsection; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">The amount of the lien claimed in paragraph (1)(iii) of this subsection may not include any amount for storage charges incurred or imposed by the lienor.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">After application of the proceeds in accordance with paragraph (1) or (2) of this subsection, any remaining balance shall be paid to the owner of the property.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If property is stored, storage fees of the third party holder may not exceed $5 per day or a total of $300.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The exclusion or limitation of any storage fees as provided in subsection (e)(1)(iii) of this section and paragraph (1) of this subsection does not apply to any person who conducts auctions as a business in this State, and is required to maintain records under &#xA7; 15-113 of the Transportation Article, and that person is also exempt from the maximum storage fee limits under this subsection.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The notice requirements of &#xA7; 16-203(b) of this subtitle do not apply when:<section prefix="(i)">The lienor conducts auctions as a business in this State and is required to maintain records under &#xA7; 15-113 of the Transportation Article; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">The lien arises out of that business.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
