<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcl" order_by="gcl" level="1">Commercial Law</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcl-17-304</section_number>
  <catch_line>Any stock or other certificate of ownership, or any dividend, profit, distribution, interest, paymen...</catch_line>
  <order_by>304</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Any stock or other certificate of ownership, or any dividend, profit, distribution, interest, payment on principal, or other sum held by a business association for or to a shareholder, certificate holder, member, bondholder or other security holder, or participating patron of a cooperative, who has not claimed it or corresponded in writing with the business association concerning it within 3 years after the date prescribed for payment or delivery, is presumed abandoned if:<section prefix="(1)">It is held by a business association organized under the laws of or created in this State;</section><section prefix="(2)">It is held by a business association doing business in this State but not organized under the laws of this State, and the records of the business association indicate that the last known address of the person entitled to it is in this State; or</section><section prefix="(3)">It is held by a business association not doing business in this State and not organized under the laws of this State, but the records of the business association indicate that the last known address of the person entitled to it is in this State.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">This section shall apply to the stock or other certificate of ownership on, for or from which the amounts described in subsection (a) of this section have been presumed abandoned if the owner of said underlying stock or certificate has not, within the 3-year period giving rise to the presumption of abandonment:<section prefix="(1)">Communicated in writing with the association regarding the interest or a dividend, distribution, or other sum payable as a result of the interest; or</section><section prefix="(2)">Otherwise communicated with the association regarding the interest or a dividend, distribution, or other sum payable as a result of the interest, as evidenced by a memorandum or other record on file with the association prepared by an employee of the association.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">At the expiration of a 3-year period following the failure of the owner to claim a dividend, distribution, or other sum payable to the owner as a result of the interest, the interest is not presumed abandoned unless there have been at least 3 dividends, distributions, or other sums paid during the period, none of which has been claimed by the owner. If 3 dividends, distributions, or other sums are paid during the 3-year period, the period leading to a presumption of abandonment commences on the date payment of the first such unclaimed dividend, distribution, or other sum became due and payable. If 3 dividends, distributions, or other sums are not paid during the presumptive period, the period continues to run until there have been 3 dividends, distributions, or other sums that have not been claimed by the owner.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The running of the 3-year period of abandonment ceases immediately upon the occurrence of a communication referred to in subsection (b) of this section. If any future dividend, distribution, or other sum payable to the owner as a result of the interest is subsequently not claimed by the owner, a new period of abandonment commences and relates back to the time a subsequent dividend, distribution, or other sum became due and payable.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">At the time an interest is presumed abandoned under this section, any dividend, distribution, or other sum then held for or owing to the owner as a result of the interest, and not previously presumed abandoned, is presumed abandoned.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">This section does not apply to any stock or other intangible ownership interest enrolled in a plan that provides for the automatic reinvestment of dividends, distributions, or other sums payable as a result of the interest unless the records available to the Administrator of the plan show, with respect to any intangible ownership interest not enrolled in the reinvestment plan, that the owner has not within 3 years communicated in any manner described in subsection (b) of this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">The holder of an interest under this section shall deliver a duplicate certificate or other evidence of ownership if the holder does not issue certificates of ownership to the Administrator. Upon delivery of a duplicate certificate to the Administrator, the holder and any transfer agent, registrar, or other person acting for or on behalf of a holder in executing or delivering the duplicate certificate is relieved of all liability of every kind in accordance with the provision of &#xA7; 17-313 of this subtitle to every person, including any person acquiring the original certificate or the duplicate of the certificate issued to the Administrator, for any losses or damages resulting to any person by the issuance and delivery to the Administrator of the duplicate certificate.</section>
  </text>
</law>
