<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gcl" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="12-918.1" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcl-12-918.1</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, "Commissioner" means the Commissioner of Financial Regulation.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Except as provided in subsection (c) of this section, the penalty provided under &#xA7; 12-918(a)(2) of this subtitle does not apply if a credit grantor:<section prefix="(1)">Performed or omitted to perform an act in conformity with or in reliance on:<section prefix="(i)">A written opinion of the Attorney General of Maryland or a regulation adopted by the Commissioner;</section><section prefix="(ii)">A written opinion by the Commissioner or Deputy Commissioner; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">An interpretation by the Commissioner in a written notice or examination report; or</section></section><section prefix="(2)">Used a form or procedure that has been approved in writing by the Commissioner and the Attorney General.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The provisions of subsection (b) of this section do not apply to an act or omission to act that occurs after:<section prefix="(1)">The opinion, regulation, or interpretation relied on is amended, repealed, or determined to be invalid for any reason by any judicial or other authority; or</section><section prefix="(2)">Approval for a form or procedure is amended, rescinded, or determined to be invalid for any reason by any judicial or other authority.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">This section may not be construed to:<section prefix="(1)">Limit the imposition of any civil or criminal penalty for a knowing or willful violation of this subtitle; or</section><section prefix="(2)">Limit the power of the Commissioner or the courts to order a refund to a borrower of moneys collected in violation of this subtitle.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
