<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcl" order_by="" level="1">Commercial Law</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcl-12-601</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>601</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Agreement" means an installment sale agreement, a renewed or extended installment sale agreement, and any renewal, extension, or refund agreement made in connection with an installment sale agreement.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Buyer" means a person who buys or leases goods under an installment sale agreement, even though the person has entered into one or more renewal, extension, or refund agreements.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Buyer" includes a prospective buyer.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">"Cash price" means the minimum price for which goods subject to an installment sale agreement, or other goods of like kind and quality, may be purchased for cash from the seller by the buyer.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Collateral security" means any security interest in, encumbrance on, or pledge of property or goods that is given to secure performance of an obligation of a buyer or a surety for a buyer under an agreement.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Collateral security" includes the undertaking of a surety for a buyer.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Collateral security" does not include any goods or interest in goods that are the subject of an installment sale agreement.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">"Consumer goods" means goods bought for use primarily for personal, family, or household purposes, as distinguished from industrial, commercial, or agricultural purposes.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">"County" includes Baltimore City.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">"Debt cancellation agreement" means an agreement between a seller and a buyer which provides for cancellation of the outstanding balance payable under an installment sale agreement in the event of theft or total destruction of the motor vehicle that is the subject of the installment sale agreement minus the proceeds of any insurance maintained on the motor vehicle or, if the buyer does not have insurance, the actual cash value of the motor vehicle at the time of loss, determined as provided in the agreement.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">"Down payment" includes all amounts paid in cash, credits, or the agreed value of goods, by or for a buyer and to or for the benefit of a seller at or before execution of an installment sale agreement.</section>
    <section prefix="(j)">"Finance charge" means the amount in excess of the cash price of the goods sold, agreed on by a seller and a buyer, to be paid by the buyer for the privilege of purchasing the goods under an installment sale agreement.</section>
    <section prefix="(k)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Goods" means all tangible personal property that has a cash price of $25,000 or less.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Goods" does not include money or things in action.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(l)">"Holder" means a person, including a seller and a sales finance company, entitled to enforce an agreement against a buyer.</section>
    <section prefix="(m)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Installment sale agreement" means a contract for the retail sale of consumer goods, negotiated or entered into in this State, under which:<section prefix="(i)">Part or all of the price is payable in one or more payments after the making of the contract; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">The seller takes collateral security or keeps a security interest in the goods sold.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Installment sale agreement" includes:<section prefix="(i)">A prospective installment sale agreement;</section><section prefix="(ii)">A purchase money security agreement; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">A contract for the bailment or leasing of consumer goods under which the bailee or lessee contracts to pay as compensation a sum that is substantially equal to or is more than the value of the goods.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Installment sale agreement" does not include:<section prefix="(i)">A bona fide C.O.D. transaction or a layaway agreement as defined in &#xA7; 14-1101(g) of this article; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">A lease for industrial, commercial, or agricultural purposes.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(n)">"Mechanical repair contract" has the meaning stated in Title 15, Subtitle 3 of the Transportation Article.</section>
    <section prefix="(o)">"Motor vehicle" has the meaning stated in Title 11 of the Transportation Article.</section>
    <section prefix="(p)">"Outstanding balance", when used in reference to a debt cancellation agreement, does not include:<section prefix="(1)">Any delinquent or deferred payments;</section><section prefix="(2)">Past due charges;</section><section prefix="(3)">Late payment charges;</section><section prefix="(4)">Unearned interest;</section><section prefix="(5)">Unearned rental payments;</section><section prefix="(6)">The portion of any financed taxes or charges, including charges for credit life insurance, credit health insurance, credit involuntary unemployment benefit insurance, and mechanical repair contracts, actually refunded to the buyer or credited as a reduction to the loan balance; or</section><section prefix="(7)">	By agreement of the parties, the amount of any primary insurance deductible.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(q)">"Person" includes an individual, corporation, business trust, statutory trust, estate, trust, partnership, association, two or more persons having a joint or common interest, or any other legal or commercial entity.</section>
    <section prefix="(r)">"Principal balance" means the sum of items described in &#xA7; 12-606(b)(5), (6), and (7) of this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(s)">"Retail sale" means the sale of goods for use or consumption by the buyer or for the benefit or satisfaction that the buyer may derive from the use or consumption of the goods by another, but not for resale by the buyer.</section>
    <section prefix="(t)">"Sales finance company" means a person who is engaged, whether by purchase, discount, pledge, loan, or otherwise, in the business of acquiring, investing in, or lending money or credit on the security of any interest in:<section prefix="(1)">An installment sale agreement made between other parties;</section><section prefix="(2)">A retail credit account transaction, as defined in &#xA7; 12-501 of this title, made between other parties; or</section><section prefix="(3)">A transaction that deals with home improvement, as defined in &#xA7; 8-101 of the Business Regulation Article, made between other parties, if collateral security is required by and given to the contractor as a condition to the transaction.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(u)">"Security interest" has the meaning stated in &#xA7; 1-201(37) of this article.</section>
    <section prefix="(v)">"Seller" means a person who sells or leases or agrees to sell or lease goods under an installment sale agreement.</section>
    <section prefix="(w)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Surety" includes a guarantor.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Surety" does not include a seller who sells, transfers, or assigns an agreement.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(x)">"Time balance" means the sum of the items described in &#xA7; 12-606(b)(10) and (11) of this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(y)">"Wages" means all remuneration paid to any employee for his employment, including the cash value of all remuneration paid in any medium other than cash.</section>
  </text>
</law>
