<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcl" order_by="" level="1">Commercial Law</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcl-13-205</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>205</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">After obtaining the advice of the Consumer Council and holding a public hearing, the Division may adopt reasonable rules, regulations, and standards appropriate to effectuate the purposes of this subtitle, including rules, regulations, or standards which further define specific unfair or deceptive trade practices.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">These rules, regulations, and standards may not modify, expand or conflict with the definitions or standards set forth in this title.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">In addition to any publication of notice required to be made in the Maryland Register by the State Documents Law, a notice of the hearing shall be published in two daily newspapers at least 15 days before the hearing.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">If the Division adopts a rule, regulation, or standard, it shall issue a concise statement of:<section prefix="(1)">The reasons for adoption; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Any reasons against adoption which were rejected by the Division.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Any bona fide consumer group or trade association, the members of which are directly affected by a rule, regulation, or standard, has standing to challenge it in the name of the group or the association, even though the group or association may not be directly affected by the rule, regulation, or standard.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A challenge to a rule, regulation, or standard shall be made in accordance with the Administrative Procedure Act.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">Copies of each rule, regulation, and standard shall be filed in accordance with the Administrative Procedure Act and the State Documents Law and shall be made available to the public.</section>
  </text>
</law>
