<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gcl" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="22-103" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcl-22-103</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">This title applies to computer information transactions.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Except as otherwise provided in subsection (d) of this section and &#xA7; 22-104 of this subtitle, if a computer information transaction includes subject matter other than computer information, the following rules apply:<section prefix="(1)">If a transaction includes computer information and goods, this title applies to the part of the transaction involving computer information, informational rights in it, and creation or modification of it. However, if a copy of a computer program is contained in and sold or leased as part of goods, this title applies to the copy and the computer program only if:<section prefix="(A)">The goods are a computer or computer peripheral; or</section><section prefix="(B)">Giving the buyer or lessee of the goods access to or use of the program is ordinarily a material purpose of transactions in goods of the type sold or leased.</section></section><section prefix="(2)">Subject to subsection (d)(3)(A) of this section, if a transaction includes an agreement for creating or for obtaining rights to create computer information and a motion picture, this title does not apply to the agreement if the dominant character of the agreement is for creating or obtaining rights to create a motion picture. In all other such agreements, this title does not apply to the part of the agreement that involves a motion picture excluded under subsection (d)(3) of this section, but does apply to the computer information.</section><section prefix="(3)">In all other cases, this title applies to the entire transaction if the computer information and informational rights, or access to them, is the primary subject matter, but otherwise applies only to the part of the transaction involving computer information, informational rights in it, and creation or modification of it.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">To the extent of a conflict between this title and Title 9 of this article, Title 9 governs.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">This title does not apply to:<section prefix="(1)">A financial services transaction;</section><section prefix="(2)">An insurance services transaction;</section><section prefix="(3)">An agreement to create, perform or perform in, include information in, acquire, use, distribute, modify, reproduce, have access to, adapt, make available, transmit, license, or display:<section prefix="(A)">A motion picture or audio or visual programming, other than in (i) a mass-market transaction or (ii) a submission of an idea or information or release of informational rights that may result in making a motion picture or a similar information product; or</section><section prefix="(B)">A sound recording, musical work, or phonorecord as defined or used in Title 17 of the United States Code as of July 1, 1999, or an enhanced sound recording;</section></section><section prefix="(4)">A compulsory license;</section><section prefix="(5)">A contract of employment of an individual, other than an individual hired as an independent contractor to create or modify computer information, unless such independent contractor is a freelancer in the news reporting industry as that term is commonly understood in that industry;</section><section prefix="(6)">A contract that does not require that information be furnished as computer information or in which under the agreement the form of the information as computer information is otherwise insignificant with respect to the primary subject matter of the part of the transaction pertaining to the information; or</section><section prefix="(7)">Subject matter within the scope of Title 3, 4, 4A, 5, 6, 7, or 8 of this article.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">As used in subsection (d)(3)(B) of this section, "enhanced sound recording" means a separately identifiable product or service the dominant character of which consists of recorded sounds but which includes (i) statements or instructions whose purpose is to allow or control the perception, reproduction, or communication of those sounds or (ii) other information so long as recorded sounds constitute the dominant character of the product or service despite the inclusion of the other information.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">As used in this section, "motion picture" means "motion picture" as defined in Title 17 of the United States Code as of July 1, 1999, or a separately identifiable product or service the dominant character of which consists of a linear motion picture, but which includes (i) statements or instructions whose purpose is to allow or control the perception, reproduction, or communication of the motion picture or (ii) other information so long as the motion picture constitutes the dominant character of the product or service despite the inclusion of the other information.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">As used in this section, "audio or visual programming" means audio or visual programming that is provided by broadcast, satellite, or cable as defined in the Federal Communications Act of 1934 and related regulations as they existed on July 1, 1999, or by similar methods of delivery.</section>
  </text>
</law>
