<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcl" order_by="" level="1">Commercial Law</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcl-14-12B-06</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>06</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">A health club services agreement may not contain an automatic renewal clause, unless the agreement provides for a renewal option for continued membership which must be accepted by the buyer.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A buyer described in &#xA7; 14-12B-01(d)(1)(i) of this subtitle may cancel a health club services agreement within 3 business days after receipt of a copy of the agreement by notifying the health club in writing. Written notification shall be delivered in person or by certified mail, return receipt requested, bearing a postmark from the United States Postal Service, and if mailed shall be postmarked by midnight of the third business day.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If the buyer cancels within 3 business days, the health club facility shall refund any deposit, down payment, or payment on the agreement including any initiation, deposit, membership, or other fees.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Each contract for health club services shall conspicuously disclose under the heading "Notice of Consumer Rights":<section prefix="(i)">The seller's health club registration number with the Division;</section><section prefix="(ii)">A description of whether the seller is bonded and the amount of the bond or, if not bonded, an explanation of the basis for the seller's exemption from the bonding requirements;</section><section prefix="(iii)">The buyer's right to cancel as defined in this section;</section><section prefix="(iv)">The buyer's rights in the event of a disability or temporary closing under &#xA7; 14-12B-04 of this subtitle; and</section><section prefix="(v)">For those persons who register in accordance with &#xA7; 14-12B-02(b)(3)(iii) of this subtitle, a statement that the facility does not:<section prefix="1.">Charge an initiation fee or other fee that is not identified as a payment for specific future services;</section><section prefix="2.">Contractually obligate a buyer of health club services to pay in advance of the date the services are provided to the buyer; or</section><section prefix="3.">Collect from a buyer of health club services any payment in advance of the date the services are provided to the buyer.</section></section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">Each contract for the sale of health club services shall contain in a form acceptable to the Division:<section prefix="(i)">A clear and conspicuous itemized description of any fees and charges; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">If the facility is not in operation, the expected date of opening and a description of the specific services and facilities that will be available upon opening.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A person who registers in accordance with &#xA7; 14-12B-02(b)(3)(iii) of this subtitle shall post in a clear and conspicuous manner a sign in a prominent location in each health club facility that the person opens or operates that states that the facility does not:<section prefix="(1)">Charge an initiation fee or other fee that is not identified as a payment for specific future services;</section><section prefix="(2)">Contractually obligate a buyer of health club services to pay in advance of the date the services are provided to the buyer; or</section><section prefix="(3)">Collect from a buyer of health club services any payment in advance of the date the services are provided to the buyer.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
