<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gcl" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="14-4A-04" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcl-14-4A-04</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">A warrantor of a vehicle protection product that is sold or offered for sale in the State shall register with the Division on the form that the Division  provides.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The registration form shall include:<section prefix="(1)">The name, address, and telephone number of the warrantor, including any name under which the warrantor does business;</section><section prefix="(2)">The name, address, and telephone number of the warrantor's administrator, if any;</section><section prefix="(3)">The name and address of the warrantor's registered agent, if any;</section><section prefix="(4)">The name of at least one officer of the warrantor who is directly responsible for the warrantor's vehicle protection product business;</section><section prefix="(5)"><section prefix="(i)">If the warrantor elects to carry warranty reimbursement insurance in accordance with &#xA7; 14-4A-07(a)(1) of this subtitle, a copy of the warrantor's warranty reimbursement insurance policy; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">If the warrantor elects to meet its financial obligations in accordance with &#xA7; 14-4A-07(a)(2) of this subtitle, one of the following:</section></section><section prefix="(6)">A copy of each warranty that the warrantor proposes to use in the State.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A warrantor that registers under subsection (a) of this section shall pay a registration fee to the Division at the time of registration.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">On January 1 of each year following a warrantor's initial registration, the warrantor shall pay a renewal fee to the Division.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The registration fee and the renewal fee required under this subsection shall be set by the Division in an amount not exceeding $500 for each fee.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
