<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcl" order_by="" level="1">Commercial Law</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcl-14-3301</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>3301</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Client" means a noncitizen or any person seeking to sponsor a noncitizen for whom an immigration consultant performs or offers to perform a service relating to the noncitizen's immigration status.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Immigration consultant" means a person that provides nonlegal advice, guidance, information, or services to a client on an immigration matter for a fee.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">"Immigration matter" means any legal proceeding, filing, or action that:<section prefix="(1)">Affects the immigration status of a noncitizen; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Arises under:<section prefix="(i)">Any immigration and naturalization law, executive order, or presidential proclamation of the United States or any foreign country; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">An action of the United States Department of Homeland Security, the United States Department of Labor, the United States Department of State, the United States Department of Justice, or the United States Department of Commerce.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Legal services" means the legal representation of an individual.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Legal services" includes providing forms to an individual, completing forms on behalf of an individual, filing forms on behalf of an individual, advising an individual to file forms, or applying for a benefit on behalf of an individual.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">"Secretarial services" means:<section prefix="(1)">Writing, typing, or copying information as provided by an individual; or</section><section prefix="(2)">Translating documents into English for an individual.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
