<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcl" order_by="gcl" level="1">Commercial Law</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcl-14-2402</section_number>
  <catch_line>Within 10 calendar days after the execution of the contract to purchase a vacation club membership, ...</catch_line>
  <order_by>2402</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Within 10 calendar days after the execution of the contract to purchase a vacation club membership, either party may cancel the contract without penalty by mailing or delivering a notice of cancellation to the other party at the address specified in the contract.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Cancellation of a vacation club membership shall entitle the purchaser to a refund of the entire consideration paid for the contract, including the cost of financing.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The sales agent shall deliver the refund to the purchaser at the address specified in the contract within 15 business days after receipt of the notice of cancellation.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The right of cancellation may not be waived or otherwise surrendered.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A contract to purchase a vacation club membership shall contain the following statement:</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The statement required under this subsection shall:<section prefix="(i)">Be in at least 14-point bold-faced type; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Appear immediately before and on the same page as the space designated for signature of the purchaser.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This subtitle applies to vacation club membership plans that provide accommodations in time-share units.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The requirements of this section do not apply to a time-share estate, time-share plan, or time-share exchange program or any renewal thereof that is:<section prefix="(i)">Required to provide a consumer with a 10-day right to cancel under &#xA7; 11A-114 of the Real Property Article; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">Regulated under Title 11A of the Real Property Article.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
