<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcl" order_by="gcl" level="1">Commercial Law</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcl-12-109</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this section the following words have the meanings indicated....</catch_line>
  <order_by>109</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Lending institution" means a bank, savings bank, or savings and loan association doing business in Maryland.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Escrow account" means an expense or escrow account which tends to protect the security of a loan by the accumulation of funds for the payment of taxes, insurance premiums, or other expenses.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A lending institution which lends money secured by a first mortgage or first deed of trust on any interest in residential real property and creates or is the assignee of an escrow account in connection with that loan shall pay interest to the borrower on the funds in the escrow account at an annual rate not less than the 6-month average dealer bid rate on nationally traded certificates of deposit, as published by the Federal Reserve in "Selected Interest Rates (Daily) - H.15", as of the first business day of the calendar year.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Interest on these funds shall be:<section prefix="(i)">Adjusted, if applicable, as of the first day of each calendar year to reflect the rate to be paid during that year, as determined under paragraph (1) of this subsection;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Computed on the average monthly balance in the escrow account; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Paid annually to the borrower by crediting the escrow account with the amount of interest due.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The lending institution shall annually provide the borrower with a statement of the escrow balance.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The provisions of this section do not apply to a lending institution which provides for the payment of taxes, insurance, or other expenses under the direct reduction method by which these expenses, when paid by the lender, are added to the outstanding principal balance of the loan.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">This section does not apply if the loan is purchased by an out-of-state lender through the Federal National Mortgage Association, the Government National Mortgage Association, or the Federal Home Loan Mortgage Corporation and the out-of-state lender as a condition of purchase elects to service the loan. However, this section shall apply if the out-of-state lender sells the loan to a Maryland lender or places the loan with a Maryland lender for servicing.</section>
  </text>
</law>
