<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcl" order_by="gcl" level="1">Commercial Law</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcl-14-4A-01</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated....</catch_line>
  <order_by>01</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Administrator" means a person that is designated by a warrantor to be responsible for the administration of a vehicle protection product warranty.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Division" means the Division of Consumer Protection of the Office of the Attorney General.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Incidental costs" means an expense that:<section prefix="(i)">Is specified in a vehicle protection product warranty;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Is incurred by the warranty holder; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Relates to the failure of a vehicle protection product to perform as provided in the vehicle protection product warranty.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Incidental costs" include:<section prefix="(i)">Insurance policy deductibles;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Charges for rental vehicles;</section><section prefix="(iii)">The difference between the value of a stolen vehicle at the time of theft and the cost of a replacement vehicle;</section><section prefix="(iv)">Sales taxes;</section><section prefix="(v)">Registration fees;</section><section prefix="(vi)">Transaction fees; and</section><section prefix="(vii)">Mechanical inspection fees.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Vehicle protection product" means a vehicle protection device, system, or service that:<section prefix="(i)">Is sold with a written warranty;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Is installed on or applied to a vehicle; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Is designed to prevent loss or damage to a vehicle from a specific cause.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Vehicle protection product" includes:<section prefix="(i)">An alarm system;</section><section prefix="(ii)">A body part marking product;</section><section prefix="(iii)">A steering lock;</section><section prefix="(iv)">A window etch product;</section><section prefix="(v)">A pedal or ignition lock;</section><section prefix="(vi)">A fuel or ignition kill switch; and</section><section prefix="(vii)">An electronic, radio, or satellite tracking device.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">"Vehicle protection product warranty" means a written agreement by a warrantor that provides that if a vehicle protection product fails to prevent loss or damage to a vehicle from a specific cause, the warrantor shall pay to, or on behalf of, the warranty holder specified incidental costs incurred as a result of the failure of the vehicle protection product to perform in accordance with the terms of the vehicle protection product warranty.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Warrantor" means a person that is contractually obligated to the warranty holder under the terms of the vehicle protection product warranty.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Warrantor" does not include an authorized insurer that issues a warranty reimbursement insurance policy.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(h)">"Warranty holder" means a person that purchases a vehicle protection product warranty or a permitted transferee.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">"Warranty reimbursement insurance policy" means a policy of insurance that is issued to a warrantor to:<section prefix="(1)">Provide reimbursement to the warrantor; or</section><section prefix="(2)">Pay on behalf of the warrantor all covered contractual obligations incurred by the warrantor under the terms and conditions of the insured vehicle protection product warranties sold by the warrantor.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
