<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gcl" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="14-3801" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcl-14-3801</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Consumer" means an individual who, individually or in conjunction with another individual, is solicited for, applies for, or receives a refund anticipation loan or refund anticipation check.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Creditor" means a person who makes a refund anticipation loan or who takes an assignment of a refund anticipation loan.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Facilitator" means a person who, individually or in conjunction or cooperation with another person:<section prefix="(i)">Processes, receives, or accepts an application or agreement for a refund anticipation loan or refund anticipation check;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Services or collects on a refund anticipation loan or refund anticipation check; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">Facilitates the making of a refund anticipation loan or refund anticipation check.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Facilitator" does not include:<section prefix="(i)">A bank, savings and loan association, or credit union;</section><section prefix="(ii)">An affiliate or subsidiary of a bank, savings and loan association, or credit union that, in connection with refund anticipation loans or refund anticipation checks, acts solely as a servicer for the financial institution with which it is affiliated or of which it is a subsidiary; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">A person who acts solely as an intermediary and does not deal with the public in the making of a refund anticipation loan or refund anticipation check.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"Refund anticipation check" means a check, stored value card, or other payment mechanism:<section prefix="(1)">That represents the proceeds of a consumer's tax refund;</section><section prefix="(2)">That was issued by a depository institution or other person that received a direct deposit of the consumer's tax refund; and</section><section prefix="(3)">For which the consumer has paid a fee or other consideration.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Refund anticipation loan" means a loan arranged to be paid directly or indirectly from the proceeds of a consumer's tax refund.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Refund anticipation loan" includes a sale, assignment, or purchase of a consumer's tax refund at a discount or for a fee, whether or not the consumer is required to repay the buyer or assignee if the Internal Revenue Service denies or reduces the consumer's tax refund.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Refund anticipation loan fee" means any charge, fee, or other consideration charged or imposed directly or indirectly for the making of or in connection with a refund anticipation loan.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Refund anticipation loan fee" includes a charge, fee, or other consideration for a deposit account that is used for receipt of a consumer's tax refund to repay the amount owed on a refund anticipation loan.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
