<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcp" order_by="" level="1">Criminal Procedure</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcp-12-101</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>101</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this title the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Chief executive officer" means:<section prefix="(1)">for Baltimore City, the Mayor;</section><section prefix="(2)">for a charter county, the county executive or, if there is no county executive, the county council;</section><section prefix="(3)">for a code county, the county commissioners or county council;</section><section prefix="(4)">for a county commissioner county, the county commissioners; or</section><section prefix="(5)">for a municipal corporation, the legislative body established by municipal charter.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Controlled Dangerous Substances law" means Title 5 of the Criminal Law Article.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">"Convicted" means found guilty.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"Final disposition" means a dismissal, entry of a nolle prosequi, the marking of a criminal charge "stet" on the docket, entry of a not guilty verdict, the pronouncement of sentence, or imposition of probation under &#xA7; 6-220 of this article.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">"Forfeiting authority" means:<section prefix="(1)">the unit or person designated by agreement between the State's Attorney for a county and the chief executive officer of the governing body having jurisdiction over assets subject to forfeiture to act on behalf of the governing body regarding those assets; or</section><section prefix="(2)">if the seizing authority is a unit of the State, a unit or person that the Attorney General or the Attorney General's designee designates by agreement with a State's Attorney, county attorney, or municipal attorney to act on behalf of the State regarding assets subject to forfeiture by the State.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(g)">"Governing body" includes:<section prefix="(1)">the State, if the seizing authority is a unit of the State;</section><section prefix="(2)">a county, if the seizing authority is a unit of a county;</section><section prefix="(3)">a municipal corporation, if the seizing authority is a unit of a municipality; and</section><section prefix="(4)">Baltimore City, if the seizing authority is the Police Department of Baltimore City.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(h)">"Lien" includes a mortgage, deed of trust, pledge, security interest, encumbrance, or right of setoff.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">"Lienholder" means a person who has a lien or a secured interest on property created before the seizure.</section>
    <section prefix="(j)">"Local financial authority" means:<section prefix="(1)">if the seizing authority is a unit of a county, the treasurer or director of finance of the county; or</section><section prefix="(2)">if the seizing authority is a unit of a municipal corporation, the treasurer or director of finance of that municipal corporation.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(k)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Owner" means a person having a legal, equitable, or possessory interest in property.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Owner" includes:<section prefix="(i)">a co-owner;</section><section prefix="(ii)">a life tenant;</section><section prefix="(iii)">a remainderman to a life tenancy in real property;</section><section prefix="(iv)">a holder of an inchoate interest in real property; and</section><section prefix="(v)">a bona fide purchaser for value.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(l)">"Proceeds" includes property derived directly or indirectly in connection with or as a result of a crime under the Controlled Dangerous Substances law.</section>
    <section prefix="(m)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Property" includes:<section prefix="(i)">real property and anything growing on or attached to real property;</section><section prefix="(ii)">tangible and intangible personal property, including:<section prefix="1.">securities;</section><section prefix="2.">negotiable and nonnegotiable instruments;</section><section prefix="3.">vehicles and conveyances of any type;</section><section prefix="4.">privileges;</section><section prefix="5.">interests;</section><section prefix="6.">claims; and</section><section prefix="7.">rights;</section></section><section prefix="(iii)">an item, object, tool, substance, device, or weapon used in connection with a crime under the Controlled Dangerous Substances law; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">money.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Property" does not include:<section prefix="(i)">an item unlawfully in the possession of a person other than the owner when used in connection with a crime under the Controlled Dangerous Substances law; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">a lessor's interest in property subject to a bona fide lease, unless the forfeiting authority can show that the lessor participated in a crime under the Controlled Dangerous Substances law or that the property was the proceeds of a crime under the Controlled Dangerous Substances law.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(n)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Real property" means land or an improvement to land.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Real property" includes:<section prefix="(i)">a leasehold or other limited interest in real property;</section><section prefix="(ii)">an easement; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">a reversionary interest in a 99-year ground lease renewable forever.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(o)">"Seizing authority" means a law enforcement unit in the State that is authorized to investigate violations of the Controlled Dangerous Substances law and that has seized property under this title.</section>
  </text>
</law>
