<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcp" order_by="" level="1">Criminal Procedure</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcp-11-709</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>709</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Within 3 days after a tier III sex offender or a sexually violent predator completes the registration requirements of &#xA7; 11-707(a) of this subtitle, a local law enforcement unit shall send notice of the tier III sex offender's or sexually violent predator's quarterly registration to the Department.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">Every 6 months within 3 days after a tier I sex offender or a tier II sex offender completes the registration requirements of &#xA7; 11-707(a) of this subtitle, a local law enforcement unit shall send notice of the tier I sex offender's or tier II sex offender's biannual registration to the Department.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Every 6 months, a local law enforcement unit shall send a tier III sex offender's and sexually violent predator's updated digital image to the Department within 6 days after the digital image is submitted.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">As soon as possible but not later than 3 working days after receiving a registration statement of a sex offender, notice of a change of address of a sex offender, or change in a county in which a homeless sex offender habitually lives, a local law enforcement unit shall send written notice of the registration statement, change of address, or change of county to the county superintendent, as defined in &#xA7; 1-101 of the Education Article, and all nonpublic primary and secondary schools in the county within 1 mile of where the sex offender is to reside or habitually live or where a sex offender who is not a resident of the State is a transient or will work or attend school.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">As soon as possible but not later than 10 working days after receiving notice from the local law enforcement unit under paragraph (1) of this subsection, the county superintendent shall send written notice of the registration statement to principals of the schools under the superintendent's supervision that the superintendent considers necessary to protect the students of a school from a sex offender.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A local law enforcement unit that receives a notice from a supervising authority under this subtitle shall send a copy of the notice to the police department, if any, of a municipal corporation if the registrant:<section prefix="(1)">is to reside or habitually live in the municipal corporation after release;</section><section prefix="(2)">escapes from a facility but resided or habitually lived in the municipal corporation before being committed to the custody of a supervising authority; or</section><section prefix="(3)">is to change addresses to another place of residence within the municipal corporation.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">As soon as possible but not later than 3 working days after receiving notice from a local law enforcement unit under this section, a police department of a municipal corporation shall send a copy of the notice to the commander of each local police precinct or district in which the sex offender is to reside or habitually live or where a sex offender who is not a resident of the State will work or attend school.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">As soon as possible but not later than 3 working days after receiving a notice from a supervising authority under this subtitle, a local law enforcement unit shall send a copy of the notice to the commander of the law enforcement unit in each district or area in which the sex offender is to reside or habitually live or where a sex offender who is not a resident of the State will work or attend school.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">A local law enforcement unit may notify the following entities that are located within the community in which a sex offender is to reside or habitually live or where a sex offender who is not a resident of the State will work or attend school of the filing of a registration statement or notice of change of address or county where the registrant will habitually live by the sex offender:<section prefix="(1)">family child care homes or child care centers registered, licensed, or issued a letter of compliance under Title 5, Subtitle 5 of the Family Law Article;</section><section prefix="(2)">child recreation facilities;</section><section prefix="(3)">faith institutions; and</section><section prefix="(4)">other organizations that serve children and other individuals vulnerable to sex offenders who victimize children.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(g)">As soon as possible, but not later than 3 working days after receipt of a registrant's change of residence or change in the county in which the registrant habitually lives, the local law enforcement unit shall notify the Department of the change.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">As soon as possible, but not later than 3 working days after receipt of notice under &#xA7; 11-705(e) of this subtitle, the local law enforcement unit shall give notice to the Department of the registrant's intent to change residence, a county in which the registrant habitually lives, vehicle or license plate information, electronic mail or Internet identifiers, or landline or cellular phone numbers.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">As soon as possible, but not later than 3 working days after receipt of notice under &#xA7; 11-705(g) of this subtitle, the local law enforcement unit shall give notice to the Department of the change of name.</section>
    <section prefix="(j)">As soon as possible, but not later than 3 working days after receipt of notice under &#xA7; 11-705(h) of this subtitle, the local law enforcement unit shall give notice to the Department of the registrant's intent to leave the United States.</section>
    <section prefix="(k)">As soon as possible, but not later than 3 working days after receipt of notice under &#xA7; 11-705(i) of this subtitle, the local law enforcement unit shall give notice to the Department of the registrant's intent to obtain temporary lodging or to be absent from the registrant's permanent residence or locations where the registrant habitually lives.</section>
  </text>
</law>
