<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gcp" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="6-204" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcp-6-204</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Commission consists of the following 19 members:<section prefix="(1)">a chairman, appointed by the Governor;</section><section prefix="(2)"><section prefix="(i)">the Chief Judge of the Court of Appeals; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">a judge or former judge of the Court of Appeals or the Court of Special Appeals designated by the Chief Judge of the Court of Appeals;</section></section><section prefix="(3)">one circuit court judge, appointed by the Chief Judge of the Court of Appeals;</section><section prefix="(4)">one District Court judge, appointed by the Chief Judge of the Court of Appeals;</section><section prefix="(5)">the Attorney General or the Attorney General's designee;</section><section prefix="(6)">one State's Attorney who is recommended by the President of the Maryland State's Attorneys Association, appointed by the Governor;</section><section prefix="(7)">the Public Defender or the Public Defender's designee;</section><section prefix="(8)">a criminal defense attorney who is recommended by the President of the Maryland Criminal Defense Attorneys Association, appointed by the Governor;</section><section prefix="(9)">two members of the State Senate, including at least one member of the Senate Judicial Proceedings Committee, appointed by the President of the Senate;</section><section prefix="(10)">two members of the House of Delegates, including at least one member of the House Judiciary Committee, appointed by the Speaker of the House;</section><section prefix="(11)">the Secretary of the Department or the Secretary's designee;</section><section prefix="(12)">one representative from a victims' advocacy group, appointed by the Governor;</section><section prefix="(13)">one representative from law enforcement, appointed by the Governor;</section><section prefix="(14)">one member with a background in criminal justice or corrections policy who is a recognized expert in the field and who is appointed by the Governor;</section><section prefix="(15)">one representative of local correctional facilities, appointed by the Governor; and</section><section prefix="(16)">two representatives of the public, appointed by the Governor.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The term of an appointed member is 4 years.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The terms of the appointed members are staggered as required by the terms provided for members of the Commission on October 1, 2001.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">At the end of a term, an appointed member continues to serve until a successor is appointed and qualifies.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">A member who is appointed after a term has begun serves only for the rest of the term and until a successor is appointed and qualifies.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
