<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gcp" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="11-724" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcp-11-724</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">A person subject to lifetime sexual offender supervision may not knowingly or willfully violate the conditions of the lifetime sexual offender supervision imposed under &#xA7; 11-723 of this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A person who violates any conditions imposed under &#xA7; 11-723 of this subtitle:<section prefix="(1)">for a first offense, is guilty of a misdemeanor and on conviction is subject to imprisonment not exceeding 5 years or a fine not exceeding $5,000 or both; and</section><section prefix="(2)">for a second or subsequent offense, is guilty of a felony and on conviction is subject to imprisonment not exceeding 10 years or a fine not exceeding $10,000 or both.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Imprisonment for a lifetime sexual offender supervision violation is not subject to diminution credits.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A violation of subsection (a) of this section does not discharge a person from lifetime sexual offender supervision.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">On release from a sentence imposed under subsection (b) of this section, a person remains on lifetime sexual offender supervision, subject to the original terms of supervision, until discharged under subsection (f) of this section.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">During the period of lifetime sexual offender supervision, the court may:<section prefix="(1)">remand the person to a correctional facility or release the person with or without bail pending the hearing or determination of a charge of violation of a condition of lifetime sexual offender supervision; and</section><section prefix="(2)">if the court finds that the person committed a violation of a condition of supervision, impose a sentence as prescribed in subsection (b) of this section.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The sentencing court shall hear and adjudicate a petition for discharge from lifetime sexual offender supervision.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A person may file a petition for discharge after serving at least 5 years of extended sexual offender supervision.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">If a petition for discharge is denied, a person may not renew the petition for a minimum of 1 year.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">A petition for discharge shall include:<section prefix="(i)">a risk assessment of the person conducted by a sexual offender treatment provider within 3 months before the date of the filing of the petition; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">a recommendation regarding the discharge of the person from the sexual offender management team.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(5)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The sentencing court may not deny a petition for discharge without a hearing.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The court may not discharge a person from lifetime sexual offender supervision unless the court makes a finding on the record that the petitioner is no longer a danger to others.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(6)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The judge who originally imposed the lifetime sexual offender supervision shall hear a petition for discharge.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">If the judge has been removed from office, has died or resigned, or is otherwise incapacitated, another judge may act in the matter.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
