<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcp" order_by="gcp" level="1">Criminal Procedure</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcp-6-220</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this section, "custodial confinement" means:...</catch_line>
  <order_by>220</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, "custodial confinement" means:<section prefix="(1)">home detention;</section><section prefix="(2)">a corrections options program established under law which requires the individual to participate in home detention, inpatient treatment, or other similar program involving terms and conditions that constitute the equivalent of confinement; or</section><section prefix="(3)">inpatient drug or alcohol treatment.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">When a defendant pleads guilty or nolo contendere or is found guilty of a crime, a court may stay the entering of judgment, defer further proceedings, and place the defendant on probation subject to reasonable conditions if:<section prefix="(i)">the court finds that the best interests of the defendant and the public welfare would be served; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">the defendant gives written consent after determination of guilt or acceptance of a nolo contendere plea.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Subject to paragraphs (3) and (4) of this subsection, the conditions may include an order that the defendant:<section prefix="(i)">pay a fine or monetary penalty to the State or make restitution; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">participate in a rehabilitation program, the parks program, or a voluntary hospital program.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Before the court orders a fine, monetary penalty, or restitution, the defendant is entitled to notice and a hearing to determine the amount of the fine, monetary penalty, or restitution, what payment will be required, and how payment will be made.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">Any fine or monetary penalty imposed as a condition of probation shall be within the amount set by law for a violation resulting in conviction.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">As a condition of probation, the court may order a person to a term of custodial confinement or imprisonment.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">When the crime for which the judgment is being stayed is for a violation of &#xA7; 21-902 of the Transportation Article or &#xA7; 2-503, &#xA7; 2-504, &#xA7; 2-505, &#xA7; 2-506, or &#xA7; 3-211 of the Criminal Law Article, the court:<section prefix="(i)">before imposing a period of probation, may order the Department of Health and Mental Hygiene to evaluate the defendant in accordance with &#xA7; 8-505 of the Health - General Article;</section><section prefix="(ii)">if an evaluation was ordered under item (i) of this paragraph, shall review the evaluation before imposing a period of probation; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">shall impose a period of probation and, as a condition of the probation:<section prefix="1.">shall require the defendant to participate in an alcohol or drug treatment or education program approved by the Department of Health and Mental Hygiene, unless the court finds and states on the record that the interests of the defendant and the public do not require the imposition of this condition; and</section><section prefix="2.">may prohibit the defendant from operating a motor vehicle unless the motor vehicle is equipped with an ignition interlock system under &#xA7; 27-107 of the Transportation Article.</section></section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">When the crime for which the judgment is being stayed is for a violation of any provision of Title 5 of the Criminal Law Article, the court shall impose a period of probation and, as a condition of probation, require the defendant to participate in a drug treatment or education program approved by the Department of Health and Mental Hygiene, unless the court finds and states on the record that the interests of the defendant and the public do not require the imposition of this condition.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Notwithstanding subsections (b) and (c) of this section, a court may not stay the entering of judgment and place a defendant on probation for:<section prefix="(1)">a violation of &#xA7; 21-902 of the Transportation Article or &#xA7; 2-503, &#xA7; 2-504, &#xA7; 2-505, &#xA7; 2-506, or &#xA7; 3-211 of the Criminal Law Article, if within the preceding 10 years the defendant has been convicted under &#xA7; 21-902 of the Transportation Article or &#xA7; 2-503, &#xA7; 2-504, &#xA7; 2-505, &#xA7; 2-506, or &#xA7; 3-211 of the Criminal Law Article, or has been placed on probation in accordance with this section, after being charged with a violation of &#xA7; 21-902 of the Transportation Article or &#xA7; 2-503, &#xA7; 2-504, &#xA7; 2-505, &#xA7; 2-506, or &#xA7; 3-211 of the Criminal Law Article;</section><section prefix="(2)">a second or subsequent controlled dangerous substance crime under Title 5 of the Criminal Law Article, except that the court may stay the entering of judgment and place a defendant on probation for possession of a controlled dangerous substance under &#xA7; 5-601 of the Criminal Law Article if:<section prefix="(i)">the defendant has been convicted once previously of or received probation before judgment once previously for possession of a controlled dangerous substance under &#xA7; 5-601 of the Criminal Law Article;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the court requires the defendant to graduate from drug court or successfully complete a substance abuse treatment program as a condition of probation; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">the defendant graduates from drug court or successfully completes a substance abuse treatment program as required;</section></section><section prefix="(3)">a violation of any of the provisions of &#xA7;&#xA7; 3-303 through 3-307, &#xA7;&#xA7; 3-309 through 3-312, &#xA7; 3-315, or &#xA7; 3-602 of the Criminal Law Article for a crime involving a person under the age of 16 years; or</section><section prefix="(4)">a moving violation, as defined in &#xA7; 11-136.1 of the Transportation Article, if:<section prefix="(i)">the defendant holds a provisional license under &#xA7; 16-111 of the Transportation Article; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">the defendant has previously been placed on probation under this section for the commission of a moving violation while the defendant held a provisional license.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">By consenting to and receiving a stay of entering of the judgment as provided by subsections (b) and (c) of this section, the defendant waives the right to appeal at any time from the judgment of guilt.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Before granting a stay, the court shall notify the defendant of the consequences of consenting to and receiving a stay of entry of judgment under paragraph (1) of this subsection.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">On violation of a condition of probation, the court may enter judgment and proceed as if the defendant had not been placed on probation.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">On fulfillment of the conditions of probation, the court shall discharge the defendant from probation.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The discharge is a final disposition of the matter.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Discharge of a defendant under this section shall be without judgment of conviction and is not a conviction for the purpose of any disqualification or disability imposed by law because of conviction of a crime.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(h)">Repealed.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">If an individual violates the terms of probation, any time served by the individual in custodial confinement shall be credited against any sentence of incarceration imposed by the court.</section>
  </text>
</law>
