<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcp" order_by="" level="1">Criminal Procedure</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcp-11-113</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>113</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">After conviction or a finding of a prohibited exposure, a finding of probable cause under &#xA7; 11-110(3) of this subtitle, or a granting of probation before judgment under &#xA7; 11-112 of this subtitle, the State's Attorney shall within 3 days notify the local health officer of the written request by the victim or victim's representative for testing.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">On receipt of a court order for testing issued under &#xA7; 11-110(3) or &#xA7; 11-112 of this subtitle, the local health officer or the local health officer's designee from any other governmental unit shall:<section prefix="(i)">collect the blood sample within 7 days from the person who is charged with, convicted of, or found to have committed a prohibited exposure;</section><section prefix="(ii)">test the blood sample; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">give pretest and posttest counseling to the victim or victim's representative and the person subject to testing in accordance with Title 18, Subtitle 3, Part VI of the Health - General Article.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">After receiving the results of a test conducted under subsection (a) of this section, the local health officer shall promptly send notice of the test results to:<section prefix="(i)">the victim or victim's representative; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">the person charged with, convicted of, or found to have committed a prohibited exposure.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The local health officer may not disclose positive test results to a victim or victim's representative or a person charged with, convicted of, or found to have committed a prohibited exposure without also giving, offering, or arranging for appropriate counseling to:<section prefix="(i)">the victim or victim's representative; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">the person.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The following shall notify a victim of prohibited exposure or the victim's representative of the provisions of Part II of this subtitle:<section prefix="(1)">a sexual assault crisis program established under &#xA7; 11-923 of this title when a victim or victim's representative contacts the program;</section><section prefix="(2)">an intake officer who receives a complaint for the alleged prohibited exposure under &#xA7; 3-8A-10 of the Courts Article; or</section><section prefix="(3)">on the filing of a charging document or delinquency petition for the alleged prohibited exposure:<section prefix="(i)">the Department of State Police;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the Police Department of Baltimore City;</section><section prefix="(iii)">the police unit of a county;</section><section prefix="(iv)">the police unit of a municipal corporation;</section><section prefix="(v)">the office of the sheriff of a county;</section><section prefix="(vi)">the office of the State's Attorney of a county;</section><section prefix="(vii)">the Office of the Attorney General;</section><section prefix="(viii)">the Office of the State Prosecutor;</section><section prefix="(ix)">the Department of Juvenile Services; or</section><section prefix="(x)">the police unit of a bicounty unit or the University of Maryland.</section></section></section>
  </text>
</law>
