<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gcp" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="16-212" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcp-16-212</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The reasonable value of the services rendered to an indigent individual in accordance with this title is a lien on real or personal property in which the indigent individual has or acquires an interest, except for the residence of the indigent individual.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">To perfect the lien, the Public Defender shall submit to the court having jurisdiction in the matter an affidavit setting forth the services rendered to the indigent individual and their reasonable value.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The court shall set a hearing date and shall notify the indigent individual of the date and the fact that the Public Defender filed an affidavit to perfect the lien.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The indigent individual may:<section prefix="(i)">appear;</section><section prefix="(ii)">be represented by an attorney;</section><section prefix="(iii)">present evidence; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">examine witnesses.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The indigent individual may contest the affidavit.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">If the court determines that the Public Defender is not entitled to a lien, the proceeding shall be dismissed.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">If the court determines that the Public Defender is entitled to a lien, the court shall determine the reasonable value of the services rendered to the indigent individual.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">On adjudication, a lien shall be filed or docketed with the clerk of the circuit court or District Court where the services were performed or where the indigent individual works or resides.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The lien shall:<section prefix="(i)">constitute a lien on the indigent individual's property for 10 years from the date of filing or docketing unless the lien is discharged sooner; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">have the force and effect of a judgment at law.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The clerks of the circuit courts and the District Court shall provide separate books to record liens under this section.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The books shall be properly indexed in the name of the debtor.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">The Public Defender may not be required to pay filing or recording fees.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
