<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gcp" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="15-408" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcp-15-408</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">This section applies only in Cecil County.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The State's Attorney is entitled to:<section prefix="(i)">a salary that is 95% of the salary of a judge of the District Court of Maryland; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">the same benefits as a full-time county employee.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The State's Attorney:<section prefix="(i)">is entitled to a reasonable expense allowance for the operation of the office and performance of the duties of State's Attorney as provided in the county budget; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">subject to the approval of the administrative judge of the circuit court for the county, may spend $1,500 each year for special work and employing extra help.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The State's Attorney may appoint one deputy State's Attorney and the number of assistant State's Attorneys as provided in the county budget.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The salary of the deputy State's Attorney and the assistant State's Attorneys shall be as provided in the county budget.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The deputy State's Attorney and the assistant State's Attorneys have the same legal powers as the State's Attorney to represent the State before the grand jury and in criminal proceedings.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The deputy State's Attorney and the assistant State's Attorneys:<section prefix="(i)">serve at the pleasure of the State's Attorney;</section><section prefix="(ii)">serve part time; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">are entitled to the same benefits as a full-time county employee.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The State's Attorney may appoint clerical, secretarial, administrative, investigative, and other support staff that the State's Attorney considers necessary for the proper conduct of the office.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The State's Attorney's executive secretary and criminal investigators serve at the pleasure of the State's Attorney.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">Except for the State's Attorney's executive secretary and criminal investigators, the positions appointed under this subsection are subject to county personnel policies and procedures governing county employees.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The salaries of the positions appointed under this subsection shall be as provided in the county budget.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The State's Attorney shall serve full time and may not engage in the private practice of law.</section>
  </text>
</law>
