<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gcp" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="11-923" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcp-11-923</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The General Assembly finds that an increasing number of sexual assault offense victims in the State:<section prefix="(1)">lack necessary counseling and follow-up services; and</section><section prefix="(2)">in some parts of the State, have only the help of extremely limited support services.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The purpose of this section is to provide for sexual assault crisis programs that address the special needs of sexual assault victims.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Governor's Office of Crime Control and Prevention shall help establish sexual assault crisis programs in the State.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The programs shall be developed and located to facilitate their use by alleged victims residing in surrounding areas.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The programs shall:<section prefix="(i)">provide specialized support services to adult and minor alleged victims of sexual assault crimes; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">include a hotline and counseling service.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Governor's Office of Crime Control and Prevention may award grants to public or private nonprofit organizations to operate the sexual assault crisis programs.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The Governor's Office of Crime Control and Prevention shall regularly consult, collaborate with, and consider the recommendations of the federally recognized State sexual assault coalition regarding sexual assault crisis programs and policies, practices, and procedures that impact victims of sexual assault.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">Money for the sexual assault crisis programs shall be as provided in the annual State budget and shall be used to supplement, but not supplant, money that the programs receive from other sources.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">The Executive Director of the Governor's Office of Crime Control and Prevention shall include a report on the sexual assault crisis programs in the annual report submitted by the Governor's Office of Crime Control and Prevention to the General Assembly, in accordance with &#xA7; 2-1246 of the State Government Article.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Governor's Office of Crime Control and Prevention shall establish and sustain child advocacy centers in the State.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The child advocacy centers:<section prefix="(i)">may be based in private nonprofit organizations, local departments of social services, local law enforcement agencies, or a partnership among any of these entities;</section><section prefix="(ii)">shall be developed and located to facilitate their use by alleged victims residing in the surrounding areas;</section><section prefix="(iii)">shall investigate allegations of sexual crimes against children and sexual abuse of minors;</section><section prefix="(iv)">shall provide or facilitate referrals to appropriate counseling, legal, medical, and advocacy services for victims; and</section><section prefix="(v)">shall be included in all joint investigation procedures developed in accordance with &#xA7; 5-706 of the Family Law Article.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Governor's Office of Crime Control and Prevention may contract with public or private nonprofit organizations to operate child advocacy centers.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">Money for child advocacy centers shall be as provided in the annual State budget and shall be used to supplement, but not supplant, money that the programs receive from other sources.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">On or before January 1 each year, the Governor's Office of Crime Control and Prevention shall submit an annual report, in accordance with &#xA7; 2-1246 of the State Government Article, on child advocacy centers to the General Assembly.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
