<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gcp" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="11-610" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcp-11-610</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, the provisions of this section do not apply in Baltimore City.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">In Baltimore City, a judgment of restitution shall:<section prefix="(i)">be entered, indexed, and recorded under Maryland Rule 3-601; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">constitute a lien as provided under Maryland Rule 3-621(b).</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A judgment of restitution that the District Court orders under Part I of this subtitle may not be recorded and indexed by the Clerk of the District Court as a money judgment in the District Court until the person or governmental unit to whom the restitution obligor has been ordered to pay restitution files with the Clerk of the District Court a written request for the recording and indexing.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Once a judgment of restitution is recorded and indexed as a money judgment under subsection (a) of this section:<section prefix="(1)">the Clerk of the District Court shall immediately forward a notice of lien of judgment to the circuit court for the county of entry of judgment; and</section><section prefix="(2)">on the receipt of the written statement from the person or governmental unit to whom a restitution obligor has been ordered to pay restitution, the Clerk of the District Court shall forward a notice of lien of judgment to the circuit court of any other county as the Maryland Rules provide.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Whenever the Clerk of the District Court forwards a notice of lien under subsection (b) of this section to a circuit court, the clerk of the circuit court shall record and index the notice of lien as the Maryland Rules provide.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A judgment of restitution that is issued by the District Court and is recorded and indexed as a money judgment under subsection (a) of this section is a lien in the amount of the judgment on the restitution obligor's interest in land in a county.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The lien is in effect from the date that a notice of lien is recorded and indexed in the circuit court of the county.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If the District Court enters a judgment of restitution under Part I of this subtitle, the Clerk of the District Court shall send a written notice to the person or governmental unit in whose favor the judgment of restitution is entered.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The notice shall say in substance:</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
