<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcp" order_by="" level="1">Criminal Procedure</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcp-2-104</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>104</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, "federal law enforcement officer" means an officer who may:<section prefix="(1)">make an arrest with or without a warrant for violations of the United States Code; and</section><section prefix="(2)">carry firearms in the performance of the officer's duties.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Subject to the limitations of paragraph (2) of this subsection, a federal law enforcement officer may:<section prefix="(i)">make arrests as set forth in Subtitle 2 of this title; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">execute arrest and search and seizure warrants issued under the laws of the State.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A federal law enforcement officer may exercise the powers granted by this subsection when:<section prefix="(i)">the federal law enforcement officer is participating in a joint investigation with officials from a State or local law enforcement unit;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the federal law enforcement officer is rendering assistance to a police officer;</section><section prefix="(iii)">the federal law enforcement officer is acting at the request of a local police officer or State Police officer; or</section><section prefix="(iv)">an emergency exists.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A federal law enforcement officer who acts under the authority granted by this section shall notify the following persons of an investigation or enforcement action:<section prefix="(i)"><section prefix="1.">the chief of police, if any, or chief's designee, when in a municipal corporation;</section><section prefix="2.">the police commissioner or police commissioner's designee, when in Baltimore City;</section><section prefix="3.">the chief of police or chief's designee, when in a county with a county police department, except Baltimore City;</section><section prefix="4.">the sheriff or sheriff's designee, when in a county without a county police department;</section><section prefix="5.">the Secretary of Natural Resources or Secretary's designee, when on property owned, leased, operated by, or under the control of the Department of Natural Resources; or</section><section prefix="6.">the chief of police of the Maryland Transportation Authority or chief's designee, when on property owned, leased, operated by, or under the control of the Maryland Transportation Authority, Maryland Aviation Administration, or Maryland Port Administration; and</section></section><section prefix="(ii)">the Department of State Police barrack commander or commander's designee, unless there is an agreement otherwise with the Department of State Police.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">When the federal law enforcement officer participates in a joint investigation with officials from a State or local law enforcement unit, the federal law enforcement officer shall give the notice required under paragraph (1) of this subsection reasonably in advance.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A federal law enforcement officer who acts under the authority granted by this section:<section prefix="(1)">has the same legal status as a police officer;</section><section prefix="(2)">has the same protections as a police officer under &#xA7; 2-608 of the Courts Article with regard to charging documents against police officers; and</section><section prefix="(3)">has the same immunity from liability described in &#xA7; 5-611 of the Courts Article.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">This section does not impose liability on or require indemnification by the State or a local subdivision for an act performed by a federal law enforcement officer under this section.</section>
  </text>
</law>
