<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gcp" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="3-121" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcp-3-121</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If the State's Attorney receives a report that alleges that a committed person has violated a condition of a conditional release, or if the State's Attorney is notified by the court or Health Department under subsection (b) of this section, the State's Attorney shall determine whether there is a factual basis for the complaint.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If the State's Attorney determines that there is no factual basis for the complaint, the State's Attorney shall notify the person who made the report and take no further action.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">If the State's Attorney determines that there is a factual basis to believe that the committed person has violated the terms of a conditional release and believes further action by the court is necessary, the State's Attorney promptly shall:<section prefix="(i)">notify the Health Department of the alleged violation; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">file with the court a petition for revocation or modification of conditional release and send a copy of the petition to the Health Department.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If a court receives a report that alleges that a committed person has violated a condition of a conditional release, the court promptly shall:<section prefix="(i)">notify the Health Department; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">notify the State's Attorney and provide the name, address, and telephone number of the person who reported the violation and a copy of the order for conditional release.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If the Health Department receives a report that alleges that a committed person has violated conditional release, the Department shall:<section prefix="(i)">notify the court and the State's Attorney; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">provide the State's Attorney with the name, address, and telephone number of the person who reported the violation and a copy of the order for conditional release.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The petition for revocation or modification of a conditional release shall contain:<section prefix="(1)">a statement that the committed person has violated a term of a conditional release and that there is therefore reason to believe that the committed person no longer meets the criteria for eligibility for conditional release;</section><section prefix="(2)">a statement of the conditions violated;</section><section prefix="(3)">the factual basis for the statements in items (1) and (2) of this subsection;</section><section prefix="(4)">the most recent evaluation report on the committed person; and</section><section prefix="(5)">the designation by the Health Department of the facility to receive the returned committed person.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">If the court's review of the petition determines that there is no probable cause to believe that the committed person has violated a conditional release, the court shall:<section prefix="(1)">note the determination on the petition and file it in the court file on the committed person; and</section><section prefix="(2)">notify the State's Attorney, the Health Department, and the person who reported the violation.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">If the court's review of the petition determines that there is probable cause to believe that the committed person has violated a conditional release, the court promptly shall:<section prefix="(1)">issue a hospital warrant for the committed person and direct that on execution the committed person shall be transported to the facility designated by the Health Department; and</section><section prefix="(2)">send a copy of the hospital warrant and the petition to:<section prefix="(i)">the State's Attorney;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the Public Defender;</section><section prefix="(iii)">the counsel of record for the committed person;</section><section prefix="(iv)">the person who reported the violation;</section><section prefix="(v)">the Office; and</section><section prefix="(vi)">the Health Department.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">Within 10 days after the committed person is returned to the Health Department in accordance with the hospital warrant, the Office shall hold a hearing unless:<section prefix="(1)">the hearing is postponed or waived by agreement of the parties; or</section><section prefix="(2)">the Office postpones the hearing for good cause shown.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(g)">At the hearing on revocation or modification:<section prefix="(1)">the committed person is entitled to be represented by counsel including, if the committed person is indigent, the Public Defender or designee of the Public Defender;</section><section prefix="(2)">the committed person, Health Department, and State's Attorney are entitled to offer evidence, to cross-examine adverse witnesses, and to exercise any other rights that the Office considers necessary for a fair hearing; and</section><section prefix="(3)">the Office shall find:<section prefix="(i)">whether, by a preponderance of the evidence, the State has proved that the committed person violated conditional release; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">whether, by a preponderance of the evidence, the committed person nevertheless has proved eligibility for conditional release.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(h)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Office promptly shall:<section prefix="(i)">send a report of the hearing and determination to the court; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">send copies of the report to the committed person, counsel for the committed person, the State's Attorney, and the Health Department.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Within 5 days after receipt of the report of the Office, the committed person, the State's Attorney, or the Health Department may file exceptions to the determination of the Office.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(i)">After the court considers the report of the Office, the evidence, and any exceptions filed, within 10 days after the court receives the report, the court shall:<section prefix="(1)">revoke the conditional release and order the committed person returned to the facility designated by the Health Department;</section><section prefix="(2)">modify the conditional release as required by the evidence;</section><section prefix="(3)">continue the present conditions of release; or</section><section prefix="(4)">extend the conditional release by an additional term of 5 years.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(j)">The court shall notify the Criminal Justice Information System Central Repository of the issuance of any hospital warrant and any revocation it orders under this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(k)">
      <section prefix="(1)">An appeal from a District Court order shall be on the record in circuit court.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">An appeal from a circuit court order shall be by application for leave to appeal to the Court of Special Appeals.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
