<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gcp" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="10-232" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcp-10-232</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">This section does not apply to a person who provides services or performs duties voluntarily and without compensation for the government of Carroll County.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The County Commissioners of Carroll County may request a State and national criminal history records check from the Central Repository for:<section prefix="(1)">a current or prospective employee of Carroll County who is or will be assigned to a position that involves:<section prefix="(i)">inspections;</section><section prefix="(ii)">approval or denial of a permit, license, or other grant of authority;</section><section prefix="(iii)">work in the offices of the County Commissioners, sheriff, State's Attorney, circuit court, or county attorney; or</section><section prefix="(iv)">collecting or handling money; or</section></section><section prefix="(2)">a current or prospective employee of a person that has a contract with Carroll County if the contract involves work in a place that requires security of personnel or files, including the county courthouse, the local correctional facility, the State's Attorney's office, a county commissioner's office, and the county attorney's office.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Comptroller of Carroll County shall pay to the Department the fee that the Department imposes for each request made under subsection (b) of this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">If the request for a criminal history records check under subsection (b) of this section requires that information be obtained from the Federal Bureau of Investigation, the person who is the subject of the request shall submit to the Department a complete and legible set of the person's fingerprints on standard fingerprint cards.</section>
  </text>
</law>
