<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gcp" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="15-404" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcp-15-404</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">This section applies only in Baltimore County.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Subject to Article III, &#xA7; 35 of the Maryland Constitution and paragraph (2) of this subsection, beginning with the term of the State's Attorney who was elected to that position in 1982, the State's Attorney's salary:<section prefix="(i)">is equal to the salary of a circuit court judge; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">shall be increased 5% each year during the State's Attorney's term of office.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Beginning with the term of the State's Attorney elected to that position in 2010, the salary of the State's Attorney is $194,276; and</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">for the year beginning on January 1, 2012, and each year thereafter until January 1, 2023, the salary shall be increased by 1%.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The State's Attorney shall appoint two deputy State's Attorneys, one of whom shall be designated deputy State's Attorney of trial and administration and the other shall be designated deputy State's Attorney of operations.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">A deputy State's Attorney shall perform the work that the State's Attorney requires.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">Subject to the approval of the County Executive and the County Council, the State's Attorney shall set the salaries of the deputy State's Attorneys.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">As authorized by the County Executive, the State's Attorney may appoint assistant State's Attorneys.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">Subject to the approval of the County Executive and the County Council, the State's Attorney shall set the salaries of the assistant State's Attorneys.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The deputy and assistant State's Attorneys have the same legal powers as the State's Attorney to represent the State before the grand jury and in criminal proceedings.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The State's Attorney may appoint clerical, administrative, and other staff that the State's Attorney considers necessary for the proper conduct of the office.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The staff appointed under paragraph (1) of this subsection shall perform clerical and other work as directed by the State's Attorney.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The State's Attorney and the deputy State's Attorneys shall serve full time and may not engage in the private practice of law.</section>
  </text>
</law>
