<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcp" order_by="" level="1">Criminal Procedure</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcp-11-402</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>402</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">A presentence investigation that the Division of Parole and Probation completes under &#xA7; 6-112 of the Correctional Services Article or a predisposition investigation that the Department of Juvenile Services completes shall include a victim impact statement if:<section prefix="(1)">the defendant or child respondent caused physical, psychological, or economic injury to the victim in committing a felony or delinquent act that would be a felony if committed by an adult; or</section><section prefix="(2)">the defendant caused serious physical injury or death to the victim in committing a misdemeanor.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">If the court does not order a presentence investigation or predisposition investigation, the prosecuting attorney or the victim may prepare a victim impact statement to be submitted to the court and the defendant or child respondent in accordance with the Maryland Rules.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The prosecuting attorney shall notify a victim who has filed a notification request form under &#xA7; 11-104 of this title of the victim's right to submit a victim impact statement to the court in a transfer hearing under &#xA7; 4-202 of this article or a waiver hearing under &#xA7; 3-8A-06 of the Courts Article.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">This subsection does not preclude a victim who has not filed a notification request form under &#xA7; 11-104 of this title from submitting a victim impact statement to the court.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The court may consider a victim impact statement in determining whether to transfer jurisdiction under &#xA7; 4-202 of this article or waive jurisdiction under &#xA7; 3-8A-06 of the Courts Article.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The court shall consider the victim impact statement in determining the appropriate sentence or disposition and in entering a judgment of restitution for the victim under &#xA7; 11-603 of this title.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">A victim impact statement for a crime or delinquent act shall:<section prefix="(1)">identify the victim;</section><section prefix="(2)">itemize any economic loss suffered by the victim;</section><section prefix="(3)">identify any physical injury suffered by the victim and describe the seriousness and any permanent effects of the injury;</section><section prefix="(4)">describe any change in the victim's personal welfare or familial relationships;</section><section prefix="(5)">identify any request for psychological services initiated by the victim or the victim's family;</section><section prefix="(6)">identify any request by the victim to prohibit the defendant or child respondent from having contact with the victim as a condition of probation, parole, mandatory supervision, work release, or any other judicial or administrative release of the defendant or child respondent; and</section><section prefix="(7)">contain any other information related to the impact on the victim or the victim's family that the court requires.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">If the victim is deceased, under a mental, physical, or legal disability, or otherwise unable to provide the information required under this section, the information may be obtained from the victim's representative.</section>
  </text>
</law>
