<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcp" order_by="gcp" level="1">Criminal Procedure</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcp-10-233.1</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this section the following words have the meanings indicated....</catch_line>
  <order_by>233.1</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Massage establishment license":<section prefix="(i)">means a certificate, license, permit, or similar document that would allow a person to own, operate, or manage a massage establishment in Howard County; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">includes any renewal of a document described in item (i) of this paragraph.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Pawnbroker or secondhand dealer establishment license":<section prefix="(i)">means a certificate, license, permit, or similar document that would allow a person to own, operate, or manage a pawnbroker or secondhand dealer establishment in Howard County; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">includes any renewal of a document described in item (i) of this paragraph.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">"Taxicab license":<section prefix="(i)">means a certificate, license, permit, or similar document that would allow a person to own, operate, or drive a taxicab in Howard County; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">includes any renewal of a document described in item (i) of this paragraph.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">This section does not apply to an applicant that:<section prefix="(1)">is a licensed massage therapist or registered massage practitioner under Title 3, Subtitle 5A of the Health Occupations Article; and</section><section prefix="(2)">is the owner, manager, or operator of a sole proprietorship or other massage therapy establishment in which each massage therapist is a licensed massage therapist or registered massage practitioner.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Howard County Department of Inspections, Licenses and Permits may request from the Central Repository a State and national criminal history records check on an applicant for:<section prefix="(1)">a massage establishment license;</section><section prefix="(2)">a pawnbroker or secondhand dealer establishment license; or</section><section prefix="(3)">a taxicab license.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">As part of the application for a criminal history records check, the Howard County Department of Inspections, Licenses and Permits shall submit to the Central Repository:<section prefix="(i)">two complete sets of the applicant's legible fingerprints taken on forms approved by the Director of the Central Repository and the Director of the Federal Bureau of Investigation;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the fee authorized under &#xA7; 10-221(b)(7) of this subtitle for access to Maryland criminal history records; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">the mandatory processing fee required by the Federal Bureau of Investigation for a national criminal history records check.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">In accordance with this subtitle, the Central Repository shall forward to the applicant and the Howard County Department of Inspections, Licenses and Permits the applicant's criminal history record information.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Information obtained from the Central Repository under this section:<section prefix="(i)">is confidential and may not be disseminated; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">may be used only for a license-related purpose concerning an applicant for a massage establishment license, a pawnbroker or secondhand dealer establishment license, or a taxicab license as authorized by this section.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The subject of a criminal history records check under this section may contest the contents of the printed statement issued by the Central Repository as provided under &#xA7; 10-223 of this subtitle.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The governing body of Howard County may adopt guidelines to carry out this section.</section>
  </text>
</law>
