<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcp" order_by="gcp" level="1">Criminal Procedure</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcp-15-415</section_number>
  <catch_line>This section applies only in Kent County....</catch_line>
  <order_by>415</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">This section applies only in Kent County.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The State's Attorney's salary is 80% of the salary of a judge of the District Court of Maryland.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The county commissioners shall set the State's Attorney's allowance for office expenses.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The State's Attorney shall submit expense vouchers to the county commissioners for approval and payment.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The State's Attorney has a special fund allowance of $4,000 for the costs of investigations.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">At the end of each fiscal year:<section prefix="1.">the State's Attorney shall account to the county commissioners for expenditures from the fund; and</section><section prefix="2.">any balance remaining in the fund shall revert to the general fund of the county.</section></section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The State's Attorney may employ one or more deputy State's Attorneys and assistant State's Attorneys who shall:<section prefix="(i)">serve at the pleasure of the State's Attorney; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">be members in good standing of the local bar.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The county commissioners shall set the salaries of the deputy and assistant State's Attorneys.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The State's Attorney may employ a criminal investigator who serves at the pleasure of the State's Attorney.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The State's Attorney may employ an administrative coordinator and other administrative and clerical staff that the State's Attorney considers necessary for the conduct of the office.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The county commissioners shall set the salaries of the criminal investigator, administrative coordinator, and administrative and clerical staff.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The State's Attorney shall serve full time and may not engage in the private practice of law.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Subject to the approval of the county commissioners, a deputy or assistant State's Attorney may engage in the private practice of law.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
