<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gcp" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="3-101" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcp-3-101</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this title the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Committed person" means a person committed to the Health Department as not criminally responsible under the test for criminal responsibility.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Court" means a court that has criminal jurisdiction.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">"Health Department" means the Department of Health and Mental Hygiene.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"Hospital warrant" means a legal document issued by a court that:<section prefix="(1)">authorizes any law enforcement officer in the State to apprehend a person who is alleged to have violated an order for conditional release and transport the person to a facility designated by the Health Department; and</section><section prefix="(2)">requires that the issuance of the warrant is entered in the person's criminal history record information of the criminal justice information system.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">"Incompetent to stand trial" means not able:<section prefix="(1)">to understand the nature or object of the proceeding; or</section><section prefix="(2)">to assist in one's defense.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Mental disorder" means a behavioral or emotional illness that results from a psychiatric or neurological disorder.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Mental disorder" includes a mental illness that so substantially impairs the mental or emotional functioning of a person as to make care or treatment necessary or advisable for the welfare of the person or for the safety of the person or property of another.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Mental disorder" does not include mental retardation.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(h)">"Office" means the Office of Administrative Hearings.</section>
  </text>
</law>
