<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcp" order_by="" level="1">Criminal Procedure</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcp-4-101</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>101</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">"Citation" means a written charging document that a police officer or fire marshal issues to a defendant, alleging the defendant has committed a crime.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">"Citation" does not include an indictment, information, or statement of charges.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Fire marshal" means:<section prefix="(i)">the State Fire Marshal;</section><section prefix="(ii)">a deputy State fire marshal; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">as designated under &#xA7; 6-304 of the Public Safety Article:<section prefix="1.">an assistant State fire marshal; or</section><section prefix="2.">a special assistant State fire marshal.</section></section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">"Police officer" has the meaning stated in &#xA7; 2-101 of this article.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Within areas of the National Park System, a United States Park Police officer may exercise the authority of a police officer to issue a citation under this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Subject to paragraph (2) of this subsection, in addition to any other law allowing a crime to be charged by citation, a police officer shall charge by citation for:<section prefix="(i)">any misdemeanor or local ordinance violation that does not carry a penalty of imprisonment;</section><section prefix="(ii)">any misdemeanor or local ordinance violation for which the maximum penalty of imprisonment is 90 days or less, except:<section prefix="1.">failure to comply with a peace order under &#xA7; 3-1508 of the Courts Article;</section><section prefix="2.">failure to comply with a protective order under &#xA7; 4-509 of the Family Law Article;</section><section prefix="3.">violation of a condition of pretrial or posttrial release while charged with a sexual crime against a minor under &#xA7; 5-213.1 of this article;</section><section prefix="4.">possession of an electronic control device after conviction of a drug felony or crime of violence under &#xA7; 4-109(b) of the Criminal Law Article;</section><section prefix="5.">violation of an out-of-state domestic violence order under &#xA7; 4-508.1 of the Family Law Article; or</section><section prefix="6.">abuse or neglect of an animal under &#xA7; 10-604 of the Criminal Law Article; or</section></section><section prefix="(iii)">possession of marijuana under &#xA7; 5-601 of the Criminal Law Article.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A police officer may charge a defendant by citation only if:<section prefix="(i)">the officer is satisfied with the defendant's evidence of identity;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the officer reasonably believes that the defendant will comply with the citation;</section><section prefix="(iii)">the officer reasonably believes that the failure to charge on a statement of charges will not pose a threat to public safety;</section><section prefix="(iv)">the defendant is not subject to arrest for another criminal charge arising out of the same incident; and</section><section prefix="(v)">the defendant complies with all lawful orders by the officer.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A police officer who has grounds to make a warrantless arrest for an offense that may be charged by citation under this subsection may:<section prefix="(i)">issue a citation in lieu of making the arrest; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">make the arrest and subsequently issue a citation in lieu of continued custody.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Subject to paragraph (2) of this subsection, in addition to any other law allowing a crime to be charged by citation, a fire marshal may issue a citation for:<section prefix="(i)">discharging fireworks without a permit under &#xA7; 10-104 or &#xA7; 10-110 of the Public Safety Article;</section><section prefix="(ii)">possessing with intent to discharge or allowing the discharge of fireworks under &#xA7; 10-104 or &#xA7; 10-110 of the Public Safety Article; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">maintaining a fire hazard under &#xA7; 6-317 of the Public Safety Article.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A fire marshal may issue a citation if the fire marshal is satisfied with the defendant's evidence of identity and reasonably believes that the defendant will comply with the citation.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This section does not apply to a citation that is:<section prefix="(i)">authorized for a violation of a parking ordinance or a regulation adopted by a State unit or political subdivision of the State under Title 26, Subtitle 3 of the Transportation Article;</section><section prefix="(ii)">authorized by the Department of Natural Resources under &#xA7; 1-205 of the Natural Resources Article; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">authorized by Baltimore City under &#xA7; 16-16A (special enforcement officers) of the Code of Public Local Laws of Baltimore City for violation of a code, ordinance, or public local law of Baltimore City concerning building, housing, health, fire, safety, zoning, or sanitation.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Except as otherwise expressly provided by law, the Chief Judge of the District Court shall prescribe a uniform, statewide form of a citation.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Except for the uniform motor vehicle citation form, the law enforcement agencies of the State, the United States Park Police, and the Office of the State Fire Marshal shall reimburse the District Court for printing the citation forms that law enforcement officers and the State Fire Marshal require.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
