<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcp" order_by="gcp" level="1">Criminal Procedure</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcp-10-208</section_number>
  <catch_line>The Advisory Board consists of the following 25 members:...</catch_line>
  <order_by>208</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Advisory Board consists of the following 25 members:<section prefix="(1)">one member of the Senate appointed by the President;</section><section prefix="(2)">one member of the House of Delegates appointed by the Speaker;</section><section prefix="(3)">three members from the Judicial Branch of State government appointed by the Chief Judge of the Court of Appeals;</section><section prefix="(4)">the Executive Director of the Governor's Office of Crime Control and Prevention;</section><section prefix="(5)">three members recommended by the Secretary;</section><section prefix="(6)">two members who are executive officials from State, county, or municipal police units;</section><section prefix="(7)">the Director of the Maryland Justice Analysis Center of the Department of Criminology and Criminal Justice of the University of Maryland;</section><section prefix="(8)">two elected county officials;</section><section prefix="(9)">the Attorney General;</section><section prefix="(10)">two elected officials from separate municipal corporations;</section><section prefix="(11)">one State's Attorney;</section><section prefix="(12)">one member of the State Council on Child Abuse and Neglect recommended by the Council chairperson;</section><section prefix="(13)">one representative of the Department of Health and Mental Hygiene recommended by the Secretary of Health and Mental Hygiene;</section><section prefix="(14)">one representative of the Department of Juvenile Services recommended by the Secretary of Juvenile Services;</section><section prefix="(15)">one representative from the Motor Vehicle Administration recommended by the Secretary of Transportation;</section><section prefix="(16)">the State Chief Information Officer;</section><section prefix="(17)">the Executive Director of the Governor's Office of Homeland Security; and</section><section prefix="(18)">one member from the public.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Except for ex officio members and members appointed by the President of the Senate, the Speaker of the House of Delegates, or the Chief Judge of the Court of Appeals, the Governor shall appoint the members of the Advisory Board.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Governor shall designate a member of the Advisory Board as the Chairman.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Subject to &#xA7; 10-209 of this subtitle, the term of a member is 3 years.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">At the end of a term, a member continues to serve until a successor is appointed and qualifies.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A member who is appointed after a term has begun serves only for the rest of the term and until a successor is appointed and qualifies.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except for the member of the Advisory Board from the public, each member may designate a person to represent the member at any meeting or other activity of the Advisory Board.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A person designated by a member under paragraph (1) of this subsection may vote on behalf of the member.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
