<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcp" order_by="" level="1">Criminal Procedure</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcp-15-416</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>416</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">This section applies only in Montgomery County.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The County Council shall set the salary of the State's Attorney.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Subject to approval by the County Council, the State's Attorney is entitled a reasonable expense allowance for the operation of the office and performance of the duties of the State's Attorney.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The State's Attorney may appoint two deputy State's Attorneys and the number of assistant State's Attorneys that the County Council approves.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Each deputy and assistant State's Attorney is:<section prefix="(i)">subject to the exclusive control of the State's Attorney; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">entitled to the same benefits as a county employee under the merit system.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The deputy and assistant State's Attorneys:<section prefix="(i)">shall perform the work directed by the State's Attorney or authorized by law; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">under the direction of the State's Attorney, may present cases to the grand jury, sign indictments and criminal informations, and perform other necessary duties relating to the grand jury and the operation of the office.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">
        <section prefix="(i)">In addition to the assistant State's Attorneys appointed in accordance with paragraph (1) of this subsection, the State's Attorney may file a petition in circuit court for authority to appoint additional assistant State's Attorneys.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The State's Attorney shall:<section prefix="1.">include the reasons for the appointment in the petition; and</section><section prefix="2.">deliver notice of the petition to the County Executive and County Council.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">The County Executive and County Council may file a response to each petition.</section>
        <section prefix="(iv)">The county shall pay the salary and expenses of an assistant State's Attorney appointed under this paragraph.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The State's Attorney may appoint the number of special investigators approved by the County Council.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">In addition to the special investigators appointed in accordance with paragraph (1) of this subsection, the State's Attorney may file a petition in circuit court for authority to appoint additional special investigators.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The State's Attorney shall:<section prefix="1.">include the reasons for the appointment in the petition; and</section><section prefix="2.">deliver notice of the petition to the County Executive and County Council.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">The County Executive and County Council may file a response to each petition.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The county shall pay the salary and expenses of a special investigator appointed under this subsection.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">A special investigator appointed under this subsection:<section prefix="(i)">is directly under the supervision of the State's Attorney; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">shall perform each duty designated by the State's Attorney.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(5)">A special investigator appointed under this subsection is:<section prefix="(i)">subject to the exclusive control of the State's Attorney; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">entitled to the same benefits as a county employee under the merit system.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The State's Attorney may appoint the number of administrative assistants, clerks, administrative aides, paralegal interns, and other staff that the County Council approves.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The employees appointed under this subsection are:<section prefix="(i)">subject to the exclusive control of the State's Attorney; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">entitled to the same benefits as county employees under the merit system.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The State's Attorney, deputy State's Attorneys, and assistant State's Attorneys shall serve full time and may not engage in the private practice of law.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A special investigator shall serve full time and may not engage in other employment.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
