<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcp" order_by="gcp" level="1">Criminal Procedure</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcp-11-707</section_number>
  <catch_line>A tier I sex offender and a tier II sex offender shall register in person every 6 months with a loca...</catch_line>
  <order_by>707</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">A tier I sex offender and a tier II sex offender shall register in person every 6 months with a local law enforcement unit for the term provided under paragraph (4) of this subsection.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">Registration shall include a digital image that shall be updated every 6 months.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">A tier III sex offender shall register in person every 3 months with a local law enforcement unit for the term provided under paragraph (4) of this subsection.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">Registration shall include a digital image that shall be updated every 6 months.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">A sexually violent predator shall register in person every 3 months with a local law enforcement unit for the term provided under paragraph (4) of this subsection.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">Registration shall include a digital image that shall be updated every 6 months.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(4)">Subject to subsection (c) of this section, the term of registration is:<section prefix="(i)">15 years, if the registrant is a tier I sex offender;</section><section prefix="(ii)">25 years, if the registrant is a tier II sex offender;</section><section prefix="(iii)">the life of the registrant, if the registrant is a tier III sex offender; or</section><section prefix="(iv)">up to 5 years, if the registrant is a person described under &#xA7; 11-704(c)(1) of this subtitle, subject to reduction by the juvenile court on the filing of a petition by the registrant for a reduction in the term of registration.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(5)">A registrant who is not a resident of the State shall register for the appropriate time specified in this subsection or until the registrant's employment, student enrollment, or transient status in the State ends.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A term of registration described in this section shall be computed from:<section prefix="(1)">the last date of release;</section><section prefix="(2)">the date granted probation;</section><section prefix="(3)">the date granted a suspended sentence; or</section><section prefix="(4)">the date the juvenile court's jurisdiction over the registrant terminates under &#xA7; 3-8A-07 of the Courts Article if the registrant was a minor who lived in the State at the time the act was committed for which registration is required.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The term of registration for a tier I sex offender shall be reduced to 10 years if, in the 10 years following the date on which the registrant was required to register, the registrant:<section prefix="(1)">is not convicted of any offense for which a term of imprisonment of more than 1 year may be imposed;</section><section prefix="(2)">is not convicted of any sex offense;</section><section prefix="(3)">successfully completes, without revocation, any period of supervised release, parole, or probation; and</section><section prefix="(4)">successfully completes an appropriate sex offender treatment program.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
