<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcp" order_by="gcp" level="1">Criminal Procedure</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcp-3-120</section_number>
  <catch_line>If at any time the Health Department considers that a committed person is eligible for conditional r...</catch_line>
  <order_by>120</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If at any time the Health Department considers that a committed person is eligible for conditional release, the Health Department may apply for the conditional release to the court that committed the person.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Health Department shall send a copy of the application for conditional release:<section prefix="(i)">to the committed person;</section><section prefix="(ii)">to counsel for the committed person; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">to the State's Attorney, by certified mail, return receipt requested.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Within 30 days after receipt of the application from the Health Department, the court shall issue an order that is in accordance with &#xA7; 3-114 of this title for:<section prefix="(1)">continued commitment; or</section><section prefix="(2)">conditional release under the conditions it imposes after giving consideration to the recommendations of specific conditions from the Health Department.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">If the court orders a conditional release of the committed person under this section, the committed person, the State's Attorney, or the Health Department may apply for a revocation, change, or extension under &#xA7; 3-122 of this title.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">An appeal from a District Court order shall be on the record in circuit court.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">An appeal from a circuit court order shall be by application for leave to appeal to the Court of Special Appeals.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
