<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcp" order_by="" level="1">Criminal Procedure</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcp-15-409</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>409</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">This section applies only in Charles County.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The State's Attorney's salary is equal to the salary of a circuit court judge.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Subject to the approval of the county commissioners, the State's Attorney is entitled to reimbursement for reasonable expenses incurred during the performance of the duties of the office.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The State's Attorney may appoint deputy State's Attorneys and assistant State's Attorneys.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Subject to the approval of the county commissioners and paragraph (3) of this subsection, the State's Attorney shall set the salary for positions appointed under this subsection.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The salary of an assistant State's Attorney may not exceed the salary of the State's Attorney.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The deputy and assistant State's Attorneys:<section prefix="(i)">shall serve at the pleasure of the State's Attorney;</section><section prefix="(ii)">	shall perform work as directed by the State's Attorney or as authorized by law; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">may present cases to the grand jury, sign indictments and criminal informations, and perform other functions necessary to operate the office.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The State's Attorney may appoint clerical, administrative, investigative, and other staff that the State's Attorney considers necessary for the proper conduct of the office.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Subject to the approval of the county commissioners, the State's Attorney shall set the salaries for the employees appointed under this subsection.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">An employee appointed under this subsection is entitled to the same benefits as a county employee.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The State's Attorney:<section prefix="(i)">shall serve full time; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">except in connection with performing the duties of the office, may not:<section prefix="1.">appear as counsel or represent any party before a court or unit of the State or a political subdivision of the State; or</section><section prefix="2.">otherwise engage in the private practice of law.</section></section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A deputy State's Attorney shall serve full time and may not engage in the private practice of law.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">An assistant State's Attorney may serve full time or part time and may not engage in the private practice of criminal law.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
