<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gcp" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="10-216" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcp-10-216</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, "law enforcement unit" means:<section prefix="(1)">a State, county, or municipal police unit; or</section><section prefix="(2)">a sheriff's office.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If a defendant was not fingerprinted at the time of arrest for the sentenced crime, the sentencing judge shall order the defendant to be fingerprinted by the appropriate and available law enforcement unit when the defendant:<section prefix="(i)">is found guilty or pleads guilty or nolo contendere to a crime that is reportable as criminal history record information under this subtitle; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">is sentenced to commitment in a local correctional facility or receives a suspended sentence, probation, probation before judgment under &#xA7; 6-220 of this article, or a fine.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If the defendant cannot be fingerprinted at the time of sentencing, the sentencing judge shall order the defendant to report to a designated law enforcement unit to be fingerprinted within 3 days after the date of the sentencing.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">If a defendant fails to report to the designated law enforcement unit as ordered under subsection (b)(2) of this section, the defendant is in contempt of court.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This subsection only applies to an adjudication of delinquency of a child:<section prefix="(i)">for an act described in &#xA7; 3-8A-03(d)(1) of the Courts Article if the child is at least 14 years old; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">for an act described in &#xA7; 3-8A-03(d)(4) or (5) of the Courts Article if the child is at least 16 years old.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If a child has not been previously fingerprinted as a result of arrest for the delinquent act, the court that held the disposition hearing of the child adjudicated delinquent shall order the child to be fingerprinted by the appropriate and available law enforcement unit.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">If the child cannot be fingerprinted at the time of the disposition hearing held under paragraph (2) of this subsection, the court shall order the child to report to a designated law enforcement unit to be fingerprinted within 3 days after making a disposition on an adjudication of delinquency.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
