<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gcp" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="3-119" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcp-3-119</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Not earlier than 1 year after the initial release hearing ends or was waived, and not more than once a year thereafter, a committed person may apply for release under either subsection (b) or (c) of this section, but not both.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Notwithstanding the time restrictions in paragraph (1) of this subsection, a committed person may file an application for release at any time if the application is accompanied by an affidavit of a physician or licensed psychologist that states an improvement in the mental condition of the committed person since the last hearing.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">To apply for release under this subsection, the committed person shall file an application for release with the Health Department and notify the court and State's Attorney, in writing, of this request.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The provisions of this title governing administrative hearing and judicial determination of eligibility for release apply to any application for release under this subsection.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">To apply for release under this subsection, the committed person shall file a petition for release with the court that ordered commitment.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The committed person shall send a copy of the petition for release to the Health Department and the State's Attorney.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">If the committed person requests a trial by jury, the trial shall be held in a circuit court with a jury as in a civil action at law.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The trier of fact shall:<section prefix="(i)">determine whether the committed person has proved eligibility for release by a preponderance of the evidence; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">render a verdict for:</section></section>
      <section prefix="(5)">If the trier of fact renders a verdict for conditional release, within 30 days after the verdict, the court shall release the committed person under conditions it imposes in accordance with specific recommendations for conditions under &#xA7; 3-116(b) of this title.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">An appeal from a District Court order shall be on the record in the circuit court.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">An appeal from a circuit court order shall be by application for leave to appeal to the Court of Special Appeals.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
