<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcp" order_by="" level="1">Criminal Procedure</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcp-10-109</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>109</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Disclosure of expunged information about criminal charges in an application, interview, or other means may not be required:<section prefix="(i)">by an employer or educational institution of a person who applies for employment or admission; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">by a unit, official, or employee of the State or a political subdivision of the State of a person who applies for a license, permit, registration, or governmental service.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A person need not refer to or give information concerning an expunged charge when answering a question concerning:<section prefix="(i)">a criminal charge that did not result in a conviction; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">a conviction that the Governor pardoned.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Refusal by a person to disclose information about criminal charges that have been expunged may not be the sole reason for:<section prefix="(i)">an employer to discharge or refuse to hire the person; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">a unit, official, or employee of the State or a political subdivision of the State to deny the person's application.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A person who violates this section is guilty of a misdemeanor and on conviction is subject to a fine not exceeding $1,000 or imprisonment not exceeding 1 year or both for each violation.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">In addition to the penalties provided in paragraph (1) of this subsection, an official or employee of the State or a political subdivision of the State who is convicted under this section may be removed or dismissed from public service.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
