<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcp" order_by="" level="1">Criminal Procedure</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcp-12-103</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>103</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Property or an interest in property described in &#xA7; 12-102(a)(4), (10), and (11) of this subtitle may not be forfeited if the owner establishes by a preponderance of the evidence that the violation of the Controlled Dangerous Substances law was committed without the owner's actual knowledge.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A conveyance used as a common carrier or vehicle for hire in the transaction of business as a common carrier or vehicle for hire may not be seized or forfeited under this title unless it appears that the owner or other person in charge of the conveyance was a consenting party or privy to a violation of the Controlled Dangerous Substances law.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A conveyance may not be forfeited under this title for an act or omission that the owner shows was committed or omitted by a person other than the owner while the person other than the owner possessed the conveyance in criminal violation of federal law or the law of any state.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">An owner's interest in real property may not be forfeited for a violation of &#xA7; 5-601, &#xA7; 5-619, or &#xA7; 5-620 of the Criminal Law Article.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, real property used as the principal family residence may not be forfeited under this subtitle unless one of the owners of the real property was convicted of a violation of &#xA7;&#xA7; 5-602 through 5-609, &#xA7;&#xA7; 5-612 through 5-614, &#xA7; 5-617, &#xA7; 5-618, or &#xA7; 5-628 of the Criminal Law Article or of an attempt or conspiracy to violate Title 5 of the Criminal Law Article.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Without a conviction, a court may order a forfeiture of real property used as the principal family residence if the owner of the family residence:<section prefix="(i)">fails to appear for a required court appearance; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">fails to surrender to the jurisdiction of the court within 180 days after the required court appearance.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">Real property used as the principal family residence by a husband and wife and held by the husband and wife as tenants by the entirety may not be forfeited unless:<section prefix="(1)">the property was used in connection with a violation of &#xA7;&#xA7; 5-602 through 5-609, &#xA7;&#xA7; 5-612 through 5-614, &#xA7; 5-617, &#xA7; 5-618, or &#xA7; 5-628 of the Criminal Law Article or with an attempt or conspiracy to violate Title 5 of the Criminal Law Article; and</section><section prefix="(2)">both the husband and wife are convicted of a violation of &#xA7;&#xA7; 5-602 through 5-609, &#xA7;&#xA7; 5-612 through 5-614, &#xA7; 5-617, &#xA7; 5-618, or &#xA7; 5-628 of the Criminal Law Article or of an attempt or conspiracy to violate Title 5 of the Criminal Law Article.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
