<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcp" order_by="" level="1">Criminal Procedure</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcp-4-202.2</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>202.2</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">At sentencing, a court exercising criminal jurisdiction in a case involving a child shall determine whether to transfer jurisdiction to the juvenile court if:<section prefix="(1)">as a result of trial or a plea entered under Maryland Rule 4-242, all charges that excluded jurisdiction from the juvenile court under &#xA7; 3-8A-03(d)(1) or (4) of the Courts Article do not result in a finding of guilty; and</section><section prefix="(2)"><section prefix="(i)">pretrial transfer was prohibited under &#xA7; 4-202(c)(3) of this subtitle; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">the court did not transfer jurisdiction after a hearing under &#xA7; 4-202(b) of this subtitle.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">In determining whether to transfer jurisdiction under subsection (a) of this section, the court shall consider:<section prefix="(1)">the age of the child;</section><section prefix="(2)">the mental and physical condition of the child;</section><section prefix="(3)">the amenability of the child to treatment in an institution, facility, or program available to delinquent children;</section><section prefix="(4)">the nature of the child's acts as proven in the trial or admitted to in a plea entered under Maryland Rule 4-242; and</section><section prefix="(5)">public safety.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The court may not consider transferring jurisdiction to the juvenile court under this section if:<section prefix="(1)">under the terms of a plea agreement entered under Maryland Rule 4-243, the child agrees that jurisdiction is not to be transferred; or</section><section prefix="(2)">pretrial transfer was prohibited under &#xA7; 4-202(c)(1) or (2) of this subtitle.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A victim or victim's representative shall be given notice of the transfer hearing as provided under &#xA7; 11-104 of this article.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">A victim or victim's representative may submit a victim impact statement to the court as provided in &#xA7; 11-402 of this article.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">This paragraph does not preclude a victim or victim's representative who has not filed a notification request form under &#xA7; 11-104 of this article from submitting a victim impact statement to the court.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">The court shall consider a victim impact statement in determining whether to transfer jurisdiction under this section.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If the court transfers its jurisdiction to the juvenile court, the court shall conduct a disposition under the regular procedures of the juvenile court.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The record of the hearing and of the disposition shall be transferred to the juvenile court, subject to &#xA7; 3-8A-27 of the Courts Article.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
