<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcp" order_by="" level="1">Criminal Procedure</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcp-11-104</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>104</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Victim" means a person who suffers actual or threatened physical, emotional, or financial harm as a direct result of a crime or delinquent act.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Victim's representative" includes a family member or guardian of a victim who is:<section prefix="(i)">a minor;</section><section prefix="(ii)">deceased; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">disabled.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">On first contact with a victim or victim's representative, a law enforcement officer, District Court commissioner, or juvenile intake officer shall give the victim or the victim's representative the pamphlet described in &#xA7; 11-914(9)(i) of this title.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Within 10 days after the filing or the unsealing of an indictment or information in circuit court, whichever is later, the prosecuting attorney shall:<section prefix="(i)">mail or deliver to the victim or victim's representative the pamphlet described in &#xA7; 11-914(9)(ii) of this title and the notification request form described in &#xA7; 11-914(10) of this title; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">certify to the clerk of the court that the prosecuting attorney has complied with this paragraph or is unable to identify the victim or victim's representative.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If the prosecuting attorney files a petition alleging that a child is delinquent for committing an act that could only be tried in the circuit court if committed by an adult, the prosecuting attorney shall:<section prefix="(i)">inform the victim or victim's representative of the right to request restitution under &#xA7; 11-606 of this title;</section><section prefix="(ii)">mail or deliver to the victim or victim's representative the notification request form described in &#xA7; 11-914(10) of this title; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">certify to the clerk of the juvenile court that the prosecuting attorney has complied with this paragraph or is unable to identify the victim or victim's representative.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">For cases described under this subsection, the prosecuting attorney may provide a State's witness in the case with the guidelines for victims, victims' representatives, and witnesses available under &#xA7;&#xA7; 11-1001 through 11-1004 of this title.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A victim or victim's representative may file a completed notification request form with the prosecuting attorney.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The prosecuting attorney shall send a copy of the completed notification request form to the clerk of the circuit court or juvenile court.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">By filing a completed notification request form, a victim or victim's representative complies with Article 47 of the Maryland Declaration of Rights and each provision of the Code that requires a victim or victim's representative to request notice.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">To keep the address of a victim or victim's representative confidential, the victim or victim's representative shall designate in the notification request form a person who has agreed to receive notice for the victim or victim's representative.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The prosecuting attorney shall send a victim or victim's representative prior notice of each court proceeding in the case, of the terms of any plea agreement, and of the right of the victim or victim's representative to submit a victim impact statement to the court under &#xA7; 11-402 of this title if:<section prefix="(i)">prior notice is practicable; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">the victim or victim's representative has filed a notification request form under subsection (d) of this section.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If the case is in a jurisdiction in which the office of the clerk of the circuit court or juvenile court has an automated filing system, the prosecuting attorney may ask the clerk to send the notice required by paragraph (1) of this subsection.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">As soon after a proceeding as practicable, the prosecuting attorney shall tell the victim or victim's representative of the terms of any plea agreement, judicial action, and proceeding that affects the interests of the victim or victim's representative, including a bail hearing, change in the defendant's pretrial release order, dismissal, nolle prosequi, stetting of charges, trial, disposition, and postsentencing court proceeding if:<section prefix="(i)">the victim or victim's representative has filed a notification request form under subsection (d) of this section and prior notice to the victim or victim's representative is not practicable; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">the victim or victim's representative is not present at the proceeding.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">Whether or not the victim or victim's representative has filed a notification request form under subsection (d) of this section, the prosecuting attorney may give the victim or victim's representative information about the status of the case if the victim or victim's representative asks for the information.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">If a victim or victim's representative has filed a notification request form under subsection (d) of this section, the clerk of the circuit court or juvenile court:<section prefix="(1)">shall include a copy of the form with any commitment order or probation order that is passed; and</section><section prefix="(2)">if an appeal is filed, shall send a copy of the form to the Attorney General and the court to which the case has been appealed.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(g)">This section does not prohibit a victim or victim's representative from filing a notification request form with a unit to which a defendant or child respondent has been committed.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">After filing a notification request form under subsection (d) of this section, a victim or victim's representative may discontinue further notices by filing a written request with:<section prefix="(1)">the prosecuting attorney, if the case is still in a circuit court or juvenile court; or</section><section prefix="(2)">the unit to which the defendant or child respondent has been committed, if a commitment order has been issued in the case.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
