<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcp" order_by="gcp" level="1">Criminal Procedure</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcp-4-201</section_number>
  <catch_line>In the District Court, a prosecution for a crime shall be brought in the district that includes the ...</catch_line>
  <order_by>201</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In the District Court, a prosecution for a crime shall be brought in the district that includes the county where the crime was committed, and the trial shall be held in that county unless the case is lawfully removed.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">If a person is feloniously stricken or poisoned in a county and dies in another county of the same stroke or poison, a prosecution for the felony shall be brought in the county where the stroke or poison was given.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A prosecution may be brought in the county in which the defendant is arrested or first brought if the prosecution is for:<section prefix="(1)">a crime committed on the waters of the Chesapeake Bay and not in a county;</section><section prefix="(2)">aiding, abetting, or comforting the perpetrator of such a crime; or</section><section prefix="(3)">being an accessory to such a crime.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">If a person is feloniously stricken or poisoned on the waters of the Chesapeake Bay and not in a county, and dies of the same stroke or poison in a county, a prosecution for the felony, or for being an accessory to the felony, shall be brought in the county where the person died.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">If a person is feloniously stricken or poisoned in a county, and dies of the same stroke or poison on the waters of the Chesapeake Bay and not in a county, a prosecution for the felony, or for being an accessory to the felony, shall be brought in the county where the stroke or poison was given.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this subsection, "common carrier" means a steamboat, railroad train, motor bus, airplane, or other means of intercity or interstate public transportation.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Subject to paragraph (3) of this subsection, a prosecution for an indictable crime committed on a common carrier may be brought, and a District Court commissioner may hold the defendant to bail if the crime is bailable, in any county from, to, or through which the common carrier runs.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">If the accused is held to bail under this subsection by a District Court commissioner, prosecution for the crime shall be in the county where the defendant is held.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A prosecution for a crime may be brought in the county in which process for the arrest and prosecution of the defendant is first issued if:<section prefix="(i)">the crime was committed at the boundary between counties; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">the boundary is so uncertain or the site of the crime is so near to the boundary that it is doubtful in which county the crime was committed.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">To establish the venue alleged in the charging document, the State need only prove that a set of facts in paragraph (1)(i) or (ii) of this subsection is true.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(h)">Except as otherwise provided by law, a prosecution of a person for being an accessory after the fact to murder or other felony shall be brought in the county in which the person became an accessory.</section>
  </text>
</law>
