<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcp" order_by="" level="1">Criminal Procedure</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcp-15-407</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>407</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">This section applies only in Carroll County.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The State's Attorney's salary is 80% of the salary of a judge of the District Court of Maryland.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">A salary increase shall take effect at the beginning of the elected term of office and may not increase during the term of office.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The county commissioners shall:<section prefix="(i)">provide space for the offices of the State's Attorney and pay the expenses of the office, including general operating expenses, equipment costs, and reasonable costs for secretarial or stenographic needs; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">as determined by the county commissioners, pay a reasonable allowance to reimburse the State's Attorney for the costs of the operation of the office.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The State's Attorney:<section prefix="(i)">may appoint two deputy State's Attorneys and the number of assistant State's Attorneys necessary to staff the office; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">subject to the approval of the county commissioners, shall set the salaries for the deputy and assistant State's Attorneys.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">In addition to the assistant State's Attorneys appointed under paragraph (1) of this subsection, if both the State's Attorney and the resident judge of the circuit court of the county consider it necessary and the judge approves, the State's Attorney may appoint an assistant State's Attorney.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The county commissioners shall set the salary of an assistant State's Attorney appointed under this paragraph.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The State's Attorney shall serve full time.</section>
  </text>
</law>
