<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcp" order_by="gcp" level="1">Criminal Procedure</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcp-11-403</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this section, "sentencing or disposition hearing" means a hearing at which the imposition of a se...</catch_line>
  <order_by>403</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, "sentencing or disposition hearing" means a hearing at which the imposition of a sentence, disposition in a juvenile court proceeding, or alteration of a sentence or disposition in a juvenile court proceeding is considered.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">In the sentencing or disposition hearing the court:<section prefix="(1)">if practicable, shall allow the victim or the victim's representative to address the court under oath before the imposition of sentence or other disposition:<section prefix="(i)">at the request of the prosecuting attorney; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">if the victim has filed a notification request form under &#xA7; 11-104 of this title; and</section></section><section prefix="(2)">may allow the victim or the victim's representative to address the court under oath before the imposition of sentence or other disposition at the request of the victim or the victim's representative.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If the victim or the victim's representative is allowed to address the court, the defendant or child respondent may cross-examine the victim or the victim's representative.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The cross-examination is limited to the factual statements made to the court.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A victim or the victim's representative has the right not to address the court at the sentencing or disposition hearing.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A person may not attempt to coerce a victim or the victim's representative to address the court at the sentencing or disposition hearing.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If the victim or the victim's representative fails to appear at a hearing on a motion for a revision, modification, or reduction of a sentence or disposition in circuit court or juvenile court, the prosecuting attorney shall state on the record that proceeding without the appearance of the victim or the victim's representative is justified because:<section prefix="(i)">the victim or victim's representative was contacted by the prosecuting attorney and waived the right to attend the hearing;</section><section prefix="(ii)">efforts were made to contact the victim or the victim's representative and, to the best knowledge and belief of the prosecuting attorney, the victim or victim's representative cannot be located; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">the victim or victim's representative has not filed a notification request form under &#xA7; 11-104 of this title.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If the court is not satisfied by the statement that proceeding without the appearance of the victim or the victim's representative is justified, or, if no statement is made, the court may postpone the hearing.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">A victim or victim's representative who has been denied a right provided under this section may file an application for leave to appeal in the manner provided under &#xA7; 11-103 of this title.</section>
  </text>
</law>
