<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcp" order_by="" level="1">Criminal Procedure</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcp-10-105</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>105</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">A person who has been charged with the commission of a crime, including a violation of the Transportation Article for which a term of imprisonment may be imposed, or who has been charged with a civil offense or infraction, except a juvenile offense, as a substitute for a criminal charge may file a petition listing relevant facts for expungement of a police record, court record, or other record maintained by the State or a political subdivision of the State if:<section prefix="(1)">the person is acquitted;</section><section prefix="(2)">the charge is otherwise dismissed;</section><section prefix="(3)">a probation before judgment is entered, unless the person is charged with a violation of &#xA7; 21-902 of the Transportation Article or Title 2, Subtitle 5 or &#xA7; 3-211 of the Criminal Law Article;</section><section prefix="(4)">a nolle prosequi or nolle prosequi with the requirement of drug or alcohol treatment is entered;</section><section prefix="(5)">the court indefinitely postpones trial of a criminal charge by marking the criminal charge "stet" or stet with the requirement of drug or alcohol abuse treatment on the docket;</section><section prefix="(6)">the case is compromised under &#xA7; 3-207 of the Criminal Law Article;</section><section prefix="(7)">the charge was transferred to the juvenile court under &#xA7; 4-202 of this article;</section><section prefix="(8)">the person:<section prefix="(i)">is convicted of only one criminal act, and that act is not a crime of violence; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">is granted a full and unconditional pardon by the Governor;or</section></section><section prefix="(9)">the person was convicted of a crime under any State or local law that prohibits:<section prefix="(i)">urination or defecation in a public place;</section><section prefix="(ii)">panhandling or soliciting money;</section><section prefix="(iii)">drinking an alcoholic beverage in a public place;</section><section prefix="(iv)">obstructing the free passage of another in a public place or a public conveyance;</section><section prefix="(v)">sleeping on or in park structures, such as benches or doorways;</section><section prefix="(vi)">loitering;</section><section prefix="(vii)">vagrancy;</section><section prefix="(viii)">riding a transit vehicle without paying the applicable fare or exhibiting proof of payment; or</section><section prefix="(ix)">except for carrying or possessing an explosive, acid, concealed weapon, or other dangerous article as provided in &#xA7; 7-705(b)(6) of the Transportation Article, any of the acts specified in &#xA7; 7-705 of the Transportation Article.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(a-1)">A person's attorney or personal representative may file a petition, on behalf of the person, for expungement under this section if the person died before disposition of the charge by nolle prosequi or dismissal.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in paragraphs (2) and (3) of this subsection, a person shall file a petition in the court in which the proceeding began.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If the proceeding began in one court and was transferred to another court, the person shall file the petition in the court to which the proceeding was transferred.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">If the proceeding in a court of original jurisdiction was appealed to a court exercising appellate jurisdiction, the person shall file the petition in the appellate court.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The appellate court may remand the matter to the court of original jurisdiction.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, a petition for expungement based on an acquittal, a nolle prosequi, or a dismissal may not be filed within 3 years after the disposition, unless the petitioner files with the petition a written general waiver and release of all the petitioner's tort claims arising from the charge.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A petition for expungement based on a probation before judgment or a stet with the requirement of drug or alcohol abuse treatment may not be filed earlier than the later of:<section prefix="(i)">the date the petitioner was discharged from probation or the requirements of obtaining drug or alcohol abuse treatment were completed; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">3 years after the probation was granted or stet with the requirement of drug or alcohol abuse treatment was entered on the docket.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A petition for expungement based on a nolle prosequi with the requirement of drug or alcohol treatment may not be filed until the completion of the required treatment.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">A petition for expungement based on a full and unconditional pardon by the Governor may not be filed later than 10 years after the pardon was signed by the Governor.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">Except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, a petition for expungement based on a stet or a compromise under &#xA7; 3-207 of the Criminal Law Article may not be filed within 3 years after the stet or compromise.</section>
      <section prefix="(6)">A petition for expungement based on the conviction of a crime under subsection (a)(9) of this section may not be filed within 3 years after the conviction or satisfactory completion of the sentence, including probation, that was imposed for the conviction, whichever is later.</section>
      <section prefix="(7)">A court may grant a petition for expungement at any time on a showing of good cause.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The court shall have a copy of a petition for expungement served on the State's Attorney.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Unless the State's Attorney files an objection to the petition for expungement within 30 days after the petition is served, the court shall pass an order requiring the expungement of all police records and court records about the charge.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If the State's Attorney files a timely objection to the petition, the court shall hold a hearing.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If the court at the hearing finds that the person is entitled to expungement, the court shall order the expungement of all police records and court records about the charge.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">If the court finds that the person is not entitled to expungement, the court shall deny the petition.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The person is not entitled to expungement if:<section prefix="(i)">the petition is based on the entry of probation before judgment, a nolle prosequi, a stet, including a nolle prosequi with the requirement of drug or alcohol treatment or a stet with the requirement of drug or alcohol abuse treatment, a conviction for a crime specified in subsection (a)(9) of this section, or the grant of a pardon by the Governor; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">the person:<section prefix="1.">since the full and unconditional pardon, entry, or conviction has been convicted of a crime other than a minor traffic violation; or</section><section prefix="2.">is a defendant in a pending criminal proceeding.</section></section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">Unless an order is stayed pending an appeal, within 60 days after entry of the order, every custodian of the police records and court records that are subject to the order of expungement shall advise in writing the court and the person who is seeking expungement of compliance with the order.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The State's Attorney is a party to the proceeding.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A party aggrieved by the decision of the court is entitled to appellate review as provided in the Courts Article.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
