<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcp" order_by="gcp" level="1">Criminal Procedure</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcp-11-617</section_number>
  <catch_line>If a court issues a judgment of restitution under &#xA7; 11-603 of this subtitle, the court may enter an...</catch_line>
  <order_by>617</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If a court issues a judgment of restitution under &#xA7; 11-603 of this subtitle, the court may enter an immediate and continuing earnings withholding order in an amount sufficient to pay the restitution.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The court may enter the order:<section prefix="(i)">at the sentencing or disposition hearing;</section><section prefix="(ii)">when the defendant or child respondent is placed on work release or probation; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">when the payment of restitution is overdue.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Subject to federal law, the order of priority of execution of an earnings withholding order is:<section prefix="(1)">first, an earnings withholding order issued under &#xA7; 10-128 of the Family Law Article;</section><section prefix="(2)">second, an earnings withholding order issued under this section; and</section><section prefix="(3)">lastly, any other lien or legal process.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This subsection applies whenever a court orders an earnings withholding order under this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">On entry of the order, the clerk of the court immediately shall:<section prefix="(i)">serve a copy on any current or subsequent employer of the restitution obligor, if known; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">mail a copy to the restitution obligor at the last known address or place of incarceration or commitment of the restitution obligor.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A restitution obligor immediately shall notify the court, the Central Collection Unit, and the Division or Department of Juvenile Services of:<section prefix="(i)">any objection to an earnings withholding order;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the current home address of the restitution obligor;</section><section prefix="(iii)">the name of the employer;</section><section prefix="(iv)">the work address of the restitution obligor; and</section><section prefix="(v)">any change of employer, home address, or work address of the restitution obligor.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">An employer who is served with an earnings withholding order under this section immediately shall notify the court, the Central Collection Unit, and the Division or Department of Juvenile Services of:<section prefix="(i)">any justification for the employer's inability to comply with the earnings withholding order;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the home address of the restitution obligor on the termination of employment;</section><section prefix="(iii)">information regarding the new place of employment of the restitution obligor; or</section><section prefix="(iv)">the employer's reemployment of the restitution obligor.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(5)">Unless the information has been provided to the court, the Division, Department of Juvenile Services, or the Central Collection Unit shall notify the court of a current or subsequent home address of the restitution obligor and the employer and work address of the restitution obligor.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as otherwise provided in this section, an earnings withholding order issued under this section shall:<section prefix="(i)">comply with the requirements of &#xA7;&#xA7; 10-128(a) and 10-129(a) through (c) of the Family Law Article; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">set forth the obligations and responsibilities of an employer and a restitution obligor under an earnings withholding order and the consequences of violating this section.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Each amount withheld in an earnings withholding order under this section is payable to the Division, Department of Juvenile Services, or Central Collection Unit.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">An earnings withholding order is binding on each present and future employer of the restitution obligor who is served with the order.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Subject to paragraphs (2) and (3) of this subsection, the payment amount under an earnings withholding order under this section is 20% of the earnings of a restitution obligor less other deductions required by law to be paid out of any funds earned under a work release plan.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If the restitution obligation of the restitution obligor is overdue, the court may impose a payment exceeding the amount allowed in paragraph (1) of this subsection.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The amount of an earnings withholding order issued under this section may not exceed the limits of the federal Consumer Credit Protection Act.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The court shall reduce an amount of an earnings withholding order that exceeds the limits of the federal Consumer Credit Protection Act to the maximum allowed under the Act.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This subsection applies to a restitution obligor and the employer of a restitution obligor.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A person who violates this section is subject to a fine not exceeding $250.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A fine collected under this section shall be distributed in the same way as costs are distributed under &#xA7; 7-409 of the Courts Article.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">In addition to a fine imposed under this subsection, an employer is liable for damages for the failure to deduct the earnings of a restitution obligor or failure to make a timely payment as required in the earnings withholding order.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
