<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcp" order_by="" level="1">Criminal Procedure</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcp-8-301</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>301</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">A person charged by indictment or criminal information with a crime triable in circuit court and convicted of that crime may, at any time, file a petition for writ of actual innocence in the circuit court for the county in which the conviction was imposed if the person claims that there is newly discovered evidence that:<section prefix="(1)">creates a substantial or significant possibility that the result may have been different, as that standard has been judicially determined; and</section><section prefix="(2)">could not have been discovered in time to move for a new trial under Maryland Rule 4-331.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A petition filed under this section shall:<section prefix="(1)">be in writing;</section><section prefix="(2)">state in detail the grounds on which the petition is based;</section><section prefix="(3)">describe the newly discovered evidence;</section><section prefix="(4)">contain or be accompanied by a request for hearing if a hearing is sought; and</section><section prefix="(5)">distinguish the newly discovered evidence claimed in the petition from any claims made in prior petitions.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A petitioner shall notify the State in writing of the filing of a petition under this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The State may file a response to the petition within 90 days after receipt of the notice required under this subsection or within the period of time that the court orders.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Before a hearing is held on a petition filed under this section, the victim or victim's representative shall be notified of the hearing as provided under &#xA7; 11-104 or &#xA7; 11-503 of this article.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A victim or victim's representative has the right to attend a hearing on a petition filed under this section as provided under &#xA7; 11-102 of this article.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, the court shall hold a hearing on a petition filed under this section if the petition satisfies the requirements of subsection (b) of this section and a hearing was requested.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The court may dismiss a petition without a hearing if the court finds that the petition fails to assert grounds on which relief may be granted.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In ruling on a petition filed under this section, the court may set aside the verdict, resentence, grant a new trial, or correct the sentence, as the court considers appropriate.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The court shall state the reasons for its ruling on the record.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">A petitioner in a proceeding under this section has the burden of proof.</section>
  </text>
</law>
