<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcp" order_by="" level="1">Criminal Procedure</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcp-15-419</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>419</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">This section applies only in St. Mary's County.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The State's Attorney's salary is 90% of the salary of a judge of the District Court of Maryland and shall be paid biweekly.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">A salary increase shall take effect at the beginning of the elected term of office and may not increase during the term of office.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The county commissioners shall provide for the administrative support staff, independent office facilities, office equipment, supplies, books, and other items necessary for the operation of the office.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The State's Attorney shall present vouchers to the county commissioners for the payment of office expenses.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The State's Attorney may appoint one deputy State's Attorney and two or more assistant State's Attorneys who:<section prefix="(i)">shall serve at the pleasure of the State's Attorney; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">may be full-time or part-time employees.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The State's Attorney shall pay the salaries of the deputy and assistant State's Attorneys biweekly from money that the county commissioners appropriate each year.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The State's Attorney may appoint:<section prefix="(i)">administrative staff necessary for the operation of the office; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">one or more full-time or part-time investigators as employees.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The staff appointed under paragraph (1) of this subsection shall be in the county merit system.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The State's Attorney shall pay the salaries of the investigators appointed under paragraph (1)(ii) of this subsection biweekly from money that the county commissioners appropriate each year.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The State's Attorney may not:<section prefix="(1)">engage in the private practice of law; and</section><section prefix="(2)">except in connection with performing the duties of the office, appear professionally in a criminal proceeding in the State.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
