<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcp" order_by="" level="1">Criminal Procedure</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcp-10-239</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>239</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this part the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Attorney General" means the Attorney General of the United States.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Compact officer" means:<section prefix="(1)">with respect to the federal government, an official so designated by the Director of the FBI; and</section><section prefix="(2)">with respect to a party state, the chief administrator of the state's criminal history records repository or a designee of the chief administrator who is a regular full-time employee of the repository.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">"Council" means the Compact Council established under Section 10-244 of this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"Criminal history records":<section prefix="(1)">means information collected by criminal justice agencies on individuals consisting of identifiable descriptions and notations of arrests, detentions, indictments, or other formal criminal charges, and any disposition arising therefrom, including acquittal, sentencing, correctional supervision, or release; and</section><section prefix="(2)">does not include identification information such as fingerprint records if such information does not indicate involvement of the individual with the criminal justice system.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">"Criminal history records repository" means the state agency designated by the governor or other appropriate executive official or the legislature of a state to perform centralized record keeping functions for criminal history records and services in the state.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">"Criminal justice" includes activities relating to the detection, apprehension, detention, pretrial release, posttrial release, prosecution, adjudication, correctional supervision, or rehabilitation of accused persons or criminal offenders. The administration of criminal justice includes criminal identification activities and the collection, storage, and dissemination of criminal history records.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">"Criminal justice agency":<section prefix="(1)">means:<section prefix="(i)">courts; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">a governmental agency or any subunit thereof that:<section prefix="1.">performs the administration of criminal justice pursuant to a statute or executive order; and</section><section prefix="2.">allocates a substantial part of its annual budget to the administration of criminal justice; and</section></section></section><section prefix="(2)">includes federal and state inspectors general offices.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(i)">"Criminal justice services" means services provided by the FBI to criminal justice agencies in response to a request for information about a particular individual or as an update to information previously provided for criminal justice purposes.</section>
    <section prefix="(j)">"Criterion offense" means any felony or misdemeanor offense not included on the list of nonserious offenses published periodically by the FBI.</section>
    <section prefix="(k)">"Direct access" means access to the National Identification Index by computer terminal or other automated means not requiring the assistance of or intervention by any other party or agency.</section>
    <section prefix="(l)">"Executive order" means an order of the President of the United States or the chief executive officer of a state that has the force of law and that is promulgated in accordance with applicable law.</section>
    <section prefix="(m)">"FBI" means the Federal Bureau of Investigation.</section>
    <section prefix="(n)">"Interstate Identification Index System" or "III System":<section prefix="(1)">means the cooperative federal-state system for the exchange of criminal history records; and</section><section prefix="(2)">includes the National Identification Index, the National Fingerprint File and, to the extent of their participation in such system, the criminal history record repositories of the states and the FBI.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(o)">"National Fingerprint File" means a database of fingerprints, or other uniquely personal identifying information, relating to an arrested or charged individual maintained by the FBI to provide positive identification of record subjects indexed in the III System.</section>
    <section prefix="(p)">"National Identification Index" means an index maintained by the FBI consisting of names, identifying numbers, and other descriptive information relating to record subjects about whom there are criminal history records in the III System.</section>
    <section prefix="(q)">"National indices" means the National Identification Index and the National Fingerprint File.</section>
    <section prefix="(r)">"Nonparty state" means a state that has not ratified this Compact.</section>
    <section prefix="(s)">"Noncriminal justice purposes" means uses of criminal history records for purposes authorized by federal or state law other than purposes relating to criminal justice activities, including employment suitability, licensing determinations, immigration and naturalization matters, and national security clearances.</section>
    <section prefix="(t)">"Party state" means a state that has ratified this Compact.</section>
    <section prefix="(u)">"Positive identification" means a determination, based upon a comparison of fingerprints or other equally reliable biometric identification techniques, that the subject of a record search is the same person as the subject of a criminal history record or records indexed in the III System. Identifications based solely upon a comparison of subjects' names or other nonunique identification characteristics or numbers, or combinations thereof, shall not constitute positive identification.</section>
    <section prefix="(v)">"Sealed record information" means:<section prefix="(1)">with respect to adults, that portion of a record that is:<section prefix="(i)">not available for criminal justice uses;</section><section prefix="(ii)">not supported by fingerprints or other accepted means of positive identification; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">subject to restrictions on dissemination for noncriminal justice purposes pursuant to a court order related to a particular subject or pursuant to a federal or state statute that requires action on a sealing petition filed by a particular record subject; and</section></section><section prefix="(2)">with respect to juveniles, whatever each state determines is a sealed record under its own law and procedure.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(w)">"State" means any state, territory, or possession of the United States, the District of Columbia, and the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico.</section>
  </text>
</law>
