<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcp" order_by="gcp" level="1">Criminal Procedure</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcp-10-108</section_number>
  <catch_line>A person may not open or review an expunged record or disclose to another person any information fro...</catch_line>
  <order_by>108</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">A person may not open or review an expunged record or disclose to another person any information from that record without a court order from:<section prefix="(1)">the court that ordered the record expunged; or</section><section prefix="(2)">the District Court that has venue in the case of a police record expunged under &#xA7; 10-103 of this subtitle.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A court may order the opening or review of an expunged record or the disclosure of information from that record:<section prefix="(1)">after notice to the person whom the record concerns, a hearing, and the showing of good cause; or</section><section prefix="(2)">on an ex parte order, as provided in subsection (c) of this section.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The court may pass an ex parte order allowing access to an expunged record, without notice to the person who is the subject of that record, on a verified petition filed by a State's Attorney alleging that:<section prefix="(i)">the expunged record is needed by a law enforcement unit for a pending criminal investigation; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">the investigation will be jeopardized or life or property will be endangered without immediate access to the expunged record.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">In an ex parte order, the court may not allow a copy of the expunged record to be made.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A person who violates this section is guilty of a misdemeanor and on conviction is subject to a fine not exceeding $1,000 or imprisonment not exceeding 1 year or both.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">In addition to the penalties provided in paragraph (1) of this subsection, an official or employee of the State or a political subdivision of the State who is convicted under this section may be removed or dismissed from public service.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
