<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcp" order_by="gcp" level="1">Criminal Procedure</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcp-15-423</section_number>
  <catch_line>This section applies only in Wicomico County....</catch_line>
  <order_by>423</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">This section applies only in Wicomico County.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The State's Attorney's salary is 90% of the annual salary of a judge of the District Court of Maryland.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">After receiving a voucher submitted by the State's Attorney, the County Council shall pay all expenses that the State's Attorney considers necessary for the conduct of the office, including clerical and secretarial expenses, telephone charges, office supplies, postage, and premiums on official bonds.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The State's Attorney shall maintain and staff an office in the Wicomico County courthouse.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Subject to the terms, conditions, and salaries as approved by the County Council, the State's Attorney may appoint assistant State's Attorneys who shall:<section prefix="(i)">serve at the pleasure of the State's Attorney; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">have the same legal powers as the State's Attorney to represent the State before the grand jury and in criminal proceedings.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">In addition to the assistant State's Attorneys appointed under paragraph (1) of this subsection, the State's Attorney may appoint special assistant State's Attorneys to serve for one or more cases:<section prefix="(i)">with the prior approval of the resident judge of the circuit court and the County Council; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">subject to the terms, conditions, and salaries that the County Council approves.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The State's Attorney shall serve full time and may not engage in the private practice of law.</section>
  </text>
</law>
