<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcp" order_by="gcp" level="1">Criminal Procedure</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcp-4-109</section_number>
  <catch_line>A law enforcement agency may make a written request for the State's Attorney within the jurisdiction...</catch_line>
  <order_by>109</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">A law enforcement agency may make a written request for the State's Attorney within the jurisdiction of the law enforcement agency to petition the administrative judge of the district to have a warrant, summons, or other criminal process for a misdemeanor offense in the possession of the law enforcement agency invalidated and destroyed due to the age of the unexecuted warrant, summons, or other criminal process and unavailability of the defendant, or other special circumstances, if:<section prefix="(1)">the warrant, summons, or other criminal process was issued for the arrest of the defendant in order that the defendant might stand for trial and has remained unexecuted for at least 5 years;</section><section prefix="(2)">the warrant, summons, or other criminal process was issued for the failure of the defendant to make a deferred payment of a fine or costs as ordered by the court and has remained unexecuted for at least 5 years;</section><section prefix="(3)">the warrant, summons, or other criminal process was issued for a violation of probation and has remained unexecuted for at least 5 years;</section><section prefix="(4)">except as provided in item (5) of this subsection, the warrant, summons, or other criminal process was issued for the arrest of the defendant for the failure of the defendant to appear as directed by the court and has remained unexecuted for at least 5 years; or</section><section prefix="(5)">the defendant was released on bail posted by a private surety, and the warrant was issued for the arrest of the defendant for the failure of the defendant to appear as directed by the court and has remained unexecuted for at least 10 years.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">On receipt of a request made under subsection (a)(1), (a)(2), (a)(3), or (a)(4) of this section, the State's Attorney:<section prefix="(i)">if the warrant, summons, or other criminal process has remained unexecuted for more than 5 years but less than 7 years, may petition the Administrative Judge of the District for the invalidation and destruction of the unexecuted warrant, summons, or other process; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">if the warrant, summons, or other criminal process has remained unexecuted for at least 7 years, shall petition the Administrative Judge of the District for the invalidation and destruction of the unexecuted warrant, summons, or other process.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">On receipt of a request made under subsection (a)(5) of this section, the State's Attorney shall petition the Administrative Judge of the District for the invalidation and destruction of the unexecuted warrant, summons, or other criminal process.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The State's Attorney may argue against the invalidation and destruction of the unexecuted warrant, summons, or other criminal process due to a justifiable continuing active investigation of the case.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Unless preservation is determined by the court to be justifiable, the court shall order the invalidation and destruction of an unexecuted warrant for a misdemeanor offense, summons, or other criminal process in accordance with &#xA7; 1-605 of the Courts and Judicial Proceedings Article.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">An arrest may not be made under the authority of a warrant or other criminal process that has been ordered invalidated and destroyed.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The State's Attorney may enter a nolle prosequi or place the case on the stet docket at the time of the court order under this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">Nothing in this section may be construed to:<section prefix="(1)">prevent the reissuance of a warrant, summons, or other criminal process;</section><section prefix="(2)">affect the time within which a prosecution for a misdemeanor may be commenced; or</section><section prefix="(3)">affect any pending criminal charge.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
