<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcp" order_by="" level="1">Criminal Procedure</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcp-11-805</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>805</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Subject to the authority of the Secretary as set forth in Title 2, Subtitle 1 of the Correctional Services Article, the Board has the following powers and duties:<section prefix="(1)">to establish and maintain an office and to appoint and prescribe the duties of a claims examiner, a secretary, clerks, and any other employees and agents as may be necessary;</section><section prefix="(2)">to adopt regulations to carry out the provisions and purposes of this subtitle, including procedures for the review and evaluation of claims and regulations for the approval of attorneys' fees for representation before the Board or before the court on judicial review;</section><section prefix="(3)">to request from the State's Attorney, the Department of State Police, or county or municipal police departments any investigation and information that will help the Board to determine:<section prefix="(i)">whether a crime or a delinquent act was committed or attempted; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">whether and to what extent the victim or claimant was responsible for the victim's or claimant's own injury;</section></section><section prefix="(4)">to hear and determine each claim for an award filed with the Board under this subtitle and to reinvestigate or reopen a case as the Board determines to be necessary;</section><section prefix="(5)">to direct medical examination of victims;</section><section prefix="(6)">to hold hearings, administer oaths, examine any person under oath, and issue subpoenas requiring the attendance and testimony of witnesses or requiring the production of documents or other evidence;</section><section prefix="(7)">to take or cause to be taken affidavits or depositions within or outside the State; and</section><section prefix="(8)">to submit each year to the Governor, to the Secretary, and, subject to &#xA7; 2-1246 of the State Government Article, to the General Assembly a written report of the activities of the Board.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Except as otherwise provided by law, an employee of the Board is subject to the State Personnel and Pensions Article.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Board may delegate to a member or employee of the Board its powers under this section to hold hearings, administer oaths, examine a person under oath, and issue subpoenas.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A subpoena issued under this section is subject to the Maryland Rules.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
