<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gcp" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="14-110" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcp-14-110</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The State Prosecutor has all the powers and duties of a State's Attorney, including the use of a grand jury in any county, when the State Prosecutor:<section prefix="(1)">investigates a case under &#xA7; 14-107 of this title; or</section><section prefix="(2)">prosecutes a case under &#xA7; 14-109 of this title.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">For the limited purpose of furthering an ongoing criminal investigation under &#xA7; 14-107 of this title, the State Prosecutor may issue a subpoena to a person to produce telephone, business, governmental, or corporate records or documents.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The subpoena may be served in the same manner as one issued by a circuit court.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A person may have an attorney present during any contact with the State Prosecutor made under subsection (b) of this section.	</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The State Prosecutor shall advise a person of the right to counsel when the subpoena is served.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The State Prosecutor immediately may report the failure of a person to obey a lawfully served subpoena under subsection (b) of this section to the circuit court of the county having jurisdiction.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The State Prosecutor shall provide a copy of the subpoena and proof of service to the circuit court.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">After conducting a hearing at which the person who allegedly failed to comply with a subpoena issued under subsection (b) of this section has an opportunity to be heard and represented by counsel, the court may grant appropriate relief.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">This section does not allow the contravention, denial, or abrogation of a privilege or right recognized by law.</section>
  </text>
</law>
