<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gcp" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="15-410" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcp-15-410</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">This section applies only in Dorchester County.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The State's Attorney's salary is 80% of the salary of a judge of the District Court of Maryland.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Subject to the approval of the County Council, the State's Attorney is entitled to an allowance for the expenses of operating the office, including the costs of telephone charges, office supplies and equipment, postage, travel, training, conferences, books and publications, and premiums on office bonds.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The State's Attorney may appoint the number of full-time or part-time deputy State's Attorneys and assistant State's Attorneys that the County Council approves.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The deputy and assistant State's Attorneys shall:<section prefix="(i)">serve at the pleasure of the State's Attorney;</section><section prefix="(ii)">receive compensation as approved by the County Council; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">have the same legal powers as the State's Attorney to present cases to the grand jury and perform all other necessary duties in relation to the grand jury and the operation of the office.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Subject to the approval of the County Council, the State's Attorney may employ administrative and clerical employees who shall:<section prefix="(1)">receive salaries in accordance with the county pay scale; and</section><section prefix="(2)">be considered county employees and members of the pension system in which a county employee is eligible for membership.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The State's Attorney:<section prefix="(1)">shall serve full time;</section><section prefix="(2)">may not engage in the private practice of law; and</section><section prefix="(3)">except in connection with performing the duties of the office, may not appear professionally in a criminal proceeding in the State.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
