<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcp" order_by="" level="1">Criminal Procedure</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcp-10-219</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>219</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Except in accordance with applicable federal law and regulations, a criminal justice unit and the Central Repository may not disseminate criminal history record information.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Central Repository shall disseminate on a monthly basis information concerning a child charged as an adult to the Maryland Justice Analysis Center of the Institute of Criminal Justice and Criminology of the University of Maryland.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">In addition to any reportable event, as defined in &#xA7; 10-215 of this subtitle, the Central Repository shall include in its dissemination of information to the Maryland Justice Analysis Center the age, race, and gender of the child.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Central Repository may disseminate to the Maryland Justice Analysis Center unique identifiers relating to the child, including the name of the child, fingerprint identification numbers, and record or file numbers.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The information disseminated to the Maryland Justice Analysis Center in accordance with this subsection shall be used only for the purposes of research, evaluation, and statistical analysis.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">Except as otherwise required under State law, the Maryland Justice Analysis Center may not disseminate criminal history record information received from the Central Repository.</section>
      <section prefix="(6)">By June 30 and December 31 of each year, the Maryland Justice Analysis Center shall report to the Governor, and, subject to &#xA7; 2-1246 of the State Government Article, the General Assembly, on the results of its research, evaluation, and statistical analysis.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
