<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcp" order_by="gcp" level="1">Criminal Procedure</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcp-11-717</section_number>
  <catch_line>The Department shall make available to the public registration statements or information about regis...</catch_line>
  <order_by>717</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Department shall make available to the public registration statements or information about registration statements.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Information about registration statements shall include, in plain language that can be understood without special knowledge of the criminal laws of the State, a factual description of the crime of the offender that is the basis for the registration, excluding details that would identify the victim.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Registration information provided to the public may not include a sex offender's Social Security number, driver's license number, medical or therapeutic treatment, travel and immigration document numbers, and arrests not resulting in conviction.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Department shall post on the Internet:<section prefix="(1)">a current listing of each registrant's name and other identifying information; and</section><section prefix="(2)">in plain language that can be understood without special knowledge of the criminal laws of the State, a factual description of the crime of the offender that is the basis for the registration, excluding details that would identify the victim.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Department, through an Internet posting of current registrants, shall:<section prefix="(1)">allow the public to electronically transmit information the public may have about a registrant to the Department, a parole agent of a registrant, and each local law enforcement unit where a registrant resides or habitually lives or where a registrant who is not a resident of the State will work or attend school; and</section><section prefix="(2)">provide information regarding the out-of-state registration status for each registrant who is also registered in another state as available through a national sex offender public registry website.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Department shall allow members of the public who live in a county in which a registrant is to reside or habitually live or where the registrant, if not a resident of the State, will work or attend school, by request, to receive electronic mail notification of the release from incarceration of the registered offender and the registration information of the offender.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The Department shall establish regulations to carry out this section.</section>
  </text>
</law>
