<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcp" order_by="" level="1">Criminal Procedure</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcp-7-109</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>109</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Within 30 days after the court passes an order in accordance with this subtitle, a person aggrieved by the order, including the Attorney General and a State's Attorney, may apply to the Court of Special Appeals for leave to appeal the order.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The application for leave to appeal shall be in the form set by the Maryland Rules.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If the Attorney General or a State's Attorney states an intention to file an application for an appeal under this section, the court may:<section prefix="(i)">stay the order; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">set bail for the petitioner.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">If the application for leave to appeal is granted:<section prefix="(i)">the procedure for the appeal shall meet the requirements of the Maryland Rules; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">the Court of Special Appeals may:<section prefix="1.">affirm, reverse, or modify the order appealed from; or</section><section prefix="2.">remand the case for further proceedings.</section></section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">If the application for leave to appeal is denied, the order sought to be reviewed becomes final.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Court of Special Appeals shall direct the political subdivision in which an order is passed to pay the necessary costs and expenses associated with a review under this section, including all court costs, stenographic services, and printing, if:<section prefix="(1)">a person seeks a review under this section within 30 days after judgment;</section><section prefix="(2)">the Court of Special Appeals grants leave to appeal under this section; and</section><section prefix="(3)">the Court of Special Appeals finds that the person is unable to pay the costs of the review.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
