<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gcp" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="16-204" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcp-16-204</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Representation of an indigent individual may be provided in accordance with this title by the Public Defender or, subject to the supervision of the Public Defender, by the deputy public defender, district public defenders, assistant public defenders, or panel attorneys.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Indigent defendants or parties shall be provided representation under this title in:<section prefix="(i)">a criminal or juvenile proceeding in which a defendant or party is alleged to have committed a serious offense;</section><section prefix="(ii)">a criminal or juvenile proceeding in which an attorney is constitutionally required to be present prior to presentment being made before a commissioner or judge;</section><section prefix="(iii)">a postconviction proceeding for which the defendant has a right to an attorney under Title 7 of this article;</section><section prefix="(iv)">any other proceeding in which confinement under a judicial commitment of an individual in a public or private institution may result;</section><section prefix="(v)">a proceeding involving children in need of assistance under &#xA7; 3-813 of the Courts Article; or</section><section prefix="(vi)">a family law proceeding under Title 5, Subtitle 3, Part II or Part III of the Family Law Article, including:</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Except as provided in subparagraph (ii) of this paragraph, representation shall be provided to an indigent individual in all stages of a proceeding listed in paragraph (1) of this subsection, including, in criminal proceedings, custody, interrogation, bail hearing before a District Court or circuit court judge, preliminary hearing, arraignment, trial, and appeal.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">Representation is not required to be provided to an indigent individual at an initial appearance before a District Court commissioner.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
