<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcp" order_by="" level="1">Criminal Procedure</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcp-11-103</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>103</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section, "violent crime" means:<section prefix="(i)">a crime of violence;</section><section prefix="(ii)">a delinquent act that would be a crime of violence if committed by an adult; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, a crime or delinquent act involving, causing, or resulting in death or serious bodily injury.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Violent crime" does not include an offense under the Maryland Vehicle Law or under Title 8, Subtitle 7 of the Natural Resources Article unless the offense is punishable by imprisonment.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Although not a party to a criminal or juvenile proceeding, a victim of a violent crime for which the defendant or child respondent is charged may file an application for leave to appeal to the Court of Special Appeals from an interlocutory or final order that denies or fails to consider a right secured to the victim by &#xA7; 4-202 of this article, &#xA7; 11-102, &#xA7; 11-104, &#xA7; 11-302, &#xA7; 11-402, &#xA7; 11-403, &#xA7; 11-404, or &#xA7; 11-603 of this title, &#xA7; 3-8A-06, &#xA7; 3-8A-13, or &#xA7; 3-8A-19 of the Courts Article, or &#xA7; 6-112 of the Correctional Services Article.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The filing of an application for leave to appeal under this section does not stay other proceedings in a criminal or juvenile case unless all parties consent.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">For purposes of this section, a victim's representative, including the victim's spouse or surviving spouse, parent or legal guardian, child, or sibling, may represent a victim of a violent crime who dies or is disabled.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If there is a dispute over who shall be the victim's representative, the court shall designate the victim's representative.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In any court proceeding involving a crime against a victim, the court shall ensure that the victim is in fact afforded the rights provided to victims by law.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">	 (i)	A victim who alleges that the victim's right to restitution under &#xA7; 11-603 of this title was not considered or was improperly denied may file a motion requesting relief within 30 days of the denial or alleged failure to consider.<section prefix="(ii)">If the court finds that the victim's right to restitution under &#xA7; 11-603 of this title was not considered or was improperly denied, the court may enter a judgment of restitution.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
