<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcp" order_by="gcp" level="1">Criminal Procedure</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcp-15-421</section_number>
  <catch_line>This section applies only in Talbot County....</catch_line>
  <order_by>421</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">This section applies only in Talbot County.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The State's Attorney's salary is 80% of the salary of a judge of the District Court of Maryland.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Subject to the approval of the County Council, the State's Attorney is entitled to a reasonable allowance for the expenses of operating the office, including the costs of:<section prefix="(i)">administrative, clerical, and secretarial expenses, including salaries and benefits;</section><section prefix="(ii)">telephone charges;</section><section prefix="(iii)">office supplies and equipment;</section><section prefix="(iv)">postage;</section><section prefix="(v)">travel, training, and conferences;</section><section prefix="(vi)">books and publications; and</section><section prefix="(vii)">premiums on office bonds.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The State's Attorney may appoint the number of full-time or part-time deputy State's Attorneys and assistant State's Attorneys that the County Council approves.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">Each deputy and assistant State's Attorney appointed under this paragraph shall:<section prefix="1.">serve at the pleasure of the State's Attorney;</section><section prefix="2.">receive the compensation that the County Council approves; and</section><section prefix="3.">have the same legal powers as the State's Attorney to present cases to the grand jury and perform necessary duties in relation to the grand jury and the operation of the office.</section></section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The State's Attorney may appoint special assistant State's Attorneys as the State's Attorney considers necessary to serve in an investigation or a case.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">A special assistant State's Attorney appointed under this paragraph:<section prefix="1.">shall serve on a temporary basis;</section><section prefix="2.">subject to paragraph (3) of this subsection, shall receive compensation from the County Council in the form and amount authorized by order of the circuit court; and</section><section prefix="3.">may not be considered to hold an office for profit or to have vacated a public office or employment in another State's Attorney's office by serving as a special assistant State's Attorney.</section></section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The county may not compensate an individual who is appointed as a special assistant State's Attorney and is employed by the Office of the Attorney General, the Office of the State Prosecutor, or the Office of the State's Attorney in another county.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">Notwithstanding subparagraph (i) of this paragraph, the county may enter into an agreement to reimburse the appropriate governmental unit for the services of an individual employed by that governmental unit who is appointed as a special assistant State's Attorney under paragraph (2) of this subsection.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Subject to the approval of the County Council, the State's Attorney may appoint full-time or part-time criminal investigators.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If the State's Attorney appoints more than one criminal investigator, the State's Attorney may designate one as chief investigator and assign other ranks and titles to the other criminal investigators.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A criminal investigator who is appointed under this subsection:<section prefix="(i)">shall serve at the pleasure of the State's Attorney;</section><section prefix="(ii)">is subject to the regulations of the State's Attorney;</section><section prefix="(iii)">shall perform the duties that the State's Attorney designates;</section><section prefix="(iv)">shall take an oath of office that the clerk of the circuit court administers;</section><section prefix="(v)">shall meet the criteria regarding training and experience that the State's Attorney requires;</section><section prefix="(vi)">may serve a summons or subpoena that the State's Attorney issues;</section><section prefix="(vii)">may wear or display appropriate metallic badges that the State's Attorney authorizes; and</section><section prefix="(viii)">is not subject to Title 3, Subtitle 1 of the Public Safety Article.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The State's Attorney may designate a criminal investigator as a peace officer if the criminal investigator meets the selection and training standards of the Police Training Commission as set forth in Title 3, Subtitle 2 of the Public Safety Article.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">A criminal investigator designated as a peace officer may not be subject to Title 3, Subtitle 1 of the Public Safety Article.</section>
      <section prefix="(6)">In addition to the authority, duties, and limitations described under paragraph (3) of this subsection, a criminal investigator designated as a peace officer may:<section prefix="(i)">arrest a person who commits a crime in the county or in a municipal corporation in the county;</section><section prefix="(ii)">serve a warrant, summons, or subpoena that the District Court of Maryland in the county or a circuit court issues; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">possess and carry a firearm, including a handgun, or other weapon that the State's Attorney requires.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The State's Attorney shall serve full time and may not engage in the private practice of law.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">An attorney appointed as a special assistant State's Attorney under subsection (c)(2) of this section may not be precluded from the private practice of criminal law.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
