<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcp" order_by="" level="1">Criminal Procedure</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcp-11-701</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>701</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Board" means the Sexual Offender Advisory Board.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Employment" means an occupation, job, or vocation that is full time or part time for a period exceeding 14 days or for an aggregate period exceeding 30 days during a calendar year, whether financially compensated, volunteered, or for the purpose of government or educational benefit.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Habitually lives" means any place where a person lives, sleeps, or visits with any regularity, including where a homeless person is stationed during the day or sleeps at night.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Habitually lives" includes any place where a person visits for longer than 5 hours per visit more than 5 times within a 30-day period.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"Homeless" means having no fixed residence.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">"Imprisonment" means incarceration pursuant to a conviction, regardless of the nature of the institution in which the offender serves the sentence.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">"Jurisdiction" means a state or a Native American tribe that elects to function as a registration jurisdiction under federal law.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">"Local law enforcement unit" means the law enforcement unit in a county that has been designated by resolution of the county governing body as the primary law enforcement unit in the county.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as otherwise provided in this subsection, "release" means any type of release from the custody of a supervising authority.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Release" means:<section prefix="(i)">release on parole;</section><section prefix="(ii)">mandatory supervision release;</section><section prefix="(iii)">release from a correctional facility with no required period of supervision;</section><section prefix="(iv)">work release;</section><section prefix="(v)">placement on home detention; and</section><section prefix="(vi)">the first instance of entry into the community that is part of a supervising authority's graduated release program.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Release" does not include:<section prefix="(i)">an escape; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">leave that is granted on an emergency basis.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(j)">"Sexually violent offense" means:<section prefix="(1)">a violation of &#xA7;&#xA7; 3-303 through 3-307 or &#xA7;&#xA7; 3-309 through 3-312 of the Criminal Law Article;</section><section prefix="(2)">assault with intent to commit rape in the first or second degree or a sexual offense in the first or second degree as prohibited on or before September 30, 1996, under former Article 27, &#xA7; 12 of the Code; or</section><section prefix="(3)">a crime committed in another jurisdiction, federal or military court, or foreign country that, if committed in this State, would constitute one of the crimes listed in item (1) or (2) of this subsection.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(k)">"Sexually violent predator" means a person who:<section prefix="(1)">is convicted of a sexually violent offense; and</section><section prefix="(2)">has been determined in accordance with this subtitle to be at risk of committing another sexually violent offense.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(l)">"Sex offender" means a person who has been convicted of:<section prefix="(1)">an offense that would require the person to be classified as a tier I sex offender, tier II sex offender, or tier III sex offender;</section><section prefix="(2)">an offense committed in another state or in a federal, military, or tribal jurisdiction that, if committed in this State, would require the person to be classified as a tier I sex offender, tier II sex offender, or tier III sex offender; or</section><section prefix="(3)">an offense in a court of Canada, Great Britain, Australia, New Zealand, or any other foreign country where the United States Department of State has determined in its Country Reports on Human Rights Practices that an independent judiciary generally or vigorously enforced the right to a fair trial during the year in which the conviction occurred that, if committed in this State, would require the person to be classified as a tier I sex offender, tier II sex offender, or tier III sex offender.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(m)">"Student" means an individual who is enrolled in or attends an education institution, including a public or private secondary school, trade or professional school, or an institution of higher education.</section>
    <section prefix="(n)">"Supervising authority" means an agency or person that is responsible for collecting the information for the initial registration of a sex offender and is:<section prefix="(1)">the Secretary, if the registrant is in the custody of a correctional facility operated by the Department;</section><section prefix="(2)">the administrator of a local correctional facility, if the registrant, including a participant in a home detention program, is in the custody of the local correctional facility;</section><section prefix="(3)">the court that granted the probation or suspended sentence, except as provided in item (9) of this subsection, if the registrant is granted probation before judgment, probation after judgment, or a suspended sentence;</section><section prefix="(4)">the Director of the Patuxent Institution, if the registrant is in the custody of the Patuxent Institution;</section><section prefix="(5)">the Secretary of Health and Mental Hygiene, if the registrant is in the custody of a facility operated by the Department of Health and Mental Hygiene;</section><section prefix="(6)">the court in which the registrant was convicted, if the registrant's sentence does not include a term of imprisonment or if the sentence is modified to time served;</section><section prefix="(7)">the Secretary, if the registrant is in the State under terms and conditions of the Interstate Compact for Adult Offender Supervision, set forth in Title 6, Subtitle 2 of the Correctional Services Article, or the Interstate Corrections Compact, set forth in Title 8, Subtitle 6 of the Correctional Services Article;</section><section prefix="(8)">the local law enforcement unit where the sex offender is a resident, is a transient, or habitually lives on moving from another jurisdiction or foreign country that requires registration if the sex offender is not under the supervision, custody, or control of another supervising authority;</section><section prefix="(9)">the Director of Parole and Probation, if the registrant is under the supervision of the Division of Parole and Probation; or</section><section prefix="(10)">the Secretary of Juvenile Services, if the registrant was a minor at the time the act was committed for which registration is required.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(o)">"Tier I sex offender" means a person who has been convicted of:<section prefix="(1)">conspiring to commit, attempting to commit, or committing a violation of &#xA7; 3-308 of the Criminal Law Article;</section><section prefix="(2)">conspiring to commit, attempting to commit, or committing a violation of &#xA7; 3-902 or &#xA7; 11-208 of the Criminal Law Article, if the victim is a minor;</section><section prefix="(3)">a crime committed in a federal, military, tribal, or other jurisdiction that, if committed in this State, would constitute one of the crimes listed in item (1) or (2) of this subsection;</section><section prefix="(4)">any of the following federal offenses:<section prefix="(i)">misleading domain names on the Internet under 18 U.S.C. &#xA7; 2252B;</section><section prefix="(ii)">misleading words or digital images on the Internet under 18 U.S.C. &#xA7; 2252C;</section><section prefix="(iii)">engaging in illicit conduct in foreign places under 18 U.S.C. &#xA7; 2423(c);</section><section prefix="(iv)">failure to file a factual statement about an alien individual under 18 U.S.C. &#xA7; 2424;</section><section prefix="(v)">transmitting information about a minor to further criminal sexual conduct under 18 U.S.C. &#xA7; 2425;</section><section prefix="(vi)">sex trafficking by force, fraud, or coercion under 18 U.S.C. &#xA7; 1591; or</section><section prefix="(vii)">travel with intent to engage in illicit conduct under 18 U.S.C. &#xA7; 2423(b);</section></section><section prefix="(5)">any military offense specified by the Secretary of Defense under Section 115(A)(8)(C)(i) of Public Law 105-119 (codified at 10 U.S.C. &#xA7; 951 Note) that is similar to those offenses listed in item (4) of this subsection; or</section><section prefix="(6)">a crime in a court of Canada, Great Britain, Australia, New Zealand, or any other foreign country where the United States Department of State has determined in its Country Reports on Human Rights Practices that an independent judiciary generally or vigorously enforced the right to a fair trial during the year in which the conviction occurred that, if the crime were committed in this State, would constitute one of the crimes listed in items (1) through (5) of this subsection.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(p)">"Tier II sex offender" means a person who has been convicted of:<section prefix="(1)">conspiring to commit, attempting to commit, or committing a violation of &#xA7; 3-307(a)(4) or (5), &#xA7; 3-324, &#xA7; 11-207, or &#xA7; 11-209 of the Criminal Law Article;</section><section prefix="(2)">conspiring to commit, attempting to commit, or committing a violation of &#xA7; 11-303, &#xA7; 11-305, or &#xA7; 11-306 of the Criminal Law Article, if the intended prostitute or victim is a minor;</section><section prefix="(3)">conspiring to commit, attempting to commit, or committing a violation of &#xA7; 3-314 or &#xA7; 3-603 of the Criminal Law Article, if the victim is a minor who is at least 14 years old;</section><section prefix="(4)">conspiring to commit, attempting to commit, or committing an offense that would require the person to register as a tier I sex offender after the person was already registered as a tier I sex offender;</section><section prefix="(5)">a crime that was committed in a federal, military, tribal, or other jurisdiction that, if committed in this State, would constitute one of the crimes listed in items (1) through (3) of this subsection; or</section><section prefix="(6)">a crime in a court of Canada, Great Britain, Australia, New Zealand, or any other foreign country where the United States Department of State has determined in its Country Reports on Human Rights Practices that an independent judiciary generally or vigorously enforced the right to a fair trial during the year in which the conviction occurred that, if the crime were committed in this State, would constitute one of the crimes listed in items (1) through (3) of this subsection.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(q)">"Tier III sex offender" means a person who has been convicted of:<section prefix="(1)">conspiring to commit, attempting to commit, or committing a violation of:<section prefix="(i)">&#xA7; 2-201(a)(4)(viii), (x), or (xi) of the Criminal Law Article;</section><section prefix="(ii)">&#xA7; 3-303, &#xA7; 3-304, &#xA7; 3-305, &#xA7; 3-306, &#xA7; 3-307(a)(1) or (2), &#xA7; 3-309, &#xA7; 3-310, &#xA7; 3-311, &#xA7; 3-312, &#xA7; 3-315, &#xA7; 3-323, or &#xA7; 3-602 of the Criminal Law Article;</section><section prefix="(iii)">&#xA7; 3-502 of the Criminal Law Article, if the victim is a minor;</section><section prefix="(iv)">&#xA7; 3-502 of the Criminal Law Article, if the victim is an adult, and the person has been ordered by the court to register under this subtitle; or</section><section prefix="(v)">the common law offense of sodomy or &#xA7; 3-322 of the Criminal Law Article if the offense was committed with force or threat of force;</section></section><section prefix="(2)">conspiring to commit, attempting to commit, or committing a violation of &#xA7; 3-307(a)(3), &#xA7; 3-314, &#xA7; 3-503, or &#xA7; 3-603 of the Criminal Law Article, if the victim is under the age of 14 years;</section><section prefix="(3)">conspiring to commit, attempting to commit, or committing the common law offense of false imprisonment, if the victim is a minor;</section><section prefix="(4)">conspiring to commit, attempting to commit, or committing an offense that would require the person to register as a tier I or tier II sex offender after the person was already registered as a tier II sex offender;</section><section prefix="(5)">a crime committed in a federal, military, tribal, or other jurisdiction that, if committed in this State, would constitute one of the crimes listed in items (1) through (3) of this subsection; or</section><section prefix="(6)">a crime in a court of Canada, Great Britain, Australia, New Zealand, or any other foreign country where the United States Department of State has determined in its Country Reports on Human Rights Practices that an independent judiciary generally or vigorously enforced the right to a fair trial during the year in which the conviction occurred that, if the crime were committed in this State, would constitute one of the crimes listed in items (1) through (3) of this subsection.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(r)">"Transient" means a nonresident registrant who enters a county of this State with the intent to be in the State or is in the State for a period exceeding 14 days or for an aggregate period exceeding 30 days during a calendar year for a purpose other than employment or to attend an educational institution.</section>
  </text>
</law>
