<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gcp" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="16-301" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcp-16-301</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">There is a Board of Trustees of the Office of the Public Defender.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Board of Trustees consists of 13 members.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Each member of the Board of Trustees shall be a resident of the State.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">11 members of the Board of Trustees shall be appointed by the Governor with the advice and consent of the Senate and shall include a representative of each judicial circuit of the State.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">All members of the Board of Trustees shall be active attorneys admitted to practice before the Court of Appeals of Maryland.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">One member shall be appointed by the President of the Senate.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">One member shall be appointed by the Speaker of the House of Delegates.</section>
      <section prefix="(6)">Each member appointed to the Board of Trustees shall:<section prefix="(i)">have significant experience in criminal defense or other matters relevant to the work of the Board of Trustees; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">have demonstrated a strong commitment to quality representation of indigent defendants, including juvenile respondents.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(7)">A member of the Board of Trustees may not be:<section prefix="(i)">a current member or employee of:</section><section prefix="(ii)"/></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The term of an appointed member of the Board of Trustees is 3 years.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The terms of appointed members are staggered as required by the terms provided for members of the Board of Trustees on October 1, 2010.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A vacancy occurring on the Board of Trustees during the term of a member shall be filled for the remainder of the unexpired term in the same manner as provided for appointments in this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">At the end of a term a member continues to serve until a successor is appointed and qualifies.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">A member whose term has expired may be reappointed to the Board of Trustees.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Board of Trustees annually shall elect a chair from among its members.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The chair shall preside over and represent the interests of the Board of Trustees in carrying out this title.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">Seven members of the Board of Trustees are a quorum.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Board of Trustees shall hold at least one regular annual meeting at a time and place that the chair designates.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Additional meetings shall be held as necessary and may be called on notice by the chair or at the request of at least two members of the Board of Trustees.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(h)">A member of the Board of Trustees:<section prefix="(1)">may not receive compensation for serving on the Board of Trustees; but</section><section prefix="(2)">is entitled to reimbursement for expenses under the Standard State Travel Regulations, as provided in the State budget.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
