<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcp" order_by="gcp" level="1">Criminal Procedure</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcp-11-704</section_number>
  <catch_line>A person shall register with the person's supervising authority if the person is:...</catch_line>
  <order_by>704</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">A person shall register with the person's supervising authority if the person is:<section prefix="(1)">a tier I sex offender;</section><section prefix="(2)">a tier II sex offender;</section><section prefix="(3)">a tier III sex offender; or</section><section prefix="(4)">a sex offender who is required to register by another jurisdiction, a federal, military, or tribal court, or a foreign government, and who is not a resident of this State, and who enters this State:<section prefix="(i)">to begin residing or to habitually live;</section><section prefix="(ii)">to carry on employment;</section><section prefix="(iii)">to attend a public or private educational institution, including a secondary school, trade or professional institution, or institution of higher education, as a full-time or part-time student; or</section><section prefix="(iv)">as a transient.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, a person is no longer subject to registration under this subtitle if:<section prefix="(1)">the underlying conviction requiring registration is reversed, vacated, or set aside; or</section><section prefix="(2)">the registrant is pardoned for the underlying conviction.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A person who has been adjudicated delinquent for an act that, if committed by an adult, would constitute a violation of &#xA7; 3-303, &#xA7; 3-304, &#xA7; 3-305, or &#xA7; 3-306 of the Criminal Law Article, or &#xA7; 3-307(a)(1) or (2) or &#xA7; 3-308(b)(1) of the Criminal Law Article involving conduct described in &#xA7; 3-301(f)(2) of the Criminal Law Article, shall register with the person's supervising authority if:<section prefix="(i)">the person was a minor who was at least 13 years old at the time the delinquent act was committed;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the State's Attorney or the Department of Juvenile Services requests that the person be required to register;</section><section prefix="(iii)">90 days prior to the time the juvenile court's jurisdiction over the person terminates under &#xA7; 3-8A-07 of the Courts Article, the court, after a hearing, determines under a clear and convincing evidence standard that the person is at significant risk of committing a sexually violent offense or an offense for which registration as a tier II sex offender or tier III sex offender is required; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">the person is at least 18 years old.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If the person has committed a delinquent act that would cause the court to make a determination regarding registration under paragraph (1) of this subsection:<section prefix="(i)">the State's Attorney shall serve written notice to the person or the person's counsel at least 30 days before a hearing to determine if the person is required to register under this section; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">the Department of Juvenile Services shall:<section prefix="1.">provide the court with any information necessary to make the determination; and</section><section prefix="2.">conduct any follow-up the court requires.</section></section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The form of petitions and all other pleadings under this subsection and, except as otherwise provided under Title 3 of the Courts and Judicial Proceedings Article, the procedures to be followed by the court under this subsection shall be specified in the Maryland Rules.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The court may order an evaluation of the person in making the determination under paragraph (1) of this subsection.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
