<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcp" order_by="gcp" level="1">Criminal Procedure</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcp-15-403</section_number>
  <catch_line>This section applies only in Anne Arundel County....</catch_line>
  <order_by>403</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">This section applies only in Anne Arundel County.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The State's Attorney's salary:<section prefix="(1)">for calendar year 2003, is equal to the salary of a circuit court judge as of December 31, 2002; and</section><section prefix="(2)">shall be increased each calendar year thereafter by 3% over the salary of the State's Attorney for the previous calendar year.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The State's Attorney may:<section prefix="(i)"><section prefix="1.">appoint two deputy State's Attorneys; and</section><section prefix="2.">subject to the approval of the county, set salaries for the deputy State's Attorneys that may not exceed 90% of the State's Attorney's salary; and</section></section><section prefix="(ii)"><section prefix="1.">appoint the number of assistant State's Attorneys as provided by the county; and</section><section prefix="2.">subject to approval by the county, set salaries for the assistant State's Attorneys that may not exceed 80% of the State's Attorney's salary.</section></section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Subject to approval by the administrative judge of the circuit court, the State's Attorney may:<section prefix="(i)">appoint a temporary assistant State's Attorney for a particular case or series of cases; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">subject to the approval of the county, set the compensation for the temporary assistant State's Attorney.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The State's Attorney may appoint clerical, administrative, investigative, and other staff the State's Attorney considers necessary for the proper conduct of the office.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Except in connection with performing the duties of the office, the State's Attorney may not appear as counsel or represent any party before a court or unit of the State or a political subdivision of the State.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The State's Attorney may not engage in the private practice of law.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The deputy State's Attorneys shall serve full time and may not engage in the private practice of criminal law.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Subject to paragraph (4) of this subsection, the assistant State's Attorneys:<section prefix="(i)">may not engage in the private practice of criminal law; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">except for one assistant State's Attorney, shall serve full time.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">In accordance with the Anne Arundel County Code, the State's Attorney may designate two or more assistant State's Attorneys to share one or more full-time positions.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
