<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcp" order_by="" level="1">Criminal Procedure</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcp-3-118</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>118</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Within 15 days after a judicial hearing ends or is waived, the court shall determine whether the evidence indicates that the committed person proved by a preponderance of the evidence eligibility for release, with or without conditions, in accordance with &#xA7; 3-114 of this title, and enter an appropriate order containing a concise statement of the findings of the court, the reasons for those findings, and ordering:<section prefix="(1)">continued commitment;</section><section prefix="(2)">conditional release; or</section><section prefix="(3)">discharge from commitment.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If timely exceptions are not filed, and, on review of the report of recommendations from the Office, the court determines that the recommendations are supported by the evidence and a judicial hearing is not necessary, the court shall enter an order in accordance with the recommendations within 30 days after receiving the report from the Office.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A court may not enter an order that is not in accordance with the recommendations from the Office unless the court holds a hearing or the hearing is waived.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Unless the conditional release is extended under &#xA7; 3-122 of this title, the court may not continue the conditions of a conditional release for more than 5 years.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The court shall notify the Criminal Justice Information System Central Repository whenever it orders conditional release or discharge of a committed person.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">An appeal from a District Court order shall be on the record in the circuit court.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">An appeal from a circuit court order shall be by application for leave to appeal to the Court of Special Appeals.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
