<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcp" order_by="gcp" level="1">Criminal Procedure</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcp-14-103</section_number>
  <catch_line>There is a State Prosecutor Selection and Disabilities Commission....</catch_line>
  <order_by>103</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">There is a State Prosecutor Selection and Disabilities Commission.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Commission consists of:<section prefix="(1)">the Attorney General; and</section><section prefix="(2)">six individuals appointed by the Governor as follows:<section prefix="(i)">two individuals shall be appointed from a list of two or more nominees submitted by the President of the Senate:<section prefix="1.">only one of the individuals appointed shall be a lawyer; and</section><section prefix="2.">none of the nominees may be a member of the General Assembly or a full-time State employee;</section></section><section prefix="(ii)">two individuals shall be appointed from a list of two or more nominees submitted by the Speaker of the House of Delegates:<section prefix="1.">only one of the individuals appointed shall be a lawyer; and</section><section prefix="2.">none of the nominees may be a member of the General Assembly or a full-time State employee;</section></section><section prefix="(iii)">one individual who:<section prefix="1.">shall be appointed from a list of one or more nominees submitted by the Board of Governors of the Maryland State Bar Association; and</section><section prefix="2.">is a lawyer admitted to practice law in the State; and</section></section><section prefix="(iv)">one individual who:<section prefix="1.">shall be appointed from a list of one or more nominees submitted by the governing board of the Maryland State's Attorneys Association; and</section><section prefix="2.">is a State's Attorney at the time of appointment and throughout the individual's term on the Commission.</section></section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Governor shall appoint the members of the Commission from the nominees submitted to the Governor under this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Governor may reject an individual as a nominee only for cause.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">If the Governor rejects an individual as a nominee, the Governor shall request the appropriate nominating authority to submit another nominee.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The term of an appointed member is 4 years.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The terms of appointed members are staggered as required by the terms in effect for members on October 1, 2008.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">An appointed member serves until a successor is appointed and qualifies.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">An appointed member is eligible for reappointment.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">From among the members, the Governor shall designate the chair of the Commission for the period that the Governor determines.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">A vacancy that occurs on the Commission shall be filled by the Governor in the same manner as provided for appointments in this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">A member of the Commission:<section prefix="(1)">may not receive compensation for serving on the Commission; but</section><section prefix="(2)">is entitled to reimbursement for expenses under the Standard State Travel Regulations, as provided in the State budget.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
