<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcp" order_by="" level="1">Criminal Procedure</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcp-13-407</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>407</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Except as provided in this section, disposition of property after forfeiture under this subtitle shall be subject to &#xA7;&#xA7; 12-401, 12-402, and 12-404 of this article.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The court determination under &#xA7; 12-402(c) of this article shall include that the property was being used or was to be used in violation of the Mortgage Fraud law rather than the Controlled Dangerous Substances law.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">In this subsection the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">"Identifiable losses" include:<section prefix="1.">expenses necessary to:</section><section prefix="2.">lost wages resulting from time away from work in order to rectify any fraud caused by a violation of the Mortgage Fraud law.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">"Victim" includes a business that loses any thing of value as a result of a violation of the Mortgage Fraud law.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Disposition of forfeited property under this subtitle shall follow the procedures in this subsection.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Whenever property is forfeited under this subtitle, the governing body where the property was seized shall sell the property at public auction.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The proceeds of a sale under this subsection shall be distributed as follows:<section prefix="(i)">first, to pay all proper expenses of the proceedings for forfeiture and sale, including expenses of seizure, maintenance of custody, advertising, and court costs;</section><section prefix="(ii)">second, for restitution as ordered by the court to victims to pay for identifiable losses resulting from the violation of the Mortgage Fraud law; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">finally, to the General Fund of the State.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
