<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcp" order_by="gcp" level="1">Criminal Procedure</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcp-15-417</section_number>
  <catch_line>This section applies only in Prince George's County....</catch_line>
  <order_by>417</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">This section applies only in Prince George's County.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The State's Attorney's salary is $150,000.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The State's Attorney's salary and expenses shall be paid in equal semimonthly installments.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The State's Attorney may appoint the number of deputy State's Attorneys and assistant State's Attorneys as authorized by law by the County Executive and County Council.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The deputy and assistant State's Attorneys serve at the pleasure of the State's Attorney.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The salary of a deputy State's Attorney shall be within the discretion of the State's Attorney but may not exceed a maximum salary authorized by law by the County Executive and County Council.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The salary of an assistant State's Attorney shall be within the discretion of the State's Attorney but may not exceed a maximum salary authorized by law by the County Executive and County Council.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">The county shall pay the salaries of the deputy and assistant State's Attorneys in equal semimonthly installments.</section>
      <section prefix="(6)">The deputy and assistant State's Attorneys:<section prefix="(i)">shall perform the work directed by the State's Attorney or as authorized by law; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">under the direction of the State's Attorney, may present cases to the grand jury, sign indictments and criminal informations, and perform other necessary duties relating to the grand jury and the operation of the office.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The State's Attorney may appoint an administrative assistant who serves at the pleasure of the State's Attorney.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The salary of the administrative assistant shall be within the discretion of the State's Attorney but may not exceed a maximum salary authorized by law by the County Executive and County Council.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">The administrative assistant is not subject to the regulations of the county merit system but is entitled to the same benefits as a county employee under the merit system.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Each eligible, full-time, nonexempt employee, as described in the Prince George's County Labor Code, of the State's Attorney's office is subject to the Prince George's County personnel law.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">Employees described in subparagraph (i) of this paragraph:<section prefix="1.">may organize and bargain collectively; and</section><section prefix="2.">are subject to the Prince George's County Labor Code with regard to collective bargaining for compensation, including pension and fringe benefits, hours, and other terms and conditions of employment.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">The County Executive is the employer of an employee described in subparagraph (i) of this paragraph for the purpose of collective bargaining for hours and compensation, including pension and fringe benefits.</section>
        <section prefix="(iv)">
          <section prefix="1.">The State's Attorney is the employer of an employee described in subparagraph (i) of this paragraph for the purpose of collective bargaining for other terms and conditions of employment.</section>
          <section prefix="2.">The funding required for a collective bargaining agreement negotiated by the State's Attorney under this subparagraph is subject to the approval of the County Executive.</section>
        </section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except in connection with duties of the office, the State's Attorney or a deputy or assistant State's Attorney may not appear as counsel or represent any party before a court or unit of the State, or political subdivision of the State.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Except as provided in subparagraph (ii) of this paragraph, the State's Attorney or a deputy or assistant State's Attorney may not engage in the private practice of law.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The State's Attorney or a deputy or assistant State's Attorney may participate in the pro bono program administered by the Prince George's County Bar Foundation.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
