<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gcp" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="14-104" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcp-14-104</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">On notification by the Governor that a vacancy exists or is about to occur in the position of State Prosecutor, the Commission shall:<section prefix="(1)">seek and review applications of proposed nominees;</section><section prefix="(2)">notify and request recommendations from the Maryland State Bar Association; and</section><section prefix="(3)">seek recommendations from members of the Commission and interested citizens and groups.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Commission shall:<section prefix="(1)">interview and evaluate each eligible applicant; and</section><section prefix="(2)">nominate to the Governor, on a vote taken by secret ballot, one or more individuals whom a majority of the authorized membership of the Commission finds to be legally and professionally qualified.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Commission shall report, in writing, to the Governor the name of the individual or individuals it nominates within 70 days after notification that a vacancy exists or is about to occur.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The Governor may reject a nominee for cause.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">If a nominee is rejected for cause, the Commission shall submit another nominee.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If the Governor rejects a nominee:<section prefix="(i)">the Governor shall send to the Commission a written statement that contains the reasons for the rejection; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">a copy of the statement of rejection shall be furnished to the nominee.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The statement shall be confidential and privileged, unless the privilege is deemed waived by the Commission by the acts of the nominee in presenting to the public the reason for the rejection.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The Commission may make the statement public.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The Governor shall exercise the power of appointment or rejection within 30 days after receipt of the Commission's report.</section>
  </text>
</law>
