<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcp" order_by="" level="1">Criminal Procedure</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcp-6-225</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>225</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section, "custodial confinement" means:<section prefix="(i)">home detention;</section><section prefix="(ii)">a corrections options program established under law which requires the individual to participate in home detention, inpatient treatment, or other similar program involving terms and conditions that constitute the equivalent of confinement; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">inpatient drug or alcohol treatment.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Custodial confinement" does not include imprisonment.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Probation may be granted whether the crime is punishable by fine or imprisonment or both.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">If the crime is punishable by both fine and imprisonment, the court may impose a fine and place the defendant on probation as to the imprisonment.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">Probation may be limited to one or more counts or indictments but, in the absence of express limitation, extends to the entire sentence and judgment.</section>
        <section prefix="(iv)">The court may revoke or modify a condition of probation or may reduce the period of probation.</section>
        <section prefix="(v)">As a condition of probation, the court may order a defendant to a term of custodial confinement.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If a sentence of imprisonment is imposed and a part of it is suspended with the defendant placed on probation, the court may impose as a condition of probation that the probation begin on the day the defendant is released from imprisonment.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">If the court places on probation a defendant who has been convicted of a violation of any provision of Title 5 of the Criminal Law Article, the court shall require as a condition that the defendant participate in a drug treatment or education program approved by the Department of Health and Mental Hygiene, unless the court finds and states on the record that the interests of the defendant and the public do not require the imposition of this condition.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The court may impose a sentence of custodial confinement or imprisonment as a condition of probation.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">If an individual violates the terms of probation, any time served by the individual in custodial confinement shall be credited against any sentence of incarceration imposed by the court.</section>
  </text>
</law>
