<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcp" order_by="" level="1">Criminal Procedure</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcp-2-208.1</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>208.1</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, "Montgomery County fire and explosive investigator" means an individual who:<section prefix="(1)">is assigned full time to the Fire and Explosive Investigations Section of the Montgomery County Fire Marshal's Office and is a paid employee;</section><section prefix="(2)">has been employed by the Montgomery County Fire and Rescue Service as a firefighter/rescuer for at least 5 years;</section><section prefix="(3)">has successfully completed a training program from a police training school approved by the Police Training Commission established under Title 3, Subtitle 2 of the Public Safety Article; and</section><section prefix="(4)">at all times maintains active certification by the Police Training Commission.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Except as provided in subsection (c) of this section, a Montgomery County fire and explosive investigator has the same authority granted to the State Fire Marshal or a full-time investigative and inspection assistant of the Office of the State Fire Marshal under &#xA7; 2-208 of this subtitle:<section prefix="(1)">while operating in Montgomery County; and</section><section prefix="(2)">while operating outside Montgomery County when:<section prefix="(i)">the Montgomery County fire and explosive investigator is participating in a joint investigation with officials from another state, federal, or local law enforcement unit, at least one of which has local jurisdiction;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the Montgomery County fire and explosive investigator is rendering assistance to another law enforcement officer;</section><section prefix="(iii)">the Montgomery County fire and explosive investigator is acting at the request of a law enforcement officer or State law enforcement officer; or</section><section prefix="(iv)">an emergency exists.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Montgomery County Fire Chief:<section prefix="(1)">may limit the authority of a Montgomery County fire and explosive investigator under this section; and</section><section prefix="(2)">shall express the limitation in a written policy.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
