<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcp" order_by="gcp" level="1">Criminal Procedure</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcp-9-112</section_number>
  <catch_line>The officer or person executing the Governor's warrant of arrest or the agent of the demanding state...</catch_line>
  <order_by>112</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The officer or person executing the Governor's warrant of arrest or the agent of the demanding state to whom the prisoner may have been delivered may, when necessary, confine the prisoner in the correctional facility of any county or municipal corporation through which the officer, person, or agent may pass.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The managing official of the correctional facility must receive and safely keep the prisoner until the officer, person, or agent having charge of the prisoner is ready to proceed.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The officer, person, or agent is chargeable with the expense of keeping the prisoner.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The officer or agent of a demanding state to whom a prisoner may have been delivered following extradition proceedings in another state, or to whom a prisoner may have been delivered after waiving extradition in another state, and who is passing through this State with the prisoner for the purpose of immediately returning the prisoner to the demanding state may, when necessary, confine the prisoner in the correctional facility of any county or municipal corporation through which the officer or agent may pass.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The managing official of the correctional facility must receive and safely keep the prisoner until the officer or agent having charge of the prisoner is ready to proceed.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The officer or agent is chargeable with the expense of keeping the prisoner.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The officer or agent shall produce and show to the managing official of the correctional facility satisfactory written evidence of the fact that the officer or agent is actually transporting the prisoner to the demanding state after a requisition by the executive authority of the demanding state.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">The prisoner is not entitled to demand a new requisition while in this State.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
