<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcp" order_by="" level="1">Criminal Procedure</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcp-11-710</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>710</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">As soon as possible but not later than 3 working days after receipt of notice of a registrant's change of address, a county in which a registrant habitually lives, vehicle or license plate information, electronic mail or Internet identifiers, or landline or cellular phone numbers, the Department shall give notice of the change:<section prefix="(1)">if the registration is premised on a conviction under federal, military, or Native American tribal law, to the designated federal unit;</section><section prefix="(2)">to any other jurisdiction or foreign country where the sex offender is required to register; and</section><section prefix="(3)"><section prefix="(i)">to each local law enforcement unit in whose county the new residence is located or where the registrant intends to habitually live; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">if the new residence or location where the registrant will habitually live is in a different state that has a registration requirement, to the designated law enforcement unit or sex offender registration unit in that state.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">As soon as possible but not later than 3 working days after receipt of notice under &#xA7; 11-705(f) of this subtitle, the Department shall give notice to the campus police agency of the institution of higher education where the registrant is commencing or terminating enrollment or employment.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">If an institution of higher education does not have a campus police agency, the notice required under this section shall be provided to the local law enforcement unit having primary law enforcement authority for the campus.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Institutions of higher education currently required to disclose campus security policy and campus crime statistics data shall advise the campus community where law enforcement agency information provided by a state concerning registered sex offenders may be obtained.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">An institution of higher education is not prohibited from disclosing information provided to the institution under this subtitle concerning registered sex offenders.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">As soon as possible but not later than 3 working days after receipt of notice under &#xA7; 11-705(g) of this subtitle, the Department shall give notice of the change of name:<section prefix="(1)">if the registration is due to a conviction under federal, military, or Native American tribal law, to the designated federal unit;</section><section prefix="(2)">to each local law enforcement unit in whose county the registrant resides or habitually lives or where a registrant who is not a resident of the State will work or attend school; and</section><section prefix="(3)">if the registrant is enrolled in or employed at an institution of higher education in the State, to:<section prefix="(i)">the campus police agency of the institution of higher education; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">if the institution does not have a campus police agency, the local law enforcement unit having primary jurisdiction for the campus.</section></section></section>
  </text>
</law>
