<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcp" order_by="gcp" level="1">Criminal Procedure</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcp-11-613</section_number>
  <catch_line>Notwithstanding any other provision of Part I of this subtitle and except as provided in subsection ...</catch_line>
  <order_by>613</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Notwithstanding any other provision of Part I of this subtitle and except as provided in subsection (b) of this section, a victim or other person or governmental unit may not execute on a judgment recorded and indexed under Part I of this subtitle if the restitution obligor:<section prefix="(1)">files a motion under the Maryland Rules to stay execution of the judgment of restitution and the motion has not been decided by the court; and</section><section prefix="(2)">challenges the conviction, sentence, or judgment of restitution by:<section prefix="(i)">filing an appeal in a State court or in federal court;</section><section prefix="(ii)">applying for leave to appeal following a plea of guilty in a circuit court;</section><section prefix="(iii)">filing a motion for exercise of revisory power by the sentencing court under the Maryland Rules;</section><section prefix="(iv)">filing an application for review of criminal sentence under Title 8 of this article; or</section><section prefix="(v)">filing a notice for in banc review under the Maryland Rules.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">If a restitution obligor has complied with the requirements of subsection (a) of this section and the court has not yet ruled on the request for a stay, a person or governmental unit may not execute on a judgment recorded and indexed under Part I of this subtitle until a court issues a final judgment that upholds the conviction, sentence, or judgment of restitution.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A person or governmental unit may not execute on a judgment recorded and indexed under Part I of this subtitle until the time has expired in which a restitution obligor may file any of the actions listed under subsection (a)(2)(i) through (v) of this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The judgment of restitution may be enforced in the same way that a monetary judgment is enforced.</section>
  </text>
</law>
