<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gcp" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="11-505" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcp-11-505</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">This section applies to a victim or victim's representative who:<section prefix="(1)">has made a written request to the Department for notification; or</section><section prefix="(2)">has filed a notification request form under &#xA7; 11-104 of this title.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If a parole release hearing is scheduled for an inmate who has been convicted of and sentenced for a crime, the victim or victim's representative has the rights provided under &#xA7; 7-801 of the Correctional Services Article.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">At a parole release hearing, a victim or victim's representative has the rights provided under &#xA7; 7-304 of the Correctional Services Article.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Whenever a person who was convicted of a violent crime as defined in &#xA7; 7-101 of the Correctional Services Article is found guilty of violating a condition of parole, the Department shall notify the victim or victim's representative as provided under &#xA7; 7-804 of the Correctional Services Article.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Whenever a warrant or subpoena is issued for a person who was convicted of a violent crime as defined in &#xA7; 7-101 of the Correctional Services Article for an alleged violation of a condition of parole, the Department shall notify the victim or victim's representative as provided under &#xA7; 7-804 of the Correctional Services Article.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Whenever a person who is sentenced is considered for a commutation, pardon, or remission of sentence, the Department shall notify the victim or victim's representative as provided under &#xA7; 7-805(b) and (f) of the Correctional Services Article.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If the person described in paragraph (1) of this subsection was convicted of a violent crime as defined in &#xA7; 7-101 of the Correctional Services Article, a victim or victim's representative has the additional rights regarding submission and consideration of a victim impact statement provided under &#xA7; 7-805(c) and (d) of the Correctional Services Article.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Whenever a person convicted of a crime of violence is found guilty of violating a condition of mandatory supervision, the Department shall notify the victim or victim's representative as provided under &#xA7; 7-505(b) of the Correctional Services Article.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Whenever a warrant or subpoena is issued for a person convicted of a violent crime as defined in &#xA7; 7-101 of the Correctional Services Article for an alleged violation of a condition of mandatory supervision, the Department shall notify the victim or victim's representative as provided under &#xA7; 7-804 of the Correctional Services Article.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">Before entering into a predetermined parole release agreement with an inmate, the Maryland Parole Commission shall notify the victim or victim's representative as provided under &#xA7; 7-803 of the Correctional Services Article.</section>
  </text>
</law>
