<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcp" order_by="gcp" level="1">Criminal Procedure</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcp-4-202.1</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this section, "child" means a defendant who is under the age of 18 years and whose case is eligib...</catch_line>
  <order_by>202.1</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, "child" means a defendant who is under the age of 18 years and whose case is eligible for transfer under the provisions of &#xA7; 4-202(b)(1) and (2) and (c) of this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">If a child remains in custody for any reason after a bail review hearing:<section prefix="(1)">in the case of a child charged with a felony that is not within the jurisdiction of the District Court, the District Court shall:<section prefix="(i)">clearly indicate on the case file and in computer records that the case involves a detained child; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">set a preliminary hearing to be held within 15 days after the bail review hearing; or</section></section><section prefix="(2)">in the case of a child charged with a crime in the District Court, the District Court:<section prefix="(i)">shall clearly indicate on the case file and in computer records that the case involves a detained child;</section><section prefix="(ii)">shall set a transfer hearing under &#xA7; 4-202 of this subtitle to be held within 30 days after the filing of the charging document;</section><section prefix="(iii)">may order that a study be made under &#xA7; 4-202 of this subtitle; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">shall require that prompt notice be given to counsel for the child, or, if the child is not represented by counsel, to the Office of the Public Defender.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">On receipt of a District Court case file that indicates that the case involves a child who was detained after a bail review hearing under subsection (b) of this section, a circuit court:<section prefix="(1)">unless previously set by the District Court under subsection (b)(2) of this section, shall set a transfer hearing under &#xA7; 4-202 of this subtitle to be held within 30 days after the filing of the charging document in the circuit court;</section><section prefix="(2)">unless previously ordered by the District Court under subsection (b)(2) of this section, may order that a study be made under &#xA7; 4-202 of this subtitle; and</section><section prefix="(3)">shall require that prompt notice be given to counsel for the child, or, if the child is not represented by counsel, to the Office of the Public Defender.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
