<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcp" order_by="gcp" level="1">Criminal Procedure</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcp-14-107</section_number>
  <catch_line>Except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, the State Prosecutor may investigate:...</catch_line>
  <order_by>107</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, the State Prosecutor may investigate:<section prefix="(i)">a criminal offense under the State election laws;</section><section prefix="(ii)">a criminal offense under the State Public Ethics Law;</section><section prefix="(iii)">a violation of the State bribery laws in which an official or employee of the State, a political subdivision of the State, or a bicounty or multicounty unit of the State was the offeror, offeree, or intended offeror or offeree of a bribe;</section><section prefix="(iv)">an offense constituting criminal malfeasance, misfeasance, or nonfeasance in office committed by an officer or employee of the State, of a political subdivision of the State, or of a bicounty or multicounty unit of the State; and</section><section prefix="(v)">a violation of the State extortion, perjury, or obstruction of justice laws related to an activity described in this paragraph.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The State Prosecutor may not investigate an offense alleged to have been committed by the State Prosecutor or a member of the State Prosecutor's staff.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The State Prosecutor may investigate an alleged offense under paragraph (1) of this subsection on the State Prosecutor's own initiative or on request of:<section prefix="(i)">the Governor;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the Attorney General;</section><section prefix="(iii)">the General Assembly;</section><section prefix="(iv)">the State Ethics Commission; or</section><section prefix="(v)">a State's Attorney.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">An individual who is advised by the State Prosecutor that the individual is under investigation under paragraph (1)(iv) of this subsection may release this information to the public, as well as any results of the investigation that pertain to the individual.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">On request of the Governor, the Attorney General, the General Assembly, or a State's Attorney, the State Prosecutor may investigate criminal activity that is committed:<section prefix="(1)">partly in the State and partly in another jurisdiction; or</section><section prefix="(2)">in more than one political subdivision of the State.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
