<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcp" order_by="gcp" level="1">Criminal Procedure</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcp-9-113</section_number>
  <catch_line>This section applies whenever:...</catch_line>
  <order_by>113</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">This section applies whenever:<section prefix="(1)">it is charged on the oath of a credible witness before a judge or District Court commissioner that a person in this State:<section prefix="(i)">has committed a crime in another state and, except in cases arising under &#xA7; 9-106 of this title, has fled from justice; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">has been convicted of a crime in another state and has escaped from confinement or has broken the terms of bail, probation, or parole; or</section></section><section prefix="(2)">complaint is made before a judge or District Court commissioner in this State setting forth on the affidavit of a credible person in another state that a person is believed to be in this State and:<section prefix="(i)">that a crime has been committed in the other state, the person has been charged in the other state with committing the crime and, except in cases arising under &#xA7; 9-106 of this title, the person has fled from justice; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">that the person has been convicted of a crime in the other state and has escaped from confinement or has broken the terms of bail, probation, or parole.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A judge or District Court commissioner shall issue a warrant directed to any law enforcement officer commanding the officer to apprehend the person named therein, wherever found in this State, and to bring the person before the judge, District Court commissioner, or any other judge or court available in or convenient to the place where the arrest may be made, to answer the charge or complaint and affidavit.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A certified copy of the sworn charge or complaint and affidavit upon which the warrant is issued shall be attached to the warrant.</section>
  </text>
</law>
