<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gcp" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="5-210" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcp-5-210</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Agent" means a person that acts or is authorized to act as the representative of a bail bondsman.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">"Bail bondsman" means a licensed limited surety agent or a licensed professional bail bondsman.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">"Bail bondsman" does not include a person that contracts with a public agency to provide bail bonds to persons detained in a correctional facility.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">On the grounds of a courthouse or correctional facility, a bail bondsman, an agent of a bail bondsman, an employee of the courthouse, or an employee of a correctional facility may not:<section prefix="(1)">approach, entice, or invite a person to use the services of a specific bail bondsman;</section><section prefix="(2)">distribute, display, or wear an item that advertises the services of a bail bondsman; or</section><section prefix="(3)">otherwise solicit business as a bail bondsman.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A person who violates subsection (b) of this section is guilty of a misdemeanor and on conviction is subject to:<section prefix="(1)">a fine not exceeding $2,500, and if licensed in accordance with the Insurance Article, a 30-day license suspension for a first offense; and</section><section prefix="(2)">a fine not exceeding $5,000, and if licensed in accordance with the Insurance Article, a 90-day license suspension for a subsequent offense.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A person convicted of a violation of subsection (b) of this section shall be referred to the Insurance Commissioner for appropriate action.</section>
  </text>
</law>
