<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcp" order_by="" level="1">Criminal Procedure</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcp-3-108</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>108</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In addition to any other report required under this title, the Health Department shall report to the court that has ordered commitment of a defendant under &#xA7; 3-106 of this title:<section prefix="(i)">every 6 months from the date of commitment of the defendant; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">whenever the Health Department determines that:<section prefix="1.">the defendant no longer is incompetent to stand trial;</section><section prefix="2.">the defendant no longer is, because of mental retardation  or a mental disorder, a danger to self or the person or property of others; or</section><section prefix="3.">there is not a substantial likelihood that the defendant will become competent to stand trial in the foreseeable future.</section></section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Department shall include a supplemental report that provides a plan for services to facilitate the defendant remaining competent to stand trial or not dangerous, as a result of mental retardation or a mental disorder, to self or the person or property of others, if:<section prefix="(i)">a report required under this title states an opinion that the defendant is competent to stand trial or is not dangerous, as a result of mental retardation or a mental disorder, to self or the person or property of others; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">services are necessary to maintain the defendant safely in the community, to maintain competency, or to restore competency.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">If appropriate, the plan required in the report under paragraph (2) of this subsection shall include recommended:<section prefix="(i)">mental health treatment, including providers of care;</section><section prefix="(ii)">vocational, rehabilitative, or support services;</section><section prefix="(iii)">housing;</section><section prefix="(iv)">case management services;</section><section prefix="(v)">alcohol or substance abuse treatment; and</section><section prefix="(vi)">other clinical services.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">If the report required under paragraph (2) of this subsection recommends community placement for the defendant, the report shall include:<section prefix="(i)">the location of the recommended community placement;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the names and addresses of the recommended service providers;</section><section prefix="(iii)">a statement indicating if the service provider is willing and able to serve the defendant; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">if available, the date of placement or service for the defendant.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(5)">If the plan required in the report under paragraph (2) of this subsection is for a defendant committed to a State residential center, the report shall state whether:<section prefix="(i)">the defendant meets the requirements for commitment under &#xA7; 3-106(d) of this title;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the services required for the defendant may be provided in a less restrictive setting; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">the defendant is eligible for services pursuant to &#xA7; 7-404 of the Health - General Article.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(6)">If the report required under paragraph (2) of this subsection states an opinion that there is not a substantial likelihood that the defendant will become competent in the foreseeable future, the report shall contain an opinion regarding whether the defendant meets the criteria for commitment under &#xA7; 3-106(d) of this title.</section>
      <section prefix="(7)">A statement made by the defendant in the course of any examination for a report under this section is not admissible as evidence in any criminal proceeding for the purpose of proving the commission of a criminal offense or to enhance the sentence of the defendant.</section>
      <section prefix="(8)">A report prepared under this section is not admissible in a criminal proceeding for the purpose of proving the commission of a criminal offense or to enhance the sentence of the defendant.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The clerk of court shall give the State's Attorney and the last counsel of record for the defendant a copy of any report received under this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The facility of the Health Department that has charge of a person committed as incompetent to stand trial shall notify the Criminal Justice Information System Central Repository if the person escapes.</section>
  </text>
</law>
