<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcp" order_by="" level="1">Criminal Procedure</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcp-15-412</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>412</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">This section applies only in Garrett County.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The county commissioners shall set the State's Attorney's salary in accordance with Chapter 91 of the Public Local Laws of Garrett County.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The State's Attorney's allowance for office expenses shall be at least $10,000.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">An allowance of more than $10,000 shall be at the discretion of the county commissioners.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Subject to the approval of the county commissioners and as provided for in the county budget, the State's Attorney may appoint assistant State's Attorneys.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">An assistant State's Attorney shall:<section prefix="(i)">serve at the pleasure of the State's Attorney; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">receive a salary of at least $25,000.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Subject to the approval of the county commissioners and if provided for in the county budget, the State's Attorney may appoint investigators who shall:<section prefix="(i)">be law enforcement officers in the State; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">have the same powers, rights, protections, and benefits as a county deputy sheriff.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The State's Attorney may employ clerical, administrative, investigative, and other staff necessary for the proper conduct of the office.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">Subject to the approval of the county commissioners and in conformity with the county pay and classification plans, the State's Attorney shall set the salaries and classifications for the employees described in subparagraph (i) of this paragraph.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The State's Attorney shall serve full time.</section>
  </text>
</law>
