<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gcp" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="4-203" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcp-4-203</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Corporation" includes a joint-stock company and an association.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Limited liability company" includes a limited liability partnership and a limited liability limited partnership.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">If a charging document is filed against a corporation or limited liability company, the clerk of court may issue a summons to the corporation or limited liability company in its corporate or company name to appear at the court to answer the charging document.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A summons served under subsection (b) of this section may be served in the same manner as provided for service of process in a civil suit under the Maryland Rules.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If a sheriff or other officer returns a summons served under this section as "summoned" or "served":<section prefix="(i)">the corporation or limited liability company to whom the summons was issued shall be considered as in court and as appearing to the charging document; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">the court shall order the clerk to enter an appearance for the corporation or limited liability company and to endorse a plea of not guilty on the charging document.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">After the clerk makes the entry and endorsement specified in paragraph (1)(ii) of this subsection, further proceedings may occur concerning the charging document in the same manner as if the corporation or limited liability company had appeared and pleaded not guilty.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If a corporation or limited liability company is served a summons under this section and is convicted on the charging document, a court may:<section prefix="(i)">pass a judgment concerning the charging document; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">issue process of execution to the sheriff of the county against the property of the corporation or limited liability company for the amount of the fine and costs that may be awarded against the corporation or limited liability company in the same manner as on a judgment in a civil action.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A sheriff shall sell the property of the corporation or limited liability company on an execution under paragraph (1) of this subsection in the same manner as on an execution issued in a civil suit.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
