<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gcp" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="11-601" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcp-11-601</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In Part I of this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Central Collection Unit" means the Central Collection Unit in the Department of Budget and Management.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Child" means a person under the age of 18 years.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Crime" means an act committed by a person in the State that is a crime under:<section prefix="(i)">common law;</section><section prefix="(ii)">&#xA7; 109 of the Code of Public Local Laws of Caroline County;</section><section prefix="(iii)">&#xA7; 4-103 of the Code of Public Local Laws of Carroll County;</section><section prefix="(iv)">&#xA7; 8A-1 of the Code of Public Local Laws of Talbot County; or</section><section prefix="(v)">except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, the Annotated Code.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Crime" does not include a violation of the Transportation Article that is not punishable by a term of confinement.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"Defendant" means a person:<section prefix="(1)">who has received probation before judgment;</section><section prefix="(2)">who has been found guilty of a crime, even if the defendant has been found not criminally responsible; or</section><section prefix="(3)">whose plea of nolo contendere to a crime has been accepted by the court.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">"Division" means the Division of Parole and Probation.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">"Judgment of restitution" means a direct order for payment of restitution or an order for payment of restitution that is a condition of probation in an order of probation.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">"Liable parent" means a parent:<section prefix="(1)">whose child has committed a crime or delinquent act; and</section><section prefix="(2)">who has been ordered to pay restitution under &#xA7; 11-604 of this subtitle.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(i)">"Restitution obligor" means a defendant, child respondent, or liable parent against whom a judgment of restitution has been entered.</section>
    <section prefix="(j)">"Victim" means:<section prefix="(1)">a person who suffers death, personal injury, or property damage or loss as a direct result of a crime or delinquent act; or</section><section prefix="(2)">if the person is deceased, the personal representative of the estate of the person.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
