<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcp" order_by="gcp" level="1">Criminal Procedure</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcp-13-203</section_number>
  <catch_line>By an appropriate inquiry and investigation, the seizing authority shall attempt to identify and loc...</catch_line>
  <order_by>203</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">By an appropriate inquiry and investigation, the seizing authority shall attempt to identify and locate the owner of a handgun that is seized.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If the owner is a resident of the State, the seizing authority may return the handgun to the owner.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">If the owner of the handgun is not a resident of the State, the seizing authority shall send the handgun for disposition to the appropriate law enforcement unit where the owner is a resident if the handgun:<section prefix="(i)">is not needed for investigation or evidence; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">is not disposed of under subsection (b) of this section.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If the seizing authority under subsection (a) of this section does not return the handgun to its owner, the seizing authority shall promptly notify the owner that the owner may apply within 30 days to the seizing authority for a review to determine whether the owner knew or should have known that the handgun was worn, carried, transported, or used in violation of &#xA7; 4-203 or &#xA7; 4-204 of the Criminal Law Article, and whether the owner is qualified to possess the handgun.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Qualification for possession of a handgun is the same as for sale or transfer of a handgun under &#xA7;&#xA7; 5-103, 5-104, 5-118, 5-119, 5-120, 5-121, 5-122, 5-123, 5-124, 5-125, 5-126, and 5-127 of the Public Safety Article.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A person who knowingly gives false information or makes a material misstatement in an application for review or an investigation relating to an application is subject to the penalties under &#xA7; 5-139 of the Public Safety Article.</section>
  </text>
</law>
