<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcp" order_by="" level="1">Criminal Procedure</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcp-10-214</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>214</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Each criminal justice unit shall report in accordance with this section the criminal history record information that it collects to the Central Repository.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Subject to subsection (c) of this section:<section prefix="(1)">the data pertaining to an arrest or the issuance of an arrest warrant shall be reported within 72 hours after the earlier of the arrest or the issuance of the arrest warrant; and</section><section prefix="(2)">the data pertaining to any other reportable event shall be reported within 60 days after the reportable event occurs.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Secretary by regulation or the Court of Appeals by rule may reduce the time for reporting the criminal history record information specified in subsection (b) of this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The criminal history record information may be reported under subsection (b) of this section to the Central Repository:<section prefix="(1)">directly by the criminal justice unit;</section><section prefix="(2)">if the criminal history record information can be readily collected and reported through the court system, by the Administrative Office of the Courts; or</section><section prefix="(3)">if the criminal history record information can be readily collected and reported through criminal justice units that are part of a geographically based information system, by those criminal justice units.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A criminal justice unit may maintain criminal history record information that is more detailed than required for reporting to the Central Repository.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A criminal justice unit may disseminate criminal history record information maintained under paragraph (1) of this subsection only in accordance with &#xA7; 10-219 of this subtitle.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
