<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gcp" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="11-107" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcp-11-107</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In Part II of this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Charged" means to be the subject of an indictment, an information, or a petition alleging a delinquent act.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Health officer" has the meaning stated in &#xA7; 1-101 of the Health - General Article.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">"HIV" means any human immunodeficiency virus that causes Acquired Immune Deficiency Syndrome (AIDS).</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Prohibited exposure" means a crime or delinquent act that may have caused or resulted in exposure to HIV.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Prohibited exposure" includes:<section prefix="(i)">contact that occurs on penetration, however slight, between the penis and the vulva or anus; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">contact between the mouth and the penis, vulva, or anus.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Victim" means the victim of a prohibited exposure.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Victim" includes:<section prefix="(i)">a law enforcement officer who is exposed to HIV while acting in the performance of duty;</section><section prefix="(ii)">a paid or volunteer firefighter, an emergency medical technician, or rescue squad member who is exposed to HIV while acting in the performance of duty; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">a forensic scientist, working under the direction of a law enforcement agency, who is exposed to HIV while acting in the performance of duty.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">"Victim's representative" means:<section prefix="(1)">the parent of a victim who is a minor;</section><section prefix="(2)">the legal guardian of a victim; or</section><section prefix="(3)">the person authorized to give consent for the victim under &#xA7; 5-605 of the Health - General Article.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
