<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gcp" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="11-603" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcp-11-603</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">A court may enter a judgment of restitution that orders a defendant or child respondent to make restitution in addition to any other penalty for the commission of a crime or delinquent act, if:<section prefix="(1)">as a direct result of the crime or delinquent act, property of the victim was stolen, damaged, destroyed, converted, or unlawfully obtained, or its value substantially decreased;</section><section prefix="(2)">as a direct result of the crime or delinquent act, the victim suffered:<section prefix="(i)">actual medical, dental, hospital, counseling, funeral, or burial expenses or losses;</section><section prefix="(ii)">direct out-of-pocket loss;</section><section prefix="(iii)">loss of earnings; or</section><section prefix="(iv)">expenses incurred with rehabilitation;</section></section><section prefix="(3)">the victim incurred medical expenses that were paid by the Department of Health and Mental Hygiene or any other governmental unit;</section><section prefix="(4)">a governmental unit incurred expenses in removing, towing, transporting, preserving, storing, selling, or destroying an abandoned vehicle as defined in &#xA7; 25-201 of the Transportation Article;</section><section prefix="(5)">the Criminal Injuries Compensation Board paid benefits to a victim; or</section><section prefix="(6)">the Department of Health and Mental Hygiene or other governmental unit paid expenses incurred under Subtitle 1, Part II of this title.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A victim is presumed to have a right to restitution under subsection (a) of this section if:<section prefix="(1)">the victim or the State requests restitution; and</section><section prefix="(2)">the court is presented with competent evidence of any item listed in subsection (a) of this section.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A judgment of restitution does not preclude the property owner or the victim who suffered personal physical or mental injury, out-of-pocket loss of earnings, or support from bringing a civil action to recover damages from the restitution obligor.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A civil verdict shall be reduced by the amount paid under the criminal judgment of restitution.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">In making a disposition on a finding that a child at least 13 years old has committed an act of graffiti under &#xA7; 6-301(d) of the Criminal Law Article, the court shall order the child to perform community service or pay restitution or both.</section>
  </text>
</law>
