<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gcp" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="1-203" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcp-1-203</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A circuit court judge or District Court judge may issue forthwith a search warrant whenever it is made to appear to the judge, by application as described in paragraph (2) of this subsection, that there is probable cause to believe that:<section prefix="(i)">a misdemeanor or felony is being committed by a person or in a building, apartment, premises, place, or thing within the territorial jurisdiction of the judge; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">property subject to seizure under the criminal laws of the State is on the person or in or on the building, apartment, premises, place, or thing.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">An application for a search warrant shall be:</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">An application for a search warrant may contain a request that the search warrant authorize the executing law enforcement officer to enter the building, apartment, premises, place, or thing to be searched without giving notice of the officer's authority or purpose, on the grounds that there is reasonable suspicion to believe that, without the authorization:</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The search warrant shall:<section prefix="(i)">be directed to a duly constituted police officer, the State Fire Marshal, or a full-time investigative and inspection assistant of the Office of the State Fire Marshal and authorize the police officer, the State Fire Marshal, or a full-time investigative and inspection assistant of the Office of the State Fire Marshal to search the suspected person, building, apartment, premises, place, or thing and to seize any property found subject to seizure under the criminal laws of the State;</section><section prefix="(ii)">name or describe, with reasonable particularity:</section><section prefix="(iii)">if warranted by application as described in paragraph (2) of this subsection, authorize the executing law enforcement officer to enter the building, apartment, premises, place, or thing to be searched without giving notice of the officer's authority or purpose.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The search and seizure under the authority of a search warrant shall be made within 15 calendar days after the day that the search warrant is issued.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">After the expiration of the 15-day period, the search warrant is void.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A circuit court judge or District Court judge shall cause property taken under a search warrant to be restored to the person from whom it was taken if, at any time, on application to the judge, it appears that:<section prefix="(i)">the property taken is not the same as that described in the search warrant;</section><section prefix="(ii)">there is no probable cause for believing the existence of the grounds on which the search warrant was issued; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">the property was taken under a search warrant issued more than 15 calendar days before the seizure.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The judge may receive an oral motion made in open court at any time making application for the return of seized property if the application for return is based on any ground described in paragraph (1) of this subsection.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">If the judge grants the oral motion described in paragraph (2) of this subsection, the order of the court shall be in writing and a copy of the order shall be sent to the State's Attorney.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">Court costs may not be assessed against the person from whom the property was taken if:<section prefix="(i)">the judge denies the oral motion and requires the person from whom the property was taken to proceed for return of the seized property by petition and an order to show cause to the police authority seizing the property; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">it is later ordered that the property be restored to the person from whom it was taken.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(5)">If the judge finds that the property taken is the same as that described in the search warrant and that there is probable cause for believing the existence of the grounds on which the search warrant was issued, the judge shall order the property to be retained in the custody of the police authority seizing it or to be otherwise disposed of according to law.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This subsection does not apply to contraband or other property prohibited by law from being recoverable.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Property seized under a search warrant issued under subsection (a) of this section may be returned to the person to whom the property belongs without the necessity of that person bringing an action for replevin or any other proceeding against the unit with custody of the property if:<section prefix="(i)">the criminal case in which the property was seized is disposed of because of a nolle prosequi, dismissal, or acquittal;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the State does not appeal the criminal case in which the property was seized; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">the time for appeal has expired.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A circuit court judge or District Court judge shall cause property rightfully taken under a search warrant to be restored to the person from whom it was taken if, at any time, on application to the judge, the judge finds that the property is being wrongfully withheld after there is no further need for retention of the property.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The judge may receive an oral motion made in open court at any time making application for the return of seized property if the application for return is based on the ground that the property, although rightfully taken under a search warrant, is being wrongfully withheld after there is no further need for retention of the property.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">If the judge grants the oral motion described in paragraph (2) of this subsection, the order of the court shall be in writing and a copy of the order shall be sent to the State's Attorney.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">Court costs may not be assessed against the person from whom the property was taken if:<section prefix="(i)">the judge denies the oral motion and requires the person from whom the property was taken to proceed for return of the seized property by petition and an order to show cause to the police authority wrongfully withholding the property; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">it is later ordered that the property be restored to the person from whom it was taken.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Notwithstanding any provision of the Maryland Rules, a circuit court judge or District Court judge, on a finding of good cause, may order that an affidavit presented in support of a search and seizure warrant be sealed for a period not exceeding 30 days.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A finding of good cause required by paragraph (1) of this subsection is established by evidence that:<section prefix="(i)">the criminal investigation to which the affidavit is related is of a continuing nature and likely to yield further information that could be of use in prosecuting alleged criminal activities; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">the failure to maintain the confidentiality of the investigation would:</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A court may grant one 30-day extension of the time that an affidavit presented in support of a search and seizure warrant is to remain sealed if:<section prefix="(i)">law enforcement provides continued evidence as described in paragraph (2) of this subsection; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">the court makes a finding of good cause based on the evidence.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">After the order sealing the affidavit expires, the affidavit shall be:<section prefix="(i)">unsealed; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">delivered within 15 days:</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
