<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gcp" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="8-302" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcp-8-302</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">A person convicted of prostitution under &#xA7; 11-306 of the Criminal Law Article may file a motion to vacate the judgment if, when the person committed the act or acts of prostitution, the person was acting under duress caused by an act of another committed in violation of the prohibition against human trafficking under &#xA7; 11-303 of the Criminal Law Article or under federal law.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A motion filed under this section shall:<section prefix="(1)">be in writing;</section><section prefix="(2)">be signed and consented to by the State's Attorney;</section><section prefix="(3)">be made within a reasonable period of time after the conviction; and</section><section prefix="(4)">describe the evidence and provide copies of any documents showing that the defendant is entitled to relief under this section.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, the court shall hold a hearing on a motion filed under this section if the motion satisfies the requirements of subsection (b) of this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The court may dismiss a motion without a hearing if the court finds that the motion fails to assert grounds on which relief may be granted.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In ruling on a motion filed under this section, the court may vacate the conviction, modify the sentence, or grant a new trial.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The court shall state the reasons for its ruling on the record.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">A defendant in a proceeding under this section has the burden of proof.</section>
  </text>
</law>
