<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcp" order_by="" level="1">Criminal Procedure</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcp-11-725</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>725</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Under the supervision of the Division of Parole and Probation, a sexual offender management team shall conduct lifetime sexual offender supervision and the supervision of probation, parole, or mandatory release of a person subject to lifetime sexual offender supervision.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A sexual offender management team:<section prefix="(1)">consists of:<section prefix="(i)">a specially trained parole and probation agent; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">a representative of a sexual offender treatment program or provider; and</section></section><section prefix="(2)">may include:<section prefix="(i)">victim advocates or victim service providers with recognized expertise in sexual abuse and victimization;</section><section prefix="(ii)">faith counselors;</section><section prefix="(iii)">employment counselors;</section><section prefix="(iv)">community leaders;</section><section prefix="(v)">a polygraph examiner with recognized expertise in sexual offender-specific polygraph examination;</section><section prefix="(vi)">a law enforcement officer;</section><section prefix="(vii)">an assistant State's Attorney;</section><section prefix="(viii)">an assistant public defender; and</section><section prefix="(ix)">a foreign or sign language interpreter.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A sexual offender management team shall submit a progress report on each person under supervision to the sentencing court, or juvenile court in the case of a person who is required to register under &#xA7; 11-704(c) of this subtitle, once every 6 months.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Unless disclosure of a report would be in violation of laws regarding confidentiality of treatment records, a sexual offender management team shall provide copies of each progress report to local law enforcement units of the county in which the person resides.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
