<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcp" order_by="gcp" level="1">Criminal Procedure</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcp-10-242</section_number>
  <catch_line>To the extent authorized by Section 552A of Title 5, (commonly known as the "Privacy Act of 1974"), ...</catch_line>
  <order_by>242</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">To the extent authorized by Section 552A of Title 5, (commonly known as the "Privacy Act of 1974"), the FBI shall provide on request criminal history records (excluding sealed records) to state criminal history records repositories for noncriminal justice purposes allowed by federal statute, federal executive order, or a state statute that has been approved by the Attorney General and that authorizes national indices checks.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The FBI, to the extent authorized by Section 552A of Title 5, (commonly known as the "Privacy Act of 1974"), and state criminal history records repositories shall provide criminal history records (excluding sealed records) to criminal justice agencies and other governmental or nongovernmental agencies for noncriminal justice purposes allowed by federal statute, federal executive order, or a state statute that has been approved by the Attorney General, that authorizes national indices checks.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Any record obtained under this Compact may be used only for the official purposes for which the record was requested. Each Compact officer shall establish procedures, consistent with this Compact, and with rules, procedures, and standards established by the Council under Section 10-244 of this subtitle, which procedures shall protect the accuracy and privacy of the records, and shall:<section prefix="(1)">ensure that records obtained under this Compact are used only by authorized officials for authorized purposes;</section><section prefix="(2)">require that subsequent record checks are requested to obtain current information whenever a new need arises; and</section><section prefix="(3)">ensure that record entries that may not legally be used for a particular noncriminal justice purpose are deleted from the response and, if no information authorized for release remains, an appropriate "no record" response is communicated to the requesting official.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
