<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcp" order_by="" level="1">Criminal Procedure</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcp-11-809</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>809</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A claimant shall file a claim not later than 3 years after the occurrence of the crime or delinquent act or the death of the victim.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">In a case of child abuse, a claimant may file a claim up to 3 years after the claimant knew or should have known of the child abuse.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Claims shall be filed in the office of the Board in person or by mail.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Board shall:<section prefix="(i)">accept for filing each claim that meets the requirements of this subtitle and the regulations of the Board; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">notify the claimant within 10 days after receipt of the claim.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">In this subsection, "debt collection activities" means:<section prefix="1.">repeatedly calling or writing to a claimant and threatening to refer the unpaid health care matter to a debt collection agency or to an attorney for collection; or</section><section prefix="2.">filing a legal action or pursuing any legal process or legal proceeding.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">"Debt collection activities" does not include routine billing or inquiries about the status of the claim.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">When a claimant files a claim under this subtitle, all health care providers, as defined in &#xA7; 3-2A-01(e) of the Courts Article and in &#xA7; 4-301(g) of the Health - General Article, that have been given notice of a pending claim shall refrain from all debt collection activities relating to health care, as defined in &#xA7; 4-301(f) of the Health - General Article, received by the claimant in connection with a claim until a final decision is made by the Secretary on the claim.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">On filing by a party of a notice of a claim filed under this subtitle, a court shall stay all proceedings in an action related to health care provided to a claimant in connection with the claim until the court is notified that a final decision on the claim has been made.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">Claimants under this subtitle are protected under the Maryland Consumer Debt Collection Act in Title 14, Subtitle 2 of the Commercial Law Article.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">
        <section prefix="(i)">A health care provider who receives notice that a claim has been filed under this subtitle may notify the Board in writing of the debt owed by the claimant in connection with the claim.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">If a health care provider notifies the Board under subparagraph (i) of this paragraph, the Board shall notify the health care provider in writing when a final decision is made on the claim.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(6)">After a final decision on the claim under this subtitle, a health care provider that has received notice of a pending claim under this subtitle may engage in debt collection activities or file a civil action in court until the later of:<section prefix="(i)">the expiration of the time for filing a civil action in court; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">6 months after the date of the final decision on the claim under this subtitle.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
