<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcp" order_by="gcp" level="1">Criminal Procedure</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcp-11-302</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this section the following words have the meanings indicated....</catch_line>
  <order_by>302</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Representative" means a person who is designated by:<section prefix="(i)">the next of kin or guardian of a victim who is deceased or disabled; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">the court in a dispute over who will be the representative.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Victim" means a person who is the victim of a crime or delinquent act.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">This section applies to:<section prefix="(1)">a criminal trial; and</section><section prefix="(2)">a juvenile delinquency adjudicatory hearing that is held in open court or that a victim or representative may attend under &#xA7; 3-8A-13 of the Courts Article.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Except as provided in subsections (d) and (e) of this section:<section prefix="(1)">a representative has the right to be present at the trial of the defendant or juvenile delinquency adjudicatory hearing of the child respondent; and</section><section prefix="(2)">after initially testifying, a victim has the right to be present at the trial of the defendant or juvenile delinquency adjudicatory hearing of the child respondent.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The court may sequester a representative or, after a victim has initially testified, the victim from any part of the trial or juvenile delinquency adjudicatory hearing on request of the defendant, child respondent, or the State only after the court determines, with specific findings of fact on the record, that:<section prefix="(1)">there is reason to believe that the victim will be recalled or the representative will be called to testify at the trial or juvenile delinquency adjudicatory hearing; and</section><section prefix="(2)">the presence of the victim or representative would influence the victim's or representative's future testimony in a manner that would materially affect a defendant's right to a fair trial or a child respondent's right to a fair hearing.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The court may remove a victim or representative from the trial or juvenile delinquency adjudicatory hearing for the same causes and in the same manner as the law provides for the exclusion or removal of a defendant or a child respondent.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">As provided in &#xA7; 9-205 of the Courts Article, a person may not be deprived of employment solely because of job time lost because the person attended a proceeding that the person has a right to attend under this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">This section does not limit a victim's or representative's right to attend a trial or juvenile delinquency adjudicatory hearing as provided in &#xA7; 3-8A-13 of the Courts Article or &#xA7; 11-102 of this title.</section>
  </text>
</law>
