<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gcp" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="10-102" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcp-10-102</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">A police record or a court record is subject to expungement under this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A court record or a police record that existed before July 1, 1975, and is still maintained, may be expunged under this subtitle.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A person who is entitled to the expungement of a court record or a police record that existed before July 1, 1975, may use the procedures for expungement provided under this subtitle.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The limitation periods provided in &#xA7; 10-105 of this subtitle begin when the person becomes entitled to expungement of a court record or a police record that existed before July 1, 1975.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The custodian of court records or police records that were made before July 1, 1975, and that may be expunged under this subtitle:<section prefix="(i)">shall make a reasonable search for a record requested for expungement; but</section><section prefix="(ii)">need not expunge a court record or a police record that is not found after a reasonable search.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">This subtitle does not apply to:<section prefix="(1)">a record about a minor traffic violation;</section><section prefix="(2)">the published opinion of a court;</section><section prefix="(3)">a cash receipt or disbursement record that is necessary for audit purposes;</section><section prefix="(4)">a transcript of court proceedings made by a court reporter in a multiple defendant case;</section><section prefix="(5)">an investigatory file; or</section><section prefix="(6)">a record of the work product of a law enforcement unit that is used solely for police investigation.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
