<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcp" order_by="" level="1">Criminal Procedure</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcp-15-413</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>413</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">This section applies only in Harford County.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The State's Attorney's salary is $98,500.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Subject to paragraph (3) of this subsection, on or after July 1 of each year, the salary shall be adjusted using the annual Consumer Price Index that is published by the U.S. Bureau of Labor Statistics:<section prefix="(i)">for the period ending each December;</section><section prefix="(ii)">for all regions; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">to reflect the annual change in the "Consumer Price Index" for "All urban consumers" for the expenditure category "All items not seasonally adjusted".</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The annual adjustment under paragraph (2) of this subsection may not exceed 3% in a fiscal year.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The county government shall pay all reasonable expenses for the conduct of the office.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The State's Attorney may appoint:<section prefix="(i)">not more than two deputy State's Attorneys; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">the number of assistant State's Attorneys authorized by the County Executive and County Council.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The deputy and assistant State's Attorneys:<section prefix="(i)">serve at the pleasure of the State's Attorney;</section><section prefix="(ii)">receive compensation as provided by the County Executive and County Council; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">have the same legal powers as the State's Attorney to represent the State before the grand jury and in criminal proceedings.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The State's Attorney may appoint a secretary or clerical assistant who shall:<section prefix="(i)">serve at the pleasure of the State's Attorney; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">receive a salary that conforms to the exempt classification and pay plan authorized by the County Executive and County Council.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The State's Attorney may employ clerical, administrative, investigative, and other staff necessary for the proper conduct of the office.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">Subject to the approval of the County Executive and County Council and in conformity with the county pay and classification plans, the State's Attorney shall set salaries and classifications for employees appointed under this paragraph.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">An employee appointed under this paragraph is entitled to the same benefits as a similarly classified county employee.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">Except in connection with performing the duties of the office, the State's Attorney may not engage in the private practice of law or appear as counsel or represent any party before a court or unit of the State or a political subdivision of the State.</section>
  </text>
</law>
