<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcp" order_by="gcp" level="1">Criminal Procedure</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcp-16-303</section_number>
  <catch_line>There are four regional advisory boards of the Office....</catch_line>
  <order_by>303</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">There are four regional advisory boards of the Office.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Each regional advisory board consists of five members appointed by the Governor.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Of the four regional advisory boards:<section prefix="(1)">the first shall advise public defender districts one, eight, and nine, which encompass Baltimore City, Baltimore County, and Harford County;</section><section prefix="(2)">the second shall advise public defender districts two and three, which encompass Caroline County, Cecil County, Dorchester County, Kent County, Queen Anne's County, Somerset County, Talbot County, Wicomico County, and Worcester County;</section><section prefix="(3)">the third shall advise public defender districts four, five, and seven, which encompass Anne Arundel County, Calvert County, Charles County, Prince George's County, and St. Mary's County; and</section><section prefix="(4)">the fourth shall advise public defender districts six, ten, eleven, and twelve, which encompass Allegany County, Carroll County, Frederick County, Garrett County, Howard County, Montgomery County, and Washington County.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Each member of a regional advisory board shall be:<section prefix="(1)">a resident of a district represented by that regional advisory board; and</section><section prefix="(2)"><section prefix="(i)">a judge of a circuit court;</section><section prefix="(ii)">a judge of the District Court; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">an active attorney admitted to practice before the Court of Appeals of Maryland.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The term of a member of a regional advisory board is 3 years.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A vacancy occurring on a regional advisory board during the term of a member shall be filled by the Governor for the remainder of the unexpired term.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Governor shall annually designate a chair of each regional advisory board from among the members of that regional advisory board.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The chair shall preside over and represent the interests of that regional advisory board in carrying out this title.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">Three members of a regional advisory board are a quorum.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Each regional advisory board shall hold at least one regular annual meeting at a time and place that the chair designates.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Additional meetings may be called:<section prefix="(i)">on notice by the chair;</section><section prefix="(ii)">on notice by the Public Defender;</section><section prefix="(iii)">on notice by the district public defender from a district represented by that regional advisory board; or</section><section prefix="(iv)">at the request of at least three members of the regional advisory board.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(i)">A member of a regional advisory board:<section prefix="(1)">may not receive compensation for serving on the regional advisory board; but</section><section prefix="(2)">is entitled to reimbursement for expenses under the Standard State Travel Regulations, as provided in the State budget.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
