<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcp" order_by="" level="1">Criminal Procedure</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcp-11-708</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>708</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">When a registrant registers, the supervising authority shall:<section prefix="(1)">give written notice to the registrant of the requirements of this subtitle;</section><section prefix="(2)">explain the requirements of this subtitle to the registrant, including:<section prefix="(i)">the duties of a registrant when the registrant changes residence address in this State or changes the county in which the registrant habitually lives;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the duties of a registrant under &#xA7; 11-705 of this subtitle;</section><section prefix="(iii)">the requirement for a sex offender to register in person with the local law enforcement unit of each county where the sex offender will reside or habitually live or where the sex offender who is not a resident of this State is a transient or will work or attend school; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">the requirement that if the registrant changes residence address, employment, or school enrollment to another state that has a registration requirement, the registrant shall register with the designated law enforcement unit or sex offender registration unit of that state within 3 days after the change; and</section></section><section prefix="(3)">obtain a statement signed by the registrant acknowledging that the supervising authority explained the requirements of this subtitle and gave written notice of the requirements to the registrant.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The supervising authority shall obtain an updated digital image, fingerprints, and palm prints of the registrant and forward the updated digital image, fingerprints, and palm prints to the Department.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">For a registrant who has not submitted a DNA sample, as defined in &#xA7; 2-501 of the Public Safety Article, for inclusion in the statewide DNA database system of the Department of State Police Crime Laboratory, the supervising authority shall:<section prefix="(i)">obtain a DNA sample from the registrant at the registrant's initial registration; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">provide the sample to the statewide DNA database system of the Department of State Police Crime Laboratory.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Within 3 days after obtaining a registration statement, the supervising authority shall send a copy of the registration statement with the attached fingerprints, palm prints, and updated digital image of the registrant to the local law enforcement unit in each county where the registrant will reside or habitually live or where a registrant who is not a resident is a transient or will work or attend school.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">If the registrant is enrolled in or carries on employment at, or is expecting to enroll in or carry on employment at, an institution of higher education in the State, within 3 days after obtaining a registration statement, the supervising authority shall send a copy of the registration statement with the attached fingerprints, palm prints, and updated digital image of the registrant to the campus police agency of the institution of higher education.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">If an institution of higher education does not have a campus police agency, the copy of the registration statement with the attached fingerprints, palm prints, and updated digital image of the registrant shall be provided to the local law enforcement agency having primary jurisdiction for the campus.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">As soon as possible but not later than 3 working days after the registration is complete, a supervising authority that is not a unit of the Department shall send the registration statement to the Department.</section>
  </text>
</law>
