<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcp" order_by="gcp" level="1">Criminal Procedure</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcp-16-203</section_number>
  <catch_line>The head of the Office is the Public Defender....</catch_line>
  <order_by>203</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The head of the Office is the Public Defender.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Public Defender shall be appointed by the Board of Trustees.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">By a vote of at least seven members, the Board of Trustees may remove the Public Defender for:<section prefix="(i)">misconduct in office;</section><section prefix="(ii)">persistent failure to perform the duties of the Office; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">conduct prejudicial to the proper administration of justice.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">To qualify for appointment as Public Defender, an individual shall be an attorney admitted to practice law in the State by the Court of Appeals of Maryland who has engaged in the practice of law for at least 5 years before appointment.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">The Public Defender shall receive the same salary as a judge of a circuit court.</section>
      <section prefix="(6)">The Public Defender may not engage in the private practice of law.</section>
      <section prefix="(7)">The Public Defender serves for a term of 6 years.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">With the approval of the Board of Trustees, the Public Defender shall appoint:<section prefix="(i)">a deputy public defender; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">one district public defender for each district of the District Court.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The deputy public defender and each district public defender shall have the same qualifications as the Public Defender.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A district public defender shall:<section prefix="(i)">assist the Public Defender to perform the duties of the Office; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">subject to the supervision of the Public Defender, be in charge of the public defender offices in the district for which the district public defender is appointed.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">With the advice of the district public defenders, the Public Defender may appoint assistant public defenders in accordance with the State budget.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">To qualify for appointment as an assistant public defender, an individual shall be an attorney and admitted to practice law in the State by the Court of Appeals of Maryland.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The deputy public defender, district public defenders, and assistant public defenders:<section prefix="(1)">shall serve at the pleasure of the Public Defender; and</section><section prefix="(2)">may not engage in the private practice of criminal law.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The Public Defender shall appoint investigators, stenographic assistants, clerical assistants, and other personnel as may be required to assist the Public Defender and the district public defenders to perform the duties of the Office in accordance with the State budget.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Subject to paragraph (2) of this subsection, the Public Defender shall establish and maintain suitable offices in the State.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">At least one Public Defender's office shall be in each district.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">The number of positions, compensation, and expenses for the Office shall be in accordance with the State budget.</section>
  </text>
</law>
