<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcp" order_by="" level="1">Criminal Procedure</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcp-11-723</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>723</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Except where a term of natural life without the possibility of parole is imposed, a sentence for the following persons shall include a term of lifetime sexual offender supervision:<section prefix="(1)">a person who is a sexually violent predator;</section><section prefix="(2)">a person who has been convicted of a violation of &#xA7; 3-303, &#xA7; 3-304, &#xA7; 3-305, or &#xA7; 3-306(a)(1) or (2) of the Criminal Law Article;</section><section prefix="(3)">a person who has been convicted of a violation of &#xA7; 3-309, &#xA7; 3-310, or &#xA7; 3-311 of the Criminal Law Article or an attempt to commit a violation of &#xA7; 3-306(a)(1) or (2) of the Criminal Law Article;</section><section prefix="(4)">a person who has been convicted of a violation of &#xA7; 3-602 of the Criminal Law Article involving a child under the age of 12 years;</section><section prefix="(5)">a person who is required to register under &#xA7; 11-704(c) of this subtitle; and</section><section prefix="(6)">a person who has been convicted more than once arising out of separate incidents of a crime that requires registration under this subtitle.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Except where a term of natural life without the possibility of parole is imposed, a sentence for a violation of &#xA7; 3-307(a)(1) or (2) of the Criminal Law Article may include a term of lifetime sexual offender supervision.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, the term of lifetime sexual offender supervision imposed on a person for a crime committed on or after October 1, 2010, shall:<section prefix="(i)">be a term of life; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">commence on the expiration of the later of any term of imprisonment, probation, parole, or mandatory supervision.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">For a person who is required to register under &#xA7; 11-704(c) of this subtitle, the term of lifetime sexual offender supervision imposed for an act committed on or after October 1, 2010, shall:<section prefix="(i)">commence when the person's obligation to register commences; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">expire when the person's obligation to register expires, unless the juvenile court:<section prefix="1.">finds after a hearing that there is a compelling reason for the supervision to continue; and</section><section prefix="2.">orders the supervision to continue for a specified period of time.</section></section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">For a sentence that includes a term of lifetime sexual offender supervision, the sentencing court, or juvenile court in the case of a person who is required to register under &#xA7; 11-704(c) of this subtitle, shall impose special conditions of lifetime sexual offender supervision on the person at the time of sentencing, or imposition of the registration requirement in juvenile court, and advise the person of the length, conditions, and consecutive nature of that supervision.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Before imposing special conditions, the sentencing court or juvenile court shall order:<section prefix="(i)">a presentence investigation in accordance with &#xA7; 6-112 of the Correctional Services Article; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">for a sentence for a violation of &#xA7; 3-307(a)(1) or (2) of the Criminal Law Article, a risk assessment of the person conducted by a sexual offender treatment provider.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The conditions of lifetime sexual offender supervision may include:<section prefix="(i)">monitoring through global positioning satellite tracking or equivalent technology;</section><section prefix="(ii)">where appropriate and feasible, restricting a person from living in proximity to or loitering near schools, family child care homes, child care centers, and other places used primarily by minors;</section><section prefix="(iii)">restricting a person from obtaining employment or from participating in an activity that would bring the person into contact with minors;</section><section prefix="(iv)">requiring a person to participate in a sexual offender treatment program;</section><section prefix="(v)">prohibiting a person from using illicit drugs or alcohol;</section><section prefix="(vi)">authorizing a parole and probation agent to access the person's personal computer to check for material relating to sexual relations with minors;</section><section prefix="(vii)">requiring a person to take regular polygraph examinations;</section><section prefix="(viii)">prohibiting a person from contacting specific individuals or categories of individuals; and</section><section prefix="(ix)">any other conditions deemed appropriate by the sentencing court or juvenile court.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The sentencing court or juvenile court may adjust the special conditions of lifetime sexual offender supervision, in consultation with the person's sexual offender management team.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
