<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gcp" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="6-222" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcp-6-222</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">A circuit court or the District Court may:<section prefix="(1)">impose a sentence for a specified time and provide that a lesser time be served in confinement;</section><section prefix="(2)">suspend the remainder of the sentence; and</section><section prefix="(3)"><section prefix="(i)">order probation for a time longer than the sentence but, subject to subsections (b) and (c) of this section, not longer than:</section><section prefix="(ii)">if a defendant convicted of sexual abuse of a minor under &#xA7; 3-602 of the Criminal Law Article or a crime involving a minor under &#xA7; 3-303, &#xA7; 3-304, &#xA7; 3-305, &#xA7; 3-306, or &#xA7; 3-307 of the Criminal Law Article, consents in writing, order probation for a time longer than the sentence that was imposed on the defendant, but not longer than:</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">For the purpose of making restitution, the court may extend the probation beyond the time allowed under subsection (a)(3)(i) of this section for:<section prefix="(i)">an additional 5 years if the probation is ordered by a circuit court; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">an additional 3 years if the probation is ordered by the District Court.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">An extension of probation under this subsection may be unsupervised or supervised by the Division of Parole and Probation.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The court may extend the probation beyond the time allowed under subsection (b) of this section if:<section prefix="(1)">the defendant consents in writing; and</section><section prefix="(2)">the extension is only for making restitution.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">For the purpose of a commitment to the Department of Health and Mental Hygiene for treatment under &#xA7; 8-507 of the Health - General Article, the court may extend the probation for 1 year beyond the time allowed under subsection (a)(3)(i) of this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">An extension of probation under this subsection shall be supervised by the Division of Parole and Probation.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The court may extend the probation beyond the time allowed under subsection (d) of this section only if:<section prefix="(1)">the defendant consents in writing; and</section><section prefix="(2)">the extension is only for a commitment to the Department of Health and Mental Hygiene for treatment under &#xA7; 8-507 of the Health - General Article.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
