<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gcp" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="15-411" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcp-15-411</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">This section applies only in Frederick County.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The State's Attorney's annual salary is equal to the salary of a  circuit court judge.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The county commissioners shall:<section prefix="(i)">provide an office in the courthouse for the State's Attorney;</section><section prefix="(ii)">pay the office expenses, including general operating expenses and the cost of equipment; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">pay the reasonable salary of a stenographer to be appointed by the State's Attorney.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The State's Attorney may appoint two deputy State's Attorneys who shall:</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">Subject to the approval of the county commissioners, the State's Attorney shall set the salary of each deputy State's Attorney.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The State's Attorney may appoint the number of full-time and part-time assistant State's Attorneys that are approved by the county commissioners and who:<section prefix="(i)">serve at the pleasure of the State's Attorney;</section><section prefix="(ii)">receive the compensation that the county commissioners approve; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">have the same legal powers that the State's Attorney has to present cases to the grand jury and perform other necessary duties in relation to the grand jury and the operation of the office.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Subject to the approval of the county commissioners, the State's Attorney may appoint other staff.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Employees appointed under this subsection shall:<section prefix="(i)">serve at the pleasure of the State's Attorney; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">receive the compensation that the county commissioners approve.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The State's Attorney and deputy State's Attorneys may not engage in the private practice of law.</section>
  </text>
</law>
