<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcp" order_by="" level="1">Criminal Procedure</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcp-5-205</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>205</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">A District Court judge may:<section prefix="(1)">set bond or bail;</section><section prefix="(2)">release a defendant on personal recognizance or on a personal or other bail bond;</section><section prefix="(3)">commit a defendant to a correctional facility in default of a bail bond;</section><section prefix="(4)">order a bail bond forfeited if the defendant fails to meet the conditions of the bond; and</section><section prefix="(5)">exercise all of the powers of a justice of the peace under the Constitution of 1867.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This subsection does not apply to a defendant who has been arrested for failure to appear in court or for contempt of court.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Notwithstanding any other law or rule to the contrary, in a criminal or traffic case in the District Court in which a bail bond has been set and if expressly authorized by the court or District Court commissioner, the defendant or a private surety acting for the defendant may post the bail bond by:<section prefix="1.">executing it in the full penalty amount; and</section><section prefix="2.">depositing with the clerk of the court or a commissioner the greater of 10% of the penalty amount or $25.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">A judicial officer may increase the percentage of cash surety required in a particular case but may not authorize a cash deposit of less than $25.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">On depositing the amount required under paragraph (2) of this subsection and executing the recognizance, the defendant shall be released from custody subject to the conditions of the bail bond.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">When all conditions of the bail bond have been performed without default and the defendant has been discharged from all obligations in the cause for which the recognizance was posted, the clerk of the court shall return the deposit to the person or private surety who deposited it.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">If the defendant fails to perform any condition of the bail bond, the bail bond shall be forfeited.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">If the bail bond is forfeited, the liability of the bail bond shall extend to the full amount of the bail bond set and the amount posted as a deposit shall be applied to reduce the liability incurred by the forfeiture.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
