<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcp" order_by="gcp" level="1">Criminal Procedure</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcp-11-912</section_number>
  <catch_line>The Board consists of the following 22 members:...</catch_line>
  <order_by>912</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Board consists of the following 22 members:<section prefix="(1)">as ex officio members:<section prefix="(i)">the Governor or the Governor's designee;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the Attorney General or the Attorney General's designee;</section><section prefix="(iii)">the chairman of the Maryland Criminal Injuries Compensation Board;</section><section prefix="(iv)">the Secretary of Human Resources or the Secretary's designee;</section><section prefix="(v)">the Secretary of Juvenile Services or the Secretary's designee;</section><section prefix="(vi)">the Secretary of Public Safety and Correctional Services or the Secretary's designee; and</section><section prefix="(vii)">the Executive Director or the Executive Director's designee;</section></section><section prefix="(2)">14 persons appointed by the Governor as follows:<section prefix="(i)">two State's Attorneys, recommended by the Attorney General;</section><section prefix="(ii)">six members of the public, recommended by the Executive Director;</section><section prefix="(iii)">four professional victim service providers, recommended by the Executive Director;</section><section prefix="(iv)">one representative of the Maryland Chiefs of Police; and</section><section prefix="(v)">one representative of the Maryland State Sheriff's Association; and</section></section><section prefix="(3)">one member of the judiciary of the State, appointed by the Chief Judge of the Court of Appeals.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The term of an appointed member is 5 years.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The terms of appointed members are staggered as required by the terms provided for members of the Board on October 1, 2001.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">At the end of a term, an appointed member continues to serve until a successor is appointed and qualifies.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">A member who is appointed after a term has begun serves only for the rest of the term and until a successor is appointed and qualifies.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Governor may remove a member for incompetence or misconduct.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Governor or the Governor's designee shall serve as chairman.</section>
  </text>
</law>
