<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcp" order_by="" level="1">Criminal Procedure</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcp-11-503</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>503</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, "subsequent proceeding" includes:<section prefix="(1)">a sentence review under &#xA7; 8-102 of this article;</section><section prefix="(2)">a hearing on a request to have a sentence modified or vacated under the Maryland Rules;</section><section prefix="(3)">in a juvenile delinquency proceeding, a review of a commitment order or other disposition under the Maryland Rules;</section><section prefix="(4)">an appeal to the Court of Special Appeals;</section><section prefix="(5)">an appeal to the Court of Appeals;</section><section prefix="(6)">a hearing on an adjustment of special conditions of lifetime sexual offender supervision under &#xA7; 11-723 of this title or a hearing on a violation of special conditions of lifetime sexual offender supervision or a petition for discharge from special conditions of lifetime sexual offender supervision under &#xA7; 11-724 of this title; and</section><section prefix="(7)">any other postsentencing court proceeding.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Following conviction or adjudication and sentencing or disposition of a defendant or child respondent, the State's Attorney shall notify the victim or victim's representative of a subsequent proceeding in accordance with &#xA7; 11-104(e) of this title if:<section prefix="(1)">before the State's Attorney distributes notification request forms under &#xA7; 11-104(c) of this title, the victim or victim's representative submitted to the State's Attorney a written request to be notified of subsequent proceedings; or</section><section prefix="(2)">after the State's Attorney distributes notification request forms under &#xA7; 11-104(c) of this title, the victim or victim's representative submits a notification request form in accordance with &#xA7; 11-104(d) of this title.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The State's Attorney's office shall:<section prefix="(i)">notify the victim or victim's representative of all appeals to the Court of Special Appeals and the Court of Appeals; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">send an information copy of the notification to the Office of the Attorney General.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">After the initial notification to the victim or victim's representative or receipt of a notification request form, as defined in &#xA7; 11-104 of this title, the Office of the Attorney General shall:<section prefix="(i)">notify the victim or victim's representative of each subsequent date pertinent to the appeal, including dates of hearings, postponements, and decisions of the appellate courts; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">send an information copy of the notification to the State's Attorney's office.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A notice sent under this section shall include the date, the time, the location, and a brief description of the subsequent proceeding.</section>
  </text>
</law>
