<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcp" order_by="" level="1">Criminal Procedure</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcp-16-207</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>207</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The primary duty of the Public Defender is to provide representation for indigent individuals in accordance with this title.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Public Defender shall:<section prefix="(1)">be responsible generally for the operation of the Office and all district offices;</section><section prefix="(2)">prepare schedules of professional fees and expenses for panel attorneys and other professional and technical services rendered to indigent individuals other than by the Public Defender's staff, taking into consideration the nature of the services, the time spent, the skill or experience required, and any other pertinent factor;</section><section prefix="(3)">consult and cooperate with professional groups about the causes of criminal conduct and the development of effective means to:<section prefix="(i)">reduce and discourage the commission of crime;</section><section prefix="(ii)">rehabilitate and correct individuals charged and convicted of crime;</section><section prefix="(iii)">administer criminal justice; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">administer and conduct the Office; and</section></section><section prefix="(4)">maintain financial and statistical records about each case in which the Office provides legal assistance to an indigent individual, including data to calculate all direct and indirect costs to the Office.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Public Defender may:<section prefix="(1)">adopt regulations to carry out the purposes of this title and promote the efficient conduct of the work and general administration of the Office, its professional staff, and other employees;</section><section prefix="(2)">make necessary arrangements to coordinate services of the Office with any federal program to provide an attorney to indigent individuals;</section><section prefix="(3)">arrange for the Office to receive money or services available to assist in the duties under this title; and</section><section prefix="(4)">accept the services of volunteer workers or consultants at no compensation or at nominal or token compensation and reimburse them for their necessary expenses.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Subject to paragraph (2) of this subsection, in Baltimore City, the Public Defender may contract with private or public organizations to provide legal, administrative, or technical services for indigent individuals.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A contract shall require that:<section prefix="(i)">the level and quality of the work at least equal that of the Office; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">the Public Defender supervise and control all services rendered.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
