<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcp" order_by="gcp" level="1">Criminal Procedure</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcp-7-106</section_number>
  <catch_line>For the purposes of this title, an allegation of error is finally litigated when:...</catch_line>
  <order_by>106</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">For the purposes of this title, an allegation of error is finally litigated when:<section prefix="(1)">an appellate court of the State decides on the merits of the allegation:<section prefix="(i)">on direct appeal; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">on any consideration of an application for leave to appeal filed under &#xA7; 7-109 of this subtitle; or</section></section><section prefix="(2)">a court of original jurisdiction, after a full and fair hearing, decides on the merits of the allegation in a petition for a writ of habeas corpus or a writ of error coram nobis, unless the decision on the merits of the petition is clearly erroneous.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Except as provided in subparagraph (ii) of this paragraph, an allegation of error is waived when a petitioner could have made but intelligently and knowingly failed to make the allegation:<section prefix="1.">before trial;</section><section prefix="2.">at trial;</section><section prefix="3.">on direct appeal, whether or not the petitioner took an appeal;</section><section prefix="4.">in an application for leave to appeal a conviction based on a guilty plea;</section><section prefix="5.">in a habeas corpus or coram nobis proceeding began by the petitioner;</section><section prefix="6.">in a prior petition under this subtitle; or</section><section prefix="7.">in any other proceeding that the petitioner began.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">
          <section prefix="1.">Failure to make an allegation of error shall be excused if special circumstances exist.</section>
          <section prefix="2.">The petitioner has the burden of proving that special circumstances exist.</section>
        </section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">When a petitioner could have made an allegation of error at a proceeding set forth in paragraph (1)(i) of this subsection but did not make an allegation of error, there is a rebuttable presumption that the petitioner intelligently and knowingly failed to make the allegation.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This subsection applies after a decision on the merits of an allegation of error or after a proceeding in which an allegation of error may have been waived.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Notwithstanding any other provision of this title, an allegation of error may not be considered to have been finally litigated or waived under this title if a court whose decisions are binding on the lower courts of the State holds that:<section prefix="(i)">the Constitution of the United States or the Maryland Constitution imposes on State criminal proceedings a procedural or substantive standard not previously recognized; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">the standard is intended to be applied retrospectively and would thereby affect the validity of the petitioner's conviction or sentence.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
