<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcp" order_by="" level="1">Criminal Procedure</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcp-1-209</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>209</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section, "department" means:<section prefix="(i)">the Department of Agriculture;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the Department of the Environment;</section><section prefix="(iii)">the Department of Health and Mental Hygiene;</section><section prefix="(iv)">the Department of Human Resources;</section><section prefix="(v)">the Department of Labor, Licensing, and Regulation; or</section><section prefix="(vi)">the Department of Public Safety and Correctional Services.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Department" includes any unit of a department specified in paragraph (1) of this subsection.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">This section does not apply to a person who was previously convicted of a crime of violence, as defined in &#xA7; 14-101 of the Criminal Law Article.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">It is the policy of the State to encourage the employment of nonviolent ex-offenders and remove barriers to their ability to demonstrate fitness for occupational licenses or certifications required by the State.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A department may not deny an occupational license or certificate to an applicant solely on the basis that the applicant has previously been convicted of a crime, unless the department determines that:<section prefix="(1)">there is a direct relationship between the applicant's previous conviction and the specific occupational license or certificate sought; or</section><section prefix="(2)">the issuance of the license or certificate would involve an unreasonable risk to property or to the safety or welfare of specific individuals or the general public.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">In making the determination under subsection (d) of this section, the department shall consider:<section prefix="(1)">the policy of the State expressed in subsection (c) of this section;</section><section prefix="(2)">the specific duties and responsibilities required of a licensee or certificate holder;</section><section prefix="(3)">whether the applicant's previous conviction has any impact on the applicant's fitness or ability to perform the duties and responsibilities authorized by the license or certificate;</section><section prefix="(4)">the age of the applicant at the time of the conviction and the amount of time that has elapsed since the conviction;</section><section prefix="(5)">the seriousness of the offense for which the applicant was convicted;</section><section prefix="(6)">other information provided by the applicant or on the applicant's behalf with regard to the applicant's rehabilitation and good conduct; and</section><section prefix="(7)">the legitimate interest of the department in protecting property and the safety and welfare of specific individuals or the general public.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
