<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gcp" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="10-103.1" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcp-10-103.1</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">For arrests or confinements occurring on or after October 1, 2007, a person who is arrested or confined by a law enforcement unit and then is released without being charged with the commission of a crime is entitled to expungement of all police records, including photographs and fingerprints, relating to the matter.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Within 60 days after release of a person entitled to expungement of a police record under subsection (a) of this section, the law enforcement unit shall:<section prefix="(1)">search diligently for and expunge each police record about the arrest or confinement of the person; and</section><section prefix="(2)">send a notice of expungement containing all relevant facts about the expungement and underlying arrest or confinement to:<section prefix="(i)">the Central Repository;</section><section prefix="(ii)">each booking facility or law enforcement unit that the law enforcement unit believes may have a police record about the arrest or confinement; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">the person entitled to expungement.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Within 60 days after receipt of the notice, the Central Repository, a booking facility, and any other law enforcement unit shall:<section prefix="(1)">search diligently for and expunge each police record about the arrest or confinement of the person; and</section><section prefix="(2)">advise in writing the person entitled to expungement of compliance with the order.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A police record expunged under this section may not be expunged by obliteration until 3 years after the date of expungement.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">During the 3-year period described in paragraph (1) of this subsection, the records shall be removed to a separate secure area to which persons who do not have a legitimate reason for access are denied access.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">For purposes of this subsection, a legitimate reason for accessing the records includes using the records for purposes of proceedings relating to the arrest.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">If a law enforcement unit, a booking facility, or the Central Repository fails to expunge a police record as required under subsection (b) or (c) of this section, the person entitled to expungement may:<section prefix="(1)">seek redress by means of any appropriate legal remedy; and</section><section prefix="(2)">recover court costs.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">A person who is entitled to expungement under this section may not be required to pay any fee or costs in connection with the expungement.</section>
  </text>
</law>
