<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gcp" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="6-226" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcp-6-226</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, "supervisee" means a person that the court places under the supervision of the Division of Parole and Probation.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Unless the supervisee is exempt under subsection (d) of this section, the court shall impose a monthly fee of $50 on a supervisee.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The fee imposed under this section shall be paid to the Division of Parole and Probation.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Division of Parole and Probation shall pay the money collected under this section into the General Fund of the State.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The court may exempt a supervisee as a whole or in part from the fee imposed under this section if:<section prefix="(1)">the supervisee has diligently tried but has been unable to obtain employment that provides sufficient income for the supervisee to pay the fee;</section><section prefix="(2)"><section prefix="(i)">the supervisee is a student in a school, college, or university or is enrolled in a course of vocational or technical training designed to prepare the student for gainful employment; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">certification of student status is supplied to the court by the institution in which the supervisee is enrolled;</section></section><section prefix="(3)">the supervisee has a handicap limiting employment, as determined by a physical or psychological examination accepted or ordered by the court;</section><section prefix="(4)">the supervisee is responsible for the support of dependents and the payment of the fee is an undue hardship on the supervisee; or</section><section prefix="(5)">other extenuating circumstances exist.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The fee imposed by this section is in addition to court costs and fines.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The court may revoke probation for failure to make the required payment of the fee imposed under this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If the supervisee does not comply with the fee requirement, the Division of Parole and Probation shall notify the court.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The court shall hold a hearing to determine if there are sufficient grounds to find the supervisee in violation.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">At a hearing under this subsection, the court may consider:<section prefix="(i)">any material change in the supervisee's financial status;</section><section prefix="(ii)">good faith efforts of the supervisee to pay the fee; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">alternative means to ensure payment of the fee before the period of supervision ends.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In addition to fees imposed under this section, the Division of Parole and Probation may require a supervisee to pay:<section prefix="(i)">for drug or alcohol abuse testing if the court orders testing; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">any monthly program fee provided under &#xA7; 6-115 of the Correctional Services Article.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Failure to make a payment required for drug or alcohol abuse testing may be considered grounds for revocation of probation by the court.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Division of Parole and Probation may exempt a supervisee as a whole or in part from a payment for testing if the Division determines that any of the criteria in subsection (d) of this section apply.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(h)">The Division of Parole and Probation shall:<section prefix="(1)">adopt guidelines for collecting the supervision fee;</section><section prefix="(2)">adopt guidelines for collecting the cost of drug and alcohol testing;</section><section prefix="(3)">investigate requests for an exemption from payment, if the court requests an investigation;</section><section prefix="(4)">keep records of all payments by each supervisee; and</section><section prefix="(5)">report delinquencies to the court.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
