<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gcp" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="11-804" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcp-11-804</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">There is a Criminal Injuries Compensation Board in the Department.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Board consists of five members.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Of the five members of the Board:<section prefix="(i)">no more than four may belong to the same political party; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">one shall have been admitted to practice law in the State for at least 5 years immediately preceding the appointment.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Secretary shall appoint the members of the Board, with the approval of the Governor and the advice and consent of the Senate.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The term of a member is 5 years.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A member who is appointed to fill a vacancy occurring other than by expiration of a term serves for the rest of the unexpired term.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">With the approval of the Governor, the Secretary shall designate one member of the Board as chairman.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The chairman serves at the pleasure of the Secretary.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Each member of the Board shall devote the time necessary to perform the duties listed under this subtitle.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Each member of the Board is entitled to:<section prefix="(i)">compensation in accordance with the State budget; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">reimbursement for expenses under the Standard State Travel Regulations, as provided in the State budget.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
