<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcp" order_by="" level="1">Criminal Procedure</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcp-11-801</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>801</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Board" means the Criminal Injuries Compensation Board.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Claimant" means the person filing a claim under this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Crime" means:<section prefix="(i)">except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, a criminal offense under state, federal, or common law that is committed in:<section prefix="1.">this State; or</section><section prefix="2.">another state against a resident of this State; or</section></section><section prefix="(ii)">an act of international terrorism as defined in Title 18, &#xA7; 2331 of the United States Code that is committed outside of the United States against a resident of this State.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Crime" does not include an act involving the operation of a vessel or motor vehicle unless the act is:<section prefix="(i)">a violation of &#xA7; 20-102, &#xA7; 20-104, &#xA7; 21-902, or &#xA7; 21-904 of the Transportation Article; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">operating a motor vehicle or vessel that results in an intentional injury.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"Dependent" means:<section prefix="(1)">a surviving spouse or child of a person; or</section><section prefix="(2)">a person who is dependent on another person for principal support.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">"Victim" means a person:<section prefix="(1)">who suffers physical injury or death as a result of a crime or delinquent act;</section><section prefix="(2)">who suffers psychological injury as a direct result of:<section prefix="(i)">a fourth degree sexual offense or a delinquent act that would be a fourth degree sexual offense if committed by an adult;</section><section prefix="(ii)">a felony or a delinquent act that would be a felony if committed by an adult; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">physical injury or death directly resulting from a crime or delinquent act; or</section></section><section prefix="(3)">who suffers physical injury or death as a direct result of:<section prefix="(i)">trying to prevent a crime or delinquent act or an attempted crime or delinquent act from occurring in the person's presence;</section><section prefix="(ii)">trying to apprehend an offender who had committed a crime or delinquent act in the person's presence or had committed a felony or a delinquent act that would be a felony if committed by an adult; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">helping a law enforcement officer in the performance of the officer's duties or helping a member of a fire department who is being obstructed from performing the member's duties.</section></section></section>
  </text>
</law>
