<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gcp" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="10-103" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcp-10-103</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">For arrests, detentions, or confinements occurring before October 1, 2007, a person who is arrested, detained, or confined by a law enforcement unit for the suspected commission of a crime and then is released without being charged with the commission of a crime may request the expungement of the police record.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The person shall request expungement within 8 years after the date of the incident.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">On receipt of a timely filed request, the law enforcement unit promptly shall investigate and try to verify the facts stated in the request.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If the law enforcement unit finds the facts are true, the law enforcement unit shall:<section prefix="(i)">search diligently for each police record about the arrest, detention, or confinement of the person;</section><section prefix="(ii)">expunge each police record it has about the arrest, detention, or confinement within 60 days after receipt of the request; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">send a copy of the request and the law enforcement unit's verification of the facts in the request to:</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Within 60 days after receipt of the request, the Central Repository, booking facility, and any other law enforcement unit shall search diligently for and expunge a police record about the arrest, detention, or confinement.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">If the law enforcement unit to which the person has sent a request finds that the person is not entitled to an expungement of the police record, the law enforcement unit, within 60 days after receipt of the request, shall advise the person in writing of:<section prefix="(1)">the denial of the request for expungement; and</section><section prefix="(2)">the reasons for the denial.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">If a request by the person for expungement of a police record is denied under subsection (e) of this section, the person may apply for an order of expungement in the District Court that has proper venue against the law enforcement unit.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The person shall file the application within 30 days after the written notice of the denial is mailed or delivered to the person.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">After notice to the law enforcement unit, the court shall hold a hearing.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">If the court finds that the person is entitled to expungement, the court shall order the law enforcement unit to expunge the police record.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">If the court finds that the person is not entitled to expungement of the police record, the court shall deny the application.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The law enforcement unit is a party to the proceeding.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">Each party to the proceeding is entitled to appellate review on the record, as provided in the Courts Article for appeals in civil cases from the District Court.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">A person who is entitled to expungement under this section may not be required to pay any fee or costs in connection with the expungement.</section>
  </text>
</law>
