<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gcp" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="11-705" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcp-11-705</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, "resident" means a person who has a home or other place where the person habitually lives located in this State when the person:<section prefix="(1)">is released;</section><section prefix="(2)">is granted probation;</section><section prefix="(3)">is granted a suspended sentence;</section><section prefix="(4)">receives a sentence that does not include a term of imprisonment; or</section><section prefix="(5)">is released from the juvenile court's jurisdiction under &#xA7; 3-8A-07 of the Courts Article, if the person was a minor who lived in the State at the time the act was committed for which registration is required.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A registrant shall register with the appropriate supervising authority in the State:<section prefix="(1)">if the registrant was sentenced to a term of imprisonment before the date that the registrant is released; or</section><section prefix="(2)">within 3 days of the date that the registrant:<section prefix="(i)">is granted probation before judgment;</section><section prefix="(ii)">is granted probation after judgment;</section><section prefix="(iii)">is granted a suspended sentence; or</section><section prefix="(iv)">receives a sentence that does not include a term of imprisonment;</section></section><section prefix="(3)">if the registrant was a resident who was a minor at the time the act was committed for which registration is required, within 3 days after the juvenile court's jurisdiction over the person terminates under &#xA7; 3-8A-07 of the Courts Article;</section><section prefix="(4)">if the registrant moves into the State, within 3 days after the earlier of the date that the registrant:<section prefix="(i)">establishes a temporary or permanent residence in the State;</section><section prefix="(ii)">begins to habitually live in the State; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">applies for a driver's license in the State; or</section></section><section prefix="(5)">if the registrant is not a resident, within 3 days after the registrant:<section prefix="(i)">begins employment in the State;</section><section prefix="(ii)">registers as a student in the State; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">enters the State as a transient.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A sex offender shall also register in person with the local law enforcement unit of each county where the sex offender resides within 3 days of:<section prefix="(i)">release from any period of imprisonment or arrest; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">registering with the supervising authority, if the registrant is moving into this State and the local law enforcement unit is not the supervising authority.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A sex offender may be required to give to the local law enforcement unit more information than required under &#xA7; 11-706 of this subtitle.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A homeless registrant also shall register in person with the local law enforcement unit in each county where the registrant habitually lives:<section prefix="(i)">within 3 days after the earlier of the date of release or after registering with the supervising authority; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">within 3 days after entering and remaining in a county.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">After initially registering with a local law enforcement unit under this subsection, a homeless registrant shall register once a week in person during the time the homeless registrant habitually lives in the county.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The registration requirements under this subsection are in addition to any other requirements the homeless registrant is subject to according to the registrant's classification as a tier I sex offender, tier II sex offender, tier III sex offender, or sexually violent predator.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">If a registrant who was homeless obtains a fixed address, the registrant shall register with the appropriate supervising authority and local law enforcement unit within 3 days after obtaining a fixed address.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">Within 3 days of any change, a registrant shall notify the local law enforcement unit where the registrant most recently registered and each local law enforcement unit where the registrant will reside or habitually live of changes in:<section prefix="(1)">residence;</section><section prefix="(2)">the county in which the registrant habitually lives;</section><section prefix="(3)">vehicle or license plate information;</section><section prefix="(4)">electronic mail or Internet identifiers;</section><section prefix="(5)">home or cell phone numbers; or</section><section prefix="(6)">employment.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A registrant who commences or terminates enrollment as a full-time or part-time student at an institution of higher education in the State shall provide notice in person to the local law enforcement unit where the institution of higher education is located within 3 days after the commencement or termination of enrollment.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A registrant who commences or terminates carrying on employment at an institution of higher education in the State shall provide notice in person to the local law enforcement unit where the institution of higher education is located within 3 days after the commencement or termination of employment.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">A registrant who is granted a legal change of name by a court shall send written notice of the change to each local law enforcement unit where the registrant resides or habitually lives within 3 days after the change is granted.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">A registrant shall notify each local law enforcement unit where the registrant resides or habitually lives at least 3 days prior to leaving the United States to commence residence or employment or attend school in a foreign country.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A registrant shall notify each local law enforcement unit where the registrant resides or habitually lives when the registrant obtains a temporary residence or alters the location where the registrant resides or habitually lives for more than 5 days or when the registrant will be absent from the registrant's residence or location where the registrant resides or habitually lives for more than 7 days.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Notification under this subsection shall:<section prefix="(i)">be made in writing or in person prior to obtaining a temporary residence, commencing the period of absence, or temporarily altering a location where the registrant resides or habitually lives;</section><section prefix="(ii)">include the temporary address or detailed description of the temporary location where the registrant will reside or habitually live; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">contain the anticipated dates that the temporary residence or location will be used by the registrant and the anticipated dates that the registrant will be absent from the registrant's permanent residence or locations where the registrant regularly resides or habitually lives.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(j)">A registrant who establishes a new electronic mail address, computer log-in or screen name or identity, instant-message identity, or electronic chat room identity shall send written notice of the new information to the State registry within 3 days after the electronic mail address, computer log-in or screen name or identity, instant-message identity, or electronic chat room identity is established.</section>
  </text>
</law>
