<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcp" order_by="" level="1">Criminal Procedure</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcp-4-202</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>202</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Victim" has the meaning stated in &#xA7; 11-104 of this article.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Victim's representative" has the meaning stated in &#xA7; 11-104 of this article.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Except as provided in subsection (c) of this section, a court exercising criminal jurisdiction in a case involving a child may transfer the case to the juvenile court before trial or before a plea is entered under Maryland Rule 4-242 if:<section prefix="(1)">the accused child was at least 14 but not 18 years of age when the alleged crime was committed;</section><section prefix="(2)">the alleged crime is excluded from the jurisdiction of the juvenile court under &#xA7; 3-8A-03(d)(1), (4), or (5) of the Courts Article; and</section><section prefix="(3)">the court determines by a preponderance of the evidence that a transfer of its jurisdiction is in the interest of the child or society.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The court may not transfer a case to the juvenile court under subsection (b) of this section if:<section prefix="(1)">the child previously has been transferred to juvenile court and adjudicated delinquent;</section><section prefix="(2)">the child was convicted in an unrelated case excluded from the jurisdiction of the juvenile court under &#xA7; 3-8A-03(d)(1) or (4) of the Courts Article; or</section><section prefix="(3)">the alleged crime is murder in the first degree and the accused child was 16 or 17 years of age when the alleged crime was committed.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">In determining whether to transfer jurisdiction under subsection (b) of this section, the court shall consider:<section prefix="(1)">the age of the child;</section><section prefix="(2)">the mental and physical condition of the child;</section><section prefix="(3)">the amenability of the child to treatment in an institution, facility, or program available to delinquent children;</section><section prefix="(4)">the nature of the alleged crime; and</section><section prefix="(5)">the public safety.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">In making a determination under this section, the court may order that a study be made concerning the child, the family of the child, the environment of the child, and other matters concerning the disposition of the case.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The court shall make a transfer determination within 10 days after the date of a transfer hearing.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">If the court transfers its jurisdiction under this section, the court may order the child held for an adjudicatory hearing under the regular procedure of the juvenile court.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Pending a determination under this section to transfer its jurisdiction, the court may order a child to be held in a secure juvenile facility.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A hearing on a motion requesting that a child be held in a juvenile facility pending a transfer determination shall be held not later than the next court day, unless extended by the court for good cause shown.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(i)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A victim or victim's representative shall be given notice of the transfer hearing as provided under &#xA7; 11-104 of this article.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">A victim or a victim's representative may submit a victim impact statement to the court as provided in &#xA7; 11-402 of this article.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">This paragraph does not preclude a victim or victim's representative who has not filed a notification request form under &#xA7; 11-104 of this article from submitting a victim impact statement to the court.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">The court shall consider a victim impact statement in determining whether to transfer jurisdiction under this section.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(j)">At a bail review or preliminary hearing before the District Court involving a child whose case is eligible for transfer under subsection (b) of this section, the District Court may order that a study be made under the provisions of subsection (e) of this section, or that the child be held in a secure juvenile facility under the provisions of subsection (h) of this section, regardless of whether the District Court has criminal jurisdiction over the case.</section>
  </text>
</law>
