<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcp" order_by="" level="1">Criminal Procedure</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcp-11-722</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>722</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">This section does not apply to a registrant who enters real property:<section prefix="(1)">where the registrant is a student or the registrant's child is a student or receives child care, if:<section prefix="(i)">within the past year the registrant has been given the specific written permission of the Superintendent of Schools, the local school board, the principal of the school, or the owner or operator of the registered family child care home, licensed child care home, or licensed child care institution, as applicable; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">the registrant promptly notifies an agent or employee of the school, home, or institution of the registrant's presence and purpose of visit; or</section></section><section prefix="(2)">for the purpose of voting at a school on an election day in the State if the registrant is properly registered to vote and the registrant's polling place is at the school.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A registrant may not knowingly enter onto real property:<section prefix="(1)">that is used for public or nonpublic elementary or secondary education; or</section><section prefix="(2)">on which is located:<section prefix="(i)">a family child care home registered under Title 5, Subtitle 5 of the Family Law Article; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">a child care home or a child care institution licensed under Title 5, Subtitle 5 of the Family Law Article.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A person who enters into a contract with a county board of education or a nonpublic school may not knowingly employ an individual to work at a school if the individual is a registrant.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A person who violates this section is guilty of a misdemeanor and on conviction is subject to imprisonment not exceeding 5 years or a fine not exceeding $5,000 or both.</section>
  </text>
</law>
