<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcp" order_by="" level="1">Criminal Procedure</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcp-15-202</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>202</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Council consists of:<section prefix="(1)">the Attorney General;</section><section prefix="(2)">the State's Attorney for Anne Arundel County;</section><section prefix="(3)">the State's Attorney for Baltimore City;</section><section prefix="(4)">the State's Attorney for Baltimore County;</section><section prefix="(5)">the State's Attorney for Montgomery County;</section><section prefix="(6)">the State's Attorney for Prince George's County;</section><section prefix="(7)">the State's Attorney for Allegany County, Frederick County, Garrett County, or Washington County who is chosen by a majority vote of the State's Attorneys for those counties;</section><section prefix="(8)">the State's Attorney for Calvert County, Charles County, or St. Mary's County who is chosen by a majority vote of the State's Attorneys for those counties;</section><section prefix="(9)">the State's Attorney for Caroline County, Cecil County, Kent County, Queen Anne's County, or Talbot County who is chosen by a majority vote of the State's Attorneys for those counties;</section><section prefix="(10)">the State's Attorney for Carroll County, Harford County, or Howard County who is chosen by a majority vote of the State's Attorneys for those counties; and</section><section prefix="(11)">the State's Attorney for Dorchester County, Somerset County, Wicomico County, or Worcester County who is chosen by a majority vote of the State's Attorneys for those counties.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This subsection only applies to members chosen in accordance with subsection (a)(7) through (11) of this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The term of a member of the Council is 2 years.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A member continues to serve until a successor is chosen and qualifies.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">A member may serve only during the time the member holds the office that qualifies the member for membership.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">A member is eligible to serve more than one term.</section>
      <section prefix="(6)">A vacancy on the Council shall be filled in the same manner used to choose the original membership in subsection (a) of this section.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Membership on the Council does not constitute holding an office of profit.</section>
  </text>
</law>
