<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcp" order_by="" level="1">Criminal Procedure</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcp-10-235</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>235</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, "Central Repository" means the Criminal Justice Information System Central Repository of the Department of Public Safety and Correctional Services.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The County Administrator in Washington County may request with reference to a prospective employee of Washington County:<section prefix="(1)">a State and national criminal history records check from the Central Repository; or</section><section prefix="(2)">a background investigation from an independent private investigation agency.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">As part of the application for a criminal history records check, the County Administrator of Washington County shall submit to the Central Repository:<section prefix="(i)">two complete sets of the prospective employee's legible fingerprints taken on forms approved by the Director of the Central Repository and the Director of the Federal Bureau of Investigation;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the fee authorized under &#xA7; 10-221(b)(7) of this subtitle for access to Maryland criminal history records; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">the mandatory processing fee required by the Federal Bureau of Investigation for a national criminal history records check.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">In accordance with &#xA7;&#xA7; 10-201 through 10-234 of this subtitle, the Central Repository shall forward to the prospective employee and the County Administrator of Washington County the prospective employee's criminal history record information.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Information obtained from the Central Repository under this section:<section prefix="(i)">is confidential and may not be redisseminated; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">may be used only for the employment purpose authorized by this section.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The subject of a criminal history records check under this section may contest the contents of the printed statement issued by the Central Repository as provided in &#xA7; 10-223 of this subtitle.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The County Administrator of Washington County shall pay to the independent private investigation agency the fee that is imposed for each request made under subsection (b) of this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The County Commissioners of Washington County may adopt regulations, guidelines, and policies to carry out this section.</section>
  </text>
</law>
