<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gcp" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="5-203" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcp-5-203</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Subject to paragraph (2) of this subsection, a circuit court may adopt rules setting the terms and conditions of bail bonds filed in that court and rules on the qualifications of and fees charged by bail bondsmen.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Notwithstanding any other law or rule to the contrary, if expressly authorized by the court, a defendant or a private surety acting for the defendant may post a bail bond by executing it in the full penalty amount and depositing with the clerk of court the greater of 10% of the penalty amount or $25.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A bail bond commissioner may be appointed to carry out rules adopted under this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">A violation of a rule adopted under this section is contempt of court and shall be punished in accordance with Title 15, Chapter 200 of the Maryland Rules.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">A person may not engage in the business of becoming a surety for compensation on bail bonds in criminal cases unless the person is:<section prefix="(i)">approved in accordance with any rules adopted under this section; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">if required under the Insurance Article, licensed in accordance with the Insurance Article.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In the circuit courts in the Seventh Judicial Circuit, a bail bondsman approved under subsection (a) of this section shall pay a license fee of 1% of the gross value of all bail bonds written in all courts of the circuit, if the fee is approved by the court of the county in which it applies.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The fee shall be paid to the court as required by the rules of court and shall be used to pay the expenses of carrying out this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Any absolute bail bond forfeitures collected may be used to pay the expenses of carrying out this section.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
