<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcr" order_by="gcr" level="1">Criminal Law</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcr-13-1108</section_number>
  <catch_line>A gaming event may be conducted only in accordance with this subtitle....</catch_line>
  <order_by>1108</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A gaming event may be conducted only in accordance with this subtitle.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A gaming device may only be managed or operated by a representative of the fundraising organization named in the gaming permit for the gaming event.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A professional gaming operator may not manage, operate, or assist in the management or operation of a gaming device.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">A person may not receive any commission, salary, reward, tip, or other compensation for managing or operating a gaming device at a gaming event.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">A minor may not participate in a gaming event.</section>
      <section prefix="(6)">A fundraising organization may lease gaming devices or premises for a gaming event only from a fundraising organization that the board approves.</section>
      <section prefix="(7)">
        <section prefix="(i)">A lease agreement of gaming devices or premises for a gaming event shall be priced on the basis of fair market value of the equipment or premises.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">A lease agreement may not include a provision for sharing profit from a gaming event with a lessor or a provision that reasonably may be interpreted to provide for sharing profit from a gaming event.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(8)">A fundraising organization may not conduct more than three gaming events during a calendar quarter.</section>
      <section prefix="(9)">
        <section prefix="(i)">A fundraising organization may not conduct a gaming event under a single gaming permit for a period greater than 48 hours.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The actual gaming time may not exceed 24 hours in that 48-hour period, which may be divided into not more than two separate gaming periods.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">Notwithstanding subparagraph (i) of this paragraph, a fundraising organization that conducts a gaming event at the Charles County Fair in conjunction with the Charles County Fair Board may conduct the gaming event under a single gaming permit for more than 48 hours, subject to regulations that the county commissioners adopt on recommendation of the board.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A fundraising organization that has conducted a gaming event shall submit a report to the board within 30 days after the end of the calendar quarter in which the gaming event was conducted.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The report shall contain:<section prefix="(i)">the name of the fundraising organization;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the number of the gaming permit;</section><section prefix="(iii)">the date of the gaming event;</section><section prefix="(iv)">the date, amount, nature, source, and recipient of each receipt and expenditure associated with the gaming event, in the format that the board prescribes;</section><section prefix="(v)">a separate list of the date, amount, and recipient of each charitable donation from the proceeds;</section><section prefix="(vi)">the name, age, address, and date of membership of each representative who managed, operated, or assisted in the operation or management of a gaming device at the gaming event;</section><section prefix="(vii)">a statement that each listed representative qualified as a representative under &#xA7; 13-1101(i) of this subtitle at the time of the gaming event;</section><section prefix="(viii)">a statement that:<section prefix="1.">an agreement does not exist and has not existed for sharing the proceeds of a gaming event with any other person; and</section><section prefix="2.">only the fundraising organization or its representative has received or will receive any proceeds of the gaming event, except to further the purposes of the fundraising organization; and</section></section><section prefix="(ix)">any other information that the board considers necessary or helpful.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A principal officer of the fundraising organization shall sign and verify the report under the penalties of perjury.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A fundraising organization that conducts a gaming event shall maintain accurate records of each transaction concerning the gaming event, and shall keep the records available for examination by the board and the county commissioners for 3 years after the gaming event.</section>
  </text>
</law>
