<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcr" order_by="" level="1">Criminal Law</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcr-5-403</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>403</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Schedule II consists of each controlled dangerous substance:<section prefix="(1)">listed in this section;</section><section prefix="(2)">added to Schedule II by the Department under &#xA7; 5-202(b) of this title; or</section><section prefix="(3)">designated as a Schedule II controlled dangerous substance by the federal government unless the Department objects under &#xA7; 5-202(f) of this title.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Unless the substance is listed in another schedule and except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, opium and opiate, and a salt, compound, derivative, or preparation of opium or opiate is a substance listed in Schedule II, including:<section prefix="(i)">raw opium;</section><section prefix="(ii)">opium extracts;</section><section prefix="(iii)">opium fluid;</section><section prefix="(iv)">powdered opium;</section><section prefix="(v)">granulated opium;</section><section prefix="(vi)">tincture of opium;</section><section prefix="(vii)">codeine;</section><section prefix="(viii)">ethylmorphine;</section><section prefix="(ix)">etorphine hydrochloride;</section><section prefix="(x)">hydrocodone;</section><section prefix="(xi)">hydromorphone;</section><section prefix="(xii)">metopon;</section><section prefix="(xiii)">morphine;</section><section prefix="(xiv)">oxycodone;</section><section prefix="(xv)">oxymorphone; and</section><section prefix="(xvi)">thebaine.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Apomorphine, dextrorphan, nalbuphine, naloxone, and naltrexone, and their respective salts, are not substances listed in Schedule II.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Substances listed in Schedule II also include:<section prefix="(i)">except for the isoquinoline alkaloids of opium, a salt, compound, derivative, or preparation that is chemically equivalent or identical to a substance listed in paragraph (1) of this subsection;</section><section prefix="(ii)">opium poppy and poppy straw;</section><section prefix="(iii)">coca leaf;</section><section prefix="(iv)">cocaine, its salts, optical and geometric isomers, and salts of isomers;</section><section prefix="(v)">ecgonine, its derivatives, their salts, isomers, and salts of isomers; and</section><section prefix="(vi)">a compound, mixture, or preparation that contains any of the substances listed in this section.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">A substance that is listed in Schedule II is included whether produced:<section prefix="(i)">directly or indirectly by extraction from substances of vegetable origin;</section><section prefix="(ii)">independently by chemical synthesis; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">by a combination of extraction and chemical synthesis.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">These opiates are substances listed in Schedule II:<section prefix="(i)">alphaprodine;</section><section prefix="(ii)">anileridine;</section><section prefix="(iii)">bezitramide;</section><section prefix="(iv)">dihydrocodeine;</section><section prefix="(v)">diphenoxylate;</section><section prefix="(vi)">fentanyl;</section><section prefix="(vii)">isomethadone;</section><section prefix="(viii)">levoalphacetylmethadol;</section><section prefix="(ix)">levomethorphan;</section><section prefix="(x)">levorphanol;</section><section prefix="(xi)">metazocine;</section><section prefix="(xii)">methadone;</section><section prefix="(xiii)">methadone--intermediate, 4-cyano-2-dimethylamino-4, 4-diphenyl butane;</section><section prefix="(xiv)">moramide--intermediate, 2-methyl-3-morpholino-1, 1-diphenyl-propane-carboxylic acid;</section><section prefix="(xv)">pethidine;</section><section prefix="(xvi)">pethidine--intermediate--A, 4-cyano-1-methyl-4-phenylpiperidine;</section><section prefix="(xvii)">pethidine--intermediate--B, ethyl-4-phenylpiperidine-4-carboxylate;</section><section prefix="(xviii)">pethidine--intermediate--C, 1-methyl-4-phenylpiperidine-4-carboxylic acid;</section><section prefix="(xix)">phenazocine;</section><section prefix="(xx)">piminodine;</section><section prefix="(xxi)">racemethorphan;</section><section prefix="(xxii)">racemorphan; and</section><section prefix="(xxiii)">sulfentanil.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Unless specifically excepted under this subtitle, an isomer, ester, ether, or salt of an opiate and a salt of an isomer, ester, or ether is a substance listed in Schedule II if the existence of the isomer, ester, ether, or salt is possible within the specific chemical designation.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A substance is listed in Schedule II if the substance includes a material, compound, mixture, or preparation that contains any quantity of the following substances having a potential for abuse associated with a stimulant effect on the central nervous system:<section prefix="(1)">amphetamine, its salts, optical isomers, and salts of its optical isomers;</section><section prefix="(2)">phenmetrazine and its salts;</section><section prefix="(3)">a substance that contains any methamphetamine, including salts, optical isomers, and salts of its optical isomers, in combination with one or more active nonnarcotic ingredients in recognized therapeutic amounts;</section><section prefix="(4)">methylphenidate; and</section><section prefix="(5)">methamphetamine, its salts, optical isomers, and salts of optical isomers.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Unless specifically excepted under this subtitle or listed in another schedule, a substance is listed in Schedule II if the substance includes a material, compound, mixture, or preparation that contains any quantity of the following substances having a depressant effect on the central nervous system:<section prefix="(i)">amobarbital;</section><section prefix="(ii)">secobarbital;</section><section prefix="(iii)">pentobarbital;</section><section prefix="(iv)">phencyclidine;</section><section prefix="(v)">1-(1-phenylcyclohexyl) piperidine;</section><section prefix="(vi)">1-phenylcyclohexylamine; and</section><section prefix="(vii)">1-piperidinocyclohexanecarbonitrile.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Unless specifically excepted under this subtitle or listed in another schedule, a salt, isomer, or salt of an isomer of a substance listed in this subsection is included in Schedule II if the existence of the salt, isomer, or salt of an isomer is possible within the specific chemical designation.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The Department may not add a substance to Schedule II under &#xA7; 5-202 of this title unless the Department finds:<section prefix="(1)">a high potential for abuse of the substance;</section><section prefix="(2)">currently accepted medical use of the substance in the United States, or currently accepted medical use with severe restrictions; and</section><section prefix="(3)">evidence that abuse of the substance may lead to severe psychological or physical dependence.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
