<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcr" order_by="gcr" level="1">Criminal Law</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcr-4-403</section_number>
  <catch_line>A manufacturer of a machine gun shall keep a register of each machine gun manufactured or handled by...</catch_line>
  <order_by>403</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A manufacturer of a machine gun shall keep a register of each machine gun manufactured or handled by the manufacturer.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The register shall contain:<section prefix="(i)">the method of manufacture and serial number of the machine gun;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the date of manufacture, sale, loan, gift, delivery, and receipt of the machine gun from the manufacturer; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">the name, address, and occupation of the person to whom the machine gun was sold, loaned, given or delivered, or from whom the machine gun was received, and the purpose for which the machine gun was acquired.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A person who violates this subsection is guilty of a misdemeanor and on conviction is subject to a fine not exceeding $100.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">On demand, a manufacturer of a machine gun shall allow a marshal, sheriff, or police officer to inspect the manufacturer's entire stock of machine guns, parts, and supplies and the register required under subsection (a) of this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A person who violates paragraph (1) of this subsection is guilty of a misdemeanor and on conviction is subject to a fine not exceeding $100.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A person who acquires a machine gun shall register the machine gun with the Secretary of  State Police:<section prefix="(i)">within 24 hours after acquiring the machine gun; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">in each succeeding year during the month of May.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Secretary of State Police shall prepare and, on request of an applicant, furnish an application form for registration under this subsection.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">An application for registration shall contain:<section prefix="(i)">the make, model, serial number, caliber, type, barrel length, finish, and country of origin of the machine gun;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the name, address, race, gender, date of birth, Maryland driver's license number, and occupation of the person in possession of the machine gun; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">the name of the person from whom the machine gun was acquired and the purpose for acquiring the machine gun.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">Each application for registration filed with the Secretary of State Police shall be accompanied by a nonrefundable registration fee of $10.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">Registration data provided under this section is not open to public inspection.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
