<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcr" order_by="gcr" level="1">Criminal Law</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcr-9-505</section_number>
  <catch_line>A person may not manufacture, possess, transport, or place:...</catch_line>
  <order_by>505</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">A person may not manufacture, possess, transport, or place:<section prefix="(1)">a device or container that is labeled as containing or is intended to represent a toxic material, as defined in &#xA7; 4-501 of this article, with the intent to terrorize, frighten, intimidate, threaten, or harass; or</section><section prefix="(2)">a device that is constructed to represent a destructive device, as defined in &#xA7; 4-501 of this article, with the intent to terrorize, frighten, intimidate, threaten, or harass.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A person who violates this section is guilty of a felony and on conviction is subject to imprisonment not exceeding 10 years or a fine not exceeding $10,000 or both.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In addition to the penalty provided in subsection (b) of this section, a person convicted or found to have committed a delinquent act under this section may be ordered by the court to pay restitution to:<section prefix="(i)">the State, county, municipal corporation, bicounty unit, multicounty unit, county board of education, public authority, or special taxing district for actual costs reasonably incurred as a result of a violation of this section; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">the owner or tenant of a property for the actual value of any goods, services, or income lost as a result of the evacuation of the property as a result of a violation of this section.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">This subsection may not be construed to limit the right of a person to restitution under Title 11, Subtitle 6 of the Criminal Procedure Article.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">If the person convicted or found to have committed a delinquent act in violation of this section is a minor, the court may order the minor, the minor's parent, or both to pay the restitution described in paragraph (1) of this subsection.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">Except as otherwise provided in this section, the provisions of Title 11, Subtitle 6 of the Criminal Procedure Article apply to an order of restitution under this paragraph.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">In addition to any other penalty authorized by law, if the person convicted or found to have committed a delinquent act under this section is a minor, the court may order the Motor Vehicle Administration to initiate an action, under the motor vehicle laws, to suspend the driving privilege of the minor for a specified period not to exceed:<section prefix="(1)">for a first violation, 6 months; and</section><section prefix="(2)">for each subsequent violation, 1 year or until the person is 21 years old, whichever is longer.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
