<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcr" order_by="" level="1">Criminal Law</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcr-13-2416</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>2416</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The gaming commission consists of seven members.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Of the seven members of the gaming commission:<section prefix="(i)">three shall be appointed by the county commissioners;</section><section prefix="(ii)">one shall be appointed by the State Senators whose districts are in or include part of the county;</section><section prefix="(iii)">one shall be appointed by the chairperson of the county delegation to the House of Delegates, with the concurrence of that delegation;</section><section prefix="(iv)">one shall be from the Washington County Clubs Association, appointed by the county Senate and House delegations; and</section><section prefix="(v)">one shall be a representative of the alcoholic beverages, restaurant, and tavern industries in the county, appointed by the county Senate and House delegations.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Each member of the gaming commission shall be a resident of the county.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A member appointed to the gaming commission under subsection (a)(2)(i), (ii), or (iii) of this section may not:<section prefix="(i)">hold a tip jar license or wholesaler's license or be employed by a person who holds a tip jar license or wholesaler's license; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">hold an ownership interest in or receive a direct benefit from a person who holds a tip jar license or wholesaler's license.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If a member of the gaming commission serves on the board of directors or as an officer of an organization and that organization applies for funds from the gaming commission, the member shall cease immediately to serve on the gaming commission.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The term of a member of the gaming commission is 2 years and begins on March 1 or October 1, according to the staggered schedule required by the terms provided for members of the gaming commission on October 1, 2002.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">At the end of a term, a member continues to serve until a successor is appointed.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A member who is appointed after a term has begun serves only for the rest of the term and until a successor is appointed.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">A member who completes two full terms on the gaming commission may not be reappointed within the 5 years after the end of the second term.</section>
  </text>
</law>
