<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcr" order_by="" level="1">Criminal Law</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcr-4-501</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>501</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Destructive device" means explosive material, incendiary material, or toxic material that is:<section prefix="(i)">combined with a delivery or detonating apparatus so as to be capable of inflicting injury to persons or damage to property; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">deliberately modified, containerized, or otherwise equipped with a special delivery, activation, or detonation component that gives the material destructive characteristics of a military ordnance.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Destructive device" includes a bomb, grenade, mine, shell, missile, flamethrower, poison gas, Molotov cocktail, pipe bomb, and petroleum-soaked ammonium nitrate.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Explosive material" means material that explodes when detonated and has a destructive capability.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Explosive material" includes:<section prefix="(i)">explosives as defined in &#xA7; 11-101 of the Public Safety Article; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">dynamite for construction work, ammonium nitrate, natural gas in pipelines or storage tanks, ether, and cannisterized oxygen for health care facilities.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Explosive material" does not include items excluded from explosives in &#xA7; 11-101 of the Public Safety Article when the items are used in their original configuration.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Incendiary material" means a flammable or combustible liquid.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Incendiary material" includes gasoline, acetone, benzene, butane, jet fuel, fuel oil, kerosene, and diesel fuel.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Toxic material" means material that is capable of causing death or serious bodily injury almost immediately on being absorbed through the skin, inhaled, or ingested.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Toxic material" includes:<section prefix="(i)">nerve gas, mustard gas, cyanide gas, chlorine gas, sulphuric acid, or their precursors; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">a biological substance containing a disease organism or microorganism.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
