<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gcr" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="5-301" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcr-5-301</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as otherwise provided in this section, a person shall be registered by the Department before the person manufactures, distributes, or dispenses a controlled dangerous substance in the State.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Department shall adopt regulations to carry out this subsection.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">An applicant must register separately each principal place of business or professional practice where the applicant manufactures, distributes, or dispenses a controlled dangerous substance.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">To the extent authorized by the registration and subject to subsection (b) of this section and this subtitle, a person registered by the Department under this subtitle may:<section prefix="(1)">possess, manufacture, distribute, or dispense controlled dangerous substances; and</section><section prefix="(2)">perform any activity listed in item (1) of this subsection to conduct research.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A person need not register with the Department to possess a controlled dangerous substance while acting in the course of the person's business or profession if the person is:<section prefix="(1)">an agent or agent's employee of a registered manufacturer, distributor, or dispenser of a controlled dangerous substance;</section><section prefix="(2)">a common or contract carrier or warehouseman, or an employee of a common or contract carrier or warehouseman; or</section><section prefix="(3)">an ultimate user or person in possession of a controlled dangerous substance acting in good faith in accordance with a lawful order of an authorized provider.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">If the Department finds that a waiver is consistent with public health and safety, by regulation, the Department may waive the registration requirement for a manufacturer, distributor, or dispenser.</section>
  </text>
</law>
