<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gcr" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="10-201" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcr-10-201</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">"Public conveyance" means a conveyance to which the public or a portion of the public has access to and a right to use for transportation.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">"Public conveyance" includes an airplane, vessel, bus, railway car, school vehicle, and subway car.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">"Public place" means a place to which the public or a portion of the public has access and a right to resort for business, dwelling, entertainment, or other lawful purpose.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">"Public place" includes:</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">For purposes of a prosecution under this section, a public conveyance or a public place need not be devoted solely to public use.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A person may not willfully and without lawful purpose obstruct or hinder the free passage of another in a public place or on a public conveyance.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A person may not willfully act in a disorderly manner that disturbs the public peace.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A person may not willfully fail to obey a reasonable and lawful order that a law enforcement officer makes to prevent a disturbance to the public peace.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">A person who enters the land or premises of another, whether an owner or lessee, or a beach adjacent to residential riparian property, may not willfully:<section prefix="(i)">disturb the peace of persons on the land, premises, or beach by making an unreasonably loud noise; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">act in a disorderly manner.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(5)">A person from any location may not, by making an unreasonably loud noise, willfully disturb the peace of another:<section prefix="(i)">on the other's land or premises;</section><section prefix="(ii)">in a public place; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">on a public conveyance.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(6)">In Worcester County, a person may not build a bonfire or allow a bonfire to burn on a beach or other property between 1 a.m. and 5 a.m.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A person who violates this section is guilty of a misdemeanor and on conviction is subject to imprisonment not exceeding 60 days or a fine not exceeding $500 or both.</section>
  </text>
</law>
