<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcr" order_by="" level="1">Criminal Law</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcr-13-2426</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>2426</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">By regulation, the county commissioners may establish a temporary tip jar license for a nonprofit organization that desires to raise money solely for an athletic, charitable, or educational purpose that:<section prefix="(1)">meets the requirements for a charitable contribution under &#xA7; 170(c) of the Internal Revenue Code; and</section><section prefix="(2)">does not benefit a:<section prefix="(i)">law enforcement agency;</section><section prefix="(ii)">law enforcement fraternal organization;</section><section prefix="(iii)">political club, political committee, or political party; or</section><section prefix="(iv)">unit of the State government or of a political subdivision of the State other than:<section prefix="1.">an ambulance, fire fighting, or rescue squad; or</section><section prefix="2.">a primary or secondary school or an institution of higher education.</section></section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">If the county commissioners establish a temporary tip jar license, by regulation, the county commissioners shall:<section prefix="(1)">set the fee for a temporary tip jar license;</section><section prefix="(2)">set the term of a temporary tip jar license;</section><section prefix="(3)">prescribe which provisions of Part III of this subtitle apply to the issuance of a temporary tip jar license and the operation of a tip jar under a temporary tip jar license; and</section><section prefix="(4)">establish any additional requirements that the county commissioners consider appropriate concerning operation of a tip jar under a temporary tip jar license.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">An organization that receives a temporary tip jar license is subject to audit by the gaming commission.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">An individual involved in the operation of a tip jar under a temporary tip jar license may not personally benefit financially from the operation of the tip jar.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">If an organization that has operated a tip jar under a temporary tip jar license disbands, the organization shall transfer any remaining proceeds from the operation of a tip jar to the fund.</section>
  </text>
</law>
