<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcr" order_by="gcr" level="1">Criminal Law</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcr-4-503</section_number>
  <catch_line>A person may not knowingly:...</catch_line>
  <order_by>503</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">A person may not knowingly:<section prefix="(1)">manufacture, transport, possess, control, store, sell, distribute, or use a destructive device; or</section><section prefix="(2)">possess explosive material, incendiary material, or toxic material with intent to create a destructive device.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A person who violates this section is guilty of a felony and on conviction is subject to imprisonment not exceeding 25 years or a fine not exceeding $250,000 or both.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A sentence imposed under this subsection may be separate from and consecutive to or concurrent with a sentence for a crime based on the act or acts establishing the violation of this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">In addition to any other penalty authorized by law, if the person convicted or found to have committed a delinquent act under this section is a minor, the court may order the Motor Vehicle Administration to initiate an action, under the motor vehicle laws, to suspend the driving privilege of the minor for a specified period not to exceed:<section prefix="(i)">for a first violation, 6 months; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">for each subsequent violation, 1 year or until the person is 21 years old, whichever is longer.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In addition to any penalty provided in subsection (b) of this section, a person convicted or found to have committed a delinquent act under this section may be ordered by the court to pay restitution to:<section prefix="(i)">the State, county, municipal corporation, bicounty agency, multicounty agency, county board of education, public authority, or special taxing district for actual costs reasonably incurred due to a violation of this section, including the search for, removal of, and damages caused by a destructive device; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">the owner or tenant of a property for the actual value of any goods, services, or income lost as a result of the evacuation of the property or damage sustained due to a violation of this section.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">If a person convicted or found to have committed a delinquent act under this section is a minor, the court may order the minor, the minor's parent, or both to pay the restitution described in paragraph (1) of this subsection.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">Except as otherwise provided in this section, the provisions of Title 11, Subtitle 6 of the Criminal Procedure Article apply to an order of restitution under this paragraph.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">This subsection does not limit the right of a person to restitution under Title 11, Subtitle 6 of the Criminal Procedure Article.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
