<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcr" order_by="gcr" level="1">Criminal Law</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcr-9-804</section_number>
  <catch_line>A person may not:...</catch_line>
  <order_by>804</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">A person may not:<section prefix="(1)">participate in a criminal gang knowing that the members of the gang engage in a pattern of criminal gang activity; and</section><section prefix="(2)">knowingly and willfully direct or participate in an underlying crime, or act by a juvenile that would be an underlying crime if committed by an adult, committed for the benefit of, at the direction of, or in association with a criminal gang.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A person may not violate subsection (a) of this section that results in the death of a victim.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Except as provided in subparagraph (ii) of this paragraph, a person who violates this section is guilty of a felony and on conviction is subject to imprisonment not exceeding 10 years or a fine not exceeding $100,000 or both.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">A person who violates subsection (b) of this section is guilty of a felony and on conviction is subject to imprisonment not exceeding 20 years or a fine not exceeding $100,000 or both.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">A sentence imposed under paragraph (1)(i) of this subsection  for a first offense may be separate from and consecutive to or concurrent with a sentence for any crime based on the act establishing a violation of this section.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">A sentence imposed under paragraph (1)(i) of this subsection for a second or subsequent offense, or paragraph (1)(ii) of this subsection shall be separate from and consecutive to a sentence for any crime based on the act establishing a violation of this section.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">A consecutive sentence for a second or subsequent offense shall not be mandatory unless the State notifies the person in writing of the State's intention to proceed against the person as a second or subsequent offender at least 30 days before trial.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A person may be charged with a violation of this section only by indictment, criminal information, or petition alleging a delinquent act.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Attorney General, at the request of the State's Attorney for a county in which a violation or an act establishing a violation of this section occurs, may:<section prefix="(i)">aid in the investigation of the violation or act; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">prosecute the violation or act.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">In exercising authority under paragraph (1) of this subsection, the Attorney General has all the powers and duties of a State's Attorney, including the use of the grand jury in the county, to prosecute the violation.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, in circumstances in which violations of this section are alleged to have been committed in more than one county, the respective State's Attorney of each county, or the Attorney General, may join the causes of action in a single complaint with the consent of each State's Attorney having jurisdiction over an offense sought to be joined.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">Notwithstanding any other provision of law and provided at least one criminal gang activity of a criminal gang allegedly occurred in the county in which a grand jury is sitting, the grand jury may issue subpoenas, summon witnesses, and otherwise conduct an investigation of the alleged criminal gang's activities and offenses in other counties.</section>
  </text>
</law>
