<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gcr" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="13-507" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcr-13-507</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">This section and &#xA7; 13-509 of this subtitle also apply to games of instant bingo.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Before an organization listed in subsection (c) or (d) of this section may conduct bingo in Baltimore City, the organization shall obtain a permit to do so from the commissioner.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">An organization that meets the conditions of subsection (i)(1) of this section may conduct bingo in Baltimore City if the organization is a bona fide:<section prefix="(1)">religious organization;</section><section prefix="(2)">fraternal organization;</section><section prefix="(3)">patriotic organization;</section><section prefix="(4)">educational organization; or</section><section prefix="(5)">charitable organization.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">An organization that meets the conditions of subsection (i)(2) of this section may conduct bingo in Baltimore City if the organization is:<section prefix="(1)">devoted exclusively to religious, charitable, or educational purposes;</section><section prefix="(2)">a service organization;</section><section prefix="(3)">a fraternal organization; or</section><section prefix="(4)">a veterans' organization.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Before the commissioner may issue a permit, the commissioner shall review the character of the organization applying for the permit to ascertain that the organization meets the requirements of this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The organization applying for the permit shall pay the permit fee set in subsection (g) of this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">An application for a permit and the action taken by the commissioner on that application are public records.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The commissioner may issue a permit for:<section prefix="(1)">1 day; or</section><section prefix="(2)">a period exceeding 1 day and not exceeding 12 months.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(g)">Except as allowed under subsection (h)(1) of this section, the commissioner shall collect from each permit holder, to cover the costs of administering the Baltimore City bingo laws, a permit fee not exceeding:<section prefix="(1)">$10 for each day on which bingo may be conducted;</section><section prefix="(2)">$750 for a 3-month period; or</section><section prefix="(3)">$3,000 for a 12-month period.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(h)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The commissioner may collect a special annual permit fee of $5 for a nonprofit organization or nonprofit corporation to conduct, over 1 year, a number of bingo games for which, for each game:<section prefix="(i)">the value of any prize of merchandise or money is not more than $5; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">not more than 100 individuals play.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The commissioner may revoke a special annual permit for cause.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(i)">
      <section prefix="(1)">An organization conducting bingo in Baltimore City under subsection (c) of this section:<section prefix="(i)">except as provided in subsection (d) of this section, may not offer or award, in any game:</section><section prefix="(ii)">after reimbursing any costs incurred in conducting bingo for personnel, supplies, equipment, and other expenses, shall use the entire proceeds for:</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">An organization conducting bingo in Baltimore City under subsection (d) of this section:<section prefix="(i)">may not use the net proceeds to benefit a stockholder or member of the organization;</section><section prefix="(ii)">after reimbursing any costs incurred in conducting bingo for personnel, supplies, equipment, and other expenses, shall use the net proceeds:</section><section prefix="(iii)">shall limit prizes of money or merchandise to a value not exceeding:</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A bingo permit holder issued a permit under either subsection (c) or (d) of this section may not conduct bingo:<section prefix="(i)">in a restaurant or tavern where alcoholic beverages are sold;</section><section prefix="(ii)">in a permanent place of amusement or entertainment; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">on Sunday, except by a bona fide religious organization that conducts bingo on property owned or leased by the organization.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
