<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcr" order_by="gcr" level="1">Criminal Law</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcr-11-203</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this section the following words have the meanings indicated....</catch_line>
  <order_by>203</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Distribute" includes to rent.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Illicit sex" means:<section prefix="(i)">human genitals in a state of sexual stimulation or arousal;</section><section prefix="(ii)">acts of human masturbation, sexual intercourse, or sodomy; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">fondling or other erotic touching of human genitals.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">"Item" means a:<section prefix="(i)">still picture or photograph;</section><section prefix="(ii)">book, pocket book, pamphlet, or magazine;</section><section prefix="(iii)">videodisc, videotape, video game, film, or computer disc; or</section><section prefix="(iv)">recorded telephone message.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(5)">"Obscene" means:<section prefix="(i)">that the average adult applying contemporary community standards would find that the work, taken as a whole, appeals to the prurient interest;</section><section prefix="(ii)">that the work depicts sexual conduct specified in subsection (b) of this section in a way that is patently offensive to prevailing standards in the adult community as a whole with respect to what is suitable material; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">that the work, taken as a whole, lacks serious artistic, educational, literary, political, or scientific value.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(6)">"Partially nude figure" means a figure with:<section prefix="(i)">less than completely and opaquely covered human genitals, pubic region, buttocks, or female breast below a point immediately above the top of the areola; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">human male genitals in a discernibly turgid state, even if completely and opaquely covered.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A person may not willfully or knowingly display or exhibit to a minor an item:<section prefix="(i)">the cover or content of which is principally made up of an obscene description or depiction of illicit sex; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">that consists of an obscene picture of a nude or partially nude figure.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A person may not willfully or knowingly engage in the business of displaying, exhibiting, selling, showing, advertising for sale, or distributing to a minor an item:<section prefix="(i)">the cover or content of which is principally made up of an obscene description or depiction of illicit sex; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">that consists of an obscene picture of a nude or partially nude figure.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">If a newsstand or other place of business is frequented by minors, the owner, operator, franchisee, manager, or an employee with managerial responsibility may not openly and knowingly display at the place of business an item whose sale, display, exhibition, showing, or advertising is prohibited by paragraph (2) of this subsection.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The provision of services or facilities by a telephone company under a tariff approved by the Public Service Commission is not a violation of subsection (b) of this section relating to recorded telephone messages.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A person who violates this section is guilty of a misdemeanor and on conviction is subject to:<section prefix="(1)">for a first violation, imprisonment not exceeding 1 year or a fine not exceeding $1,000 or both; and</section><section prefix="(2)">for each subsequent violation, imprisonment not exceeding 3 years or a fine not exceeding $5,000 or both.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
