<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcr" order_by="gcr" level="1">Criminal Law</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcr-6-301</section_number>
  <catch_line>A person may not willfully and maliciously destroy, injure, or deface the real or personal property ...</catch_line>
  <order_by>301</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">A person may not willfully and maliciously destroy, injure, or deface the real or personal property of another.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A person who, in violation of this section, causes damage of at least $500 to the property is guilty of a misdemeanor and on conviction is subject to imprisonment not exceeding 3 years or a fine not exceeding $2,500 or both.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A person who, in violation of this section, causes damage of less than $500 to the property is guilty of a misdemeanor and on conviction is subject to imprisonment not exceeding 60 days or a fine not exceeding $500 or both.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">For purposes of this subsection, an act of "graffiti" means a permanent drawing, permanent painting, or a permanent mark or inscription on the property of another without the permission of the owner of the property.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">In addition to the penalties set forth in subsections (b) and (c) of this section, the court shall order a person convicted of causing malicious destruction by an act of graffiti to pay restitution or perform community service or both.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Title 11, Subtitle 6 of the Criminal Procedure Article applies to an order of restitution under this subsection.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, to determine a penalty, the court may consider as one crime the aggregate value of damage to each property resulting from one scheme or continuing course of conduct.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If separate acts resulting in damage to the properties of one or more owners are set forth by separate counts in one or more charging documents, the separate counts may not be merged for sentencing.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The value of damage is not a substantive element of a crime under this section and need not be stated in the charging document.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The value of damage shall be based on the evidence and that value shall be applied for the purpose of imposing the penalties established in this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">If it cannot be determined from the evidence whether the value of the damage to the property is more or less than $500, the value is deemed to be less than $500.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
