<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcr" order_by="gcr" level="1">Criminal Law</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcr-8-205</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this section the following words have the meanings indicated....</catch_line>
  <order_by>205</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Falsely emboss" means to complete a credit card without the authorization of the issuer named on the credit card by adding any of the matter, other than the signature of the cardholder, that the issuer requires to appear on a credit card before it can be used by a cardholder.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Falsely make" means:<section prefix="(i)">to make or draw, wholly or partly, a device or instrument that purports to be a credit card but that is not a credit card because an issuer did not authorize the making or drawing; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">to alter a credit card that was validly issued.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A person may not, with the intent to defraud another:<section prefix="(1)">falsely make a purported credit card;</section><section prefix="(2)">falsely emboss a credit card; or</section><section prefix="(3)">transfer or possess:<section prefix="(i)">a falsely made instrument or device that purports to be a credit card, with knowledge that the instrument or device was falsely made; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">a falsely embossed credit card with knowledge that the credit card was falsely made or falsely embossed.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A person other than the cardholder or one authorized by the cardholder may not sign a credit card with the intent to defraud another.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A person who violates this section is guilty of the felony of credit card counterfeiting and on conviction is subject to imprisonment not exceeding 15 years or a fine not exceeding $1,000 or both.</section>
  </text>
</law>
