<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcr" order_by="gcr" level="1">Criminal Law</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcr-13-604</section_number>
  <catch_line>Subject to subsections (b) and (c) of this section, an organization may conduct:...</catch_line>
  <order_by>604</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Subject to subsections (b) and (c) of this section, an organization may conduct:<section prefix="(1)">one casino event that includes a card game during each calendar month; and</section><section prefix="(2)">one casino event that includes roulette during each calendar year.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">To conduct a casino event under subsection (a) of this section, an organization shall be a bona fide:<section prefix="(1)">religious organization;</section><section prefix="(2)">fraternal organization;</section><section prefix="(3)">civic organization, including:<section prefix="(i)">a hunting organization;</section><section prefix="(ii)">a social organization; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">a sporting organization;</section></section><section prefix="(4)">volunteer fire company;</section><section prefix="(5)">war veterans' organization; or</section><section prefix="(6)">charitable organization.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A permit holder for a casino event that includes a card game or roulette shall ensure that:<section prefix="(i)">the event is conducted in accordance with &#xA7; 13-603(d)(3) of this subtitle;</section><section prefix="(ii)">a parent, subsidiary, or affiliate of the organization sponsoring the event has not sponsored a casino event within the calendar month; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">the casino event is conducted between 4 p.m. and 1 a.m.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A person that holds a casino event that includes a card game or roulette may not:<section prefix="(i)">offer or award a money prize to a player of the card game or roulette game;</section><section prefix="(ii)">allow a player to bet more than $10 in any one game within the calendar month;</section><section prefix="(iii)">exchange tokens used in wagering for an item of merchandise that is worth more than $1,000; or</section><section prefix="(iv)">exchange merchandise that was received for tokens that were used in wagering for:<section prefix="1.">money; or</section><section prefix="2.">an item of merchandise having a value that is different from the fair retail market value of the item of merchandise that was received for the tokens.</section></section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Within 60 days after holding a casino event that includes a card game or roulette, the holder of the permit for the event shall submit to the Department of Permits and Development Management a financial report that lists the receipts and expenditures for the casino event.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">Before the permit holder submits the report to the Department of Permits and Development Management, the permit holder shall submit the report to the county police department for review.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Department of Permits and Development Management shall adopt regulations to govern:<section prefix="(i)">the issuing of a permit to conduct a casino event; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">the conduct and management of a casino event in a manner designed to prevent fraud and protect the public.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The regulations shall require that a separate permit be issued for each casino event to be conducted.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
