<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcr" order_by="" level="1">Criminal Law</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcr-13-903</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>903</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Before an organization may conduct a gaming event, the organization shall obtain a permit from the county commissioners.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">To conduct bingo or a gaming event an organization  must be a bona fide:<section prefix="(1)">religious organization;</section><section prefix="(2)">fraternal organization;</section><section prefix="(3)">civic organization;</section><section prefix="(4)">war veterans' organization;</section><section prefix="(5)">hospital;</section><section prefix="(6)">amateur athletic organization;</section><section prefix="(7)">charitable organization; or</section><section prefix="(8)">volunteer fire company.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Before the county commissioners issue a permit, they shall determine whether the organization applying for the permit qualifies under this subtitle and the conditions of this subtitle are met.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">An application for a permit and the action taken by the county commissioners on that application are public records.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The permit shall state that the gaming event shall be managed and operated only by members of the organization holding the permit.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A permit is not transferable.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A gaming event conducted under this section shall be conducted for the benefit of an organization listed in subsection (b) of this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">An individual or group of individuals may not benefit financially, or receive proceeds for personal use or benefit, from a gaming event conducted under this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A permit may not authorize the operation of a gaming event after 1 a.m. on Sunday.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Except as provided in subparagraphs (ii) and (iv) of this paragraph, an organization conducting a gaming event may award a money prize not exceeding $100 or merchandise not exceeding $100 of value to any individual in any one game.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The maximum amount of a prize awarded in a raffle is governed by &#xA7; 13-904(c) of this subtitle.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">The maximum amount of a prize awarded in a paddle wheel or wheel of fortune game is governed by &#xA7; 13-905(a) of this subtitle.</section>
        <section prefix="(iv)">The maximum amount of a prize awarded in bingo is governed by &#xA7; 13-908 of this subtitle.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
