<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gcr" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="5-810" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcr-5-810</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Drug crime" means:<section prefix="(i)">a violation of this title;</section><section prefix="(ii)">a violation of Title 12 of the Criminal Procedure Article; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">a violation of the law of any other jurisdiction if the prohibited conduct would be a violation of this title or Title 12 of the Criminal Procedure Article if committed in this State.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"License" has the meaning stated in Article 41, &#xA7; 1-501 of the Code.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">"Licensing authority" has the meaning stated in Article 41, &#xA7; 1-501 of the Code.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">"Licensing information" means a statement of:<section prefix="(i)">each license held by the defendant on the date of sentencing;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the full name of the licensee as it appears on the license and, if different, as it appears in the court's docket;</section><section prefix="(iii)">the birth date of the licensee; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">the name of each licensing authority by whom the defendant is licensed.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If an individual is convicted of a drug crime, the court:<section prefix="(i)">shall determine at sentencing whether the individual holds a license; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">if the individual holds a license, shall obtain the licensing information.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If the individual holds a license, at sentencing, the court shall make a prima facie finding of fact as to whether a relationship exists between the conviction and the license including:<section prefix="(i)">a determination of the individual's ability to perform the tasks authorized by the license;</section><section prefix="(ii)">a finding of whether the public will be protected if the individual continues to perform the tasks authorized by the license;</section><section prefix="(iii)">a finding of whether the nature and circumstances of the drug crime merit referral to the licensing authority; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">a finding of any other facts that the court considers relevant.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">If the court makes a prima facie finding of fact that a relationship between the conviction and the license exists, the court shall follow the procedures under subsection (c) of this section.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This subsection applies to a conviction of a licensee for a drug crime if:<section prefix="(i)">the licensee has at least one prior conviction or probation before judgment for a drug crime committed on or after January 1, 1991; or</section><section prefix="(ii)"/></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">On conviction of a licensee, the court shall:<section prefix="(i)">notify the clerk of the court of the determination; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">provide the clerk of the court with the licensing information.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The clerk of the court shall certify and report the conviction and the licensing information to the licensing authority, under administrative orders that the Chief Judge of the Court of Appeals adopts.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">If the court makes a prima facie finding of fact under subsection (b) of this section that a relationship between the conviction and the license does not exist, the clerk may not certify or report to a licensing authority the conviction or the licensing information.</section>
  </text>
</law>
