<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gcr" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="8-613" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcr-8-613</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Service" includes the use of telephone or telegraph facilities, gas, electricity, or a musical instrument, phonograph, or other property.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Vending machine" includes a slot machine, pay telephone, or other receptacle designed to receive United States currency in connection with the sale or use of property or of a service.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A person may not:<section prefix="(1)">operate, cause to be operated, or attempt to operate or cause to be operated a vending machine by a means not lawfully authorized by the owner, lessee, or licensee of the vending machine, including by means of a slug or by counterfeit, mutilated, sweated, or foreign currency;</section><section prefix="(2)">take, obtain, or receive from or in connection with a vending machine any property or service, without depositing into the vending machine United States currency in the amount required by the owner, lessee, or licensee of the vending machine; or</section><section prefix="(3)">manufacture for sale, sell, or give away a slug or device that is intended to be deposited in a vending machine if the person:<section prefix="(i)">intends to defraud the owner, lessee, licensee, or other person entitled to the contents of the vending machine; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">knows that the slug or device is intended for unlawful use.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A person who violates this section is guilty of a misdemeanor and on conviction is subject to imprisonment not exceeding 3 months or a fine not exceeding $500 or both.</section>
  </text>
</law>
