<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gcr" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="13-2424" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcr-13-2424</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">At least three times a year, a tip jar licensee shall submit to the county commissioners a report concerning the tip jars the person operates.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Each report shall:<section prefix="(1)">identify gaming stickers used;</section><section prefix="(2)">indicate the number of tip jars in operation;</section><section prefix="(3)">indicate the number of tip jar packets purchased; and</section><section prefix="(4)">include any additional information that the county commissioners require.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This subsection only applies to a person who qualifies for a tip jar license under &#xA7; 13-2420(b)(7), (8), or (9) of this subtitle.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">In accordance with regulations of the county commissioners, a person subject to this subsection shall include in each report an accounting of receipts and disbursements made in connection with tip jars for the reporting period.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Each report shall include a written statement, signed by the individual making the report, in which the individual affirms under the penalties of Part III of this subtitle and under the penalty of perjury that the contents of the report are true to the best of the individual's knowledge, information, and belief.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This subsection only applies to an organization that qualifies for a tip jar license under &#xA7; 13-2420(b)(1) through (6) of this subtitle.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Each report for an organization that is subject to this subsection:<section prefix="(i)">shall be filed by an officer of the organization; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">in accordance with regulations of the county commissioners, shall include for the reporting period an accounting of:</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">In filing a report under this subsection, the officer of the organization may not:<section prefix="(i)">fraudulently use a false or fictitious name;</section><section prefix="(ii)">knowingly conceal a material fact;</section><section prefix="(iii)">knowingly make a false statement; or</section><section prefix="(iv)">otherwise commit fraud.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">A person who violates paragraph (3) of this subsection is guilty of a misdemeanor and on conviction is subject to imprisonment not exceeding 90 days or a fine not exceeding $1,000 or both.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
