<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcr" order_by="gcr" level="1">Criminal Law</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcr-3-212</section_number>
  <catch_line>An indictment, information, or other charging document for a crime described in &#xA7; 3-211 of this sub...</catch_line>
  <order_by>212</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">An indictment, information, or other charging document for a crime described in &#xA7; 3-211 of this subtitle is sufficient if it substantially states:<section prefix="(1)">"(name of defendant) on (date) in (county) caused a life-threatening injury to (name of victim) while under the influence of alcohol, in violation of &#xA7; 3-211(c)(1)(i) of the Criminal Law Article against the peace, government, and dignity of the State.";</section><section prefix="(2)">"(name of defendant) on (date) in (county) caused a life-threatening injury to (name of victim) while under the influence of alcohol per se, in violation of &#xA7; 3-211(c)(1)(ii) of the Criminal Law Article against the peace, government, and dignity of the State.";</section><section prefix="(3)">"(name of defendant) on (date) in (county) caused a life-threatening injury to (name of victim) while impaired by alcohol, in violation of &#xA7; 3-211(d) of the Criminal Law Article against the peace, government, and dignity of the State.";</section><section prefix="(4)">"(name of defendant) on (date) in (county) caused a life-threatening injury to (name of victim) while impaired by drugs, in violation of &#xA7; 3-211(e) of the Criminal Law Article against the peace, government, and dignity of the State."; or</section><section prefix="(5)">"(name of defendant) on (date) in (county) caused a life-threatening injury to (name of victim) while impaired by a controlled dangerous substance, in violation of &#xA7; 3-211(f) of the Criminal Law Article against the peace, government, and dignity of the State.".</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">An indictment, information, or other charging document for a crime described in &#xA7; 3-211 of this subtitle need not set forth the manner or means of the life-threatening injury.</section>
  </text>
</law>
