<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gcr" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="5-101" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcr-5-101</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this title the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Administer" means to introduce a substance into the system of a human or animal by injection, inhalation, ingestion, application to the skin, or any combination of those methods or by any other means.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Agent" means an employee or other authorized person who acts for or at the direction of a manufacturer, distributor, or authorized provider.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Agent" does not include:<section prefix="(i)">a common carrier, contract carrier, or public warehouseman; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">an employee of a common carrier, contract carrier, or public warehouseman.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Authorized provider" means:<section prefix="(i)">a person licensed, registered, or otherwise allowed to administer, distribute, dispense, or conduct research on a controlled dangerous substance in the State in the course of professional practice or research; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">a pharmacy, laboratory, hospital, or other institution licensed, registered, or otherwise allowed to administer, distribute, dispense, or conduct research on a controlled dangerous substance in the State in the course of professional practice or research.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Authorized provider" includes:<section prefix="(i)">a scientific investigator;</section><section prefix="(ii)">an individual authorized by the State to practice medicine, dentistry, or veterinary medicine; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">an animal control facility licensed under &#xA7; 2-305 of the Agriculture Article.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Coca leaf" includes a leaf containing cocaine, the optical and geometric isomers of cocaine, and any compound, manufactured substance, salt, derivative, mixture, or preparation of a coca leaf.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Coca leaf" does not include a derivative of a coca leaf that does not contain cocaine, ecgonine, or a substance from which cocaine or ecgonine may be synthesized or made.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Controlled dangerous substance" means:<section prefix="(i)">a drug or substance listed in Schedule I through Schedule V; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">an immediate precursor to a drug or substance listed in Schedule I through Schedule V that:</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Controlled dangerous substance" does not include distilled spirits, wine, malt beverages, or tobacco.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">"Controlled paraphernalia" means:<section prefix="(1)">a hypodermic syringe, needle, or any other object or combination of objects adapted to administer a controlled dangerous substance by hypodermic injection;</section><section prefix="(2)">a gelatin capsule, glassine envelope, or other container suitable for packaging individual quantities of a controlled dangerous substance; or</section><section prefix="(3)">lactose, quinine, mannite, mannitol, dextrose, sucrose, procaine hydrochloride, or any other substance suitable as a diluent or adulterant.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(h)">"Deliver" means to make an actual, constructive, or attempted transfer or exchange from one person to another whether or not remuneration is paid or an agency relationship exists.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">"Department" means the Department of Health and Mental Hygiene.</section>
    <section prefix="(j)">"Depressant or stimulant drug" means a drug that contains any quantity of a substance that the Attorney General of the United States by regulation designates as having a potential for abuse because of:<section prefix="(1)">a depressant or stimulant effect on the central nervous system; or</section><section prefix="(2)">a hallucinogenic effect.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(k)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Dispense" means to deliver to the ultimate user or the human research subject by or in accordance with the lawful order of an authorized provider.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Dispense" includes to prescribe, administer, package, label, or compound a substance for delivery.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(l)">"Distribute" means, with respect to a controlled dangerous substance, to deliver other than by dispensing.</section>
    <section prefix="(m)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Drug" means:<section prefix="(i)">a substance recognized in the official United States Pharmacopoeia, official Homeopathic Pharmacopoeia of the United States, or official National Formulary;</section><section prefix="(ii)">a substance intended for use in the diagnosis, cure, mitigation, treatment, or prevention of disease in humans or other animals;</section><section prefix="(iii)">except for food, a substance intended to affect the structure or function of the body of humans or other animals; or</section><section prefix="(iv)">a substance intended for use as a component of any substance specified in item (i), (ii), or (iii) of this paragraph.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Drug" does not include a device or an accessory, part, or component of a device.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(n)">"Drug dependent person" means a person who:<section prefix="(1)">is using a controlled dangerous substance; and</section><section prefix="(2)">is in a state of psychological or physical dependence, or both, that:<section prefix="(i)">arises from administration of that controlled dangerous substance on a continuous basis; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">is characterized by behavioral and other responses that include a strong compulsion to take the substance on a continuous basis in order to experience its psychological effects or to avoid the discomfort of its absence.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(o)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Drug paraphernalia" means equipment, a product, or material that is used, intended for use, or designed for use, in:<section prefix="(i)">planting, propagating, cultivating, growing, harvesting, manufacturing, compounding, converting, producing, processing, preparing, testing, analyzing, packaging, repackaging, storing, containing, or concealing a controlled dangerous substance in violation of this title; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">injecting, ingesting, inhaling, or otherwise introducing into the human body a controlled dangerous substance in violation of this title.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Drug paraphernalia" includes:<section prefix="(i)">a kit used, intended for use, or designed for use in planting, propagating, cultivating, growing, or harvesting any species of plant that is a controlled dangerous substance or from which a controlled dangerous substance can be derived;</section><section prefix="(ii)">a kit used, intended for use, or designed for use in manufacturing, compounding, converting, producing, processing, or preparing a controlled dangerous substance;</section><section prefix="(iii)">an isomerization device used, intended for use, or designed for use in increasing the potency of any species of plant that is a controlled dangerous substance;</section><section prefix="(iv)">testing equipment used, intended for use, or designed for use in identifying or in analyzing the strength, effectiveness, or purity of a controlled dangerous substance;</section><section prefix="(v)">a scale or balance used, intended for use, or designed for use in weighing or measuring a controlled dangerous substance;</section><section prefix="(vi)">a diluent or adulterant, such as quinine hydrochloride, mannitol, mannite, dextrose, or lactose, used, intended for use, or designed for use in cutting a controlled dangerous substance;</section><section prefix="(vii)">a separation gin or sifter used, intended for use, or designed for use in removing twigs and seeds from, or in otherwise cleaning or refining, marijuana;</section><section prefix="(viii)">a blender, bowl, container, spoon, or mixing device used, intended for use, or designed for use in compounding a controlled dangerous substance;</section><section prefix="(ix)">a capsule, balloon, envelope, or other container used, intended for use, or designed for use in packaging small quantities of a controlled dangerous substance;</section><section prefix="(x)">a container or other object used, intended for use, or designed for use in storing or concealing a controlled dangerous substance;</section><section prefix="(xi)">a hypodermic syringe, needle, or other object used, intended for use, or designed for use in parenterally injecting a controlled dangerous substance into the human body; and</section><section prefix="(xii)">an object used, intended for use, or designed for use in ingesting, inhaling, or otherwise introducing marijuana, cocaine, hashish, or hashish oil into the human body such as:</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(p)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Manufacture", with respect to a controlled dangerous substance, means to produce, prepare, propagate, compound, convert, or process a controlled dangerous substance:<section prefix="(i)">directly or indirectly by extraction from substances of natural origin;</section><section prefix="(ii)">independently by chemical synthesis; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">by a combination of extraction and chemical synthesis.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Manufacture" includes to package and repackage a controlled dangerous substance and label and relabel its containers.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Manufacture" does not include:<section prefix="(i)">to prepare or compound a controlled dangerous substance by an individual for the individual's own use; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">to prepare, compound, package, or label a controlled dangerous substance:</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(q)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Marijuana" means:<section prefix="(i)">all parts of any plant of the genus Cannabis, whether or not the plant is growing;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the seeds of the plant;</section><section prefix="(iii)">the resin extracted from the plant; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">each compound, manufactured product, salt, derivative, mixture, or preparation of the plant, its seeds, or its resin.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Marijuana" does not include:<section prefix="(i)">the mature stalks of the plant;</section><section prefix="(ii)">fiber produced from the mature stalks;</section><section prefix="(iii)">oil or cake made from the seeds of the plant;</section><section prefix="(iv)">except for resin, any other compound, manufactured product, salt, derivative, mixture, or preparation of the mature stalks, fiber, oil, or cake; or</section><section prefix="(v)">the sterilized seed of the plant that is incapable of germination.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(r)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Narcotic drug" means a substance:<section prefix="(i)">that has been found to present an extreme danger to the health and welfare of the community because of addiction-forming and addiction-sustaining qualities;</section><section prefix="(ii)">that is:</section><section prefix="(iii)">that is produced:</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Narcotic drug" includes decocainized coca leaf or an extract of coca leaf that does not contain cocaine or ecgonine.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(s)">"Noncontrolled substance" means a substance that is not classified as a controlled dangerous substance under Subtitle 4 of this title.</section>
    <section prefix="(t)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Opiate" means a substance that has an addiction-forming or addiction-sustaining quality similar to morphine or that can be converted into a drug that has this addiction-forming or addiction-sustaining quality.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Opiate" includes:<section prefix="(i)">the racemic and levorotatory forms of an opiate;</section><section prefix="(ii)">except for seeds, the opium poppy, the plant of the species Papaver somniferum L.;</section><section prefix="(iii)">the poppy straw consisting of the opium poppy after mowing except the seeds; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">coca leaf.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Opiate" does not include, unless specifically designated as controlled under &#xA7; 5-202 of this title, the dextrorotatory isomer of 3-methoxy-n-methyl-morphinan and its salts (dextromethorphan).</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(u)">"Possess" means to exercise actual or constructive dominion or control over a thing by one or more persons.</section>
    <section prefix="(v)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Prescription drug" means a drug that:<section prefix="(i)">is intended to be used by an individual; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">because of its toxicity, other potentiality for harmful effect, method of use, or collateral measures necessary for its use:</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Prescription drug" does not include a controlled dangerous substance.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(w)">"Produce", with respect to a controlled dangerous substance, includes to manufacture, plant, cultivate, grow, and harvest.</section>
    <section prefix="(x)">"Registrant" means a person who is registered by the Department to manufacture, distribute, or dispense a controlled dangerous substance in the State.</section>
    <section prefix="(y)">"Schedule I" means a list of controlled dangerous substances that appears in &#xA7; 5-402 of this title.</section>
    <section prefix="(z)">"Schedule II" means a list of controlled dangerous substances that appears in &#xA7; 5-403 of this title.</section>
    <section prefix="(aa)">"Schedule III" means a list of controlled dangerous substances that appears in &#xA7; 5-404 of this title.</section>
    <section prefix="(bb)">"Schedule IV" means a list of controlled dangerous substances that appears in &#xA7; 5-405 of this title.</section>
    <section prefix="(cc)">"Schedule V" means a list of controlled dangerous substances that appears in &#xA7; 5-406 of this title.</section>
    <section prefix="(dd)">"Secretary" means the Secretary of the Department.</section>
    <section prefix="(ee)">"Ultimate user" means a person who lawfully possesses a controlled dangerous substance for the person's own use, for the use of a member of the person's household, or for administration to an animal owned by the person or by a member of the person's household.</section>
  </text>
</law>
