<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcr" order_by="" level="1">Criminal Law</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcr-13-1503</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>1503</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Before an organization conducts a gaming event under this subtitle, the organization shall obtain a license from the sheriff.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The following organizations may obtain a license to conduct a gaming event:<section prefix="(1)">a bona fide religious group that has conducted religious services at a fixed location in the county for at least 3 years before applying for a license;</section><section prefix="(2)">a State-chartered organization authorized by a nationally chartered veterans organization;</section><section prefix="(3)">a tax-supported volunteer fire company; or</section><section prefix="(4)">a nonprofit organization that intends to raise money for an exclusively charitable, athletic, or educational purpose which is specifically described in the application for a license.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">An application for a license shall contain a certification by a principal officer of the organization that states:<section prefix="(1)">the scheduled time and place of the gaming event and the date of any raffle drawing;</section><section prefix="(2)">that the licensed activities will be managed and conducted solely and personally by the regular members of the organization without the assistance of gaming professionals;</section><section prefix="(3)">that all money prizes offered will comply with the limits listed in this subtitle;</section><section prefix="(4)">that the organization, by one of its principal officers, shall, within 15 days after the last day named in the application for conducting the licensed activities, file a report under penalties of perjury containing the information required by &#xA7; 13-1509 of this subtitle; and</section><section prefix="(5)">if the organization is a nonprofit organization that intends to raise money for an exclusively charitable, athletic, or educational purpose, a specific description of the purpose.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The sheriff shall charge the following license fees:<section prefix="(1)">$5 for a bingo license;</section><section prefix="(2)">$10 for a paddle wheel license;</section><section prefix="(3)">$10 for a raffle license;</section><section prefix="(4)">$10 for a 50/50 license; and</section><section prefix="(5)">$15 for a members-only instant bingo license.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">An activity for which a license is issued under this subtitle must be conducted and managed solely and personally by regular members of the organization:<section prefix="(1)">who do not regularly conduct gaming activities for any other organization; and</section><section prefix="(2)">without the assistance of gaming professionals.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
