<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gcr" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="4-209" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcr-4-209</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Except as otherwise provided in this section, the State preempts the right of a county, municipal corporation, or special taxing district to regulate the purchase, sale, taxation, transfer, manufacture, repair, ownership, possession, and transportation of:<section prefix="(1)">a handgun, rifle, or shotgun; and</section><section prefix="(2)">ammunition for and components of a handgun, rifle, or shotgun.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A county, municipal corporation, or special taxing district may regulate the purchase, sale, transfer, ownership, possession, and transportation of the items listed in subsection (a) of this section:<section prefix="(i)">with respect to minors;</section><section prefix="(ii)">with respect to law enforcement officials of the subdivision; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, within 100 yards of or in a park, church, school, public building, and other place of public assembly.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A county, municipal corporation, or special taxing district may not prohibit the teaching of or training in firearms safety, or other educational or sporting use of the items listed in subsection (a) of this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A county, municipal corporation, or special taxing district may not prohibit the transportation of an item listed in subsection (a) of this section by a person who is carrying a court order requiring the surrender of the item, if:<section prefix="(i)">the handgun, rifle, or shotgun is unloaded;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the person has notified the law enforcement unit, barracks, or station that the item is being transported in accordance with the court order; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">the person transports the item directly to the law enforcement unit, barracks, or station.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">To the extent that a local law does not create an inconsistency with this section or expand existing regulatory control, a county, municipal corporation, or special taxing district may exercise its existing authority to amend any local law that existed on or before December 31, 1984.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, in accordance with law, a county, municipal corporation, or special taxing district may regulate the discharge of handguns, rifles, and shotguns.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A county, municipal corporation, or special taxing district may not prohibit the discharge of firearms at established ranges.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
