<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcr" order_by="gcr" level="1">Criminal Law</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcr-3-902</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this section the following words have the meanings indicated....</catch_line>
  <order_by>902</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Camera" includes any electronic device that can be used surreptitiously to observe an individual.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Female breast" means a portion of the female breast below the top of the areola.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">"Private area of an individual" means the naked or undergarment-clad genitals, pubic area, buttocks, or female breast of an individual.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">
        <section prefix="(i)">"Private place" means a room in which a person can reasonably be expected to fully or partially disrobe and has a reasonable expectation of privacy, in:<section prefix="1.">an office, business, or store;</section><section prefix="2.">a recreational facility;</section><section prefix="3.">a restaurant or tavern;</section><section prefix="4.">a hotel, motel, or other lodging facility;</section><section prefix="5.">a theater or sports arena;</section><section prefix="6.">a school or other educational institution;</section><section prefix="7.">a bank or other financial institution;</section><section prefix="8.">any part of a family child care home used for the care and custody of a child; or</section><section prefix="9.">another place of public use or accommodation.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">"Private place" includes a tanning room, dressing room, bedroom, or restroom.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(6)">
        <section prefix="(i)">"Visual surveillance" means the deliberate, surreptitious observation of an individual by any means.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">"Visual surveillance" includes surveillance by:<section prefix="1.">direct sight;</section><section prefix="2.">the use of mirrors; or</section><section prefix="3.">the use of cameras.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">"Visual surveillance" does not include a casual, momentary, or unintentional observation of an individual.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">This section does not apply to a person who without prurient intent:<section prefix="(1)">conducts filming by or for the print or broadcast media;</section><section prefix="(2)">conducts or procures another to conduct visual surveillance of an individual to protect property or public safety or prevent crime; or</section><section prefix="(3)">conducts visual surveillance and:<section prefix="(i)">holds a license issued under Title 13 or Title 19 of the Business Occupations and Professions Article; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">is acting within the scope of the person's occupation.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A person may not with prurient intent conduct or procure another to conduct visual surveillance of:<section prefix="(1)">an individual in a private place without the consent of that individual; or</section><section prefix="(2)">the private area of an individual by use of a camera without the consent of the individual under circumstances in which a reasonable person would believe that the private area of the individual would not be visible to the public, regardless of whether the individual is in a public or private place.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A person who violates this section is guilty of a misdemeanor and on conviction is subject to imprisonment not exceeding 1 year or a fine not exceeding $2,500 or both.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">An individual who was under visual surveillance in violation of this section has a civil cause of action against any person who conducted or procured another to conduct the visual surveillance.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">In an action under this subsection, the court may award actual damages and reasonable attorney's fees.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">This section does not affect any legal or equitable right or remedy otherwise provided by law.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">This section does not affect the application of &#xA7; 3-901 of this subtitle.</section>
  </text>
</law>
