<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gcr" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="13-1803" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcr-13-1803</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A qualified organization may conduct bingo in the county to benefit charity or to further the purpose of the qualified organization.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Bingo shall be conducted only by the qualified organization and not by a person who:<section prefix="(i)">retains a portion of the proceeds from the bingo game; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">is compensated by the qualified organization for which the bingo is held.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A person may not receive a private profit from the proceeds of bingo.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">A qualified organization that conducts bingo shall:<section prefix="(i)">keep accurate records of all transactions that occur on behalf of the bingo game;</section><section prefix="(ii)">keep the records for 2 years after the bingo game; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">on request, make the records available for examination by:</section></section>
      <section prefix="(5)">A person conducting bingo shall be a resident of the county and a member of the qualified organization.</section>
      <section prefix="(6)">Alcoholic beverages may not be sold or consumed in the room in which bingo is conducted, either during a game or an intermission between games.</section>
      <section prefix="(7)">Money prizes not exceeding $1,000 in each game may be awarded in bingo.</section>
      <section prefix="(8)">The qualified organization may sell breakout tickets in the room in which bingo is conducted, either during a game or an intermission between games.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Notwithstanding any other provision of this subtitle, a person may conduct bingo at the annual Montgomery County Fair for the benefit of the Montgomery County Agricultural Center, Inc.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A person who conducts bingo under this subsection may award only noncash prizes.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
