<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcr" order_by="gcr" level="1">Criminal Law</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcr-13-1403</section_number>
  <catch_line>Before an organization listed in subsection (b) of this section may conduct a gaming event, the orga...</catch_line>
  <order_by>1403</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Before an organization listed in subsection (b) of this section may conduct a gaming event, the organization shall obtain a permit from the county agency that the County Commissioners designate.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">An organization may conduct a gaming event for its own benefit if the organization is:<section prefix="(1)">a bona fide:<section prefix="(i)">religious organization;</section><section prefix="(ii)">fraternal organization;</section><section prefix="(iii)">civic organization;</section><section prefix="(iv)">war veterans' organization;</section><section prefix="(v)">hospital;</section><section prefix="(vi)">amateur athletic organization;</section><section prefix="(vii)">patriotic organization;</section><section prefix="(viii)">educational organization; or</section><section prefix="(ix)">charitable organization;</section></section><section prefix="(2)">a county volunteer fire department or rescue squad; or</section><section prefix="(3)">an auxiliary for a county volunteer fire department or rescue squad.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Before the county agency may issue a gaming permit, the county agency shall determine whether the organization applying for the gaming permit meets the requirements of this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">An application and the action that the county agency takes on the application are public records.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">A gaming permit is valid for 1 year after the date that it is issued.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">A gaming permit may not be transferred.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The County Commissioners may charge a permit fee.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Only members of an organization that holds a gaming permit may conduct a gaming event.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Except as allowed under &#xA7; 13-1405 of this subtitle, an individual may not benefit financially from a gaming event.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A gaming permit may not authorize a gaming event to be conducted on a Sunday before 1 p.m.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The holder of a gaming permit may award:<section prefix="(1)">prizes to individuals at a gaming event; and</section><section prefix="(2)">only one major prize at each gaming event.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
