<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gcr" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="10-125" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcr-10-125</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as otherwise provided in subsection (c) of this section, an occupant of a motor vehicle may not possess an open container that contains any amount of an alcoholic beverage in a passenger area of a motor vehicle on a highway.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A driver of a motor vehicle may not be subject to prosecution for a violation of this subsection based solely on possession of an open container that contains any amount of an alcoholic beverage by another occupant of the motor vehicle.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This subsection does not apply to the driver of a motor vehicle.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Except as otherwise provided in subsection (c) of this section, an occupant of a motor vehicle may not consume an alcoholic beverage in a passenger area of a motor vehicle on a highway.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Subsections (a)(1) and (b)(2) of this section do not apply to an occupant, who is not the driver, in:<section prefix="(1)">a motor vehicle designed, maintained, and used primarily for the transportation of a person for compensation, including:<section prefix="(i)">a bus;</section><section prefix="(ii)">a taxicab; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">a limousine; or</section></section><section prefix="(2)">the living quarters of a motor home, motor coach, or recreational vehicle.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Notwithstanding Article 2B, Title 19 of the Code or any other provision of law, the prohibitions contained in this section apply throughout the State.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">A violation of this section is not:<section prefix="(1)">a moving violation for the purposes of &#xA7; 16-402 of the Transportation Article; or</section><section prefix="(2)">a traffic violation for the purposes of the Maryland Vehicle Law.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
