<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcr" order_by="" level="1">Criminal Law</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcr-5-202</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>202</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Department shall control all substances listed in Subtitle 4 of this title.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">In accordance with the Administrative Procedure Act, the Department may add a substance as a controlled dangerous substance on its own initiative or on the petition of an interested party.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">To determine whether to add a substance as a controlled dangerous substance, the Department shall consider:<section prefix="(1)">the actual or relative potential for abuse of the substance;</section><section prefix="(2)">if known, scientific evidence of the pharmacological effect of the substance;</section><section prefix="(3)">the state of current scientific knowledge regarding the substance;</section><section prefix="(4)">the history and current pattern of abuse of the substance;</section><section prefix="(5)">the scope, duration, and significance of abuse of the substance;</section><section prefix="(6)">any risk that the substance poses to the public health;</section><section prefix="(7)">the ability of the substance to cause psychological or physiological dependence; and</section><section prefix="(8)">whether the substance is an immediate precursor of a controlled dangerous substance.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">After considering the factors listed in subsection (c) of this section, the Department shall:<section prefix="(1)">make findings with respect to those factors; and</section><section prefix="(2)">issue an order to control the substance if the Department finds that the substance has a potential for abuse.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">If the Department designates a substance as an immediate precursor of a controlled dangerous substance, a substance that is a precursor of the immediate precursor is not subject to control solely because it is a precursor of the immediate precursor.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A new substance that is designated as a controlled substance under federal law is a similarly controlled dangerous substance under this title unless the Department objects to the inclusion.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If the Department objects, it shall publish the reasons for the objection and give each interested party an opportunity to be heard.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">After the hearing, the Department shall publish its decision, which is final.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">An action for judicial review of a final decision made in accordance with this section does not stay the effect of the decision.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">The Department annually shall update and republish a schedule.</section>
  </text>
</law>
