<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcr" order_by="" level="1">Criminal Law</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcr-5-609</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>609</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Except as otherwise provided in this section, a person who violates a provision of &#xA7;&#xA7; 5-602 through 5-606 of this subtitle with respect to any of the following controlled dangerous substances is guilty of a felony and on conviction is subject to imprisonment not exceeding 20 years or a fine not exceeding $20,000 or both:<section prefix="(1)">phencyclidine;</section><section prefix="(2)">1-(1-phenylcyclohexyl) piperidine;</section><section prefix="(3)">1-phenylcyclohexylamine;</section><section prefix="(4)">1-piperidinocyclohexanecarbonitrile;</section><section prefix="(5)">N-ethyl-1-phenylcyclohexylamine;</section><section prefix="(6)">1-(1-phenylcyclohexyl)-pyrrolidine;</section><section prefix="(7)">1-(1-(2-thienyl)-cyclohexyl)-piperidine;</section><section prefix="(8)">lysergic acid diethylamide; or</section><section prefix="(9)">750 grams or more of 3, 4-methylenedioxymethamphetamine (MDMA).</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A person who is convicted under subsection (a) of this section or of conspiracy to commit a crime included in subsection (a) of this section shall be sentenced to imprisonment for not less than 10 years and is subject to a fine not exceeding $100,000 if the person previously has been convicted once:<section prefix="(i)">under subsection (a) of this section or &#xA7; 5-608 of this subtitle;</section><section prefix="(ii)">of conspiracy to commit a crime included in subsection (a) of this section or &#xA7; 5-608 of this subtitle;</section><section prefix="(iii)">of a crime under the laws of another state or the United States that would be a crime included in subsection (a) of this section or &#xA7; 5-608 of this subtitle if committed in this State; or</section><section prefix="(iv)">of any combination of these crimes.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The court may not suspend the mandatory minimum sentence to less than 10 years.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Except as provided in &#xA7; 4-305 of the Correctional Services Article, the person is not eligible for parole during the mandatory minimum sentence.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">A person convicted under subsection (a) of this section is not prohibited from participating in a drug treatment program under &#xA7; 8-507 of the Health - General Article because of the length of the sentence.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A person who is convicted under subsection (a) of this section or of conspiracy to commit a crime included in subsection (a) of this section shall be sentenced to imprisonment for not less than 25 years and is subject to a fine not exceeding $100,000 if the person previously:<section prefix="(i)">has served at least one term of confinement of at least 180 days in a correctional institution as a result of a conviction under subsection (a) of this section, &#xA7; 5-608 of this subtitle, or &#xA7; 5-614 of this subtitle; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">if the convictions do not arise from a single incident, has been convicted twice:<section prefix="1.">under subsection (a) of this section or &#xA7; 5-608 of this subtitle;</section><section prefix="2.">of conspiracy to commit a crime included in subsection (a) of this section or &#xA7; 5-608 of this subtitle;</section><section prefix="3.">of a crime under the laws of another state or the United States that would be a crime included in subsection (a) of this section or &#xA7; 5-608 of this subtitle if committed in this State; or</section><section prefix="4.">of any combination of these crimes.</section></section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The court may not suspend any part of the mandatory minimum sentence of 25 years.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Except as provided in &#xA7; 4-305 of the Correctional Services Article, the person is not eligible for parole during the mandatory minimum sentence.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">A separate occasion is one in which the second or succeeding crime is committed after there has been a charging document filed for the preceding crime.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A person who is convicted under subsection (a) of this section or of conspiracy to commit a crime included in subsection (a) of this section shall be sentenced to imprisonment for not less than 40 years and is subject to a fine not exceeding $100,000 if the person previously has served three separate terms of confinement as a result of three separate convictions:<section prefix="(i)">under subsection (a) of this section or &#xA7; 5-608 of this subtitle;</section><section prefix="(ii)">of conspiracy to commit a crime included in subsection (a) of this section or &#xA7; 5-608 of this subtitle;</section><section prefix="(iii)">of a crime under the laws of another state or the United States that would be a crime included in subsection (a) of this section or &#xA7; 5-608 of this subtitle if committed in this State; or</section><section prefix="(iv)">of any combination of these crimes.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The court may not suspend any part of the mandatory minimum sentence of 40 years.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Except as provided in &#xA7; 4-305 of the Correctional Services Article, the person is not eligible for parole during the mandatory minimum sentence.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
