<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcr" order_by="gcr" level="1">Criminal Law</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcr-3-802</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this section, "stalking" means a malicious course of conduct that includes approaching or pursuin...</catch_line>
  <order_by>802</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, "stalking" means a malicious course of conduct that includes approaching or pursuing another where the person intends to place or knows or reasonably should have known the conduct would place another in reasonable fear:<section prefix="(1)"><section prefix="(i)">of serious bodily injury;</section><section prefix="(ii)">of an assault in any degree;</section><section prefix="(iii)">of rape or sexual offense as defined by &#xA7;&#xA7; 3-303 through 3-308 of this title or attempted rape or sexual offense in any degree;</section><section prefix="(iv)">of false imprisonment; or</section><section prefix="(v)">of death; or</section></section><section prefix="(2)">that a third person likely will suffer any of the acts listed in item (1) of this subsection.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The provisions of this section do not apply to conduct that is:<section prefix="(1)">performed to ensure compliance with a court order;</section><section prefix="(2)">performed to carry out a specific lawful commercial purpose; or</section><section prefix="(3)">authorized, required, or protected by local, State, or federal law.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A person may not engage in stalking.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A person who violates this section is guilty of a misdemeanor and on conviction is subject to imprisonment not exceeding 5 years or a fine not exceeding $5,000 or both.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">A sentence imposed under this section may be separate from and consecutive to or concurrent with a sentence for any other crime based on the acts establishing a violation of this section.</section>
  </text>
</law>
