<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcr" order_by="" level="1">Criminal Law</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcr-10-126</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>126</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">A police officer may issue a citation to a person who the police officer has probable cause to believe has committed a violation under this part.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A violation under this part is a civil offense.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Adjudication of a violation under this part:<section prefix="(i)">is not a criminal conviction for any purpose; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">does not impose any of the civil disabilities that may result from a criminal conviction.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A citation issued under this part shall be signed by the police officer who issues the citation and shall contain:<section prefix="(1)">the name and address of the person charged;</section><section prefix="(2)">the statute allegedly violated;</section><section prefix="(3)">the date, location, and time that the violation occurred;</section><section prefix="(4)">the fine that may be imposed;</section><section prefix="(5)">a notice stating that prepayment of the fine is allowed; and</section><section prefix="(6)">a notice that states that the District Court shall promptly send the person a summons to appear for trial.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The form of the citation shall be uniform throughout the State and shall be prescribed by the District Court.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The Chief Judge of the District Court shall establish a schedule for the prepayment of a fine.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The law enforcement agency of the police officer who issued the citation shall forward to the District Court having venue a copy of the citation and a request for trial.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The District Court shall promptly schedule the case for trial and summon the defendant to appear.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">If a person is found to have committed a violation under this part, the person is subject to a fine not exceeding $25.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">The court costs for a violation under this part are $5.</section>
  </text>
</law>
