<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcr" order_by="" level="1">Criminal Law</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcr-5-1002</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>1002</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, "fund" means the Maryland Drug and Alcohol Grants Program Fund.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">There is a Maryland Drug and Alcohol Grants Program Fund.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The fund is a special, nonlapsing fund that is not subject to &#xA7; 7-302 of the State Finance and Procurement Article.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The fund consists of money appropriated in the State budget to the fund, all earnings from investment of money in the fund, and other money accepted for the benefit of the fund from a governmental or private source.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The State Treasurer shall hold the fund separately.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">The State Comptroller shall account for the fund.</section>
      <section prefix="(6)">The fund shall be invested and reinvested in the same manner as other State funds.</section>
      <section prefix="(7)">The Comptroller shall pay out money from the fund as directed by the Governor's Office of Crime Control and Prevention or as approved in the State budget.</section>
      <section prefix="(8)">The fund is subject to audit by the Office of Legislative Audits under &#xA7; 2-1220 of the State Government Article.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The purpose of the fund is to provide grant money for neighborhood crime prevention programs and drug and alcohol abuse education, prevention, treatment, and law enforcement programs under this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Administrative expenditures under this section may be made only in accordance with the State budget.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Governor's Office of Crime Control and Prevention shall administer the fund in accordance with this section and all other applicable law.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Disbursements from the fund shall supplement and may not substitute for money designated in the State budget for neighborhood crime prevention programs and drug and alcohol abuse education, prevention, treatment, and law enforcement programs.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">If the terms of a grant allow, a recipient may expend grant money beyond the fiscal year in which the grant is received.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This subsection does not apply to a program that has received funds from the Hotspot Communities Initiative administered by the Governor's Office of Crime Control and Prevention.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">To the extent possible, the Governor's Office of Crime Control and Prevention shall allocate at least 10% of the grants provided from the fund to programs that provide services in two or more counties of the State.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
