<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gcr" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="14-101" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcr-14-101</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, "crime of violence" means:<section prefix="(1)">abduction;</section><section prefix="(2)">arson in the first degree;</section><section prefix="(3)">kidnapping;</section><section prefix="(4)">manslaughter, except involuntary manslaughter;</section><section prefix="(5)">mayhem;</section><section prefix="(6)">maiming, as previously proscribed under former Article 27, &#xA7;&#xA7; 385 and 386 of the Code;</section><section prefix="(7)">murder;</section><section prefix="(8)">rape;</section><section prefix="(9)">robbery under &#xA7; 3-402 or &#xA7; 3-403 of this article;</section><section prefix="(10)">carjacking;</section><section prefix="(11)">armed carjacking;</section><section prefix="(12)">sexual offense in the first degree;</section><section prefix="(13)">sexual offense in the second degree;</section><section prefix="(14)">use of a handgun in the commission of a felony or other crime of violence;</section><section prefix="(15)">child abuse in the first degree under &#xA7; 3-601 of this article;</section><section prefix="(16)">sexual abuse of a minor under &#xA7; 3-602 of this article if:<section prefix="(i)">the victim is under the age of 13 years and the offender is an adult at the time of the offense; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">the offense involved:</section></section><section prefix="(17)">an attempt to commit any of the crimes described in items (1) through (16) of this subsection;</section><section prefix="(18)">continuing course of conduct with a child under &#xA7; 3-315 of this article;</section><section prefix="(19)">assault in the first degree;</section><section prefix="(20)">assault with intent to murder;</section><section prefix="(21)">assault with intent to rape;</section><section prefix="(22)">assault with intent to rob;</section><section prefix="(23)">assault with intent to commit a sexual offense in the first degree; and</section><section prefix="(24)">assault with intent to commit a sexual offense in the second degree.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">This section does not apply if a person is sentenced to death.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in subsection (g) of this section, on conviction for a fourth time of a crime of violence, a person who has served three separate terms of confinement in a correctional facility as a result of three separate convictions of any crime of violence shall be sentenced to life imprisonment without the possibility of parole.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Notwithstanding any other law, the provisions of this subsection are mandatory.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in subsection (g) of this section, on conviction for a third time of a crime of violence, a person shall be sentenced to imprisonment for the term allowed by law but not less than 25 years, if the person:<section prefix="(i)">has been convicted of a crime of violence on two prior separate occasions:</section><section prefix="(ii)">has served at least one term of confinement in a correctional facility as a result of a conviction of a crime of violence.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The court may not suspend all or part of the mandatory 25-year sentence required under this subsection.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A person sentenced under this subsection is not eligible for parole except in accordance with the provisions of &#xA7; 4-305 of the Correctional Services Article.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">On conviction for a second time of a crime of violence committed on or after October 1, 1994, a person shall be sentenced to imprisonment for the term allowed by law, but not less than 10 years, if the person:<section prefix="(i)">has been convicted on a prior occasion of a crime of violence, including a conviction for a crime committed before October 1, 1994; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">served a term of confinement in a correctional facility for that conviction.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The court may not suspend all or part of the mandatory 10-year sentence required under this subsection.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">If the State intends to proceed against a person as a subsequent offender under this section, it shall comply with the procedures set forth in the Maryland Rules for the indictment and trial of a subsequent offender.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A person sentenced under this section may petition for and be granted parole if the person:<section prefix="(i)">is at least 65 years old; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">has served at least 15 years of the sentence imposed under this section.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Maryland Parole Commission shall adopt regulations to implement this subsection.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
