<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gcr" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="5-614" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcr-5-614</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Unless authorized by law to possess the substance, a person may not bring into the State:<section prefix="(i)">45 kilograms or more of marijuana;</section><section prefix="(ii)">28 grams or more of cocaine;</section><section prefix="(iii)">any mixture containing 28 grams or more of cocaine;</section><section prefix="(iv)">4 grams or more of morphine or opium or any derivative, salt, isomer, or salt of an isomer of morphine or opium;</section><section prefix="(v)">1,000 dosage units of lysergic acid diethylamide;</section><section prefix="(vi)">any mixture containing the equivalent of 1,000 dosage units of lysergic acid diethylamide;</section><section prefix="(vii)">28 grams or more of phencyclidine in liquid or powder form;</section><section prefix="(viii)">112 grams or more of any mixture containing phencyclidine;</section><section prefix="(ix)">1,000 dosage units or more of methaqualone;</section><section prefix="(x)">28 grams or more of methamphetamine;</section><section prefix="(xi)">any mixture containing 28 grams or more of methamphetamine; or</section><section prefix="(xii)">4 grams or more of fentanyl or a fentanyl analogue.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A person who violates this subsection is guilty of a felony and on conviction is subject to imprisonment not exceeding 25 years or a fine not exceeding $50,000 or both.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Unless authorized by law to possess the marijuana, a person may not bring into the State more than 5 kilograms but less than 45 kilograms of marijuana.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A person who violates this subsection is guilty of a felony and on conviction is subject to imprisonment not exceeding 10 years or a fine not exceeding $10,000 or both.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
