<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcr" order_by="" level="1">Criminal Law</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcr-4-201</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>201</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Antique firearm" means:<section prefix="(1)">a firearm, including a firearm with a matchlock, flintlock, percussion cap, or similar ignition system, manufactured before 1899; or</section><section prefix="(2)">a replica of a firearm described in item (1) of this subsection that:<section prefix="(i)">is not designed or redesigned to use rimfire or conventional centerfire fixed ammunition; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">uses rimfire or conventional centerfire fixed ammunition that is no longer manufactured in the United States and is not readily available in the ordinary channels of commercial trade.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Handgun" means a pistol, revolver, or other firearm capable of being concealed on the person.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Handgun" includes a short-barreled shotgun and a short-barreled rifle.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Handgun" does not include a shotgun, rifle, or antique firearm.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">"Law enforcement official" means:<section prefix="(1)">a full-time member of a police force or other unit of the United States, a state, a county, a municipal corporation, or other political subdivision of a state who is responsible for the prevention and detection of crime and the enforcement of the laws of the United States, a state, a county, a municipal corporation, or other political subdivision of a state;</section><section prefix="(2)">a part-time member of a police force of a county or municipal corporation who is certified by the county or municipal corporation as being trained and qualified in the use of handguns;</section><section prefix="(3)">a fire and explosive investigator of the Prince George's County Fire/EMS Department as defined in &#xA7; 2-208.3 of the Criminal Procedure Article;</section><section prefix="(4)">a Montgomery County fire and explosive investigator as defined in &#xA7; 2-208.1 of the Criminal Procedure Article;</section><section prefix="(5)">an Anne Arundel County or City of Annapolis fire and explosive investigator as defined in &#xA7; 2-208.2 of the Criminal Procedure Article;</section><section prefix="(6)">a Worcester County fire and explosive investigator as defined in &#xA7; 2-208.4 of the Criminal Procedure Article; or</section><section prefix="(7)">a City of Hagerstown fire and explosive investigator as defined in &#xA7; 2-208.5 of the Criminal Procedure Article.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"Rifle" means a weapon that is:<section prefix="(1)">designed or redesigned, made or remade, and intended to be fired from the shoulder; and</section><section prefix="(2)">designed or redesigned, and made or remade to use the energy of the explosive in a fixed metallic cartridge to fire only a single projectile through a rifled bore for each single pull of the trigger.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">"Short-barreled rifle" means:<section prefix="(1)">a rifle that has one or more barrels less than 16 inches long; or</section><section prefix="(2)">a weapon that has an overall length of less than 26 inches and that was made from a rifle, whether by alteration, modification, or otherwise.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(g)">"Short-barreled shotgun" means:<section prefix="(1)">a shotgun that has one or more barrels less than 18 inches long; or</section><section prefix="(2)">a weapon that has an overall length of less than 26 inches long and was made from a shotgun, whether by alteration, modification, or otherwise.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(h)">"Shotgun" means a weapon that is:<section prefix="(1)">designed or redesigned, made or remade, and intended to be fired from the shoulder; and</section><section prefix="(2)">designed or redesigned and made or remade to use the energy of the explosive in a fixed shotgun shell to fire through a smooth bore one or more projectiles for each pull of the trigger.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(i)">"Vehicle" means a motor vehicle as defined in Title 11, Subtitle 1 of the Transportation Article, a train, an aircraft, or a vessel.</section>
  </text>
</law>
