<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gcr" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="5-406" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcr-5-406</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Schedule V consists of each controlled dangerous substance:<section prefix="(1)">listed in this section;</section><section prefix="(2)">added to Schedule V by the Department under &#xA7; 5-202(b) of this title; or</section><section prefix="(3)">designated as a Schedule V controlled dangerous substance by the federal government unless the Department objects under &#xA7; 5-202(f) of this title.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A substance is listed in Schedule V if the substance includes a compound, mixture, or preparation that contains the following quantities of narcotic drugs or their salts:<section prefix="(1)"><section prefix="(i)">not more than 200 milligrams of codeine per 100 milliliters or per 100 grams;</section><section prefix="(ii)">not more than 100 milligrams of dihydrocodeine per 100 milliliters or per 100 grams;</section><section prefix="(iii)">not more than 50 milligrams of ethylmorphine per 100 milliliters or per 100 grams;</section><section prefix="(iv)">not more than 2.5 milligrams of diphenoxylate and not less than 25 micrograms of atropine sulfate per dosage unit; or</section><section prefix="(v)">unless specifically excepted under this subtitle, or unless listed in another schedule, any material, compound, mixture, or preparation containing buprenorphine or its salt; and</section></section><section prefix="(2)">nonnarcotic active medicinal ingredients in sufficient proportion to confer on the compound, mixture, or preparation valuable medicinal qualities other than those possessed by the narcotic drug alone.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Department may not add a substance to Schedule V under &#xA7; 5-202 of this title unless the Department finds:<section prefix="(1)">the substance has a low potential for abuse relative to the substances listed in Schedule IV;</section><section prefix="(2)">the substance has currently accepted medical use in the United States; and</section><section prefix="(3)">abuse of the substance may lead to limited physical dependence or psychological dependence liability relative to the substances listed in Schedule IV.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
