<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcr" order_by="" level="1">Criminal Law</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcr-3-306</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>306</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">A person may not engage in a sexual act with another:<section prefix="(1)">by force, or the threat of force, without the consent of the other;</section><section prefix="(2)">if the victim is a mentally defective individual, a mentally incapacitated individual, or a physically helpless individual, and the person performing the sexual act knows or reasonably should know that the victim is a mentally defective individual, a mentally incapacitated individual, or a physically helpless individual; or</section><section prefix="(3)">if the victim is under the age of 14 years, and the person performing the sexual act is at least 4 years older than the victim.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A person 18 years of age or older may not violate subsection (a)(1) or (2) of this section involving a child under the age of 13 years.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, a person who violates this section is guilty of the felony of sexual offense in the second degree and on conviction is subject to imprisonment not exceeding 20 years.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Subject to subparagraph (iv) of this paragraph, a person 18 years of age or older who violates subsection (b) of this section is guilty of the felony of sexual offense in the second degree and on conviction is subject to imprisonment for not less than 15 years and not exceeding life.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">A court may not suspend any part of the mandatory minimum sentence of 15 years.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">The person is not eligible for parole during the mandatory minimum sentence.</section>
        <section prefix="(iv)">If the State fails to comply with subsection (d) of this section, the mandatory minimum shall not apply.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">If the State intends to seek a sentence of imprisonment for not less than 15 years under subsection (c)(2) of this section, the State shall notify the person in writing of the State's intention at least 30 days before trial.</section>
  </text>
</law>
