<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gcr" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="12-301.1" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcr-12-301.1</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this subtitle, "Commission" means the State Lottery and Gaming Control Commission.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in paragraphs (2) and (3) of this subsection and consistent with the provisions of this title and Title 13 of this article, the Commission shall certify and regulate the operation, ownership, and manufacture of an electronic gaming device authorized under this title.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">This section does not apply to:<section prefix="(i)">the ownership or operation of slot machines that are subject to regulation by the Comptroller under &#xA7; 12-304 of this title; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">paper tip jar gaming where authorized.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">This paragraph applies only in Baltimore City and Baltimore County.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">If a local law enforcement agency refuses to enforce a provision regarding the legal operation of amusement games, the Commission shall refer the matter to the appropriate office of the State's Attorney.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Commission shall adopt regulations that:<section prefix="(1)">define lawful and unlawful electronic and mechanical equipment used in connection with gaming devices that are consistent with this title;</section><section prefix="(2)">approve and license electronic gaming devices authorized under State law;</section><section prefix="(3)">approve and license owners, operators, and manufacturers of electronic gaming devices authorized under State law;</section><section prefix="(4)">establish procedures for the license application and renewal processes required under this section; and</section><section prefix="(5)">establish license fees that are sufficient to cover the direct and indirect costs of licensure required under this section.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Commission may determine:<section prefix="(1)">that a county's licensing and regulatory process for electronic gaming devices is equivalent to the State licensing and regulatory process required under this section; and</section><section prefix="(2)">that a county license for owning, operating, or manufacturing an electronic gaming device in that county is equivalent to a State license.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">An electronic gaming device that is not licensed or otherwise operated in compliance with the provisions of this section as of January 1, 2013, is an illegal gaming device that may not legally operate in the State.</section>
  </text>
</law>
