<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcr" order_by="gcr" level="1">Criminal Law</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcr-8-601</section_number>
  <catch_line>A person, with intent to defraud another, may not counterfeit, cause to be counterfeited, or willing...</catch_line>
  <order_by>601</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">A person, with intent to defraud another, may not counterfeit, cause to be counterfeited, or willingly aid or assist in counterfeiting any:<section prefix="(1)">bond;</section><section prefix="(2)">check;</section><section prefix="(3)">deed;</section><section prefix="(4)">draft;</section><section prefix="(5)">endorsement or assignment of a bond, draft, check, or promissory note;</section><section prefix="(6)">entry in an account book or ledger;</section><section prefix="(7)">letter of credit;</section><section prefix="(8)">negotiable instrument;</section><section prefix="(9)">power of attorney;</section><section prefix="(10)">promissory note;</section><section prefix="(11)">release or discharge for money or property;</section><section prefix="(12)">title to a motor vehicle;</section><section prefix="(13)">waiver or release of mechanics' lien; or</section><section prefix="(14)">will or codicil.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A person may not knowingly, willfully, and with fraudulent intent possess a counterfeit of any of the items listed in subsection (a) of this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A person who violates subsection (a) of this section is guilty of a felony and on conviction is subject to imprisonment not exceeding 10 years or a fine not exceeding $1,000 or both.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A person who violates subsection (b) of this section is guilty of a misdemeanor and on conviction is subject to imprisonment not exceeding 3 years or a fine not exceeding $1,000 or both.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the prosecution of an alleged violation of this section or for an alleged violation of a crime based on an act that establishes a violation of this section may be commenced in any county in which:<section prefix="(1)">an element of the crime occurred;</section><section prefix="(2)">the deed or other alleged counterfeit instrument is recorded in the county land records, filed with the clerk of the circuit court, or filed with the register of wills;</section><section prefix="(3)">the victim resides; or</section><section prefix="(4)">if the victim is not an individual, the victim conducts business.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
