<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcr" order_by="gcr" level="1">Criminal Law</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcr-11-208</section_number>
  <catch_line>A person may not knowingly possess and intentionally retain a film, videotape, photograph, or other ...</catch_line>
  <order_by>208</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">A person may not knowingly possess and intentionally retain a film, videotape, photograph, or other visual representation showing an actual child under the age of 16 years:<section prefix="(1)">engaged as a subject of sadomasochistic abuse;</section><section prefix="(2)">engaged in sexual conduct; or</section><section prefix="(3)">in a state of sexual excitement.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, a person who violates this section is guilty of a misdemeanor and on conviction is subject to imprisonment not exceeding 5 years or a fine not exceeding $2,500 or both.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A person who violates this section, having previously been convicted under this section, is guilty of a felony and on conviction is subject to imprisonment not exceeding 10 years or a fine not exceeding $10,000 or both.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Nothing in this section may be construed to prohibit a parent from possessing visual representations of the parent's own child in the nude unless the visual representations show the child engaged:<section prefix="(1)">as a subject of sadomasochistic abuse; or</section><section prefix="(2)">in sexual conduct and in a state of sexual excitement.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">It is an affirmative defense to a charge of violating this section that the person promptly and in good faith:<section prefix="(1)">took reasonable steps to destroy each visual representation; or</section><section prefix="(2)">reported the matter to a law enforcement agency.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
