<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcr" order_by="gcr" level="1">Criminal Law</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcr-3-805</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this section, "electronic communication" means the transmission of information, data, or a commun...</catch_line>
  <order_by>805</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, "electronic communication" means the transmission of information, data, or a communication by the use of a computer or any other electronic means that is sent to a person and that is received by the person.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A person may not maliciously engage in a course of conduct, through the use of electronic communication, that alarms or seriously annoys another:<section prefix="(1)">with the intent to harass, alarm, or annoy the other;</section><section prefix="(2)">after receiving a reasonable warning or request to stop by or on behalf of the other; and</section><section prefix="(3)">without a legal purpose.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">It is not a violation of this section for any of the following persons to provide information, facilities, or technical assistance to another who is authorized by federal or State law to intercept or provide electronic communication or to conduct surveillance of electronic communication, if a court order directs the person to provide the information, facilities, or technical assistance:<section prefix="(1)">a provider of electronic communication;</section><section prefix="(2)">an officer, employee, agent, landlord, or custodian of a provider of electronic communication; or</section><section prefix="(3)">a person specified in a court order directing the provision of information, facilities, or technical assistance to another who is authorized by federal or State law to intercept or provide electronic communication or to conduct surveillance of electronic communication.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">This section does not apply to a peaceable activity intended to express a political view or provide information to others.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">A person who violates this section is guilty of a misdemeanor and on conviction is subject to imprisonment not exceeding 1 year or a fine not exceeding $500 or both.</section>
  </text>
</law>
