<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcr" order_by="" level="1">Criminal Law</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcr-8-204</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>204</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A person may not:<section prefix="(i)">take a credit card from another, or from the possession, custody, or control of another without the consent of the cardholder; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">with knowledge that a credit card has been taken under the circumstances described in item (i) of this paragraph, receive the credit card with the intent to use it or sell or transfer it to another who is not the issuer or the cardholder.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A person who violates this subsection is guilty of credit card theft.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A person may not receive a credit card that the person knows was lost, mislaid, or delivered under a mistake as to the identity or address of the cardholder and retain possession of the credit card with the intent to use, sell, or transfer it to another who is not the issuer or the cardholder.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A person who violates this subsection is guilty of credit card theft.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A person may not:<section prefix="(1)">sell a credit card unless the person is the issuer; or</section><section prefix="(2)">buy a credit card from a person other than the issuer.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A person other than the issuer may not receive a credit card that the person knows was taken or retained under circumstances that constitute:<section prefix="(1)">credit card theft;</section><section prefix="(2)">a violation of &#xA7; 8-203 of this subtitle; or</section><section prefix="(3)">a violation of subsection (c) of this section.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">A person who violates this section is guilty of a misdemeanor and on conviction is subject to imprisonment not exceeding 18 months or a fine not exceeding $500 or both.</section>
  </text>
</law>
