<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gcr" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="13-2419" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcr-13-2419</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The county commissioners shall adopt regulations to carry out Part III of this subtitle.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The agency may recommend to the county commissioners regulations or guidelines concerning the administration of Part III of this subtitle.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The county commissioners shall make available for public inspection:<section prefix="(1)">audit reports completed under &#xA7; 13-2432(a) of this subtitle; and</section><section prefix="(2)">in accordance with regulations of the county commissioners, tip jar reports submitted under &#xA7; 13-2424 of this subtitle.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">By regulation, the county commissioners may require:<section prefix="(1)">an applicant for a tip jar license or wholesaler's license or an individual involved in the operation of a tip jar to be fingerprinted for purposes of a criminal history records check; and</section><section prefix="(2)">the agency to obtain a criminal history records check in accordance with subsection (d) of this section.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If the county commissioners direct the agency to obtain criminal history records checks, the agency shall apply to the Criminal Justice Information System Central Repository of the Department of Public Safety and Correctional Services for a State criminal history records check for each:<section prefix="(i)">applicant for a tip jar license or wholesaler's license; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">individual involved in the operation of a tip jar.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">As part of the application for a criminal history records check, the agency shall submit to the Criminal Justice Information System Central Repository:<section prefix="(i)">a complete set of the applicant's or individual's legible fingerprints on forms approved by the director of the Criminal Justice Information System Central Repository; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">the fee authorized under &#xA7; 10-221(b)(7) of the Criminal Procedure Article.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Criminal Justice Information System Central Repository shall provide the requested information in accordance with Title 10, Subtitle 2 of the Criminal Procedure Article.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
