<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcr" order_by="gcr" level="1">Criminal Law</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcr-5-601</section_number>
  <catch_line>Except as otherwise provided in this title, a person may not:...</catch_line>
  <order_by>601</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Except as otherwise provided in this title, a person may not:<section prefix="(1)">possess or administer to another a controlled dangerous substance, unless obtained directly or by prescription or order from an authorized provider acting in the course of professional practice; or</section><section prefix="(2)">obtain or attempt to obtain a controlled dangerous substance, or procure or attempt to procure the administration of a controlled dangerous substance by:<section prefix="(i)">fraud, deceit, misrepresentation, or subterfuge;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the counterfeiting or alteration of a prescription or a written order;</section><section prefix="(iii)">the concealment of a material fact;</section><section prefix="(iv)">the use of a false name or address;</section><section prefix="(v)">falsely assuming the title of or representing to be a manufacturer, distributor, or authorized provider; or</section><section prefix="(vi)">making, issuing, or presenting a false or counterfeit prescription or written order.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Information that is communicated to a physician in an effort to obtain a controlled dangerous substance in violation of this section is not a privileged communication.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in paragraphs (2) and (3) of this subsection, a person who violates this section is guilty of a misdemeanor and on conviction is subject to imprisonment not exceeding 4 years or a fine not exceeding $25,000 or both.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">A person whose violation of this section involves the use or possession of marijuana is subject to imprisonment not exceeding 1 year or a fine not exceeding $1,000 or both.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">
          <section prefix="1.">A person convicted of the use or possession of less than 10 grams of marijuana is subject to imprisonment not exceeding 90 days or a fine not exceeding $500 or both.</section>
          <section prefix="2.">Unless specifically charged by the State, the use or possession of less than 10 grams of marijuana under subsubparagraph 1 of this subparagraph may not be considered a lesser included crime of any other crime.</section>
          <section prefix="3.">If a person is convicted under this subparagraph, the court shall stay any sentence imposed that includes an unserved, nonsuspended period of imprisonment without requiring an appeal bond:</section>
        </section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">
          <section prefix="1.">In this paragraph the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
          <section prefix="2.">"Bona fide physician-patient relationship" means a relationship in which the physician has ongoing responsibility for the assessment, care, and treatment of a patient's medical condition.</section>
          <section prefix="3.">"Debilitating medical condition" means a chronic or debilitating disease or medical condition or the treatment of a chronic or debilitating disease or medical condition that produces one or more of the following, as documented by a physician with whom the patient has a bona fide physician-patient relationship:</section>
        </section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">
          <section prefix="1.">In a prosecution for the use or possession of marijuana, the defendant may introduce and the court shall consider as a mitigating factor any evidence of medical necessity.</section>
          <section prefix="2.">Notwithstanding paragraph (2) of this subsection, if the court finds that the person used or possessed marijuana because of medical necessity, on conviction of a violation of this section, the maximum penalty that the court may impose on the person is a fine not exceeding $100.</section>
        </section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">
          <section prefix="1.">In a prosecution for the use or possession of marijuana under this section, it is an affirmative defense that the defendant used or possessed marijuana because:</section>
          <section prefix="2.">The affirmative defense may not be used if the defendant was:</section>
        </section>
      </section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
