<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcr" order_by="" level="1">Criminal Law</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcr-5-303</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>303</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Unless the Department determines that the issuance of the registration is inconsistent with the public interest, the Department shall register an applicant to manufacture or distribute controlled dangerous substances included in Schedule I through Schedule V.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">To determine the public interest, the Department shall consider:<section prefix="(1)">the maintenance of effective controls against diversion of particular controlled dangerous substances and any Schedule I or Schedule II substance compounded from a controlled dangerous substance into other than legitimate medical, scientific, or industrial channels;</section><section prefix="(2)">compliance with applicable federal, State, and local law;</section><section prefix="(3)">any convictions of the applicant under federal, State, and local laws relating to the manufacture, distribution, or dispensing of controlled dangerous substances;</section><section prefix="(4)">the applicant's experience in the manufacture and distribution of controlled dangerous substances and the effectiveness of the applicant's controls against diversion; and</section><section prefix="(5)">any other factor that is relevant to and consistent with public health and safety.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A registrant may manufacture or distribute only a controlled dangerous substance that is specified in the registration.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A manufacturer or distributor who complies with federal law on registration, other than fees, is deemed to have complied with this section.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A registrant may distribute controlled dangerous substances in Schedule I and Schedule II only in accordance with an order form.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A registrant who complies with federal law on order forms for Schedule I and Schedule II is deemed to have complied with this subsection.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
