<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcr" order_by="gcr" level="1">Criminal Law</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcr-3-503</section_number>
  <catch_line>A person may not, without color of right:...</catch_line>
  <order_by>503</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A person may not, without color of right:<section prefix="(i)">forcibly abduct, take, or carry away a child under the age of 12 years from:<section prefix="1.">the home or usual place of abode of the child; or</section><section prefix="2.">the custody and control of the child's parent or legal guardian;</section></section><section prefix="(ii)">without the consent of the child's parent or legal guardian, persuade or entice a child under the age of 12 years from:<section prefix="1.">the child's home or usual place of abode; or</section><section prefix="2.">the custody and control of the child's parent or legal guardian; or</section></section><section prefix="(iii)">with the intent of depriving the child's parent or legal guardian, or any person lawfully possessing the child, of the custody, care, and control of the child, knowingly secrete or harbor a child under the age of 12 years.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">In addition to the prohibitions provided under paragraph (1) of this subsection, a person may not, by force or fraud, kidnap, steal, take, or carry away a child under the age of 16 years.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A person who violates subsection (a)(1) of this section is guilty of a felony and on conviction is subject to imprisonment not exceeding 20 years.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Except as provided under subparagraph (ii) of this paragraph, a person, other than a parent of the child, who violates subsection (a)(2) of this section is guilty of a felony and on conviction is subject to imprisonment not exceeding 30 years.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">
          <section prefix="1.">If a person convicted under subsection (a)(2) of this section is convicted in the same proceeding of rape or a first degree sexual offense under Subtitle 3 of this title, the person is guilty of a felony and on conviction is subject to imprisonment not exceeding life without the possibility of parole.</section>
          <section prefix="2.">If the State intends to seek a sentence of imprisonment for life without the possibility of parole under subsubparagraph 1 of this subparagraph, the State shall notify the person in writing of the State's intent at least 30 days before trial.</section>
        </section>
      </section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
