<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gcr" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="13-907" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcr-13-907</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Before an organization may conduct bingo under this subtitle, the organization shall obtain a permit from the county commissioners.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this subsection, "qualified organization" means a bona fide:<section prefix="(i)">religious organization;</section><section prefix="(ii)">fraternal organization;</section><section prefix="(iii)">patriotic organization;</section><section prefix="(iv)">educational organization;</section><section prefix="(v)">charitable organization;</section><section prefix="(vi)">volunteer fire company; or</section><section prefix="(vii)">senior center site council.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A qualified organization may conduct bingo in the county to benefit charity or to further the purpose of the qualified organization.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A senior center site council may obtain a permit to conduct bingo in a senior center 5 days per week, excluding Sunday.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A senior center site council may not:<section prefix="(i)">award a prize of money to a winner exceeding $50 in each session; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">charge more than 5 cents for each bingo card.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">All money that remains after prizes are awarded shall be distributed to the senior center site council.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">An applicant for a permit shall pay the fee that the county commissioners set.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The county commissioners shall set the permit fee at a level sufficient to cover the costs of issuing the permit.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Only the holder of a permit issued under this section may conduct bingo authorized by the permit.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The holder of a permit issued under this section may not transfer or assign the right to conduct bingo to another person.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
