<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcr" order_by="gcr" level="1">Criminal Law</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcr-13-2503</section_number>
  <catch_line>The sheriff may issue a license to an organization listed in subsection (b) of this section to condu...</catch_line>
  <order_by>2503</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The sheriff may issue a license to an organization listed in subsection (b) of this section to conduct a game that uses any of the following devices to award prizes of merchandise or money:<section prefix="(1)">a paddle wheel;</section><section prefix="(2)">a wheel of fortune;</section><section prefix="(3)">a chance book;</section><section prefix="(4)">bingo;</section><section prefix="(5)">a raffle; or</section><section prefix="(6)">any other gaming device.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">To qualify for a license under this subtitle, an organization shall be:<section prefix="(1)">a bona fide religious organization that has conducted religious services at a fixed location in the county for at least 5 years before the organization applies for a license;</section><section prefix="(2)">a tax-supported volunteer fire company or an auxiliary unit whose members are directly associated with the fire company;</section><section prefix="(3)">an organization that has been located in the county for at least 5 years before it applies for a license and is:<section prefix="(i)">a nationally chartered veterans' organization or an auxiliary unit whose members are directly associated with the veterans' organization;</section><section prefix="(ii)">a nonprofit organization that is exempt from taxation under &#xA7; 501(c)(3) or (4) of the Internal Revenue Code;</section><section prefix="(iii)">a nonprofit fraternal organization that is exempt from taxation under &#xA7; 501(c)(10) of the Internal Revenue Code; or</section><section prefix="(iv)">a nonprofit organization that:<section prefix="1.">intends to use the gaming license to raise money for an exclusively charitable, athletic, or educational purpose that meets the conditions of subsection (c) of this section; and</section><section prefix="2.">states the charitable, athletic, or educational purpose in the application to the sheriff.</section></section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">For the purposes of subsection (b)(3)(iv) of this section, a purpose is considered a charitable, athletic, or educational purpose if the purpose:<section prefix="(1)">meets the requirements for a charitable contribution under &#xA7; 170(c) of the Internal Revenue Code; and</section><section prefix="(2)">does not benefit a:<section prefix="(i)">law enforcement unit;</section><section prefix="(ii)">fraternal organization for a law enforcement unit;</section><section prefix="(iii)">political club;</section><section prefix="(iv)">political committee;</section><section prefix="(v)">political party; or</section><section prefix="(vi)">unit of State government or a political subdivision of the State other than:<section prefix="1.">an ambulance company;</section><section prefix="2.">a fire fighting company;</section><section prefix="3.">a rescue company;</section><section prefix="4.">a primary school;</section><section prefix="5.">a secondary school; or</section><section prefix="6.">an institution of higher education.</section></section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">An applicant for a license shall submit an application to the sheriff.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The application shall contain:<section prefix="(i)">a copy of the tax-exempt verification of the organization;</section><section prefix="(ii)">a copy of the applicant's charter, if applicable; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">a certification by a principal officer of the applicant stating:<section prefix="1.">the dates for which the license is sought;</section><section prefix="2.">the place at which the game will be conducted;</section><section prefix="3.">the type of game for which the license is sought;</section><section prefix="4.">that only the regular members of the applicant will conduct the games and operate the gaming device for which the license is sought;</section><section prefix="5.">that the applicant will not use the assistance of gaming professionals in conducting games or operating gaming devices;</section><section prefix="6.">that persons conducting the games and operating the gaming devices or assisting in conducting the games and operating the gaming devices will not receive compensation or reward; and</section><section prefix="7.">that all proceeds obtained under the license will be used to further the purposes of the organization.</section></section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The sheriff shall retain the copies of the applicant's verification of tax exemption and charter.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The sheriff may issue a license:<section prefix="(i)">for one or more specific dates; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">for a period not exceeding 1 year.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The licensing year shall run from July 1 through the following June 30.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The license shall state:<section prefix="(i)">the dates that the game will be conducted;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the place that the game will be conducted; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">the type of game authorized.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided under paragraph (2) of this subsection, a licensee may not conduct a game on Sunday.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">A licensee may operate a raffle on Sunday.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">A raffle is considered to be operated on the day that the licensee selects the raffle winner.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">The sheriff shall license a 50/50 game operated for a period of more than 1 day as a raffle.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A licensee may not allow a child who is under the age of 16 years to:<section prefix="(i)">operate a game or gaming device for which a license is issued under this subtitle;</section><section prefix="(ii)">conduct a game in which a gaming device is operated; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">play or participate in a game in which a gaming device is operated.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The licensee may not pay a fee for the rental of the premises on which a game is conducted to:<section prefix="(i)">itself;</section><section prefix="(ii)">a trustee of the licensee;</section><section prefix="(iii)">a committee of the licensee; or</section><section prefix="(iv)">an organization with the same members or substantially the same members as the licensee.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">The sheriff shall charge each applicant:<section prefix="(1)">a license fee of $1 for each day for which a license is issued; and</section><section prefix="(2)">the following additional amounts:<section prefix="(i)">except as provided in items (ii) through (v) of this item, $1 for each gaming device to be operated each day;</section><section prefix="(ii)">$1 for each day that a pull tab or instant bingo device is to be sold;</section><section prefix="(iii)">$1 for each day that a bingo event is to be conducted;</section><section prefix="(iv)">$1 for each day that a bingo special event is to be conducted; and</section><section prefix="(v)">$1 for each raffle to be conducted.</section></section></section>
  </text>
</law>
