<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcr" order_by="" level="1">Criminal Law</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcr-4-104</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>104</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Ammunition" means a cartridge, shell, or other device containing explosive or incendiary material designed and intended for use in a firearm.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Child" means an individual under the age of 16 years.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">
        <section prefix="(i)">"Firearm" means a handgun, rifle, shotgun, short-barreled rifle, or short-barreled shotgun, as those terms are defined in &#xA7; 4-201 of this title, or any other firearm.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">"Firearm" does not include an antique firearm as defined in &#xA7; 4-201 of this title.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">This section does not apply if:<section prefix="(1)">the child's access to a firearm is supervised by an individual at least 18 years old;</section><section prefix="(2)">the child's access to a firearm was obtained as a result of an unlawful entry;</section><section prefix="(3)">the firearm is in the possession or control of a law enforcement officer while the officer is engaged in official duties; or</section><section prefix="(4)">the child has a certificate of firearm and hunter safety issued under &#xA7; 10-301.1 of the Natural Resources Article.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A person may not store or leave a loaded firearm in a location where the person knew or should have known that an unsupervised child would gain access to the firearm.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A person who violates this section is guilty of a misdemeanor and on conviction is subject to a fine not exceeding $1,000.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A violation of this section may not:<section prefix="(i)">be considered evidence of negligence;</section><section prefix="(ii)">be considered evidence of contributory negligence;</section><section prefix="(iii)">limit liability of a party or an insurer; or</section><section prefix="(iv)">diminish recovery for damages arising out of the ownership, maintenance, or operation of a firearm or ammunition.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A party, witness, or lawyer may not refer to a violation of this section during a trial of a civil action that involves property damage, personal injury, or death.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
