<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcr" order_by="" level="1">Criminal Law</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcr-10-119</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>119</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A person who violates &#xA7;&#xA7; 10-113 through 10-115 or &#xA7; 10-118 of this part shall be issued a citation under this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A minor who violates &#xA7; 10-116 or &#xA7; 10-117(a) of this part shall be issued a citation under this section.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A citation for a violation of &#xA7;&#xA7; 10-113 through 10-115 or a violation of &#xA7; 10-118 of this part may be issued by:<section prefix="(i)">a police officer authorized to make arrests;</section><section prefix="(ii)">in State forestry reservations, State parks, historic monuments, and recreation areas, a forest or park warden under &#xA7; 5-206(a) or (b) of the Natural Resources Article; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">subject to paragraphs (2) and (3) of this subsection, in Anne Arundel County, Frederick County, Harford County, Montgomery County, Prince George's County, and Talbot County, and only in the inspector's jurisdiction, an alcoholic beverages inspector who investigates license violations under Article 2B of the Code.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">In Anne Arundel County, Frederick County, Harford County, Montgomery County, Prince George's County, and Talbot County, the inspector shall successfully complete an appropriate program of training in the proper use of arrest authority and pertinent police procedures as required by the board of license commissioners.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">In Anne Arundel County, Harford County, Montgomery County, Prince George's County, and Talbot County, the inspector may not carry a firearm in the performance of the inspector's duties.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A person authorized under this section to issue a citation shall issue it if the person has probable cause to believe that the person charged is committing or has committed a Code violation.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Subject to paragraph (2) of this subsection, the form of citation issued to an adult shall be as prescribed by the District Court and shall be uniform throughout the State.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The citation issued to an adult shall contain:<section prefix="(i)">the name and address of the person charged;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the statute allegedly violated;</section><section prefix="(iii)">the location, date, and time that the violation occurred;</section><section prefix="(iv)">the fine that may be imposed;</section><section prefix="(v)">a notice stating that prepayment of the fine is not allowed;</section><section prefix="(vi)">a notice that the District Court shall promptly send the person charged a summons to appear for trial;</section><section prefix="(vii)">the signature of the person issuing the citation; and</section><section prefix="(viii)">a space for the person charged to sign the citation.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The form of citation issued to a minor shall:<section prefix="(i)">be prescribed by the State Court Administrator;</section><section prefix="(ii)">be uniform throughout the State; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">contain the information listed in &#xA7; 3-8A-33(b) of the Courts Article.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except for a citation subject to the jurisdiction of a circuit court, the issuing jurisdiction shall forward a copy of the citation and a request for trial to the District Court in the district having venue.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The District Court shall promptly schedule the case for trial and summon the defendant to appear.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">Willful failure of the defendant to respond to the summons is contempt of court.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">For purposes of this section, a violation of &#xA7;&#xA7; 10-113 through 10-115 or a violation of &#xA7; 10-118 of this part is a Code violation and is a civil offense.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A person charged who is under the age of 18 years shall be subject to the procedures and dispositions provided in Title 3, Subtitle 8A of the Courts Article.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A person charged who is at least 18 years old shall be subject to the provisions of this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">Adjudication of a Code violation is not a criminal conviction for any purpose, and it does not impose any of the civil disabilities ordinarily imposed by a criminal conviction.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">In any proceeding for a Code violation:<section prefix="(1)">the State has the burden to prove the guilt of the defendant to the same extent as is required by law in the trial of criminal causes, and in any such proceeding, the court shall apply the evidentiary standards as prescribed by law or rule for the trial of criminal causes;</section><section prefix="(2)">the court shall ensure that the defendant has received a copy of the charges against the defendant and that the defendant understands those charges;</section><section prefix="(3)">the defendant is entitled to cross-examine all witnesses who appear against the defendant, to produce evidence or witnesses on behalf of the defendant, or to testify on the defendant's own behalf, if the defendant chooses to do so;</section><section prefix="(4)">the defendant is entitled to be represented by counsel of the defendant's choice and at the expense of the defendant; and</section><section prefix="(5)">the defendant may enter a plea of guilty or not guilty, and the verdict of the court in the case shall be:<section prefix="(i)">guilty of a Code violation;</section><section prefix="(ii)">not guilty of a Code violation; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">before rendering judgment, the court may place the defendant on probation in the same manner and to the same extent as is allowed by law in the trial of a criminal case.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(h)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, if the District Court finds that a person has committed a Code violation, the court shall require the person to pay:<section prefix="(i)">a fine not exceeding $500; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">if the violation is a subsequent violation, a fine not exceeding $1,000.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If the District Court finds that a person has committed a Code violation under &#xA7; 10-117 of this subtitle, the court shall require the person to pay:<section prefix="(i)">a fine not exceeding $2,500; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">if the violation is a subsequent violation, a fine not exceeding $5,000.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Chief Judge of the District Court may not establish a schedule for the prepayment of fines for a Code violation under this part.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(i)">When a defendant has been found guilty of a Code violation and a fine has been imposed by the court:<section prefix="(1)">the court may direct that the payment of the fine be suspended or deferred under conditions that the court may establish; and</section><section prefix="(2)">if the defendant willfully fails to pay the fine imposed by the court, that willful failure may be treated as a criminal contempt of court, for which the defendant may be punished by the court as provided by law.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(j)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The defendant is liable for the costs of the proceedings in the District Court and for payment to the Criminal Injuries Compensation Fund.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The court costs in a Code violation case in which costs are imposed are $5.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(k)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this subsection, "driver's license" means a license or permit to drive a motor vehicle that is issued under the laws of this State or any other jurisdiction.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">This subsection applies only to:<section prefix="(i)">a person who is at least 18 but under 21 years of age; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">a minor if the minor is subject to the jurisdiction of the court.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">If a person is found guilty of a Code violation under &#xA7; 10-113 of this part that involved the use of a driver's license or a document purporting to be a driver's license, the court shall notify the Motor Vehicle Administration of the violation.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The Chief Judge of the District Court, in conjunction with the Motor Vehicle Administrator, shall establish uniform procedures for reporting Code violations described in this subsection.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(l)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A defendant who has been found guilty of a Code violation has the right to appeal or to file a motion for a new trial or a motion for a revision of a judgment provided by law in the trial of a criminal case.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A motion shall be made in the same manner as provided in the trial of criminal cases, and the court, in ruling on the motion has the same authority provided in the trial of criminal cases.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(m)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The State's Attorney for any county may prosecute a Code violation in the same manner as prosecution of a violation of the criminal laws of this State.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">In a Code violation case the State's Attorney may:<section prefix="(i)">enter a nolle prosequi in or place the case on the stet docket; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">exercise authority in the same manner as prescribed by law for violation of the criminal laws of this State.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
