<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcr" order_by="gcr" level="1">Criminal Law</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcr-4-106</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this section and &#xA7; 4-107 of this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated....</catch_line>
  <order_by>106</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section and &#xA7; 4-107 of this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Ammunition" means a cartridge, shell, or other device containing explosive or incendiary material designed and intended for use in a firearm.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Bulletproof body armor" means a material or object that is designed to cover or be worn on any part of the body to prevent, deflect, or slow down the penetration of ammunition.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">"Crime of violence" has the meaning stated in &#xA7; 14-101 of this article.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">"Drug trafficking crime" has the meaning stated in &#xA7; 5-621 of this article.</section>
      <section prefix="(6)">"Firearm" includes:<section prefix="(i)">a handgun, antique firearm, rifle, shotgun, short-barreled shotgun, or short-barreled rifle as those terms are defined in &#xA7; 4-201 of this title;</section><section prefix="(ii)">an assault pistol as defined in &#xA7; 4-301 of this title;</section><section prefix="(iii)">a machine gun as defined in &#xA7; 4-401 of this title; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">a regulated firearm as defined in &#xA7; 5-101 of the Public Safety Article.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(7)">"Secretary" means the Secretary of State Police or the Secretary's designee.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A person may not wear bulletproof body armor in the commission of a crime of violence.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A person may not wear or possess bulletproof body armor during and in relation to a drug trafficking crime.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A person who violates this section is guilty of a misdemeanor and on conviction is subject to imprisonment not exceeding 5 years or a fine not exceeding $5,000 or both.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">A sentence imposed under this section may be separate from a sentence for any crime of violence or drug trafficking crime establishing the violation of this section.</section>
  </text>
</law>
