<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gcr" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="13-1810" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcr-13-1810</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">A qualified organization may conduct a raffle in the county to benefit charity or to further the purpose of the qualified organization.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A raffle shall be conducted by a qualified organization and not by a person who:<section prefix="(1)">retains a portion of the proceeds from the raffle; or</section><section prefix="(2)">is compensated by the qualified organization for which the raffle is held.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A person may not receive a private profit from the proceeds of a raffle.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A qualified organization that conducts a raffle shall:<section prefix="(1)">keep accurate records of all transactions that occur on behalf of the raffle;</section><section prefix="(2)">keep the records for 2 years after the raffle; and</section><section prefix="(3)">on request, make the records available for examination by:<section prefix="(i)">the State's Attorney for the county;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the county sheriff;</section><section prefix="(iii)">the county Department of Health and Human Services;</section><section prefix="(iv)">the county attorney;</section><section prefix="(v)">the Department of State Police; or</section><section prefix="(vi)">a designated officer or agent of any of those units.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">A person operating a raffle shall be a resident of the county and a member of the qualified organization.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">Prizes of money or merchandise may be awarded in a raffle conducted under this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">For a raffle of real property, the requirements of this section are in addition to the requirements of &#xA7; 12-106(a) of this article.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, a qualified organization may not conduct more than 12 raffles each year.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">There is no limit to the number of 50/50 raffles that a qualified organization may conduct if the prize for each 50/50 raffle does not exceed $300.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
