<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gcr" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="7-104" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcr-7-104</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">A person may not willfully or knowingly obtain or exert unauthorized control over property, if the person:<section prefix="(1)">intends to deprive the owner of the property;</section><section prefix="(2)">willfully or knowingly uses, conceals, or abandons the property in a manner that deprives the owner of the property; or</section><section prefix="(3)">uses, conceals, or abandons the property knowing the use, concealment, or abandonment probably will deprive the owner of the property.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A person may not obtain control over property by willfully or knowingly using deception, if the person:<section prefix="(1)">intends to deprive the owner of the property;</section><section prefix="(2)">willfully or knowingly uses, conceals, or abandons the property in a manner that deprives the owner of the property; or</section><section prefix="(3)">uses, conceals, or abandons the property knowing the use, concealment, or abandonment probably will deprive the owner of the property.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A person may not possess stolen personal property knowing that it has been stolen, or believing that it probably has been stolen, if the person:<section prefix="(i)">intends to deprive the owner of the property;</section><section prefix="(ii)">willfully or knowingly uses, conceals, or abandons the property in a manner that deprives the owner of the property; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">uses, conceals, or abandons the property knowing that the use, concealment, or abandonment probably will deprive the owner of the property.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">In the case of a person in the business of buying or selling goods, the knowledge required under this subsection may be inferred if:<section prefix="(i)">the person possesses or exerts control over property stolen from more than one person on separate occasions;</section><section prefix="(ii)">during the year preceding the criminal possession charged, the person has acquired stolen property in a separate transaction; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">being in the business of buying or selling property of the sort possessed, the person acquired it for a consideration that the person knew was far below a reasonable value.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">In a prosecution for theft by possession of stolen property under this subsection, it is not a defense that:<section prefix="(i)">the person who stole the property has not been convicted, apprehended, or identified;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the defendant stole or participated in the stealing of the property;</section><section prefix="(iii)">the property was provided by law enforcement as part of an investigation, if the property was described to the defendant as being obtained through the commission of theft; or</section><section prefix="(iv)">the stealing of the property did not occur in the State.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">Unless the person who criminally possesses stolen property participated in the stealing, the person who criminally possesses stolen property and a person who has stolen the property are not accomplices in theft for the purpose of any rule of evidence requiring corroboration of the testimony of an accomplice.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A person may not obtain control over property knowing that the property was lost, mislaid, or was delivered under a mistake as to the identity of the recipient or nature or amount of the property, if the person:<section prefix="(1)">knows or learns the identity of the owner or knows, is aware of, or learns of a reasonable method of identifying the owner;</section><section prefix="(2)">fails to take reasonable measures to restore the property to the owner; and</section><section prefix="(3)">intends to deprive the owner permanently of the use or benefit of the property when the person obtains the property or at a later time.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">A person may not obtain the services of another that are available only for compensation:<section prefix="(1)">by deception; or</section><section prefix="(2)">with knowledge that the services are provided without the consent of the person providing them.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">Under this section, an offender's intention or knowledge that a promise would not be performed may not be established by or inferred solely from the fact that the promise was not performed.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A person convicted of theft of property or services with a value of:<section prefix="(i)">at least $1,000 but less than $10,000 is guilty of a felony and:</section><section prefix="(ii)">at least $10,000 but less than $100,000 is guilty of a felony and:</section><section prefix="(iii)">$100,000 or more is guilty of a felony and:</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Except as provided in paragraphs (3) and (4) of this subsection, a person convicted of theft of property or services with a value of less than $1,000, is guilty of a misdemeanor and:<section prefix="(i)">is subject to imprisonment not exceeding 18 months or a fine not exceeding $500 or both; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">shall restore the property taken to the owner or pay the owner the value of the property or services.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A person convicted of theft of property or services with a value of less than $100 is guilty of a misdemeanor and:<section prefix="(i)">is subject to imprisonment not exceeding 90 days or a fine not exceeding $500 or both; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">shall restore the property taken to the owner or pay the owner the value of the property or services.	</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">Subject to paragraph (5) of this subsection, a person who has two or more prior convictions under this subtitle and who is convicted of theft of property or services with a value of less than $1,000 under paragraph (2) of this subsection is guilty of a misdemeanor and:<section prefix="(i)">is subject to imprisonment not exceeding 5 years or a fine not exceeding $5,000 or both; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">shall restore the property taken to the owner or pay the owner the value of the property or services.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(5)">The court may not impose the penalties under paragraph (4) of this subsection unless the State's Attorney serves notice on the defendant or the defendant's counsel before the acceptance of a plea of guilty or nolo contendere or at least 15 days before trial that:<section prefix="(i)">the State will seek the penalties under paragraph (4) of this subsection; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">lists the alleged prior convictions.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(h)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If a person is convicted of a violation under this section for failure to pay for motor fuel after the motor fuel was dispensed into a vehicle, the court shall:<section prefix="(i)">notify the person that the person's driver's license may be suspended under &#xA7; 16-206.1 of the Transportation Article; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">notify the Motor Vehicle Administration of the violation.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Chief Judge of the District Court and the Administrative Office of the Courts, in conjunction with the Motor Vehicle Administration, shall establish uniform procedures for reporting a violation under this subsection.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(i)">An action or prosecution for a violation of subsection (g)(2) or (3) of this section shall be commenced within 2 years after the commission of the crime.</section>
    <section prefix="(j)">A person who violates this section by use of an interactive computer service may be prosecuted, indicted, tried, and convicted in any county in which the victim resides or the electronic communication originated or terminated.</section>
  </text>
</law>
