<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcr" order_by="gcr" level="1">Criminal Law</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcr-13-1703</section_number>
  <catch_line>The county commissioners may issue a permit to an organization specified in subsection (c) of this s...</catch_line>
  <order_by>1703</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The county commissioners may issue a permit to an organization specified in subsection (c) of this section to use two or more of the following gaming devices in conducting a fundraiser at which a prize of merchandise or money may be awarded:<section prefix="(1)">a paddle wheel;</section><section prefix="(2)">a wheel of fortune;</section><section prefix="(3)">a chance book;</section><section prefix="(4)">a card game;</section><section prefix="(5)">a raffle; or</section><section prefix="(6)">any other gaming device.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Unless conducted at an event requiring a permit under subsection (a) of this section, a raffle is not a multiple gaming device regulated under this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this subsection, "charity" means an organization, institution, association, society, or corporation that is exempt from taxation under &#xA7; 501(c)(3) of the Internal Revenue Code.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The county commissioners may issue a permit to use multiple gaming devices to:<section prefix="(i)">a bona fide religious organization that has conducted religious services at the same location in the county for at least 3 years before applying for a permit;</section><section prefix="(ii)">a county-supported or municipally supported volunteer fire company or an auxiliary unit whose members are directly associated with the volunteer fire company or auxiliary unit;</section><section prefix="(iii)">a nationally chartered veterans' organization or an auxiliary unit whose members are directly associated with the veterans' organization;</section><section prefix="(iv)">for the purpose of conducting a fundraiser for the benefit of a charity located in the county, a bona fide:<section prefix="1.">fraternal organization;</section><section prefix="2.">educational organization;</section><section prefix="3.">civic organization;</section><section prefix="4.">patriotic organization; or</section><section prefix="5.">charitable organization; or</section></section><section prefix="(v)">a bona fide nonprofit organization that:<section prefix="1.">has operated on a nonprofit basis in the county for at least 3 years before applying for a permit; and</section><section prefix="2.">intends to use the multiple gaming devices to raise money for an exclusively charitable, athletic, or educational purpose specifically described in the permit application.</section></section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Before issuing a permit, the county commissioners shall determine that the organization seeking the permit:<section prefix="(1)">is organized in and serves the residents of the county; and</section><section prefix="(2)">meets the conditions of this subtitle.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Except as provided in subparagraph (ii) of this paragraph, a permit is valid for one event that does not last longer than 6 hours.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The county commissioners may issue a permit for an event longer than 6 hours if the permit holder does not seek more than one permit in the same year.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The county commissioners may not approve a permit for gaming events to be held on premises that are licensed under a Class B or Class D alcoholic beverages license.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The county commissioners may not issue more than two permits to an organization in a single year.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The county commissioners may:<section prefix="(i)">charge a fee set by resolution for each permit;</section><section prefix="(ii)">set the number of permits that may be issued each year; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">adopt regulations governing permit applications and the issuance of permits.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">An organization that is issued a permit shall conduct its fundraiser in a:<section prefix="(i)">structure that the organization owns, leases, or occupies;</section><section prefix="(ii)">structure that any organization that would qualify for a permit owns, leases, or occupies; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">public location that is:<section prefix="1.">described in the permit application; and</section><section prefix="2.">approved by the State's Attorney for the county.</section></section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Unless the county commissioners grant a waiver, only a resident of the county may manage and operate a fundraiser for which a permit is issued on behalf of the permit holder.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">Each permit holder shall designate an individual to be responsible for compliance with the terms and conditions of this subtitle and a permit issued under this subtitle.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">A person may not be compensated for operating the gaming activity conducted under a permit.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The permit holder shall use at least one-half of the funds raised using the permit for civic, charitable, or educational purposes.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Within 30 days after a fundraiser, the permit holder shall send to the county commissioners:<section prefix="(i)">an accounting of all funds received or pledged;</section><section prefix="(ii)">an accounting of all expenses paid or incurred; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">a statement under oath of the application of the net profits.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(h)">The county commissioners may deny a permit for not more than 3 years to an organization that violates this subtitle or regulations adopted under this subtitle.</section>
  </text>
</law>
