<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gcr" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="3-314" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcr-3-314</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">"Correctional employee" means a:</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">"Correctional employee" includes a sheriff, warden, or other official who is appointed or employed to supervise a correctional facility.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">"Inmate" has the meaning stated in &#xA7; 1-101 of this article.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">"Inmate" includes an individual confined in a community adult rehabilitation center.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This subsection applies to:<section prefix="(i)">a correctional employee;</section><section prefix="(ii)">any other employee of the Department of Public Safety and Correctional Services or a correctional facility;</section><section prefix="(iii)">an employee of a contractor providing goods or services to the Department of Public Safety and Correctional Services or a correctional facility; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">any other individual working in a correctional facility, whether on a paid or volunteer basis.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A person described in paragraph (1) of this subsection  may not engage in sexual contact, vaginal intercourse, or a sexual act with an inmate.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A person may not engage in sexual contact, vaginal intercourse, or a sexual act with an individual confined in a child care institution licensed by the Department, a detention center for juveniles, or a facility for juveniles listed in &#xA7; 9-226(b) of the Human Services Article.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A person who violates this section is guilty of a misdemeanor and on conviction is subject to imprisonment not exceeding 3 years or a fine not exceeding $3,000 or both.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">A sentence imposed for violation of this section may be separate from and consecutive to or concurrent with a sentence for another crime under &#xA7;&#xA7; 3-303 through 3-312 of this subtitle.</section>
  </text>
</law>
