<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcr" order_by="gcr" level="1">Criminal Law</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcr-8-106</section_number>
  <catch_line>A person who obtains property or services with a value of $500 or more by issuing or passing a check...</catch_line>
  <order_by>106</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">A person who obtains property or services with a value of $500 or more by issuing or passing a check in violation of &#xA7; 8-103 of this subtitle is guilty of a felony and on conviction is subject to imprisonment not exceeding 15 years or a fine not exceeding $1,000 or both.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A person who obtains property or services by issuing or passing more than one check in violation of &#xA7; 8-103 of this subtitle is guilty of a felony and on conviction is subject to imprisonment not exceeding 15 years or a fine not exceeding $1,000 or both if:<section prefix="(1)">each check that is issued is for less than $500 and is issued to the same person within a 30-day period; and</section><section prefix="(2)">the cumulative value of the property or services is $500 or more.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Except as provided in subsections (b) and (d) of this section, a person who obtains property or services with a value of less than $500 by issuing or passing a check in violation of &#xA7; 8-103 of this subtitle is guilty of a misdemeanor and on conviction is subject to imprisonment not exceeding 18 months or a fine not exceeding $100 or both.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A person who obtains property or services with a value of less than $100 by issuing or passing a check in violation of &#xA7; 8-103 of this subtitle is guilty of a misdemeanor and on conviction is subject to imprisonment not exceeding 90 days or a fine not exceeding $500 or both.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">It is not a defense to the crime of obtaining property or services with a value of less than $100 by issuing or passing a check in violation of &#xA7; 8-103 of this subtitle that the value of the property or services at issue is $100 or more.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
