<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcr" order_by="" level="1">Criminal Law</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcr-13-606</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>606</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Before an organization may conduct bingo in the county, the organization shall obtain a bingo license from the Department of Permits and Development Management.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">An organization may conduct bingo to benefit charity in the county or to further its purposes if the organization is:<section prefix="(1)">a tax-supported volunteer fire company or an auxiliary unit whose members are directly associated with a tax-supported volunteer fire company;</section><section prefix="(2)">a nationally chartered veterans' organization or an auxiliary unit whose members are directly associated with a nationally chartered veterans' organization;</section><section prefix="(3)">a bona fide religious group that has conducted religious services at a fixed location in the county for at least 3 years before applying for a bingo license;</section><section prefix="(4)">the Maryland State Fair and Agricultural Society;</section><section prefix="(5)">a bona fide fraternal organization;</section><section prefix="(6)">a bona fide patriotic organization; or</section><section prefix="(7)">a bona fide charitable organization that has been located at a fixed location in the county for 3 years before applying for a bingo license.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">An applicant for a bingo license shall apply for a license on the application form that the Department of Permits and Development Management provides.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The application shall include:<section prefix="(i)">the name of the applicant;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the name and address of each officer and director of the applicant;</section><section prefix="(iii)">a complete statement of the purposes of the applicant;</section><section prefix="(iv)">a statement of the purpose for which the proceeds of the bingo operation will be used;</section><section prefix="(v)">an affidavit that an agreement does not exist to divide any part of the proceeds of the bingo operation with any other person that is made by:<section prefix="1.">the president;</section><section prefix="2.">the treasurer;</section><section prefix="3.">the chief executive; or</section><section prefix="4.">a fiscal officer;</section></section><section prefix="(vi)">an affidavit that only the applicant or a member of the applicant will receive any of the proceeds of the bingo operation except to further the purposes of the applicant organization; and</section><section prefix="(vii)">any other information the Department of Permits and Development Management requires.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">An annual bingo license issued by the Department of Permits and Development Management authorizes the license holder to conduct bingo at the fixed location stated on the license:<section prefix="1.">at any time during the year for which the license is issued; but</section><section prefix="2.">not more often than twice each week in the year for which the license is issued.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">An applicant for an annual license shall pay the fee that the Department of Permits and Development Management sets.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">A temporary license issued by the Department of Permits and Development Management authorizes the license holder to conduct bingo at the fixed location stated on the license for not more than 10 days in the year for which the license is issued.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">An applicant for a temporary license shall pay the fee that the administrative officer of the county sets.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">A 1-day license issued by the Department of Permits and Development Management authorizes the license holder to conduct bingo at a fixed location stated on the license for not more than 1 day in the year for which the license is issued.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">An applicant for a 1-day license shall pay a fee that the administrative officer of the county sets.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">The Department of Permits and Development Management may not grant an applicant more than three 1-day licenses in any calendar year.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Department of Permits and Development Management may require the holder of a bingo license to produce its financial records for inspection so that the Department may ensure that the license holder and the members of the license holder have complied with subsection (c)(2)(v) and (vi) of this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A person may not conduct bingo on Sunday.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The Department of Permits and Development Management shall deposit the fees paid for bingo licenses issued under this section in the county Widows' Pension Fund.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">After a public hearing, the Department of Permits and Development Management may revoke the license of a license holder that fails to comply with this section or the regulations that the Department adopts under this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">The Department of Permits and Development Management may adopt regulations to govern:<section prefix="(1)">the conduct of bingo;</section><section prefix="(2)">the amounts of the prizes that may be awarded in a game of bingo;</section><section prefix="(3)">the method of awarding prizes;</section><section prefix="(4)">the hours that bingo may be conducted; and</section><section prefix="(5)">any other matters related to the proper conduct of bingo.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(i)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">A person may not divert or pay any proceeds of bingo conducted under a bingo license to:<section prefix="1.">any other person, except to a member of the license holder; or</section><section prefix="2.">any other partnership or corporation, except to further the purposes of the license holder.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">A person who is not a member of a license holder may not receive any of the proceeds of bingo conducted under a bingo license except to further the purposes of the license holder.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">A person may not violate a regulation that the Department of Permits and Development Management adopts under subsection (h) of this section.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A person who violates this subsection is guilty of a misdemeanor and on conviction is subject to imprisonment not exceeding 2 years or a fine not exceeding $1,000 or both.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
