<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcr" order_by="" level="1">Criminal Law</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcr-5-805</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>805</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, "controlled premises" means:<section prefix="(1)">a place where a registrant or person exempted from registration requirements under this title is required to keep records; or</section><section prefix="(2)">a place, including a factory, warehouse, establishment, or conveyance, where a registrant or person exempted from registration requirements under this title may possess, manufacture, compound, process, sell, deliver, or dispose of a controlled dangerous substance.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Department may make administrative inspections of controlled premises in accordance with this section and designate those who may seize property under this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">An officer or employee designated by the Department may enter controlled premises to conduct an administrative inspection:<section prefix="(1)">when authorized by an administrative inspection warrant issued under &#xA7; 5-804 of this subtitle; and</section><section prefix="(2)">on presenting the warrant and appropriate credentials to the owner, operator, or agent in charge.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">When authorized by an administrative inspection warrant, an officer or employee designated by the Department may:<section prefix="(1)">inspect and copy records that must be kept under this title;</section><section prefix="(2)">inspect, within reasonable limits and in a reasonable manner:<section prefix="(i)">controlled premises and all pertinent equipment, finished and unfinished material, containers, and labeling in the controlled premises;</section><section prefix="(ii)">except as provided in subsection (e) of this section, all other things in the controlled premises, including records, files, papers, processes, controls, and facilities, bearing on violation of this title; and</section></section><section prefix="(3)">inventory stock and obtain samples of a controlled dangerous substance in the controlled premises.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">Without a warrant, the Department may inspect books and records in accordance with this title and enter and conduct administrative inspections, including seizures of property:<section prefix="(1)">with the consent of the owner, operator, or agent in charge of the controlled premises;</section><section prefix="(2)">in a situation that presents imminent danger to health or safety;</section><section prefix="(3)">in a situation that involves inspection of a conveyance where there is reasonable cause to believe that the mobility of the conveyance makes it impracticable to obtain a warrant;</section><section prefix="(4)">in any other exceptional or emergency situation in which time or opportunity to apply for a warrant is lacking; and</section><section prefix="(5)">in all other situations where a warrant is not legally required.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">Unless the owner, operator, or agent in charge of the controlled premises consents in writing, an inspection authorized under this section may not extend to:<section prefix="(1)">financial data;</section><section prefix="(2)">sales data other than shipment data; or</section><section prefix="(3)">pricing data.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
