<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcr" order_by="" level="1">Criminal Law</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcr-10-127</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>127</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In a proceeding for a violation under this part:<section prefix="(1)">the State has the burden to prove the guilt of the defendant to the same extent as is required by law in the trial of a criminal case;</section><section prefix="(2)">the court shall apply the evidentiary standards as prescribed by law for the trial of a criminal case;</section><section prefix="(3)">the court shall ensure that the defendant has received a copy of the charges against the defendant and that the defendant understands those charges;</section><section prefix="(4)">the defendant is entitled to:<section prefix="(i)">cross-examine each witness who appears against the defendant;</section><section prefix="(ii)">produce evidence and witnesses on the defendant's own behalf;</section><section prefix="(iii)">testify on the defendant's own behalf if the defendant chooses to do so; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">be represented by counsel of the defendant's own selection and expense;</section></section><section prefix="(5)">the defendant may enter a plea of guilty or not guilty;</section><section prefix="(6)">the verdict shall be:<section prefix="(i)">guilty of a civil violation; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">not guilty of a civil violation; and</section></section><section prefix="(7)">before entering a judgment, a court may place the defendant on probation in the same manner and to the same extent as is permitted by law in a criminal case.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">If a defendant is found guilty of a violation under this part and a fine is imposed, a court may direct that the payment of the fine be suspended or deferred under conditions determined by the court.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A defendant's willful failure to pay a fine imposed under this part may be treated as a criminal contempt punishable as provided by law.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A defendant who is found guilty of a violation under this part, as provided by law for a criminal case, may file:<section prefix="(1)">an appeal;</section><section prefix="(2)">a motion for a new trial; or</section><section prefix="(3)">a motion for a revision of a judgment.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The State's Attorney for each county may:<section prefix="(1)">prosecute a violation under this part in the same manner as a prosecution of a criminal case, including entering a nolle prosequi or placing the case on violation on a stet docket; and</section><section prefix="(2)">exercise authority in the same manner prescribed by law for a violation of the criminal laws of the State.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
