<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gcr" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="4-208" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcr-4-208</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">"Demonstration" means one or more persons demonstrating, picketing, speechmaking, marching, holding a vigil, or engaging in any other similar conduct that involves the communication or expression of views or grievances and that has the effect, intent, or propensity to attract a crowd or onlookers.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">"Demonstration" does not include the casual use of property by visitors or tourists that does not have the intent or propensity to attract a crowd or onlookers.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">"Firearm" means a handgun, rifle, shotgun, short-barreled rifle, short-barreled shotgun, or any other firearm, whether loaded or unloaded.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">"Firearm" does not include an antique firearm.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(4)">"Handgun" has the meaning stated in &#xA7; 5-101 of the Public Safety Article.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">"Law enforcement officer" means:<section prefix="(i)">a member of a police force or other unit of the United States, the State, a county, municipal corporation, or other political subdivision who is responsible for the prevention and detection of crime and the enforcement of the laws of the United States, the State, a county, municipal corporation, or other political subdivision;</section><section prefix="(ii)">a park police officer of the Maryland-National Capital Park and Planning Commission;</section><section prefix="(iii)">a member of the University of Maryland police force; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">any military or militia personnel directed by constituted authority to keep law and order.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(6)">
        <section prefix="(i)">"Public place" means a place to which the general public has access and a right to resort for business, entertainment, or other lawful purpose.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">"Public place" is not limited to a place devoted solely to the uses of the public.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">"Public place" includes:</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This subsection does not apply to a law enforcement officer.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A person may not have a firearm in the person's possession or on or about the person at a demonstration in a public place or in a vehicle that is within 1,000 feet of a demonstration in a public place after:<section prefix="(i)">the person has been advised by a law enforcement officer that a demonstration is occurring at the public place; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">the person has been ordered by the law enforcement officer to leave the area of the demonstration until the person disposes of the firearm.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A person who violates this section is guilty of a misdemeanor and on conviction is subject to imprisonment not exceeding 1 year or a fine not exceeding $1,000 or both.</section>
  </text>
</law>
