<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcr" order_by="" level="1">Criminal Law</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcr-3-206</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>206</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">An indictment, information, other charging document, or warrant for a crime described in &#xA7; 3-202, &#xA7; 3-203, or &#xA7; 3-205 of this subtitle is sufficient if it substantially states:</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">If the general form of indictment or information described in subsection (a) of this section is used to charge a crime described in &#xA7; 3-202, &#xA7; 3-203, or &#xA7; 3-205 of this subtitle in a case in the circuit court, the defendant, on timely demand, is entitled to a bill of particulars.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A charge of assault in the first degree also charges a defendant with assault in the second degree.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">To be found guilty of reckless endangerment under &#xA7; 3-204 of this subtitle, a defendant must be charged specifically with reckless endangerment.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A charging document for reckless endangerment under &#xA7; 3-204 of this subtitle is sufficient if it substantially states:</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">If more than one individual is endangered by the conduct of the defendant, a separate charge may be brought for each individual endangered.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">A charging document containing a charge of reckless endangerment under &#xA7; 3-204 of this subtitle may:<section prefix="(i)">include a count for each individual endangered by the conduct of the defendant; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">contain a single count based on the conduct of the defendant, regardless of the number of individuals endangered by the conduct of the defendant.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(5)">If the general form of charging document described in paragraph (2) of this subsection is used to charge reckless endangerment under &#xA7; 3-204 of this subtitle in a case in the circuit court, the defendant, on timely demand, is entitled to a bill of particulars.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
