<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcr" order_by="gcr" level="1">Criminal Law</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcr-5-613</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this section, "drug kingpin" means an organizer, supervisor, financier, or manager who acts as a ...</catch_line>
  <order_by>613</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, "drug kingpin" means an organizer, supervisor, financier, or manager who acts as a coconspirator in a conspiracy to manufacture, distribute, dispense, transport in, or bring into the State a controlled dangerous substance.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A drug kingpin who conspires to manufacture, distribute, dispense, transport in, or bring into the State a controlled dangerous substance in an amount listed in &#xA7; 5-612 of this subtitle is guilty of a felony and on conviction is subject to imprisonment for not less than 20 years and not exceeding 40 years without the possibility of parole or a fine not exceeding $1,000,000 or both.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A court may not suspend any part of the mandatory minimum sentence of 20 years.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The person is not eligible for parole during the mandatory minimum sentence.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">It is not a defense to a prosecution under this section that the controlled dangerous substance was brought into or transported in the State solely for ultimate distribution or dispensing in another jurisdiction.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Notwithstanding any other provision of this title, a conviction under this section does not merge with the conviction for any crime that is the object of the conspiracy.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The provisions of &#xA7; 6-220 of the Criminal Procedure Article do not apply to a conviction under this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">This section does not:<section prefix="(1)">prohibit a court from imposing an enhanced penalty under &#xA7; 5-905 of this title; or</section><section prefix="(2)">preclude or limit a prosecution for any other crime.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
