<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcr" order_by="gcr" level="1">Criminal Law</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcr-13-302</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this section, "paper gaming" means a game of chance in which:...</catch_line>
  <order_by>302</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section, "paper gaming" means a game of chance in which:<section prefix="(i)">prizes are awarded; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">the devices used to play the game are constructed out of paper or cardboard.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Paper gaming" includes tip jar and punchboard gaming.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Paper gaming" does not include bingo.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">This section applies only in Allegany County.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Subject to paragraphs (2) and (3) of this subsection, a person that is a for profit business or qualified organization may engage in paper gaming if the person obtains a paper gaming license that is issued by the Board of County Commissioners.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If the person is a for profit business, the person shall also hold a Class A, C, or D retail alcoholic beverages license.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Qualified organizations that do not have an alcoholic beverages license and fire and rescue departments may engage in paper gaming without obtaining a paper gaming license.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A person may sell paper gaming devices to a paper gaming licensee if the person obtains a wholesale vendor's license issued by the Board of County Commissioners.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The Board of County Commissioners shall set annual fees for a paper gaming license and a wholesale vendor's license.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">Monthly, wholesale vendor licensees shall provide a list to the Board of County Commissioners of all customers to whom they sell paper gaming products and the total number of products sold to each customer.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">A paper gaming licensee may not have on its premises a paper gaming device that does not display a gaming sticker.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">The Board of County Commissioners shall ensure that each retail alcoholic beverages licensee who holds a paper gaming license sells to the public the same serial-numbered paper gaming devices that are listed on the bill of sale from the wholesale vendor licensee.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Board of County Commissioners may impose the following paper gaming taxes:<section prefix="(i)">on licensees that are qualified organizations, 10% of gross profits minus the costs of paper gaming products; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">on licensees that are for profit businesses, 40% of gross profits minus the costs of paper gaming products.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Board of County Commissioners may not impose a paper gaming tax on qualified organizations that do not have an alcoholic beverages license or fire and rescue departments that buy paper gaming devices from a licensed wholesale vendor.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(j)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this subsection, "Fund" means the Special Gaming Fund.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Board of County Commissioners may establish a Special Gaming Fund.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Fund is a special continuing, nonlapsing fund.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The Fund may be used only to benefit fire and rescue departments and to pay for specified school costs.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The Fund consists of:<section prefix="1.">revenue derived from the taxation of gross profits from tip jar sales; and</section><section prefix="2.">subject to subparagraph (ii) of this paragraph, money received from other sources.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">Money from the General Fund of the State or county, including any federal money, may not be transferred by budget amendment or otherwise to the Fund.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(6)">The Fund shall be invested and reinvested in the same manner as other county funds.</section>
      <section prefix="(7)">Annually the Board of County Commissioners shall:<section prefix="(i)">pay from the Fund all administrative costs of carrying out this section, including the hiring of additional necessary personnel; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">allocate the remaining money in the Fund as follows:<section prefix="1.">at least 25% but not more than 35% to fire and rescue departments; and</section><section prefix="2.">the balance to pay for school construction, school supplies, and other nonmaintenance of effort costs.</section></section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(k)">The Board of County Commissioners may adopt rules and regulations to administer and enforce this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(l)">The Board of County Commissioners may:<section prefix="(1)">hire one or more inspectors; and</section><section prefix="(2)">authorize each inspector to enter the premises of a licensee to ensure compliance with this section or a rule or regulation adopted under this section.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(m)">The Board of County Commissioners may adopt an ordinance or resolution declaring that a violation of this section or a rule or regulation adopted under this section is:<section prefix="(1)">a civil infraction under Article 25B, &#xA7; 13C of the Code; or</section><section prefix="(2)">a misdemeanor punishable by a term of imprisonment not exceeding 30 days or a fine not exceeding $1,000 or both.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(n)">After a hearing, if the Board of County Commissioners or a designee of the Board finds that a paper gaming licensee, a wholesale vendor licensee, or an agent of a licensee has violated this section or a rule or regulation adopted under this section, the Board may suspend or revoke the license in addition to any fine or penalty imposed under subsection (m) of this section.</section>
  </text>
</law>
