<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcr" order_by="gcr" level="1">Criminal Law</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcr-13-1104</section_number>
  <catch_line>There is a Charles County Gaming Permit Review Board....</catch_line>
  <order_by>1104</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">There is a Charles County Gaming Permit Review Board.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The board consists of seven members.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Of the seven members of the board:<section prefix="(i)">one shall be a member of the county sheriff's office;</section><section prefix="(ii)">one shall be a member of the Department of State Police;</section><section prefix="(iii)">one shall be a member of a fundraising organization in the county;</section><section prefix="(iv)">one shall be an individual with background and experience in finance; and</section><section prefix="(v)">three shall be members at large.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Each member at large:<section prefix="(i)">shall be a member of the general public;</section><section prefix="(ii)">may not be a member of a fundraising organization or otherwise be subject to regulation by the board;</section><section prefix="(iii)">may not, within 1 year before appointment, have had a financial interest in or have received compensation from a person regulated by the board; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">may not, while a member of the board, have a financial interest in or receive compensation from a person regulated by the board.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">Each member of the board shall be a resident of the county.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">The board shall select a chairperson from among its members, to serve the term that the board sets.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The term of a member is 4 years.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The terms of members are staggered as required by the terms provided for members of the board on October 1, 2002.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">At the end of a term, a member continues to serve until a successor is appointed and qualifies.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">A member who is appointed after a term has begun serves only for the rest of the term and until a successor is appointed and qualifies.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The board may recommend to the county commissioners:<section prefix="(1)">the types of gaming devices that may be operated in the county;</section><section prefix="(2)">approval or denial of a gaming permit; and</section><section prefix="(3)">modifications of the county gaming regulations and procedures.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The board shall:<section prefix="(1)">review at least quarterly gaming permit applications;</section><section prefix="(2)">review gaming regulations and permit procedures;</section><section prefix="(3)">keep a list of all approved lessors of gaming devices and premises for gaming events;</section><section prefix="(4)">keep a record of the gaming permits that the board has reviewed; and</section><section prefix="(5)">undertake the other duties regarding gaming regulation that the county commissioners delegate.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">As the county commissioners consider appropriate, the county commissioners shall provide for the board a clerk, legal counsel, supplies, and funding.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">The county commissioners may pay salaries to the members of the board.</section>
  </text>
</law>
