<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcr" order_by="gcr" level="1">Criminal Law</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcr-2-401</section_number>
  <catch_line>After a death sentence is imposed and the judgment becomes final, the Court of Appeals shall review ...</catch_line>
  <order_by>401</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">After a death sentence is imposed and the judgment becomes final, the Court of Appeals shall review the sentence on the record.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Court of Appeals shall consolidate an appeal from the verdict with the sentence review.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The clerk of the trial court shall send to the Clerk of the Court of Appeals:<section prefix="(1)">the entire record and the transcript of the sentencing proceeding within 10 days after receiving the transcript;</section><section prefix="(2)">the determination and written findings of the court or jury; and</section><section prefix="(3)">a report of the trial court that:<section prefix="(i)">is in the form of a standard questionnaire supplied by the Court of Appeals; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">includes a recommendation by the trial court as to whether the death sentence is justified.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The defendant and the State may submit briefs and present oral arguments to the Court of Appeals within the time allowed by the Court.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In addition to any error properly before the Court on appeal, the Court of Appeals shall consider the imposition of the death sentence.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">With regard to the death sentence, the Court of Appeals shall determine whether:<section prefix="(i)">the imposition of the death sentence was influenced by passion, prejudice, or any other arbitrary factor;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the evidence supports the finding by the court or jury of a statutory aggravating circumstance under &#xA7; 2-303(g) of this title; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">the evidence supports a finding by the court or jury that the aggravating circumstances outweigh the mitigating circumstances under &#xA7; 2-303(h) and (i)(1) of this title.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">In addition to its review under any direct appeal, with regard to the death sentence, the Court of Appeals shall:<section prefix="(i)">affirm the death sentence;</section><section prefix="(ii)">set the death sentence aside and remand the case for a new sentencing proceeding under &#xA7; 2-303 of this title; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">set the death sentence aside and remand the case for modification of the sentence to imprisonment for life.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The Court of Appeals may adopt rules of procedure for the expedited review of death sentences under this section.</section>
  </text>
</law>
