<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcr" order_by="gcr" level="1">Criminal Law</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcr-7-103</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this section, "value" means:...</catch_line>
  <order_by>103</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, "value" means:<section prefix="(1)">the market value of the property or service at the time and place of the crime; or</section><section prefix="(2)">if the market value cannot satisfactorily be ascertained, the cost of the replacement of the property or service within a reasonable time after the crime.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The value of property or service under this part shall be determined in accordance with this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, this subsection applies to a written instrument whether or not the instrument has been issued or delivered.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">This subsection does not apply to a written instrument that has a readily ascertainable market value.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">For purposes of this part, a written instrument is valued as provided by this paragraph.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The value of an instrument constituting evidence of debt, including a check, draft, or promissory note, is the amount due or collectible on the instrument. That value is ordinarily the face amount of the instrument, less any portion that has been satisfied.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">The value of any other instrument that creates, releases, discharges, or otherwise affects a valuable legal right, privilege, or obligation is the amount of economic loss the owner of the instrument might reasonably suffer because of the loss of the instrument.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The value of a trade secret lacking a readily ascertainable market value is a reasonable value that represents the damage the owner suffered by the loss of an advantage over those who do not know or use the trade secret.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">For the purposes of determining whether a theft violation subject to either &#xA7; 7-104(g)(1) or (2) of this subtitle has been committed, when it cannot be determined whether the value of the property or service is more or less than $500 under the standards of this section, the value is deemed to be less than $500.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">For the purposes of determining whether a theft violation subject to either &#xA7; 7-104(g)(2) or (3) of this subtitle has been committed, when it cannot be determined whether the value of the property or service is more or less than $100 under the standards of this section, the value is deemed to be less than $100.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">When theft is committed in violation of this part under one scheme or continuing course of conduct, whether from the same or several sources:<section prefix="(1)">the conduct may be considered as one crime; and</section><section prefix="(2)">the value of the property or services may be aggregated in determining whether the theft is a felony or a misdemeanor.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
