<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcr" order_by="" level="1">Criminal Law</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcr-13-1203</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>1203</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">A person must have a license for each day that the person conducts bingo unless the bingo is conducted in a licensed gaming event.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Notwithstanding any other provision of this subtitle or Subtitle 2 of this title, in addition to bingo conducted in connection with a gaming event under Subtitle 2 of this title, the clerk of the circuit court of the county may issue a license to conduct bingo.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">To qualify for a license to conduct bingo, an applicant shall be a:<section prefix="(1)">bona fide religious group that has conducted religious services at a fixed location in the county for at least 3 years before applying for a license;</section><section prefix="(2)">tax-supported volunteer fire company or an auxiliary unit whose members are directly associated with the fire company;</section><section prefix="(3)">nationally chartered veterans' organization or an auxiliary unit whose members are directly associated with the organization; or</section><section prefix="(4)">nonprofit organization that:<section prefix="(i)">intends to raise money for an exclusively charitable, athletic, or educational purpose that is described in the application for a license; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">has operated in the county for at least 3 years before applying for a license.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">An application for a license to conduct bingo shall contain a certification, by a principal officer of the applicant, stating:<section prefix="(1)">the time and place of the activities for which the license is sought;</section><section prefix="(2)">that the bingo will be conducted and managed solely and personally by the regular members of the applicant without the assistance of gaming professionals; and</section><section prefix="(3)">that no compensation or reward will be paid to any person for conducting or assisting in the conducting of the bingo.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
