<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcr" order_by="" level="1">Criminal Law</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcr-10-617</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>617</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, "animal control unit" means the local organization or governmental unit that the appropriate local governmental body designates to house, care for, and control domestic animals of unknown ownership.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">An animal control unit shall dispose of an unclaimed dog or cat only by:<section prefix="(1)">placing the animal in a suitable home;</section><section prefix="(2)">retaining the animal in the animal control unit; or</section><section prefix="(3)">humanely destroying the animal.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A domestic animal that is impounded by an animal control unit may not be sold, placed, or destroyed until the animal has been carefully inspected for a tag, tattoo, or other identification to ascertain the owner and:<section prefix="(1)">72 hours have elapsed after notice has been given to the owner;</section><section prefix="(2)">if the owner cannot be notified, 72 hours have elapsed after the animal is impounded;</section><section prefix="(3)">the animal is seriously diseased or severely injured; or</section><section prefix="(4)">the animal is under 3 months of age.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">An owner who retrieves an animal from an animal control unit shall pay all fees, costs, and expenses incurred by the animal control unit.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The necessary expenses for food and attention given to an animal under this section may be collected from the owner, and the animal is not exempt from levy and sale on execution of a judgment for the expenses.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A new owner with whom an animal is placed under subsection (b)(1) of this section may be charged an adoption fee.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">A person who violates this section is guilty of a misdemeanor and on conviction is subject to a fine not exceeding $500.</section>
  </text>
</law>
