<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gcr" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="7-318" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcr-7-318</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">A person who has suffered a specific and direct injury to a right protected by this part because of a violation of &#xA7; 7-315 of this part may bring a civil action in a court of competent jurisdiction.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The court:<section prefix="(1)">may impose preliminary and final injunctions to prevent or restrain a violation of &#xA7; 7-315 of this part;</section><section prefix="(2)">at any time while an action is pending, may order the impounding of any unlawful telecommunication device or access code or unlawful access device that is in the custody or control of the violator and that the court has reasonable cause to believe was involved in the alleged violation of &#xA7; 7-315 of this part;</section><section prefix="(3)">may award damages subject to subsection (d) of this section; or</section><section prefix="(4)">as part of a final judgment or decree finding a violation of &#xA7; 7-315 of this part, may order the remedial modification or destruction of any unlawful telecommunication device or access code or unlawful access device involved in the violation that is in the custody or control of the violator or that has been impounded under paragraph (2) of this subsection.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">This section does not allow the District Court to grant relief under subsection (b)(1) of this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Damages awarded by a court under this section may be computed as actual damages suffered by the complaining party as a result of the violation of &#xA7; 7-315 of this part and any profits of the violator that are attributable to the violation and are not taken into account in computing the actual damages.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">In determining the profits of the violator under paragraph (1) of this subsection:<section prefix="(i)">the complaining party must prove only the violator's gross revenue; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">the violator must prove the deductible expenses and elements of profit attributable to factors other than the violation.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
