<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcr" order_by="gcr" level="1">Criminal Law</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcr-9-609</section_number>
  <catch_line>This section does not apply:...</catch_line>
  <order_by>609</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">This section does not apply:<section prefix="(1)">to alarm systems activated by weather conditions or causes beyond the control of the alarm user;</section><section prefix="(2)">in Frederick County if the Board of County Commissioners of Frederick County adopts regulations under Article 25, &#xA7; 221A of the Code providing for the registration of alarm system contractors and alarm users, the issuance of civil citations, and penalties for a violation of a regulation;</section><section prefix="(3)">in Calvert County if the Board of County Commissioners of Calvert County adopts regulations under Article 25, &#xA7; 236D of the Code providing for the registration of alarm system contractors and alarm users, the issuance of civil citations, and penalties for a violation of a regulation; or</section><section prefix="(4)">in Washington County if the Board of County Commissioners of Washington County adopts regulations under Article 25, &#xA7; 236E of the Code providing for the registration of alarm system contractors and alarm users, the issuance of civil citations, and penalties for a violation of a regulation.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">An alarm system that is activated more than once within a 12-hour period when a premises with an alarm system is unoccupied and that is not in response to an actual emergency situation or threatened suggested criminal activity constitutes one false alarm if:<section prefix="(1)">access to the building is provided to the alarm system contractor; and</section><section prefix="(2)">an alarm system contractor or an employee of an alarm system contractor responds to the activated alarm system.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A law enforcement unit or fire department may issue a civil citation to an alarm user for the negligent or accidental activation of an alarm system as a result of faulty, malfunctioning, or improperly installed or maintained equipment or for a false alarm if the number of activations or false alarms to which the law enforcement unit or fire department responds exceeds:<section prefix="(i)">three responses within a 30-day period; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">eight responses within a 12-month period.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A civil citation issued under this section shall assess a penalty of $30 for each negligent or accidental activation or false alarm.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
