<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcr" order_by="" level="1">Criminal Law</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcr-13-2621</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>2621</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The county commissioners may issue a permit to any of the following organizations to conduct a fundraiser at which merchandise or money prizes may be awarded by gaming devices:<section prefix="(1)">a bona fide religious organization that has conducted religious services at the same location in the county for at least 3 years before applying for a permit;</section><section prefix="(2)">a volunteer fire company that is supported by the county or a municipal corporation in the county or an auxiliary unit whose members are directly associated with the volunteer fire company or auxiliary unit;</section><section prefix="(3)">a nationally chartered veterans' organization or an auxiliary unit whose members are directly associated with the veterans' organization;</section><section prefix="(4)">a bona fide nonprofit fraternal, educational, civic, patriotic, or charitable organization that intends to conduct a fundraiser for the benefit of a charity located in the county; or</section><section prefix="(5)">a bona fide nonprofit organization that:<section prefix="(i)">intends to raise money for an exclusively charitable, athletic, or educational purpose that is specifically described in the permit application; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">has operated as a nonprofit organization in the county for at least 3 years before applying for a permit.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The county commissioners shall determine whether an organization qualifies for a permit under this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">An organization must be organized in and serve the residents of the county to be eligible for a permit under this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">An organization that is exempt from taxation under &#xA7; 501(c)(3) of the Internal Revenue Code is a bona fide charity under this section.</section>
  </text>
</law>
