<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcr" order_by="gcr" level="1">Criminal Law</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcr-7-110</section_number>
  <catch_line>It is not a defense to the crime of theft that the defendant has an interest in the property that wa...</catch_line>
  <order_by>110</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">It is not a defense to the crime of theft that the defendant has an interest in the property that was the subject of the theft if another also has an interest in or right to possess the property that the defendant is not entitled to infringe.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">In determining the right of possession:<section prefix="(i)">a joint or common owner of the property does not have a right of possession of the property that is superior to the right of any other joint or common owner of the property; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">in the absence of a contrary agreement, a person in lawful possession of the property has a right of possession superior to the right of possession of a person who has only a security interest in the property, even if legal title to the property lies with the holder of the security interest under a conditional sale contract or other security agreement.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">It is not a defense to the crime of theft that the property was taken, obtained, or withheld from a person who had obtained the property by illegal means.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">It is not a defense to the crime of theft of property or services with a value of less than $100 as provided under &#xA7; 7-104(g)(3) of this subtitle that the value of the property or services at issue is $100 or more.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">It is a defense to the crime of theft that:<section prefix="(1)">the defendant acted under a good faith claim of right to the property involved;</section><section prefix="(2)">the defendant acted in the honest belief that the defendant had the right to obtain or exert control over the property as the defendant did;</section><section prefix="(3)">the property involved was that of the defendant's spouse, unless the defendant and the defendant's spouse were not living together as husband and wife and were living in separate residences at the time of the alleged theft; or</section><section prefix="(4)">in a case of theft of a trade secret, the defendant rightfully knew the trade secret, or the trade secret was available to the defendant from a source other than the owner.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Any common law and evidentiary presumption applicable on July 1, 1979 to the crimes consolidated under this part also apply to the crime of theft, unless the presumption:<section prefix="(1)">is repealed or modified under this part; or</section><section prefix="(2)">is modified by a court decision rendered after July 1, 1979.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
