<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcr" order_by="gcr" level="1">Criminal Law</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcr-2-202</section_number>
  <catch_line>A defendant found guilty of murder in the first degree may be sentenced to death only if:...</catch_line>
  <order_by>202</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">A defendant found guilty of murder in the first degree may be sentenced to death only if:<section prefix="(1)">at least 30 days before trial, the State gave written notice to the defendant of:<section prefix="(i)">the State's intention to seek a sentence of death; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">each aggravating circumstance on which the State intends to rely;</section></section><section prefix="(2)"><section prefix="(i)">with respect to &#xA7; 2-303(g) of this title, except for &#xA7; 2-303(g)(1)(i) and (vii) of this title, the defendant was a principal in the first degree; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">with respect to &#xA7; 2-303(g)(1)(i) of this title, a law enforcement officer, as defined in &#xA7; 2-303(a) of this title, was murdered and the defendant was:<section prefix="1.">a principal in the first degree; or</section><section prefix="2.">a principal in the second degree who:</section></section></section><section prefix="(3)">the State presents the court or jury with:<section prefix="(i)">biological evidence or DNA evidence that links the defendant to the act of murder;</section><section prefix="(ii)">a video taped, voluntary interrogation and confession of the defendant to the murder; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">a video recording that conclusively links the defendant to the murder; and</section></section><section prefix="(4)">the sentence of death is imposed in accordance with &#xA7; 2-303 of this title.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this subsection, a defendant is "mentally retarded" if:<section prefix="(i)">the defendant had significantly below average intellectual functioning, as shown by an intelligence quotient of 70 or below on an individually administered intelligence quotient test and an impairment in adaptive behavior; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">the mental retardation was manifested before the age of 22 years.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A defendant may not be sentenced to death, but shall be sentenced to imprisonment for life without the possibility of parole subject to the requirements of &#xA7; 2-203(1) of this subtitle or imprisonment for life, if the defendant:<section prefix="(i)">was under the age of 18 years at the time of the murder; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">proves by a preponderance of the evidence that at the time of the murder the defendant was mentally retarded.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A defendant may not be sentenced to death, but shall be sentenced to imprisonment for life without the possibility of parole subject to the requirements of &#xA7; 2-203(1) of this subtitle or imprisonment for life, if the State relies solely on evidence provided by eyewitnesses.</section>
  </text>
</law>
