<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcr" order_by="gcr" level="1">Criminal Law</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcr-8-508</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this part the following words have the meanings indicated....</catch_line>
  <order_by>508</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this part the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"False representation" means the knowing and willful:<section prefix="(1)">concealing, falsifying, or omitting of a material fact;</section><section prefix="(2)">making of a materially false or fraudulent statement; or</section><section prefix="(3)">use of a document that contains a statement of material fact that the user knows to be false or fraudulent.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Health care service" means health or medical care procedures, goods, or services that:<section prefix="(i)">provide testing, diagnosis, or treatment of human disease or dysfunction; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">dispense drugs, medical devices, medical appliances, or medical goods for the treatment of human disease or dysfunction.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Health care service" includes any procedure, goods, or service that is a required benefit of a State health plan.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">"Representation" includes an acknowledgment, certification, claim, ratification, report of demographic statistics, encounter data, enrollment claims, financial information, health care services available or rendered, and qualifications of a person rendering health care or ancillary services.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"Serious injury" means an injury that:<section prefix="(1)">creates a substantial risk of death;</section><section prefix="(2)">causes serious permanent or serious protracted disfigurement;</section><section prefix="(3)">causes serious permanent or serious protracted loss of the function of any body part, organ, or mental faculty;</section><section prefix="(4)">causes serious permanent or serious protracted impairment of the function of any bodily member or organ; or</section><section prefix="(5)">involves extreme physical pain.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"State health plan" includes:<section prefix="(i)">the State Medical Assistance Plan established in accordance with Title XIX of the federal Social Security Act of 1939;</section><section prefix="(ii)">a medical assistance plan established by the State; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">a private health insurance carrier, health maintenance organization, managed care organization as defined in &#xA7; 15-101 of the Health - General Article, health care cooperative or alliance, or other person that provides or contracts to provide health care services that are wholly or partly reimbursed by or are a required benefit of a health plan established in accordance with Title XIX of the federal Social Security Act of 1939 or by the State.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"State health plan" includes a person that provides or contracts or subcontracts to provide health care services for an entity described in paragraph (1) of this subsection.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
