<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcr" order_by="gcr" level="1">Criminal Law</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcr-12-304</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this section, "eligible organization" means:...</catch_line>
  <order_by>304</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, "eligible organization" means:<section prefix="(1)">a nonprofit organization that:<section prefix="(i)">has been located in a county listed in subsection (b) of this section for at least 5 years before the organization applies for a license under subsection (e) of this section; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">is a bona fide:<section prefix="1.">fraternal organization;</section><section prefix="2.">religious organization; or</section><section prefix="3.">war veterans' organization; or</section></section></section><section prefix="(2)">a nonprofit organization that has been affiliated with a national fraternal organization for less than 5 years and has been located in a county listed in subsection (b) of this section for at least 50 years before the nonprofit organization applies for a license under subsection (e) of this section.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">This section applies in:<section prefix="(1)">Caroline County;</section><section prefix="(2)">Cecil County;</section><section prefix="(3)">Dorchester County;</section><section prefix="(4)">Kent County;</section><section prefix="(5)">Queen Anne's County;</section><section prefix="(6)">Somerset County;</section><section prefix="(7)">Talbot County;</section><section prefix="(8)">Wicomico County; and</section><section prefix="(9)">Worcester County.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this subsection, a console or set of affixed slot machines is not an individual slot machine.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Notwithstanding any other provision of this subtitle, an eligible organization may own and operate a slot machine if the eligible organization:<section prefix="(i)">obtains a license under subsection (e) of this section for each slot machine;</section><section prefix="(ii)">owns each slot machine that the eligible organization operates;</section><section prefix="(iii)">owns not more than five slot machines;</section><section prefix="(iv)">locates and operates its slot machines at its principal meeting hall in the county in which the eligible organization is located;</section><section prefix="(v)">does not locate or operate its slot machines in a private commercial facility;</section><section prefix="(vi)">uses:<section prefix="1.">at least one-half of the net after payout proceeds from its slot machines for the benefit of a charity; and</section><section prefix="2.">the remainder of the proceeds from its slot machines to further the purposes of the eligible organization;</section></section><section prefix="(vii)">does not use any of the proceeds of the slot machine for the financial benefit of an individual; and</section><section prefix="(viii)">reports annually under affidavit to the State Comptroller:<section prefix="1.">the income of each slot machine; and</section><section prefix="2.">the disposition of the income from each slot machine.</section></section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">An eligible organization may not use or operate a slot machine unless:<section prefix="(1)">the slot machine is equipped with a tamperproof meter or counter that accurately records gross receipts; and</section><section prefix="(2)">the eligible organization keeps an accurate record of the gross receipts and payoffs of the slot machine.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The State Comptroller shall regulate the operation of slot machines under this section.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The State Comptroller may adopt regulations to implement the requirements of this section, including requiring audits of the annual reports submitted to the State Comptroller under subsection (c)(2)(viii) of this section.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Before an eligible organization may operate a slot machine under this section, the eligible organization shall obtain a license for the slot machine from the State Comptroller.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The State Comptroller shall:<section prefix="1.">charge an annual fee for each license for a machine; and</section><section prefix="2.">issue a license sticker to the applicant.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The applicant shall place the sticker on the slot machine.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">The State Comptroller shall set the amount of the annual fee so that the total proceeds of the annual fee equal an amount directly related to administrative costs of the State Comptroller to regulate the operation of slot machines under this section.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(4)">In the application to the State Comptroller for a license, one of the principal officers of the eligible organization shall certify under affidavit that the organization:<section prefix="(i)">is an eligible organization; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">will comply with this section.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A principal officer of the eligible organization may not intentionally misrepresent a statement of fact on the application.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A person who violates this subsection is guilty of perjury and on conviction is subject to the penalty provided under Title 9, Subtitle 1 of this article.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">The Comptroller may not issue a license for a slot machine to an eligible organization located in Ocean City that is located east of South and North Baltimore Avenues.</section>
  </text>
</law>
