<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gcr" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="5-623" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcr-5-623</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Drug crime" means:<section prefix="(i)">a crime under this title; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">a crime committed in another jurisdiction that would be a crime under this title if committed in this State.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Financial transaction" means:<section prefix="(i)">a payment;</section><section prefix="(ii)">a purchase;</section><section prefix="(iii)">a sale;</section><section prefix="(iv)">a loan;</section><section prefix="(v)">a pledge;</section><section prefix="(vi)">a transfer;</section><section prefix="(vii)">a delivery;</section><section prefix="(viii)">a deposit;</section><section prefix="(ix)">a withdrawal; or</section><section prefix="(x)">an extension of credit or exchange of a monetary instrument or equivalent property, including precious metals, stones or jewelry, airline tickets, stamps, or credit in a financial institution as defined in &#xA7; 1-101 of the Financial Institutions Article.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">"Monetary instrument" means:<section prefix="(i)">coin or currency of the United States or any other country;</section><section prefix="(ii)">a bank check;</section><section prefix="(iii)">a travelers' check;</section><section prefix="(iv)">a money order;</section><section prefix="(v)">an investment security; or</section><section prefix="(vi)">a negotiable instrument.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(5)">"Proceeds" means money or any other property with a value exceeding $10,000.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Except for a financial transaction necessary to preserve a person's right to representation as guaranteed by the 6th Amendment to the United States Constitution and Article 21 of the Maryland Declaration of Rights, a person may not, with the intent to promote a drug crime or with the intent to conceal or disguise the nature, location, source, ownership, or control of proceeds of a drug crime:<section prefix="(1)">receive or acquire proceeds knowing that the proceeds are derived from a drug crime;</section><section prefix="(2)">engage in a financial transaction involving proceeds knowing that the proceeds are derived from a drug crime;</section><section prefix="(3)">give, sell, transfer, trade, invest, conceal, transport, or maintain an interest in proceeds knowing that the proceeds are derived from a drug crime;</section><section prefix="(4)">direct, promote, plan, organize, initiate, finance, manage, supervise, or facilitate the transportation or transfer of proceeds knowing that the proceeds are derived from a drug crime; or</section><section prefix="(5)">conduct a financial transaction involving proceeds knowing that the proceeds are derived from a drug crime.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A person who violates this section is guilty of a felony and on conviction is subject to:<section prefix="(1)">for a first violation:<section prefix="(i)">imprisonment not exceeding 5 years;</section><section prefix="(ii)">a fine not exceeding the greater of $250,000 or twice the value of the proceeds involved in the financial transaction; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">both; or</section></section><section prefix="(2)">for each subsequent violation:<section prefix="(i)">imprisonment not exceeding 10 years;</section><section prefix="(ii)">a fine not exceeding the greater of $500,000 or 5 times the value of the proceeds involved in the financial transaction; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">both.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, for purposes of this section each financial transaction is a separate violation.</section>
  </text>
</law>
