<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcr" order_by="gcr" level="1">Criminal Law</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcr-3-903</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this section, "camera" includes any electronic device that can be used surreptitiously to observe...</catch_line>
  <order_by>903</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, "camera" includes any electronic device that can be used surreptitiously to observe an individual.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">This section does not apply to:<section prefix="(1)">an adult resident of the private residence where a camera is placed;</section><section prefix="(2)">a person who places or procures another to place a camera on real property without the intent to conduct deliberate surreptitious observation of an individual inside the private residence;</section><section prefix="(3)">a person who has obtained the consent of an adult resident, or the adult resident's legal guardian, to place a camera on real property to conduct deliberate surreptitious observation of an individual inside the private residence;</section><section prefix="(4)">any otherwise lawful observation with a camera conducted by a law enforcement officer while performing official duties;</section><section prefix="(5)">filming conducted by a person by or for the print or broadcast media through use of a camera that is not secreted from view;</section><section prefix="(6)">any part of a private residence used for business purposes, including any part of a private residence used as a family child care home for the care and custody of a child;</section><section prefix="(7)">filming of a private residence by a person through use of a camera that is not located on the real property where the private residence is located; or</section><section prefix="(8)">any otherwise lawful observation with a camera of the common area of multiunit family dwellings by a person that holds a license under Title 13 or Title 19 of the Business Occupations and Professions Article, acting within the scope of the person's occupation.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A person may not place or procure another to place a camera on real property where a private residence is located to conduct deliberate surreptitious observation of an individual inside the private residence.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A person who violates this section is guilty of a misdemeanor and on conviction is subject to imprisonment not exceeding 1 year or a fine not exceeding $2,500 or both.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">Subject to subsection (b)(1) of this section, it is not a defense to a prosecution under this section that the defendant owns the private residence.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">A good faith reliance on a court order is a complete defense to a civil or criminal action brought under this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">An individual who was observed through the use of a camera in violation of this section has a civil cause of action against any person who placed or procured another to place the camera on the real property.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">In an action under this subsection, the court may award damages and reasonable attorney's fees.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(h)">This section does not affect any legal or equitable right or remedy otherwise provided by law.</section>
  </text>
</law>
