<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gcr" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="7-304" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcr-7-304</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Customer" means a person who subscribes to, or is financially responsible for a subscription to, telephone service from a telephone company.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Telephone" means a device used by a person for voice communications transmitted in analog, data, or any other form.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">"Telephone company" means a person that provides commercial telephone service to a customer, regardless of the communication technology used, including:<section prefix="(i)">traditional wireline or cable telephone service;</section><section prefix="(ii)">cellular, broadband PCS, or other commercial mobile radiotelephone service;</section><section prefix="(iii)">microwave, satellite, or other terrestrial telephone service; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">voice over Internet telephone service.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(5)">
        <section prefix="(i)">"Telephone record" means information retained by a telephone company that relates to:</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">"Telephone record" does not include information collected or retained by customers using caller I.D. or similar technology.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">This section does not apply to:<section prefix="(1)">a person acting under a valid court order, warrant, or subpoena; or</section><section prefix="(2)">a law enforcement officer acting in the performance of official duty.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A person may not:<section prefix="(1)">knowingly obtain, attempt to obtain, or solicit or conspire with another to obtain, a telephone record:<section prefix="(i)">without the authorization of the customer to whom the record pertains; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">by fraudulent, deceptive, or false means;</section></section><section prefix="(2)">knowingly sell or attempt to sell a telephone record without the authorization of the customer to whom the record pertains; or</section><section prefix="(3)">receive a telephone record:<section prefix="(i)">knowing that the record has been obtained without the authorization of the customer to whom the record pertains; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">by fraudulent, deceptive, or false means.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A violation of this section is an unfair or deceptive trade practice under Title 13 of the Commercial Law Article.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A person who violates this section is guilty of a misdemeanor and on conviction is subject to imprisonment not exceeding 2 years or a fine not exceeding $2,000 or both.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">Notwithstanding any other law, the prosecution for a violation of this section may be commenced in any county in which:<section prefix="(1)">an element of the crime occurred; or</section><section prefix="(2)">the victim resides.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">This section may not be construed to prohibit a telephone company from obtaining, using, disclosing, or allowing access to a customer's telephone record:<section prefix="(1)">as otherwise authorized by law;</section><section prefix="(2)">with the consent of the customer;</section><section prefix="(3)">in connection with service provided to the customer;</section><section prefix="(4)">for purposes of billing or collection from the customer;</section><section prefix="(5)">as necessary to prevent fraud or abusive practices;</section><section prefix="(6)">to a governmental entity, if the telephone company reasonably believes that an emergency involving immediate danger of death or serious physical injury to any person justifies disclosure of the telephone record; or</section><section prefix="(7)">to the National Center for Missing and Exploited Children, in connection with a report submitted under &#xA7; 227 of the federal Victims of Child Abuse Act of 1990.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
