<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcr" order_by="" level="1">Criminal Law</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcr-3-602.1</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>602.1</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Family member" has the meaning stated in &#xA7; 3-601 of this subtitle.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Household member" has the meaning stated in &#xA7; 3-601 of this subtitle.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">"Mental injury" means the substantial impairment of a minor's mental or psychological ability to function.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">
        <section prefix="(i)">"Neglect" means the intentional failure to provide necessary assistance and resources for the physical needs or mental health of a minor that creates a substantial risk of harm to the minor's physical health or a substantial risk of mental injury to the minor.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">"Neglect" does not include the failure to provide necessary assistance and resources for the physical needs or mental health of a minor when the failure is due solely to a lack of financial resources or homelessness.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A parent, family member, household member, or other person who has permanent or temporary care or custody or responsibility for the supervision of a minor may not neglect the minor.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A person who violates this section is guilty of the misdemeanor of child neglect and on conviction is subject to imprisonment not exceeding 5 years or a fine not exceeding $5,000 or both.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A sentence imposed under this section shall be in addition to any other sentence imposed for a conviction arising from the same facts and circumstances unless the evidence required to prove each crime is substantially identical.</section>
  </text>
</law>
