<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcr" order_by="gcr" level="1">Criminal Law</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcr-5-612</section_number>
  <catch_line>A person may not manufacture, distribute, dispense, or possess:...</catch_line>
  <order_by>612</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">A person may not manufacture, distribute, dispense, or possess:<section prefix="(1)">50 pounds or more of marijuana;</section><section prefix="(2)">448 grams or more of cocaine;</section><section prefix="(3)">448 grams or more of any mixture containing a detectable amount of cocaine;</section><section prefix="(4)">50 grams or more of cocaine base, commonly known as "crack";</section><section prefix="(5)">28 grams or more of morphine or opium or any derivative, salt, isomer, or salt of an isomer of morphine or opium;</section><section prefix="(6)">any mixture containing 28 grams or more of morphine or opium or any derivative, salt, isomer, or salt of an isomer of morphine or opium;</section><section prefix="(7)">1,000 dosage units or more of lysergic acid diethylamide;</section><section prefix="(8)">any mixture containing the equivalent of 1,000 dosage units of lysergic acid diethylamide;</section><section prefix="(9)">16 ounces or more of phencyclidine in liquid form;</section><section prefix="(10)">448 grams or more of any mixture containing phencyclidine;</section><section prefix="(11)">448 grams or more of methamphetamine; or</section><section prefix="(12)">any mixture containing 448 grams or more of methamphetamine.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">For the purpose of determining the quantity of a controlled dangerous substance involved in individual acts of manufacturing, distributing, dispensing, or possessing under subsection (a) of this section, the acts may be aggregated if each of the acts occurred within a 90-day period.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A person who is convicted of a violation of subsection (a) of this section shall be sentenced to imprisonment for not less than 5 years and is subject to a fine not exceeding $100,000.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The court may not suspend any part of the mandatory minimum sentence of 5 years.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Except as provided in &#xA7; 4-305 of the Correctional Services Article, the person is not eligible for parole during the mandatory minimum sentence.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
