<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcr" order_by="gcr" level="1">Criminal Law</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcr-2-103</section_number>
  <catch_line>For purposes of a prosecution under this title, "viable" has the meaning stated in &#xA7; 20-209 of the ...</catch_line>
  <order_by>103</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">For purposes of a prosecution under this title, "viable" has the meaning stated in &#xA7; 20-209 of the Health - General Article.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Except as provided in subsections (d) through (f) of this section, a prosecution may be instituted for murder or manslaughter of a viable fetus.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A person prosecuted for murder or manslaughter as provided in subsection (b) of this section must have:<section prefix="(1)">intended to cause the death of the viable fetus;</section><section prefix="(2)">intended to cause serious physical injury to the viable fetus; or</section><section prefix="(3)">wantonly or recklessly disregarded the likelihood that the person's actions would cause the death of or serious physical injury to the viable fetus.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Nothing in this section applies to or infringes on a woman's right to terminate a pregnancy as stated in &#xA7; 20-209 of the Health - General Article.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">Nothing in this section subjects a physician or other licensed medical professional to liability for fetal death that occurs in the course of administering lawful medical care.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">Nothing in this section applies to an act or failure to act of a pregnant woman with regard to her own fetus.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">Nothing in this section shall be construed to confer personhood or any rights on the fetus.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">The commission of first degree murder of a viable fetus under this section, in conjunction with the commission of another first degree murder arising out of the same incident, does not constitute an aggravating circumstance subjecting a defendant to the death penalty under &#xA7; 2-303(g)(ix) of this title.</section>
  </text>
</law>
