<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcr" order_by="" level="1">Criminal Law</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcr-13-403</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>403</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">"Qualified member" means a person who:<section prefix="(1)">obtained a membership in an organization in accordance with the charter and bylaws of the organization; and</section><section prefix="(2)">has been a member for at least 12 months immediately before the gaming event.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A gaming device that is used at a gaming event shall be operated:<section prefix="(1)">by qualified members of the organization or qualified members of other organizations allowed to operate gaming devices under this section; and</section><section prefix="(2)">without the assistance of professional gaming device operators.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A person may not receive compensation from an organization for managing or operating a gaming device at a gaming event.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Another organization that operates a gaming device under this subtitle may receive compensation from an organization for managing or operating a gaming device at a gaming event.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Each organization conducting a gaming event shall submit to the Department of Inspections and Permits, in a manner determined by the county, a report under oath for each gaming event that provides:<section prefix="(1)">an accounting of all funds received; and</section><section prefix="(2)">a listing of the names, addresses, ages, and dates of membership of each individual who managed or operated a gaming device at the gaming event, including a statement that the individual is a qualified member of the organization.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">This section may not be construed to:<section prefix="(1)">limit or restrict the authority of the county to regulate, license, and designate the type of amusement or gaming devices that may be operated in the county; or</section><section prefix="(2)">amend or apply to the laws pertaining to raffles in the county under &#xA7; 13-405 of this subtitle.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
