<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcr" order_by="" level="1">Criminal Law</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcr-7-301</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>301</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Code grabbing device" means a device that is capable of:<section prefix="(i)">receiving and recording the coded signal transmitted by an electronic security system; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">playing back the coded signal to disarm the electronic security system.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Electronic security system" includes:<section prefix="(i)">an electronic home security system;</section><section prefix="(ii)">a motor vehicle security alarm system;</section><section prefix="(iii)">an automatic garage door opener;</section><section prefix="(iv)">a home detention monitoring device; and</section><section prefix="(v)">an electronic or magnetic theft detection device used in a retail establishment.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A person may not manufacture, sell, use, or possess a code grabbing device with the intent that the code grabbing device be used in the commission of a crime.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A person may not knowingly possess a device intended to shield merchandise from detection by an electronic security system with the intent to commit theft.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A person may not knowingly possess a tool or device designed to allow the deactivation or removal from any merchandise an electronic security system or a device used as part of an electronic security system with the intent to:<section prefix="(1)">use the tool or device to deactivate any electronic security system; or</section><section prefix="(2)">remove any electronic security system or device used as part of an electronic security system from any merchandise without the permission of the merchant or person owning or lawfully holding the merchandise.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">A person who violates this section is guilty of a misdemeanor and on conviction is subject to imprisonment not exceeding 1 year or a fine not exceeding $1,000 or both.</section>
  </text>
</law>
