<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gcr" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="8-302" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcr-8-302</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, "offer for sale" includes to induce, solicit, attempt, or advertise in a manner intended to encourage a person to purchase an identification card.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Subject to subsection (c) of this section, a person may not:<section prefix="(1)">sell, issue, offer for sale, or offer to issue an identification card or document that contains:<section prefix="(i)">a blank space for a person's age or date of birth; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">a person's incorrect age or date of birth; or</section></section><section prefix="(2)">knowingly sell, issue, offer for sale, or offer to issue an identification card or document that contains:<section prefix="(i)">an incorrect name instead of a person's true name; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">an incorrect address for a person.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">This section does not prohibit a manufacturer of identification cards or documents from selling or issuing identification cards or documents that contain a blank space for a person's age or date of birth to:<section prefix="(1)">employers, for use as employee identification cards or documents;</section><section prefix="(2)">hospitals, for use as patient identification cards; or</section><section prefix="(3)">governmental units.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A person who violates this section is guilty of a misdemeanor and on conviction is subject to imprisonment not exceeding 2 years or a fine not exceeding $2,000 or both.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Each identification card or document sold or issued and each offer in violation of this section is a crime that may be separately prosecuted.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The Attorney General, or the State's Attorney for a county where a violation of this section occurs, may seek an injunction to stop a sale, issue, or offer that violates this section.</section>
  </text>
</law>
