<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcr" order_by="gcr" level="1">Criminal Law</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcr-5-804</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this section, "administrative probable cause" means a valid public interest in the effective enfo...</catch_line>
  <order_by>804</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, "administrative probable cause" means a valid public interest in the effective enforcement of this title or regulations sufficient to justify administrative inspection of the area, premises, building, or conveyance in the circumstances specified in the application for the administrative inspection warrant.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">On showing of administrative probable cause, a judge of the State may issue an administrative inspection warrant to conduct:<section prefix="(1)">administrative inspections authorized by this title; and</section><section prefix="(2)">seizures of property appropriate to the inspections.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">An administrative inspection warrant shall issue only on an affidavit:<section prefix="(i)">of a designated officer or employee with knowledge of the facts alleged;</section><section prefix="(ii)">that is sworn to before the judge; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">that establishes the grounds for issuing the warrant.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If the judge is satisfied that grounds for the application exist or that there is administrative probable cause to believe they exist, the judge shall issue an administrative inspection warrant that identifies:<section prefix="(i)">the area, premises, building, or conveyance to be inspected;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the purpose of the inspection; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">where appropriate, the type of property to be inspected.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The warrant shall be directed to a person authorized to execute it.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The warrant shall:<section prefix="(i)">identify the item or type of property to be seized;</section><section prefix="(ii)">state the grounds for its issuance and the name of the affiant;</section><section prefix="(iii)">require the person to whom the warrant is directed to inspect the area, premises, building, or conveyance identified for the specified purpose;</section><section prefix="(iv)">require, where appropriate, the seizure of the specified property;</section><section prefix="(v)">require that the warrant be served during normal business hours; and</section><section prefix="(vi)">designate the judge to whom the warrant is to be returned.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">An administrative inspection warrant issued in accordance with this section shall be executed and returned within 10 days after its date.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If property is seized in accordance with an administrative inspection warrant, the person who executes the warrant:<section prefix="(i)">shall give to the person from whom or from whose premises the property was taken a copy of the warrant and a receipt for the property taken; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">shall leave the copy and receipt at the place from which the property was taken.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The warrant shall be returned promptly and be accompanied by a written inventory of any property taken.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The inventory shall be made in the presence of the person executing the warrant and:<section prefix="(i)">the person from whose possession or premises the property was taken; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">if that person is not present, at least one other credible person.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(5)">On request, the judge shall deliver a copy of the inventory to:<section prefix="(i)">the person from whom or from whose premises the property was taken; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">the applicant for the warrant.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(6)">A judge who issues an administrative inspection warrant under this section shall:<section prefix="(i)">attach to the warrant a copy of the return and all papers filed in connection with the return; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">file them with the clerk of the court from which the warrant was issued.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
