<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gcr" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="12-106" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcr-12-106</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Notwithstanding any other provision of this subtitle, Subtitle 2 of this title, or Title 13 of this article and except as otherwise provided in this subsection, a bona fide charitable organization in this State may conduct a raffle for the exclusive benefit of the charitable organization if the prize awarded is real property:<section prefix="(i)">to which the charitable organization holds title; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">for which the charitable organization has the ability to convey title.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A charitable organization may not conduct more than two raffles of real property in a calendar year.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Secretary of State may adopt regulations governing a raffle of real property by a charitable organization under this subsection.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Notwithstanding any other provision of this article and except as otherwise provided in this subsection, a political committee or candidate for public office may conduct a raffle if the prizes awarded are money or merchandise.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The cost of a raffle ticket under this subsection may not exceed $5.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">An individual may not purchase more than $50 worth of tickets.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">This subsection does not relieve a political committee or candidate from the reporting and record keeping requirements under the Election Law Article.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Notwithstanding any other provision of this article, a credit union organized under Title 6 of the Financial Institutions Article may conduct a savings promotion raffle under &#xA7; 6-716 of the Financial Institutions Article.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Notwithstanding any other provision of this article, a depository institution, as defined in &#xA7; 1-211 of the Financial Institutions Article, may conduct a savings promotion raffle under &#xA7; 1-211 of the Financial Institutions Article.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
