<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcr" order_by="gcr" level="1">Criminal Law</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcr-9-504</section_number>
  <catch_line>This section does not apply to a statement made or rumor circulated by an officer, employee, or agen...</catch_line>
  <order_by>504</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">This section does not apply to a statement made or rumor circulated by an officer, employee, or agent of a bona fide civilian defense organization or unit, if made in the regular course of the person's duties.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A person may not circulate or transmit to another, with intent that it be acted on, a statement or rumor that the person knows to be false about the location or possible detonation of a destructive device or the location or possible release of toxic material, as those terms are defined in &#xA7; 4-501 of this article.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A person who violates this section is guilty of a felony and on conviction is subject to imprisonment not exceeding 10 years or a fine not exceeding $10,000 or both.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A crime under this section committed using a telephone or other electronic means may be prosecuted:<section prefix="(1)">in the county in which the communication originated; or</section><section prefix="(2)">in the county in which the communication was received.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In addition to the penalty provided in subsection (c) of this section, a court may order a person convicted or found to have committed a delinquent act under this section to pay restitution to:<section prefix="(i)">the State, county, municipal corporation, bicounty unit, multicounty unit, county board of education, public authority, or special taxing district for actual costs reasonably incurred in responding to a location and searching for a destructive device as a result of a violation of this section; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">the owner or tenant of a property for the actual value of any goods, services, or income lost as a result of the evacuation of the property as a result of a violation of this section.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">This subsection may not be construed to limit the right of a person to restitution under Title 11, Subtitle 6 of the Criminal Procedure Article.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">If the person convicted or found to have committed a delinquent act under this section is a minor, the court may order the minor, the minor's parent, or both to pay the restitution described in paragraph (1) of this subsection.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">Except as otherwise provided in this section, the provisions of Title 11, Subtitle 6 of the Criminal Procedure Article apply to an order of restitution under this paragraph.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">In addition to any other penalty authorized by law, if the person convicted or found to have committed a delinquent act under this section is a minor, the court may order the Motor Vehicle Administration to initiate an action, under the motor vehicle laws, to suspend the driving privilege of the minor for a specified period not to exceed:<section prefix="(1)">for a first violation, 6 months; and</section><section prefix="(2)">for each subsequent violation, 1 year or until the person is 21 years old, whichever is longer.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
