<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcr" order_by="" level="1">Criminal Law</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcr-8-522</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>522</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">This section applies to a simulated document even if the document contains a statement that it is not legal process or a government document.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A person may not use, sell, or send or deliver to another, with the intent to induce the payment of a claim, a document that:<section prefix="(i)">simulates a summons, complaint, or other court process of any kind; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">implies that the person is a part of or associated with a unit of the federal government or a unit of the State or a county or municipal government.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">With intent to induce the payment of a claim, a person may not use a seal, insignia, envelope, or any other form that simulates the seal, insignia, envelope, or form of any governmental unit.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A person who violates this section is guilty of a misdemeanor and on conviction is subject to a fine not exceeding:<section prefix="(1)">$100 for the first violation; and</section><section prefix="(2)">$500 for each subsequent violation.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">This section does not prohibit the printing, publication, or distribution of genuine court or legal process forms in blank.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">Proof that the document was mailed or delivered to any person with the intent that it be forwarded to the intended recipient is sufficient proof of sending.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">A person who has been charged with a violation of this section may be prosecuted in the county in which the simulated document was used, sold, sent, or delivered.</section>
  </text>
</law>
