<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gcr" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="13-2504" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcr-13-2504</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In accordance with paragraph (2) of this subsection, a principal officer of a licensee shall file a report under oath with the sheriff on the form that the sheriff provides.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">A licensee that is issued a license for a period of less than 1 year shall file the report within 15 days after the date that the license expires.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">A licensee that is issued a license for a period of 1 year shall file:</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">A licensee also shall keep a weekly report in the form that the sheriff requires.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The weekly report shall be completed under oath.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">The weekly report is subject to audit at a reasonable hour by:</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The report that a licensee submits to the sheriff shall:<section prefix="(1)">state whether the authorized activities were conducted:<section prefix="(i)">on the dates and at the location stated in the application; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">by the regular members of the licensee without the assistance of gaming professionals;</section></section><section prefix="(2)">report the amount of the proceeds obtained from the licensed activities;</section><section prefix="(3)">report the disbursements made in connection with the licensed activities; and</section><section prefix="(4)">state that the licensee has not paid a fee for the rental of premises on which the game was conducted to:<section prefix="(i)">itself;</section><section prefix="(ii)">a trustee of the licensee;</section><section prefix="(iii)">a committee of the licensee; or</section><section prefix="(iv)">any organization with the same members or substantially the same members as the licensee.</section></section></section>
  </text>
</law>
