<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcr" order_by="" level="1">Criminal Law</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcr-7-308</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>308</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Deliver" means to sell, rent, distribute, or circulate.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Performance" includes a live performance and a performance that is transmitted by wire, radio, or television.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">"Recorded article" means a phonograph record, disc, wire, tape, film, videocassette, or other article on which sounds are recorded or otherwise stored.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This subsection applies only to sound recordings initially fixed before February 15, 1972.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Except as otherwise provided in this section, a person may not knowingly transfer or cause to be transferred any sounds recorded on a recorded article to any other recorded article:<section prefix="(i)">with the intent to sell or cause to be sold for profit or used to promote the sale of any product; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">without the consent of the owner of the original fixation of sounds embodied in the master recorded article.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Except as otherwise provided in this section, a person may not knowingly deliver, offer for delivery, possess for delivery, cause to be delivered, cause to be offered for delivery, or cause to be possessed for delivery a recorded article or device:<section prefix="(1)">on which sounds have been transferred without the consent of the owner of the original fixation of sounds embodied in the master recorded article; or</section><section prefix="(2)">embodying a performance without the consent of the performer.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as otherwise provided in this section, a person may not knowingly transfer to or cause to be transferred to a recorded article on which sounds or images have been transferred or stored any performance:<section prefix="(i)">with the intent to sell or cause to be sold for profit or used to promote the sale of any product; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">without the consent of the performer.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A person may not knowingly deliver, offer for delivery, or possess for the purpose of delivery a recorded article on which sounds or images have been transferred or stored, unless the recorded article bears in a prominent place on its outside face or package:<section prefix="(i)">the actual name and street address of the transferor of the sounds or images; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">the actual name of the performer or group.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">Except in the lobby area of a motion picture theater, a person may not knowingly operate an audiovisual recording function of a device in a motion picture theater without the consent of the owner or lessee of the theater.</section>
  </text>
</law>
