<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcr" order_by="gcr" level="1">Criminal Law</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcr-5-404</section_number>
  <catch_line>Schedule III consists of each controlled dangerous substance:...</catch_line>
  <order_by>404</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Schedule III consists of each controlled dangerous substance:<section prefix="(1)">listed in this section;</section><section prefix="(2)">added to Schedule III by the Department under &#xA7; 5-202(b) of this title; or</section><section prefix="(3)">designated as a Schedule III controlled dangerous substance by the federal government unless the Department objects under &#xA7; 5-202(f) of this title.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Substances listed in Schedule III include:<section prefix="(i)">nalorphine; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, an anabolic steroid consisting of a material, compound, or preparation that includes:<section prefix="1.">boldenone;</section><section prefix="2.">chlorotestosterone;</section><section prefix="3.">clostebol;</section><section prefix="4.">dehydrochlormethyltestosterone;</section><section prefix="5.">dihydrotestosterone;</section><section prefix="6.">drostanolone;</section><section prefix="7.">ethylestroenol;</section><section prefix="8.">fluoxymesterone;</section><section prefix="9.">formobulone;</section><section prefix="10.">mesterolone;</section><section prefix="11.">methandienone;</section><section prefix="12.">methandranone;</section><section prefix="13.">methandriol;</section><section prefix="14.">methandrostenolone;</section><section prefix="15.">methenolone;</section><section prefix="16.">methyltestosterone;</section><section prefix="17.">mibolerone;</section><section prefix="18.">nandrolone;</section><section prefix="19.">norethandrolone;</section><section prefix="20.">oxandrolone;</section><section prefix="21.">oxymesterone;</section><section prefix="22.">oxymetholone;</section><section prefix="23.">stanolone;</section><section prefix="24.">stanozolol;</section><section prefix="25.">testolactone;</section><section prefix="26.">testosterone;</section><section prefix="27.">trenbolone; and</section><section prefix="28.">any isomer, ester, salt, or derivative of a substance listed in this paragraph.</section></section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The following substances are not included in Schedule III:<section prefix="(i)">an estrogen, progestin, or corticosteroid; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">a substance covered by paragraph (1) of this subsection if:<section prefix="1.">expressly intended for administration through implants to cattle or other nonhuman species; and</section><section prefix="2.">approved for that use by the Food and Drug Administration.</section></section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Unless listed in another schedule, a substance is listed in Schedule III if the substance includes a material, compound, mixture, or preparation that contains any quantity of the following substances having a stimulant effect on the central nervous system:<section prefix="(i)">benzphetamine;</section><section prefix="(ii)">chlorphentermine;</section><section prefix="(iii)">clortermine;</section><section prefix="(iv)">mazindol; and</section><section prefix="(v)">phendimetrazine.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Subject to paragraph (3) of this subsection, substances in Schedule III include:<section prefix="(i)">a salt of a substance listed in this subsection;</section><section prefix="(ii)">an optical, position, or geometric isomer of a substance listed in this subsection; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">a salt of an isomer of a substance listed in this subsection.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Unless listed in another schedule, a salt, isomer, or salt of an isomer described in paragraph (2) of this subsection may be included in Schedule III only if the existence of the salts, isomers, and salts of isomers is possible within the specific chemical designation.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Unless listed in another schedule, a substance is listed in Schedule III if the substance includes a material, compound, mixture, or preparation that contains any quantity of the following substances having a potential for abuse associated with a depressant effect on the central nervous system:<section prefix="(1)">except those substances that are specifically listed in other schedules, a substance that contains any quantity of a derivative of barbituric acid, or a salt of a derivative of a barbituric acid;</section><section prefix="(2)">chlorhexadol;</section><section prefix="(3)">glutethimide;</section><section prefix="(4)">lysergic acid;</section><section prefix="(5)">lysergic acid amide;</section><section prefix="(6)">methyprylon;</section><section prefix="(7)">pentazocine;</section><section prefix="(8)">sulfondiethylmethane;</section><section prefix="(9)">sulfonethylmethane; and</section><section prefix="(10)">sulfonmethane.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Substances listed in Schedule III include a material, compound, mixture, or preparation that contains limited quantities of any of these narcotic drugs or their salts:<section prefix="(i)">not more than 1.80 grams of codeine per 100 milliliters or not more than 90 milligrams per dosage unit, with an equal or greater quantity of an isoquinoline alkaloid of opium;</section><section prefix="(ii)">not more than 1.80 grams of codeine per 100 milliliters or not more than 90 milligrams per dosage unit, with one or more active, nonnarcotic ingredients in recognized therapeutic amounts;</section><section prefix="(iii)">not more than 300 milligrams of dihydrocodeinone per 100 milliliters or not more than 15 milligrams per dosage unit, with a fourfold or greater quantity of an isoquinoline alkaloid of opium;</section><section prefix="(iv)">not more than 300 milligrams of dihydrocodeinone per 100 milliliters or not more than 15 milligrams per dosage unit, with one or more active, nonnarcotic ingredients in recognized therapeutic amounts;</section><section prefix="(v)">not more than 1.80 grams of dihydrocodeine per 100 milliliters or not more than 90 milligrams per dosage unit, with one or more active, nonnarcotic ingredients in recognized therapeutic amounts;</section><section prefix="(vi)">not more than 300 milligrams of ethylmorphine per 100 milliliters or not more than 15 milligrams per dosage unit, with one or more active, nonnarcotic ingredients in recognized therapeutic amounts;</section><section prefix="(vii)">not more than 500 milligrams of opium per 100 milliliters or per 100 grams, or not more than 25 milligrams per dosage unit, with one or more active, nonnarcotic ingredients in recognized therapeutic amounts;</section><section prefix="(viii)">not more than 100 milligrams of opium per 100 milliliters or per 100 grams, or not more than 5 milligrams per dosage unit; and</section><section prefix="(ix)">not more than 50 milligrams of morphine per 100 milliliters or per 100 grams with one or more active, nonnarcotic ingredients in recognized therapeutic amounts.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Substances listed in Schedule III include a compound, mixture, or preparation or salt of a compound, mixture, or preparation and another active medicinal ingredient that is not listed in another schedule and that contains:<section prefix="(i)">amobarbital;</section><section prefix="(ii)">secobarbital; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">pentobarbital.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">If not combined with one or more active medicinal ingredients that are listed in another schedule, substances listed in Schedule III include a suppository dosage form or salt of a suppository dosage that contains:<section prefix="(i)">amobarbital;</section><section prefix="(ii)">secobarbital; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">pentobarbital.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">Substances listed in Schedule III include:<section prefix="(1)">dronabinol (synthetic) in sesame oil and encapsulated in a soft gelatin capsule in a U.S. Food and Drug Administration-approved product; and</section><section prefix="(2)">ketamine, its salts, isomers, and salts of isomers.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(g)">The Department may not add a substance to Schedule III under &#xA7; 5-202 of this title unless the Department finds:<section prefix="(1)">a potential for abuse of the substance that is less than that for the substances listed in Schedule I and Schedule II;</section><section prefix="(2)">well documented and approved medical use of the substance in the United States; and</section><section prefix="(3)">evidence that abuse of the substance may lead to moderate or low physical dependence or high psychological dependence.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
