<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcr" order_by="gcr" level="1">Criminal Law</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcr-13-503</section_number>
  <catch_line>Before an organization listed in subsection (b) of this section may operate a gaming event, the orga...</catch_line>
  <order_by>503</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Before an organization listed in subsection (b) of this section may operate a gaming event, the organization shall obtain a permit from the commissioner.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">An organization that meets the conditions of paragraph (2) of this subsection may conduct a gaming event for the benefit of any of the following listed organizations if the organization is a bona fide:<section prefix="(i)">religious organization;</section><section prefix="(ii)">fraternal organization;</section><section prefix="(iii)">civic organization;</section><section prefix="(iv)">veterans' hospital;</section><section prefix="(v)">amateur athletic organization in which all playing members are under the age of 18 years; or</section><section prefix="(vi)">charitable organization.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">An organization conducting a gaming event shall:<section prefix="(i)">be located in Baltimore City; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">spend a majority of the organization's funds in Baltimore City for:<section prefix="1.">fraternal purposes;</section><section prefix="2.">civic purposes;</section><section prefix="3.">purposes related to a veterans' hospital;</section><section prefix="4.">purposes related to amateur athletics; or</section><section prefix="5.">charitable purposes.</section></section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Before the commissioner may issue a permit, the commissioner shall review the character of the organization applying for the permit to ascertain that the organization meets the requirements of &#xA7;&#xA7; 13-503 through 13-505 of this subtitle.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The commissioner shall make any application for a permit and the action taken by the commissioner on that application a matter of public record.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The permit shall state that the gaming event shall be managed and operated personally only by members of the organization obtaining the permit.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The permit is not transferable.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">An organization conducting a gaming event in Baltimore City may not allow an individual or group of individuals to:<section prefix="(1)">benefit financially from the gaming event; or</section><section prefix="(2)">receive any of the proceeds of the gaming event for personal use or benefit.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
