<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcr" order_by="" level="1">Criminal Law</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcr-10-403</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>403</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">This section does not apply to:<section prefix="(1)">a person acting in the course of medical, archaeological, educational, or scientific study;</section><section prefix="(2)">a licensed mortician or other professional who transports human remains in the course of carrying out professional duties; or</section><section prefix="(3)">a person acting under the authority of:<section prefix="(i)">&#xA7; 10-402 of this subtitle; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">&#xA7; 4-215 or &#xA7; 5-408 of the Health - General Article.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A person may not knowingly sell, buy, or transport for sale or profit, or offer to buy, sell, or transport for sale or profit:<section prefix="(1)">unlawfully removed human remains; or</section><section prefix="(2)">an associated funerary object obtained in violation of &#xA7; 10-404 of this subtitle.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A person who violates this section is guilty of a misdemeanor and on conviction is subject to imprisonment not exceeding 1 year or a fine not exceeding $5,000 or both.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Maryland Historical Trust may appropriate all human remains and associated funerary objects obtained in violation of this subtitle for management, care, and administration until a determination of final disposition as provided by law.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">This section may not be construed to interfere with the normal operation and maintenance of a cemetery including:<section prefix="(1)">correction of improper burial siting; and</section><section prefix="(2)">moving the human remains within a cemetery with the consent of a person who qualifies as an heir as defined in &#xA7; 1-101 of the Estates and Trusts Article.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
