<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcr" order_by="" level="1">Criminal Law</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcr-9-601</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>601</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, "emergency" means a circumstance in which:<section prefix="(1)">an individual is or is reasonably believed by the person transmitting the communication to be in imminent danger of death or serious bodily harm; or</section><section prefix="(2)">property is in imminent danger of damage or destruction.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A person may not:<section prefix="(1)">knowingly, intentionally, or recklessly interrupt, disrupt, impede, or otherwise interfere with the transmission of a two-way radio communication made:<section prefix="(i)">to inform or inquire about an emergency; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">on a frequency commonly used or monitored by an emergency services organization; or</section></section><section prefix="(2)">transmit false information about an emergency on a two-way radio frequency commonly used or monitored by an emergency services organization.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A person who violates this section is guilty of a misdemeanor and on conviction is subject to imprisonment not exceeding 6 months or a fine not exceeding $1,000 or both.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A two-way radio and related equipment used in violation of this section is subject to seizure.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">On conviction of a violation of this section, any property seized under paragraph (1) of this subsection shall be forfeited to the State and no property right shall exist in the property.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Any property that is forfeited under paragraph (2) of this subsection shall be turned over to the Secretary of General Services, who may:<section prefix="(i)">order that the property be retained for official use of State units; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">otherwise dispose of the property as the Secretary considers appropriate.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
