<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcr" order_by="gcr" level="1">Criminal Law</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcr-13-2434</section_number>
  <catch_line>Before the agency takes action under &#xA7; 13-2433(a) of this subtitle, it shall give the person agains...</catch_line>
  <order_by>2434</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Before the agency takes action under &#xA7; 13-2433(a) of this subtitle, it shall give the person against whom the action is contemplated the opportunity for a hearing.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">If a hearing is requested, the county commissioners shall:<section prefix="(1)">give notice and hold the hearing in accordance with Title 10, Subtitle 2 of the State Government Article; or</section><section prefix="(2)">delegate to the Office of Administrative Hearings the authority to hold the hearing.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">If the county commissioners hold the hearing, the county commissioners may administer oaths in connection with the hearing.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If the Office of Administrative Hearings holds the hearing:<section prefix="(i)">the administrative law judge shall state on the record the conclusions of law and findings of fact; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">subject to paragraph (2) of this subsection, the determination of the administrative law judge is a final decision for purposes of judicial review in the same manner as a final decision in a contested case under &#xA7; 10-222 of the State Government Article.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">In an appeal of a decision of the administrative law judge:<section prefix="(i)">if the civil penalty is less than $5,000, judicial review of disputed issues of fact shall be confined to the record; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">if the civil penalty is $5,000 or more, judicial review shall be de novo.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">After notice, if the person against whom the action is contemplated:<section prefix="(1)">fails or refuses to appear, nevertheless the county commissioners may hear and determine the matter; or</section><section prefix="(2)">does not request a hearing, the county commissioners may impose a civil penalty without a hearing.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
