<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcr" order_by="" level="1">Criminal Law</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcr-4-402</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>402</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The presence of a machine gun in a room, boat, or vehicle is evidence of the possession or use of the machine gun by each person occupying the room, boat, or vehicle.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">This subtitle does not prohibit or interfere with:<section prefix="(1)">the manufacture, sale, and transportation of a machine gun for or to a military force or peace officer of the United States, a state, or a political subdivision of a state;</section><section prefix="(2)">the possession of a machine gun for a scientific purpose;</section><section prefix="(3)">the possession, as a curiosity, ornament, or keepsake, of a machine gun that cannot be used as a weapon;</section><section prefix="(4)">the possession of a machine gun for a purpose that is manifestly not aggressive or offensive; or</section><section prefix="(5)">the transportation of a lawfully possessed machine gun by a person who is carrying a court order requiring the surrender of the machine gun, if:<section prefix="(i)">the machine gun is unloaded;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the person has notified the law enforcement unit, barracks, or station that the machine gun is being transported in accordance with the court order; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">the person transports the machine gun directly to the law enforcement unit, barracks, or station.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A court may issue a warrant to search for and seize a machine gun possessed in violation of this subtitle under the same procedure as for issuance of a warrant for stolen property.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">On application by the State's Attorney, a court may order the confiscation or destruction of a legally seized machine gun or the transfer of the machine gun to a peace officer of the State or a political subdivision of the State.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
