<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcs" order_by="gcs" level="1">Correctional Services</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcs-3-809</section_number>
  <catch_line>The Commissioner, the Deputy Commissioner, the Assistant Commissioner for Operations, or the Assista...</catch_line>
  <order_by>809</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Commissioner, the Deputy Commissioner, the Assistant Commissioner for Operations, or the Assistant Commissioner for Administration may grant special leave within or outside of the State as provided under this section to an inmate who:<section prefix="(1)">is confined in a correctional facility in the Division;</section><section prefix="(2)">has been selected to participate in a prerelease program; and</section><section prefix="(3)">is within 3 months of the inmate's anticipated release.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Commissioner, the Deputy Commissioner, the Assistant Commissioner for Operations, or the Assistant Commissioner for Administration may grant special leave to an inmate:<section prefix="(1)">for an employment interview;</section><section prefix="(2)">as part of a prerelease program relating to employment; or</section><section prefix="(3)">to participate in a community treatment or educational program that will contribute to the inmate's rehabilitation.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Commissioner, the Deputy Commissioner, the Assistant Commissioner for Operations, or the Assistant Commissioner for Administration:<section prefix="(i)">may grant weekend leave to an inmate if:<section prefix="1.">the inmate has participated for at least 2 months in a prerelease program as authorized under this section; and</section><section prefix="2.">the inmate's direct Division supervisor in the prerelease program recommends the inmate for weekend leave; and</section></section><section prefix="(ii)">shall establish the terms and conditions of weekend leave, which may include the inmate's agreement to waive the right to contest extradition proceedings.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Weekend leave may not begin before 6 p.m. on Friday or end after 6 p.m. on the Sunday that immediately follows.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
