<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcs" order_by="" level="1">Correctional Services</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcs-10-901</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>901</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Appointing authority" has the meaning stated in &#xA7; 1-101 of the State Personnel and Pensions Article.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Correctional officer" means an employee of the Department working in a State correctional facility who serves in the classification of correctional officer I, II, sergeant, lieutenant, captain, or major, and includes:<section prefix="(1)">a correctional dietary officer;</section><section prefix="(2)">a correctional maintenance officer;</section><section prefix="(3)">a correctional laundry officer;</section><section prefix="(4)">a correctional recreation officer; and</section><section prefix="(5)">a correctional supply officer.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Hearing" means a proceeding during an investigation conducted by a hearing board to take testimony or receive other evidence, or a contested case proceeding before the Office of Administrative Hearings, elected by the correctional officer.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Hearing" does not include an interrogation at which no testimony is taken under oath.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"Hearing board" means a hearing board that is authorized under &#xA7; 10-908 of this subtitle to hold a hearing on a complaint against a correctional officer.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">"Internal Investigative Unit" means the Internal Investigative Unit established under &#xA7; 10-701 of this title.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">"Misconduct" means:<section prefix="(1)">engaging in intentional behavior, without justification, that injures another person, causes damage to property, or threatens the safety of the workplace;</section><section prefix="(2)">engaging in unjustifiably offensive conduct toward fellow employees, inmates, or the public;</section><section prefix="(3)">using excessive force in the treatment or care of an inmate;</section><section prefix="(4)">possessing or trafficking in contraband at a Department facility;</section><section prefix="(5)">being on duty while under the influence of alcohol or a controlled dangerous substance, or while engaged in the illegal use of a prescription drug;</section><section prefix="(6)">engaging in a social, personal, intimate, or sexual relationship with an inmate;</section><section prefix="(7)">stealing State property with a value of $300 or less;</section><section prefix="(8)">engaging in conduct involving dishonesty, fraud, deceit, misrepresentation, or illegality;</section><section prefix="(9)">willfully making a false official statement or report;</section><section prefix="(10)">violating a lawful order or failing to obey a lawful order given by a superior;</section><section prefix="(11)">engaging in any of the actions that are cause for automatic termination of employment under &#xA7; 11-105 of the State Personnel and Pensions Article; or</section><section prefix="(12)">committing any violation of the Department's Standards of Conduct.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
