<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcs" order_by="gcs" level="1">Correctional Services</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcs-6-208</section_number>
  <catch_line>The Interstate Commission shall meet and take such actions as are consistent with the provisions of ...</catch_line>
  <order_by>208</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Interstate Commission shall meet and take such actions as are consistent with the provisions of this Compact.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Except as otherwise provided in this Compact and unless a greater percentage is required by the bylaws, in order to constitute an act of the Interstate Commission, such act shall have been taken at a meeting of the Interstate Commission and shall have received an affirmative vote of a majority of the members present.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Each member of the Interstate Commission shall have the right and power to cast a vote to which that compacting state is entitled and to participate in the business and affairs of the Interstate Commission. A member shall vote in person on behalf of the state and shall not delegate a vote to another member state. However, a State Council shall appoint another authorized representative, in the absence of the Commissioners from that state, to cast a vote on behalf of the member state at a specified meeting. The bylaws may provide for members' participation in meetings by telephone or other means of telecommunication or electronic communication. Any voting conducted by telephone, or other means of telecommunication or electronic communication shall be subject to the same quorum requirements of meetings where members are present in person.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Interstate Commission shall meet at least once during each calendar year. The chairperson of the Interstate Commission may call additional meetings at any time and, upon the request of a majority of the members, shall call additional meetings.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The Interstate Commission's bylaws shall establish conditions and procedures under which the Interstate Commission shall make its information and official records available to the public for inspection or copying. The Interstate Commission may exempt from disclosure any information or official records to the extent they would adversely affect personal privacy rights or proprietary interests. In promulgating such rules, the Interstate Commission may make available to law enforcement agencies records and information otherwise exempt from disclosure, and may enter into agreements with law enforcement agencies to receive or exchange information or records subject to nondisclosure and confidentiality provisions.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Public notice shall be given of all meetings and all meetings shall be open to the public, except as set forth in the rules or as otherwise provided in the Compact. The Interstate Commission shall promulgate rules consistent with the principles contained in the "Government in Sunshine Act", 5 U.S.C. Section 552b, as may be amended. The Interstate Commission and any of its committees may close a meeting to the public where it determines by two-thirds vote that an open meeting would be likely to:<section prefix="(i)">Relate solely to the Interstate Commission's internal personnel practices and procedures;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Disclose matters specifically exempted from disclosure by statute;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Disclose trade secrets or commercial or financial information which is privileged or confidential;</section><section prefix="(iv)">Involve accusing any person of a crime or formally censuring any person;</section><section prefix="(v)">Disclose information of a personal nature where disclosure would constitute a clearly unwarranted invasion of personal privacy;</section><section prefix="(vi)">Disclose investigatory records compiled for law enforcement purposes;</section><section prefix="(vii)">Disclose information contained in or related to examination, operating or condition reports prepared by, or on behalf of or for the use of, the Interstate Commission with respect to a regulated entity for the purpose of regulation or supervision of such entity;</section><section prefix="(viii)">Disclose information, the premature disclosure of which would significantly endanger the life of a person or the stability of a regulated entity; and</section><section prefix="(ix)">Specifically relate to the Interstate Commission's issuance of a subpoena or its participation in a civil action or proceeding.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">For every meeting closed pursuant to this subsection, the Interstate Commission's chief legal officer shall publicly certify that, in the chief legal officer's opinion, the meeting may be closed to the public, and shall reference each relevant exemptive provision. The Interstate Commission shall keep minutes which shall fully and clearly describe all matters discussed in any meeting and shall provide a full and accurate summary of any actions taken, and the reasons therefor, including a description of each of the views expressed on any item and the record of any roll call vote (reflected in the vote of each member on the question). All documents considered in connection with any action shall be identified in such minutes.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">The Interstate Commission shall collect standardized data concerning the interstate movement of offenders as directed through its bylaws and rules which shall specify the data to be collected, the means of collection, and data exchange and reporting requirements.</section>
  </text>
</law>
