<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gcs" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="3-602" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcs-3-602</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Except as otherwise provided in this subtitle, the contents of a case record maintained under &#xA7; 3-601 of this subtitle may not be disclosed.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The contents of a case record may be disclosed:<section prefix="(1)">if the record is necessary to ensure proper medical treatment, to a provider of medical services to the inmate;</section><section prefix="(2)">to the inmate's attorney;</section><section prefix="(3)">to a person authorized by a court order;</section><section prefix="(4)">to a person expressly authorized by law;</section><section prefix="(5)">to a judge of a State court;</section><section prefix="(6)">to a State's Attorney;</section><section prefix="(7)">to an employee of any State unit or a federal or local law enforcement unit, if disclosure is in furtherance of the employee's lawful duties; and</section><section prefix="(8)">on written request, to a person who has written authorization for the disclosure from the inmate.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Except for a disclosure under subsection (b)(5) or (6) of this section, an inmate's case record may be disclosed only if the managing official of the correctional facility:<section prefix="(1)">approves the disclosure; and</section><section prefix="(2)">is satisfied that:<section prefix="(i)">each applicable condition set forth in subsection (b) of this section has been met;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the record will be used solely for the legitimate purposes of the person or governmental unit that receives it and not for any improper or unauthorized purpose; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">the record will not be further disseminated to a person or governmental unit not authorized to receive it.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Commissioner shall adopt regulations in accordance with this section to establish procedures that govern the disclosure of an inmate's case record.</section>
  </text>
</law>
