<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcs" order_by="gcs" level="1">Correctional Services</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcs-10-701</section_number>
  <catch_line>There is an Internal Investigative Unit in the Department....</catch_line>
  <order_by>701</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">There is an Internal Investigative Unit in the Department.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Secretary shall appoint the Director of the Internal Investigative Unit.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Subject to the authority of the Secretary, the Internal Investigative Unit shall:<section prefix="(i)">investigate:<section prefix="1.">alleged criminal violations committed by employees of the Department while on duty;</section><section prefix="2.">alleged criminal violations committed by inmates, visitors, and other individuals that affect the safety or security of the Department's facilities or programs; and</section><section prefix="3.">alleged professional misconduct by employees of the Department; and</section></section><section prefix="(ii)">adopt regulations for the conduct of its investigations.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">An investigator in the Internal Investigative Unit may exercise the powers of a peace or police officer in the State on property that is owned, leased, operated by, or under the control of the Department.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">An investigator in the Internal Investigative Unit may exercise the powers of a peace or police officer in the State on property that is not owned, leased, operated by, or under the control of the Department when:<section prefix="(i)">engaged in fresh pursuit of a suspected offender;</section><section prefix="(ii)">requested or authorized to do so by the chief executive officer or chief police officer of a county;</section><section prefix="(iii)">necessary to facilitate the orderly flow of traffic to and from property owned, leased, operated by, or under the control of the Department;</section><section prefix="(iv)">necessary to investigate and protect property that is owned, leased, operated by, or under the control of the Department;</section><section prefix="(v)">engaged in an active and official investigation of the conduct of an employee of the Department when the employee's alleged conduct will compromise the safety or security of the Department's facilities or programs;</section><section prefix="(vi)">engaged in an active and official investigation of an inmate in the custody of the Commissioner of Correction or the Commissioner of Pretrial Detention and Services, an inmate subject to the jurisdiction of the Patuxent Institution, or an individual sentenced to probation or released on parole or mandatory supervision; or</section><section prefix="(vii)">ordered to do so by the Governor.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">When acting under the authority granted in this subsection in connection with an investigation or enforcement action, the Internal Investigative Unit shall notify the following persons:<section prefix="(i)">when in an incorporated municipality, the chief of police, if any, or the chief's designee;</section><section prefix="(ii)">when in a county that has a county police department, the chief of police or the chief's designee;</section><section prefix="(iii)">when in a county without a police department, the sheriff or the sheriff's designee;</section><section prefix="(iv)">when in Baltimore City, the Police Commissioner or the Police Commissioner's designee;</section><section prefix="(v)">when on any property owned, leased, operated by, or under the control of the Department of Natural Resources, the Secretary of Natural Resources or the Secretary's designee;</section><section prefix="(vi)">when on any property owned, leased, operated by, or under the control of the Maryland Transportation Authority, the Maryland Aviation Administration, or the Maryland Port Administration, the respective chief of police or the chief's designee; and</section><section prefix="(vii)">unless there is an agreement otherwise with the Department of State Police, the Department of State Police barrack commander or designee.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The notification required under paragraph (2) of this subsection shall be made:<section prefix="(i)">in advance, if practicable; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">if advance notification is not practicable, as soon as possible after the exercise of the powers.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">When acting under the authority granted in this subsection, a member of the Internal Investigative Unit shall have all the immunities from liability and exemptions as that of a State Police officer in addition to any other immunities and exemptions to which the member may otherwise be entitled.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">A member of the Internal Investigative Unit who uses the authority granted in this subsection shall at all times and for all purposes remain an employee of the Internal Investigative Unit.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">An individual who is employed as an investigator in the Internal Investigative Unit shall meet the minimum qualifications required and satisfactorily complete the training prescribed by the Maryland Police Training Commission.</section>
  </text>
</law>
