<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gcs" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="8-406" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcs-8-406</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The appropriate officer of the jurisdiction in which an untried indictment, information, or complaint is pending shall be entitled to have the prisoner against whom the officer has lodged a detainer and who is serving a term of imprisonment in any party state made available in accordance with &#xA7; 8-407(a) of this subtitle (Article V (a) of the Agreement) upon presentation of a written request for temporary custody or availability to the appropriate authorities of the state in which the prisoner is incarcerated; provided that the court having jurisdiction of the indictment, information, or complaint shall have duly approved, recorded, and transmitted the request; and provided further that there shall be a period of 30 days after receipt by the appropriate authorities before the request be honored, within which period the governor of the sending state may disapprove the request for temporary custody or availability either upon the governor's own motion or upon motion of the prisoner.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Upon receipt of the officer's written request as provided under subsection (a) of this section, the appropriate authorities having the prisoner in custody shall furnish the officer with a certificate stating the term of commitment under which the prisoner is being held, the time already served, the time remaining to be served on the sentence, the amount of good time earned, the time of parole eligibility of the prisoner, and any decisions of the state parole agency relating to the prisoner. The authorities simultaneously shall furnish all other officers and appropriate courts in the receiving state who have lodged detainers against the prisoner with similar certificates and with notices informing them of the request for custody or availability and of the reasons therefor.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">In respect of any proceeding made possible by this section (Article IV of the Agreement), trial shall be commenced within 120 days of the arrival of the prisoner in the receiving state, but for good cause shown in open court, the prisoner or the prisoner's counsel being present, the court having jurisdiction of the matter may grant any necessary or reasonable continuance.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Nothing contained in this section (Article IV of the Agreement) shall be construed to deprive any prisoner of any right that the prisoner may have to contest the legality of the prisoner's delivery under subsection (a) of this section, but the delivery may not be opposed or denied on the ground that the executive authority of the sending state has not affirmatively consented to or ordered the delivery.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">If trial is not had on any indictment, information, or complaint contemplated hereby prior to the prisoner's being returned to the original place of imprisonment under &#xA7; 8-407(e) of this subtitle (Article V (e) of the Agreement), the indictment, information, or complaint shall not be of any further force or effect, and the court shall enter an order dismissing the indictment, information, or complaint with prejudice.</section>
  </text>
</law>
