<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcs" order_by="gcs" level="1">Correctional Services</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcs-6-204</section_number>
  <catch_line>The compacting states hereby create the "Interstate Commission for Adult Offender Supervision". The ...</catch_line>
  <order_by>204</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The compacting states hereby create the "Interstate Commission for Adult Offender Supervision". The Interstate Commission shall be a body corporate and joint agency of the compacting states. The Interstate Commission shall have all the responsibilities, powers, and duties set forth herein, including the power to sue and be sued, and such additional powers as may be conferred upon it by subsequent action of the respective legislatures of the compacting states in accordance with the terms of this Compact.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Interstate Commission shall consist of commissioners selected and appointed by resident members of a State Council for Interstate Adult Offender Supervision for each state. In addition to the commissioners who are the voting representatives of each state, the Interstate Commission shall include individuals who are not commissioners but who are members of interested organizations; such noncommissioner members must include a member of the national organizations of governors, legislators, state chief justices, attorneys general, and crime victims. All noncommissioner members of the Interstate Commission shall be ex officio (nonvoting) members. The Interstate Commission may provide in its bylaws for such additional, ex officio, nonvoting members as it deems necessary.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Each compacting state represented at any meeting of the Interstate Commission is entitled to one vote. A majority of the compacting states shall constitute a quorum for the transaction of business, unless a larger quorum is required by the bylaws of the Interstate Commission. The Interstate Commission shall meet at least once each calendar year. The chairperson may call additional meetings and, upon the request of 27 or more compacting states, shall call additional meetings. Public notice shall be given of all meetings and meetings shall be open to the public.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Interstate Commission shall establish an Executive Committee which shall include Commission officers, members, and others as shall be determined by the bylaws. The Executive Committee shall have the power to act on behalf of the Interstate Commission during periods when the Interstate Commission is not in session, with the exception of rulemaking and/or amendment to the Compact.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The Executive Committee shall:<section prefix="(1)">Oversee the day-to-day activities managed by the Executive Director and Interstate Commission staff;</section><section prefix="(2)">Administer enforcement and compliance with the provisions of the Compact and its bylaws, as directed by the Interstate Commission; and</section><section prefix="(3)">Perform other duties as directed by the Commission or set forth in the bylaws.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
