<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gcs" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="11-104" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcs-11-104</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">This section applies except as provided in &#xA7; 11-105 of this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If a county or counties determine to construct or maintain a local correctional facility, the county or counties may apply to the Secretary for financial assistance for the construction or enlargement of the local correctional facility.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The applicant shall provide information in the form required by the Secretary, including:<section prefix="(i)">the program and plans for construction; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">the rehabilitation and training programs to be instituted.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">If the Secretary approves a construction plan under this section, the State shall pay the same share as that provided for jail construction or rehabilitation.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Secretary may receive a grant of funds from the federal government or any other public or private foundation or agency for the purposes designated in this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Subject to the provisions of paragraph (2) of this subsection, if a county that maintains, operates, or participates in a local correctional facility provides for improvements to the local correctional facility that are required as the result of the adoption of mandatory or approved standards, the Board of Public Works shall make provision for the State to pay 50% of the costs of the construction or improvements.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The plans and costs for construction or improvements under this section shall be subject to approval by:<section prefix="(i)">the Secretary;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the Division of Correction;</section><section prefix="(iii)">the Department of General Services; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">the Department of Budget and Management.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
