<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcs" order_by="" level="1">Correctional Services</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcs-11-313</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>313</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">If a center is operated by a county in accordance with &#xA7; 11-311(a) of this subtitle and the county is a charter county, the director and any assistant director shall be appointed and removed by the chief executive officer of the county government with the advice of the community advisory board and the advice and consent of the Commissioner.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Except as provided in subsection (e) of this section, if a center is operated by a county in accordance with &#xA7; 11-311(a) of this subtitle and the county is not a charter county subject to Article XI-A of the Maryland Constitution, the director and any assistant director shall be appointed and removed by the county commissioners with the advice of the community advisory board and the advice and consent of the Commissioner.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">If a center is a regional center operated by agreement of the counties in the region in accordance with &#xA7; 11-311(b) of this subtitle, the director and any assistant director shall be appointed and removed by the officials of the county governments in accordance with the regional agreement and with the advice of the community advisory board and the advice and consent of the Commissioner.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">If a center is operated by the State in accordance with &#xA7; 11-311(c) of this subtitle, the director and any assistant director shall be appointed and removed by the Commissioner with the advice of the community advisory board.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">If a center is operated by Cecil County:<section prefix="(1)">the Sheriff shall appoint a center director;</section><section prefix="(2)">the director serves at the pleasure of the Sheriff; and</section><section prefix="(3)">the Sheriff may remove the director at any time with or without cause.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
