<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcs" order_by="" level="1">Correctional Services</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcs-11-720</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>720</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">This section applies only in St. Mary's County.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Sheriff may establish:<section prefix="(i)">a home detention program; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">a work release program.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">If the Sheriff establishes a program under this section, the Sheriff shall adopt regulations necessary to implement each program established.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">If a condition that a court imposes on an inmate is inconsistent with a regulation adopted under this subsection, the condition imposed by the court controls as to that inmate.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">At the time of sentencing or at any time during an individual's confinement, the court may allow the individual to participate in any program established under this section if the individual:<section prefix="(i)">is sentenced to the custody of the Sheriff; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">has no other charges for a felony or a violation of a crime of violence as defined in &#xA7; 14-101 of the Criminal Law Article pending in any jurisdiction.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">An inmate who is participating in any program established under this section and who is sentenced to the St. Mary's County Detention Center may leave the detention center to:<section prefix="(i)">continue regular employment;</section><section prefix="(ii)">seek new employment; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">attend any court-ordered treatment appointments.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Sheriff and the Board of County Commissioners of St. Mary's County may charge an inmate participating in the work release program a reasonable monetary amount or program participation fee to pay for the costs incurred by the county for providing the inmate with food, lodging, and clothing.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If an inmate violates a trust or a condition that a court or Sheriff has established for participating in any program established under this section, the Sheriff or the Sheriff's designee shall notify the court in writing of the violation.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">An inmate who violates a trust or a condition that a court or Sheriff has established for participating in any program established under this section is subject to:<section prefix="(i)">removal from the program; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">cancellation of any earned diminution of the inmate's term of confinement.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
