<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcs" order_by="" level="1">Correctional Services</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcs-4-303</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>303</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Subject to &#xA7; 4-305 of this subtitle, inmates transferred to the Institution for treatment are eligible for the work release and leave of absence programs provided for in &#xA7;&#xA7; 3-801 through 3-806 and 3-808 through 3-811 of this article.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Board of Review shall perform the functions of the warden and the Commissioner under &#xA7;&#xA7; 3-801 through 3-806 and 3-808 through 3-811 of this article with respect to inmates confined in the Institution.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Board of Review may not grant an eligible person work release or leave under this section until the Board of Review mails written notice to the victim that the Board of Review intends to decide whether to grant work release or leave to the eligible person.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Before the Board of Review decides whether to grant work release or leave to an eligible person, the Board of Review shall give the victim a reasonable opportunity to comment in writing on work release or leave or to present oral testimony in the manner that the Board of Review establishes by regulation.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Board of Review promptly shall notify the victim of the decision of the Board of Review regarding work release or leave.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The victim may designate, in writing to the Board of Review, the name and address of a representative who is a resident of the State to receive notice for the victim.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">The Board of Review shall delete the victim's address and phone number from a document before the Board of Review allows examination of the document by the eligible person or the eligible person's representative.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
