<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gcs" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="10-801" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcs-10-801</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section:<section prefix="(1)">"contraband" means any item, material, substance, or other thing of value that:<section prefix="(i)">is not authorized for inmate possession by the Commissioner of Correction, the Director of Patuxent Institution, the Commissioner of Pretrial Detention and Services, or the warden of a State correctional facility; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">is brought into a State correctional facility in a manner prohibited by the Commissioner of Correction, the Director of Patuxent Institution, the Commissioner of Pretrial Detention and Services, or the warden of a State correctional facility.</section></section><section prefix="(2)">"contraband" includes any other property defined in regulations by the Commissioner of Correction, the Director of Patuxent Institution, or the Commissioner of Pretrial Detention and Services.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A State correctional facility shall hold for 30 days any personal property of an inmate that comes into the possession of any official or employee of the State correctional facility:<section prefix="(i)">as the result of an escape by the inmate; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">because the personal property has been unclaimed by an inmate who has the right to its possession.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">During the 30-day holding period, the State correctional facility shall post notice in a conspicuous location in the State correctional facility.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The State correctional facility shall deliver personal property being held by the State correctional facility to an inmate if:<section prefix="(i)">the property is claimed within the 30-day holding period;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the inmate satisfactorily establishes a right to possession of the property; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">the inmate gives a proper receipt for the property.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Commissioner of Correction, the Director of the Patuxent Institution, and the Commissioner of Pretrial Detention and Services shall adopt regulations:<section prefix="(i)">to define what property constitutes contraband in State correctional facilities;</section><section prefix="(ii)">to establish procedures for the confiscation of contraband by staff of State correctional facilities; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">to establish procedures governing hearings on the issue of forfeiture of confiscated property.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Except as provided in paragraph (3) of this subsection, an inmate whose property is confiscated as contraband shall be notified of the right to have the property removed from the State correctional facility or sent to a person outside the State correctional facility at the inmate's expense.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">If an inmate fails to have property removed from or sent outside the State correctional facility within 30 days after receipt of notice of confiscation, the property shall be deemed abandoned property under subsection (d)(2) and (3) of this section.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Property confiscated as contraband may be subject to forfeiture.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">Property may not be forfeited under subparagraph (i) of this paragraph, unless, prior to forfeiture, the State correctional facility provides notice to the inmate:</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">A hearing on a disciplinary infraction may include the adjudication of any issue of forfeiture of confiscated property.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Personal property that is unclaimed within the 30-day holding period established under subsection (b) of this section shall be deemed abandoned property.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Abandoned property may be sold, converted to the use of the Division of Correction, the Patuxent Institution, or the Division of Pretrial Detention and Services, or otherwise disposed of in accordance with procedures established by regulation.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">All claims to abandoned property are absolutely barred.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This section does not create or recognize any cause, action, or defense or abridge any immunity of the Department or any of its units, officials, or employees.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">This section does not affect the authority of State correctional facilities to seize and dispose of personal property that is contraband per se in accordance with applicable law without a hearing.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
