<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gcs" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="11-105" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcs-11-105</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">If the Secretary determines that the anticipated confinement of inmates who are serving sentences of more than 6 months but not exceeding 12 months in a county's local correctional facility would exceed the capacity of the local correctional facility, a county may apply to the Secretary for financial assistance for the construction of a new or enlarged existing local correctional facility.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">For the purpose of anticipating inmate confinement under subsection (a) of this section, the Secretary annually shall review and study each county's local correctional facility population in conjunction with data relevant to patterns of:<section prefix="(1)">sentencing;</section><section prefix="(2)">geographic distribution of inmates; and</section><section prefix="(3)">the rates of growth in the number of inmates sentenced to more than 6 months but not exceeding 12 months as compared to the number similarly sentenced before January 1, 1988.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Subject to the State budget appropriation process and in accordance with this section, if a county applies for financial assistance under subsection (a) of this section and a county's construction plan is approved by the Secretary under this section, the State shall pay 100% of the approved costs of acquisition, construction, architectural and engineering services, and capital equipment for:<section prefix="(i)">a new local correctional facility; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">enlargement of an existing local correctional facility.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If a county's construction plan is disapproved by the Secretary, the county may appeal to the Board of Public Works.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Subject to the State budget appropriation process, if a county applies for financial assistance under subsection (a) of this section and the Board of Public Works approves the construction plan, the State shall pay 100% of the approved costs of acquisition, construction, architectural and engineering services, and capital equipment for:<section prefix="(i)">a new local correctional facility; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">enlargement of an existing local correctional facility.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The plans and costs for construction or enlargement of a local correctional facility by a county under this section are subject to:<section prefix="(1)">the procedures followed by State units for requested capital projects; and</section><section prefix="(2)">approval by the Secretary.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
