<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcs" order_by="gcs" level="1">Correctional Services</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcs-11-903</section_number>
  <catch_line>Each fund is a special continuing, nonlapsing fund....</catch_line>
  <order_by>903</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Each fund is a special continuing, nonlapsing fund.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Each fund consists of:<section prefix="1.">profits derived from the sale of goods through the commissary operation and telephone and vending machine commissions; and</section><section prefix="2.">subject to subparagraph (ii) of this paragraph, money received from other sources.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">Money from the General Fund of the State or county, including any federal funds, may not be transferred by budget amendment or otherwise to a fund.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Except as provided in subparagraph (ii) of this paragraph, the chief financial officer for a county shall separately hold and shall account for each fund in the county.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The chief financial officer for Dorchester County or the managing official of the local correctional facility as designated by Dorchester County shall separately hold and shall account for each fund in Dorchester County.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(4)">This section may not be construed to:<section prefix="(i)">prohibit a periodic or special audit by the State, the federal government, or a county that provides funds for a local correctional facility; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">affect the calculation of reimbursement rates, as provided in &#xA7; 9-403 of this article.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Each fund shall be invested and reinvested in the same manner as other county funds.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Any investment earnings of a fund shall be credited to the fund.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
