<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gcs" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="10-601" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcs-10-601</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">As used in this section, "facility" means a correctional facility of any kind for adults or juveniles.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Another state may not begin construction or otherwise locate a facility in this State unless the other state submits a written request for approval to construct or locate the facility to and receives approval from:<section prefix="(1)">the Secretary of Public Safety and Correctional Services, in the case of a facility for adults; or</section><section prefix="(2)">the Secretary of Juvenile Services, in the case of a facility for juveniles.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Secretary of Public Safety and Correctional Services may approve or disapprove a request for approval to construct or locate a facility for adults in this State.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Secretary of Juvenile Services may approve or disapprove a request for approval to construct or locate a facility for juveniles in this State.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Approval or disapproval shall be:<section prefix="(i)">after consultation with the Governor, the governing body of the county in which the facility will be located, and the community in which the facility will be located; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">in accordance with applicable standards concerning the location of facilities.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">If another state has an existing facility in this State, the other state may not increase the inmate population of that facility by more than 5% unless the other state first submits a written request for the increase to and receives approval for the increase from:<section prefix="(1)">the Secretary of Public Safety and Correctional Services, in the case of a facility for adults; or</section><section prefix="(2)">the Secretary of Juvenile Services, in the case of a facility for juveniles.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
