<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcs" order_by="" level="1">Correctional Services</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcs-8-201</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>201</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Approved correctional training school" means a school authorized by the Commission to offer training programs as provided under this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Commission" means the Correctional Training Commission.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">"Correctional administrator" means a correctional officer who has been promoted from a supervisory rank to first-line administrative duties.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Correctional officer" means a member of a correctional unit whose duties relate to the investigation, care, custody, control, or supervision of inmates and individuals who:<section prefix="(i)">have been placed on parole or mandatory supervision;</section><section prefix="(ii)">have been placed on probation; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">have received a suspended sentence.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Correctional officer" does not include:<section prefix="(i)">the head or deputy head of a correctional unit; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">a sheriff, warden, or superintendent or an individual with an equivalent title who is appointed or employed by a unit of government to exercise equivalent supervisory authority.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">"Correctional supervisor" means a correctional officer who has been promoted to first-line supervisory duties.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Correctional unit" means a unit of State, county, or municipal government that is responsible under a statute, ordinance, or court order for the investigation, care, custody, control, and supervision of inmates and individuals who:<section prefix="(i)">have been placed on parole or mandatory supervision;</section><section prefix="(ii)">have been placed on probation; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">have received a suspended sentence.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Correctional unit" includes those facilities as set forth in &#xA7; 9-226 of the Human Services Article and other facilities as designated by the Secretary of Juvenile Services.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(h)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Department of Juvenile Services employee" means a youth supervisor, youth counselor, direct care worker, or other employee of the Department of Juvenile Services whose employment responsibility is the investigation, custody, control, or supervision of minors, juvenile delinquents, and youthful offenders who are committed, detained, awaiting placement, adjudicated delinquent, or are otherwise under the supervision of the Department of Juvenile Services.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Department of Juvenile Services employee" includes an employee of any nonprofit or for-profit entity under contract with the Department of Juvenile Services whose employment responsibility is the investigation, custody, control, or supervision of minors, juvenile delinquents, and youthful offenders as described under paragraph (1) of this subsection.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(i)">"Permanent appointment" means an appointment that has permanent status.</section>
  </text>
</law>
