<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gcs" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="11-203" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcs-11-203</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The managing official of a local correctional facility shall provide to an inmate in the custody of the managing official:<section prefix="(i)">food and board; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">any article of comfort that is considered necessary for a sick inmate by the physician attending the inmate.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Except as provided in &#xA7;&#xA7; 11-204 and 11-205 of this subtitle and subject to subsections (b), (c), and (d) of this section, the county shall pay the costs associated with food, board, and articles of comfort provided to inmates under paragraph (1) of this subsection.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">An inmate in a local correctional facility who is sick, injured, or disabled shall:<section prefix="(1)">reimburse the county, as appropriate, for the payment of medical expenses; and</section><section prefix="(2)">provide the managing official with any information relating to:<section prefix="(i)">the existence of any health insurance, group health plan, or prepaid medical care coverage under which the inmate is insured or covered;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the inmate's eligibility for benefits under the Maryland Medical Assistance Program;</section><section prefix="(iii)">the name and address of any third party payor; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">any policy or other identifying number relating to items (i) through (iii) of this item.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In addition to obtaining any reimbursement authorized under subsection (b) of this section and subject to paragraph (4) of this subsection, the governing body of each county shall establish a reasonable fee, not to exceed $4, for each visit by an inmate in a local correctional facility to an institutional medical unit or noninstitutional physician, dentist, or optometrist.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The per visit fee shall be deducted from an inmate's spending financial account, reserve financial account, or similar account held by the managing official on behalf of the inmate.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The fees collected under this subsection shall be deposited in the general fund of the county.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">This subsection does not apply to a visit by an inmate to a medical unit or a physician, dentist, or optometrist if the visit is:<section prefix="(i)">required as a part of the intake process;</section><section prefix="(ii)">required for an initial physical examination;</section><section prefix="(iii)">due to a referral by a nurse or physician's assistant;</section><section prefix="(iv)">provided during a follow-up visit that is initiated by a medical professional from the local correctional facility;</section><section prefix="(v)">initiated by a medical or mental health staff member of the local correctional facility; or</section><section prefix="(vi)">required for necessary treatment.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Subsections (b) and (c) of this section do not impose liability for reimbursement or payment of medical expenses on any person other than an inmate personally or through a person that provides insurance, coverage, or other benefits described under subsection (b) of this section.</section>
  </text>
</law>
