<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcs" order_by="gcs" level="1">Correctional Services</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcs-9-601</section_number>
  <catch_line>If a representation is made to the managing official of a correctional facility in the Department th...</catch_line>
  <order_by>601</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">If a representation is made to the managing official of a correctional facility in the Department that an inmate in the correctional facility is pregnant and about to give birth, the managing official:<section prefix="(1)">a reasonable time before the anticipated birth, shall make an investigation; and</section><section prefix="(2)">if the facts require, shall recommend through the Maryland Parole Commission that the Governor exercise executive clemency.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Without notice, the Governor may:<section prefix="(1)">parole the inmate;</section><section prefix="(2)">commute the inmate's sentence; or</section><section prefix="(3)">suspend the execution of the inmate's sentence for a definite period or from time to time.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">If the Governor suspends the execution of an inmate's sentence, the managing official of the correctional facility:<section prefix="(1)">a reasonable time before the anticipated birth, shall have the inmate transferred from the correctional facility to another facility that provides comfortable accommodations, maintenance, and medical care under supervision and safeguards that the managing official determines necessary to prevent the inmate's escape from custody; and</section><section prefix="(2)">shall require the inmate to be returned to the correctional facility as soon after giving birth as the inmate's health allows.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The expenses of an inmate's accommodation, maintenance, and medical care incurred as a result of the inmate's transfer under subsection (c)(1) of this section shall be paid:<section prefix="(i)">by the inmate;</section><section prefix="(ii)">by relatives or friends of the inmate; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">from any available fund that may be used to pay the hospital expenses of an inmate in the correctional facility.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If money is not available under any of the sources identified in paragraph (1) of this subsection to pay the specified expenses:<section prefix="(i)">the county from which the inmate was committed is responsible for payment of the expenses; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">the managing official of the correctional facility to which the inmate was committed shall collect payment in accordance with Title 16 of the Health - General Article.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">After receiving proof from the father or other relative of the child of the ability to properly care for the child, the Department may order that the father or other relative take custody of the child.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The father or other relative of the child that receives custody under paragraph (1) of this subsection shall maintain and care for the child at the father's or other relative's expense until the inmate is released from the correctional facility or the child, as provided by law, is adopted.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">If the father or other relative of the child is unable to properly maintain and care for the child, the Department shall place the child in the care of the Department of Human Resources.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">Notwithstanding any other provision of this section, the Department may allow an inmate to participate in programming and to retain custody of the newborn child in or out of custody if:<section prefix="(1)">the environment and program is consistent with the best interests of the child and consistent with public safety; and</section><section prefix="(2)">the custody is not inconsistent with the parental rights of any individual who is not detained or confined in a correctional facility.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
