<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gcs" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="6-203" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcs-6-203</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">As used in this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated, unless the context clearly requires a different construction.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Adult" means both individuals legally classified as adults and juveniles treated as adults by court order, statute, or operation of law.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Bylaws" means those bylaws established by the Interstate Commission for its governance, or for directing or controlling the Interstate Commission's actions or conduct.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">"Compact Administrator" means the individual in each compacting state appointed pursuant to the terms of this Compact responsible for the administration and management of the state's supervision and transfer of offenders subject to the terms of this Compact, the rules adopted by the Interstate Commission, and policies adopted by the State Council under this Compact.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"Compacting state" means any state which has enacted the enabling legislation for this Compact.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">"Commissioner" means the voting representative of each compacting state appointed pursuant to Article III of this Compact.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">"Interstate Commission" means the Interstate Commission for Adult Offender Supervision established by this Compact.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">"Member" means the commissioner of a compacting state or designee, who shall be a person officially connected with the commissioner.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">"Noncompacting state" means any state which has not enacted the enabling legislation for this Compact.</section>
    <section prefix="(j)">"Offender" means an adult placed under, or subject to, supervision as the result of the commission of a criminal offense and released to the community under the jurisdiction of courts, paroling authorities, corrections, or other criminal justice agencies.</section>
    <section prefix="(k)">"Person" means any individual, corporation, business enterprise, or other legal entity, either public or private.</section>
    <section prefix="(l)">"Rules" means acts of the Interstate Commission, duly promulgated pursuant to Article VIII of this Compact, substantially affecting interested parties in addition to the Interstate Commission, which shall have the force and effect of law in the compacting states.</section>
    <section prefix="(m)">"State" means a state of the United States, the District of Columbia, and any other territorial possessions of the United States.</section>
    <section prefix="(n)">"State Council" means the resident members of the State Council for Interstate Adult Offender Supervision created by each state under Article III of this Compact.</section>
  </text>
</law>
