<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcs" order_by="" level="1">Correctional Services</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcs-8-502</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>502</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">This section applies whenever the Division of Correction, the Patuxent Institution, or any local correctional facility receives notice of an untried indictment, information, warrant, or complaint against an inmate who:<section prefix="(1)">in the case of the Division of Correction, is serving a sentence in a correctional facility in the Division of Correction;</section><section prefix="(2)">in the case of the Patuxent Institution, is confined at the Patuxent Institution; or</section><section prefix="(3)">in the case of a local correctional facility, is serving a sentence in the local correctional facility.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">An inmate shall be brought to trial within 120 days after the inmate has delivered a written request for a final disposition of the indictment, information, warrant, or complaint to:<section prefix="(1)">the State's Attorney of the county in which the indictment, information, warrant, or complaint is pending; and</section><section prefix="(2)">the appropriate court.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The request for final disposition required under subsection (b) of this section shall be accompanied by a statement from the managing official having immediate supervision over the inmate setting forth:<section prefix="(1)">the inmate's term of confinement;</section><section prefix="(2)">the time already served;</section><section prefix="(3)">the time remaining to be served;</section><section prefix="(4)">the amount of diminution credits awarded for good conduct;</section><section prefix="(5)">the date of parole eligibility for the inmate; and</section><section prefix="(6)">the most recent decision of the Maryland Parole Commission or the Board of Review of the Patuxent Institution relating to the inmate.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">For good cause shown in open court, with the inmate or the inmate's counsel present, the court having jurisdiction of the matter may grant any necessary or reasonable continuance.</section>
  </text>
</law>
