<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcs" order_by="gcs" level="1">Correctional Services</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcs-7-309</section_number>
  <catch_line>This section applies to any inmate who is sentenced to a term of incarceration for which all sentenc...</catch_line>
  <order_by>309</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">This section applies to any inmate who is sentenced to a term of incarceration for which all sentences being served, including any life sentence, are with the possibility of parole.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">An inmate who is so debilitated or incapacitated by a medical or mental health condition, disease, or syndrome as to be physically incapable of presenting a danger to society may be released on medical parole at any time during the term of that inmate's sentence, without regard to the eligibility standards specified in &#xA7; 7-301 of this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A request for a medical parole under this section may be filed with the Maryland Parole Commission by:<section prefix="(i)">the inmate seeking the medical parole;</section><section prefix="(ii)">an attorney;</section><section prefix="(iii)">a prison official or employee;</section><section prefix="(iv)">a medical professional;</section><section prefix="(v)">a family member; or</section><section prefix="(vi)">any other person.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The request shall be in writing and shall articulate the grounds that support the appropriateness of granting the medical parole.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Following review of the request, the Commission may:<section prefix="(1)">find the request to be inconsistent with the best interests of public safety and take no further action; or</section><section prefix="(2)">request that department or local correctional facility personnel provide information for formal consideration of parole release.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The information to be considered by the Commission before granting medical parole shall, at a minimum, include:<section prefix="(1)">the inmate's medical information, including:<section prefix="(i)">a description of the inmate's condition, disease, or syndrome;</section><section prefix="(ii)">a prognosis concerning the likelihood of recovery from the condition, disease, or syndrome;</section><section prefix="(iii)">a description of the inmate's physical incapacity and score on the Karnofsky Performance Scale Index or similar classification of physical impairment; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">a mental health evaluation, where relevant;</section></section><section prefix="(2)">discharge information, including:<section prefix="(i)">availability of treatment or professional services within the community;</section><section prefix="(ii)">family support within the community; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">housing availability, including hospital or hospice care; and</section></section><section prefix="(3)">case management information, including:<section prefix="(i)">the circumstances of the current offense;</section><section prefix="(ii)">institutional history;</section><section prefix="(iii)">pending charges, sentences and other jurisdictions, and any other detainers; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">criminal history information.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The Commission may require as a condition of release on medical parole that:<section prefix="(1)">the parolee agree to placement for a definite or indefinite period of time in a hospital or hospice or other housing accommodation suitable to the parolee's medical condition, including the family home of the parolee, as specified by the Commission or the supervising agent; and</section><section prefix="(2)">the parolee forward authentic copies of applicable medical records to indicate that the particular medical condition giving rise to the release continues to exist.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If the Commission has reason to believe that a parolee is no longer so debilitated or incapacitated as to be physically incapable of presenting a danger to society, the parolee shall be returned to the custody of the Division of Correction or the local correctional facility from which the inmate was released.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">A parole hearing for a parolee returned to custody shall be held to consider whether the parolee remains incapacitated and shall be heard promptly.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">A parolee returned to custody under this subsection shall be maintained in custody, if the incapacitation is found to no longer exist.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">An inmate whose medical parole is revoked for lack of continued incapacitation may be considered for parole in accordance with the eligibility requirements specified in &#xA7; 7-301 of this subtitle.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(h)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Subject to paragraph (2) of this subsection, provisions of law relating to victim notification and opportunity to be heard shall apply to proceedings relating to medical parole.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">In cases of imminent death, time limits relating to victim notification and opportunity to be heard may be waived in the discretion of the Commission.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(i)">Consistent with &#xA7; 7-301(d)(4) of this subtitle, a medical parole under this section for a person serving a life sentence shall require the approval of the Governor.</section>
    <section prefix="(j)">The Commission shall issue regulations to implement the provisions of this section.</section>
  </text>
</law>
