<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gcs" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="10-913" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcs-10-913</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">This subtitle does not prohibit emergency suspension with pay by a correctional officer of higher rank as designated by the appointing authority.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The appointing authority may impose emergency suspension with pay if it appears that the action is in the best interest of the inmates, the public, and the correctional facility.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If the correctional officer is suspended with pay, the appointing authority may suspend the correctional powers of the correctional officer and reassign the correctional officer to restricted duties pending:<section prefix="(i)">a determination by a court with respect to a criminal violation; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">a final determination by the hearing board or the Office of Administrative Hearings with respect to a correctional facility violation.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A correctional officer who is suspended under this subsection is entitled to a prompt hearing.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If a correctional officer is charged with a felony, the appointing authority may impose an emergency suspension of correctional powers without pay.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A correctional officer who is suspended under paragraph (1) of this subsection is entitled to a prompt hearing, held no more than 90 days after the suspension.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Except as provided in paragraph (4) of this subsection, a correctional officer who is suspended under paragraph (1) of this subsection and who is not convicted of the felony for which the suspension was imposed shall have:<section prefix="(i)">the suspension rescinded; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">any lost time, compensation, status, and benefits restored.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">Paragraph (3) of this subsection does not apply to a correctional officer who:<section prefix="(i)">resigns before the disposition of the criminal matter for which the suspension was imposed; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">is no longer employed by the Department when a determination is made by a court with respect to the criminal matter for which the suspension was imposed.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
