<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gcs" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="11-723" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcs-11-723</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">This section applies only in Washington County.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Sheriff shall:<section prefix="(i)">establish and administer:</section><section prefix="(ii)">adopt regulations necessary to implement each program established under this section.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">At the time of sentencing or at any time during an individual's confinement, the court may allow an individual who is placed in the custody of the Sheriff to participate in any program established under this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Subject to paragraph (4) of this subsection, an inmate is eligible to participate in any program established under this section if the inmate:<section prefix="(i)">is recommended for the program by the court; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">meets eligibility criteria set by the Sheriff.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">An inmate is not eligible to participate in any program established under this section if the inmate:<section prefix="(i)">is incarcerated for or has been convicted previously of a crime of violence listed in &#xA7; 14-101 of the Criminal Law Article; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">has been found guilty of the crime of:</section></section>
      <section prefix="(5)">While participating in any program established under this section an inmate is responsible for:<section prefix="(i)">the inmate's medical care and related expenses; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">costs of lodging, food, clothing, transportation, restitution, and taxes.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(6)">The Sheriff may:<section prefix="(i)">collect a reasonable fee from each inmate participating in any program established under this section; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">waive or reduce the fee.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(7)">The Sheriff may determine the maximum number of inmates that may participate in any program established under this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(8)">An inmate who knowingly violates a term or a condition of any program established under this section is subject to the penalties provided under &#xA7; 11-726 of this subtitle and to other disciplinary action provided by law.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
