<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gcs" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="10-905" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcs-10-905</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The investigation or interrogation by the appointing authority or by the Internal Investigative Unit of a correctional officer for a reason that may lead to disciplinary action, demotion, or dismissal shall be conducted in accordance with this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The investigating officer or interrogating officer shall be a member of the Internal Investigative Unit or a designee of the appointing authority.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">At least 24 hours before an interrogation, the correctional officer under investigation shall be informed of the name, rank, and command of:<section prefix="(i)">the person in charge of the investigation;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the interrogating officer; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">each individual who will be present during the interrogation.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">At least 24 hours before an interrogation, the correctional officer under investigation shall be informed in writing by the appointing authority of:<section prefix="(i)">the nature of the investigation; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">the correctional officer's rights under this subtitle.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">If the correctional officer under interrogation is under arrest, or is likely to be placed under arrest as a result of the interrogation, the correctional officer shall be informed completely of the correctional officer's constitutional rights before the interrogation begins.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">Unless the seriousness of the investigation is of a degree that an immediate interrogation is required, the interrogation shall be conducted at a reasonable hour, preferably when the correctional officer is on duty.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The interrogation shall take place at:<section prefix="(1)">the appointing authority's office;</section><section prefix="(2)">the appointing authority's conference room; or</section><section prefix="(3)">another reasonable and appropriate place.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">All questions directed to the correctional officer under interrogation shall be asked by one person during any one session of interrogation.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Each session of interrogation shall allow for personal necessities and rest periods as reasonably necessary.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(h)">The correctional officer under interrogation may not be threatened with criminal prosecution, transfer, dismissal, or disciplinary action.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If requested by or on behalf of the correctional officer under investigation, the correctional officer may not be questioned or interrogated, and any current questioning or interrogation must cease, unless:<section prefix="(i)"/><section prefix="(ii)">the legal counsel or the agent selected by the correctional officer is present and available for consultation at all times during the interrogation.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Subject to subparagraph (ii) of this paragraph, if representation is not available, the interrogation shall be suspended until representation is obtained.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">A suspension of interrogation under subparagraph (i) of this paragraph may not exceed 10 days unless the appointing authority, for good cause shown, extends the period for obtaining representation.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">During the interrogation, the correctional officer's counsel or representative may:<section prefix="(i)">request a recess at any time to consult with the correctional officer;</section><section prefix="(ii)">object to any question posed; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">state on the record outside the presence of the correctional officer the reason for the objection.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(j)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A complete record shall be kept of the entire interrogation, including all recess periods.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The record shall be made by electronic equipment or by a stenographer.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">On completion of the investigation, and on request of the correctional officer or the correctional officer's counsel or representative, a copy of the record of the interrogation shall be provided within 5 days of the request.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(k)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The person assigned to conduct the investigation may order the correctional officer under investigation to submit to blood alcohol tests, blood, breath, or urine tests for controlled dangerous substances, polygraph examinations, or interrogations that specifically relate to the subject matter of the investigation.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If the correctional officer is ordered to submit to a test, examination, or interrogation described in paragraph (1) of this subsection and the correctional officer refuses to do so, the appointing authority may commence an action that may lead to discipline as a result of the refusal.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">If a correctional officer is ordered to submit to a test, examination, or interrogation described in paragraph (1) of this subsection, the results of the test, examination, or interrogation are not admissible or discoverable in a criminal proceeding against the correctional officer.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(l)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If the correctional officer is ordered to submit to a polygraph examination, the results of the polygraph examination may not be used as evidence in a hearing board or an administrative hearing unless the appointing authority and the correctional officer agree to the admission of the results.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The correctional officer's counsel or representative need not be present during the actual administration of a polygraph examination by a certified polygrapher if:<section prefix="(i)">the questions to be asked are reviewed with the correctional officer or the counsel or representative before the administration of the examination;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the counsel or representative is allowed to observe the administration of the examination; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">a copy of the final report of the examination by the certified polygrapher is made available to the correctional officer or the counsel or representative within a reasonable time, not exceeding 10 days, after completion of the examination.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(m)">On completion of an investigation and at least 20 days before a hearing, the correctional officer under investigation shall be:<section prefix="(1)">notified of the name of each witness and of each charge and specification against the correctional officer; and</section><section prefix="(2)">provided with a copy of the investigatory file and any exculpatory information, if the correctional officer and the correctional officer's counsel or representative agree to execute a confidentiality agreement with the appointing authority or the Internal Investigative Unit not to disclose any material contained in the investigatory file or exculpatory information for any purpose other than to defend the correctional officer.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(n)">A person may not insert adverse material into a file of the correctional officer, except the file of the Internal Investigative Unit, unless the correctional officer has an opportunity to review, sign, receive a copy of, and comment in writing on the adverse material.</section>
  </text>
</law>
