<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcs" order_by="" level="1">Correctional Services</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcs-3-810</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>810</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">On the recommendation of treatment staff and with the approval of the managing official of a correctional facility in the Division, the Commissioner or Deputy Commissioner may grant special leave to an inmate to allow an inmate to participate in a special community or other meritorious program or activity within or outside of the State that the Commissioner and managing official believe:<section prefix="(1)">would benefit the inmate;</section><section prefix="(2)">would not be detrimental to the public; and</section><section prefix="(3)">would help rehabilitate the inmate.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Commissioner or Deputy Commissioner may grant special leave for the purpose of allowing an inmate to:<section prefix="(1)">attend an educational program;</section><section prefix="(2)">improve job skills;</section><section prefix="(3)">attend a trade licensing examination;</section><section prefix="(4)">be interviewed for employment;</section><section prefix="(5)">participate as a volunteer for a governmental unit in an activity that serves the general public;</section><section prefix="(6)">participate in athletic competition;</section><section prefix="(7)">participate in a civic activity that benefits the inmate or the community; or</section><section prefix="(8)">participate in a residential or nonresidential treatment program including a program for pregnant women or a program to establish bonding between mothers and newborn children.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">An inmate granted leave under this section may be allowed to remain outside the institution for any period of time consistent with public safety.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">An inmate is not eligible for special leave under this section unless the managing official and Commissioner concur that positive attitudinal and growth patterns are being established.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Special leave shall be issued in writing and signed personally by both the managing official and either the Commissioner or Deputy Commissioner.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">As a condition of granting special leave, the Commissioner may require that the inmate agree to waive the right to contest extradition proceedings.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The Commissioner or Deputy Commissioner shall file the order granting special leave in the Division.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
