<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcs" order_by="" level="1">Correctional Services</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcs-7-702</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>702</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, "supervisee" means an individual supervised by the Division of Parole and Probation for the Commission.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Unless a supervisee is exempted by the Commission under subsection (d) of this section, the Commission shall assess a monthly fee of $50 as a condition of supervision for each supervisee.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The fee assessed under subsection (b) of this section shall be paid to the Division of Parole and Probation.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Division of Parole and Probation shall pay all money collected under this section into the General Fund of the State.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Commission may exempt a supervisee wholly or partly from the fee assessed under subsection (b) of this section if:<section prefix="(1)">the supervisee has diligently attempted but has been unable to obtain employment that provides sufficient income for the supervisee to pay the fee;</section><section prefix="(2)"><section prefix="(i)">the supervisee is a student in a school, college, or university or is enrolled in a course of vocational or technical training designed to prepare the supervisee for gainful employment; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">the institution in which the supervisee is enrolled supplies certification of student status to the Commission;</section></section><section prefix="(3)">the supervisee has a disability that limits possible employment, as determined by a physical or psychological examination that the Commission accepts or orders;</section><section prefix="(4)">the supervisee is responsible for the support of dependents and the payment of the fee constitutes an undue hardship on the supervisee; or</section><section prefix="(5)">other extenuating circumstances exist.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The fee assessed under subsection (b) of this section is in addition to court costs and fines.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If a supervisee does not comply with the fee requirement:<section prefix="(i)">the Division of Parole and Probation shall notify the Commission; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">the Commission may revoke parole or mandatory supervision.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Commission shall conduct a hearing to determine if there are sufficient grounds to find the supervisee in violation of the fee requirement.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">At a hearing under this subsection, the Commission may consider:<section prefix="(i)">any material change in the supervisee's financial status;</section><section prefix="(ii)">good faith efforts of the supervisee to pay the fee; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">alternative means to assure payment of the fee before the period of supervision ends.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In addition to the fee assessed under subsection (b) of this section, the Division of Parole and Probation may require a supervisee to pay for drug or alcohol abuse testing that the Commission orders.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If a supervisee fails to pay for drug or alcohol abuse testing as required by the Division of Parole and Probation, the Commission may revoke parole or mandatory supervision.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">If the Division of Parole and Probation determines that any of the criteria specified in subsection (d) of this section are applicable, the Division may exempt a supervisee wholly or partly from a payment for drug or alcohol abuse testing.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(h)">The Division of Parole and Probation shall:<section prefix="(1)">adopt guidelines for collecting the supervision fee;</section><section prefix="(2)">adopt guidelines for collecting the cost of drug and alcohol abuse testing; and</section><section prefix="(3)">investigate requests for an exemption from payment if the Commission requests an investigation.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(i)">The Division of Parole and Probation shall:<section prefix="(1)">keep records of all payments by each supervisee; and</section><section prefix="(2)">report delinquencies to the Commission.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(j)">On release of a supervisee, the Department and the appropriate local detention center shall provide the supervisee with an oral and a written notice that:<section prefix="(1)">states the criteria listed in subsection (d) of this section that the Commission may use in determining whether to exempt a supervisee from the supervision fee assessed under subsection (b) of this section; and</section><section prefix="(2)">explains the process of applying for an exemption from the supervision fee.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
