<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcs" order_by="" level="1">Correctional Services</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcs-3-516</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>516</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Except as authorized under subsection (b) of this section, goods and services of Maryland Correctional Enterprises may not be sold on the open market.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Goods and services of Maryland Correctional Enterprises may be sold on the open market:<section prefix="(1)">if they are produced or provided by an individual on parole or in a work release program;</section><section prefix="(2)">if the sale is made to a charitable, civic, educational, fraternal, or religious agency, association, or institution for its own use and not for resale within 1 year of the purchase;</section><section prefix="(3)">to a person for national defense purposes if not prohibited by an act of Congress;</section><section prefix="(4)">if they are surplus goods remaining after meeting the forecasted requirements of units of State government and political subdivisions and the goods remain unsold 1 year after being produced;</section><section prefix="(5)">for use by a contractor or subcontractor in performance of a contract with a unit of State government or any other governmental unit in the State;</section><section prefix="(6)">as allowed under the Private Sector/Prison Industry Enhancement Certification Program of the United States Department of Justice, Bureau of Justice Assistance; or</section><section prefix="(7)">if they are related to the preparation or distribution of food or services related to agriculture or seafood processing, when the following conditions are met:<section prefix="(i)">the State labor pools are diminished; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">it has been determined that inmate labor is the available source.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Secretary and the Secretary of Labor, Licensing, and Regulation shall adopt regulations that specify how to determine the need for inmate labor under subsection (b)(7) of this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Wages paid to inmates under subsection (b)(7) of this section may not be less than wages paid for similar work in the private sector of the same locality as determined by the Secretary of Labor, Licensing, and Regulation.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Inmate labor under subsection (b)(7) of this section applies only to inmates at the minimum, prerelease, and work release security levels.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
