<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcs" order_by="gcs" level="1">Correctional Services</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcs-11-702</section_number>
  <catch_line>This section applies only in Allegany County....</catch_line>
  <order_by>702</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">This section applies only in Allegany County.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Sheriff may:<section prefix="(i)">establish a pretrial release program that offers alternatives to pretrial detention; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">adopt regulations to administer the program.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A court may order an individual to participate in the pretrial release program if the individual:<section prefix="(i)">appears before the court after being charged and detained on bond; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">meets the eligibility requirements of paragraph (4) of this subsection.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The court may make the order at the imposition of bond, on review of bond, or any other time during the individual's pretrial detention.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">An individual is eligible for the pretrial release program if the individual:<section prefix="(i)">is recommended to the court for placement in the program by the program staff;</section><section prefix="(ii)">has no other charges pending in any jurisdiction; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">is not in detention for:<section prefix="1.">a crime of violence; or</section><section prefix="2.">the crime of escape under &#xA7; 9-404 of the Criminal Law Article.</section></section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Sheriff's Department may:<section prefix="(i)">establish and direct a work release program; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">adopt guidelines for the operation of the program.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">At the time of sentencing or at any time during an inmate's confinement, the sentencing judge may order that the inmate participate in the work release program, subject to the guidelines adopted by the Sheriff.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">If the sentencing judge is unable to act at the time of an inmate's petition for work release, another judge of the committing court may order that the inmate participate in the work release program.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">In ordering an inmate to participate in the work release program, the court may allow the inmate to leave actual confinement to:<section prefix="(i)">work at gainful, private employment;</section><section prefix="(ii)">seek gainful, private employment; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">participate in an educational, rehabilitative, or training program in the county.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">Unless the committing court directs otherwise, an inmate shall be confined in the detention center when not participating in the work release program.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The Sheriff or the Sheriff's designee shall collect the earnings of an inmate in the work release program, less payroll deductions required by law.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">From the earnings of the inmate, the Sheriff shall deduct and disburse:<section prefix="1.">an amount determined to be the cost to the county for food, lodging, and clothing for the inmate;</section><section prefix="2.">the actual cost of necessary food and travel and other expenses incidental to the inmate's participation in the program;</section><section prefix="3.">any amount a court imposes for a fine, cost, or restitution;</section><section prefix="4.">any amount that the inmate is legally obligated or reasonably desires to pay for support of a dependent; and</section><section prefix="5.">if applicable, any amount that a court orders the inmate to repay to the State or to the county for the services of an attorney appointed by the court.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">The Sheriff shall:<section prefix="1.">credit to the inmate's account the remaining balance; and</section><section prefix="2.">dispose of the balance in the inmate's account as the inmate reasonably requests and as the Sheriff approves.</section></section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(6)">If an inmate violates a trust or a condition that a judge or the Sheriff establishes for conduct or employment, after an administrative hearing that upholds the violation, the inmate is subject to:<section prefix="(i)">removal from the work release program; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">cancellation of any earned diminution of the inmate's term of confinement.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Sheriff shall:<section prefix="(i)">establish and administer a home detention program; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">adopt regulations for the program.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">At the time of sentencing or at any time during an individual's confinement, the sentencing judge may allow an individual who is convicted of a crime and sentenced to imprisonment to participate in the home detention program.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Subject to paragraph (4) of this subsection, an inmate is eligible for the home detention program if the inmate:<section prefix="(i)">is recommended for the program by the sentencing judge; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">has no other charges pending in any jurisdiction.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">An inmate is not eligible for the home detention program if the inmate:<section prefix="(i)">is serving a sentence for a crime of violence; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">has been found guilty of the crime of:<section prefix="1.">child abuse under &#xA7; 3-601 or &#xA7; 3-602 of the Criminal Law Article; or</section><section prefix="2.">escape under &#xA7; 9-404 of the Criminal Law Article.</section></section></section>
      <section prefix="(5)">While participating in the home detention program an inmate is responsible for:<section prefix="(i)">the inmate's medical care and related expenses; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">costs of lodging, food, clothing, transportation, restitution, and taxes.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(6)">The Sheriff may:<section prefix="(i)">collect a reasonable fee from each inmate participating in the home detention program; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">waive or reduce the fee.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(7)">The Sheriff may determine the maximum number of inmates that may participate in the home detention program.</section>
      <section prefix="(8)">An inmate who knowingly violates a term or a condition of the home detention program is subject to the penalties provided under &#xA7; 11-726 of this subtitle and other disciplinary action provided by law.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
