<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcs" order_by="gcs" level="1">Correctional Services</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcs-6-108</section_number>
  <catch_line>With the Secretary's approval, the Director may establish a home detention program under which an of...</catch_line>
  <order_by>108</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">With the Secretary's approval, the Director may establish a home detention program under which an offender may live in a private dwelling that the Director approves.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">An offender in the program shall be supervised by means of:<section prefix="(1)">electronic devices; and</section><section prefix="(2)">direct contact by employees of the Division.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">An offender is not eligible for the program if a violation of a condition of parole or mandatory supervision is based on the commission of a crime of violence.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">While in the program, an offender must remain in the offender's approved dwelling except:<section prefix="(1)">with the approval of the Director, to go directly to and from:<section prefix="(i)">the offender's approved place of employment;</section><section prefix="(ii)">a medical or mental health treatment facility; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">offices of the Department;</section></section><section prefix="(2)">as required by legitimate medical or other emergencies; or</section><section prefix="(3)">as otherwise allowed or directed by the Director.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">An offender in the program is responsible for all of the offender's living expenses, including those for food, clothing, medical care, shelter, and utilities.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Unless otherwise allowed by the Commission, as a condition of participation in the program, an offender shall make any court ordered payments for the support of dependents.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">After determining the amount of reasonable payments necessary to satisfy court ordered restitution, fines, court costs, and other fees that are legally collectible, the Division shall establish a reasonable fee for the cost of electronic monitoring and, except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, collect the fee from each offender in the program.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If the Division determines that an offender cannot afford to pay the fee established under paragraph (1) of this subsection, the Division may exempt the offender wholly or partly from the fee.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">An offender in the program is not an agent or employee of the Division.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">The Director shall employ parole and probation employees to supervise offenders in the program.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">The Commission may remove an offender from the program at any time and for any reason.</section>
    <section prefix="(j)">
      <section prefix="(1)">With the Secretary's approval, the Director shall adopt regulations to implement the program.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Notwithstanding &#xA7; 10-101(g)(2)(i) of the State Government Article, the regulations shall be adopted in accordance with the requirements of Title 10, Subtitle 1 of the State Government Article.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
