<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gcs" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="4-301" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcs-4-301</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Director may request that the Commissioner refer an inmate to the Institution for evaluation as to whether the inmate is an eligible person if the inmate:<section prefix="(i)">is serving a sentence of imprisonment following conviction of a crime;</section><section prefix="(ii)">has more than 3 years remaining to serve on a sentence;</section><section prefix="(iii)">has not been evaluated by or confined at the Institution within the preceding 3 years;</section><section prefix="(iv)">is not disqualified from being an eligible person under &#xA7; 4-101(e)(2) of this title; and</section><section prefix="(v)">meets the eligibility criteria that the Secretary establishes under &#xA7; 4-208(b) of this title.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The request that the Commissioner refer an inmate to the Institution shall be based:<section prefix="(i)">on recommendation of the sentencing court;</section><section prefix="(ii)">on application by the inmate or the State's Attorney of the county in which the inmate was last convicted; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">on the Commissioner's own initiative.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Commissioner shall promptly refer any inmate requested for evaluation by the Director unless the Commissioner determines that such a referral will constitute a security risk.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Within 6 months after an inmate is referred to the Institution, an evaluation team shall examine the inmate.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Before proceeding with the examination, the evaluation team shall assemble and review all available and relevant information about the inmate provided for in &#xA7; 4-209 of this title.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Based on the information reviewed under subsection (b)(2) of this section and an examination of the inmate, the evaluation team shall determine whether, in the opinion of a majority of the team, the inmate is an eligible person.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The evaluation team shall submit to the Director a written report that states its findings.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The report shall state in detail the reasoning supporting the team's conclusion with respect to each of the criteria for an eligible person set forth in &#xA7; 4-101(e) of this title.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
