<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gcs" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="4-209" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcs-4-209</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Institution shall compile and maintain a complete record of each inmate transferred to it for evaluation or treatment.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The record shall include the following materials to the extent that the materials are physically available and the inclusion is not prohibited by federal law:<section prefix="(1)">police reports and other relevant information concerning the crime of which the inmate was most recently convicted and the sentence imposed for that conviction;</section><section prefix="(2)">the inmate's criminal and juvenile history and all relevant records concerning this history;</section><section prefix="(3)">presentence investigation, parole, probation, and other reports concerning the inmate;</section><section prefix="(4)">school records;</section><section prefix="(5)">information concerning the inmate's medical and mental health history, including relevant medical and hospital records and reports; and</section><section prefix="(6)">all other relevant information, records, and reports concerning the inmate's social, physical, or mental condition and history.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Institution shall record a full and accurate description, including photographs, of each inmate transferred to the Institution for treatment.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Institution may adopt the Bertillon method or any other accurate method of description, measurement, and registration.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In order that the Institution may comply with this section, all State and local officials and units:<section prefix="(i)">shall cooperate with the Institution; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">promptly, on request of the Institution, shall furnish or cause to be furnished to the Institution the information, records, and reports in their possession.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The provisions of &#xA7; 3-8A-27(b) of the Courts Article do not apply to a request made for juvenile records under this section.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">To the extent that any record, report, or information compiled under this section is legally confidential, it shall remain confidential and may not be disclosed to any person or unit except to:<section prefix="(1)">the Commissioner or the Commissioner's authorized staff;</section><section prefix="(2)">the Division of Parole and Probation;</section><section prefix="(3)">the Maryland Parole Commission;</section><section prefix="(4)">a State's Attorney, when required in the prosecution or defense of a proceeding in court;</section><section prefix="(5)">a federal, State, or local law enforcement officer on a written request signed by an authorized commanding officer of the law enforcement unit certifying that the record, report, or information is needed for a pending investigation;</section><section prefix="(6)">an authorized correctional official or probation officer of:<section prefix="(i)">the United States; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">a state, if that jurisdiction has made reciprocal provision by law to furnish similar records, reports, or information to comparable officials of this State;</section></section><section prefix="(7)">the Attorney General;</section><section prefix="(8)">the Inmate Grievance Office, to the extent relevant to a matter pending before it and with the written consent of the inmate to whom the record, report, or information pertains;</section><section prefix="(9)">the Division of Rehabilitation Services of the Department of Education solely to determine if an inmate confined at the Institution qualifies for benefits provided by that Division;</section><section prefix="(10)">providers of medical care to the extent necessary to ensure proper medical treatment;</section><section prefix="(11)">a judge of a circuit court or the District Court when required in connection with a pretrial release, presentence, or postsentence investigation; and</section><section prefix="(12)">State, local, and federal units and private agencies to the extent that the release of the record, report, or information will benefit an eligible person but only with the written consent of the inmate to whom the record, report, or information pertains.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">Confidential records, reports, or information may be disclosed under subsection (e) of this section only if the Director reasonably believes that the record, report, or information:<section prefix="(1)">will be used solely for the legitimate purposes of the person or unit receiving it; and</section><section prefix="(2)">will not be further disseminated to any person or unit not authorized to receive it under subsection (e) of this section.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(g)">Juvenile records obtained under subsection (d) of this section may be disclosed only:<section prefix="(1)">to a person or unit listed in subsection (e)(1), (2), and (3) of this section; and</section><section prefix="(2)">in accordance with subsection (f) of this section.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
