<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gcs" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="7-801" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcs-7-801</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, "victim" means:<section prefix="(1)">an individual who suffers personal physical injury or death as a direct result of a crime;</section><section prefix="(2)">a victim of child abuse under &#xA7; 3-601 or &#xA7; 3-602 of the Criminal Law Article;</section><section prefix="(3)">a victim of a violent crime; or</section><section prefix="(4)">if the victim is deceased, disabled, or a minor, a designated family member or other representative of the victim.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">At least 90 days before an inmate's parole release hearing, the Department shall notify the victim or the victim's designated representative in writing, directed to the most current address on file, that the parole release hearing has been scheduled if:<section prefix="(i)">the victim or the victim's representative filed a notification request form under &#xA7; 11-104 of the Criminal Procedure Article; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">the victim makes a written request to the Department for notification and maintains a current address on file with the Department.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The victim may designate in writing to the Department the name and address of a representative who is a resident of the State to receive notice for the victim.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Not later than 30 days after the date of the Department's notice under subsection (b) of this section, the victim of a violent crime may submit to the Department a written request that the Division of Parole and Probation be required to complete an updated victim impact statement.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If the victim submits a request as authorized by paragraph (1) of this subsection, the Department shall direct the Division of Parole and Probation to:<section prefix="(i)">complete the updated statement at least 30 days before the parole release hearing; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">send promptly the updated victim impact statement to the Commission.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A victim may:<section prefix="(1)">at least 30 days before the parole release hearing:<section prefix="(i)">make a written recommendation to the Commission on the advisability of releasing the inmate on parole; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">request that the inmate be prohibited from having any contact with the victim as a condition of parole, mandatory supervision, work release, or other administrative release; and</section></section><section prefix="(2)">request a meeting with a commissioner.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The Commission shall make an updated victim impact statement and a victim's written recommendation available for review by the inmate or the inmate's representative under &#xA7; 7-303(b) of this title.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The Commission shall consider an updated victim impact statement or victim's written recommendation at the parole release hearing.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">If a victim requested an open hearing under &#xA7; 7-304 of this title, the victim may present oral testimony at the inmate's parole release hearing in a manner established in regulations adopted by the Commission.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">The Department shall notify promptly the victim or the victim's designated representative of the decision of the Commission regarding parole for the inmate.</section>
  </text>
</law>
