<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gcs" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="5-202" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcs-5-202</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">With the approval of the Governor, the Secretary shall appoint a Commissioner of Pretrial Detention and Services.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Commissioner serves at the pleasure of the Secretary.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Commissioner:<section prefix="(1)">has the same authority over the Division as this Code vests in the Commissioner of Correction over the Division of Correction;</section><section prefix="(2)">shall keep safely any inmate committed or transferred to the custody of the Commissioner until the inmate is discharged in accordance with law;</section><section prefix="(3)">is in charge of the Division, subject to the authority of the Secretary;</section><section prefix="(4)">is the appointing authority for all employees of the Division;</section><section prefix="(5)">shall establish a home detention program under terms and conditions that the Secretary provides;</section><section prefix="(6)">may enter agreements with the Commissioner of Correction and governmental units for the housing of any inmate held in the Baltimore City Detention Center;</section><section prefix="(7)">may enter agreements for the housing of any inmate committed to federal or local governmental units in the Baltimore City Detention Center; and</section><section prefix="(8)">may enter other agreements necessary to carry out the purposes of this title.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Subject to paragraph (2) of this subsection and notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Commissioner shall establish by regulation the terms and conditions of the home detention program required under subsection (c)(5) of this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The authority of a court to determine the conditions of pretrial release or to find that a defendant awaiting trial may not be placed on a home detention program may not be limited or superseded by:<section prefix="(i)">a regulation of the Division or Department; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">the Division or the Commissioner.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
