<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gcs" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="4-401" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcs-4-401</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, "Youth Program" means the Patuxent Institution Youth Program.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">There is a Patuxent Institution Youth Program.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">This section applies to an individual under the age of 21 years who is sentenced to a term of imprisonment of 3 years or more.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">At sentencing, a court may refer an individual to the Institution for evaluation.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The Director shall:<section prefix="(1)">review recommendations of a court for admission of an individual to the Youth Program; and</section><section prefix="(2)">admit or deny admission of an individual based on the criteria for admission established under subsection (j) of this section.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">An inmate's status in the Youth Program shall be reviewed by the Board of Review on an annual basis.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">The Board of Review may grant an inmate in the Youth Program leave, work or school release, or parole according to the same procedures and with the same notice to victims as required with respect to the eligible person program.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">If an individual is transferred to the Youth Program under this section, the duration of the transfer to the Institution shall terminate when:<section prefix="(1)">the Director orders the individual transferred to the Division of Correction;</section><section prefix="(2)">the Board of Review orders the individual transferred to the Division of Correction;</section><section prefix="(3)">with the approval of the Secretary, the Board of Review orders the individual paroled; or</section><section prefix="(4)">the individual completes the individual's term of confinement as provided by law.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(i)">An individual who is transferred to the Youth Program as provided under this section is deemed to be committed to the custody of and subject to the jurisdiction of the Institution.</section>
    <section prefix="(j)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Regulations adopted by the Secretary under &#xA7; 4-208 of this title shall include regulations governing the management and operation of the Youth Program, including criteria for admission to the Youth Program.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Regulations establishing criteria for admission to the Youth Program shall:<section prefix="(i)">be consistent with this title and any other statutory requirements; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">include criteria regarding:</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
