<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcs" order_by="gcs" level="1">Correctional Services</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcs-7-805</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this section, "victim" means an individual who suffers personal physical injury or death as a dir...</catch_line>
  <order_by>805</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, "victim" means an individual who suffers personal physical injury or death as a direct result of a crime or, if the victim is deceased, a designated family member of the victim.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">If the victim made a written request to the Department for notification and maintains a current address on file with the Department or the victim or the victim's representative filed a notification request form under &#xA7; 11-104 of the Criminal Procedure Article, the Department shall notify the victim or the victim's designated representative in writing that an inmate sentenced to the Division of Correction is being considered for a:<section prefix="(1)">commutation of sentence;</section><section prefix="(2)">pardon; or</section><section prefix="(3)">remission of sentence.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If the inmate was convicted of a violent crime, the victim may submit to the Commission a victim impact statement and recommendation.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Commission shall make the victim impact statement and recommendation available for review by the inmate or the inmate's representative subject to &#xA7; 7-303(b) of this title.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">If a victim impact statement or recommendation is submitted under this section, the Commission shall consider the victim impact statement or recommendation.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">A victim may request a meeting with a commissioner.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The Department shall notify promptly the victim or the victim's designated representative of the Commission's decision.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">The victim may designate in writing to the Department the name and address of a representative to receive notice for the victim.</section>
  </text>
</law>
