<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gcs" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="8-407" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcs-8-407</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In response to a request made under &#xA7; 8-405 or &#xA7; 8-406 of this subtitle (Article III or IV of the Agreement), the appropriate authority in a sending state shall offer to deliver temporary custody of the prisoner to the appropriate authority in the state where the indictment, information, or complaint is pending against the prisoner in order that speedy and efficient prosecution may be had. If the request for final disposition is made by the prisoner, the offer of temporary custody shall accompany the written notice required under &#xA7; 8-405 of this subtitle (Article III of the Agreement). In the case of a federal prisoner, the appropriate authority in the receiving state shall be entitled to temporary custody as provided by this Agreement or to the prisoner's presence in federal custody at the place for trial, whichever custodial arrangement may be approved by the custodian.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The officer or other representative of a state accepting an offer of temporary custody shall present the following upon demand:<section prefix="(1)">proper identification and evidence of the officer's authority to act for the state into whose temporary custody the prisoner is to be given; and</section><section prefix="(2)">a duly certified copy of the indictment, information, or complaint on the basis of which the detainer has been lodged and on the basis of which the request for temporary custody of the prisoner has been made.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">If the appropriate authority shall refuse or fail to accept temporary custody of the person, or in the event that an action on the indictment, information, or complaint on the basis of which the detainer has been lodged is not brought to trial within the period provided in &#xA7; 8-405 or &#xA7; 8-406 of this subtitle (Article III or IV of the Agreement), the appropriate court of the jurisdiction where the indictment, information, or complaint has been pending shall enter an order dismissing the same with prejudice, and any detainer based on the indictment, information, or complaint shall cease to be of any force or effect.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The temporary custody referred to in this Agreement shall be only for the purpose of permitting prosecution on the charge or charges contained in one or more untried indictments, informations, or complaints that form the basis of the detainer or detainers or for prosecution on any other charge or charges arising out of the same transaction. Except for the prisoner's attendance at court and while being transported to or from any place at which the prisoner's presence may be required, the prisoner shall be held in a suitable jail or other facility regularly used for persons awaiting prosecution.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">At the earliest practicable time consonant with the purposes of this Agreement, the prisoner shall be returned to the sending state.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">During the continuance of temporary custody or while the prisoner is otherwise being made available for trial as required by this Agreement, time being served on the sentence shall continue to run but good time shall be earned by the prisoner only if, and to the extent that, the law and practice of the jurisdiction that imposed the sentence may allow.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">For all purposes other than that for which temporary custody as provided in this Agreement is exercised, the prisoner shall be deemed to remain in the custody of and subject to the jurisdiction of the sending state. Any escape from temporary custody may be dealt with in the same manner as an escape from the original place of imprisonment or in any other manner permitted by law.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">From the time that a party state receives custody of a prisoner under this Agreement until the prisoner is returned to the territory and custody of the sending state, the state in which the one or more untried indictments, informations, or complaints are pending or in which trial is being had shall be responsible for the prisoner and shall also pay all costs of transporting, caring for, keeping, and returning the prisoner. The provisions of this subsection shall govern unless the states concerned shall have entered into a supplementary agreement providing for a different allocation of costs and responsibilities as between or among themselves. Nothing herein contained shall be construed to alter or affect any internal relationship among the departments, agencies, and officers of and in the government of a party state, or between a party state and its subdivisions, as to the payment of costs, or responsibilities therefor.</section>
  </text>
</law>
