<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcs" order_by="" level="1">Correctional Services</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcs-11-717</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>717</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, "Director" means the Director of the Montgomery County Department of Correction and Rehabilitation.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">This section applies only in Montgomery County.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The County Council shall establish work release and prerelease programs in accordance with this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A work release or prerelease program shall provide that an inmate of the County Department of Correction and Rehabilitation, on approval of the Director, may leave confinement during necessary and reasonable hours to seek or work at gainful employment and to participate in other rehabilitative activities, including:<section prefix="(i)">intensive counseling;</section><section prefix="(ii)">academic education;</section><section prefix="(iii)">home visitation;</section><section prefix="(iv)">transitional phased release programs; and</section><section prefix="(v)">maximum use of other community resources or other similar rehabilitative activities.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">At any time during the confinement of an inmate of the County Department of Correction and Rehabilitation, the judge who ordered the confinement or, if that judge is unable to act, another judge of the committing court, may approve the transfer of the inmate to the work release/prerelease center to participate in a work release or prerelease program:<section prefix="(i)">in accordance with the selection requirements and programs established by the County Council; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">after a recommendation by the Director or the Director's designee.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">After the inmate enters the work release or prerelease program, the judge who ordered confinement or, if that judge is unable to act, another judge of the committing court, may order the release of the inmate from custody based on:<section prefix="(i)">the recommendation of the Director or Director's designee; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">the report of the inmate's performance in the work release or prerelease program.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">When not employed or otherwise participating in a work release program, the inmate shall be confined in the prerelease center unless the committing court directs otherwise.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Director or the Director's designee shall collect the earnings of an inmate participating in a work release or prerelease program under this section, less any payroll deduction required by law.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">From the earnings of the inmate, the Director may deduct:<section prefix="(i)">the amount determined to be the cost to the county of providing food, lodging, and clothing for the inmate;</section><section prefix="(ii)">actual and necessary food, travel, and other expenses incidental to the inmate's participation in the program;</section><section prefix="(iii)">an amount the inmate is legally obligated or desires to pay for the support of a dependent;</section><section prefix="(iv)">if applicable, a reasonable amount to repay the State or the county for an attorney appointed by the court; and</section><section prefix="(v)">court-ordered payments for restitution.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Director shall:<section prefix="(i)">credit to the inmate's account any remaining balance; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">dispose of the balance in the inmate's account as the inmate requests and the Director approves.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If an inmate violates a trust or a condition that the County Council establishes for conduct or employment, the inmate is subject to:<section prefix="(i)">removal from the program; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">cancellation of any earned diminution of the inmate's term of confinement.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If an inmate violates a condition or a term of the program and the Director or the Director's designee removes the inmate from the program because of the violation, a judge of the committing court may redesignate the Division of Correction as the agency of custody for the remaining term of the inmate's confinement.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The County Department of Correction and Rehabilitation shall provide all work release, prerelease, and similar services to county residents who are sentenced to the jurisdiction of the Division of Correction.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Commissioner of Correction may transfer to the County Department of Correction and Rehabilitation only those eligible individuals who are screened and recommended for approval for the work release or prerelease program, or both programs, by both correctional agencies.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The county facilities shall operate in accordance with general operational standards that the Commissioner of Correction approves.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The County Department of Correction and Rehabilitation and the Division of Correction shall negotiate a contract each year that provides for State reimbursement on a per diem basis for operational costs to the county for providing the community correctional services described in this section to inmates sentenced to the Division of Correction and confined in the County Department of Correction and Rehabilitation.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
