<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gcs" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="3-804" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcs-3-804</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">An inmate who is employed in the community under a work-release plan shall surrender to the Division the inmate's total earnings less any payroll deductions required by law.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Division shall deduct from the inmate's earnings in the following order of priority:<section prefix="(i)">an amount the Division determines to be the cost to the State of providing food, lodging, and clothing for the inmate;</section><section prefix="(ii)">fees assessed under &#xA7; 2-118 of this article;</section><section prefix="(iii)">the actual and necessary food, travel, and other expenses of the inmate when released from actual confinement under the work-release program;</section><section prefix="(iv)">subject to paragraph (3) of this subsection, any amount that the inmate is legally obligated to pay to support the inmate's dependents; and</section><section prefix="(v)">the amount that a court orders to be paid as restitution.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Any balance that remains after the deductions are made under subsection (a) of this section shall be:<section prefix="(i)">credited to the inmate's account; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">paid to the inmate on release.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Any amount deducted under paragraph (1)(iv) of this subsection shall be paid to an inmate's dependents through the local social services administration in the county in which the dependents reside.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">If any part of the inmate's final earnings under a work-release plan are required to satisfy the obligatory deductions set forth in subsection (b) of this section, the balance of those earnings shall be forwarded to the inmate within 15 days after the inmate's release from the Division's jurisdiction.</section>
  </text>
</law>
