<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcs" order_by="gcs" level="1">Correctional Services</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcs-11-716</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this section, "warden" means the warden of the Kent County Detention Center....</catch_line>
  <order_by>716</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, "warden" means the warden of the Kent County Detention Center.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">This section applies only in Kent County.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The County Commissioners may establish under the Kent County Detention Center programs for:<section prefix="(1)">community service;</section><section prefix="(2)">home detention;</section><section prefix="(3)">pretrial release; and</section><section prefix="(4)">work release.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The County Commissioners shall adopt regulations necessary to implement each program established under this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">At the time of sentencing or at any time during an individual's confinement, the court may allow an individual to participate in any program established under this section if the individual:<section prefix="(1)">is sentenced to the custody of the warden; and</section><section prefix="(2)">has no other charges pending in any jurisdiction.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">An inmate designated to participate in a program under this section may leave the Kent County Detention Center to:<section prefix="(1)">continue regular employment;</section><section prefix="(2)">seek new employment; or</section><section prefix="(3)">receive therapy for drug or alcohol addiction.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The warden or warden's designee shall collect the earnings of an inmate designated to participate in a work release program, less any payroll deduction required by law.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">From the earnings of the inmate, the warden shall deduct and disburse an amount:<section prefix="(i)">the warden determines to be the cost to the county for providing food, lodging, and clothing for the inmate;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the county actually incurs for necessary food, travel, and other expenses incidental to participation by the inmate in the program;</section><section prefix="(iii)">a court imposes for a fine, cost, or restitution;</section><section prefix="(iv)">the inmate is legally obligated to pay, or reasonably wants to pay, for support of a dependent; and</section><section prefix="(v)">a court orders the inmate to repay to the State or to the county for the services of an attorney appointed by the court.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The warden shall:<section prefix="(i)">credit to the inmate's account any remaining balance; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">dispose of the balance in the inmate's account as the inmate reasonably requests and as the warden approves.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(h)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If an inmate violates a trust or a condition that the court or the Kent County Detention Center establishes for conduct or employment, the inmate is subject to:<section prefix="(i)">removal from a program specified in subsection (c) of this section; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">cancellation of any earned diminution of the inmate's term of confinement.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If a condition that a court imposes on an inmate is inconsistent with a regulation adopted under this section, the condition imposed by the court controls as to that inmate.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">If an inmate violates a trust or a condition that a court or the detention center establishes, the Kent County Detention Center shall notify the sentencing court in writing of the violation.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(i)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Inmates of the Kent County Detention Center who are employed under &#xA7; 11-602 of this title shall pay:<section prefix="(i)">court-ordered payments for restitution; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">the reasonable cost of the food, lodging, and clothing of the inmate.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The County Commissioners shall:<section prefix="(i)">establish a reasonable per diem rate for the food, lodging, and clothing of an inmate; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">designate the warden as the agent to collect these costs.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(j)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Subject to paragraph (2) of this subsection, the county may collect from an inmate who is sentenced to the Kent County Detention Center for nonconsecutive periods of 48 hours or less an amount determined to be the average cost to the county of providing food, lodging, and clothing for the inmate.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A court may waive any or all of the charge specified in paragraph (1) of this subsection.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(k)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The warden or warden's designee may authorize compassionate leave under this subsection for any inmate committed to the Kent County Detention Center:<section prefix="(i)">to visit a seriously ill member of the immediate family of the inmate; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">to attend a viewing or funeral of a member of the immediate family of the inmate.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">An inmate who is granted compassionate leave may be required to reimburse the Kent County Detention Center for any expenses that the detention center incurs in granting the leave.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The warden shall adopt regulations necessary to carry out this subsection.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
