<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcs" order_by="" level="1">Correctional Services</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcs-11-602</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>602</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">When an individual is convicted of a crime and sentenced to a local correctional facility, the sentencing judge may allow the individual, to the extent possible, to continue the individual's regular employment or obtain new employment during the inmate's term of confinement.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">When an individual is adjudicated to be in contempt of court and committed to the custody of a local correctional facility, the judge who commits the individual may allow the individual, to the extent possible, to continue the individual's regular employment or obtain new employment during the period in which the individual is committed to the custody of the local correctional facility.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If a judge allows an individual to continue employment or obtain new employment under paragraph (1) of this subsection, the judge shall designate either the managing official of the local correctional facility or the Division of Parole and Probation to supervise, arrange for, or obtain employment for the individual.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">If a judge designates a managing official or the Division of Parole and Probation to arrange for or obtain employment for an inmate as provided under subsection (a)(2) of this section, the managing official or Division:<section prefix="(1)">in the case of an inmate who has been regularly employed, shall arrange for continuation of employment without interruption to the extent possible; and</section><section prefix="(2)">in the case of an inmate who is not employed, shall make every effort to secure suitable employment that pays a fair and reasonable wage.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">If a managing official or the Division of Parole and Probation secures suitable employment for an inmate that pays a fair and reasonable wage, the inmate shall work a fair and reasonable number of hours each day and week.</section>
  </text>
</law>
