<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcs" order_by="" level="1">Correctional Services</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcs-1-101</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>101</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this article the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Commissioner of Correction" means the Commissioner of the Division of Correction.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Comptroller" means the Comptroller of the State.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">"Correctional facility" means a facility that is operated for the purpose of detaining or confining adults who are charged with or found guilty of a crime.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"County" means a county of the State and Baltimore City.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">"Department" means the Department of Public Safety and Correctional Services.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">"Division of Correction" means the Division of Correction in the Department of Public Safety and Correctional Services.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">"Division of Parole and Probation" means the Division of Parole and Probation in the Department of Public Safety and Correctional Services.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">"Inmate" means an individual who is actually or constructively detained or confined in a correctional facility.</section>
    <section prefix="(j)">"Local correctional facility" means a correctional facility that is operated:<section prefix="(1)">by one or more counties; or</section><section prefix="(2)">by a municipal corporation.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(k)">"Managing official" means the administrator, director, warden, superintendent, sheriff, or other individual responsible for the management of a correctional facility.</section>
    <section prefix="(l)">"Person" means an individual, receiver, trustee, guardian, personal representative, fiduciary, representative of any kind, partnership, firm, association, corporation, or other entity.</section>
    <section prefix="(m)">"Secretary" means the Secretary of Public Safety and Correctional Services.</section>
    <section prefix="(n)">"State" means:<section prefix="(1)">a state, possession, territory, or commonwealth of the United States; or</section><section prefix="(2)">the District of Columbia.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(o)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"State correctional facility" means a correctional facility that is operated by the State.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"State correctional facility" includes:<section prefix="(i)">the Patuxent Institution;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the Baltimore City Detention Center; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">the centralized booking facility in Baltimore City that is operated by the Division of Pretrial Detention and Services in the Department of Public Safety and Correctional Services.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(p)">"Treasurer" means the Treasurer of the State.</section>
  </text>
</law>
