<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcs" order_by="" level="1">Correctional Services</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcs-11-708</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>708</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">This section applies only in Carroll County.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">In this section, "crime of violence" has the meaning stated in &#xA7; 14-101 of the Criminal Law Article.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Sheriff may:<section prefix="(i)">establish a pretrial release program that offers alternatives to pretrial detention; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">adopt regulations to administer the program.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A court may order an individual to participate in the pretrial release program if the individual:<section prefix="(i)">appears before the court after being charged and detained on bond; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">meets the eligibility requirements of paragraph (4) of this subsection.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The court may make the order at the imposition of bond, on review of bond, or any other time during the individual's pretrial detention.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">An individual is eligible for the pretrial release program if the individual:<section prefix="(i)">has no other charges pending in any jurisdiction for a crime of violence; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">is not in detention for:<section prefix="1.">a crime of violence; or</section><section prefix="2.">the crime of escape under &#xA7; 9-404 of the Criminal Law Article.</section></section></section>
      <section prefix="(5)">The Sheriff may:<section prefix="(i)">collect from each individual participating in the pretrial release program a reasonable fee for the cost of supervision and administration of the program; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">waive or reduce the fee.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Sheriff's Office may establish a work release program.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">At the time of sentencing or at any time during an individual's confinement, the court may sentence the individual to participate in the work release program if the individual:<section prefix="(i)">has been sentenced to the custody of the Sheriff; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">has no other charges pending in any jurisdiction for a crime of violence.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">An inmate who has been sentenced to participate in the work release program may continue regular employment or obtain new employment.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">On approval of the Sheriff or Warden, an inmate who has been sentenced to the Carroll County Detention Center may leave the Detention Center to work, seek employment, obtain medical services, or participate in educational, rehabilitative, or training programs.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">An inmate who has been sentenced to the Carroll County Detention Center shall be confined to the Detention Center:<section prefix="(i)">except as provided in this subsection; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">unless a court orders otherwise.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(6)">An inmate who is employed under the work release program shall:<section prefix="(i)">reimburse the Sheriff's Office for:<section prefix="1.">the estimated cost to the Sheriff's Office of food and lodging for the inmate; and</section><section prefix="2.">estimated expenses incurred by the Sheriff's Office because of the participation of the inmate in the program; and</section></section><section prefix="(ii)">pay to the Sheriff court-ordered payments for restitution.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(7)">An inmate who violates a condition or provision of trust that a court, the Sheriff, or Sheriff's designee establishes is subject to:<section prefix="(i)">removal from the work release program; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">cancellation of any earned diminution of the inmate's term of confinement.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Sheriff shall:<section prefix="(i)">establish and administer a home detention program; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">adopt regulations for the home detention program.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">At the time of sentencing or at any time during an individual's confinement, the sentencing judge may require an individual who is convicted of a crime and sentenced to imprisonment under the custody of the Sheriff to participate in the home detention program.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Subject to paragraph (4) of this subsection, an inmate is eligible for the home detention program if:<section prefix="(i)">the sentencing judge recommends the inmate for sentencing to the home detention program; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">the inmate has no other charges pending in any jurisdiction.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">An inmate is not eligible for the home detention program if the inmate:<section prefix="(i)">is serving a sentence for a crime of violence; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">has been found guilty of the crime of:<section prefix="1.">child abuse under &#xA7; 3-601 or &#xA7; 3-602 of the Criminal Law Article; or</section><section prefix="2.">escape under &#xA7; 9-404 of the Criminal Law Article.</section></section></section>
      <section prefix="(5)">While participating in the home detention program, an inmate is responsible for:<section prefix="(i)">medical care and related expenses; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">costs of clothes, food, lodging, restitution, taxes, and transportation.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(6)">The Sheriff may:<section prefix="(i)">collect from each inmate participating in the home detention program a reasonable fee for the cost of electronic supervision and administration of the program; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">waive or reduce the fee.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(7)">The Sheriff may limit the number of inmates in the home detention program.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
