<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcs" order_by="gcs" level="1">Correctional Services</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcs-4-205</section_number>
  <catch_line>There is a Board of Review for the Institution....</catch_line>
  <order_by>205</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">There is a Board of Review for the Institution.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Board of Review consists of the following nine members:<section prefix="(1)">the Director;</section><section prefix="(2)">the two associate directors;</section><section prefix="(3)">the warden; and</section><section prefix="(4)">five members of the public, one of whom is a member of a victim's rights organization, appointed by the Governor with the advice and consent of the Senate.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Governor shall designate the chairperson of the Board of Review.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Seven members of the Board of Review, including at least three public members, constitute a quorum.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Except as provided in subparagraph (ii) of this paragraph, each action of the Board of Review requires the approval of 5 members.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">A decision to grant parole, work release, or leave to an eligible person requires the approval of seven members of the Board of Review.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Employees of the Institution who are members of the Board of Review or who attend meetings of or work as advisors to the Board of Review shall serve in that capacity as part of their regular duties without additional compensation.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The members of the Board of Review appointed from the public are entitled to compensation as provided in the State budget.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The term of a member of the Board of Review appointed from the public is 4 years.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">The Board of Review shall perform the duties set forth in this title.</section>
  </text>
</law>
