<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcs" order_by="gcs" level="1">Correctional Services</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcs-4-101</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this title the following words have the meanings indicated....</catch_line>
  <order_by>101</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this title the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Board of Review" means the institutional Board of Review created under &#xA7; 4-205 of this title.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Commissioner" means the Commissioner of Correction.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">"Director" means the Director of the Patuxent Institution.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Eligible person" means an individual who:<section prefix="(i)">has been convicted of a crime and is serving a sentence of imprisonment with at least 3 years remaining on the sentence;</section><section prefix="(ii)">has an intellectual impairment or emotional imbalance;</section><section prefix="(iii)">is likely to respond favorably to the programs and services that the Institution provides;</section><section prefix="(iv)">can better respond to remediation through those programs and services than by other incarceration; and</section><section prefix="(v)">meets the eligibility criteria that the Secretary establishes under &#xA7; 4-208(b) of this title.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Eligible person" does not include an individual who:<section prefix="(i)">is serving two or more sentences of imprisonment for life under &#xA7; 2-201, &#xA7; 2-303, or &#xA7; 2-304 of the Criminal Law Article;</section><section prefix="(ii)">is serving one or more sentences of imprisonment for life when a court or jury has found under &#xA7; 2-303 of the Criminal Law Article, beyond a reasonable doubt, that one or more aggravating circumstances existed; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">has been convicted of murder in the first degree, rape in the first degree, or a sexual offense in the first degree, unless the sentencing judge, at the time of sentencing or in the exercise of the judge's revisory power under the Maryland Rules, recommends that the individual be referred to the Institution for evaluation.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">"Evaluation team" means a team of at least three professional employees of the Institution, one of whom shall be a social worker, one of whom shall be a psychologist, and one of whom shall be a psychiatrist.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">"Institution" means the Patuxent Institution.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">"Patuxent programs" includes the eligible person program as defined in &#xA7; 4-301 of this title, and the Patuxent Youth Program as defined in &#xA7; 4-401 of this title.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">"Remediation" means treatment for specific areas of mental and social deficiencies that are highly related to criminal behavior.</section>
    <section prefix="(j)">"Victim" means:<section prefix="(1)">an individual who suffers personal physical injury or death as a direct result of a crime; or</section><section prefix="(2)">if the victim is deceased, a designated family member of the victim.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
