<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcs" order_by="gcs" level="1">Correctional Services</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcs-11-1004</section_number>
  <catch_line>Except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, a correctional officer has the same rights t...</catch_line>
  <order_by>1004</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, a correctional officer has the same rights to engage in political activity as a State employee.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The right of a correctional officer to engage in political activity does not apply when the correctional officer is on duty or acting in an official capacity.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A managing official:<section prefix="(1)">may not prohibit secondary employment by a correctional officer; but</section><section prefix="(2)">may adopt reasonable regulations that relate to secondary employment by a correctional officer.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A correctional officer may not be required or requested to disclose an item of the correctional officer's property, income, assets, source of income, debts, or personal or domestic expenditures, including those of a member of the correctional officer's family or household, unless:<section prefix="(1)">the information is necessary to investigate a possible conflict of interest with respect to the performance of the correctional officer's official duties; or</section><section prefix="(2)">the disclosure is required by federal or State law.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A correctional officer may not be discharged, disciplined, demoted, or denied promotion, transfer, or reassignment, or otherwise discriminated against in regard to the correctional officer's employment or be threatened with that treatment because the correctional officer:<section prefix="(1)">has exercised or demanded the rights granted by this subtitle; or</section><section prefix="(2)">has lawfully exercised constitutional rights.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">A statute may not abridge and a correctional facility may not adopt a regulation that prohibits the right of a correctional officer to bring suit that arises out of the correctional officer's duties as a correctional officer.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">A correctional officer may waive in writing any or all rights granted by this subtitle.</section>
  </text>
</law>
