<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcs" order_by="" level="1">Correctional Services</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcs-11-317</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>317</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">This section applies to inmates transferred to a center or regional center from a local correctional facility.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A center director may recommend to the court that an inmate in a local correctional facility be placed in a center based on locally established procedures.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If a center director makes a recommendation as provided under paragraph (1) of this subsection, the judge ordering the confinement, or, if that judge is unable to act, another judge of the court that committed the inmate may approve the placement of the inmate in a center.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The center director may make a recommendation to a court that an inmate in a center be released from custody.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The recommendation shall be based on a report of the inmate's performance in the center.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">If a center director recommends the release of an inmate, the judge who ordered the confinement, or if that judge is unable to act, another judge of the court that committed the inmate may order the release of the inmate from custody.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Subject to &#xA7; 11-318 of this subtitle, the center director may revoke the participation of an inmate.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">If the remaining term of confinement of the inmate exceeds 12 months, the court that committed the inmate may designate the Division of Correction as the agency of custody.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The decision of the judge shall be based on a report of the center director to the judge that shows cause for revocation.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
