<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcs" order_by="gcs" level="1">Correctional Services</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcs-3-801</section_number>
  <catch_line>The Division may establish a work-release program....</catch_line>
  <order_by>801</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Division may establish a work-release program.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Under the work-release program, an inmate who is sentenced to the jurisdiction of the Division may be granted the privilege of leaving actual confinement during necessary and reasonable hours:<section prefix="(1)">to work at gainful public or private employment;</section><section prefix="(2)">to attend school; or</section><section prefix="(3)">under appropriate conditions, to seek employment.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">An inmate may apply to the warden of the correctional facility in which the inmate is confined for permission to participate in the program.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">An application shall include:<section prefix="(i)">a statement by the inmate that the inmate agrees to abide by all terms and conditions of the particular plan that the Commissioner or the Commissioner's designee adopts for the inmate;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the name and address of a proposed employer or school training program, if any; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">any other information that the Division or the Commissioner requires, including the inmate's agreement to waive the right to contest extradition proceedings.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A warden may recommend an inmate's application to the Commissioner.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Commissioner or the Commissioner's designee may approve, disapprove, or defer action on the application.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">If an inmate's application is approved, the Commissioner or the Commissioner's designee shall adopt a work-release plan for the inmate that:<section prefix="(i)">contains terms and conditions that are necessary and proper;</section><section prefix="(ii)">may include the inmate's waiver of the right to contest extradition proceedings; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">is signed by the inmate before the inmate participates in the work-release program.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">At any time and for any reason, the Commissioner may revoke approval for an inmate to participate in the work-release program.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
