<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcs" order_by="gcs" level="1">Correctional Services</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcs-3-520</section_number>
  <catch_line>The Management Council shall determine the times and places of its meetings....</catch_line>
  <order_by>520</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Management Council shall determine the times and places of its meetings.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Eight members of the Management Council constitute a quorum.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A member of the Management Council:<section prefix="(1)">may not receive compensation for membership on the Management Council; but</section><section prefix="(2)">is entitled to reimbursement for expenses under the Standard State Travel Regulations, as provided in the State budget.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Except as provided in subsection (e) of this section, the State, the Management Council, and the members and employees of the Management Council may not be held liable for any act or omission of the Management Council or any member or employee of the Management Council in connection with the performance of their duties.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">Subsection (d) of this section does not apply in the case of willful malfeasance or breach of trust by the State, the Management Council, or any member or employee of the Management Council.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The Secretary shall employ staff for the Management Council to be paid out of funds from Maryland Correctional Enterprises, in accordance with the State budget.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">For fiscal year 2000 and each fiscal year thereafter, the Management Council shall prepare a budget for submission to the Secretary.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Secretary shall request an appropriation for the Management Council in the annual State budget sufficient for the operation of the Council.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
