<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcs" order_by="" level="1">Correctional Services</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcs-7-306</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>306</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The chairperson of the Commission shall assign hearing examiners, or commissioners acting as hearing examiners, as required to hear cases for parole.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Each proceeding before a hearing examiner shall be conducted in accordance with this section.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Commission shall keep a record of each hearing conducted by a hearing examiner.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A hearing examiner shall determine if an inmate is suitable for parole in accordance with the factors and other information specified in &#xA7; 7-305 of this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">At the conclusion of the hearing, the hearing examiner shall inform the inmate of the hearing examiner's recommendation for parole or denial of parole.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Within 21 days after the hearing, the hearing examiner shall give to the Commission, the Commissioner of Correction, and the inmate a written report of the hearing examiner's findings and recommendation for parole or denial of parole.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Commissioner of Correction or the inmate may file with the Commission written exceptions to the report of a hearing examiner no later than 5 days after the report is received.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Subject to paragraph (2) of this subsection, one commissioner assigned by the chairperson of the Commission shall review summarily the recommendation of the hearing examiner.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The Commission, on its own initiative or on the filing of an exception, may schedule a hearing on the record by the entire Commission or by a panel of at least two commissioners assigned by the chairperson of the Commission.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The Commission or panel shall render a written decision on the appeal.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">The decision of the Commission or panel is final.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">If an exception is not filed and the Commission does not act on its own initiative within the 5-day appeal period established under subsection (d)(3) of this section, the recommendation of the hearing examiner is approved.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
