<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcs" order_by="" level="1">Correctional Services</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcs-4-204</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>204</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Institution shall have the following staff:<section prefix="(1)">two associate directors, one of whom is a competent psychiatrist with at least 3 years of experience in the practice or teaching of psychiatry and one of whom is a competent behavioral scientist with at least 3 years of experience in the practice or teaching of the individual's specialty in behavioral science;</section><section prefix="(2)">a warden;</section><section prefix="(3)">at least three additional psychiatrists or clinical psychologists;</section><section prefix="(4)">at least four State licensed certified social workers-clinical; and</section><section prefix="(5)">other professional and nonprofessional staff, as provided in the State budget.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The associate directors shall assist primarily in discharging the diagnostic and remediation functions of the Institution.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The warden shall assist primarily in discharging the custodial function of the Institution.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The staff members of the Institution are entitled to compensation as provided in the State budget.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in paragraph (3) of this subsection or any other law, the staff members of the Institution are in the skilled service or professional service in the State Personnel Management System.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">With the approval of the Secretary, the Director shall appoint an individual to any position that the Secretary determines to be professional, including:<section prefix="(i)">each associate director;</section><section prefix="(ii)">each social worker;</section><section prefix="(iii)">each sociologist;</section><section prefix="(iv)">each physician; and</section><section prefix="(v)">each psychologist.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Director and each individual appointed under paragraph (2)(i) of this subsection are in the executive service, in the management service, or a special appointment in the State Personnel Management System.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
