<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gcs" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="3-808" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcs-3-808</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Commissioner, the Deputy Commissioner, the Assistant Commissioner for Operations, or the Assistant Commissioner for Administration may grant compassionate leave to an inmate confined in a correctional facility in the Division to visit a member of the inmate's immediate family who is seriously ill or attend the funeral of a member of the inmate's immediate family.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">When granting compassionate leave to an inmate, the Commissioner, the Deputy Commissioner, the Assistant Commissioner for Operations, or the Assistant Commissioner for Administration shall:<section prefix="(i)">issue a written authorization that:</section><section prefix="(ii)">file a copy of the authorization in the Commissioner's office.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">While on compassionate leave, an inmate at all times shall possess a copy of the authorization for compassionate leave.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The duration of compassionate leave shall include reasonable time:<section prefix="(i)">for travel; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">for fulfilling the purpose of the leave.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Commissioner may require an inmate to whom compassionate leave is granted or anyone acting on the inmate's behalf to reimburse the Division for the expenses incurred by the Division in granting the leave.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The failure of an inmate to comply with the terms of the inmate's authorization for compassionate leave is a violation of &#xA7; 9-404 of the Criminal Law Article.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The Commissioner may adopt regulations to carry out this section.</section>
  </text>
</law>
