<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gcs" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="3-521" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcs-3-521</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Management Council shall:<section prefix="(i)">advise Maryland Correctional Enterprises on its specific proposals to establish new industries and improve the quality and quantity of job training programs; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">recommend the establishment and maintenance of industrial plants and service centers to be used for implementing the programs developed by the Commissioner and Chief Executive Officer under &#xA7; 3-511 of this subtitle.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Maryland Correctional Enterprises shall operate industrial plants and service centers recommended under paragraph (1)(ii) of this subsection primarily with inmates in a manner that benefits the State and the training of inmates by producing goods or providing services that are practical and adaptable for a prison industry.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Management Council shall:<section prefix="(1)">review the operation of the programs of Maryland Correctional Enterprises to determine whether:<section prefix="(i)">there is undue competition with private enterprise and recommend necessary adjustments to prevent undue competition; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">there is any negative impact on workers in the State, including wage depression or job displacement;</section></section><section prefix="(2)">review the standards for goods and services and the pricing schedules as recommended by the Chief Executive Officer; and</section><section prefix="(3)">review the occupational health and safety record of programs and other working conditions of inmates in the programs of Maryland Correctional Enterprises.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Management Council shall:<section prefix="(1)">review the success of Maryland Correctional Enterprises in:<section prefix="(i)">meeting the employability development needs of inmates; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">coordinating work programs with other rehabilitative programs;</section></section><section prefix="(2)">solicit and review information pertaining to concerns of participating inmates; and</section><section prefix="(3)">recommend changes as necessary to meet the goals and objectives of Maryland Correctional Enterprises.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Management Council shall:<section prefix="(1)">solicit ideas, proposals, and suggestions from business representatives, nonprofit organizations, government entities, and members of the public as to how Maryland Correctional Enterprises could enhance the work experience of inmates and increase the ability of inmates to obtain gainful employment after release;</section><section prefix="(2)">review and recommend opportunities with private sector employers to expand the Prison Industries Enhancement Program;</section><section prefix="(3)">review and identify ways to improve the business practices of Maryland Correctional Enterprises in its sales, marketing, inventory, warehousing, and product line operations;</section><section prefix="(4)">monitor customer satisfaction with price, quality, delivery, and after delivery service; and</section><section prefix="(5)">review and comment on the operating and capital budgets of Maryland Correctional Enterprises, including cash forecasts.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
