<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcs" order_by="" level="1">Correctional Services</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcs-11-1108</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>1108</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A decision, an order, or an action taken as a result of a hearing under &#xA7; 11-1107 of this subtitle shall be in writing and accompanied by findings of fact.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The findings of fact shall consist of a concise statement on each issue in the case.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A finding of not guilty terminates the action.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">If the hearing board makes a finding of guilt, the hearing board shall:<section prefix="(i)">reconvene the hearing;</section><section prefix="(ii)">receive evidence; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">consider the correctional officer's past job performance and other relevant information as factors before making recommendations to the Sheriff.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(5)">A copy of the decision or order, findings of fact, conclusions, and written recommendations for action shall be delivered or mailed promptly to:<section prefix="(i)">the correctional officer or the correctional officer's counsel or representative of record; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">the Sheriff.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">After a disciplinary hearing and a finding of guilt, the hearing board may recommend the penalty it considers appropriate under the circumstances, including demotion, dismissal, transfer, loss of pay, reassignment, or other similar action that is considered punitive.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The recommendation of a penalty shall be in writing.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Within 30 days after receipt of the recommendations of the hearing board, the Sheriff shall:<section prefix="(i)">review the findings, conclusions, and recommendations of the hearing board; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">issue a final order.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The recommendation of a penalty by the hearing board is not binding on the Sheriff.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Sheriff shall consider the correctional officer's past job performance as a factor before imposing a penalty.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The Sheriff may increase the recommended penalty of the hearing board only if the Sheriff personally meets with the correctional officer and allows the correctional officer to be heard on the record.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
