<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcs" order_by="" level="1">Correctional Services</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcs-11-718</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>718</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, "administrator" means an administrator of a county detention center.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">This section applies only in Prince George's County.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Subject to paragraph (2) of this subsection, an administrator may allow an inmate sentenced to imprisonment in a detention center after being convicted of a crime or found in contempt of court to leave actual confinement to:<section prefix="(i)">seek or work at gainful, private employment;</section><section prefix="(ii)">participate in a training or rehabilitation program; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">attend educational or vocational institutions in the county.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The administrator may allow the inmate to leave confinement:<section prefix="(i)">in accordance with established programs;</section><section prefix="(ii)">during necessary and reasonable hours; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">after determining that the inmate is eligible for the program and recommending it to and receiving written approval from the sentencing or administrative judge.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The administrator shall adopt guidelines and rules for the conduct of the work release program that shall:<section prefix="(i)">take into consideration the security of the detention center and the safety of the public; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">conform with conditions that a sentencing or administrative judge may impose in a particular case.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">When an inmate is not employed or otherwise participating in a work release program, the inmate shall be confined in the detention center in the same manner as any other inmate committed to the custody of the administrator.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">If an inmate violates a trust or a condition that the administrator establishes in the rules for conduct or employment, the inmate is:<section prefix="(i)">subject to removal from the work release program; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">after an administrative hearing, subject to cancellation of any earned diminution of the inmate's term of confinement.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The authorized representative of a detention center shall collect the earnings of an inmate, less any payroll deductions.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">From the earnings of the inmate, the authorized representative of the detention center shall deduct:<section prefix="(i)">the amount determined to be the cost to the county for food, lodging, and clothing for the inmate;</section><section prefix="(ii)">actual and necessary food, travel, and other expenses incidental to the inmate's participation in the program;</section><section prefix="(iii)">an amount the inmate is legally obligated or desires to pay for the support of a dependent; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">court-ordered payments for restitution.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The authorized representative of the detention center shall credit to the inmate's account any remaining balance.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">An administrator may develop educational and vocational programs to further the educational and vocational training of an inmate sentenced to the detention center.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The administrator shall adopt regulations to govern the conduct and participation of an inmate in an educational or vocational program as necessary for the security of the detention center and the safety of the public.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">If an inmate violates a trust or a condition that the administrator establishes for conduct during participation in an educational or vocational program, the inmate:<section prefix="1.">is subject to removal from the program, with notice to the sentencing judge; and</section><section prefix="2.">after an administrative hearing, is subject to cancellation of any earned diminution of the inmate's term of confinement.</section></section>
      </section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
