<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcs" order_by="" level="1">Correctional Services</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcs-3-704</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>704</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">An inmate shall be allowed a deduction in advance from the inmate's term of confinement.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The deduction allowed under subsection (a) of this section shall be calculated:<section prefix="(i)">from the first day of commitment to the custody of the Commissioner through the last day of the inmate's term of confinement;</section><section prefix="(ii)">except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, at the rate of 10 days for each calendar month; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">on a prorated basis for any portion of a calendar month.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If an inmate's term of confinement includes a consecutive or concurrent sentence for a crime of violence as defined in &#xA7; 14-101 of the Criminal Law Article or a crime of manufacturing, distributing, dispensing, or possessing a controlled dangerous substance in violation of &#xA7;&#xA7; 5-602 through 5-609, &#xA7; 5-612, or &#xA7; 5-613 of the Criminal Law Article, the deduction described in subsection (a) of this section shall be calculated at the rate of 5 days for each calendar month.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A deduction under this section may not be allowed for a period during which an inmate does not receive credit for service of the inmate's term of confinement, including a period:<section prefix="(1)">during which the inmate's sentence is stayed;</section><section prefix="(2)">during which the inmate is not in the custody of the Commissioner because of escape; or</section><section prefix="(3)">for which the Maryland Parole Commission has declined to grant credit after revocation of parole or mandatory supervision.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
