<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcs" order_by="gcs" level="1">Correctional Services</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcs-7-401</section_number>
  <catch_line>If a parolee is alleged to have violated a condition of parole, one commissioner shall hear the case...</catch_line>
  <order_by>401</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">If a parolee is alleged to have violated a condition of parole, one commissioner shall hear the case on revocation of the parole at the time and place that the Commission designates.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Each individual charged with a parole violation is entitled to be represented by counsel of the individual's choice or, if eligible, counsel provided by the Public Defender's office.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Commission shall keep a record of the hearing.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">If the commissioner finds from the evidence that the parolee has violated a condition of parole, the commissioner may take any action that the commissioner considers appropriate, including:<section prefix="(1)"><section prefix="(i)">revoking the order of parole;</section><section prefix="(ii)">setting a future hearing date for consideration for reparole; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">remanding the individual to the Division of Correction or local correctional facility from which the individual was paroled; or</section></section><section prefix="(2)">continuing parole:<section prefix="(i)">without modification of its conditions; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">with modification of its conditions, including a requirement that the parolee spend all or part of the remaining parole period in a home detention program.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Subject to paragraph (2) of this subsection and further action by the Commission, if the order of parole is revoked, the inmate shall serve the remainder of the sentence originally imposed unless the commissioner hearing the parole revocation, in the commissioner's discretion, grants credit for time between release on parole and revocation of parole.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">An inmate may not receive credit for time between release on parole and revocation of parole if:<section prefix="(i)">the inmate was serving a sentence for a violent crime when parole was revoked; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">the parole was revoked due to a finding that the inmate committed a violent crime while on parole.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">Subject to subsection (d) of this section, if a sentence has commenced as provided under &#xA7; 9-202(c)(2) of this article and the inmate is serving that sentence when the order of parole is revoked, the remainder of the sentence originally imposed shall begin at the expiration of any sentences which were begun under &#xA7; 9-202(c)(2) of this article.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The inmate may seek judicial review in the circuit court within 30 days after receiving the written decision of the Commission.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The court shall hear the action on the record.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
