<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcs" order_by="" level="1">Correctional Services</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcs-3-518</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>518</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Management Council consists of the following 15 members:<section prefix="(1)">the Commissioner;</section><section prefix="(2)">a representative of the Comptroller of the Treasury, appointed by the State Comptroller;</section><section prefix="(3)">the Chief Executive Officer;</section><section prefix="(4)">a member of the House of Delegates, appointed by the Speaker of the House of Delegates;</section><section prefix="(5)">a member of the Senate, appointed by the President of the Senate;</section><section prefix="(6)">a representative of the University System of Maryland, appointed by the Chancellor;</section><section prefix="(7)">a representative of the State Department of Education, appointed by the Governor;</section><section prefix="(8)">a representative of the Department of Labor, Licensing, and Regulation, appointed by the Governor;</section><section prefix="(9)">a representative of the Governor's Office of Crime Control and Prevention, appointed by the Governor;</section><section prefix="(10)">two representatives of organized labor, one from the public sector and one from the private sector, appointed by the Governor in accordance with subsection (b) of this section;</section><section prefix="(11)">a judge, appointed by the Chief Judge of the Maryland Court of Appeals;</section><section prefix="(12)">two representatives of the business community selected from the fields of manufacturing, services, finance, and information technology, appointed by the Governor in accordance with subsection (b) of this section; and</section><section prefix="(13)">one representative of a nonprofit organization, appointed by the Governor in accordance with subsection (b) of this section.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The term of a member appointed under subsection (a)(10), (12), and (13) of this section is 3 years.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">At the end of a term the member continues to serve until a successor is appointed and qualifies.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A member appointed after a term has begun serves only for the rest of the term and until a successor is appointed and qualifies.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
