<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gcs" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="7-304" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcs-7-304</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">A parole hearing shall be open to the public if:<section prefix="(1)"><section prefix="(i)">a victim, as defined in &#xA7; 7-801 of this title, makes a written request to the Department for notification and maintains a current address on file with the Department; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">a victim or a victim's representative files a notification request form under &#xA7; 11-104 of the Criminal Procedure Article; and</section></section><section prefix="(2)">within a reasonable amount of time before a scheduled hearing, the victim makes a written request that the hearing be open to the public.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The vote of each commissioner when acting collectively or in a panel, to approve or deny parole, and a vote to close or restrict access to a parole hearing under subsection (d) of this section, shall be made available to the public.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Subject to subsection (d) of this section, the victim or victim's representative has the right to attend an open parole hearing.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Commission or a panel of commissioners may:<section prefix="(1)">restrict the number of individuals allowed to attend a parole hearing in accordance with physical limitations or security requirements of the facility where the hearing is held;</section><section prefix="(2)">deny admission or continued attendance at a parole hearing to an individual who:<section prefix="(i)">threatens or presents a danger to the security of the facility in which the hearing is being held;</section><section prefix="(ii)">threatens or presents a danger to other attendees or participants; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">disrupts the hearing;</section></section><section prefix="(3)">close a parole hearing to deliberate on the evidence and any other relevant information received at the hearing; or</section><section prefix="(4)">close a parole hearing on written request of the chief law enforcement official responsible for an ongoing criminal investigation related to the inmate, if the ongoing investigation could be compromised.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">This section does not limit the authority of the Commission to hold a parole hearing through the use of a video conference or other means of electronic transmission.</section>
  </text>
</law>
