<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcs" order_by="gcs" level="1">Correctional Services</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcs-7-101</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this title the following words have the meanings indicated....</catch_line>
  <order_by>101</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this title the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Commission" means the Maryland Parole Commission.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Commissioner" means a member of the Maryland Parole Commission.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">"Commutation of sentence" means an act of clemency in which the Governor, by order, substitutes a lesser penalty for the grantee's offense for the penalty imposed by the court in which the grantee was convicted.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"Conditional commutation of sentence" means a commutation of sentence that is dependent on compliance with conditions precedent or subsequent that the Governor specifies in the written order granting the commutation.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">"Conditional pardon" means a pardon that is dependent on compliance with conditions precedent or subsequent that the Governor specifies in the written order granting the pardon.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Mandatory supervision" means a conditional release from confinement that is granted to an inmate under &#xA7; 7-501 of this title.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Mandatory supervision" includes a conditional release granted before July 1, 1989 that was referred to as "mandatory release".</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(h)">"Pardon" means an act of clemency in which the Governor, by order, absolves the grantee from the guilt of the grantee's criminal acts and exempts the grantee from any penalties imposed by law for those criminal acts.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">"Parole" means a conditional release from confinement granted by the Commission to an inmate.</section>
    <section prefix="(j)">"Parolee" means an inmate who has been released on parole.</section>
    <section prefix="(k)">"Partial pardon" means a pardon that has been limited by the terms of the order granting the pardon to be of less effect than a full pardon.</section>
    <section prefix="(l)">"Predetermined parole release agreement" means an agreement among the Commissioner of Correction, the Commission, and an inmate for the parole of the inmate at a predetermined time if, during the inmate's term of confinement, the inmate fulfills the conditions specified in the agreement.</section>
    <section prefix="(m)">"Violent crime" means:<section prefix="(1)">a crime of violence as defined in &#xA7; 14-101 of the Criminal Law Article; or</section><section prefix="(2)">burglary in the first, second, or third degree.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
