<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gcs" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="9-202" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcs-9-202</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Division custody" means confinement resulting from a sentence to the jurisdiction of the Division of Correction.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">"Non-Division custody" means any postsentencing criminal confinement other than Division custody.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">"Non-Division custody" includes confinement resulting from a sentence to:</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A sentence to a term of Division custody that is imposed consecutive to a term of Non-Division custody shall begin when the individual is released from Non-Division custody due to the expiration of a sentence, parole, or the application of diminution credits.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A sentence to a term of Non-Division custody that is imposed consecutive to a term of Division custody shall begin when the individual is released from Division custody due to the expiration of a sentence, parole, or the application of diminution credits.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A sentence imposed consecutive to a term of confinement for which the defendant is on parole shall begin:<section prefix="(1)">if, at the time of sentencing, parole is revoked, on expiration of the original term of confinement; or</section><section prefix="(2)">if parole is not revoked, on the date that the consecutive sentence was imposed.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">An inmate under a sentence to a term of Division custody that is concurrent or partially concurrent to a term of Non-Division custody shall be subject to Division custody immediately on release from Non-Division custody due to the expiration of a sentence, parole, or the application of diminution credits.</section>
  </text>
</law>
