<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gcs" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="11-715" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcs-11-715</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following terms have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Department" means the Howard County Department of Correction.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Director" means the Director of the Howard County Department of Correction.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">This section applies only in Howard County.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Department may establish a work release program.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The work release program may include an inmate's participation in a program of employment, rehabilitation, training, education, or home detention.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Director may adopt regulations relating to the operation of the work release program.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">At the time of sentencing or at any time during an individual's confinement, the sentencing judge if available, or otherwise the court may allow an individual to participate in the work release program if the individual:<section prefix="(i)">has been sentenced to the custody of the Department; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">has no other charges pending in any jurisdiction for a crime of violence as defined under &#xA7; 14-101(d) of the Criminal Law Article.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If the Department approves, an inmate in the custody of the Howard County Detention Center may leave the Center to participate in a work release program.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">An inmate who has been designated to participate in a work release program may:<section prefix="(i)">continue regular employment; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">obtain new employment.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">An inmate who has been sentenced to the custody of the Department shall be confined to the Howard County Detention Center:<section prefix="(i)">except as provided in this section; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">unless a court orders otherwise.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">An inmate who is employed while in a work release program under this section shall:<section prefix="(1)">reimburse the Department by paying a fee based on:<section prefix="(i)">the Department's estimated cost of providing food and lodging to the inmate; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">the estimated expenses incurred by the Department because of the inmate's participation in the work release program; and</section></section><section prefix="(2)">pay to the Director court-ordered payments for restitution.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">An inmate employed in the community under this section is not an agent or employee of the county, the Director, the court or any judicial officer, or any public officer of the county.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">An inmate who violates a condition or provision of trust that the court or the Department establishes is subject to:<section prefix="(1)">removal from the work release program; and</section><section prefix="(2)">cancellation of any earned diminution of the inmate's term of confinement.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
