<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcs" order_by="gcs" level="1">Correctional Services</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcs-6-117</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this section the following words have the meanings indicated....</catch_line>
  <order_by>117</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Abatement" means an end to active supervision of a supervised individual, without effect on the legal expiration date of the case or the supervised individual's obligation to:<section prefix="(i)">obey all laws;</section><section prefix="(ii)">report as instructed; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">obtain written permission from the Division of Parole and Probation before relocating the supervised individual's residence outside the State.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Earned compliance credit" means a 20-day reduction from the period of active supervision of the supervised individual for every month that a supervised individual:<section prefix="(i)">exhibits full compliance with the conditions, goals, and treatment as part of the supervised individual's probation, parole, or mandatory release supervision, as determined by the Department;</section><section prefix="(ii)">has no new arrests;</section><section prefix="(iii)">has not violated any conditions of no contact imposed on the supervised individual;</section><section prefix="(iv)">is current on court ordered payments for restitution, fines, and fees relating to the offense for which earned compliance credits are being accrued; and</section><section prefix="(v)">is current in completing any community supervision requirements included in the conditions of the supervised individual's probation, parole, or mandatory release supervision.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">
        <section prefix="(i)">"Supervised individual" means an individual placed on probation by a court or serving a period of parole or mandatory release supervision after release from a correctional facility.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">"Supervised individual" does not include:<section prefix="1.">a person incarcerated, on probation, or convicted in this State for a crime of violence;</section><section prefix="2.">a person incarcerated, on probation, or convicted in this State for a crime under Title 3, Subtitle 3, of the Criminal Law Article;</section><section prefix="3.">a person incarcerated, on probation, or convicted in this State for a violation of &#xA7; 2-503, &#xA7; 5-602 through &#xA7; 5-617, &#xA7; 5-627, or &#xA7; 5-628 of the Criminal Law Article;</section><section prefix="4.">a person registered or eligible for registration under Title 11, Subtitle 7 of the Criminal Procedure Article;</section><section prefix="5.">a person who was convicted in any other jurisdiction of a crime and the person's supervision was transferred to this State; or</section><section prefix="6.">a person who was convicted in this State of a crime and the person's supervision was transferred to another state.</section></section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Department shall:<section prefix="(1)">establish a program to implement earned compliance credits; and</section><section prefix="(2)">adopt policies and procedures to implement the program.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Notwithstanding any other law, the Maryland Parole Commission or the court may adjust the period of a supervised individual's supervision on the recommendation of the Division of Parole and Probation for earned compliance credits accrued under a program created under this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A supervised individual whose period of active supervision has been completely reduced as a result of earned compliance credits shall remain on abatement until the expiration of the supervised individual's sentence, unless:<section prefix="(1)">the supervised individual consents to continued active supervision; or</section><section prefix="(2)">the supervised individual violates a condition of probation, parole, or mandatory release supervision including failure to pay a required payment of restitution.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">If a supervised individual violates a condition of probation while on abatement, a court may order the supervised individual to be returned to active supervision.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Twenty-five percent of the savings realized by the Department as a result of the application of earned compliance credits shall revert to the Department.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">After the savings revert to the Department in accordance with paragraph (1) of this subsection, any remaining savings shall revert to the General Fund.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">This section may not be construed to limit the authority of a court or the Parole Commission to extend probation, parole, or mandatory release supervision under &#xA7; 6-222 of the Criminal Procedure Article.</section>
  </text>
</law>
