<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcs" order_by="gcs" level="1">Correctional Services</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcs-6-210</section_number>
  <catch_line>The Interstate Commission shall oversee the interstate movement of adult offenders in the compacting...</catch_line>
  <order_by>210</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Interstate Commission shall oversee the interstate movement of adult offenders in the compacting states and shall monitor such activities being administered in noncompacting states which may significantly affect compacting states.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The courts and executive agencies in each compacting state shall enforce this Compact and shall take all actions necessary and appropriate to effectuate the Compact's purposes and intent. In any judicial or administrative proceeding in a compacting state pertaining to the subject matter of this Compact which may affect the powers, responsibilities, or actions of the Interstate Commission, the Interstate Commission shall be entitled to receive all service of process in any proceeding, and shall have standing to intervene in the proceeding for all purposes.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The compacting states shall report to the Interstate Commission on issues or activities of concern to them, and cooperate with and support the Interstate Commission in the discharge of its duties and responsibilities.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Interstate Commission shall attempt to resolve any disputes or other issues which are subject to the Compact and which may arise among compacting states and noncompacting states.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Interstate Commission shall enact a bylaw or promulgate a rule providing for both mediation and binding dispute resolution for disputes among the compacting states.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Interstate Commission, in the reasonable exercise of its discretion, shall enforce the provisions of this Compact using any or all means set forth in &#xA7; 6-213(b) of this subtitle.</section>
  </text>
</law>
