<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gcs" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="8-114" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcs-8-114</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If the Commission determines that a correctional facility is in violation of the minimum mandatory standards, the Commission shall send a compliance plan to the correctional facility.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The compliance plan shall state:<section prefix="(i)">which minimum mandatory standards the correctional facility has violated;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the time, to be determined by the Commission, that the correctional facility has to address the violations; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">the date that the Commission shall reinspect the correctional facility to determine if the correctional facility has complied with the minimum mandatory standards.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Commission shall send a copy of the compliance plan to the executive and legislative body responsible for the correctional facility.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If, after sending a compliance plan and reinspecting a correctional facility under subsection (a) of this section, the Commission determines that the correctional facility is in violation of the minimum mandatory standards, the Commission shall send a letter of reprimand to the correctional facility.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The letter of reprimand shall state:<section prefix="(i)">which minimum standards the correctional facility has violated;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the time, to be determined by the Commission but not to exceed 60 days, that the correctional facility has to address the violations; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">the date that the Commission will reinspect the correctional facility to determine if the correctional facility has complied with the minimum mandatory standards.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Commission shall send a copy of the letter of reprimand to the executive and legislative body responsible for the correctional facility.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If, after the Commission has sent a letter of reprimand to a correctional facility under subsection (b) of this section and reinspected the facility, the Commission determines that the correctional facility is in violation of the minimum mandatory standards, the Commission shall:<section prefix="(i)">conduct a full standards and performance audit of the correctional facility; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">periodically inspect the correctional facility until compliance is attained and send a report of each inspection to the executive and legislative bodies responsible for the correctional facility.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">When conducting a full standards and performance audit of a correctional facility, the Commission shall examine:<section prefix="(i)">the physical condition of the correctional facility;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the safety and treatment of inmates at the correctional facility;</section><section prefix="(iii)">whether the correctional facility has policies and procedures in place as required by the minimum mandatory standards; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">whether the correctional facility is following the required policies and procedures.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">When conducting a full standards and performance audit, the Commission shall have unrestricted access to the personnel and records of the correctional facility.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">
        <section prefix="(i)">If the Commission lacks the expertise necessary to perform a part of the full standards and performance audit, the Commission may obtain assistance from sources with expertise in the specific standard.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">If the Commission needs to obtain assistance, the correctional facility that is being audited shall reimburse the Commission for any cost incurred.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(5)">
        <section prefix="(i)">After completing a full standards and performance audit, the Commission shall send a letter to the correctional facility.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The letter shall contain:</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">The Commission shall send a copy of the letter to the executive and legislative bodies responsible for the correctional facility.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(6)">Within a reasonable time after the date specified for compliance, the Commission shall conduct an unannounced inspection to verify that the correctional facility has complied with the audit findings.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If, after performing an audit and unannounced inspection under subsection (c) of this section and holding a hearing on the issue, the Commission determines that a correctional facility has not complied with the audit findings, the Commission shall:<section prefix="(i)">petition a circuit court with venue over the proceeding for a court order requiring the correctional facility to comply with the audit findings; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">issue an order to cease operation of the correctional facility or any of its correctional elements, procedures, or functions.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Commission shall provide to a correctional facility reasonable notice of a hearing under paragraph (1) of this subsection.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Commission may subpoena witnesses and hold public hearings in accordance with Title 10, Subtitle 2 of the State Government Article before making a final decision on whether to seek a court order or close a correctional facility or any of its correctional elements, procedures, or functions.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
