<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gcs" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="7-205" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcs-7-205</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Commission has the exclusive power to:<section prefix="(1)">authorize the parole of an individual sentenced under the laws of the State to any correctional facility in the State;</section><section prefix="(2)">negotiate, enter into, and sign predetermined parole release agreements as provided under subsection (b) of this section;</section><section prefix="(3)">hear cases for parole in which:<section prefix="(i)">the Commissioner of Correction, after reviewing the recommendation of the appropriate managing official, objects to a parole;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the inmate was convicted of a homicide;</section><section prefix="(iii)">the inmate is serving a sentence of life imprisonment; or</section><section prefix="(iv)">the parole hearing is open to the public under &#xA7; 7-304 of this title;</section></section><section prefix="(4)">hear exceptions to recommendations of a hearing examiner or a commissioner acting as a hearing examiner;</section><section prefix="(5)">review summarily all recommendations of a hearing examiner or a commissioner acting as a hearing examiner to which an exception has not been filed;</section><section prefix="(6)">hear a case for parole in absentia when an individual who was sentenced in this State to serve a term of imprisonment is in a correctional facility of a jurisdiction other than this State;</section><section prefix="(7)">hear cases of parole revocation; and</section><section prefix="(8)">if delegated by the Governor, hear cases involving an alleged violation of a conditional pardon.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The Commission may negotiate, enter into, and sign a predetermined parole release agreement with the Commissioner of Correction and an inmate under the jurisdiction of the Commission.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The agreement may provide for the release of the inmate on parole at a predetermined time if, during the inmate's term of confinement, the inmate participates in the programs designated by the Commission and fulfills any other conditions specified in the agreement.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">This subsection does not affect any diminution of an inmate's term of confinement awarded under Title 3, Subtitle 7 and &#xA7;&#xA7; 9-506 and 9-513 of this article.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Each commissioner has visitorial powers over any correctional facility in which an individual is confined on a criminal charge, whether the correctional facility is operated by the State or by a county or municipal corporation of the State.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">As necessary to carry out its duties, the Commission may:<section prefix="(1)">issue subpoenas requiring the attendance and testimony of witnesses;</section><section prefix="(2)">administer oaths; and</section><section prefix="(3)">examine witnesses under oath, including any inmate who is confined in a correctional facility operated by the State or by a county or municipal corporation of the State.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A person who is personally served with a subpoena and who fails to appear or refuses to testify before the Commission is guilty of a misdemeanor and on conviction is subject to a fine of not more than $100.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The fine imposed under paragraph (1) of this subsection shall be paid into the General Fund of the State.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">A witness who makes a false statement relating to a matter that is material to the Commission's inquiry while testifying before the Commission is guilty of perjury and on conviction is subject to the penalty of &#xA7; 9-101 of the Criminal Law Article.</section>
  </text>
</law>
