<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcs" order_by="gcs" level="1">Correctional Services</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcs-11-316</section_number>
  <catch_line>Except as provided in subsection (c) of this section, the Commissioner may place an inmate in a cent...</catch_line>
  <order_by>316</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Except as provided in subsection (c) of this section, the Commissioner may place an inmate in a center if the inmate:<section prefix="(1)">is a resident of:<section prefix="(i)">the county in which the center is located; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">for a regional center, one of the counties in the region;</section></section><section prefix="(2)">has:<section prefix="(i)">less than 6 months remaining on a sentence;</section><section prefix="(ii)">less than 6 months remaining until a determined parole date; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">a sentence of 3 years or less; and</section></section><section prefix="(3)">has been screened by a center staff member and approved by the center director as provided under subsection (b) of this section.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A center staff member shall screen an inmate for placement in a center.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">After a review of the screening data, the center director may approve a placement based on screening standards that are established by the community advisory board, the center director, and the Commissioner.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The screening standards shall include a presentence investigation report if available and a complete record of previous convictions.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This subsection applies only to Cecil County.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Commissioner may place an inmate in a center operated by Cecil County if the inmate:<section prefix="(i)">has been committed by the court to the custody of the Commissioner;</section><section prefix="(ii)">is a legal resident of Cecil County;</section><section prefix="(iii)">has:<section prefix="1.">less than 6 months remaining on a sentence;</section><section prefix="2.">less than 6 months remaining until a determined parole date; or</section><section prefix="3.">a sentence of 3 years or less; and</section></section><section prefix="(iv)">has been screened by a center staff member and approved by the center director in accordance with subsection (b) of this section.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The court may recommend that an inmate be placed in a center.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
