<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcs" order_by="gcs" level="1">Correctional Services</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcs-3-601</section_number>
  <catch_line>Promptly after an inmate is sentenced to the jurisdiction of the Division, the Division shall assemb...</catch_line>
  <order_by>601</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Promptly after an inmate is sentenced to the jurisdiction of the Division, the Division shall assemble an adequate case record for the inmate that includes:<section prefix="(1)">a description of the inmate;</section><section prefix="(2)">a photograph of the inmate;</section><section prefix="(3)">the family history of the inmate;</section><section prefix="(4)">any previous record of the inmate;</section><section prefix="(5)">a summary of the facts of each case for which the inmate is serving a sentence; and</section><section prefix="(6)">the results of the physical, mental, and educational examination of the inmate required under subsection (b) of this section.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Division shall conduct a physical, mental, and educational examination of an inmate as soon as feasible after the individual is sentenced to the jurisdiction of the Division.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Based on the information assembled under subsection (a) of this section, the Division shall classify an inmate and assign the inmate to any available treatment, training, or employment that the Division considers appropriate.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">In accordance with regulations adopted by the Division, the managing official of each correctional facility shall maintain, as a part of an inmate's case record:<section prefix="(1)">an adequate record of the conduct, effort, and progress of the inmate during confinement; and</section><section prefix="(2)">a record of the character of any offense committed by the inmate and the nature and amount of punishment inflicted.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">To identify an inmate, the Division may photograph and fingerprint the inmate and record a description of the inmate's personal background data.</section>
  </text>
</law>
