<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcs" order_by="gcs" level="1">Correctional Services</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcs-3-215</section_number>
  <catch_line>In accordance with the State budget, the Division may appoint officers and other employees as necess...</catch_line>
  <order_by>215</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In accordance with the State budget, the Division may appoint officers and other employees as necessary to operate the Division and its units efficiently and effectively.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as otherwise provided in this subtitle, all officers and other employees of the Division shall be appointed and removed in accordance with the provisions of the State Personnel and Pensions Article.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The following positions are in the executive service, the management service, or are special appointments of the skilled service or the professional service in the State Personnel Management System:<section prefix="(i)">Commissioner;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Deputy Commissioner;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Assistant Commissioner;</section><section prefix="(iv)">industries general manager;</section><section prefix="(v)">warden;</section><section prefix="(vi)">facility administrator; and</section><section prefix="(vii)">assistant warden.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The warden of a correctional facility is the appointing officer for the officers and other employees of that facility.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The Commissioner is the appointing officer for the other officers and employees in the Division.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Division may provide a dwelling for a warden.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A warden may not receive any compensation or perquisite other than:<section prefix="(1)">the compensation and reimbursement provided under subsection (e) of this section; and</section><section prefix="(2)">if provided under subsection (c) of this section, a dwelling.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Officers and other employees are entitled to:<section prefix="(i)">compensation as provided in the State budget; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">reimbursement for expenses in accordance with the Standard State Travel Regulations.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Officers and other employees working 40 hours or more per week in a correctional facility are entitled to one free meal per shift as provided in the State budget.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Division may require an individual to pass a polygraph examination before being appointed to serve as a correctional officer in a correctional facility.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Commissioner shall adopt regulations governing the administration of the polygraph examination authorized under paragraph (1) of this subsection.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
