<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gcs" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="8-107" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcs-8-107</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Commission consists of the following 12 members:<section prefix="(1)">the Attorney General;</section><section prefix="(2)">the Secretary of General Services;</section><section prefix="(3)">the Secretary of Budget and Management; and</section><section prefix="(4)">the following nine members appointed by the Governor with the advice and consent of the Senate:<section prefix="(i)">two members of the public who are not directly employed in the field of corrections;</section><section prefix="(ii)">two correctional personnel from State government;</section><section prefix="(iii)">two correctional personnel from local government;</section><section prefix="(iv)">one official or employee of a national correctional accreditation organization;</section><section prefix="(v)">one elected official from a local governing body; and</section><section prefix="(vi)">one member who is licensed, certified, or registered by the State as a mental health or medical professional.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection:<section prefix="(i)">the term of a member of the Commission is 3 years; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">the terms of the members of the Commission are staggered as required by the terms provided for members of the Commission on October 1, 1999.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The Attorney General, Secretary of General Services, and Secretary of Budget and Management shall serve as ex officio members of the Commission.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">An ex officio member of the Commission may serve personally at any Commission meeting or designate a representative from the ex officio member's unit who may act at any Commission meeting to the same effect as if the ex officio member were personally present.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">At the end of a term, a member continues to serve until a successor is appointed and qualifies.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A member who is appointed after a term has begun serves only for the remainder of the term and until a successor is appointed and qualifies.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
