<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcs" order_by="gcs" level="1">Correctional Services</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcs-3-904</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this section the following words have the meanings indicated....</catch_line>
  <order_by>904</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Incompetent" means the state of mind of an inmate who, as a result of a mental disorder or mental retardation, lacks awareness:<section prefix="(i)">of the fact of the inmate's impending execution; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">that the inmate is to be executed for the crime of murder.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Inmate" means an individual who has been convicted of murder and sentenced to death.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">An inmate is not incompetent under this section merely because the inmate's competence depends on continuing treatment, including the use of medication.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The State may not execute a sentence of death against an inmate who has become incompetent.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A petition that alleges that an inmate is incompetent and that seeks to revoke a warrant of execution against the inmate may be filed by:<section prefix="(i)">the inmate;</section><section prefix="(ii)">if the inmate is represented by counsel, counsel for the inmate; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">if the inmate is not represented by counsel, any other person on the inmate's behalf.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The petition shall be filed in the circuit court of the county in which the inmate is confined.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">On the filing of the petition, the court may stay any warrant of execution that was previously issued and has not yet expired.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The petition must be accompanied by an affidavit of at least one psychiatrist that:<section prefix="(i)">is based, at least in part, on personal examination;</section><section prefix="(ii)">states that in the psychiatrist's medical opinion the inmate is incompetent; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">states the pertinent facts on which the opinion is based.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(5)">A copy of the petition shall be served on the Attorney General and the Office of the State's Attorney that prosecuted the inmate, in accordance with the service requirements of the Maryland Rules.</section>
      <section prefix="(6)">Unless the inmate is already represented by counsel, the court promptly shall appoint the public defender or, if the public defender for good cause declines representation, other counsel to represent the inmate in the proceeding.</section>
      <section prefix="(7)">Unless the State's Attorney stipulates to the inmate's incompetence, the State's Attorney shall cause the inmate to be examined and evaluated by one or more psychiatrists selected by the State's Attorney.</section>
      <section prefix="(8)">If the inmate's request is reasonable and timely made, an inmate is entitled to be independently examined by a psychiatrist that the inmate selects.</section>
      <section prefix="(9)">Unless, with the court's approval, the parties waive a hearing, the administrative judge of the court shall designate a time for an evidentiary hearing to determine the inmate's competence.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A hearing under this section shall be held without a jury:<section prefix="(i)">in court;</section><section prefix="(ii)">at the place where the inmate is confined; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">at another convenient place.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">At the hearing, the inmate:<section prefix="(i)">subject to reasonable restrictions related to the inmate's condition, may be present;</section><section prefix="(ii)">through counsel, may offer evidence, cross-examine witnesses against the inmate, and make argument; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">has the burden of establishing incompetence by a preponderance of the evidence.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The court shall enter an order that:<section prefix="(1)">declares the inmate to be competent or incompetent; and</section><section prefix="(2)">states the findings on which the declaration is based.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(g)">If the court finds the inmate to be competent, the court immediately:<section prefix="(1)">shall lift any stay of a warrant of execution that was previously issued and has not yet expired; or</section><section prefix="(2)">if all previously issued warrants of execution have expired, shall notify the court that imposed the sentence of death and request that the court issue a new warrant of execution.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(h)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If the court finds the inmate to be incompetent, the court shall:<section prefix="(i)">stay any warrant of execution that was previously issued and has not yet expired; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">remand the case to the court in which the sentence of death was imposed.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The court in which the sentence of death was imposed shall strike the sentence of death and enter in its place a sentence of life imprisonment without the possibility of parole.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The sentence of life imprisonment without the possibility of parole imposed under paragraph (2) of this subsection is mandatory and may not be suspended wholly or partly.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(i)">
      <section prefix="(1)">There is no right of appeal from an order issued by a circuit court under this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Notwithstanding paragraph (1) of this subsection, either party may seek review in the Court of Appeals by filing an application for leave to appeal in accordance with the Maryland Rules.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">If an application for leave to appeal is filed, the Court of Appeals may stay any warrant of execution that was previously issued and has not yet expired.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(j)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Not earlier than 6 months after a finding of competence, the inmate may petition the court for a redetermination of competence.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The petition must be accompanied by an affidavit of at least one psychiatrist that:<section prefix="(i)">is based, at least in part, on personal examination;</section><section prefix="(ii)">states that in the psychiatrist's medical opinion the inmate is incompetent;</section><section prefix="(iii)">states that the incompetence arose since the previous finding of competence; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">states the pertinent facts on which each opinion is based, including the facts that show the change in the inmate's condition since the previous finding.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Proceedings on a petition under this subsection shall be in accordance with subsections (d) through (i) of this section.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(k)">The Maryland Rules shall govern:<section prefix="(1)">the form of petitions and all other pleadings; and</section><section prefix="(2)">except as otherwise provided in this section, the procedures to be followed by the circuit court in determining competency or incompetency and by the Court of Appeals in reviewing applications for leave to appeal.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(l)">This section does not affect the power of the Governor to stay execution of a sentence of death under &#xA7; 3-902(f) of this subtitle or to commute a sentence of death under &#xA7; 7-601 of this article.</section>
  </text>
</law>
