<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcs" order_by="gcs" level="1">Correctional Services</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcs-11-706</section_number>
  <catch_line>This section applies only in Calvert County....</catch_line>
  <order_by>706</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">This section applies only in Calvert County.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">At the time of sentencing or on a hearing of a motion for reconsideration of sentence, the court may sentence an individual who has been convicted of a crime to participate for a fixed period in the work release program at the Calvert County Detention Center.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">After an inmate enters the work release program, the sentencing judge or, if the sentencing judge is unable to act, the judge of any court in the County may:<section prefix="(i)">order the release of the inmate from custody; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">consider the supervisor's recommendations and report of the inmate's performance in making a determination to release the inmate.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Subject to the directives and orders of the courts in the County, the supervisor of the County work release program shall establish and administer the work release program.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">During reasonable hours, an inmate in the work release program may leave confinement to:<section prefix="(i)">work at gainful employment;</section><section prefix="(ii)">participate in an outside counseling or rehabilitative program; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">obtain other services that the supervisor of the program considers necessary.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(5)">
        <section prefix="(i)">An inmate who is employed in accordance with this subsection shall surrender to the supervisor of the program the inmate's total earnings, less payroll deductions required by law.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">From the earnings of the inmate, the supervisor shall deduct and disburse in the following order of priority:<section prefix="1.">food costs to the County;</section><section prefix="2.">lodging costs to the County;</section><section prefix="3.">travel costs to the County;</section><section prefix="4.">fines and costs imposed by the court;</section><section prefix="5.">amounts that the inmate is obligated to pay for support of a dependent; and</section><section prefix="6.">court-ordered payments for restitution.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">The supervisor of the program may assist in the financial management of the inmate's other bills and debts.</section>
        <section prefix="(iv)">The supervisor of the program shall:<section prefix="1.">credit to the inmate's account any remaining balance; and</section><section prefix="2.">pay the balance in the inmate's account to the inmate on final release from confinement.</section></section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(6)">An inmate employed in the community under this subsection is not an agent or employee of the County, the Sheriff, any judicial officer, or any public officer of the County.</section>
      <section prefix="(7)">An inmate who violates a trust or a condition that the supervisor establishes for conduct and employment is subject to:<section prefix="(i)">removal from the program; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">cancellation of any earned diminution of the inmate's term of confinement.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this subsection, "Program" means the Community Services Alternative Sentencing Program.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">There is a Community Services Alternative Sentencing Program in the County Department of Public Safety.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Program shall administer community service projects for individuals who are convicted of an offense and are referred to the Program by a court.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The County Commissioners may charge a reasonable fee to individuals who participate in the Program to help defray Program expenses.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">An individual who is sentenced to participate in the substance abuse treatment program at the County treatment facility shall pay a per diem fee in an amount that the court determines to cover food, lodging, clothing, and other expenses incidental to participation in the treatment program.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">A court may waive part or all of the fee based on an individual's ability to pay.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The County attorney may bring a civil action to collect any arrearage incidental to the per diem charge that remains unpaid 30 days after the individual's discharge from the County treatment facility.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Sheriff may:<section prefix="(i)">establish a pretrial release program that offers alternatives to pretrial detention; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">adopt regulations to administer the program.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A court may order an individual to participate in the pretrial release program if the individual:<section prefix="(i)">appears before the court after being charged and detained on bond; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">meets the eligibility requirements of paragraph (4) of this subsection.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The court may make the order at the imposition of bond, on review of bond, or any other time during the individual's pretrial detention.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">An individual is eligible for the pretrial release program if the individual:<section prefix="(i)">is recommended to the court for placement in the program by the program staff;</section><section prefix="(ii)">has no other charges for a felony or a violation of a crime of violence as defined in &#xA7; 14-101 of the Criminal Law Article pending in any jurisdiction; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">is not in detention for or been previously convicted of:<section prefix="1.">a crime of violence listed in &#xA7; 14-101 of the Criminal Law Article;</section><section prefix="2.">a felony; or</section><section prefix="3.">the crime of escape under &#xA7; 9-404 of the Criminal Law Article.</section></section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
