<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gcs" order_by="" level="1">Correctional Services</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gcs-11-319</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>319</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In accordance with guidelines developed under paragraph (2) of this subsection, the center director or the director's designee may grant an inmate the privilege of leaving the confines of a center for the following purposes:<section prefix="(i)">employment or seeking employment;</section><section prefix="(ii)">educational programs;</section><section prefix="(iii)">vocational training;</section><section prefix="(iv)">community and civic activities;</section><section prefix="(v)">volunteer work;</section><section prefix="(vi)">athletic competition;</section><section prefix="(vii)">personal or family visits; or</section><section prefix="(viii)">other similar rehabilitative activities.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The guidelines for leave shall be developed by the county or counties that operate the center, reviewed by the community advisory board, and approved by the Secretary.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">When outside the confines of a center, an inmate shall carry, at all times, a copy of the form signed by the center director or the director's designee containing the terms and conditions governing the grant of leave.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">An inmate on leave shall be deemed to be in the custody of the center to the same extent, and subject to the same supervision and control, as an inmate actually in confinement in the Division of Correction.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">An inmate who escapes while on leave under this section is subject to the penalties of &#xA7; 9-404 of the Criminal Law Article.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The center director or the director's designee shall collect the earnings of an inmate, less payroll deductions required by law.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The center director or the director's designee shall keep an accurate account of the earnings of an inmate.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">From the earnings of an inmate, the center director may deduct:<section prefix="(i)">an amount determined by the director to be the cost of providing food, lodging, and clothing to the inmate;</section><section prefix="(ii)">actual and necessary food, travel, and other expenses incidental to the inmate's participation in work release and rehabilitation programs;</section><section prefix="(iii)">any amount required by court order or agreement of the inmate, and not otherwise deducted, for the support of dependents; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">court ordered restitution payments.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Except as provided in subparagraph (ii) of this paragraph, any remaining balance shall be credited to the inmate's account and paid to the inmate on release.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">If approved by the director, any remaining balance may be paid to the inmate on the request of the inmate.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
