<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gec" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="6-401" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gec-6-401</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Eligible economic development project" means an economic development project that:<section prefix="(1)">establishes or expands a business facility within a qualified distressed county; and</section><section prefix="(2)">is approved for a project tax credit or a start-up tax credit in accordance with this subtitle.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Eligible project cost" means the cost and expense a qualified business entity incurs to acquire, construct, rehabilitate, install, or equip an eligible economic development project.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Eligible project cost" includes:<section prefix="(i)">the cost of:</section><section prefix="(ii)">the interest cost before and during the acquisition, construction, installation, and equipping of the project, and for up to 2 years after project completion; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">legal, accounting, financial, printing, recording, filing, and other fees and expenses incurred to finance the project.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Eligible start-up cost" means a qualified business entity's cost to furnish and equip a new location for ordinary business functions.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Eligible start-up cost" includes:<section prefix="(i)">the cost of computers, nonrecurring costs of fixed telecommunications equipment, furnishings, and office equipment; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">expenditures for moving costs, separation costs, and other costs directly related to moving from outside of the State to a location in a qualified distressed county.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"Project tax credit" means a tax credit for eligible project costs allowed under &#xA7; 6-403 of this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">"Qualified business entity" means a person that:<section prefix="(1)"><section prefix="(i)">conducts or operates a trade or business in the State; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">operates in the State and is exempt from taxation under &#xA7; 501(c)(3) or (4) of the Internal Revenue Code; and</section></section><section prefix="(2)">is certified in accordance with &#xA7; 6-402 of this subtitle as qualifying for a project tax credit or a start-up tax credit under this subtitle.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Qualified position" means a position that:<section prefix="(i)">is a full-time position and is of indefinite duration;</section><section prefix="(ii)">pays at least 150% of the federal minimum wage;</section><section prefix="(iii)">is in a qualified distressed county;</section><section prefix="(iv)">is newly created because a business facility begins or expands in one location in a qualified distressed county; and</section><section prefix="(v)">is filled.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Qualified position" does not include a position that is:<section prefix="(i)">created when an employment function is shifted from an existing business facility of a business entity in the State to another business facility of the same business entity if the position is not a net new job in the State;</section><section prefix="(ii)">created through a change in ownership of a trade or business;</section><section prefix="(iii)">created through a consolidation, merger, or restructuring of a business entity if the position is not a net new job in the State;</section><section prefix="(iv)">created when an employment function is contractually shifted from an existing business entity in the State to another business entity if the position is not a net new job in the State; or</section><section prefix="(v)">filled for a period of less than 12 months.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(h)">"Start-up tax credit" means a tax credit for eligible start-up costs allowed under &#xA7; 6-404 of this subtitle.</section>
  </text>
</law>
