<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gec" order_by="gec" level="1">Economic Development</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gec-5-512</section_number>
  <catch_line>The Authority exercises its powers and performs its duties subject to the authority of the Secretary...</catch_line>
  <order_by>512</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Authority exercises its powers and performs its duties subject to the authority of the Secretary.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Authority may:<section prefix="(1)">adopt bylaws for the conduct of its business;</section><section prefix="(2)">adopt a seal;</section><section prefix="(3)">maintain offices in the State;</section><section prefix="(4)">sue and be sued in its own name;</section><section prefix="(5)">retain consultants;</section><section prefix="(6)">use the services of governmental units;</section><section prefix="(7)">contract for and accept, to carry out this subtitle, a loan or grant from the federal government, a political subdivision of the State, or any other source;</section><section prefix="(8)">purchase, receive, lease as lessee, or otherwise acquire, sell, mortgage, lease as lessor, pledge, administer, dispose of, or otherwise deal with property given as collateral under a loan agreement on the terms and conditions it considers advisable;</section><section prefix="(9)">adopt regulations necessary to carry out its powers;</section><section prefix="(10)">acquire or take assignments of loan documents; and</section><section prefix="(11)">do anything necessary or convenient to carry out its powers.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Authority shall:<section prefix="(1)">in its internal functions, follow the procedures of the State that govern the purchase of office space, supplies, facilities, materials, equipment, and professional services;</section><section prefix="(2)">keep proper records of its accounts;</section><section prefix="(3)">keep separate records for:<section prefix="(i)">the Small Business Development Contract Financing Fund under Part III of this subtitle;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the Small Business Development Guaranty Fund under Part IV of this subtitle;</section><section prefix="(iii)">the Equity Participation Investment Program Fund under Part V of this subtitle; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">the Small Business Surety Bond Fund under Part VI of this subtitle; and</section></section><section prefix="(4)">on or before December 31 of each year, submit a report on its condition and operations to the Governor and, in accordance with &#xA7; 2-1246 of the State Government Article, to the General Assembly.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
