<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gec" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="3-409" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gec-3-409</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Board consists of the following 15 members:<section prefix="(1)">one member of the Senate of Maryland appointed by the President of the Senate;</section><section prefix="(2)">one member of the House of Delegates appointed by the Speaker of the House; and</section><section prefix="(3)">the following members appointed by the Governor with the advice of the Secretary and the chair of the Governor's Workforce Investment Board:<section prefix="(i)">five representatives of business, of which three shall represent employers with fewer than 100 employees;</section><section prefix="(ii)">three representatives of organized labor;</section><section prefix="(iii)">one representative from the Maryland Higher Education Commission;</section><section prefix="(iv)">one representative from the State Department of Education;</section><section prefix="(v)">one representative from the Governor's Workforce Investment Board; and</section><section prefix="(vi)">two representatives of the general public.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The term of a member appointed under subsection (a)(3) of this section is 3 years.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The terms of the members appointed under subsection (a)(3) of this section are staggered as required by the terms provided for members of the Board on October 1, 2008.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">At the end of a term, a member continues to serve until a successor is appointed and qualifies.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">A member who is appointed after a term has begun serves only for the rest of the term and until a successor is appointed and qualifies.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A member of the Board:<section prefix="(1)">may not receive compensation as a member of the Board; but</section><section prefix="(2)">is entitled to reimbursement for expenses under the Standard State Travel Regulations.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Governor shall designate the chair of the Board.</section>
  </text>
</law>
