<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gec" order_by="" level="1">Economic Development</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gec-5-325</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>325</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Subject to the restrictions of this subtitle, the Department or Authority may impose the terms and conditions on financial assistance from the Fund as either considers appropriate.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in paragraph (2), (3), or (4) of this subsection, financial assistance from the Fund may not exceed 70% of the total costs of the project being financed.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Financial assistance from the Fund may constitute 100% of the total costs of the project being financed if:<section prefix="(i)">the recipient is the Corporation; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">the financial assistance is for:<section prefix="1.">an arts and entertainment enterprise;</section><section prefix="2.">an arts and entertainment project; or</section><section prefix="3.">a qualified distressed county project.</section></section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Except as provided in subparagraph (ii) of this paragraph, financial assistance from the Fund:<section prefix="1.">may be used to finance up to 50% of the costs of construction, purchase, or renovation of real property, fixtures, or equipment related to a child care facility; but</section><section prefix="2.">may not be used for working capital, supplies, or inventory related to a child care facility.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">Financial assistance from the Fund may be used to finance up to 20% of the costs described in subparagraph (i) of this paragraph incurred by a business that has received or will receive a day care loan insured by the Maryland Industrial Development Financing Authority.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(4)">Financial assistance for preparation of a strategy or plan for economic development of a county or municipal corporation may not exceed:<section prefix="(i)">50% of the costs of preparation; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">$50,000 in a 3-year period.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A loan from the Fund shall bear an interest rate below the market rate of interest, as determined by the Department, if the loan is for:<section prefix="(i)">a significant strategic economic development opportunity; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">a specialized economic development opportunity.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A loan from the Fund for a qualified distressed county project shall bear an interest rate determined by the Department or the Authority.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A loan from the Fund shall bear an interest rate not exceeding one-eighth of 1% plus the net interest cost of the most recent State general obligation bond issue preceding the approval of the loan if the loan is:<section prefix="(i)">for a local economic development opportunity; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">to a local government.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">A loan from the Fund may not bear an interest rate of less than 3% unless:<section prefix="(i)">the project funded by the loan is located in an area of high unemployment; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">the Department determines that the borrower is carrying out a compelling economic development initiative.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Department may waive interest during the first 2 years of the term of a loan from the Fund.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If a borrower defaults on a loan from the Fund, the Department may impose an interest rate that exceeds the limits set forth in subsection (c)(1) or (3) of this section.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The term of a loan from the Fund may not exceed:<section prefix="(1)">for working capital, 3 years;</section><section prefix="(2)">for financing equipment, furnishings, or fixtures, the lesser of 15 years or the useful life of the asset, as determined by the Department;</section><section prefix="(3)">for financing the construction or acquisition of buildings and real property, 25 years; and</section><section prefix="(4)">for financing the redevelopment of a qualified brownfields site or a qualified distressed county project, a term approved by the Department or Authority.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
