<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gec" order_by="" level="1">Economic Development</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gec-12-209</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>209</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Subject to subsection (c) of this section, the special fund for the development district may be used for any of the following purposes as determined by the governing body of the political subdivision:<section prefix="(1)">a purpose specified in &#xA7; 12-207 of this subtitle;</section><section prefix="(2)">accumulated to pay debt service on bonds to be issued later;</section><section prefix="(3)">payment or reimbursement of debt service, or payments under an agreement described in subsection (b) of this section, that the political subdivision is obliged under a general or limited obligation to pay, or has paid, on or relating to bonds issued by the State, a political subdivision, or the revenue authority of Prince George's County if the proceeds were used for a purpose specified in &#xA7; 12-207 of this subtitle; or</section><section prefix="(4)">payment to the political subdivision for any other legal purpose.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Subject to paragraph (2) of this subsection, the political subdivision that has created a special fund for a development district may pledge under an agreement that amounts deposited to the special fund shall be paid over to secure payment on MEDCO obligations.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The agreement shall:<section prefix="(i)">be in writing;</section><section prefix="(ii)">be executed by the political subdivision making the pledge, the Maryland Economic Development Corporation, and the other persons that the governing body of the political subdivision determines; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">run to the benefit of and be enforceable on behalf of the holders of the MEDCO obligations secured by the agreement.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">If bonds are outstanding with respect to a development district, the special fund may be used as described in subsection (a) of this section in any fiscal year only if:<section prefix="(1)">the balance of the special fund exceeds the unpaid debt service payable on the bonds in the fiscal year; and</section><section prefix="(2)">the special fund is not restricted so as to prohibit the use.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The issuance of bonds pledging the full faith and credit of the political subdivision shall comply with appropriate county or municipal charter requirements.</section>
  </text>
</law>
