<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gec" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="5-555" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gec-5-555</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Authority shall administer the Fund.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Fund is a special, nonlapsing fund that is not subject to reversion under &#xA7; 7-302 of the State Finance and Procurement Article.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Treasurer shall hold the Fund separately, and the Comptroller shall account for the Fund.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Fund consists of:<section prefix="(1)">money drawn from the Small Business Development Guaranty Fund established under Part IV of this subtitle;</section><section prefix="(2)">money the State appropriates to the Fund;</section><section prefix="(3)">money made available to the Fund through federal programs or private contributions;</section><section prefix="(4)">proceeds from the sale, disposition, lease, or rental by the Authority of collateral related to equity participation financing;</section><section prefix="(5)">premiums, fees, royalties, and repayments of principal, interest, and investments paid by and on behalf of enterprises to the Authority under the terms of equity participation financing; and</section><section prefix="(6)">any other money made available under the Program.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Authority shall use the Fund to:<section prefix="(1)">purchase qualified securities that an enterprise issues to provide equity participation financing as the Program allows;</section><section prefix="(2)">provide guaranties of investments to expand the capital resources of enterprises;</section><section prefix="(3)">purchase advisory services and technical assistance consistent with the Program;</section><section prefix="(4)">purchase securities in which a fiduciary of the State may lawfully invest;</section><section prefix="(5)">provide equity participation financing as the Program allows; and</section><section prefix="(6)">pay for administrative, legal, and actuarial services that relate to the Program.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The Fund shall be self-sustaining and shall achieve investment returns on its portfolio in the form of:<section prefix="(1)">royalties from enterprises in amounts to be determined by the Authority; and</section><section prefix="(2)">interest payments from any debt securities.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">As needed for the Program, the Authority may withdraw from time to time up to a total of $2,000,000 from the Small Business Development Guaranty Fund and deposit the withdrawal into the Fund.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Treasurer shall invest the money of the Fund in the same manner as other State money may be invested.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Any investment earnings of the Fund shall be paid into the Fund.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(h)">On or before December 31 of each year, the Authority shall submit a report on the Program to the General Assembly in accordance with &#xA7; 2-1246 of the State Government Article.</section>
  </text>
</law>
