<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gec" order_by="" level="1">Economic Development</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gec-5-338</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>338</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Department shall determine whether a brownfields site is a qualified brownfields site based on whether the property:<section prefix="(1)">is located in a densely populated urban center and is substantially underutilized; or</section><section prefix="(2)">is an existing or former industrial or commercial site that poses a threat to public health or the environment.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">When reviewing qualified brownfields sites for financial assistance under this part, the Department may consider:<section prefix="(1)">the feasibility of redevelopment;</section><section prefix="(2)">the public benefit to the community and the State through the redevelopment of the property;</section><section prefix="(3)">the extent of releases or threatened releases at the brownfields site and the degree to which the cleanup and redevelopment of the brownfields site will protect public health or the environment;</section><section prefix="(4)">the potential to attract or retain manufacturing or other economically significant employers;</section><section prefix="(5)">the absence of identifiable and financially solvent responsible persons; or</section><section prefix="(6)">any other factor relevant and appropriate to economic development.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A person may submit a request to the Department to determine whether the person qualifies for financial assistance for the potential redevelopment of a brownfields site when the person:<section prefix="(1)">applies to participate in the Voluntary Cleanup Program under Title 7, Subtitle 5 of the Environment Article; or</section><section prefix="(2)">receives approval from the Department of the Environment to implement a corrective action plan under Title 4 of the Environment Article.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Department shall notify the person whether the person qualifies for financial assistance for the redevelopment of a brownfields site within 30 days after the Department receives a request under subsection (c) of this section if:<section prefix="(i)">the Department of the Environment approves the participation in the Voluntary Cleanup Plan or a corrective action plan; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">the Department or Authority approves the financial assistance.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The notice shall specify which of the criteria in subsection (b) of this section that the person meets.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">When evaluating potential qualified brownfields sites, the Department shall consult with:<section prefix="(1)">the Department of the Environment, the Department of Planning, and relevant local officials;</section><section prefix="(2)">the neighboring community and any citizens groups located in the community;</section><section prefix="(3)">representatives of State and local environmental organizations;</section><section prefix="(4)">public health experts; and</section><section prefix="(5)">any other person the Department considers appropriate.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
