<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gec" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="10-212" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gec-10-212</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Authority may:<section prefix="(1)">develop, establish, acquire, improve, own, operate, and maintain developments and projects in the State; and</section><section prefix="(2)">pay the cost of developments or projects, including improvements to any waterways at a development or project, from:<section prefix="(i)">the proceeds of bonds;</section><section prefix="(ii)">other money available under this subtitle; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">money from the State or federal government or any of their units or instrumentalities.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Construction of a development may not begin unless a comprehensive study establishes that the construction and operation of the development would be economically and environmentally sound.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Except for the Center, construction of a development may not begin unless:<section prefix="(1)">an analysis of the economic benefits of the proposed development is submitted to the Legislative Policy Committee, in accordance with &#xA7; 2-1246 of the State Government Article; and</section><section prefix="(2)">the Legislative Policy Committee is given 45 days after receipt to comment on the proposal.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This subsection does not apply to facilities constructed on land leased or sold by the Authority to a private entity.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Before contracting to construct a facility at a development or project, the Authority shall solicit sealed bids.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">All plans and any issue of bonds to finance a development or project require approval by the Board of Public Works by resolution before the bonds are sold.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">All leases of real property and plans and contracts for the acquisition conveyance of real property require approval by the Board of Public Works.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
