<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gec" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="5-320" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gec-5-320</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">To be eligible for financial assistance from the Fund, an applicant shall be:<section prefix="(1)">a local economic development fund that meets the criteria set forth in Part V of this subtitle; or</section><section prefix="(2)">an individual, private business, not-for-profit entity, or local government, or the Corporation that intends to use the requested financial assistance for a project that:<section prefix="(i)">except as provided in subsection (b) of this section, is in an eligible industry sector under &#xA7; 5-321 of this subtitle; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">has a strong potential for expanding or retaining employment opportunities in the State.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A project need not be in an eligible industry sector if the applicant:<section prefix="(1)">is located in a qualified distressed county; or</section><section prefix="(2)"><section prefix="(i)">is a local government or the Corporation; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">does not intend to use the financial assistance to carry out a project that benefits a particular private sector entity.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">In form and content acceptable to the Department, an applicant for financial assistance from the Fund shall submit to the Department an application that contains:<section prefix="(1)">the information that the Department or Authority considers necessary to evaluate the request for financial assistance; and</section><section prefix="(2)">for a qualified distressed county project:<section prefix="(i)">a marketing plan designed to market the project to prospective businesses;</section><section prefix="(ii)">a statement of planned marketing expenditures as a percent of the total financial assistance amount requested; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">a plan for the project that is consistent with the county's local strategic economic development plan as to the location and type of project.</section></section></section>
  </text>
</law>
