<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gec" order_by="gec" level="1">Economic Development</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gec-5-431</section_number>
  <catch_line>If the requirements of this section are satisfied, and subject to &#xA7; 5-432 of this subtitle, the Aut...</catch_line>
  <order_by>431</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">If the requirements of this section are satisfied, and subject to &#xA7; 5-432 of this subtitle, the Authority may use the Fund to:<section prefix="(1)">insure the payment of any of the principal of, redemption or prepayment premiums or penalties on, and interest on authorized purpose obligations; and</section><section prefix="(2)">pay or insure the payment of fees or premiums for insurance, guarantees, or other credit support in connection with financial assistance under this subtitle.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Based on factors it considers relevant, the Authority shall determine, in its sole discretion, that the economic impact of the transaction will be substantial.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Authority shall find:<section prefix="(1)">that the transaction will not result in:<section prefix="(i)">the removal from one county to another county of the business operations of any person who benefits from the transaction; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">the abandonment of the business operations in the State of any person who benefits from the transaction; or</section></section><section prefix="(2)">if the transaction will result in removal or abandonment, that the transaction will:<section prefix="(i)">discourage the business from leaving the State; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">preserve the competitive position of the business in its industry.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Financial assistance under this section may only be used in connection with a retail establishment if the Authority determines, in its sole discretion, that the financial assistance will accomplish the purposes of this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The Authority shall find that the Authority will not be required, except on default, to operate, service, or maintain any business.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The authorized purpose obligations shall be secured in a manner that the Authority approves.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">Financial assistance from the Fund provided under this section may not exceed an aggregate amount of $2,500,000 for a single transaction.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">The aggregate amount of insurance provided under this section for a single authorized purpose obligation may not exceed:<section prefix="(1)">for an export-related financing transaction, 90% of the total of the principal of, redemption or prepayment premiums or penalties on, and interest on, the authorized purpose obligation; or</section><section prefix="(2)">for a transaction other than an export-related financing transaction, 80% of the total of the principal of, redemption or prepayment premiums or penalties on, and interest on, the authorized purpose obligation.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
