<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gec" order_by="gec" level="1">Economic Development</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gec-13-703</section_number>
  <catch_line>The Council consists of the following 26 members:...</catch_line>
  <order_by>703</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Council consists of the following 26 members:<section prefix="(1)">two commissioners from each member county;</section><section prefix="(2)">the Director of Economic Development from each member county;</section><section prefix="(3)">two mayors from each member county or their representatives, appointed by the respective chapters of the Maryland Municipal League for each member county;</section><section prefix="(4)">the chair of each member county's legislative delegation to the House of Delegates, or the chair's designee;</section><section prefix="(5)">the two members of the Senate of Maryland representing the member counties in Districts 1 and 2;</section><section prefix="(6)">six private citizens, two from each member county, who are:<section prefix="(i)">appointed by their respective commissioners;</section><section prefix="(ii)">not listed under paragraph (1), (2), (3), (4), or (5) of this subsection; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">neither elected officials nor employees of a unit of local government.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A member who qualifies because of the member's elected or appointed position is a member of the Council only during the member's term of office in the elected or appointed position.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A member appointed:<section prefix="(i)">under subsection (a)(3) of this section, serves at the pleasure of the commissioners for the county that the member represents;</section><section prefix="(ii)">under subsection (a)(4) of this section, shall reside in the member county that the member represents; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">under subsection (a)(6) of this section:</section><section prefix="1.">serves at the pleasure of the commissioners who appointed the member; and</section><section prefix="2.">has the same term as the commissioners who appointed the member.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">At the end of a term, a member continues to serve until a successor is appointed and qualifies.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">Except for an ex officio member, a member who is appointed after a term has begun serves only for the rest of the term and until a successor is appointed and qualifies.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
