<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gec" order_by="gec" level="1">Economic Development</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gec-10-101</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated....</catch_line>
  <order_by>101</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Board" means the Board of Directors of the Corporation.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Bond" means a bond or note of the Corporation issued under this subtitle.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Bond" includes:<section prefix="(i)">a bond anticipation note;</section><section prefix="(ii)">a revenue anticipation note;</section><section prefix="(iii)">a grant anticipation note;</section><section prefix="(iv)">a refunding bond;</section><section prefix="(v)">a note in the nature of commercial paper; and</section><section prefix="(vi)">any other evidence of indebtedness of the Corporation, whether a general or limited obligation.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">"Corporation" means the Maryland Economic Development Corporation.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"Cost" includes:<section prefix="(1)">the purchase price of a project;</section><section prefix="(2)">the cost to acquire any right, title, or interest in a project;</section><section prefix="(3)">the cost of any improvement;</section><section prefix="(4)">the amount to be paid to discharge each obligation necessary or desirable to vest title to any part of the project in the Corporation or other owner;</section><section prefix="(5)">the cost of any property, right, easement, franchise, and permit;</section><section prefix="(6)">the cost of labor and equipment;</section><section prefix="(7)">financing charges;</section><section prefix="(8)">interest before and during construction and, if the Corporation determines, for a limited period after the completion of construction;</section><section prefix="(9)">reserves for principal and interest and for improvements;</section><section prefix="(10)">the cost of revenue and cost estimates, engineering and legal services, plans, specifications, studies, surveys, demonstrations, and other expenses necessary or incident to determining the feasibility of an acquisition or improvement;</section><section prefix="(11)">administrative expenses; and</section><section prefix="(12)">other expenses as necessary or incident to:<section prefix="(i)">financing a project;</section><section prefix="(ii)">acquiring and improving a project;</section><section prefix="(iii)">placing a project in operation by the Corporation or other owner, including reasonable provision for working capital; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">operating and maintaining a project.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">"Finance" includes refinance.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">"Governmental unit" means a county, municipal corporation, unit of State or local government, or other public body created under State or local law.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">"Improve" means to add, alter, construct, equip, expand, extend, improve, install, reconstruct, rehabilitate, remodel, or repair.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">"Improvement" means addition, alteration, construction, equipping, expansion, extension, improvement, installation, reconstruction, rehabilitation, remodeling, or repair.</section>
    <section prefix="(j)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Person" has the meaning stated in &#xA7; 9-101 of this article.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Person" also includes:<section prefix="(i)">a person that is created, owned, or controlled by the Corporation or of which the Corporation is a member;</section><section prefix="(ii)">a for-profit or not-for-profit entity; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">a governmental unit.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(k)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Project" means any property, the acquisition or improvement of which the Board, in its sole discretion, determines by resolution will accomplish at least one of the legislative purposes listed in &#xA7; 10-104(b) of this subtitle, whether or not the property:<section prefix="(i)">is or will be used or operated for profit or not for profit;</section><section prefix="(ii)">is or will be located on a single site or multiple sites; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">may be financed by bonds, the interest on which is exempt from income taxation under federal law.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Project" includes:<section prefix="(i)">land or an interest in land;</section><section prefix="(ii)">structures, equipment, furnishings, rail or motor vehicles, barges, and boats;</section><section prefix="(iii)">property and rights related to the property, appurtenances, rights-of-way, franchises, and easements;</section><section prefix="(iv)">property that is functionally related and subordinate to property described in this subsection; and</section><section prefix="(v)">patents, licenses, and other rights necessary or useful in the improvement or operation of a project.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(l)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Revenues" means the income, revenue, and other money the Corporation receives from or in connection with a project, and all other income of the Corporation, subject to &#xA7; 10-115(11) of this subtitle.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Revenues" includes grants, rentals, rates, fees, and charges for the use of the services furnished or available.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
