<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gec" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="5-707" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gec-5-707</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">To the extent provided for in this section, a business entity is entitled to:<section prefix="(1)">the special property tax credit in &#xA7; 9-103 of the Tax - Property Article;</section><section prefix="(2)">the income tax credits in &#xA7; 10-702 of the Tax - General Article; and</section><section prefix="(3)">consideration for financial assistance from programs in Subtitle 1 of this title.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A business entity that moves into or locates in an enterprise zone on or after the date that the enterprise zone is designated under &#xA7; 5-704 of this subtitle may benefit from the incentives and initiatives in this section if:<section prefix="(1)">the business entity meets the requirements and conditions of the Code section applicable to each incentive or initiative;</section><section prefix="(2)">the respective political subdivision certifies that the business entity has complied with the standards that the subdivision submitted under &#xA7; 5-703(b)(5) of this subtitle;</section><section prefix="(3)">the business entity creates new or additional jobs or makes a capital investment to qualify for the property tax credit under &#xA7; 9-103 of the Tax - Property Article and the income tax credits under &#xA7; 10-702 of the Tax - General Article; and</section><section prefix="(4)">in considering whether the business entity qualifies for financial assistance from the programs in Subtitle 1 of this title, the Secretary determines that the business entity will create new or additional jobs.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The incentives and initiatives provided for in this section are not available to a business entity that:<section prefix="(1)">was in an enterprise zone before the date that the enterprise zone is designated, except for a capital investment or expansion of its labor force that occurs on or after the enterprise zone is designated; or</section><section prefix="(2)">is located in an enterprise zone that was designated under federal law unless the Secretary and the Board of Public Works consent to the designation.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in &#xA7; 10-702 of the Tax - General Article and &#xA7; 9-103 of the Tax - Property Article, the incentives and initiatives set forth in this section are available for 10 years after the date that an area is designated an enterprise zone.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A law enacted after the enactment of this section that eliminates or reduces the benefits available to a business entity under this section does not apply to a business entity that was in an enterprise zone before the effective date of the law.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Notwithstanding subsection (d) of this section, except for a business entity certified to receive a property tax credit under &#xA7; 9-103 of the Tax - Property Article for a tax year beginning before July 1, 2008, a business entity located in an enterprise zone may not receive the incentives and initiatives set forth in subsection (a)(1) and (2) of this section if the entity is located on land or within improvements owned by the federal government, the State, a county, or a municipal corporation unless the business entity has first utilized all applicable property tax exemptions under Title 7 of the Tax - Property Article, including entering into any available payment in lieu of tax agreement.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">Subparagraph (i) of this paragraph does not apply to a business entity leasing land or improvements owned by the Maryland Economic Development Corporation.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Notwithstanding subsection (d) of this section, a business entity located in a BRAC Revitalization and Incentive Zone established under Subtitle 13 of this title may not receive the property tax credit under &#xA7; 9-103 of the Tax - Property Article unless:<section prefix="(i)">the business entity qualified for the property tax credit before the date that the BRAC Revitalization and Incentive Zone is designated; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">the political subdivision where the business entity is located expressly grants the property tax credit to the business entity.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
