<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gec" order_by="gec" level="1">Economic Development</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gec-5-451</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this part the following words have the meanings indicated....</catch_line>
  <order_by>451</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this part the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Applicant" means the eligible business applying for fixed asset financing assisted by a linked deposit.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Eligible business" means a for-profit business that:<section prefix="(1)">is located in a qualified distressed county;</section><section prefix="(2)">is in good standing with each State regulatory authority with jurisdiction over the business of the applicant, including the State Workers' Compensation Commission, the Department of Assessments and Taxation, and the Department of Labor, Licensing, and Regulation; and</section><section prefix="(3)">employs 500 or fewer employees.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Fixed asset financing" means a commercial loan to finance:<section prefix="(i)">the acquisition or improvement of all or part of a building;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the acquisition or improvement of the land for the building if not already owned by the applicant; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">the acquisition or improvement of equipment.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Fixed asset financing" does not include refinancing an existing debt.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"Lender" means a financial institution that:<section prefix="(1)">is eligible to make commercial loans;</section><section prefix="(2)">is a public depository of State funds;</section><section prefix="(3)">agrees to receive linked deposits under this part; and</section><section prefix="(4)">is insured by the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">"Linked deposit" means a deposit that the Authority places with a lender that earns interest below the prevailing market rate for equivalent deposits made with the lender at the time of the deposit.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">"Program" means the Linked Deposit Program established under &#xA7; 5-452 of this subtitle.</section>
  </text>
</law>
