<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gec" order_by="gec" level="1">Economic Development</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gec-10-121</section_number>
  <catch_line>The Corporation may secure a bond by a trust agreement between the Corporation and a corporate trust...</catch_line>
  <order_by>121</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Corporation may secure a bond by a trust agreement between the Corporation and a corporate trustee.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A corporate trustee may be any trust company or bank that has the powers of a trust company in or outside the State.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A corporation or trust company incorporated in the State may:<section prefix="(i)">act as depository of bond proceeds or revenues; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">furnish an indemnity bond or pledge security that the Corporation requires.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The trust agreement or the resolution that provides for the issuance of a bond may:<section prefix="(1)">state the rights and remedies of bondholders and any trustee;</section><section prefix="(2)">contain provisions to protect and enforce the rights and remedies of bondholders;</section><section prefix="(3)">contain covenants stating the duties of the Corporation as to the custody, safeguarding, and application of money;</section><section prefix="(4)">restrict the individual rights of action of bondholders;</section><section prefix="(5)">provide for the payment of the bond proceeds and revenues to an officer, board, or depository that the Corporation determines with the safeguards and restrictions that the Corporation determines; and</section><section prefix="(6)">provide for the method of disbursement of the bond proceeds and revenues, with the safeguards and restrictions that the Corporation determines.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Expenses incurred in carrying out a trust agreement may be treated as part of the cost of operation of the Corporation.</section>
  </text>
</law>
