<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gec" order_by="gec" level="1">Economic Development</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gec-11-301</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated....</catch_line>
  <order_by>301</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Authority" means a corporation incorporated in accordance with this subtitle to act as a local redevelopment authority in accordance with criteria set by the United States Department of Defense or its military services under the federal Defense Base Closure and Realignment Act of 1990.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Authority" does not include:<section prefix="(i)">Bainbridge Development Corporation;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Holabird Working Group/Baltimore Development Corporation (BDC); or</section><section prefix="(iii)">PenMar Development Corporation.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Board" means the Board of Directors of an authority.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Bond" means a bond or note issued on behalf of an authority under this subtitle.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Bond" includes:<section prefix="(i)">a bond anticipation note;</section><section prefix="(ii)">a revenue anticipation note;</section><section prefix="(iii)">a grant anticipation note;</section><section prefix="(iv)">a refunding bond;</section><section prefix="(v)">a note in the nature of commercial paper; and</section><section prefix="(vi)">any other evidence of indebtedness issued on behalf of the authority, whether a general or limited obligation of the authority.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"Cost" includes:<section prefix="(1)">the purchase price of a project;</section><section prefix="(2)">the cost to acquire any right, title, or interest in a project;</section><section prefix="(3)">the amount to be paid to discharge each obligation necessary or desirable to vest title to any part of a project in the authority or other owner;</section><section prefix="(4)">the cost of any improvement;</section><section prefix="(5)">the cost of any property, right, easement, franchise, and permit;</section><section prefix="(6)">the cost of labor and equipment;</section><section prefix="(7)">financing charges;</section><section prefix="(8)">interest before and during construction and, if the authority determines, for a limited period after the completion of construction;</section><section prefix="(9)">reserves for principal and interest and for improvements;</section><section prefix="(10)">the cost of revenue estimates, engineering and legal services, plans, designs, specifications, surveys, investigations, demonstrations, studies, estimates of cost, and other expenses necessary or incident to determining the feasibility of an acquisition or improvement;</section><section prefix="(11)">administrative expenses; and</section><section prefix="(12)">other expenses necessary or incident to:<section prefix="(i)">financing a project;</section><section prefix="(ii)">acquiring and improving a project;</section><section prefix="(iii)">placing a project in operation, including reasonable provision for working capital; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">operating and maintaining a project.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">"Finance" includes refinance.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">"Improve" means to add, alter, construct, equip, expand, extend, improve, install, reconstruct, rehabilitate, remodel, or repair.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">"Improvement" means addition, alteration, construction, equipping, expansion, extension, improvement, installation, reconstruction, rehabilitation, remodeling, or repair.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Person" has the meaning stated in &#xA7; 9-101 of this article.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Person" also includes a political subdivision.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(j)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Project" means an undertaking to establish economic activity under this subtitle on property to be conveyed to an authority by the United States Department of Defense or a military service, whether or not a facility or property used or useful in connection with the undertaking:<section prefix="(i)">is or will be used for profit or not for profit;</section><section prefix="(ii)">is located on a single site or multiple sites; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">may be financed by bonds, the interest on which is exempt from taxation under federal law.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Project" includes:<section prefix="(i)">property and rights related to the property, appurtenances, rights-of-way, franchises, and easements;</section><section prefix="(ii)">structures, equipment, and furnishings;</section><section prefix="(iii)">property that is functionally related and subordinate to the project; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">patents, licenses, and other rights necessary or useful in the improvement or operation of a project.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(k)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Revenues" means the income, revenue, and other money an authority receives from or in connection with a project.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Revenues" includes grants, rentals, rates, fees, and charges for the use of the services furnished or available.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
