<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gec" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="10-434" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gec-10-434</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">There is a Maryland Stem Cell Research Fund.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The purpose of the Fund is to promote State-funded stem cell research and cures through grants and loans to public and private entities in the State.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Corporation shall administer the Fund.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Fund is a special, nonlapsing fund that is not subject to reversion under &#xA7; 7-302 of the State Finance and Procurement Article.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Treasurer shall hold the Fund separately, and the Comptroller shall account for the Fund.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The Fund consists of:<section prefix="(1)">appropriations as provided in the State budget; and</section><section prefix="(2)">any other money from any other source accepted for the benefit of the Fund.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">Money in the Fund may only be used to:<section prefix="(1)">award grants and loans for State-funded stem cell research, in accordance with the recommendations of the Commission;</section><section prefix="(2)">award grants and loans for facilities, capital leases, and capital equipment where State-funded stem cell research is conducted, in accordance with the recommendations of the Commission; and</section><section prefix="(3)">pay the costs necessary to administer the Fund.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Treasurer shall invest the money in the Fund in the same manner as other State money may be invested.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Any investment earnings shall be paid into the Fund.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(h)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Governor may include in the State budget bill each fiscal year an appropriation to the Fund.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Expenditures from the Fund may only be made in accordance with an appropriation approved by the General Assembly in the State budget or by an approved budget amendment.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
