<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gec" order_by="gec" level="1">Economic Development</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gec-12-105</section_number>
  <catch_line>To accomplish one or more of the legislative purposes listed in &#xA7; 12-103(b) of this subtitle, the l...</catch_line>
  <order_by>105</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">To accomplish one or more of the legislative purposes listed in &#xA7; 12-103(b) of this subtitle, the legislative body of a county or municipal corporation may adopt a resolution to create an industrial development authority in accordance with this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A resolution adopted under subsection (a), (f), or (g) of this section:<section prefix="(1)">is administrative in nature;</section><section prefix="(2)">is not subject to referendum; and</section><section prefix="(3)">in a county or municipal corporation that has a publicly elected chief executive, is subject to approval by the chief executive.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Subsection (a) of this section is self-executing and fully authorizes a county or municipal corporation to establish an authority, notwithstanding any other statutory or charter provision.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A resolution adopted under subsection (a) of this section shall include proposed articles of incorporation of the authority that state:<section prefix="(1)">the name of the authority, which shall be "Industrial Development Authority of (name of the incorporating county or municipal corporation)";</section><section prefix="(2)">that the authority is formed under this subtitle;</section><section prefix="(3)">the names, addresses, and terms of office of the initial members of the board of directors of the authority;</section><section prefix="(4)">the address of the principal office of the authority;</section><section prefix="(5)">the purposes for which the authority is formed; and</section><section prefix="(6)">the powers of the authority subject to the limitations on the powers of an authority under this subtitle.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The chief executive of the incorporating county or municipal corporation, or any other official designated in the resolution establishing the authority, shall execute and file the articles of incorporation of the authority for record with the State Department of Assessments and Taxation.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">When the State Department of Assessments and Taxation accepts the articles of incorporation for record, the authority becomes a body politic and corporate and an instrumentality of the incorporating county or municipal corporation.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Acceptance of the articles of incorporation for record by the State Department of Assessments and Taxation is conclusive evidence of the formation of the authority.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">By resolution, the legislative body of the incorporating county or municipal corporation may adopt an amendment to the articles of incorporation of the authority.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Articles of amendment may contain any provision that lawfully could be contained in articles of incorporation at the time of the amendment.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The articles of amendment shall be filed for record with the State Department of Assessments and Taxation.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The articles of amendment are effective as of the time the State Department of Assessments and Taxation accepts the articles for record.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">Acceptance of the articles of amendment for record by the State Department of Assessments and Taxation is conclusive evidence that the articles have been lawfully and properly adopted.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Subject to the provisions of this section and any limitations imposed by law on the impairment of contracts, the incorporating county or municipal corporation, in its sole discretion, by resolution may:<section prefix="(i)">set or change the structure, organization, procedures, programs, or activities of the authority; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">terminate the authority.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">On termination of an authority:<section prefix="(i)">title to all property of the authority shall be transferred to and vest in the incorporating county or municipal corporation; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">all obligations of the authority shall be transferred to and assumed by the incorporating county or municipal corporation.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
