<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gec" order_by="" level="1">Economic Development</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gec-5-1304</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>1304</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Within 60 days after a submission date, the Secretary, after receiving a recommendation of the Smart Growth Subcabinet, may designate one or more BRAC Revitalization and Incentive Zones from among the areas described in the applications timely submitted.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The designation of an area as a BRAC Revitalization and Incentive Zone is effective for 10 years, beginning on the date the first property in the BRAC Revitalization and Incentive Zone becomes a qualified property, as defined in &#xA7; 2-222 of the Tax - Property Article.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Secretary may not designate more than six BRAC Revitalization and Incentive Zones in a calendar year.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">A county may not receive more than two BRAC Revitalization and Incentive Zones.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">The precise location and boundaries of a BRAC Revitalization and Incentive Zone may be determined only on application to and approval by the Secretary.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The designation of the Secretary is final.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">At any time, a political subdivision may reapply to the Secretary to designate as a BRAC Revitalization and Incentive Zone an area that is not designated.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This subsection applies only to a political subdivision that is authorized under &#xA7; 7-211.3 of the Tax - Property Article to enter into a payment in lieu of tax agreement with a private developer for federal enclave property.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Secretary may not designate a BRAC Revitalization and Incentive Zone in a county until, in the judgment of the Secretary, the political subdivision has entered into good faith negotiations for a payment in lieu of tax agreement with all private developers of federal enclave property.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
