<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gec" order_by="" level="1">Economic Development</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gec-10-111</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>111</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as otherwise provided in this section, in exercising its powers, the Corporation:<section prefix="(i)">may carry out its corporate purposes without the consent of any State unit; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">is not subject to:<section prefix="1.">Title 12, Subtitles 1 through 3 of this article;</section><section prefix="2.">the following provisions of the State Finance and Procurement Article:</section><section prefix="3.">the following provisions of the State Government Article:</section><section prefix="4.">Article 41 of the Code.</section></section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Corporation is subject to the Public Information Act.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Corporation, its officers, and its employees are subject to the Public Ethics Law.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The officers and employees of the Corporation are not subject to:<section prefix="(i)">Division II of the State Personnel and Pensions Article; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">the provisions of Division I of the State Personnel and Pensions Article that govern the State Personnel Management System.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Corporation is a public body under Title 5, Subtitle 4 of this article, the Maryland Industrial Development Financing Authority Act, for purposes of applying for, receiving, and making agreements in connection with:<section prefix="(1)">a loan;</section><section prefix="(2)">a grant;</section><section prefix="(3)">insurance; or</section><section prefix="(4)">any other form of financial assistance.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Corporation is subject to the same State and local regulatory requirements as any private corporation.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">A project of the Corporation is subject to the zoning and subdivision regulations of the jurisdiction where it is located.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The Corporation, its officers, and its employees are subject to Title 12, Subtitle 4 of the State Finance and Procurement Article.</section>
  </text>
</law>
