<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gec" order_by="gec" level="1">Economic Development</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gec-12-404</section_number>
  <catch_line>A board of directors shall govern the district corporation....</catch_line>
  <order_by>404</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">A board of directors shall govern the district corporation.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Subject to paragraph (2) of this subsection, the board of a district corporation consists of five members appointed by the members of the district.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Appointment procedures shall be provided in the local law establishing the district.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">From among its members, the board shall elect a chair and other officers.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Three voting members of the board are a quorum.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The board may act on a resolution only by the affirmative vote of at least three voting members.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">A member of the board:<section prefix="(1)">may not receive compensation as a member of the board; but</section><section prefix="(2)">shall be reimbursed for expenses incurred in performing the member's duties.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The board shall exercise its powers by resolution.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">The board shall file an annual report with the governing body of the county or municipal corporation that includes:<section prefix="(1)">a financial statement for the preceding year;</section><section prefix="(2)">a proposed operating budget for the current fiscal year;</section><section prefix="(3)">any proposed revisions to the business plan; and</section><section prefix="(4)">a narrative statement or chart showing the results of operations in comparison to stated goals and objectives.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
