<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gec" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="5-1302" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gec-5-1302</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The following political subdivisions may apply to the Secretary to designate a BRAC Revitalization and Incentive Zone:<section prefix="(1)">a political subdivision for an area within that political subdivision;</section><section prefix="(2)">with the prior consent of the municipal corporation, a county on behalf of a municipal corporation for an area in the municipal corporation; or</section><section prefix="(3)">two or more political subdivisions jointly for an area astride their common boundaries.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The application shall:<section prefix="(1)">be in the form and manner and contain the information that the Secretary requires;</section><section prefix="(2)">contain sufficient information to allow the Secretary to determine if the proposed BRAC Revitalization and Incentive Zone meets the criteria in &#xA7; 5-1303 of this subtitle;</section><section prefix="(3)">be submitted for a political subdivision by its chief elected officer, or if none, its governing body; and</section><section prefix="(4)">state whether the political subdivision has examined the feasibility of creating educational or training opportunities for employers and employees of business entities located or to be located in the proposed BRAC Revitalization and Incentive Zone.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">After the Secretary's receipt of an application for designation of an area as a BRAC Revitalization and Incentive Zone or expansion of an existing zone under &#xA7; 5-1305 of this subtitle, the Secretary shall notify the members of the county delegation to the General Assembly for each county in which a zone is proposed to be located.</section>
  </text>
</law>
