<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gec" order_by="gec" level="1">Economic Development</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gec-10-601</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated....</catch_line>
  <order_by>601</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Authority" means the Maryland Stadium Authority.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Authority affiliate" means a for-profit or not-for-profit entity in which the Authority directly or indirectly owns any membership interest or equity interest.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Baltimore Convention facility" means:<section prefix="(i)">a convention center, trade show facility, meeting hall, or other structure in Baltimore City used to hold conventions, trade shows, meetings, displays, or similar events; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">offices, parking lots or garages, access roads, hotels, restaurants, railroad sidings, and any other structures, improvements, equipment, furnishings, or other property functionally related to the facilities described in item (i) of this paragraph.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Baltimore Convention facility" includes the following, if used, useful, or usable in the future as, or in connection with, a Baltimore Convention facility:<section prefix="(i)">land, structures, equipment, property, property rights, property appurtenances, rights-of-way, franchises, easements, and other interests in land;</section><section prefix="(ii)">land and facilities that are functionally related to a Baltimore Convention facility; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">patents, licenses, and other rights necessary or useful to construct or operate a Baltimore Convention facility.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"Baltimore Convention Fund" means the Baltimore Convention Financing Fund established under &#xA7; 10-651 of this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">"Baltimore Convention site" means the site of the Baltimore Convention Center located in Baltimore City at the address generally known as 1 West Pratt Street, identified in the State Department of Assessments and Taxation Real Property database as tax identification number Ward 22, Section 01, Block 0682, Lots 001 and 001A.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">"Bond" includes a note, an interim certificate, refunding bond, and any other evidence of obligation issued under this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">"Camden Yards" means the area comprising approximately 85 acres in Baltimore City bounded by Camden Street on the north, Russell Street on the west, Ostend Street on the south, and Howard Street and Interstate 395 on the east.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">"Camden Yards Fund" means the Camden Yards Financing Fund established under &#xA7; 10-652 of this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(j)">"Convention facility" means the Baltimore Convention facility, the Montgomery County Conference facility, and the Ocean City Convention facility.</section>
    <section prefix="(k)">"Facility" means:<section prefix="(1)">a structure or other improvement developed at Camden Yards;</section><section prefix="(2)">a convention facility;</section><section prefix="(3)">the Hippodrome Performing Arts facility; or</section><section prefix="(4)">a sports facility.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(l)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Hippodrome Performing Arts facility" means the performing arts center facility located at the Hippodrome Performing Arts site.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Hippodrome Performing Arts facility" includes, at the Hippodrome Performing Arts site:<section prefix="(i)">the Hippodrome theater and offices;</section><section prefix="(ii)">food service facilities; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">any other functionally related property, structures, improvements, furnishings, or equipment.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(m)">"Hippodrome Performing Arts Fund" means the Hippodrome Performing Arts Financing Fund established under &#xA7; 10-653 of this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(n)">"Hippodrome Performing Arts site" means the site of the France-Merrick Performing Arts Center located in Baltimore City at the address generally known as:<section prefix="(1)">12 North Eutaw Street Building, identified in the State Department of Assessments and Taxation Real Property database as tax identification number Ward 04, Section 08, Block 0631, Lot 001; and</section><section prefix="(2)">401 West Fayette Street, identified in the State Department of Assessments and Taxation Real Property database as tax identification number Ward 04, Section 08, Block 0631, Lot 013.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(o)">"Improve" means to add, alter, construct, equip, expand, extend, improve, install, reconstruct, rehabilitate, remodel, or repair.</section>
    <section prefix="(p)">"Improvement" means addition, alteration, construction, equipping, expansion, extension, improvement, installation, reconstruction, rehabilitation, remodeling, or repair.</section>
    <section prefix="(q)">"Montgomery County" includes the Montgomery County Revenue Authority.</section>
    <section prefix="(r)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Montgomery County Conference facility" means the Conference Center facility located at the Montgomery County Conference site used for conferences, trade shows, meetings, displays, or similar events.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Montgomery County Conference facility" includes, at the Montgomery County Conference site, offices, parking lots and garages, access roads, food service facilities, and other functionally related property, structures, improvements, furnishings, or equipment.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Montgomery County Conference facility" does not include the privately owned hotel adjacent to the Montgomery County Conference Center.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(s)">"Montgomery County Conference Fund" means the Montgomery County Conference Financing Fund established under &#xA7; 10-654 of this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(t)">"Montgomery County Conference site" means the site of the Montgomery County Conference Center located in Rockville at the address generally known as 5701 Marinelli Road, identified in the State Department of Assessments and Taxation Real Property database as tax identification number District 04, Account Number 03392987.</section>
    <section prefix="(u)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Ocean City Convention facility" means:<section prefix="(i)">a convention center, trade show facility, meeting hall, or other structure in Ocean City used to hold conventions, trade shows, meetings, displays, or similar events; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">offices, parking lots or garages, access roads, food service facilities, and any other structures, improvements, equipment, furnishings, or other property functionally related to the facilities described in item (i) of this paragraph.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Ocean City Convention facility" includes the following, if used, useful, or usable in the future as, or in connection with, an Ocean City Convention facility:<section prefix="(i)">land, structures, equipment, property, property rights, property appurtenances, rights-of-way, franchises, easements, and other interests in land;</section><section prefix="(ii)">land and facilities that are functionally related to an Ocean City Convention facility; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">patents, licenses, and other rights necessary or useful to construct or operate an Ocean City Convention facility.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(v)">"Ocean City Convention Fund" means the Ocean City Convention Financing Fund established under &#xA7; 10-655 of this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(w)">"Ocean City Convention site" means the site of the Ocean City Convention Center located in Ocean City at the address generally known as 4001 Coastal Highway, identified in the State Department of Assessments and Taxation Real Property database as tax identification numbers District 10, Account Number 055237; District 10, Account Number 066301; District 10, Account Number 247942; and District 10, Account Number 280346.</section>
    <section prefix="(x)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Sports facility" means:<section prefix="(i)">a stadium primarily for professional football, major league professional baseball, or both, in the Baltimore metropolitan region, as defined in &#xA7; 13-301 of this article;</section><section prefix="(ii)">practice fields or other areas where professional football or major league professional baseball teams practice or perform; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">offices for professional football and major league professional baseball teams or franchises.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Sports facility" includes parking lots, garages, and any other property adjacent and directly related to an item listed in paragraph (1) of this subsection.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(y)">"Tax supported debt" has the meaning stated in &#xA7; 8-104 of the State Finance and Procurement Article.</section>
  </text>
</law>
