<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gec" order_by="" level="1">Economic Development</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gec-5-540</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>540</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Authority may use the Fund to guarantee up to 80% of the principal of and interest on a long-term loan made by a financial institution to an applicant only if:<section prefix="(i)">the applicant meets the requirements under &#xA7; 5-541 of this subtitle and has not violated &#xA7; 5-545 of this subtitle;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the loan amount is $5,000 or more and the maximum amount payable by the Authority under the guaranty does not exceed $2,000,000;</section><section prefix="(iii)">the loan is used for:<section prefix="1.">working capital;</section><section prefix="2.">refinancing the applicant's existing debt;</section><section prefix="3.">acquisition and installation of equipment;</section><section prefix="4.">making necessary improvements to real property that the applicant leases or owns in fee simple; or</section><section prefix="5.">acquiring real property that the applicant will own in fee simple if the property is to be used in the applicant's trade or business for which the guaranty is sought and the financial institution or the Authority places a lien on the property;</section></section><section prefix="(iv)">the loan matures within 10 years after the closing date of the loan; and</section><section prefix="(v)">the interest rate does not exceed the monthly weighted average of the prime lending rate prevailing in Baltimore City on unsecured commercial loans, plus 2%, as determined by the Authority.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The Authority may only approve a guaranty under this section if the Authority determines that the loan to be guaranteed will have a substantial economic impact.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">To determine the economic impact of a loan, the Authority may consider:<section prefix="1.">the amount of the guaranty obligation;</section><section prefix="2.">the terms of the loan to be guaranteed;</section><section prefix="3.">the number of new jobs that the loan will create; and</section><section prefix="4.">any other factor that the Authority considers relevant.</section></section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In addition to a loan guaranty, the Authority may provide an interest subsidy for the benefit of the applicant.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The subsidy:<section prefix="(i)">may be for the life of the loan;</section><section prefix="(ii)">may not exceed 4%;</section><section prefix="(iii)">shall be payable quarterly; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">shall be made to the financial institution that makes the loan that the Authority guarantees.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The subsidy may not exceed the difference between:<section prefix="1.">the interest rate on the guaranteed loan; and</section><section prefix="2.">the discount interest rate that the Federal Reserve Bank uses.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The interest rate may not exceed the monthly weighted average of the prime lending rate that prevails in Baltimore City on unsecured commercial loans, as the Authority determines as of the date of closing, plus 2%.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The subsidy may not be paid during any period in which the loan is in default.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">In providing financial assistance under this section, the Authority shall recognize the need to serve applicants from all political subdivisions in the State.</section>
  </text>
</law>
