<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gec" order_by="" level="1">Economic Development</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gec-10-221</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>221</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Authority may secure a bond by a trust agreement between the Authority and a corporate trustee.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A corporate trustee may be any trust company or bank that has the powers of a trust company in or outside the State.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The trust agreement or the resolution that provides for the issuance of a bond may:<section prefix="(1)">provide for the protection and enforcement of rights and remedies of bondholders, including covenants setting forth the duties of the Authority in relation to:<section prefix="(i)">acquisition, improvement, maintenance, operation, and insurance of the development or project; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">custody, safeguarding, and application of money;</section></section><section prefix="(2)">provide for the rights and remedies of bondholders and of the trustee;</section><section prefix="(3)">restrict the individual right of action by bondholders as is customary in trust agreements securing bonds of corporations;</section><section prefix="(4)">provide for the deposit of the proceeds of the sale of bonds and the revenue of a development or project with an officer, board, or depositary that the Authority designates as custodian; and</section><section prefix="(5)">provide for the method of disbursing the proceeds and revenues with safeguards and restrictions that the Authority determines.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection and &#xA7; 10-222 of this subtitle, a trust agreement may pledge or assign revenues to be received from the development or project.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">No portion of a development or project may be conveyed or mortgaged without the express consent of the Board of Public Works.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The trust agreement may authorize the use of money realized from the sale or disposition of any of the property of a development or project to pay principal of and interest on the bonds.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">Expenses incurred in carrying out a trust agreement may be treated as part of the cost of maintenance, repair, and operation of a development or project.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">A bank or trust company incorporated in the State may act as a depositary of the proceeds of the bonds or the revenues and furnish indemnity bonds or pledge securities as required by the Authority.</section>
  </text>
</law>
