<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gec" order_by="gec" level="1">Economic Development</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gec-5-527</section_number>
  <catch_line>To apply for financial assistance from the Fund under &#xA7; 5-525 of this subtitle, an applicant shall ...</catch_line>
  <order_by>527</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">To apply for financial assistance from the Fund under &#xA7; 5-525 of this subtitle, an applicant shall submit to the Authority an application on the form that the Authority provides.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The application shall:<section prefix="(1)">describe the project in detail;</section><section prefix="(2)">itemize known and estimated costs;</section><section prefix="(3)">specify the total amount of investment required to perform the contract;</section><section prefix="(4)">specify the amount of funds available to the applicant without financial assistance from the Authority;</section><section prefix="(5)">specify the amount of financial assistance requested from the Authority;</section><section prefix="(6)">provide information that demonstrates the inability of the applicant to obtain adequate financing on reasonable terms through normal lending channels;</section><section prefix="(7)">provide information that demonstrates the financial status of the applicant, including:<section prefix="(i)">a current balance sheet;</section><section prefix="(ii)">a profit and loss statement; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">credit references; and</section></section><section prefix="(8)">contain any other relevant information that the Authority requires.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Authority may require an applicant to provide an audited balance sheet before the Authority approves or denies the application.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Authority may delegate the review and approval of the application information required under subsection (b)(1), (2), and (3) of this section to the Executive Director if an applicant meets all other requirements of this section.</section>
  </text>
</law>
