<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gec" order_by="gec" level="1">Economic Development</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gec-11-203</section_number>
  <catch_line>The Council consists of the following members:...</catch_line>
  <order_by>203</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Council consists of the following members:<section prefix="(1)">three members selected by the President of the Senate of Maryland to represent community interests, of which:<section prefix="(i)">one shall be a member of the Senate; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">two shall be citizens representing communities adjacent to military installations;</section></section><section prefix="(2)">three members selected by the Speaker of the House of Delegates to represent community interests, of which:<section prefix="(i)">one shall be a member of the House of Delegates; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">two shall be citizens representing communities adjacent to military installations;</section></section><section prefix="(3)">the Secretary, or the designee of the Secretary;</section><section prefix="(4)">the Secretary of Transportation, or the designee of the Secretary of Transportation;</section><section prefix="(5)">the Secretary of the Environment, or the designee of the Secretary of the Environment;</section><section prefix="(6)">the Secretary of Planning, or the designee of the Secretary of Planning;</section><section prefix="(7)">the Secretary of Veterans Affairs, or the designee of the Secretary of Veterans Affairs;</section><section prefix="(8)">the Adjutant General of the Maryland National Guard, or the designee of the Adjutant General;</section><section prefix="(9)">the President of the Southern Maryland Navy Alliance;</section><section prefix="(10)">the President of the Army Alliance;</section><section prefix="(11)">the President of the Indian Head Defense Alliance;</section><section prefix="(12)">the President of the Maritime Alliance;</section><section prefix="(13)">the President of the Fort Detrick Alliance;</section><section prefix="(14)">the President of the Fort Meade Alliance;</section><section prefix="(15)">the President of the Andrews Business and Community Alliance; and</section><section prefix="(16)">five members selected by the Governor.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The President of the Senate and the Speaker of the House of Delegates shall each appoint three members representing community interests to serve as members of the Council.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The chair may appoint:<section prefix="(i)">additional members who are presidents of other military base advocacy groups that are not-for-profit organizations and recognized by the Department; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">ex officio members as necessary to address specific issues, including a representative of the Maryland National Guard.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The term of an appointed member is 4 years.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The terms of the appointed members are staggered as required by the terms provided for appointed members of the Council on July 1, 2010.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A member of the Council:<section prefix="(1)">may not receive compensation as a member of the Council; but</section><section prefix="(2)">is entitled to reimbursement for expenses under the Standard State Travel Regulations, as provided in the State budget.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
