<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gec" order_by="gec" level="1">Economic Development</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gec-10-513</section_number>
  <catch_line>The Corporation may authorize the issuance of revenue bonds by resolution....</catch_line>
  <order_by>513</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Corporation may authorize the issuance of revenue bonds by resolution.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Corporation may issue the bonds:<section prefix="(1)">to finance all or part of the costs of a project; and</section><section prefix="(2)">for any other lawful purpose of the Corporation authorized in this subtitle.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Corporation may issue the bonds at one time or from time to time.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Corporation shall determine:<section prefix="(1)">the date of the bonds;</section><section prefix="(2)">the interest rates of the bonds;</section><section prefix="(3)">the maturity date of the bonds, which may not exceed 40 years from the date of issue;</section><section prefix="(4)">the prices, terms, and conditions of sale of the bonds;</section><section prefix="(5)">the form of the bonds;</section><section prefix="(6)">the manner of executing the bonds;</section><section prefix="(7)">the denominations of the bonds; and</section><section prefix="(8)">the places of payment of principal of and interest on the bonds, at a bank or trust company in or outside the State.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">An officer's signature or facsimile signature on a bond remains valid even if the officer leaves office before the bond is delivered.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The bonds are negotiable instruments under the laws of the State.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Bonds may be registrable.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Corporation may sell the bonds by competitive or negotiated sale in a manner and for a price that the Corporation determines.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The bonds are exempt from &#xA7;&#xA7; 8-206 and 8-208 of the State Finance and Procurement Article.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(h)">Bond proceeds may be placed in escrow pending application of the proceeds to the purposes for which the bonds are issued.</section>
  </text>
</law>
