<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gec" order_by="" level="1">Economic Development</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gec-4-216</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>216</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Tourism tax increment" means the amount, if any, by which the tourism tax revenues collected in the fiscal year 2 years before a particular fiscal year exceeds the tourism tax revenues collected in the fiscal year 3 years before the particular fiscal year.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Tourism tax revenues" means sales and use tax revenues collected on the retail sale of tourist-oriented goods and services, as determined by the Comptroller under subsection (c)(3) of this section.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">For each of fiscal years 2011 and 2012, the Governor shall include in the annual budget bill a proposed General Fund appropriation to the Fund of $5,000,000.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">For fiscal year 2013 and each fiscal year thereafter, the Governor shall include in the annual budget bill a proposed General Fund appropriation to the Fund in an amount not less than $6,000,000 for each fiscal year.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">On or before August 1 of each year, the Comptroller shall calculate the amount of the qualifying tourism tax increment for the current fiscal year in accordance with paragraph (2) of this subsection.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The qualifying tourism tax increment is:<section prefix="(i)">if the tourism tax increment exceeds 3% of the tourism tax revenues collected in the fiscal year 3 years before the current fiscal year, one-half of the amount of the tourism tax increment above the 3% increase; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">if the tourism tax increment does not exceed 3%, zero.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Comptroller shall:<section prefix="(i)">determine the classification codes that shall be included in tourism tax revenues under this subsection after consulting with the Department; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">on or before August 1 of each year, report the amount of the qualifying tourism tax increment to the Governor, the Department, the Department of Budget and Management, and, in accordance with &#xA7; 2-1246 of the State Government Article, the General Assembly.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The Governor shall consider whether to include the amount of the qualifying tourism tax increment in the appropriation to the Fund in the proposed State budget for the next fiscal year, in addition to the amount to be included in the budget bill under subsection (b) of this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">This subsection may not be construed to require funding in the State budget of the qualifying tourism tax increment.</section>
      <section prefix="(6)">If the proposed State budget for a particular fiscal year includes an appropriation to the Fund under this subsection, it is the intent of the General Assembly that the total annual funding appropriated to the Fund in any fiscal year not exceed by more than $5,000,000 the sum of:<section prefix="(i)">the portion of the qualifying tourism tax increment that the Governor included in the proposed State budget for the fiscal year immediately preceding the particular fiscal year; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">the amount stated in subsection (b) of this section.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">On or before October 1 of each year beginning in 2012, in cooperation with the Board and the Maryland Association of Destination Marketing Organizations, the Department shall report to the Governor and, in accordance with &#xA7; 2-1246 of the State Government Article, the General Assembly on the effectiveness of the funding provided under subsections (b) and (c) of this section in increasing visitor attendance and visitor spending in Maryland.</section>
  </text>
</law>
