<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gec" order_by="" level="1">Economic Development</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gec-11-306</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>306</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">A Board of Directors shall manage the affairs of the authority and exercise all of the powers of the authority.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Board consists of the following members:<section prefix="(1)">as ex officio members:<section prefix="(i)">the Secretary, or the designee of the Secretary;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the Secretary of General Services, or the designee of the Secretary of General Services;</section><section prefix="(iii)">the Secretary of Planning, or the designee of the Secretary of Planning; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">the president of the military alliance of each county in which the facility is located;</section></section><section prefix="(2)"><section prefix="(i)">if the facility is located in one county, the executive director, or equivalent officer, of the county economic development unit and two other members appointed by the governing body of the county in which the facility is located; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">if the facility is located in more than one county, the executive director, or equivalent officer, of the economic development unit of each county and one other member appointed by the governing body of each county; and</section></section><section prefix="(3)">as nonvoting, ex officio members:<section prefix="(i)">the Executive Director of the Maryland Economic Development Corporation;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the Executive Director of the authority; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">the Director of Transitional Services of the State Department of Human Resources.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The term of a member of the Board appointed under subsection (b)(2) of this section is 4 years.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The terms of appointed members shall be staggered.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">At the end of a term, a member continues to serve until a successor is appointed.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">A member who is appointed after a term has begun serves only for the rest of the term and until a successor is appointed.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
