<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gec" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="10-343" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gec-10-343</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">There is a Maryland Hospital Bond Program in the Authority.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">For public obligations issued on behalf of a hospital before October 1, 2008, the Program shall provide for the payment and refinancing of public obligations of a hospital, if:<section prefix="(1)"><section prefix="(i)">the closure of the hospital is in accordance with &#xA7; 19-120(l) of the Health - General Article; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">the delicensure of the hospital is in accordance with &#xA7; 19-325 of the Health - General Article;</section></section><section prefix="(2)">a public obligation issued on behalf of the hospital is outstanding; and</section><section prefix="(3)">the hospital plan for closure or delicensure and the related financing plan is acceptable to:<section prefix="(i)">the Secretary of Health and Mental Hygiene, in consultation with the Maryland Health Care Commission; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">the Authority.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">For public obligations issued on behalf of a hospital on or after October 1, 2008, the Program shall provide for the payment and refinancing of public obligations of a hospital, if:<section prefix="(1)"><section prefix="(i)">the closure of the hospital is in accordance with &#xA7; 19-120(l) of the Health - General Article; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">the delicensure of the hospital is in accordance with &#xA7; 19-325 of the Health - General Article;</section></section><section prefix="(2)">a public obligation issued on behalf of the hospital is outstanding;</section><section prefix="(3)">the hospital plan for closure or delicensure and the related financing plan is acceptable to:<section prefix="(i)">the Secretary of Health and Mental Hygiene, in consultation with the Maryland Health Care Commission; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">the Authority; and</section></section><section prefix="(4)">the Health Services Cost Review Commission determines that implementation of the Program is in the public interest, taking into account the amount of system-wide savings to the health care system in the State that might be expected as a result of the closure.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
