<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gec" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="5-413" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gec-5-413</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Authority may:<section prefix="(1)">adopt bylaws for the conduct of its business;</section><section prefix="(2)">adopt a seal;</section><section prefix="(3)">maintain offices in the State;</section><section prefix="(4)">sue and be sued in its own name;</section><section prefix="(5)">retain consultants;</section><section prefix="(6)">use the services of other governmental agencies;</section><section prefix="(7)">in accordance with the purposes of this subtitle, contract for and accept a loan or grant from the federal government or the State, a local government, or any of their units or instrumentalities;</section><section prefix="(8)">acquire, improve, manage, operate, dispose of, or otherwise deal with property, take assignments of rentals and leases, and make contracts, leases, agreements, and arrangements that are necessary or incidental to the performance of the Authority's duties, on the terms and conditions that it may consider advisable;</section><section prefix="(9)">acquire or receive assignment of a document executed, obtained, or delivered in connection with financial assistance under this subtitle;</section><section prefix="(10)">subject to any outstanding agreement the Authority makes under this subtitle, make a covenant or other agreement regarding the Authority's insurance funds, establish within them accounts to carry out this subtitle, and allocate revenue and receipts among the accounts;</section><section prefix="(11)">fix, charge, and collect a premium, fee, cost, or other expense related to financial assistance under this subtitle, including an application fee, commitment fee, program fee, finance charge, and publication fee;</section><section prefix="(12)">authorize the chair, vice chair, or executive director to perform, on behalf of the Authority, a duty or prescribe, specify, determine, or approve a detail, document, procedure, or a matter that the Authority, in its sole discretion, determines appropriate to carry out this subtitle; and</section><section prefix="(13)">do all things necessary or convenient to carry out the powers granted by this subtitle.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Authority shall:<section prefix="(1)">keep records of its funds and accounts; and</section><section prefix="(2)">ensure that its funds and accounts are audited annually.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">In its internal functions, the Authority shall purchase office space, supplies, facilities, materials, equipment, and professional services in accordance with the State Finance and Procurement Article.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Authority exercises its powers and performs its duties subject to the authority of the Secretary.</section>
  </text>
</law>
