<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gec" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="5-542" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gec-5-542</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">To apply for financial assistance from the Fund, a financial institution shall submit to the Authority an application on the form that the Authority provides.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The application shall include:<section prefix="(1)">a detailed description of the proposed use of the loan proceeds, including projected cash flow analyses, marketing plans, and appraisals;</section><section prefix="(2)">a detailed description of the funds available to the applicant;</section><section prefix="(3)">a detailed description of the proposed loan documents to be executed by the financial institution and the applicant;</section><section prefix="(4)">a detailed description of the property proposed as collateral for the loan and the financial institution's certification of the property's value;</section><section prefix="(5)">information that demonstrates the inability of the applicant to obtain adequate financing on reasonable terms through normal lending channels;</section><section prefix="(6)">information that demonstrates the financial status of the applicant, including:<section prefix="(i)">a current balance sheet;</section><section prefix="(ii)">a profit and loss statement; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">credit references;</section></section><section prefix="(7)">a proposed disbursement schedule;</section><section prefix="(8)">a proposed amortization schedule;</section><section prefix="(9)">a detailed description of the applicant's experience in the trade or business for which the loan and guarantee are requested;</section><section prefix="(10)">information that shows that the applicant satisfies the requirements of &#xA7; 5-541 of this subtitle; and</section><section prefix="(11)">any other relevant information that the Authority requests.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Authority may require an applicant to provide an audit report and balance sheet certified by an independent certified public accountant in accordance with generally accepted accounting principles before the Authority approves or denies the application.</section>
  </text>
</law>
