<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gec" order_by="gec" level="1">Economic Development</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gec-5-337</section_number>
  <catch_line>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Department may provide to a person, including a resp...</catch_line>
  <order_by>337</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Department may provide to a person, including a responsible person, a low-interest loan or grant to conduct the environmental site assessment of a potential brownfields site that is required to participate in the Voluntary Cleanup Program under Title 7, Subtitle 5 of the Environment Article, if the person:<section prefix="(1)">has not already applied to participate in the Program;</section><section prefix="(2)">is otherwise eligible to participate in the Program; and</section><section prefix="(3)">meets the eligibility requirements that the Department sets.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The information contained in an environmental site assessment is:<section prefix="(1)">the property of the State, if the assessment is financed wholly or partly by:<section prefix="(i)">a grant from the Department; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">a loan that is in payment default; or</section></section><section prefix="(2)">the property of the person who contracted for the assessment, if the assessment is financed by:<section prefix="(i)">a loan from the Department; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">a grant that is repaid.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Eligibility for a loan or grant for an environmental site assessment under this section does not constitute eligibility for:<section prefix="(1)">any other financial assistance under this subtitle; or</section><section prefix="(2)">the tax credits provided under &#xA7; 9-229 of the Tax - Property Article.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The recipient of a grant under this section shall repay the grant if, within 12 months after receiving the grant, the recipient does not receive approval from the Department of the Environment to:<section prefix="(1)">participate in the Voluntary Cleanup Program; or</section><section prefix="(2)">implement a corrective action plan under Title 4 of the Environment Article.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">A low-interest loan provided under this section shall convert to a market rate loan if, within 12 months after receiving the loan, the recipient does not receive approval from the Department of the Environment to:<section prefix="(1)">participate in the Voluntary Cleanup Program; or</section><section prefix="(2)">implement a corrective action plan under Title 4 of the Environment Article.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The Department may establish procedures and eligibility requirements for the approval of requests for loans and grants under this section.</section>
  </text>
</law>
