<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gec" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="13-711" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gec-13-711</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Each year the State shall appropriate money to the Council in the State budget.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The State allocation is contingent on the commitment of the participating counties to contribute matching amounts equal to the amount disbursed by the State.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">On or before August 1 of each year, the Council shall submit its proposed work programs and operating budget for the following fiscal year to the Department.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The submission shall include supporting schedules to show that the budget is financed and to provide for review and recommendations.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">After review, the Department shall forward the submission and any recommendations to the Department of Budget and Management for consideration.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The Department shall:<section prefix="(i)">review, approve, and confirm the counties' commitments; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">include with its budget request the budget request for the Council.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(5)">The Governor shall include in the State budget for the following fiscal year an appropriation to partially support the Council.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The State and Allegany, Garrett, and Washington counties may jointly finance the Council and its activities.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The commissioners of Allegany, Garrett, and Washington counties shall appropriate money each year to the Council to foster cooperative planning and development in the region.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Allegany, Garrett, and Washington counties may appropriate any other money for the Council as they consider necessary and appropriate.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">Other political subdivisions, including special districts, may appropriate money to the Council as they consider necessary and appropriate.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Council may use additional money from any other public or private source.</section>
  </text>
</law>
