<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gec" order_by="gec" level="1">Economic Development</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gec-5-301</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated....</catch_line>
  <order_by>301</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Aquaculture project" means a project that encourages innovation, expansion, and modernization of the seafood processing industry or aquaculture industry.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Arts and entertainment district" means an area designated by the Secretary as an arts and entertainment district under Title 4, Subtitle 7 of this article.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">"Arts and entertainment enterprise" means a for-profit or not-for-profit entity that is:<section prefix="(1)">located in an arts and entertainment district; and</section><section prefix="(2)">dedicated to the visual or performing arts.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"Arts and entertainment project" means a project that promotes or enhances the development of an arts and entertainment district.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Associated development and carrying costs" means costs that are associated with the acquisition and maintenance of an asset.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Associated development and carrying costs" includes:<section prefix="(i)">settlement costs;</section><section prefix="(ii)">insurance;</section><section prefix="(iii)">interest;</section><section prefix="(iv)">taxes;</section><section prefix="(v)">government fees;</section><section prefix="(vi)">utilities; and</section><section prefix="(vii)">the costs of managing and securing the asset.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">"Authority" means the Maryland Economic Development Assistance Authority.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">"Brownfields Revitalization Incentive Program" means the program in the Department that provides financial assistance from the Fund for the redevelopment of qualified brownfields sites, as provided in Part VI of this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Brownfields site" means a property that:<section prefix="(i)">is located in a county or municipal corporation that elects to participate in the Brownfields Revitalization Incentive Program in accordance with &#xA7; 5-336 of this subtitle; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">is:<section prefix="1.">an eligible property, as defined in &#xA7; 7-501 of the Environment Article, that is owned or operated by an inculpable person, as defined in &#xA7; 7-501 of the Environment Article; or</section><section prefix="2.">a property where there is a release, discharge, or threatened release of oil, as defined in &#xA7; 4-401 of the Environment Article, that is subject to Title 4 of the Environment Article.</section></section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Brownfields site" does not include property that is owned or operated by:<section prefix="(i)">a responsible person as defined in &#xA7; 7-201 of the Environment Article; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">a person responsible for the discharge, as defined in &#xA7; 4-401 of the Environment Article.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(j)">"Child care facility" means a facility that is required to be licensed as a child care center under Title 5, Subtitle 5, Part VII of the Family Law Article.</section>
    <section prefix="(k)">"Child care special loan" means a direct loan to expand or improve child care services at a child care facility, as provided in Part VII of this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(l)">"Corporation" means the Maryland Economic Development Corporation.</section>
    <section prefix="(m)">"Financial assistance" means a grant, loan, or investment provided under this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(n)">"Fund" means the Maryland Economic Development Assistance Fund.</section>
    <section prefix="(o)">"Local economic development fund" means a revolving, nonlapsing fund that one or more local governments establish for economic development in the areas under their jurisdiction.</section>
    <section prefix="(p)">"Local economic development opportunity" means a project that:<section prefix="(1)">is determined by the Department or Authority to provide a valuable economic development opportunity to the jurisdiction in which the project is located; and</section><section prefix="(2)">is a priority for and endorsed by the governing body of that jurisdiction.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(q)">"Local government" means:<section prefix="(1)">a county;</section><section prefix="(2)">a municipal corporation;</section><section prefix="(3)">a designated agency or instrumentality of a county; or</section><section prefix="(4)">a designated agency or instrumentality of a municipal corporation.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(r)">"Qualified brownfields site" means a brownfields site that is determined by the Department to be eligible for financial assistance under this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(s)">"Qualified distressed county project" means a project that a local government or the Corporation carries out in a qualified distressed county.</section>
    <section prefix="(t)">"Responsible person" has the meaning stated in &#xA7; 7-201 of the Environment Article.</section>
    <section prefix="(u)">"Significant strategic economic development opportunity" means a project that is determined by the Department or Authority to provide a valuable economic development opportunity of statewide, regional, or strategic industry impact.</section>
    <section prefix="(v)">"Specialized economic development opportunity" means:<section prefix="(1)">an aquaculture project;</section><section prefix="(2)">an arts and entertainment enterprise;</section><section prefix="(3)">an arts and entertainment project;</section><section prefix="(4)">the redevelopment of a qualified brownfields site; or</section><section prefix="(5)">a project to create or expand a child care facility.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(w)">"Working capital" means money to be used for current operations of a business.</section>
  </text>
</law>
