<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gec" order_by="" level="1">Economic Development</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gec-12-501</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>501</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, Montgomery County may make an equity investment through the county's Economic Development Fund in a company that is located in Montgomery County or that agrees to relocate its business to Montgomery County.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The proceeds of an equity investment made under subsection (a) of this section may be used for:<section prefix="(1)">working capital;</section><section prefix="(2)">salaries;</section><section prefix="(3)">marketing materials;</section><section prefix="(4)">acquisition of inventory, equipment, or real property;</section><section prefix="(5)">construction;</section><section prefix="(6)">renovation;</section><section prefix="(7)">leasehold improvements; or</section><section prefix="(8)">research and development.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The county may not acquire an ownership interest exceeding 25% of any enterprise.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The terms of an equity investment approved by the county shall be set forth in a funding agreement.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A funding agreement made under paragraph (1) of this subsection shall prohibit the county from:<section prefix="(i)">participating in the selection of the management of the company;</section><section prefix="(ii)">engaging in oversight of the operation of the company; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">assuming any present or future liability of the company.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">At the county's discretion, a funding agreement made under paragraph (1) of this subsection may consist of:<section prefix="(i)">an investment agreement;</section><section prefix="(ii)">a limited partnership agreement;</section><section prefix="(iii)">a preferred stock purchase agreement; or</section><section prefix="(iv)">other documents that the county may require.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">Notice of each equity investment made by Montgomery County under subsection (a) of this section shall be posted in a readily accessible and clearly identified location on the Montgomery County government website within 5 days after the date on which the county initiates the equity investment transaction.</section>
  </text>
</law>
