<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gec" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="10-301" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gec-10-301</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Authority" means the Maryland Health and Higher Educational Facilities Authority.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Bond" means a bond issued by the Authority under this subtitle.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Bond" includes a revenue bond, a revenue refunding bond, a note, and any other obligations.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">"Cost", with respect to a project financed under this subtitle, includes:<section prefix="(1)">the purchase price of a project;</section><section prefix="(2)">the cost to acquire any right, title, or interest in a project;</section><section prefix="(3)">the cost of any improvement;</section><section prefix="(4)">the cost of any property, right, easement, and franchise;</section><section prefix="(5)">the cost of demolition, removal, or relocation of structures;</section><section prefix="(6)">the cost of acquiring land to which the structures may be moved;</section><section prefix="(7)">the cost of equipment;</section><section prefix="(8)">financing charges;</section><section prefix="(9)">interest before and during construction and, if the Authority determines, for a limited period after the completion of construction;</section><section prefix="(10)">reserves for principal and interest and for improvements;</section><section prefix="(11)">the cost of revenue and cost estimates, architectural, engineering, financial, and legal services, plans, specifications, studies, surveys, and other expenses necessary or incident to determining the feasibility of improving a project; and</section><section prefix="(12)">other expenses as necessary or incident to:<section prefix="(i)">financing a project;</section><section prefix="(ii)">acquiring and improving a project; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">placing a project in operation.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"Educational institution" means an institution of higher education or a noncollegiate educational institution.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">"Finance" includes refinance.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Health care institution" means an institution in the State that is operated by a person, a local government, or, subject to paragraph (3) of this subsection, the State, is available to the public, and is:<section prefix="(i)">a not-for-profit hospital as defined under &#xA7; 19-301 of the Health - General Article that:</section><section prefix="(ii)">a not-for-profit related institution as defined under &#xA7; 19-301 of the Health - General Article that is licensed as a related institution by the Secretary of Health and Mental Hygiene under &#xA7; 19-318 of the Health - General Article;</section><section prefix="(iii)">a combination of institutions listed in items (i) and (ii) of this paragraph;</section><section prefix="(iv)">except as provided in paragraph (3) of this subsection:</section><section prefix="(v)">any combination of health care entities listed in item (iv) of this paragraph;</section><section prefix="(vi)">an entity affiliated or associated with an institution listed in items (i) through (v) of this paragraph, if the Authority determines by resolution that the financing of a project for the entity serves the public purpose of that institution; or</section><section prefix="(vii)">a not-for-profit health service plan that holds a certificate of authority and provides health insurance policies or contracts in the State in accordance with the Insurance Article.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Health care institution" includes a not-for-profit corporation organized to construct or acquire an institution under paragraph (1) of this subsection.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Health care institution" does not include a facility described in paragraph (1)(iv) of this subsection that is owned and operated by the State, except for the following facilities if approved by the Board of Public Works and the Joint Audit Committee:<section prefix="(i)">a not-for-profit comprehensive health center that is a medical or health care facility of the University System of Maryland; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">a not-for-profit life care or continuing care community that provides self-contained residence facilities for the retired or elderly.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">For purposes of this subsection the facilities of the University of Maryland Medical System Corporation are not considered to be owned and operated by the State.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(h)">"Improve" means to add, alter, construct, equip, expand, extend, improve, install, reconstruct, rehabilitate, remodel, or repair.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">"Improvement" means addition, alteration, construction, equipping, expansion, extension, improvement, installation, reconstruction, rehabilitation, remodeling, or repair.</section>
    <section prefix="(j)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Institution of higher education" means an educational institution in the State that:<section prefix="(i)">by law or charter:</section><section prefix="(ii)">meets the standards and regulations that the Maryland Higher Education Commission prescribes, and is authorized to issue a certificate, diploma, or degree under Title 12 of the Education Article.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Institution of higher education" includes:<section prefix="(i)">a community college for which a board of community college trustees is established under &#xA7; 16-101 of the Education Article;</section><section prefix="(ii)">a regional community college established under &#xA7; 16-202 of the Education Article;</section><section prefix="(iii)">the Baltimore City Community College established under &#xA7; 16-501 of the Education Article; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">the College of Southern Maryland established under &#xA7; 16-603 of the Education Article.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Institution of higher education" does not include an institution owned and operated by the State other than an institution listed in paragraph (2) of this subsection.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(k)">"Noncollegiate educational institution" means a noncollegiate educational institution as defined in &#xA7; 2-206 of the Education Article that:<section prefix="(1)">has received a certificate of approval from the State Board of Education; or</section><section prefix="(2)">is an institution operated by a bona fide church organization.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(l)">"Participating institution" means a participating educational institution or a participating health care institution that receives assistance under this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(m)">
      <section prefix="(1)">With respect to an educational institution:<section prefix="(i)">"project" means a structure or facility that is required or useful for an educational institution;</section><section prefix="(ii)">"project" includes:</section><section prefix="(iii)">"project" does not include books, fuel, supplies, or other items that customarily result in a current operating charge.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">With respect to a health care institution:<section prefix="(i)">"project" means a structure or facility that is required or useful for the effective operation of a health care institution;</section><section prefix="(ii)">"project" includes:</section><section prefix="(iii)">"project" does not include fuel, supplies, or other items that customarily result in a current operating charge.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(n)">"Sinking fund" means a fund established under &#xA7; 10-328 of this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(o)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Trust agreement" means an agreement entered into by the Authority to secure a bond.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Trust agreement" may include a bond contract, bond resolution, or other contract with or for the benefit of a bondholder.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
