<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gec" order_by="gec" level="1">Economic Development</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gec-4-801</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this section, "Fund" means the Special Fund for Preservation of Cultural Arts in Maryland....</catch_line>
  <order_by>801</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, "Fund" means the Special Fund for Preservation of Cultural Arts in Maryland.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">There is a Special Fund for Preservation of Cultural Arts in Maryland.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The purpose of the Fund is to provide supplemental grants to cultural arts organizations in the State that qualify for general operating support grants from the Maryland State Arts Council.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Secretary of Business and Economic Development shall administer the Fund.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Fund is a special, nonlapsing fund that is not subject to &#xA7; 7-302 of the State Finance and Procurement Article.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The State Treasurer shall hold the Fund separately, and the Comptroller shall account for the Fund.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The Fund consists of:<section prefix="(1)">revenue distributed to the Fund under &#xA7; 2-202(a)(1)(ii) of the Tax - General Article; and</section><section prefix="(2)">any other money from any other source accepted for the benefit of the Fund.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(g)">The Fund shall be used to provide supplemental grants for operating and programmatic improvements that strengthen the organizational capacity and financial stability of cultural arts organizations in the State that qualify for general operating support grants from the Maryland State Arts Council.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The State Treasurer shall invest the money of the Fund in the same manner as other State money may be invested.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Any investment earnings of the Fund shall be credited to the General Fund of the State.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(i)">For each appropriation to the Fund, the Governor may:<section prefix="(1)">include the funds in the State budget subject to appropriation by the General Assembly; or</section><section prefix="(2)">transfer the funds by budget amendment from the Fund to the expenditure account of the Maryland State Arts Council.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(j)">Supplemental grants made from the Fund are supplemental to and may not take the place of funding that otherwise would be appropriated for qualifying organizations.</section>
  </text>
</law>
