<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gec" order_by="gec" level="1">Economic Development</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gec-5-411</section_number>
  <catch_line>With the approval of the Secretary, the Authority shall appoint an Executive Director....</catch_line>
  <order_by>411</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">With the approval of the Secretary, the Authority shall appoint an Executive Director.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Executive Director serves at the pleasure of the Authority, with the concurrence of the Secretary.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The position of Executive Director is a special appointment under the State Personnel and Management System.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Executive Director is the chief administrative officer of the Authority.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Executive Director shall:<section prefix="(1)">direct and supervise the administrative affairs and technical activities of the Authority;</section><section prefix="(2)">attend the meetings of the Authority;</section><section prefix="(3)">record the minutes of the proceedings of the Authority;</section><section prefix="(4)">approve all accounts for salaries, per diem payments, and allowable expenses of the Authority, its employees, and its consultants;</section><section prefix="(5)">approve all expenses incidental to the operation of the Authority;</section><section prefix="(6)">in cooperation with the Department, submit to the Authority reports and recommendations related to proposed financial assistance under this subtitle; and</section><section prefix="(7)">perform the other duties that the Secretary or the Authority requires to carry out this subtitle.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Executive Director is the resident agent of the Authority for the receipt of service made in accordance with the Maryland Rules.</section>
  </text>
</law>
