<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gec" order_by="" level="1">Economic Development</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gec-12-111</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>111</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">For each issue of its bonds, the legislative body of a county or municipal corporation, the board of directors of an authority, or the Maryland Industrial Development Financing Authority, shall adopt a resolution that:<section prefix="(1)">specifies and describes the facility;</section><section prefix="(2)">generally describes the public purpose to be served and the financing transaction;</section><section prefix="(3)">specifies the maximum principal amount of the bonds that may be issued; and</section><section prefix="(4)">imposes terms or conditions on the issuance and sale of bonds it considers appropriate.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The legislative body of a county or municipal corporation, the board of directors of an authority, or the Maryland Industrial Development Financing Authority, by resolution, may:<section prefix="(i)">specify, determine, prescribe, and approve matters, documents, and procedures that relate to the authorization, sale, security, issuance, delivery, and payment of and for the bonds;</section><section prefix="(ii)">create security for the bonds;</section><section prefix="(iii)">provide for the administration of bond issues through trust or other agreements with a bank or trust company that cover a countersignature on a bond, the delivery of a bond, or the security for a bond; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">take other action it considers appropriate concerning the bonds.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The legislative body of a county or municipal corporation, the board of directors of an authority, or the Maryland Industrial Development Financing Authority may authorize a designee to exercise the powers provided under paragraph (1) of this subsection.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A designee may be:<section prefix="(i)">a finance board, which shall act by resolution;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the chief executive, who shall act by executive order or otherwise; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">any other appropriate administrative officer, who shall act by order or otherwise with the approval of the chief executive.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">Subject to the limitations of this subtitle and the limitations the legislative body prescribes by resolution, a chief executive or an administrative officer acting under a resolution of a legislative body shall exercise the authority granted:<section prefix="(i)">to accomplish the legislative purposes of this subtitle; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">to accomplish the public purposes of the resolution that the legislative body adopts.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A resolution or trust agreement may contain a pledge or assignment of revenues received from the financing of a facility.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The lien of the pledge or assignment made is valid and binding against a person with a claim against the public body, whether or not the person has notice of the lien.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Notwithstanding any other public general or public local law, a public body need not file or record a resolution, trust agreement, lease, installment sale agreement, loan agreement, or other instrument that it adopts or makes under this subtitle, except in the records of the public body.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">A resolution adopted under this section:<section prefix="(1)">is administrative in nature;</section><section prefix="(2)">is not subject to procedures required for legislative acts;</section><section prefix="(3)">is not subject to referendum; and</section><section prefix="(4)">in a county or municipal corporation that has a publicly elected chief executive, is subject to approval by the chief executive.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">This authorization is self-executing, and fully authorizes a public body to issue and sell bonds, notwithstanding any other statutory or charter provision.</section>
  </text>
</law>
