<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gec" order_by="" level="1">Economic Development</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gec-5-573</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>573</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">To apply for financial assistance from the Program under this part, a principal and, if applicable, a surety shall submit to the Authority an application on the form that the Authority provides.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The application shall include:<section prefix="(1)">a detailed description of the project;</section><section prefix="(2)">an itemization of known and estimated costs;</section><section prefix="(3)">the total investment required to perform the contract;</section><section prefix="(4)">the working capital available to the principal;</section><section prefix="(5)">the bonding assistance sought;</section><section prefix="(6)">information that demonstrates the inability of the principal to obtain adequate bonding on reasonable terms and conditions through normal channels without assistance from the Program;</section><section prefix="(7)">a current balance sheet, a profit and loss statement, and credit references about the financial status of the principal;</section><section prefix="(8)">a schedule of the status of existing and pending contracts; and</section><section prefix="(9)">any other relevant information the Authority requests.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Authority may require an applicant to provide an audited balance sheet before the Authority approves or denies the application.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Authority may not approve a guaranty or bond under this part for a principal that has defaulted on a loan or guaranty from the Authority unless:<section prefix="(1)">2 years have passed since the time of the default; and</section><section prefix="(2)">the principal has cured any default in any financing program administered by the Department.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
