<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gec" order_by="" level="1">Economic Development</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gec-10-840</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>840</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Center may periodically:<section prefix="(i)">issue bonds for any corporate purpose, including operating expenses;</section><section prefix="(ii)">refund those bonds;</section><section prefix="(iii)">purchase its bonds with any funds available; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">hold, pledge, cancel, or resell bonds.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">By resolution, the Board may authorize the chair, vice chair, one of its members, or a committee of its members to determine, provide for, or approve any matters relating to bonds that the Board considers appropriate including:<section prefix="(i)">specifying, determining, prescribing, and approving matters, documents, and procedures that relate to the authorization, sale, security, issuance, delivery, and payment of and for the bonds;</section><section prefix="(ii)">creating security for the bonds;</section><section prefix="(iii)">providing for the administration of bond issues; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">taking other actions it considers appropriate concerning the bonds.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The power granted in paragraph (2) of this subsection is in addition to powers conferred on the Board by this subtitle and does not limit any power of the Board under this subtitle.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Subject to subparagraph (ii) of this paragraph, the Board may authorize the Executive Director to take any of the actions described in paragraph (2) of this subsection.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">If the Board authorizes the Executive Director to take any of the actions described in paragraph (2) of this subsection, the Board shall prescribe limits within which the Executive Director may exercise discretion.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as otherwise provided by the Center, each issue of its bonds is a general obligation of the Center payable from any revenues or moneys of the Center that are available and not otherwise pledged.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The provisions of paragraph (1) of this subsection are subject to any agreements with:<section prefix="(i)">holders of particular bonds pledging any particular revenues or moneys; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">any participating institution.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">For each issue of its bonds, the Center shall pass a resolution that:<section prefix="(1)">specifies and describes the project for which the proceeds of the bond issuance are intended;</section><section prefix="(2)">generally describes the public purpose and the financing transaction to be accomplished;</section><section prefix="(3)">specifies the maximum principal amount of the bonds that may be issued by the Center; and</section><section prefix="(4)">imposes any terms or conditions on the issuance and sale of the bonds that the Center considers appropriate.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Subject to any provision for their registration, bonds are negotiable instruments for all purposes regardless of whether they are payable from a special fund.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The bonds may be:<section prefix="(i)">serial bonds;</section><section prefix="(ii)">term bonds; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">both in the discretion of the Center.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Subject to any delegation under subsection (a)(2) of this section, the resolution authorizing bonds may provide:<section prefix="(i)">the dates of the bonds;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the maturity dates of the bonds;</section><section prefix="(iii)">the interest rates on the bonds;</section><section prefix="(iv)">the time at which the bonds will be payable;</section><section prefix="(v)">the denominations of the bonds;</section><section prefix="(vi)">whether the bonds will be in a coupon or registered form;</section><section prefix="(vii)">any registration privileges of the bonds;</section><section prefix="(viii)">the manner of execution of the bonds;</section><section prefix="(ix)">the place at which the bonds will be payable; and</section><section prefix="(x)">any terms of redemption of the bonds.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The bonds shall mature within a period not to exceed 50 years after their date.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The bonds shall be payable in United States currency.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The bonds may be sold by competitive or negotiated sale at a price determined by the Center.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">Pending preparation of the definitive bonds, the Center may issue interim receipts or certificates that will be exchanged for definitive bonds.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A trust agreement authorizing bonds may contain provisions that are part of the contract with the bondholders.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The provisions may include:<section prefix="(i)">pledging the following to secure payment of bonds, subject to any existing agreements with bondholders:<section prefix="1.">the full faith and credit of the Center;</section><section prefix="2.">the full faith and credit of a participating institution;</section><section prefix="3.">revenues of a project;</section><section prefix="4.">a revenue-producing contract the Center has made with a person or public entity; or</section><section prefix="5.">the proceeds of the sale of bonds;</section></section><section prefix="(ii)">the rentals, fees, and other charges, the amounts to be raised in each year, and the use and disposition of the revenues;</section><section prefix="(iii)">the setting aside of reserves and sinking funds and their disposition;</section><section prefix="(iv)">limits on the right of the Center or its agents to restrict and regulate the use of a project;</section><section prefix="(v)">limits on the purpose to which the proceeds of sale of bonds may be applied;</section><section prefix="(vi)">limits on issuing additional bonds, the terms under which additional bonds may be issued and secured, and refunding outstanding bonds;</section><section prefix="(vii)">the procedure to amend or abrogate the terms of a contract with bondholders and the requirements for consent;</section><section prefix="(viii)">limits on the amount of project revenues to be expended for operating, administrative, or other expenses of the Center;</section><section prefix="(ix)">the acts or omissions that constitute default by the Center and the rights and remedies of the bondholders in the event of a default;</section><section prefix="(x)">the conveyance or mortgaging of a project and its site to secure the bondholders; and</section><section prefix="(xi)">creation and disposition of a collateral fund, instead of conveyance or mortgage, for the purpose of securing the bondholders.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(i)">The members of the Board and a person executing the bonds may not be held liable personally on the bonds.</section>
  </text>
</law>
