<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gec" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="10-643" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gec-10-643</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Except as allowed by &#xA7; 10-639 of this subtitle, to finance site acquisition and construction of any segment of an Ocean City Convention facility, the Authority shall comply with this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Authority shall provide to the fiscal committees of the General Assembly, at least 90 days before seeking approval of the Board of Public Works for each bond issue or other borrowing, a comprehensive financing plan for the relevant segment of the facility, including the effect of the financing plan on financing options for other segments of the facility.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Authority shall obtain the approval of the Board of Public Works of the proposed bond issue and the financing plan.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Authority shall secure a lease or other written agreement with Ocean City, as approved by the Board of Public Works, under which:<section prefix="(1)">Ocean City agrees to:<section prefix="(i)">issue bonds not later than the date of the Authority's bond issuance as authorized under &#xA7; 10-628 of this subtitle; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">contribute $14,700,000 of the proceeds from the sale of the bonds for the capital costs of the expansion of the Ocean City Convention Center;</section></section><section prefix="(2)">the Authority agrees to:<section prefix="(i)">issue bonds as authorized under &#xA7; 10-628 of this subtitle; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">contribute $14,700,000 of the proceeds from the sale of the bonds for the capital costs of the expansion of the Ocean City Convention Center;</section></section><section prefix="(3)">Ocean City and the Authority agree that if the actual capital costs of the expansion of the Ocean City Convention Center are less than $29,400,000, the savings shall be allocated:<section prefix="(i)">one-half to the Authority; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">one-half to Ocean City;</section></section><section prefix="(4)">Ocean City agrees to provide the Ocean City Convention site, as defined in &#xA7; 10-601 of this subtitle, for the expansion and renovation of the Ocean City Convention facility;</section><section prefix="(5)">Ocean City and the Authority shall each own a 50% leasehold interest as tenants in common in the improvements comprising the existing Ocean City Convention Center and the Ocean City Convention Center expansion for the duration of any bonds issued as authorized under &#xA7; 10-628 of this subtitle and for 20 years thereafter; and</section><section prefix="(6)">Ocean City and the Authority agree not to sell, assign, mortgage, pledge, or encumber the Ocean City Convention facility, or any leasehold interest in the facility, without the prior consent of the other, except for liens in favor of their respective bondholders.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The Authority shall secure a deed, lease, or written agreement with Ocean City, as approved by the Board of Public Works, authorizing the Authority to:<section prefix="(1)">design, construct, and equip, or contract for the design, construction, and equipping of the Ocean City Convention facility expansion; and</section><section prefix="(2)">pledge the Ocean City Convention facility and the Ocean City Convention site or the leasehold interest in the facility as security for the Authority's bonds.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Authority shall secure a written agreement with Ocean City, as approved by the Board of Public Works:<section prefix="(i)">in which Ocean City agrees to:</section><section prefix="(ii)">that includes provisions that:</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Paragraph (1)(i)1 of this subsection may not be construed to require gambling activities in the Ocean City Convention facility.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
