<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gec" order_by="gec" level="1">Economic Development</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gec-12-303</section_number>
  <catch_line>Before a political subdivision issues a bond, the political subdivision shall pass an ordinance or a...</catch_line>
  <order_by>303</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Before a political subdivision issues a bond, the political subdivision shall pass an ordinance or administrative resolution that:<section prefix="(1)">designates an area in the political subdivision as a designated blighted area based on the substantial presence of:<section prefix="(i)">excessive vacant land on which structures were previously located;</section><section prefix="(ii)">abandoned or vacant buildings;</section><section prefix="(iii)">substandard structures;</section><section prefix="(iv)">delinquencies in real property tax payments; or</section><section prefix="(v)">similar factors that the political subdivision determines indicate blight;</section></section><section prefix="(2)">designates the financed area for which the proceeds of the bond are to be used; and</section><section prefix="(3)">adopts a redevelopment plan for the designated blighted area.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Before a county may designate a blighted area or financed area that lies wholly or partly in a municipal corporation, the municipal corporation shall consent to the designation of the part of the area that is within the municipal corporation.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Before a municipal corporation may designate a blighted area or financed area, the county that contains the area shall consent to the designation.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Consent under this subsection shall be made by ordinance or administrative resolution.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A political subdivision that issues a bond as a qualified redevelopment bond under the Internal Revenue Code shall comply with federal law in determining:<section prefix="(1)">the designated blighted area and the financed area to which the bond relates; and</section><section prefix="(2)">any other designated blighted areas in the political subdivision.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
