<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gec" order_by="gec" level="1">Economic Development</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gec-6-501</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated....</catch_line>
  <order_by>501</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Affiliate" means:<section prefix="(i)">a person who, directly or indirectly, beneficially owns, controls, or holds power to vote 15% or more of the outstanding voting securities or other voting ownership interests of a venture firm or an insurance company; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">a person, 15% or more of whose outstanding voting securities or other voting ownership interests is directly or indirectly beneficially owned, controlled, or held with power to vote by a venture firm or an insurance company.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Affiliate" does not include an insurance company that becomes a purchaser in accordance with an allocation of investment tax credits under the Program solely by reason of the allocation.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Allocation amount" means the total amount of tax credits allocated to a purchaser.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">"Allocation date" means the date on which tax credits are allocated to a purchaser under &#xA7; 6-513 of this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"Authority" means the Maryland Venture Fund Authority established under &#xA7; 6-504 of this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">"Designated capital" means the amount of money that a purchaser invests under the Program.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">"Enterprise Fund" means the Enterprise Fund under Title 5, Subtitle 6 of this article.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">"Financing Authority" means the Maryland Small Business Development Financing Authority under Title 5, Subtitle 5 of this article.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">"Insurance premium tax liability" means:<section prefix="(1)">any liability incurred by an insurance company under Title 6, Subtitle 1 of the Insurance Article as of October 1, 2011; or</section><section prefix="(2)">if the liability referred to in item (1) of this subsection is eliminated or reduced, any other tax liability that has been imposed by the State on the insurance company as of October 1, 2011, not to exceed the amount of the liability eliminated or reduced.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(j)">"Premium tax credit" means a credit against insurance premium tax liability offered to a purchaser under the Program.</section>
    <section prefix="(k)">"Program" means the Invest Maryland Program under this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(l)">"Purchaser" means:<section prefix="(1)">an insurance company that:<section prefix="(i)">is authorized to do business in the State;</section><section prefix="(ii)">has insurance premium tax liability; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">contributes designated capital to purchase an allocation of premium tax credits under the Program; or</section></section><section prefix="(2)">a holding company that:<section prefix="(i)">has at least one insurance company subsidiary authorized to do business in the State; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">is contributing designated capital on behalf of one or more of these subsidiaries.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(m)">"Qualified business" means a business that, at the time of the first investment in the business under the Program:<section prefix="(1)">has its principal business operations located in the State and intends to maintain its principal business operations in the State after receiving an investment under the Program;</section><section prefix="(2)">has agreed to use the qualified investment primarily to:<section prefix="(i)">support business operations in the State; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">in the case of a start-up company, establish and support business operations in the State;</section></section><section prefix="(3)">has not more than 250 employees; and</section><section prefix="(4)">is not primarily engaged in:<section prefix="(i)">retail sales;</section><section prefix="(ii)">real estate development;</section><section prefix="(iii)">the business of insurance, banking, or lending; or</section><section prefix="(iv)">the provision of professional services by accountants, attorneys, or physicians.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(n)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Qualified distribution" means a distribution or payment by a venture firm in connection with:<section prefix="(i)">the reasonable costs and expenses of organizing and syndicating the venture firm, including fees paid for professional services, up to a maximum aggregate amount of $125,000;</section><section prefix="(ii)">reasonable and necessary fees paid for ongoing professional services, including legal and accounting services, related to the operation of the venture firm, up to a maximum aggregate amount of $50,000 in a single year; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">a yearly management fee in an amount that does not exceed 2.5% of the designated capital allocated to the venture firm.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Qualified distribution" does not include:<section prefix="(i)">any amount paid to a purchaser or an affiliate of a purchaser; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">any costs and expenses related to lobbying or government relations.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(o)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Qualified investment" means the direct or indirect investment of cash by the Enterprise Fund or the Financing Authority in a qualified business for the purchase of any of the following:<section prefix="(i)">a share of stock or other equity interest;</section><section prefix="(ii)">a debt instrument that is convertible into equity; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">an equity participation instrument such as an option or warrant.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A qualified investment includes the direct or indirect investment of cash by a venture firm based on the investment criteria set forth in this subtitle.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(p)">"Venture firm" means a partnership, corporation, trust, or limited liability company, whether organized on a profit or a not-for-profit basis, that is certified by the Department as meeting the criteria established under &#xA7; 6-518 of this subtitle.</section>
  </text>
</law>
