<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gec" order_by="" level="1">Economic Development</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gec-12-201</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>201</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Adjusted assessable base" means the fair market value of real property that qualifies for a farm or agricultural use under &#xA7; 8-209 of the Tax - Property Article, without regard to the agricultural use assessment for the property as of January 1 of the year preceding the effective date of the resolution creating the development district under &#xA7; 12-203 of this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Assessable base" means the total assessable base, as determined by the Supervisor of Assessments, of all real property subject to taxation in a development district.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Assessment ratio" means a real property tax assessment ratio, however designated or calculated, that is used under applicable general law to determine the assessable base.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Assessment ratio" includes the assessment percentage specified under &#xA7; 8-103(c) of the Tax - Property Article.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"Bond" means a revenue bond, note, or other similar instrument issued in accordance with this subtitle by:<section prefix="(1)">a political subdivision; or</section><section prefix="(2)">the revenue authority of Prince George's County.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">"Chief executive" means the president, chair, mayor, or other chief executive officer of a political subdivision or the revenue authority of Prince George's County.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">"Development" includes new development, redevelopment, revitalization, and renovation.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">"Development district" means a contiguous area designated by a resolution.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">"Issuer" means a political subdivision or the revenue authority of Prince George's County that issues a bond under this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(j)">"MEDCO obligation" means a bond, note, or other similar instrument that the Maryland Economic Development Corporation issues under authority other than this subtitle to finance the cost of infrastructure improvements located in or supporting a transit-oriented development or a State hospital redevelopment.</section>
    <section prefix="(k)">"Original assessable base" means the assessable base as of January 1 of the year preceding the effective date of the resolution creating the development district under &#xA7; 12-203 of this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(l)">"Original full cash value" means the dollar amount that is determined by dividing the original assessable base by the assessment ratio used to determine the original assessable base.</section>
    <section prefix="(m)">"Original taxable value" means for any tax year the dollar amount that is:<section prefix="(1)">the adjusted assessable base, if an adjusted assessable base applies; or</section><section prefix="(2)">in all other cases, the lesser of:<section prefix="(i)">the product of multiplying the original full cash value by the assessment ratio applicable to that tax year; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">the original assessable base.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(n)">"Political subdivision" means a county or a municipal corporation.</section>
    <section prefix="(o)">"State hospital redevelopment" means any combination of private or public commercial, residential, or recreational uses, improvements, and facilities that:<section prefix="(1)">is part of a comprehensive coordinated development plan or strategy involving:<section prefix="(i)">property that was occupied formerly by a State facility, as defined in &#xA7; 10-101 of the Health - General Article, or a State residential center, as defined in &#xA7; 7-101 of the Health - General Article; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">property that is adjacent or reasonably proximate to property that was occupied formerly by a State facility, as defined in &#xA7; 10-101 of the Health - General Article, or a State residential center, as defined in &#xA7; 7-101 of the Health - General Article;</section></section><section prefix="(2)">in accordance with design development principles, maximizes use of the property by those constituencies it is intended to serve; and</section><section prefix="(3)">is designated as a State hospital redevelopment by:<section prefix="(i)">the Smart Growth Subcabinet established under &#xA7; 9-1406 of the State Government Article; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">the local government or multicounty agency with land use and planning responsibility for the relevant area.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(p)">"Tax increment" means for any tax year the amount by which the assessable base as of January 1 of the preceding tax year exceeds the original taxable value divided by the assessment ratio used to determine the original taxable value.</section>
    <section prefix="(q)">"Tax year" means the period from July 1 of a calendar year through June 30 of the next calendar year.</section>
    <section prefix="(r)">"Transit-oriented development" has the meaning stated in &#xA7; 7-101 of the Transportation Article.</section>
  </text>
</law>
