<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gec" order_by="" level="1">Economic Development</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gec-10-807</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>807</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">A Board of Directors shall manage the Center and exercise its corporate powers.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Board consists of the following nine members:<section prefix="(1)">the Director, or the Director's designee; and</section><section prefix="(2)">eight members appointed by the Governor with the advice and consent of the Senate:<section prefix="(i)">two representing the not-for-profit clean energy research sector of the State;</section><section prefix="(ii)">two with expertise in venture capital financing;</section><section prefix="(iii)">two representing clean energy industries in the State; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">two members of the general public.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A member of the Board shall reside in the State.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">In making appointments to the Board, the Governor shall consider:<section prefix="(1)">diversity; and</section><section prefix="(2)">all geographic regions of the State.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">A member of the Board:<section prefix="(1)">may not receive compensation as a member of the Board; but</section><section prefix="(2)">is entitled to reimbursement for expenses under the Standard State Travel Regulations, as provided in the State budget.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The term of an appointed member is 4 years and begins on July 1.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The terms of the appointed members are staggered as required by the terms provided for members on October 1, 2008.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">At the end of a term, an appointed member continues to serve until a successor is appointed and qualifies.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">A member who is appointed after a term has begun serves only for the rest of the term and until a successor is appointed and qualifies.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">The Governor may remove an appointed member for incompetence, misconduct, or failure to perform the duties of the position.</section>
  </text>
</law>
