<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gec" order_by="gec" level="1">Economic Development</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gec-5-549</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this part the following words have the meanings indicated....</catch_line>
  <order_by>549</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this part the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Enterprise" means a business entity proposing to carry on a business in the State that meets the requirements of &#xA7; 5-526 of this subtitle.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Enterprise" includes:<section prefix="(i)">a sole proprietorship;</section><section prefix="(ii)">a partnership;</section><section prefix="(iii)">a limited partnership;</section><section prefix="(iv)">a corporation; or</section><section prefix="(v)">a joint venture.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Equity participation financing" includes investment or guaranty of investment in an enterprise.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">"Existing business" means a business whose board of directors or owners approve the sale of the business to an enterprise receiving equity participation financing.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Franchise" has the meaning stated in &#xA7; 14-201 of the Business Regulation Article.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Franchise" includes only franchise offerings that are registered or exempt under the Maryland Franchise Registration and Disclosure Law.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">"Fund" means the Equity Participation Investment Program Fund.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">"Program" means the Equity Participation Investment Program.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">"Qualified security" means:<section prefix="(1)">a note, bond, debenture, or other evidence of indebtedness;</section><section prefix="(2)">stock or other form of equity participation;</section><section prefix="(3)">a certificate of interest or participation in a profit-sharing agreement;</section><section prefix="(4)">an investment contract;</section><section prefix="(5)">a certificate of deposit for a security;</section><section prefix="(6)">a certificate of interest or participation in a patent or patent application or in royalty or other payments under a patent or patent application; or</section><section prefix="(7)">an interest or instrument commonly known as a "security" or a certificate for, receipt for, guaranty of, or option, warrant, or right to subscribe to or purchase a qualified security.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(i)">"Technology-based business" means a commercial or industrial enterprise engaged in the application of scientific knowledge to practical purposes in a particular field for a profit.</section>
  </text>
</law>
