<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gec" order_by="gec" level="1">Economic Development</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gec-2-206</section_number>
  <catch_line>The Commission may:...</catch_line>
  <order_by>206</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Commission may:<section prefix="(1)">adopt bylaws for the conduct of its business;</section><section prefix="(2)">hire consultants; and</section><section prefix="(3)">do anything necessary or convenient to carry out its powers and the purposes of this subtitle.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Commission shall:<section prefix="(1)">develop and update an economic development strategic plan for the State;</section><section prefix="(2)">seek ideas and advice from each region of the State to develop the economic development strategic plan;</section><section prefix="(3)">incorporate into the economic development strategic plan the Maryland Port Administration strategic plan developed for the Helen Delich Bentley Port of Baltimore;</section><section prefix="(4)">recommend to the Governor the program and spending priorities needed to implement the economic development strategic plan;</section><section prefix="(5)">review the allocation of financing incentives;</section><section prefix="(6)">participate in marketing the State and encouraging new businesses to locate in the State;</section><section prefix="(7)">seek contributions from the private sector to supplement economic development programs and financial incentives to business; and</section><section prefix="(8)">carry out other economic development activities that the Governor requests.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Commission may spend money raised under subsection (b) of this section only in accordance with the State budget.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Departmental regulations that pertain to financing programs shall be approved by the Commission before adoption.</section>
  </text>
</law>
