<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gec" order_by="gec" level="1">Economic Development</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gec-2-203</section_number>
  <catch_line>The Commission consists of not more than 25 voting members appointed by the Governor with the advice...</catch_line>
  <order_by>203</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The Commission consists of not more than 25 voting members appointed by the Governor with the advice and consent of the Senate.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The Secretary is a nonvoting ex officio member of the Commission.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The geographic representation of the Commission shall cover the entire State and shall include at least one representative from:<section prefix="(i)">the upper Eastern Shore;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the lower Eastern Shore;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Calvert County, Charles County, or St. Mary's County;</section><section prefix="(iv)">Allegany County or Garrett County; and</section><section prefix="(v)">Carroll County, Frederick County, or Washington County.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">When appointing Commission members, the Governor shall consider geographic and industry representation.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The members appointed shall reflect the racial and gender diversity of the population of the State.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The appointed members of the Commission shall have substantial interest or experience in business or knowledge of business and economic development.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Commission and its members are subject to the Maryland Public Ethics Law.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The term of an appointed member is 3 years.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">At the end of a term, a member continues to serve until a successor is appointed and qualifies.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A member appointed after a term has begun serves only for the remainder of the term and until a successor is appointed and qualifies.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The terms of the members are staggered as required by the terms provided for members of the Commission on October 1, 2008.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">A member may be removed by the Governor with or without cause.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
