<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gec" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="6-303" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gec-6-303</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Secretary or the Secretary's designee shall certify a person as a qualified business entity if the person meets the requirements of this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A person may not be certified as a qualified business entity unless the person notifies the Department of its intent to seek certification before hiring any qualified employees to fill the qualified positions necessary to meet the requirements of subsection (b)(1) of this section.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">To be eligible for a tax credit under this subtitle, a person shall establish or expand a business facility in the State that:<section prefix="(1)">during any 24-month period creates at least:<section prefix="(i)">60 qualified positions;</section><section prefix="(ii)">30 qualified positions if the aggregate payroll for the qualified positions is greater than a threshold amount equal to the product of multiplying 60 times the State's average annual salary, as determined by the Department; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">25 qualified positions if the business facility established or expanded is located in a State priority funding area; and</section></section><section prefix="(2)">is primarily engaged in:<section prefix="(i)">manufacturing or mining;</section><section prefix="(ii)">transportation or communications;</section><section prefix="(iii)">agriculture, forestry, or fishing;</section><section prefix="(iv)">research, development, or testing;</section><section prefix="(v)">biotechnology;</section><section prefix="(vi)">computer programming, information technology, or other computer-related services;</section><section prefix="(vii)">central services for a business entity engaged in financial services, real estate services, or insurance services;</section><section prefix="(viii)">the operation of central administrative offices;</section><section prefix="(ix)">the operation of a company headquarters other than the headquarters of a professional sports organization;</section><section prefix="(x)">the operation of a public utility;</section><section prefix="(xi)">warehousing;</section><section prefix="(xii)">business services, if the business facility established or expanded is located in a State priority funding area; or</section><section prefix="(xiii)">entertainment, recreation, cultural, or tourism-related activities in a multi-use facility located within a revitalization area if the facility:</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">To be certified as a qualified business entity for a tax credit under this subtitle, a person shall submit to the Department an application that specifies:<section prefix="(1)">the effective date of the start-up or expansion;</section><section prefix="(2)">the number of full-time employees existing before the start-up or expansion and the payroll of the existing employees;</section><section prefix="(3)">the number of qualified positions created and qualified employees hired and the payroll of the new qualified employees; and</section><section prefix="(4)">any other information that the Department requires by regulation.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">When determining whether a business facility is engaged in a qualifying activity described in subsection (b)(2) of this section, the Department shall consider the definitions set forth in the North American Industry Classification System.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The Department may require that any information provided under subsection (c) of this section be verified by an independent auditor that the qualified business entity selects.</section>
  </text>
</law>
