<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gec" order_by="gec" level="1">Economic Development</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gec-10-218</section_number>
  <catch_line>The Authority may authorize the issuance of federally tax-exempt or federally taxable revenue bonds ...</catch_line>
  <order_by>218</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Authority may authorize the issuance of federally tax-exempt or federally taxable revenue bonds by resolution.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Authority may issue revenue bonds:<section prefix="(1)">to pay any part of the cost of developments or projects;</section><section prefix="(2)">to fund a deficit in accordance with subsection (i) of this section;</section><section prefix="(3)">to pay the cost of improvements of developments or projects in accordance with subsection (j) of this section;</section><section prefix="(4)">to refund outstanding bonds issued under this subtitle; and</section><section prefix="(5)">for any other purpose set forth in this subtitle.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Authority may issue the bonds at one time or in one or more series from time to time.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Authority shall determine:<section prefix="(1)">the dates of the bonds;</section><section prefix="(2)">the maturity dates of the bonds, which may not exceed 40 years from the date of their issue;</section><section prefix="(3)">the interest rates on the bonds;</section><section prefix="(4)">the medium of payment of the principal of and interest on the bonds;</section><section prefix="(5)">interest payment dates on the bonds, which shall occur twice in every 12 months;</section><section prefix="(6)">the form of the bonds;</section><section prefix="(7)">the manner of executing the bonds;</section><section prefix="(8)">the denominations of the bonds; and</section><section prefix="(9)">the places at which the principal of and interest on the bonds will be payable, including a bank or trust company in or outside the State.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The bonds may be redeemed before maturity at the option of the Authority at the prices and under terms and conditions that the Authority sets before the bonds are issued.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">An officer's signature or facsimile on a bond remains valid even if the officer leaves office before the bond is delivered.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Authority shall sell the bonds either by competitive or negotiated sale in a manner and for a price that the Authority determines to be in its best interests.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The bonds are exempt from &#xA7;&#xA7; 8-206 and 8-208 of the State Finance and Procurement Article.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(h)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Before it prepares definitive revenue bonds, the Authority may issue temporary revenue bonds meeting the requirements of this section that are exchangeable for definitive revenue bonds when issued.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Authority may replace bonds that are mutilated, lost, or destroyed.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Authority may issue replacement bonds or bonds exchanged for temporary revenue bonds without:<section prefix="(i)">another proceeding; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">the satisfaction of any other condition.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(i)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If the proceeds of the bonds are less than the amount required for the purpose for which the bonds were authorized, the Authority may issue additional bonds to fund the amount of the deficit.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Unless otherwise provided in the resolution authorizing the issuance of bonds or in the trust agreement, the additional bonds are:<section prefix="(i)">considered to be of the same issue as the first issue; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">entitled to payment from the same funds as the first issue, without preference or priority of the bonds of the first issue.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(j)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The resolution authorizing the issuance of bonds may provide for the issuance of additional bonds to pay the cost of any necessary improvements.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The additional bonds:<section prefix="(i)">may be limited in amount by the resolution or trust agreement;</section><section prefix="(ii)">shall be considered part of the first issue authorized by the resolution; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">shall be issued under the restrictions and limitations provided by the resolution or trust agreement.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
