<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gec" order_by="" level="1">Economic Development</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gec-12-110</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>110</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Notwithstanding any limitation of law, a public body may issue and sell bonds periodically to accomplish the legislative purposes of this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A public body may issue and sell bonds to:<section prefix="(i)">subject to paragraph (2) of this subsection, finance the costs of the acquisition or improvement of a facility for a facility user, including working capital;</section><section prefix="(ii)">refund outstanding bonds;</section><section prefix="(iii)">pay the costs of preparing, printing, selling, and issuing the bonds;</section><section prefix="(iv)">fund reserves; and</section><section prefix="(v)">pay the interest on the bonds in the amount and for the period the public body considers reasonable.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">A public body may not issue bonds to acquire working capital unless the bonds are secured by a letter of credit or an interest in property.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">Working capital acquired by issuing bonds may not exceed 25% of the principal amount of the bonds.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Bonds are limited obligations and are not a pledge of the faith and credit or taxing power of the public body.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Bonds issued by an authority are issued on behalf of the public body that established the authority.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Bonds issued by the Maryland Industrial Development Financing Authority:<section prefix="(i)">are issued on behalf of the State; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">shall be issued in accordance with the Maryland Industrial Development Financing Authority Act, Title 5, Subtitle 7 of this article.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A bond:<section prefix="(i)">may be in bearer form;</section><section prefix="(ii)">may be registrable as to principal alone or as to both principal and interest; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">is a "security" as defined by &#xA7; 8-102 of the Commercial Law Article, whether or not the bond is one of a class or series or is divisible into a class or series of instruments.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">A bond shall be signed by the chief executive or by an officer designated by resolution of the public body.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">A bond may be executed by facsimile signature in accordance with &#xA7; 2-303 of the State Finance and Procurement Article.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">The seal of the public body shall be affixed to the bond and attested by the clerk or similar administrative officer of the public body designated by resolution.</section>
        <section prefix="(iv)">An officer's signature or countersignature on a bond or coupon remains valid even if the officer leaves office before the bond is delivered.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Except as provided in subparagraph (ii) of this paragraph, a bond shall mature not later than 30 years after its date of issue.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">If a bond is secured by a mortgage insured by a unit of the federal government, the bond shall have a term of maturity that does not exceed the term of the insurance.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A public body may acquire or improve a facility with bond proceeds:<section prefix="(i)">by leasing the facility to a facility user;</section><section prefix="(ii)">by selling the facility to a facility user under an installment sale agreement;</section><section prefix="(iii)">by lending bond proceeds to a facility user to be used to finance a facility; or</section><section prefix="(iv)">in any other manner that the public body considers appropriate to accomplish the legislative purposes of this subtitle.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The lease of a facility under this subtitle may authorize or require the facility user to acquire the facility on payment of the principal of and interest on the bonds applicable to the facility user.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The consideration for the acquisition of the facility may be nominal.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
