<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gec" order_by="gec" level="1">Economic Development</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gec-4-204</section_number>
  <catch_line>The Board consists of the following 24 members:...</catch_line>
  <order_by>204</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Board consists of the following 24 members:<section prefix="(1)">11 members appointed by the Governor in consultation with the Secretary and with the advice and consent of the Senate;</section><section prefix="(2)">three nonvoting members appointed by the Governor who are directors or chief executive officers from among the destination marketing organizations officially recognized by the Office;</section><section prefix="(3)">five members appointed by the President of the Senate of Maryland as follows:<section prefix="(i)">at least two members of the Senate; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">at least two members from the private business community; and</section></section><section prefix="(4)">five members appointed by the Speaker of the House of Delegates as follows:<section prefix="(i)">at least two members of the House of Delegates; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">at least two members from the private business community.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">In appointing members to the Board, the Governor and, with respect to private business community members, the President of the Senate and the Speaker of the House shall:<section prefix="(1)">ensure that each geographic region of the State is represented equitably;</section><section prefix="(2)">give due consideration to the recommendations of representatives of the tourism industry; and</section><section prefix="(3)">provide balanced representation of the lodging, food service, transportation, retail, and amusements and attractions sectors of the tourism industry.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A member of the Board who is a member of the General Assembly may not vote on a matter before the Board that relates to the exercise of the sovereign powers of the State.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The term of a member is 3 years and begins on July 1.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The terms of members are staggered as required by the terms provided for the members on October 1, 2008.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">At the end of a term, a member continues to serve only until a successor is appointed and qualifies.</section>
        <section prefix="(iv)">A member may be reappointed, but after serving for two consecutive 3-year terms, a member may not be reappointed until at least 1 year after the end of the member's previous tenure.</section>
        <section prefix="(v)">A member who is appointed after a term has begun serves only for the rest of the term and until a successor is appointed and qualifies.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A member of the General Assembly appointed by the President of the Senate or the Speaker of the House serves until a successor is appointed.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A member appointed by the Governor may be removed by the Governor with or without cause.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">A private business community member appointed by the President of the Senate or the Speaker of the House may be removed by the appointing officer with or without cause.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
