<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gec" order_by="" level="1">Economic Development</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gec-10-431</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>431</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">There is a Stem Cell Research Commission.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Commission is an independent commission that functions in the Corporation.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Commission consists of the following members:<section prefix="(1)">the Attorney General or the Attorney General's designee;</section><section prefix="(2)">three patient advocates, one appointed by the Governor, one appointed by the President of the Senate, and one appointed by the Speaker of the House of Delegates;</section><section prefix="(3)">three individuals with experience in biotechnology, one appointed by the Governor, one appointed by the President of the Senate, and one appointed by the Speaker of the House of Delegates;</section><section prefix="(4)">two individuals who work as scientists for the University System of Maryland and do not engage in stem cell research, appointed by the University System of Maryland;</section><section prefix="(5)">two individuals who work as scientists for the Johns Hopkins University and do not engage in stem cell research, appointed by the Johns Hopkins University;</section><section prefix="(6)">two bioethicists, one appointed by the University System of Maryland and one appointed by the Johns Hopkins University; and</section><section prefix="(7)">two individuals with expertise in the field of biomedical ethics as it relates to religion, appointed by the Governor.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The term of an appointed member is 2 years.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The terms of the appointed members are staggered as required by the terms provided for members on October 1, 2008.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">At the end of a term, an appointed member continues to serve until a successor is appointed and qualifies.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">An appointed member may not serve more than three consecutive full terms.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">An appointed member who is appointed after a term has begun serves only for the rest of the term and until a successor is appointed and qualifies.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">Each member of the Commission shall disclose to the State Commission on Ethics whether the member is employed by or has a financial interest in an entity that may apply to conduct State-funded stem cell research.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The members of the Commission shall elect a chair from among the appointed members of the Commission.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">A majority of the full authorized membership of the Commission is a quorum.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">The Commission shall meet at least twice a year.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">A member of the Commission:<section prefix="(1)">may not receive compensation as a member of the Commission; but</section><section prefix="(2)">is entitled to reimbursement for expenses under the Standard State Travel Regulations, as provided in the State budget.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(j)">The Commission may employ a staff, including contractual staff, in accordance with the State budget.</section>
  </text>
</law>
