<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gec" order_by="gec" level="1">Economic Development</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gec-5-557</section_number>
  <catch_line>Under the Program the Authority may not:...</catch_line>
  <order_by>557</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Under the Program the Authority may not:<section prefix="(i)">own securities representing more than 49% of the voting stock of a franchise, technology-based business, or other business or own an interest greater than 49% in a franchise, technology-based business, or other business; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">own securities representing more than 49% of the voting stock of an enterprise acquiring an existing business or own an interest greater than 49% in an enterprise acquiring an existing business.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The amount of the Authority's equity participation financing in an enterprise may not exceed:<section prefix="(i)">the lesser of:<section prefix="1.">$2,000,000 for a franchise; or</section><section prefix="2.">49% of the total initial investment in the franchise;</section></section><section prefix="(ii)">the lesser of:<section prefix="1.">$2,000,000 for an enterprise acquiring an existing business; or</section><section prefix="2.">49% of the total investment in the enterprise acquiring an existing business; or</section></section><section prefix="(iii)">$2,000,000 for a technology-based business.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Before providing equity participation financing, the Authority shall find that there is a reasonable probability that the Authority will recover its initial investment and an adequate return on investment from the equity participation financing.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The Authority's investment shall be recoverable within:<section prefix="(i)">7 years after the equity participation financing in a franchise, an enterprise acquiring an existing business, or any other type of business; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">10 years after the equity participation financing in a technology-based business.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(5)">The Authority's recovery shall be the greater of:<section prefix="(i)">the current value of the percentage of the equity investment in the enterprise; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">the amount of the initial investment in the enterprise.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(6)">The value of the business entity at the time of recovery shall be determined after obtaining at least one independent appraisal of the value from an appraiser selected from a list of at least three appraisers supplied by the Authority.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">When an enterprise applies to the Authority for equity participation financing to acquire an existing business, an enterprise or its principals shall have:<section prefix="(1)">an equity investment equal to at least 5% of the total cost of acquisition; and</section><section prefix="(2)">at least 3 years of successful experience with demonstrated achievements and management responsibilities.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Authority may provide equity participation financing for the acquisition of an existing business if the existing business:<section prefix="(1)">has been in existence for at least 5 years;</section><section prefix="(2)">has been profitable for at least 2 of the previous 3 years;</section><section prefix="(3)">has sufficient cash flow to service the debt and ensure adequate return of the Authority's investment;</section><section prefix="(4)">has the capacity for growth and job creation;</section><section prefix="(5)">has its principal place of business in the State; and</section><section prefix="(6)">has a strong customer base.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">If the applicant enterprise is a sole proprietorship, to qualify for financial assistance under this part, the applicant shall satisfy the Authority that:<section prefix="(1)">the applicant is of good moral character;</section><section prefix="(2)">the applicant has a reputation for financial responsibility, as determined from creditors, employers, and other individuals who have personal knowledge of the applicant;</section><section prefix="(3)">the applicant is a resident of the State or the principal place of business of the applicant is in the State; and</section><section prefix="(4)">the applicant is unable to obtain adequate business financing on reasonable terms through normal lending channels because the applicant:<section prefix="(i)">belongs to a group that historically has been deprived of access to normal economic or financial resources because of race, color, creed, sex, religion, or national origin;</section><section prefix="(ii)">has an identifiable physical handicap that severely limits the ability of the applicant to obtain financial assistance, but that does not limit the ability of the applicant to perform the contract or other activity for which the applicant would be receiving financial assistance;</section><section prefix="(iii)">has any other social or economic impediment that is beyond the control of the applicant, but that does not limit the ability of the applicant to perform the contract or other activity for which the applicant would be receiving financial assistance, including:<section prefix="1.">the lack of formal education or financial capacity; or</section><section prefix="2.">geographical or regional economic distress; or</section></section><section prefix="(iv)">does not meet the established credit or investment criteria of at least one financial institution.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">If the applicant enterprise is not a sole proprietorship, to qualify for financial assistance under this part, at least 51% of the enterprise shall be owned by individuals who meet the qualifications for applicants under subsection (d) of this section.</section>
  </text>
</law>
