<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gec" order_by="" level="1">Economic Development</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gec-10-211</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>211</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Authority may acquire in its own name property, franchises, and licenses by:<section prefix="(1)">purchase on terms and conditions and in the manner the Authority considers appropriate; or</section><section prefix="(2)">condemnation for public use in accordance with applicable law.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If the Authority considers it expedient to establish or construct a development or project on any land, street, alley, or public place that is owned by a political subdivision, the political subdivision may:<section prefix="(i)">lease the land, street, alley, or public place to the Authority on terms agreed to by the Authority and the political subdivision; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">convey title to the land, street, alley, or public place to the Authority on payment to the political subdivision of the reasonable value of the property, as determined by the Authority and the political subdivision, in cash or bonds of the Authority at par.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Notwithstanding paragraph (1) of this subsection, a political subdivision may lease or convey to the Authority without consideration any property that is owned by the political subdivision and suitable for use by the Authority for the purposes of this subtitle.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">A lease or conveyance under this paragraph requires approval by the political subdivision or, for Baltimore City, by the Board of Estimates.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Before an acquisition under this subsection, the Authority, on request of a political subdivision, shall remove or relocate at the expense of the Authority any public utility facilities, whether publicly or privately owned or operated, located on the property.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Authority may not acquire a site under this section for the establishment or construction of a development, or establish or construct a development on a site, unless the site is approved:<section prefix="(1)">for Baltimore City, by the Board of Estimates; and</section><section prefix="(2)">for any other political subdivision, by the county commissioners, county executive, or in a charter county without a county executive, the county council, or in a municipal corporation, by its governing body.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Authority need not accept and pay for any property or rights it acquires except from money provided under this subtitle.</section>
  </text>
</law>
