<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gec" order_by="gec" level="1">Economic Development</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gec-6-505</section_number>
  <catch_line>The Authority consists of the following nine members:...</catch_line>
  <order_by>505</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Authority consists of the following nine members:<section prefix="(1)">seven members appointed by the Governor with the advice and consent of the Senate;</section><section prefix="(2)">one member appointed by the President of the Senate; and</section><section prefix="(3)">one member appointed by the Speaker of the House.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Of the seven members appointed by the Governor:<section prefix="(i)"><section prefix="1.">at least four shall have experience in working with companies that have raised investment capital for seed-stage to venture-stage companies or in providing professional services to the venture capital industry; and</section><section prefix="2.">one of the four members selected under item 1 of  this item shall have experience in higher education research and development and technology transfer projects;</section></section><section prefix="(ii)">at least one shall have experience as a small business owner;</section><section prefix="(iii)">at least one shall have experience as a business executive that has raised venture capital investments; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">at least one shall be a resident of a rural county in the State.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Governor shall consider the geographic diversity of the State when appointing members.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The members appointed by the President and the Speaker:<section prefix="(1)">may not be elected officials; and</section><section prefix="(2)">shall have experience and expertise in venture capital investments.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Each member shall be a resident of the State.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The term of a member is 4 years.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">At the end of a term, a member continues to serve until a successor is appointed.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A member who is appointed after a term has begun serves only for the rest of the term and until a successor is appointed.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">A member appointed by the Governor may be removed by the Governor with or without cause.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">The terms of the members are staggered as required by the terms provided for members of the Authority on July 1, 2011.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">A member of the Authority may not have any financial interest in a purchaser, qualified business, or venture firm.</section>
  </text>
</law>
