<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gec" order_by="" level="1">Economic Development</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gec-10-652</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>652</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">There is a Camden Yards Financing Fund.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Authority shall:<section prefix="(1)">use the Camden Yards Fund as a nonlapsing, revolving fund for implementing this subtitle concerning sports facilities and other facilities at Camden Yards;</section><section prefix="(2)">pay all expenses and make all expenditures related to Camden Yards facilities from the Camden Yards Fund; and</section><section prefix="(3)">transfer the sum of $24,000,000 to the Public School Construction Fund established under &#xA7; 7-326 of the State Finance and Procurement Article by making an annual payment of $2,400,000 beginning in fiscal year 2001 and ending in fiscal year 2010.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">To the extent considered appropriate by the Authority, the receipts of the Camden Yards Fund shall be pledged to and charged with the following relating to sports facilities:<section prefix="(i)">the payment of debt service on Authority bonds;</section><section prefix="(ii)">all reasonable charges and expenses related to Authority borrowing; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">the management of Authority obligations.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The pledge shall be effective as provided in &#xA7; 10-634 of this subtitle and any applicable Authority resolution.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Camden Yards Fund consists of:<section prefix="(1)">proceeds from the sale of bonds related to sports facilities;</section><section prefix="(2)">revenues collected or received from any source under this subtitle related to Camden Yards facilities;</section><section prefix="(3)">any other revenues related to Camden Yards facilities, under the jurisdiction of the Authority;</section><section prefix="(4)">admissions and amusement tax revenues distributed to the Authority under the Tax - General Article;</section><section prefix="(5)">any additional revenue, gift, donation, or other funding source authorized by law related to Camden Yards facilities; and</section><section prefix="(6)">payments by Baltimore City under subsection (f) of this section.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Treasurer shall invest the money of the Camden Yards Fund in the same manner as State funds.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Any investment earnings shall be credited to the Camden Yards Fund.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">No part of the Camden Yards Fund may revert to or be credited to the General Fund or any special fund of the State.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">Baltimore City shall pay $1,000,000 each year into the Camden Yards Fund for the purposes of debt service and other forms of obligation by the Authority.</section>
  </text>
</law>
