<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gec" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="13-408" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gec-13-408</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Executive Board shall include:<section prefix="(1)">the chair of the Council;</section><section prefix="(2)">the Governor or the Governor's designee;</section><section prefix="(3)">the Secretary or the Secretary's designee;</section><section prefix="(4)">the Secretary of Agriculture or the designee of the Secretary of Agriculture;</section><section prefix="(5)">the Secretary of Health and Mental Hygiene or the designee of the Secretary of Health and Mental Hygiene;</section><section prefix="(6)">the Secretary of Housing and Community Development or the designee of the Secretary of Housing and Community Development;</section><section prefix="(7)">the Secretary of Natural Resources or the designee of the Secretary of Natural Resources;</section><section prefix="(8)">the Director of the University of Maryland Cooperative Extension Service or the Director's designee;</section><section prefix="(9)">two representatives of the Maryland Municipal League, selected from rural regions of the State;</section><section prefix="(10)">two representatives of the Maryland Association of Counties, selected from rural regions of the State;</section><section prefix="(11)">one representative of each of the rural regional planning and development councils in the State;</section><section prefix="(12)">one representative of each of the resource, conservation, and development councils in the State;</section><section prefix="(13)">one or more representatives of units of the federal government;</section><section prefix="(14)">one representative from Garrett County, Allegany County, or Washington County;</section><section prefix="(15)">one representative from Carroll County or Frederick County;</section><section prefix="(16)">one representative from Calvert County, Charles County, or St. Mary's County;</section><section prefix="(17)">one representative from Cecil County or Harford County;</section><section prefix="(18)">one representative from Dorchester County, Somerset County, Wicomico County, or Worcester County;</section><section prefix="(19)">one representative of the private for-profit sector;</section><section prefix="(20)">one representative of the not-for-profit sector;</section><section prefix="(21)">no more than six representatives of statewide not-for-profit organizations with a rural focus;</section><section prefix="(22)">two at-large members, selected by the membership of the Council; and</section><section prefix="(23)">as nonvoting members, the senators and delegates appointed to the Council under &#xA7; 13-405(b)(3) of this subtitle.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Members of the Executive Board shall be selected and serve in accordance with the bylaws of the Council.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Council may expand the membership of the Executive Board through the bylaws of the Council.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The chair of the Council is the chair of the Executive Board.</section>
  </text>
</law>
