<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gec" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="10-346" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gec-10-346</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A hospital that intends to close or is scheduled to be delicensed shall provide the Authority and the Health Services Cost Review Commission with a written statement of any outstanding public obligations issued on its behalf.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The statement shall include:<section prefix="(i)">the name of each issuer of the public obligation;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the outstanding principal amount of each public obligation;</section><section prefix="(iii)">the due dates for payment or any mandatory redemption or purchase of each public obligation;</section><section prefix="(iv)">the due dates for the payment of interest on each public obligation and the interest rates; and</section><section prefix="(v)">the documents and information about the public obligation that the Authority or the Health Services Cost Review Commission requests.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A hospital with public obligations issued on or after October 1, 2008, that intends to close or is scheduled to be delicensed, shall provide to the Secretary of Health and Mental Hygiene a closure plan that is acceptable to the Secretary, in consultation with the Maryland Health Care Commission.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The closure plan required under this subsection shall include the plan of the hospital for the provision of care to its patients and to the population in its service area.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The hospital shall file the items required under subsections (a) and (b) of this section:<section prefix="(1)">within 10 days after the date of filing the written notice of intent to close under &#xA7; 19-120(l) of the Health - General Article with the Maryland Health Care Commission; or</section><section prefix="(2)">at least 150 days before the scheduled date of delicensure under &#xA7; 19-325 of the Health - General Article.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
