<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gec" order_by="gec" level="1">Economic Development</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gec-10-205</section_number>
  <catch_line>There is a Maryland Food Center Authority....</catch_line>
  <order_by>205</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">There is a Maryland Food Center Authority.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Authority is a body politic and corporate and an instrumentality of the State.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The exercise by the State, a political subdivision of the State, or the Authority of a power under this subtitle is the performance of an essential governmental function.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Authority consists of 12 members.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Each member shall be a resident of the State.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">One member shall reside in Howard County.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Of the 12 members:<section prefix="(i)">four shall be ex officio members:<section prefix="1.">the Director of Agricultural Extension;</section><section prefix="2.">the Comptroller;</section><section prefix="3.">the Secretary of Agriculture; and</section><section prefix="4.">the Secretary of General Services; and</section></section><section prefix="(ii)">eight shall be outstanding residents appointed by the Governor with the advice and consent of the Senate.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The term of an appointed member is 5 years.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">At the end of a term, an appointed member continues to serve until a successor is appointed and qualifies.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A member who is appointed after a term has begun serves only for the rest of the term and until a successor is appointed and qualifies.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Thirty days after giving written notice to the member, the Governor may remove an appointed member for inefficiency, neglect, or misconduct.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The member is entitled to a hearing before the Governor, if a written request for a hearing is made to the Governor no later than 10 days after receiving the notice.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">If a member is removed, the Governor shall promptly appoint a successor.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">From among its members, the Authority shall elect a chair and a vice chair.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Authority shall elect a secretary-treasurer who need not be a member of the Authority.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(h)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Authority shall meet at least quarterly.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">At least 10 days before each meeting, written notice of the meeting shall be given to each member of the Authority.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(i)">Seven members of the Authority are a quorum.</section>
    <section prefix="(j)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A majority vote of the members present at a meeting having a quorum is needed for the Authority to act.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">An ex officio voting member may designate another individual to vote in that member's absence.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(k)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Authority may pay an appointed member up to $1,000 a year on a per diem basis for services.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A member of the Authority is entitled to reimbursement for expenses under the Standard State Travel Regulations.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Reimbursement and compensation under this subsection may only be paid from money provided under this subtitle.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(l)">The Authority shall adopt rules and regulations necessary for the conduct of its affairs.</section>
  </text>
</law>
