<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gec" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="10-207" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gec-10-207</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Except as otherwise provided in this subtitle, the Authority:<section prefix="(1)">is not subject to the following provisions of the State Finance and Procurement Article:<section prefix="(i)">Title 2, Subtitles 4 (Water and Sewerage Systems) and 5 (Facilities for the Handicapped);</section><section prefix="(ii)">Title 4, Subtitles 7 (State Board of Architectural Review) and 8 (Energy);</section><section prefix="(iii)">&#xA7;&#xA7; 5A-304 and 5A-305 (Historic Landmarks; certain architectural easements);</section><section prefix="(iv)">&#xA7; 7-114.1 (Archeological Costs);</section><section prefix="(v)">&#xA7;&#xA7; 8-127, 8-128, and 8-129 (Certain Restrictions on State General Obligation Debt);</section><section prefix="(vi)">Part V of Title 8, Subtitle 1 (State Revenue Anticipation Notes);</section><section prefix="(vii)">Title 10 (Board of Public Works - Miscellaneous Provisions); and</section><section prefix="(viii)">Division II of the State Finance and Procurement Article (General Procurement Laws); and</section></section><section prefix="(2)">may construct developments and projects without obtaining the consent of any other unit of State government and without any proceeding, the satisfaction of any condition, or the occurrence of any event.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In carrying out its duties relating to developments and projects, the Authority shall comply with Title 14, Subtitle 3 of the State Finance and Procurement Article (Minority Business Participation).</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Authority shall take affirmative steps to include minority businesses in its markets to at least the same extent as applicable to a procurement subject to Title 14, Subtitle 3 of the State Finance and Procurement Article.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A development or project is subject to applicable State health laws and regulations of the Secretary of Health and Mental Hygiene and the Secretary of the Environment.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A development or project is subject to all zoning and subdivision regulations of the political subdivision in which the development or project is located.</section>
  </text>
</law>
