<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gec" order_by="" level="1">Economic Development</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gec-10-340</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>340</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this part the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Affiliate" means a person that directly or indirectly, through one or more intermediaries, controls, is controlled by, or is under common control with another person.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Closure cost" means costs incurred in connection with the closure or delicensing of a hospital.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Closure cost" includes expenses of operating a hospital, payments to employees, employee benefits, fees of consultants, insurance, security services, utilities, legal fees, capital costs, costs of terminating contracts with vendors, suppliers of goods and services and others, debt service, contingencies, and other necessary or appropriate costs and expenses.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">"Control" means the direct or indirect possession of the power to direct or cause the direction of the management and policies of a person through equity interest, membership interest, or contract other than a commercial contract for goods or nonmanagement services, or otherwise, whether or not the power is exercised or sought to be exercised.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"Hospital" means an institution defined as a hospital under &#xA7; 19-301 of the Health - General Article and that is licensed as a hospital by the Secretary of Health and Mental Hygiene under &#xA7; 19-318 of the Health - General Article.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">"Program" means the Maryland Hospital Bond Program under this part.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Public obligation" means a bond, note, evidence of indebtedness, or other obligation, to repay borrowed money issued by the Authority, the State, a unit, instrumentality, or public corporation of the State, a public body as defined in Article 31, &#xA7; 9 of the Code, a county, or a municipal corporation.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Public obligation" does not include an obligation, or portion of an obligation, if:<section prefix="(i)">the principal of and interest on the obligation or the portion of the obligation is:<section prefix="1.">insured by an effective municipal bond insurance policy; and</section><section prefix="2.">issued on behalf of a hospital that voluntarily closed in accordance with &#xA7; 19-120(l) of the Health - General Article; and</section></section><section prefix="(ii)">the proceeds of the obligation or the portion of the obligation are used to finance wholly or partly:<section prefix="1.">a facility or part of a facility that is used primarily to provide outpatient services at a location other than the hospital; or</section><section prefix="2.">a facility or part of a facility that is used primarily by physicians who are not employees of the hospital to provide services to nonhospital patients.</section></section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
