<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gec" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="10-640" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gec-10-640</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Except as allowed by &#xA7; 10-639 of this subtitle, to finance site acquisition and construction, the Authority shall comply with this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Authority shall provide to the fiscal committees of the General Assembly, at least 90 days before seeking approval of the Board of Public Works for each bond issue or other borrowing, a comprehensive financing plan for the relevant segment of the facility, including the effect of the financing plan on financing options for other segments of the facility.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Authority shall obtain the approval of the Board of Public Works of the proposed bond issue and the financing plan.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Authority shall secure a lease or other written agreement with Baltimore City, as approved by the Board of Public Works, under which:<section prefix="(1)">Baltimore City agrees to pay $50,000,000 for the capital costs of the expansion of the Baltimore Convention Center not later than the date of the Authority's bond issuance as authorized under &#xA7; 10-628 of this subtitle;</section><section prefix="(2)">Baltimore City and the Authority each own a 50% leasehold interest as tenants in common in the improvements comprising the existing Baltimore Convention Center and the Baltimore Convention Center expansion for the duration of any bonds issued as authorized under &#xA7; 10-628 of this subtitle; and</section><section prefix="(3)">Baltimore City and the Authority agree not to sell, assign, mortgage, pledge, or encumber the Baltimore Convention facility, or any leasehold interest in the facility, without the prior consent of the other, except for liens in favor of their respective bondholders.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The Authority shall secure a deed, lease, or written agreement with Baltimore City, as approved by the Board of Public Works, authorizing the Authority to:<section prefix="(1)">design and construct, or contract for the design and construction of, the Baltimore Convention facility; and</section><section prefix="(2)">pledge the Baltimore Convention facility and the Baltimore Convention site or the leasehold interest in the facility as security for the Authority's bonds.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The Authority shall secure a written agreement with Baltimore City, as approved by the Board of Public Works:<section prefix="(1)">in which Baltimore City agrees to:<section prefix="(i)">operate the Baltimore Convention facility in a manner that maximizes the facility's economic return; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">maintain and repair the facility so as to keep it in first class operating condition; and</section></section><section prefix="(2)">that includes provisions that:<section prefix="(i)">protect the respective investment of the Authority, the State, and Baltimore City in the Baltimore Convention facility;</section><section prefix="(ii)">require:</section><section prefix="(iii)">provide for remedies on default, including the right of the Authority or the State, if a material default by Baltimore City is not corrected after a reasonable notice and cure period, to:</section></section></section>
  </text>
</law>
