<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gec" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="10-651" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gec-10-651</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">There is a Baltimore Convention Financing Fund.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Baltimore Convention Fund is a continuing, nonlapsing fund that shall be available in perpetuity to implement this subtitle concerning Baltimore Convention facilities.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Authority shall:<section prefix="(i)">use the Baltimore Convention Fund as a revolving fund for carrying out this subtitle concerning Baltimore Convention facilities; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">pay any and all expenses from the Baltimore Convention Fund that are incurred by the Authority related to the Baltimore Convention facility.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">To the extent considered appropriate by the Authority, the receipts of the Baltimore Convention Fund shall be pledged to and charged with the following relating to the Baltimore Convention facility:<section prefix="(i)">the payment of debt service on Authority bonds;</section><section prefix="(ii)">all reasonable charges and expenses related to Authority borrowing; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">the management of Authority obligations.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The pledge shall be effective as provided in &#xA7; 10-634 of this subtitle and any applicable Authority resolution.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Baltimore Convention Fund consists of:<section prefix="(1)">funds appropriated for deposit to the Baltimore Convention Fund;</section><section prefix="(2)">proceeds from the sale of bonds concerning the Baltimore Convention facility;</section><section prefix="(3)">revenues collected or received from any source under this subtitle related to Baltimore Convention facilities; and</section><section prefix="(4)">any additional money made available from any public or private sources for the purposes established for the Baltimore Convention Fund.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Treasurer shall invest the money of the Baltimore Convention Fund in the same manner as other State funds.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Any investment earnings shall be credited to the Baltimore Convention Fund.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">No part of the Baltimore Convention Fund may revert or be credited to the General Fund or any special fund of the State.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
