<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gec" order_by="gec" level="1">Economic Development</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gec-5-603</section_number>
  <catch_line>The Department may require that all or part of a grant be repaid, with interest at a rate the Depart...</catch_line>
  <order_by>603</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Department may require that all or part of a grant be repaid, with interest at a rate the Department sets, when conditions specified by the Department occur.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Whenever the Department is authorized by law to make a grant, including a grant from the Economic Development Opportunities Program Account authorized under &#xA7; 7-314 of the State Finance and Procurement Article, the Department may use money appropriated for the grant to make an equity investment in a business enterprise.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">In making an equity investment under this subtitle, the Department may not acquire an ownership interest in an enterprise that exceeds 25%.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Within 15 years after making an equity investment under this subtitle, the Department shall divest itself of that investment.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The liability of the State and the Department in making an equity investment under this subtitle is limited to the amount of that investment.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">The Department shall adopt regulations governing equity investments under this subsection that specify:<section prefix="(i)">the types of business enterprises in which an investment may be made;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the basic standards an enterprise shall meet to qualify for an investment;</section><section prefix="(iii)">the amount of money available for investment; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">the criteria that the Department uses to make investment decisions.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
