<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gec" order_by="gec" level="1">Economic Development</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gec-5-321</section_number>
  <catch_line>After consulting with the Department and the Department of Labor, Licensing, and Regulation, each ye...</catch_line>
  <order_by>321</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">After consulting with the Department and the Department of Labor, Licensing, and Regulation, each year the Maryland Economic Development Commission shall:<section prefix="(i)">evaluate the potential employment and economic growth of Maryland's industry sectors; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">recommend eligible industry sectors to the Authority.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Each year the Authority shall:<section prefix="(i)">consider the recommendation of the Maryland Economic Development Commission; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">establish a list of industry sectors that will be eligible for financial assistance from the Fund.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">In determining whether an applicant is engaged in an eligible industry sector, the Department shall consider the definitions set forth in the North American Industry Classification System.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">For the purpose of providing financial assistance under this subtitle, the following are deemed to be in eligible industry sectors:<section prefix="(i)">aquaculture projects;</section><section prefix="(ii)">arts and entertainment enterprises;</section><section prefix="(iii)">arts and entertainment projects;</section><section prefix="(iv)">redevelopment of qualified brownfields sites;</section><section prefix="(v)">creation or expansion of child care facilities;</section><section prefix="(vi)">projects in areas that are declared to be federal disaster areas within 1 year before the Department receives an application for financial assistance under this subtitle; and</section><section prefix="(vii)">feasibility studies.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The requirements specifically imposed on significant strategic economic development opportunities and local economic development opportunities under this subtitle do not apply to the items listed in paragraph (1) of this subsection.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
