<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gec" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="12-101" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gec-12-101</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Authority" means an industrial development authority established in accordance with &#xA7; 12-105 of this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Bond" means a revenue bond, note, or other instrument, certificate, or evidence of obligation that is issued and sold by a public body under this subtitle to finance a facility or to refund an outstanding bond.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Bond" includes:<section prefix="(i)">a bond anticipation note; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">a note in the nature of commercial paper.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">"Chief executive" means the president, chair, mayor, county executive, or any other chief executive officer of a public body.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"Facility" means any land or an interest in land, structure, working capital, equipment, or other property, or any combination of them, the acquisition or improvement of which the legislative body of a county or municipal corporation, the board of directors of an authority, or the Maryland Industrial Development Financing Authority, in its sole discretion, determines by resolution will accomplish one or more of the legislative purposes listed in &#xA7; 12-103(b) of this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">"Facility applicant" means a person, public or private corporation, or other entity, whether for-profit or not-for-profit, that, by letter of intent or similar agreement with a public body, requests the public body to participate in financing a facility under this subtitle for use by a facility user.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Facility user" means a person, public or private corporation, or other entity, whether for-profit or not-for-profit, that owns, leases, or uses all or part of a facility.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Facility user" may include a facility applicant.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(h)">"Finance" includes refinance.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Finance board" means a unit or instrumentality of a county or municipal corporation that is authorized by statute or charter to issue and sell bonds of the county or municipal corporation.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Finance board" does not include the legislative body of a county or municipal corporation.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(j)">"Improve" means to add, alter, construct, equip, expand, extend, improve, install, reconstruct, rehabilitate, remodel, or repair.</section>
    <section prefix="(k)">"Improvement" means addition, alteration, construction, equipping, expansion, extension, improvement, installation, reconstruction, rehabilitation, remodeling, or repair.</section>
    <section prefix="(l)">"Public body" means:<section prefix="(1)">a county;</section><section prefix="(2)">a municipal corporation;</section><section prefix="(3)">an authority; or</section><section prefix="(4)">the Maryland Industrial Development Financing Authority.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(m)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Public port" means the public ports and harbors on the Chesapeake Bay or the Isle of Wight Bay and their tributaries in the State.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Public port" includes:<section prefix="(i)">the Baltimore Harbor (the Patapsco River and its tributaries north and west of North Point and Bodkin Point);</section><section prefix="(ii)">the Port of Cambridge (the south side of the Choptank River between Hambrook's Bar and the Emerson C. Harrington Bridge); and</section><section prefix="(iii)">the Port of Crisfield (the Little Annemessex River east of James Island).</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
