<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gec" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="10-622" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gec-10-622</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Subject to subsection (b) of this section, the Authority may prepare studies and may design and construct projects for units of the State, the University of Maryland Medical System, and political subdivisions.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The studies may include site studies, architectural programs, budget estimates, value engineering, and project schedules.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Before beginning work under subsection (a) of this section on behalf of a unit of the State, the University of Maryland Medical System, or a political subdivision, the Authority shall:<section prefix="(1)">notify the budget committees of the General Assembly in writing of the proposed project and its estimated costs and funding sources; and</section><section prefix="(2)">allow the budget committees 30 days to review and comment on the proposed work.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Authority may enter into contracts, retain consultants, and make recommendations relating to project activities under this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">For project activities under this section, the Authority shall use money that is:<section prefix="(i)">provided by the unit of the State, the University of Maryland Medical System, or local government; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">otherwise appropriated for the particular purpose.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">In each fiscal year the Authority:<section prefix="(i)">may use up to $500,000 of its available nonbudgeted money for feasibility studies that are approved by the budget committees; but</section><section prefix="(ii)">may not use this money for construction.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
