<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gec" order_by="gec" level="1">Economic Development</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gec-13-803</section_number>
  <catch_line>The Council consists of the members described in this subsection....</catch_line>
  <order_by>803</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Council consists of the members described in this subsection.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The voting members of the Council are:<section prefix="(i)">from Somerset County, the five commissioners;</section><section prefix="(ii)">from Wicomico County:<section prefix="1.">the county executive; and</section><section prefix="2.">four members of the county council, appointed by the county council;</section></section><section prefix="(iii)">from Worcester County, five commissioners, appointed by the Board of County Commissioners;</section><section prefix="(iv)">three municipal elected officials, one from each county, appointed by:<section prefix="1.">their respective municipal corporations; or</section><section prefix="2.">the Eastern Shore Municipal Association if the municipal corporations are unable to appoint a member within a reasonable time; and</section></section><section prefix="(v)">if the majority of the member's legislative district is in the region, each member of the General Assembly representing the region.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The nonvoting members of the Council are:<section prefix="(i)">each commissioner in the region who is not appointed under paragraph (2) of this subsection; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">each other member of the General Assembly representing the region if the majority of the member's legislative district is not in the region.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The bylaws of the Council may provide for additional members who are private individuals.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A member appointed under subsection (a)(2)(i), (ii), or (iii) of this section may designate another commissioner or a county administrator representing the same county to vote by proxy for the member when the member is absent from a meeting.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A member who designates a proxy shall inform the Executive Director in advance of the meeting.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A member who qualifies because of the member's elected position is a member of the Council only during the member's term of office in the elected position.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">At the end of a term, a member continues to serve until a successor is appointed.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Council membership is not an office of profit.</section>
  </text>
</law>
