<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gec" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="12-308" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gec-12-308</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">A bond:<section prefix="(1)">may be in bearer form;</section><section prefix="(2)">may be registrable as to principal alone or as to both principal and interest; and</section><section prefix="(3)">is a "security" under &#xA7; 8-102 of the Commercial Law Article, whether or not the bond is one of a class or series or is divisible into a class or series of instruments.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A bond shall be signed manually or in facsimile by the chief executive of the political subdivision.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">An officer's signature or facsimile signature on a bond remains valid even if the officer leaves office before the bond is delivered.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The seal of the political subdivision shall be affixed to the bond and attested by the clerk or other similar administrative officer of the political subdivision.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A bond shall mature not later than 40 years after the date of issue.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Bonds may be issued as serial bonds or term bonds with provisions for a mandatory sinking fund or other annual principal redemption beginning not later than 3 years after the date of issue.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A bond shall be sold in the manner, at public or private (negotiated) sale, and on the terms at, above, or below par, as the political subdivision considers best.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A contract to acquire property may provide that payments shall be made in bonds.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A bond is not subject to Article 31, &#xA7;&#xA7; 9, 10, and 11 of the Code.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
