<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gec" order_by="" level="1">Economic Development</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gec-12-204</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>204</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Notwithstanding any limitation of law, an issuer may issue bonds from time to time to finance the development of an industrial, commercial, or residential area.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">To issue bonds under this subtitle, the governing body of a political subdivision shall adopt an ordinance that:<section prefix="(1)">describes the proposed undertaking; and</section><section prefix="(2)">states:<section prefix="(i)">that the governing body has complied with &#xA7;&#xA7; 12-203 and 12-208(c) and (d) of this subtitle;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the maximum principal amount of the bonds; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">the maximum rate of interest on the bonds.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The ordinance may specify the following for bonds issued to carry out the financing of the proposed undertaking:<section prefix="(1)">the principal amount;</section><section prefix="(2)">the rate of interest;</section><section prefix="(3)">the manner and terms of sale;</section><section prefix="(4)">the time of execution, issuance, and delivery;</section><section prefix="(5)">the form and denomination;</section><section prefix="(6)">the manner in which, and the times and places at which principal and interest shall be paid;</section><section prefix="(7)">conditions for redemption before maturity; or</section><section prefix="(8)">other provisions consistent with this subtitle that the governing body of the political subdivision determines are necessary or desirable.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The revenue authority of Prince George's County may issue bonds in accordance with an ordinance adopted by the governing body of Prince George's County.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The ordinance may specify the items listed in subsection (c) of this section or may authorize:<section prefix="(1)">the finance board to specify those items by resolution or ordinance; or</section><section prefix="(2)">the chief executive to specify those items by executive order.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, neither an ordinance authorizing the bonds nor an ordinance, resolution, or executive order issued, passed, or adopted under this section may be subject to referendum because of any other State or local law.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">An ordinance that authorizes the pledge of the full faith and credit of a political subdivision to the payment of principal and interest on a bond is subject to any applicable right to referendum.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
