<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gec" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="12-207" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gec-12-207</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Bond proceeds may be used only:<section prefix="(1)">to buy, lease, condemn, or otherwise acquire property, or an interest in property:<section prefix="(i)">in the development district; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">needed for a right-of-way or other easement to or from the development district;</section></section><section prefix="(2)">for site removal;</section><section prefix="(3)">for surveys and studies;</section><section prefix="(4)">to relocate businesses or residents;</section><section prefix="(5)">to install utilities, construct parks and playgrounds, and for other needed improvements including:<section prefix="(i)">roads to, from, or in the development district;</section><section prefix="(ii)">parking; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">lighting;</section></section><section prefix="(6)">to construct or rehabilitate buildings for a governmental purpose or use;</section><section prefix="(7)">for reserves or capitalized interest;</section><section prefix="(8)">for necessary costs to issue bonds; and</section><section prefix="(9)">to pay the principal of and interest on loans, advances, or indebtedness that a political subdivision incurs for a purpose specified in this section.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In addition to the purposes listed in subsection (a) of this section, the proceeds from bonds that Prince George's County or the revenue authority of Prince George's County issues may be used:<section prefix="(i)">for convention, conference, or visitors' centers;</section><section prefix="(ii)">to maintain infrastructure improvements and convention, conference, or visitors' centers;</section><section prefix="(iii)">to market development district facilities and other improvements; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">for the purpose of encouraging redevelopment in those areas listed in paragraph (2) of this subsection, to install infrastructure improvements, including:</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The purpose of the authority granted by paragraph (1)(iv) of this subsection is to encourage redevelopment in:<section prefix="(i)">revitalization areas designated by the county;</section><section prefix="(ii)">mixed use centers;</section><section prefix="(iii)">blighted areas; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">the Developed Tier, growth corridors, and growth centers, as defined in the county General Plan.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In addition to the purposes listed in subsection (a) of this section, the proceeds from bonds that a municipal corporation issues may be used for the purpose of encouraging redevelopment in those areas listed in paragraph (2) of this subsection, to install infrastructure improvements, including:<section prefix="(i)">streets;</section><section prefix="(ii)">parking structures of any type whether for public or private use;</section><section prefix="(iii)">utilities;</section><section prefix="(iv)">street lights;</section><section prefix="(v)">stormwater management and storm drain facilities;</section><section prefix="(vi)">fencing;</section><section prefix="(vii)">noise walls;</section><section prefix="(viii)">retaining walls;</section><section prefix="(ix)">trails;</section><section prefix="(x)">sidewalks;</section><section prefix="(xi)">pedestrian and vehicular bridges; and</section><section prefix="(xii)">park facilities.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The purpose of the authority granted by paragraph (1) of this subsection is to encourage redevelopment in:<section prefix="(i)">revitalization areas designated by a county or municipal corporation;</section><section prefix="(ii)">mixed use centers;</section><section prefix="(iii)">blighted areas; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">developed areas and growth areas, as defined in a county or municipal corporation land use plan.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
