<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gec" order_by="gec" level="1">Economic Development</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gec-5-344</section_number>
  <catch_line>An applicant for a child care special loan shall submit to the Department an application that contai...</catch_line>
  <order_by>344</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">An applicant for a child care special loan shall submit to the Department an application that contains the information that the Department requires.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The application shall include:<section prefix="(1)">a detailed description of the proposed or existing child care facility;</section><section prefix="(2)">an itemization of known and estimated costs;</section><section prefix="(3)">the total amount of money required to expand or improve child care services at the child care facility;</section><section prefix="(4)">the money available to the applicant without a child care special loan from the Department;</section><section prefix="(5)">the amount of money sought from the Department;</section><section prefix="(6)">evidence of the inability of the applicant to obtain the financing necessary for the child care facility on affordable terms through normal lending channels;</section><section prefix="(7)">information that relates to the financial status of the applicant, including, if applicable:<section prefix="(i)">a current balance sheet;</section><section prefix="(ii)">a profit and loss statement; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">credit references; and</section></section><section prefix="(8)">a lease, option to buy, deed, or evidence that the applicant is legally entitled to remain at the child care facility for at least the term of the loan.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The applicant for a child care special loan shall agree to:<section prefix="(1)">operate the child care facility for at least the term of the child care special loan; and</section><section prefix="(2)">repay the outstanding child care special loan in full on the loss of license, termination of lease, or transfer, sale, or refinancing of the child care facility, as applicable, before the end of the term of the child care special loan.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
