<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gec" order_by="" level="1">Economic Development</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gec-10-347</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>347</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Health Services Cost Review Commission may determine to provide for the payment of all or part of the reasonable closure costs of a hospital having outstanding public obligations if the Health Services Cost Review Commission determines that the payment is necessary or appropriate to:<section prefix="(1)">encourage and assist the hospital to close; or</section><section prefix="(2)">implement the Program created by this part.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">In making the determinations under subsection (a) of this section, the Health Services Cost Review Commission shall consider:<section prefix="(1)">the system-wide savings to the State health care system expected to result from the closure or delicensure of the hospital during the longer of:<section prefix="(i)">the period when the fee will be assessed to provide for the payment of the closure costs or any bond issued to finance the closure costs; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">5 years after the date of closure or delicensure; and</section></section><section prefix="(2)">the recommendations of the Maryland Health Care Commission and the Authority.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Within 60 days after receiving the notice of closure or delicensure required by &#xA7; 10-344(a)(1)(i) or (b) of this subtitle, the Health Services Cost Review Commission shall:<section prefix="(1)">determine whether to provide for the payment of all or a part of the closure costs of the hospital in accordance with this section; and</section><section prefix="(2)">give written notification of its determination to the Maryland Health Care Commission and the Authority.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">This section does not require the Health Services Cost Review Commission to provide for the payment of any closure costs of a closed or delicensed hospital.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">In a proceeding involving the validity or enforceability of a bond issued to finance closure costs or any security for the bond, the determinations of the Health Services Cost Review Commission under this section are conclusive and binding.</section>
  </text>
</law>
