<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gec" order_by="" level="1">Economic Development</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gec-6-517</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>517</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Subject to the approval of the Department, the Authority shall obtain the services of an independent third party to:<section prefix="(1)">establish application procedures for an entity to be certified as a venture firm; and</section><section prefix="(2)">review and evaluate applications for venture firm certification under this section.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The independent third party selected by the Authority shall:<section prefix="(1)">review and evaluate the application, organizational documents, and business history of each applicant;</section><section prefix="(2)">evaluate whether the applicant is likely to achieve the investment criteria set forth in this subtitle; and</section><section prefix="(3)">recommend to the Authority which venture firms should receive allocations of designated capital under the Program.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">On receiving the recommendations of the independent third party selected under subsection (a) of this section and subject to &#xA7; 6-518 of this subtitle, the Authority shall select venture firms to receive allocations of designated capital that are consistent with the investment criteria set forth in this subtitle.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Authority shall ensure that the venture firms receiving designated capital for investment under this subtitle make investments in the State that equal or exceed the amount of designated capital received under this subtitle.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Subject to the approval of the Department, the Authority may enter into written agreements, including partnership agreements and side agreements, that are necessary to carry out the purposes of this subtitle.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
