<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gec" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="10-118" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gec-10-118</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Corporation may authorize the issuance of revenue bonds by resolution.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Corporation may issue the bonds at one time or in one or more series from time to time.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Corporation shall determine:<section prefix="(1)">the date of the bonds;</section><section prefix="(2)">the maturity dates of the bonds, which may not exceed 40 years from the date of issue;</section><section prefix="(3)">the interest rates on the bonds;</section><section prefix="(4)">the medium of payment of the principal of and interest on the bonds;</section><section prefix="(5)">the form of the bonds;</section><section prefix="(6)">the manner of executing the bonds;</section><section prefix="(7)">the denominations of the bonds; and</section><section prefix="(8)">the place at which the principal of and interest on the bonds will be payable, including at a bank or trust company in or outside the State.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">An officer's signature or facsimile signature on a bond remains valid even if the officer leaves office before the bond is delivered.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Between successive holders, bonds are negotiable instruments under Title 3 of the Maryland Uniform Commercial Code.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Bonds may be registrable.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Corporation shall sell the bonds by competitive or negotiated sale in a manner and for a price the Corporation determines to be in its best interests.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Bonds are exempt from &#xA7;&#xA7; 8-206 and 8-208 of the State Finance and Procurement Article.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">Bond proceeds may be placed in escrow pending application of the proceeds to the purposes for which the bonds are issued.</section>
  </text>
</law>
