<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gec" order_by="" level="1">Economic Development</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gec-10-628</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>628</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Except as provided in subsections (b) and (c) of this section and subject to the prior approval of the Board of Public Works, the Authority may issue bonds at any time for any corporate purpose of the Authority, including the establishment of reserves and the payment of interest.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Unless authorized by the General Assembly, the Board of Public Works may not approve an issuance by the Authority of bonds for sports facilities at Camden Yards, whether taxable or tax exempt, that constitute tax supported debt if, after the issuance, there would be outstanding and unpaid $235,000,000 face amount of bonds for the purpose of financing the site acquisition and preparation, relocation, demolition and removal, construction and related expenses for construction management, professional fees, and contingencies of baseball and football stadiums or a multiuse stadium.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Subject to subparagraph (ii) of this paragraph, the limits on the issuance of bonds of the Authority, whether taxable or tax exempt, that constitute tax supported debt for the following purposes with respect to sports facilities at Camden Yards are:<section prefix="1.">$85,000,000 for site acquisition and preparation, relocation, demolition and removal, and construction and related expenses for construction management, professional fees, and contingencies for Camden Yards;</section><section prefix="2.">$70,000,000 for site work, construction and related expenses for construction management, professional fees, and contingencies of a baseball stadium;</section><section prefix="3.">$80,000,000 for site work, construction and related expenses for construction management, professional fees, and contingencies of a football stadium; and</section><section prefix="4.">$195,000,000 for site acquisition and preparation, relocation, demolition and removal, and construction and related expenses for construction management, professional fees, and contingencies of a multiuse stadium.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The Authority may exceed the monetary limits on bond issuances provided for in subparagraph (i) of this paragraph if the Authority:<section prefix="1.">obtains the authorization of the Board of Public Works; and</section><section prefix="2.">notifies the Legislative Policy Committee with accompanying justification.</section></section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Unless authorized by the General Assembly, the Board of Public Works may not approve an issuance by the Authority of bonds, whether taxable or tax exempt, that constitute tax supported debt if, after issuance, there would be outstanding and unpaid more than the following face amounts of the bonds for the purpose of financing acquisition, construction, renovation, and related expenses for construction management, professional fees, and contingencies in connection with:<section prefix="(i)">the Baltimore Convention facility - $55,000,000;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the Hippodrome Performing Arts facility - $20,250,000;</section><section prefix="(iii)">the Montgomery County Conference facility - $23,185,000; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">the Ocean City Convention facility - $17,340,000.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The limitation under paragraph (1)(i) of this subsection applies to the aggregate principal amount of bonds outstanding as of June 30 of any year.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">Refunded bonds may not be included in the determination of an outstanding aggregate amount under this paragraph.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
