<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gec" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="10-328" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gec-10-328</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Authority shall set aside a sufficient amount of the revenues derived from a project in a sinking fund or other similar fund at regular intervals to the extent required in the trust agreement.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The sinking fund is pledged to pay:<section prefix="(i)">the principal of and the interest on the bonds as they become due; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">the redemption or purchase price of bonds retired by call or purchase as specified in the trust agreement.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">To the extent provided in the trust agreement, the Authority may exclude from the amount to be deposited in the sinking fund the revenues that may be necessary:<section prefix="(i)">to pay for project maintenance, repair, and operation;</section><section prefix="(ii)">for reserves; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">for improvements to the project.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The pledge of revenues under subsection (a) of this section is valid and binding from the time the pledge is made.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The rates, rents, charges, fees, and other revenue or money that the Authority pledges and receives are subject immediately to the lien of the pledge.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">Neither physical delivery of the rates, rents, charges, fees, and other revenue or money nor any other act is required to validate the lien.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The lien of the pledge is valid and binding against each party with a claim against the Authority in tort, contract, or otherwise, regardless of whether the party has notice of the lien.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The trust agreement and any other agreement or lease creating a pledge under this section need not be filed or recorded, except in the records of the Authority.</section>
  </text>
</law>
