<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gec" order_by="gec" level="1">Economic Development</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gec-5-203</section_number>
  <catch_line>There is a Maryland Economic Adjustment Fund in the Department....</catch_line>
  <order_by>203</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">There is a Maryland Economic Adjustment Fund in the Department.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Department shall administer the Fund.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Secretary may:<section prefix="(i)">delegate to any unit in the Department the underwriting, closing, monitoring, and workout functions for Fund loans; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">contract with another entity to perform these functions.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Maryland Economic Adjustment Fund is a special, nonlapsing revolving fund that is not subject to reversion under &#xA7; 7-302 of the State Finance and Procurement Article.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Fund consists of:<section prefix="(i)">federal money allocated or granted to the Fund, including adjustment implementation grant money designated for the Fund under the Defense Conversion and Defense Economic Adjustment Program of the Economic Development Administration of the United States Department of Commerce;</section><section prefix="(ii)">private money donated or granted to the Fund;</section><section prefix="(iii)">money appropriated by the State to the Fund;</section><section prefix="(iv)">premiums, fees, interest payments, and principal payments on loans made under this subtitle, including a loan financed by the Economic Development Opportunities Program Fund under &#xA7; 7-314(f) of the State Finance and Procurement Article;</section><section prefix="(v)">proceeds from the sale, disposition, lease, or rental of collateral relating to loans under this subtitle; and</section><section prefix="(vi)">any other money made available to the Fund.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">This subtitle does not require an appropriation to the Fund from the General Fund of the State, regardless of the availability of other funding sources for the Fund.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Fund shall be used to:<section prefix="(i)">make loans to new or existing companies with 50 or fewer employees;</section><section prefix="(ii)">make grants to local or regional governmental or not-for-profit economic development revolving loan funds in the State; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">pay all expenses and disbursements authorized by the Department for administering the Fund.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A loan to an eligible company under this subtitle may include:<section prefix="(i)">advances of loan proceeds for loans; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">to the extent allowed by the regulations of the federal Economic Development Administration of the United States Department of Commerce, money for expenses for administrative, legal, actuarial, technical, and other services.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Subject to the restrictions of this subtitle, the Department may make a loan from the Fund to an applicant only if:<section prefix="(i)">the applicant meets the qualifications under this subtitle; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">the applicant meets any additional requirements imposed by the source of the money to be loaned.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Treasurer shall invest the money of the Fund in the same manner as other State money may be invested.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Any investment earnings of the Fund shall be credited to the Fund.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Treasurer shall submit a report each year to the Department on:<section prefix="(i)">the status of the money invested under this subtitle;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the market value of the assets in the Fund on the date of the report; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">the interest received from investments for the Fund during the reporting period.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
