<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gec" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="6-301" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gec-6-301</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Credit year" means the taxable year in which a qualified business entity claims the credit allowed in accordance with &#xA7; 6-304(a) of this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Qualified business entity" means a person conducting or operating a trade or business in the State that is certified in accordance with &#xA7; 6-303 of this subtitle as qualifying for the tax credit under this subtitle.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">For a person engaged in a business activity described in &#xA7; 6-303(b)(2)(xiii) of this subtitle, "qualified business entity":<section prefix="(i)">includes a person owning or operating the multi-use facility in which the entertainment, recreation, cultural, or tourism-related activities are operated; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">does not include any separate entity that leases retail space at the facility.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Qualified position" means a position that:<section prefix="(i)">is full-time and of indefinite duration;</section><section prefix="(ii)">pays at least 150% of the federal minimum wage;</section><section prefix="(iii)">is located in the State;</section><section prefix="(iv)">is newly created as a result of the establishment or expansion of a business facility in a single location in the State; and</section><section prefix="(v)">is filled.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Qualified position" does not include a position that is:<section prefix="(i)">created when an employment function is shifted from an existing business facility of a business entity in the State to another business facility of the same business entity if the position is not a net new job in the State;</section><section prefix="(ii)">created through a change in ownership of a trade or business;</section><section prefix="(iii)">created through a consolidation, merger, or restructuring of a business entity if the position is not a net new job in the State;</section><section prefix="(iv)">created when an employment function is contractually shifted from an existing business entity to another business entity in the State if the position is not a net new job in the State; or</section><section prefix="(v)">filled for a period of less than 12 months.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">For a person engaged in a business activity described in &#xA7; 6-303(b)(2)(xiii) of this subtitle, "qualified position" does not include any position other than a position engaged in:<section prefix="(i)">the operation of entertainment, recreation, cultural, or tourism-related activities within the multi-use facility; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">management, marketing, building maintenance, hotel services, or security for the multi-use facility.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"Revitalization area" means:<section prefix="(1)">an enterprise zone designated by the Secretary under &#xA7; 5-704 of this article;</section><section prefix="(2)">an enterprise zone designated by the United States government under 42 U.S.C. &#xA7;&#xA7; 11501 through 11505;</section><section prefix="(3)">an empowerment zone or enterprise community designated by the United States government under 26 U.S.C. &#xA7;&#xA7; 1391 through 1397F; or</section><section prefix="(4)">a sustainable community, as defined in &#xA7; 6-301 of the Housing and Community Development Article.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">"State priority funding area" means:<section prefix="(1)">a municipal corporation;</section><section prefix="(2)">Baltimore City;</section><section prefix="(3)">a sustainable community, as defined in &#xA7; 6-301 of the Housing and Community Development Article;</section><section prefix="(4)">an enterprise zone designated by the Secretary under &#xA7; 5-704 of this article;</section><section prefix="(5)">an enterprise zone designated by the United States government under 42 U.S.C. &#xA7;&#xA7; 11501 through 11505;</section><section prefix="(6)">those areas of the State located between Interstate Highway 495 and the District of Columbia;</section><section prefix="(7)">those areas of the State located between Interstate Highway 695 and Baltimore City;</section><section prefix="(8)">no more than one area in a county designated by the county as a priority funding area under &#xA7; 5-7B-03(c) of the State Finance and Procurement Article; and</section><section prefix="(9)">that portion of the Port Land Use Development Zone, as defined in &#xA7; 6-501 of the Transportation Article, that has been designated as an area appropriate for growth in a county comprehensive master plan.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
