<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gec" order_by="gec" level="1">Economic Development</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gec-12-106</section_number>
  <catch_line>Subject to paragraph (4) of this subsection, the board of directors of an authority consists of five...</catch_line>
  <order_by>106</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Subject to paragraph (4) of this subsection, the board of directors of an authority consists of five members appointed by the legislative body of the incorporating county or municipal corporation.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Appointment procedures shall be provided in the resolution establishing the authority.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">In a county or municipal corporation that has a publicly elected chief executive, the chief executive shall submit nominations for the initial board members.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The chief executive may nominate more than one individual for an initial board member position.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(4)">An officer or employee of the incorporating county or municipal corporation may not be appointed to the board but, if provided by resolution, may serve as an ex officio, nonvoting member of the board.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The initial five members of the board of directors of an authority shall be appointed for staggered terms, ranging from 1 to 5 years, respectively, beginning on the date the State Department of Assessments and Taxation accepts the articles of incorporation of the authority for record.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">Except as provided for initial board members, the term of an appointed member is 5 years.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">At the end of a term, an appointed member continues to serve until a successor is appointed.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A member who is appointed after a term has begun serves only for the rest of the term and until a successor is appointed.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">
        <section prefix="(i)">In a county or municipal corporation that has a publicly elected chief executive, the chief executive shall submit nominations for vacancies on the board.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The chief executive may nominate more than one individual for a vacancy.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A member may be removed at any time with or without cause.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Procedures for removal shall be those provided in the resolution establishing the authority or a subsequent resolution.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">From among its members, the board shall elect a chair and other officers.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">An ex officio member may hold any office other than chair.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Three voting members of the board are a quorum.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The board may act on a resolution only by the affirmative vote of at least three voting members.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">A member of the board:<section prefix="(1)">may not receive compensation as a member of the board; but</section><section prefix="(2)">shall be reimbursed for expenses incurred in performing the member's duties.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(g)">The board shall exercise its powers by resolution.</section>
  </text>
</law>
