<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gec" order_by="gec" level="1">Economic Development</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gec-10-644</section_number>
  <catch_line>Except as allowed by &#xA7; 10-639 of this subtitle, to finance acquisition and construction of any segm...</catch_line>
  <order_by>644</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Except as allowed by &#xA7; 10-639 of this subtitle, to finance acquisition and construction of any segment of a sports facility, the Authority shall comply with this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Authority shall provide certification to the Legislative Policy Committee and the Board of Public Works, supported by a detailed report, that the Authority has attempted:<section prefix="(1)">to maximize private investment in the sports facility proposed to be financed; and</section><section prefix="(2)">with respect to a baseball or football stadium, to maximize the State's ability to ensure that the professional baseball and football franchises will remain permanently in the State.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Authority shall provide to the fiscal committees of the General Assembly, at least 90 days before seeking approval of the Board of Public Works for each bond issue or other borrowing, a comprehensive financing plan for the relevant segment of the facility, including the effect of the financing plan on financing options for other segments of the facility and anticipated revenues from private investment.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Authority shall obtain the approval of the Board of Public Works of the proposed bond issue and the financing plan.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The Authority shall secure, as approved by the Board of Public Works:<section prefix="(1)">with respect to site acquisition and the construction of a baseball stadium, a long-term lease for a major league professional baseball team; or</section><section prefix="(2)">subject to &#xA7; 10-617 of this subtitle, with respect to site acquisition and the construction of a football stadium:<section prefix="(i)">a franchise for a National Football League team; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">a long-term lease that includes a provision requiring the football team that leases the stadium to agree to reimburse the Authority:<section prefix="1.">for $24,000,000 in stadium construction costs, including the construction, fitting out, and furnishing of the private suites that are part of the football stadium; and</section><section prefix="2.">on the terms and conditions determined by the Authority.</section></section></section></section>
  </text>
</law>
