<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gec" order_by="gec" level="1">Economic Development</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gec-10-801</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated....</catch_line>
  <order_by>801</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Administration" means the Maryland Energy Administration.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Board" means the Board of Directors of the Center.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Bond" means a bond issued by the Center under this subtitle.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Bond" includes a revenue bond, a revenue refunding bond, a note, and any other obligation, whether a general or limited obligation of the Center.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"Center" means the Maryland Clean Energy Center.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">"Clean energy" includes:<section prefix="(1)">solar photovoltaic technology;</section><section prefix="(2)">solar heating;</section><section prefix="(3)">geothermal;</section><section prefix="(4)">wind;</section><section prefix="(5)">biofuels;</section><section prefix="(6)">ethanol;</section><section prefix="(7)">other qualifying biomass as defined in &#xA7; 7-701 of the Public Utilities Article;</section><section prefix="(8)">ocean, including energy from waves, tides, currents, and thermal differences;</section><section prefix="(9)">a fuel cell that produces energy from biofuels, ethanol, or other qualifying biomass;</section><section prefix="(10)">energy efficiency and conservation;</section><section prefix="(11)">any other technology or service that the Center determines will contribute directly or indirectly to the production of energy from renewable or sustainable sources, or to the improvement of efficiency in the use of energy; and</section><section prefix="(12)">deployment of any of the technologies or services listed in items (1) through (11) of this subsection.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(g)">"Cost", with respect to a project financed under this subtitle, includes:<section prefix="(1)">the purchase price of a project;</section><section prefix="(2)">the cost to acquire any right, title, or interest in a project;</section><section prefix="(3)">the cost of any improvement;</section><section prefix="(4)">the cost of any property, right, easement, and franchise;</section><section prefix="(5)">the cost of demolition, removal, or relocation of structures;</section><section prefix="(6)">the cost of acquiring land to which the structures may be moved;</section><section prefix="(7)">the cost of equipment;</section><section prefix="(8)">financing charges;</section><section prefix="(9)">interest before and during construction and, if the Center determines, for a limited period after the completion of construction;</section><section prefix="(10)">reserves for principal and interest and for improvements;</section><section prefix="(11)">the cost of revenue and cost estimates, architectural, engineering, financial, and legal services, plans, specifications, studies, surveys, and other expenses necessary or incident to determining the feasibility of improving a project; and</section><section prefix="(12)">other expenses as necessary or incident to:<section prefix="(i)">financing a project;</section><section prefix="(ii)">acquiring and improving a project; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">placing a project in operation.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(h)">"Director" means the Director of the Administration.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">"Executive Director" means the Executive Director of the Maryland Clean Energy Center.</section>
    <section prefix="(j)">"Finance" includes refinance.</section>
    <section prefix="(k)">"Governmental unit" means:<section prefix="(1)">a county;</section><section prefix="(2)">a municipal corporation;</section><section prefix="(3)">a State unit;</section><section prefix="(4)">a local unit; or</section><section prefix="(5)">any other public body or unit established in accordance with a State or local law, ordinance, or resolution.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(l)">"Improve" means to add, alter, construct, equip, expand, extend, improve, install, reconstruct, rehabilitate, remodel, or repair.</section>
    <section prefix="(m)">"Improvement" means addition, alteration, construction, equipping, expansion, extension, improvement, installation, reconstruction, rehabilitation, remodeling, or repair.</section>
    <section prefix="(n)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Project" means any property, the acquisition or improvement of which the Board, in its sole discretion, determines by resolution will accomplish at least one of the purposes listed in &#xA7; 10-802(b) of this subtitle, whether or not the property:<section prefix="(i)">is or will be used or operated for profit or not for profit;</section><section prefix="(ii)">is or will be located on a single site or multiple sites; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">may be financed by bonds, the interest on which is exempt from income taxation under federal law.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Project" includes:<section prefix="(i)">land or an interest in land;</section><section prefix="(ii)">structures, equipment, furnishings, rail or motor vehicles, barges, and boats;</section><section prefix="(iii)">property and rights related to property, appurtenances, rights-of-way, franchises, and easements;</section><section prefix="(iv)">property that is functionally related and subordinate to a project; and</section><section prefix="(v)">patents, licenses, and other rights necessary or useful in the improvement or operation of a project.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(o)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Revenues" means the income, revenue, and other money the Center receives from or in connection with a project, and all other income of the Center.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Revenues" includes grants, rentals, rates, fees, and charges for the use of the services furnished or available.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(p)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Trust agreement" means an agreement entered into by the Center to secure a bond.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Trust agreement" may include a bond contract, bond resolution, or other contract with or for the benefit of a bondholder.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
