<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gec" order_by="" level="1">Economic Development</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gec-15-105</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>105</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The purpose of the Fund is to promote and assist community-based initiatives in qualified project areas consistent with the purpose of this title.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The State Treasurer shall hold the Fund separately, and the Comptroller shall account for the Fund.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Fund consists of:<section prefix="(i)">money appropriated in the State budget to the Fund;</section><section prefix="(ii)">proceeds of bonds that are made available for the use of the Fund, including general obligation bonds and grant anticipation revenue vehicles;</section><section prefix="(iii)">money made available for qualifying uses by the Fund from other governmental sources, including community development block grants and the Maryland Transportation Trust Fund;</section><section prefix="(iv)">contributions to the Fund made by the private developers of the relevant transit-oriented development;</section><section prefix="(v)">ground rents or land sale proceeds in accordance with &#xA7; 10-306(c)(1) of the State Finance and Procurement Article;</section><section prefix="(vi)">payments of principal of and interest on loans made under this title;</section><section prefix="(vii)">investment earnings of the Fund; and</section><section prefix="(viii)">any other money from any other source, public or private, accepted for the benefit of the Fund.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Contributions to the Fund under paragraph (1)(iv) of this subsection shall be separately accounted for in the Fund so that the revenue derived from a development in a particular qualified project area shall return to a qualified recipient in that qualified project area.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Subject to paragraph (2) of this subsection, the Comptroller shall:<section prefix="(i)">pay money in the Fund in annual installments to the Mayor and City Council of Baltimore City; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">ensure that the money in the Fund is distributed in the manner that best accomplishes the purpose of the Fund under this title.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
