<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="ged" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="8-310.3" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ged-8-310.3</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Four-year average annual full-time equivalent enrollment" means:<section prefix="(i)">The average number of students enrolled annually in grades prekindergarten through grade 12 at the Maryland School for the Deaf during 4 consecutive school years as determined by dividing the aggregate monthly enrollment during the 4-year period by the number of months school is in session during the 4-year period; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">One-half the average number of children served annually by the Maryland School for the Deaf's Early Intervention Program during 4 consecutive school years as determined by dividing the Program's aggregate monthly enrollment during the 4-year period by the number of months school is in session during the 4-year period.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Growth in the per pupil basic current expense figure" means the change in the per pupil basic current expense figure from the prior fiscal year to the current fiscal year divided by the per pupil basic current expense figure from the prior fiscal year.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">"Per pupil basic current expense figure" means the figure calculated for each fiscal year by the Department in accordance with &#xA7; 5-202 of this article.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">"Weighted enrollment growth" means the product of 0.2 times the change in the 4-year average annual full-time equivalent enrollment from the 3rd through the 6th prior school years to the 2nd through the 5th prior school years divided by the 4-year average annual full-time equivalent enrollment from the 3rd through the 6th prior school years.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, the Maryland School for the Deaf shall receive an appropriation equal to or greater than the sum of:<section prefix="(i)">75% of the prior year appropriation multiplied by the product of:</section><section prefix="(ii)">25% of the prior year appropriation multiplied by the sum of the weighted enrollment growth plus one.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The minimum appropriation required under paragraph (1) of this subsection may be reduced to the extent reductions are made to the administrative expenses of the Maryland School for the Deaf.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
