<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ged" order_by="" level="1">Economic Development</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ged-16-606</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>606</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In addition to the other powers granted and duties imposed by this title, and subject to the authority of the Commission, the Board of Trustees has the powers and duties set forth in this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Board of Trustees shall exercise general control over the College, keep separate records and minutes, and adopt reasonable rules, regulations, and bylaws to carry out the provisions of this title.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Board of Trustees may fix the salaries and tenure of the president, faculty, and other employees of the College.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Board of Trustees may purchase, lease, condemn, or otherwise acquire any property it considers necessary for the operation of the College.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Board of Trustees may sell, lease, or otherwise dispose of assets or property of the College.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The president of the College and the chairman of the Board of Trustees may execute a conveyance or other legal document under an appropriate resolution of the Board of Trustees.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The Board of Trustees may apply for and accept any gift or grant from the federal government or any other person.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">Subject to the minimum standards of the Commission, the Board of Trustees may determine entrance requirements and approve offerings that consist of:<section prefix="(1)">Transfer programs offering the equivalent of the first 2 years of a bachelor's degree program;</section><section prefix="(2)">Career programs offering technical, vocational, and semiprofessional education; and</section><section prefix="(3)">Continuing education and contract-training programs.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(h)">Except as provided in &#xA7; 16-310 of this title, the Board of Trustees may charge students reasonable tuition and fees set by it with a view to making college education available to all qualified students at low cost.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">The Board of Trustees may sue and be sued.</section>
    <section prefix="(j)">The Board of Trustees may make agreements with the federal government or any other person, including agreements between counties, if the Board of Trustees considers the agreement advisable for the establishment or operation of the College.</section>
    <section prefix="(k)">The Board of Trustees may adopt a corporate seal.</section>
    <section prefix="(l)">The Board of Trustees shall appoint a president of the College who shall be the chief executive officer of the College and the secretary/treasurer of the Board of Trustees.</section>
  </text>
</law>
