<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ged" order_by="ged" level="1">Economic Development</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ged-4-105</section_number>
  <catch_line>Each county board shall carry comprehensive liability insurance to protect the board and its agents ...</catch_line>
  <order_by>105</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Each county board shall carry comprehensive liability insurance to protect the board and its agents and employees. The purchase of this insurance is a valid educational expense.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The State Board shall establish standards for these insurance policies, including a minimum liability coverage of not less than $100,000 for each occurrence. The policies purchased under this section shall meet these standards.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A county board complies with this section if it:<section prefix="(i)">Is individually self-insured for at least $100,000 for each occurrence under the rules and regulations adopted by the State Insurance Commissioner; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">Pools with other public entities for the purpose of self-insuring property or casualty risks under Title 19, Subtitle 6 of the Insurance Article.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A county board that elects to self-insure individually under this subsection periodically shall file with the State Insurance Commissioner, in writing, the terms and conditions of the self-insurance.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The terms and conditions of this individual self-insurance:<section prefix="(i)">Are subject to the approval of the State Insurance Commissioner; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Shall conform with the terms and conditions of comprehensive liability insurance policies available in the private market.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A county board shall have the immunity from liability described under &#xA7; 5-518 of the Courts and Judicial Proceedings Article.</section>
  </text>
</law>
