<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ged" order_by="ged" level="1">Economic Development</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ged-23-501</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated....</catch_line>
  <order_by>501</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Adjusted assessed valuation of real property" means the most recent estimate by the State Department of Assessments and Taxation before the State budget is submitted to the General Assembly, of the sum of 100 percent of the assessed valuation of operating real property of public utilities and 50 percent of the assessed value of all other real property for State purposes as of July 1 of the first completed fiscal year before the fiscal year for which the calculation of State library aid is made under this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Capital expense" means principal and interest payments, or current capital spending or accumulation for:<section prefix="(1)">The purchase of land for libraries;</section><section prefix="(2)">The purchase and construction of library buildings;</section><section prefix="(3)">Remodeling and adding to library buildings; and</section><section prefix="(4)">The purchase of equipment and furniture for these library buildings.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">"Net taxable income" means the amount certified by the State Comptroller for the second full calendar year before the fiscal year for which the calculation of State library aid is made under this subtitle, based on tax returns filed on or before July 1 after that calendar year.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"Population" means population determined from figures available as of July 1 of the calendar year before the fiscal year for which the calculation is made, from:<section prefix="(1)">The latest decennial census; or</section><section prefix="(2)">Estimates prepared by the Department of Health and Mental Hygiene.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">"Real property" means all property classified as real property under &#xA7; 8-101(b) of the Tax - Property Article.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">"Wealth" means the sum of net taxable income and adjusted assessed valuation of real property.</section>
  </text>
</law>
