<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ged" order_by="" level="1">Economic Development</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ged-7-426</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>426</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Department and the Department of Health and Mental Hygiene shall jointly establish guidelines for public schools regarding providing emergency medical care to students with special health needs.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The guidelines shall include:<section prefix="(1)">Procedures for the emergency administration of medication and the proper follow-up emergency procedures;</section><section prefix="(2)">A description of parental or caregiver responsibilities, including:<section prefix="(i)">School notification of a child's special health care needs or diagnosis;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Providing appropriate medication and delivery devices and medical condition indication devices including Medic Alert bracelets or necklaces;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Parental consent for the administration of medications; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">Providing an emergency card for medical emergencies with current contact names and telephone numbers;</section></section><section prefix="(3)">A description of school responsibilities, including:<section prefix="(i)">Training for school health services personnel, teachers, coaches, transportation personnel, and other appropriate school personnel;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Providing and distributing the required notices and forms for notification, consent for the administration of medications, medical emergency contact information, and any other appropriate material; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Providing outreach and education for parents and other caregivers regarding providing emergency medical care to students with special health needs;</section></section><section prefix="(4)">A description of student responsibilities that are age and condition appropriate; and</section><section prefix="(5)">Any other issue that is relevant to the emergency medical care of students with special health needs.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Department and the Department of Health and Mental Hygiene shall:<section prefix="(1)">Provide technical assistance to schools to:<section prefix="(i)">Implement the guidelines established under this section; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Train school personnel at the local level; and</section></section><section prefix="(2)">Develop a process to monitor the implementation of the guidelines established under this section.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
