<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ged" order_by="ged" level="1">Economic Development</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ged-5-307</section_number>
  <catch_line>The Interagency Committee on Public School Construction shall assist the Prince George's County Boar...</catch_line>
  <order_by>307</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Interagency Committee on Public School Construction shall assist the Prince George's County Board of Education in developing an education facility master plan that encourages and supports the neighborhood school concept to improve the quality of education for all students in Prince George's County.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The education facility master plan under subsection (a) of this section shall be updated annually.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">To the extent the Prince George's County Board of Education and the county consider appropriate, the neighborhood school concept of the education facility master plan may include interagency utilization of neighborhood schools, including joint use of school facilities and property of:<section prefix="(1)">The Maryland-National Capital Park and Planning Commission;</section><section prefix="(2)">The Prince George's County library system;</section><section prefix="(3)">The Prince George's County Health Department;</section><section prefix="(4)">The Prince George's County Police Department;</section><section prefix="(5)">The Prince George's County Department of Social Services; and</section><section prefix="(6)">The Prince George's County Department of Family Services.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Prince George's County Board of Education may construct a school facility planned for joint use by the county board and a public agency listed in subsection (c) of this section on property owned by a public agency other than the county board.</section>
  </text>
</law>
