<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ged" order_by="" level="1">Economic Development</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ged-24-106</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>106</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">There is a Lida Lee Tall Learning Resources Center.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The purpose of the Lida Lee Tall Learning Resources Center is to provide an accessible laboratory environment for:<section prefix="(1)">Training students from public institutions of higher education to be teachers in elementary schools by providing students the opportunity for early field experience;</section><section prefix="(2)">Identifying and addressing appropriate early childhood and elementary education research needs and priorities in this State;</section><section prefix="(3)">Providing opportunities for demonstration and observation of effective teaching practices; and</section><section prefix="(4)">Providing in-service and staff development opportunities for faculty from teacher education programs, prospective principals and experienced teachers in Maryland elementary schools.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Governor shall appoint a board of trustees to govern the Lida Lee Tall Learning Resources Center who shall:<section prefix="(1)">Establish policy and exercise general control over the Lida Lee Tall Learning Resources Center;</section><section prefix="(2)">Appoint the principal and, upon the recommendation of the principal, appoint all professional and support staff and determine the salaries of the professional and support staff;</section><section prefix="(3)">Authorize the curricula to be used;</section><section prefix="(4)">Determine admission requirements for students;</section><section prefix="(5)">Set tuition; and</section><section prefix="(6)">Encourage collaboration between the Lida Lee Tall Learning Resources Center and the public institutions of higher education in Maryland.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Board of Trustees shall consist of 11 members. Of the members:<section prefix="(i)">3 shall be board members, officers, or employees of institutions of higher education in the State of Maryland;</section><section prefix="(ii)">3 shall be board members, officers, or employees of local education agencies in the State of Maryland;</section><section prefix="(iii)">1 shall be a Board member, officer, or employee of the Maryland State Department of Education;</section><section prefix="(iv)">1 shall be a Board member, officer, or employee of the Maryland Higher Education Commission;</section><section prefix="(v)">1 shall be the current President of the Lida Lee Tall Learning Resources Center Parent-Teacher Association; and</section><section prefix="(vi)">2 shall be public members.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Each member shall serve no more than 2 terms of 3 years each beginning July 1, 1984, except initially 5 members shall serve for a 2-year term.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Each year, the Board shall elect from among the members a chairman and any other officers required.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">Each member of the Board is entitled to reimbursement for expenses in accordance with the Standard State Travel Regulations.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The proposed annual program plan and budget of the Lida Lee Tall Learning Resources Center Board of Trustees shall be reviewed and approved by the Education Coordinating Committee prior to submission to the Governor. At the close of each fiscal year, the Board of Trustees shall submit to the Education Coordinating Committee an annual financial report in such form as determined by the Education Coordinating Committee.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">Funds for the operation of the Lida Lee Tall Learning Resources Center shall be as provided in the budget.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">The Lida Lee Tall Learning Resources Center may receive and spend any grant or gift budgeted or provided for it.</section>
  </text>
</law>
