<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ged" order_by="ged" level="1">Economic Development</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ged-2-303</section_number>
  <catch_line>In addition to the other powers granted and duties imposed under this article, the State Superintend...</catch_line>
  <order_by>303</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In addition to the other powers granted and duties imposed under this article, the State Superintendent has the powers and duties set forth in this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The State Superintendent shall enforce the provisions of:<section prefix="(i)">This article that are within his jurisdiction; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">The bylaws, rules, and regulations of the State Board.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If an educational institution or county board violates any of these provisions, the State Superintendent, by written notice, may require the State Comptroller to withhold from that institution or board:<section prefix="(i)">All or any part of an appropriation made by the General Assembly; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">All or any part of any other payment from funds budgeted by the State.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The State Superintendent shall:<section prefix="(1)">Carry out the educational policies of the State Board;</section><section prefix="(2)">Call and conduct conferences of county boards and professional personnel of the county school systems on the condition, needs, and improvement of the schools; and</section><section prefix="(3)">Prepare and publish pamphlets to:<section prefix="(i)">Stimulate public interest;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Promote the work of education; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Foster professional insight and efficiency in teachers.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The State Superintendent is a member of the Governor's Executive Council.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The State Superintendent shall:<section prefix="(1)">Receive and examine each report required under the bylaws, rules, and regulations of the State Board; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Examine the expenditures, business methods, and accounts of each county board and advise each county board about them.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Subject to the bylaws, rules, and regulations of the State Board, the State Superintendent shall approve or disapprove each:<section prefix="(i)">Proposal for the purchase or sale of any ground, school site, or building;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Plan or specification for the remodeling of a school building if the remodeling costs more than $350,000;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Plan or specification for the construction of a new school building; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">Change order that costs more than $25,000 for the remodeling, restoration, or construction of a school building.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If the State Superintendent disapproves any plan, specification, proposal, or change order, he shall state in writing the reasons for his disapproval.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">If the construction is to be done by a county board, the board may not begin until the plans and specifications are approved in writing by the State Superintendent.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">If the construction is to be done by contract, the contract is invalid without the written approval of the State Superintendent.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The State Superintendent shall certificate the professional personnel in each public school in accordance with this article and subject to the bylaws, rules, and regulations of the Professional Standards and Teacher Education Board.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Renewal requirements for any professionally certificated employee may be waived if:<section prefix="(i)">The renewal is recommended by the county superintendent having jurisdiction over the employee; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">The professionally certificated employee is:<section prefix="1.">55 years old or older; or</section><section prefix="2.">Employed in public or approved nonpublic school service for at least 25 years.</section></section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(h)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If the program is based on and complies with the standards established by the bylaws, rules, and regulations of the State Board, the State Superintendent shall approve any program of instruction offered by a State institution under the supervision of:<section prefix="(i)">The Department of Juvenile Services;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The Developmental Disabilities Administration or Mental Hygiene Administration of the Department of Health and Mental Hygiene;</section><section prefix="(iii)">The Department of Public Safety and Correctional Services; or</section><section prefix="(iv)">The residential school located within the Institute of Psychiatry and Human Behavior of the University Hospital.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If the State Superintendent grants approval, he shall issue a certificate of approval for the program to the institution that offers the program.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The certificate may be revoked for cause by the State Superintendent.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">Each institution that offers an approved program shall:<section prefix="(i)">Be open at all reasonable times for inspection of the program by the State Superintendent or his designated agent; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Furnish the information and reports that the State Superintendent considers necessary for evaluation of the program.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(5)">The State Superintendent shall issue a certificate of completion of credit to a resident of an institution who successfully completes an approved program of instruction.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(i)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The State Superintendent may furnish visual and auditory aids, educational television, and any other aids to facilitate instruction in all subjects in any school, institution, or organization under the supervision of the State Board.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Material collected for this purpose may be made available for a limited time to any responsible institution or organization for the benefit of citizens of this State.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The State Superintendent may make contracts to carry out the provisions of this subsection.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(j)">The State Superintendent shall establish an Early Childhood Development Division within the Department.</section>
    <section prefix="(k)">The State Superintendent shall perform any other duties assigned to him:<section prefix="(1)">Under this article; or</section><section prefix="(2)">By the State Board.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
