<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="ged" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="24-507" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ged-24-507</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Subject to the provisions of &#xA7; 24-514 of this subtitle, and in addition to any powers provided elsewhere in this subtitle, the Commission has the following powers:<section prefix="(1)">To acquire and hold real and personal property of historic, aesthetic, or cultural significance, by gift, purchase, devise or bequest including the power to acquire other property in the vicinity of significant property if the Commission considers it necessary for the proper use and administration of Historic St. Mary's City and its environs, to preserve and administer those properties, and to charge reasonable admission fees for entry to those properties;</section><section prefix="(2)">To preserve, study, curate, develop, and interpret historic, or cultural properties, buildings, fixtures, furnishings, facilities, collections, and appurtenances pertaining in any way to Historic St. Mary's City and its environs, including the replica of the State House and other reconstructions in St. Mary's City;</section><section prefix="(3)">To accept gifts, grants, legacies, bequests, and endowments for any purpose which falls within that of the Commission and, unless otherwise specified by the person making the gift, grant, legacy, bequest, or endowment, the Commission may expend both principal and income of the gift, grant, bequest, legacy, or endowment to further the purposes of the Commission;</section><section prefix="(4)">To accept governmental grants from federal, State and local governments and instrumentalities;</section><section prefix="(5)">To apply all moneys, assets, property, or other things of value it may receive as an incident to its operation to the general purposes of the Commission;</section><section prefix="(6)">To cooperate with and assist, insofar as practicable, or enter into a contractual relationship with any agency of the State or any agency of the political subdivisions of the State or any private agency or person, in furtherance of the purposes of the Commission;</section><section prefix="(7)">To fix, revise from time to time, and collect rates, rents, fees or other charges for the use of facilities or for services rendered in connection with the facilities at Historic St. Mary's City;</section><section prefix="(8)">To issue revenue bonds subject to the provisions of Part IV of this subtitle;</section><section prefix="(9)">To regulate the use and operation of the facilities at Historic St. Mary's City;</section><section prefix="(10)">To adopt bylaws that are necessary and proper and not inconsistent with this subtitle for the management, maintenance and operation of Historic St. Mary's City and to effectuate the purposes of the Commission; and</section><section prefix="(11)">To delegate any of the powers herein conferred of a nonpolicy nature to any one or more of the Commissioners or to the executive director of the Commission.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">In addition to any duties provided elsewhere in this subtitle, the Commission has the following duties:<section prefix="(1)">To maintain and carry out the mission of Historic St. Mary's City;</section><section prefix="(2)">To protect and preserve the historical and archaeological resources found within the boundaries of Historic St. Mary's City;</section><section prefix="(3)">To identify, study, curate, interpret, and develop the significant historic and archaeological resources of Historic St. Mary's City with emphasis on the 17th century colonial period;</section><section prefix="(4)">To enhance the role of Historic St. Mary's City as a statewide educational center for historical archaeology and Maryland colonial history and ultimately to raise national awareness of the place of St. Mary's City, its history, people, and ideas in our nation's development;</section><section prefix="(5)">To develop close working relationships with public and private elementary and secondary schools, local and statewide businesses and governmental agencies, and conduct activities to educate the general public about the history and significance of Historic St. Mary's City to the State of Maryland and the nation;</section><section prefix="(6)">To seek private and other public grants, gifts, bequests, endowments, and legacies for the development and use of Historic St. Mary's City;</section><section prefix="(7)">To review and comment on all plans for use and development of the archaeologically or historically significant land and real property of St. Mary's College of Maryland during the initial planning stage, to conduct such review at a special or regular meeting of the Commission after public notice of the general nature of the plans to be reviewed by the Commission, and thereafter to forward all such comments coincident with any submission made by the College pursuant to &#xA7; 3-602 of the State Finance and Procurement Article;</section><section prefix="(8)">To prepare an overall strategic plan at least once every 5 years that establishes both short-range and long-range goals, objectives, and priorities for Historic St. Mary's City in support of its mission; and</section><section prefix="(9)">To report annually to the Governor, and subject to &#xA7; 2-1246 of the State Government Article, to the General Assembly as to the Commission's activities during the preceding year, including specifically:<section prefix="(i)">The number of students served as well as the type and numbers of all other visitors;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The number of volunteers and total hours contributed to the operation of the museum;</section><section prefix="(iii)">The amount and types of private and nonstate funds donated, pledged, or otherwise provided; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">Any recommendations or requests the Commission considers appropriate to further the mission of Historic St. Mary's City.</section></section></section>
  </text>
</law>
