<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ged" order_by="ged" level="1">Economic Development</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ged-23-510</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this section the following words have the meanings indicated....</catch_line>
  <order_by>510</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Capital project" means the:<section prefix="(i)">Acquisition of land or buildings for a county library; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">Construction or improvement of a county library.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Construction or improvement" means planning, design, engineering, alteration, construction, reconstruction, enlargement, expansion, extension, improvement, replacement, rehabilitation, renovation, upgrading, repair, or capital equipping.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">"County library" means a library in a county public library system in the State.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">"Division" means the Division of Library Development and Services in the Department.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">There is a State grant program for county public library capital projects in the Division.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The grant program is in addition to the county-State minimum library program established under &#xA7; 23-502 of this subtitle.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">On or before July 15 of each year, a county public library system may submit applications to the Division to receive grants for county library capital projects for the next fiscal year.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">In order to apply for a capital project grant, a county public library system shall have:<section prefix="(i)">A countywide library plan that includes a mission statement, needs statement, and multiyear goals and objectives on file with the Division; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">A master plan that includes a description of the capital project approved by the applicant's governing body.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">An application shall include:<section prefix="(i)">A description of the scope and purpose of the project;</section><section prefix="(ii)">A building plan that includes the estimated total cost of the project; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Any other information required by the Division.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">A county public library system may not apply for more than three capital project grants in a fiscal year.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Division shall develop and administer a grant program to assist in the funding of county library capital projects.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The purpose of the grant program is to:<section prefix="(i)">Provide a uniform and objective analysis of proposed capital projects; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Support projects that address the library needs in the State.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Grants under the program:<section prefix="(i)">Require a matching fund from any combination of county, municipal, or private sources;</section><section prefix="(ii)">May not exceed 50% of the total cost of a capital project; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">May not be for an amount less than $20,000.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Division shall review grant applications submitted in accordance with subsection (c) of this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">On or before October 1 of each year, the Division shall make recommendations to the State Board regarding capital project grants for the next fiscal year.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">In making its recommendations, the Division shall consider:<section prefix="(i)">The public necessity and urgency of a project;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The need for additional sources of funding for a project;</section><section prefix="(iii)">The estimated cost and timeliness of executing a project;</section><section prefix="(iv)">The viability of matching funds for a project; and</section><section prefix="(v)">Geographic diversity.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">On or before November 1 of each year, the State Board shall:<section prefix="(i)">Approve capital projects for funding in the State budget for the next fiscal year; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Forward the list of approved capital projects to the Department of Budget and Management.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(5)">For fiscal year 2008 and each fiscal year thereafter, the Governor shall include in the annual operating or capital budget submission $5,000,000 for county library capital projects.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The State Board shall report to the Governor and, in accordance with &#xA7; 2-1246 of the State Government Article, the General Assembly, on or before October 1 of each year, on State grants awarded for county public library capital projects for the prior fiscal year.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">The State Board shall adopt regulations to implement the grant program established under this section.</section>
  </text>
</law>
