<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ged" order_by="ged" level="1">Economic Development</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ged-3-1005</section_number>
  <catch_line>There is a Shared Space Council for Prince George's County. The purpose of the Council is to conside...</catch_line>
  <order_by>1005</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">There is a Shared Space Council for Prince George's County. The purpose of the Council is to consider the alternative use of any vacant public schools and any vacant space that exists in the Prince George's County public school system.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Council shall consist of 23 members, appointed as follows:<section prefix="(1)">One member from each legislative district within Prince George's County, each of whom shall be appointed by the legislative delegation from the district.</section><section prefix="(2)">One member from each of the following governmental agencies, departments, or institutions:<section prefix="(i)">The staff of the county board of education;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The staff of the County Executive;</section><section prefix="(iii)">The staff of the County Council;</section><section prefix="(iv)">The county Department of Social Services;</section><section prefix="(v)">The staff of the county Superintendent of Education;</section><section prefix="(vi)">The Prince George's County Planning Board;</section><section prefix="(vii)">The county Department of Aging;</section><section prefix="(viii)">The county health department;</section><section prefix="(ix)">The county Office of Coordination of Services to the Handicapped;</section><section prefix="(x)">The county Juvenile Services Administration;</section><section prefix="(xi)">The county Memorial Library System; and</section><section prefix="(xii)">The county Department of Program Planning and Economic Development.</section></section><section prefix="(3)">On a rotating basis, one member shall be from the faculty or administration of Bowie State College or Prince George's Community College. Such member shall be appointed by the president of the college.</section><section prefix="(4)">The members from governmental agencies, departments, or institutions shall be appointed by the director, chairman, or chief executive officer of the agency, department, or institution.</section><section prefix="(5)">Two members shall be appointed by the County Executive.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The term of the members appointed pursuant to subsection (b)(2), (3), and (4) shall be 3 years. All other members shall serve for a term of 2 years. Any vacancy on the Council shall be filled in the same manner as the original appointment.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Council shall meet at least four times each year. It shall, on an annual basis and in conjunction with the county board of education, survey the schools within the county public school system and compile a listing of any vacant public schools and any vacant space that exists within the system. The Council shall evaluate the feasibility of using any vacant public school or vacant space for community or governmental purposes.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The Council shall report the results, findings, and recommendations derived from such survey, listing, and evaluation to the county board of education, the County Executive, the County Council and the mayor of each municipality in the county.</section>
  </text>
</law>
