<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="ged" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="3-6A-01" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ged-3-6A-01</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this subtitle, "elected member" means a voting member elected under subsection (d) or (e) of this section or a member appointed to an elected position on the Harford County Board of Education under subsection (e)(2) of this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Elected member" does not include a:<section prefix="(i)">County superintendent of schools serving as an ex officio member of the county board; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">Student member selected under subsection (f) of this section.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The county board consists of:<section prefix="(1)">Six elected members;</section><section prefix="(2)">Three appointed members;</section><section prefix="(3)">The county superintendent of schools, who is an ex officio nonvoting member; and</section><section prefix="(4)">One student member.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">A member from a councilmanic district shall be a resident of that district.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">A member from a councilmanic district who no longer resides in that district may not continue as a member of the county board.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A member of the county board shall be a registered voter of the county for at least 3 years prior to the date of the beginning of the term of office of the member.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Of the nine voting members of the county board elected or appointed under this subsection:<section prefix="(i)">One member shall be elected from each of the six councilmanic districts only by the voters of that councilmanic district; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Three members shall be appointed by the Governor.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The elected members shall be elected at a general election as required by subsection (e) of this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The appointed members shall be appointed, when appropriate, within 90 days of the general election.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except for the ex officio member and the student member, a member serves for a term of 4 years beginning July 1 after the election or appointment of the member and until a successor is elected or appointed and qualifies.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Unless otherwise disqualified under this section, a member of the county board is eligible for reelection or reappointment.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">A voting elected member or an appointed member may not serve for more than two consecutive terms as a voting member.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Harford County Board of Elections may adopt regulations to implement this subsection.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Harford County Council shall appoint a qualified individual to fill any vacancy of an elected member on the county board for the remainder of the term and until a successor is elected and qualifies.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Governor shall appoint a qualified individual to fill any vacancy of an appointed member of the county board for the remainder of the term and until a successor is appointed and qualifies.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The student member of the county board shall be elected by the high school students of the county in accordance with procedures established by the Harford County public school system.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The student member shall:<section prefix="(i)">Be an eleventh or twelfth grade student, in good standing, and regularly enrolled in the Harford County public school system;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Be a student government association representative at the student's high school;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Serve for 1 year beginning on July 1 after the election of the member;</section><section prefix="(iv)">Except as otherwise provided in paragraph (3) of this subsection, be a voting member; and</section><section prefix="(v)">Advise the county board on the thoughts and feelings of students in the Harford County public schools.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Except as otherwise provided in subparagraph (iii) of this paragraph, the student member of the county board has the same rights and privileges as a member appointed or elected under subsection (d) of this section.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">Unless invited to attend by an affirmative vote of a majority of the county board, the student member may not attend an executive session of the county board addressing a matter on which a student member is prohibited from voting on under subparagraph (iii) of this paragraph.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">The student member shall vote on and participate in all matters except those relating to:</section>
      </section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
