<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ged" order_by="ged" level="1">Economic Development</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ged-13-405</section_number>
  <catch_line>This section shall be effective only if the transfer or lease authorized by this subtitle occurs....</catch_line>
  <order_by>405</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This section shall be effective only if the transfer or lease authorized by this subtitle occurs.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">This section shall be void if the Medical System Corporation no longer operates Montebello.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Medical System Corporation shall cause annual audited financial statements for Montebello to be prepared and filed with the Governor and the Joint Audit Committee as soon as practicable following the close of each fiscal year.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Medical System Corporation shall submit with the annual audited financial statements for Montebello a report on the amount of uncompensated care provided at Montebello for the fiscal year.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">In recognition of the provision of uncompensated care by Montebello and to assist with the capital financial needs of Montebello specified as part of the transfer under &#xA7; 13-402 of this subtitle, the State shall pay the Medical System Corporation:<section prefix="(1)">In fiscal year 1993, $6,129,942;</section><section prefix="(2)">In fiscal year 1994, $5,500,000;</section><section prefix="(3)">In fiscal year 1995, $5,000,000;</section><section prefix="(4)">In fiscal year 1996, $5,000,000;</section><section prefix="(5)">In fiscal year 1997, $5,000,000; and</section><section prefix="(6)">In each fiscal year thereafter, an amount jointly agreed upon by the Department of Health and Mental Hygiene and the Medical System Corporation and calculated to enable the Medical System Corporation to continue to provide uncompensated care by Montebello and to assist with the capital financial needs of Montebello specified as part of the transfer under &#xA7; 13-402 of this subtitle.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">If the Health Services Cost Review Commission sets rates for services rendered at Montebello, then the Governor shall include in the budget bill each year an appropriation to the Medical System Corporation equal to the difference between the pension costs for Montebello University employees and employees of the Medical System Corporation working at Montebello and participating in the State Retirement and Pension Systems and the pension costs permitted by the Health Services Cost Review Commission in the rates for Montebello.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The Health Services Cost Review Commission may not set rates for the services rendered at Montebello until:<section prefix="(1)">State law authorizes the State Medical Assistance Program to reimburse the Medical System Corporation at commission rates for services rendered at Montebello; and</section><section prefix="(2)">The United States Department of Health and Human Services agrees to accept commission rates as a method of providing federal financial participation in the State Medical Assistance Program.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
