<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="ged" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="26-101" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ged-26-101</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">A person may not willfully disturb or otherwise willfully prevent the orderly conduct of the activities, administration, or classes of any institution of elementary, secondary, or higher education.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A person may not molest or threaten with bodily harm any student, employee, administrator, agent, or any other individual who is lawfully:<section prefix="(1)">On the grounds or in the immediate vicinity of any institution of elementary, secondary, or higher education;</section><section prefix="(2)">On a school vehicle;</section><section prefix="(3)">At an activity sponsored by a school that is held off school property; or</section><section prefix="(4)">On property that is owned by a county board and is used for administrative or other purposes.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A person may not threaten with bodily harm any employee of any institution of elementary, secondary, or higher education at home by any means, including in person, by telephone, or by electronic mail. This prohibition applies only to threats arising out of the scope of the employee's employment.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">In addition to the penalties provided in this section or in &#xA7; 6-409 of the Criminal Law Article, on application by the governing board of any institution of elementary, secondary, or higher education, the circuit court of the county in which the institution is located may issue an injunction restraining any specific activities that violate this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">Any person who violates any provision of this section is guilty of a misdemeanor and on conviction is subject to a fine not exceeding $2,500, imprisonment not exceeding 6 months, or both.</section>
  </text>
</law>
