<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ged" order_by="" level="1">Economic Development</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ged-7-409</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>409</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Each public school shall have a program of physical education that is given in a planned and sequential manner to all students, kindergarten through grade 12, to develop their good health and physical fitness and improve their motor coordination and physical skills.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Department shall:<section prefix="(i)">Employ a full-time director of physical education;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Subject to paragraph (2) of this subsection, adopt regulations that require a public school building that is newly constructed or completely renovated and occupied on or after January 1, 2013, to include a gymnasium and adequate support space for physical education instruction; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Adopt guidelines for facilities for physical education programs.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The regulations adopted under paragraph (1)(ii) of this subsection shall include a process by which a local school system that is conducting a complete renovation of a public school building may request a waiver, based on land or zoning constraints, from the requirement to include a gymnasium.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Each local school system may develop and implement an annual Wellness Policy Implementation and Monitoring Plan to be used to:<section prefix="(1)">Establish baseline student data for the health-related components of physical fitness;</section><section prefix="(2)">Assist students with the development of personal physical fitness plans;</section><section prefix="(3)">Encourage appropriate interventions for students identified as having unhealthy levels of physical fitness;</section><section prefix="(4)">Identify effective practices for improvement of student health-related physical fitness; and</section><section prefix="(5)">Encourage partnerships with health agencies to address student health-related issues in the State.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Department shall:<section prefix="(1)">Develop a procedure to monitor and measure the implementation of a local school system's Wellness Policy Implementation and Monitoring Plan;</section><section prefix="(2)">Provide feedback and technical assistance to each local school system that implements a Wellness Policy Implementation and Monitoring Plan;</section><section prefix="(3)">Identify and distribute to each local school system effective wellness policy practices for physical activity and physical education; and</section><section prefix="(4)">Provide staff support to each local school system that implements a Wellness Policy Implementation and Monitoring Plan.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">Each local school system that implements a Wellness Policy Implementation and Monitoring Plan under subsection (c) of this section shall submit to the Department:<section prefix="(1)">The local school system's Wellness Policy Implementation and Monitoring Plan, that shall include:<section prefix="(i)">Policy goals;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Activities;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Expected outcomes; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">Measurements for physical activity and physical education; and</section></section><section prefix="(2)">An annual report on the local school system's progress toward achieving the policy goals of the implementation plan.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Department shall establish an Advisory Council on Health and Physical Education.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Advisory Council shall consist of the following members, selected by each organization from which the member is a representative:<section prefix="(i)">A representative from the Department;</section><section prefix="(ii)">A representative from the Maryland Parent-Teacher Association;</section><section prefix="(iii)">A representative from the Maryland State Teachers Association;</section><section prefix="(iv)">A representative from the Public School Superintendents Association of Maryland;</section><section prefix="(v)">Representatives from each local school system;</section><section prefix="(vi)">A representative from the Maryland Association of Boards of Education;</section><section prefix="(vii)">A representative from the Maryland Association of Counties;</section><section prefix="(viii)">A representative from the Governor's Council on Physical Fitness and Sport;</section><section prefix="(ix)">A representative of the Professional Organization for Health, Physical Education, Recreation, and Dance;</section><section prefix="(x)">A representative from an institution of higher education having a health and physical education teacher education program;</section><section prefix="(xi)">A representative from Special Olympics of Maryland;</section><section prefix="(xii)">A representative from the Department of Health and Mental Hygiene;</section><section prefix="(xiii)">A representative from the American Academy of Pediatrics; and</section><section prefix="(xiv)">Representatives from the following health organizations:<section prefix="1.">The American Heart Association;</section><section prefix="2.">The American Cancer Society; and</section><section prefix="3.">The American Diabetes Association.</section></section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">From among its members, the Council shall elect a chair, vice chair, and any other officers necessary to carry out the Advisory Council's functions.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The Department shall provide staff and other necessary support to the Advisory Council using existing resources.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">A member of the Advisory Council may not receive compensation for serving on the Advisory Council, but is entitled to reimbursement for expenses under the Standard State Travel Regulations, as provided in the State budget.</section>
      <section prefix="(6)">The Advisory Council shall meet at least twice each year and may hold additional meetings at the discretion of the chair or at the request of a majority of the members.</section>
      <section prefix="(7)">The Advisory Council shall:<section prefix="(i)">Develop and coordinate programs in collaboration with public schools to educate students regarding the importance of:<section prefix="1.">Physical activity and physical movement;</section><section prefix="2.">The relationship of physical activity to a healthy lifestyle and improved fitness;</section><section prefix="3.">The relationship between healthy eating, physical activity, and maintaining a healthy weight; and</section><section prefix="4.">The value of physical activity and its relationship to improved academic achievement and stress reduction;</section></section><section prefix="(ii)">Identify promising health and physical education practices in the State;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Build a network of health and physical education professionals to share information and strengthen partnerships;</section><section prefix="(iv)">Support successful health and physical education programs in the State and encourage the expansion of those programs; and</section><section prefix="(v)">Consult with organizations represented on the Advisory Council as appropriate.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(8)">The Advisory Council may:<section prefix="(i)">Seek, accept, and expend funds from any source, including donations, State appropriations, and federal grants; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Seek, accept, and use services from individuals, corporations, and government entities.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
