<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="ged" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="7-416" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ged-7-416</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In Baltimore City, the nurse practitioner, physician assistant, or other appropriate health care provider shall be assigned to Walbrook Senior High School, P.S. 411.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The range of services provided by the nurse practitioner, physician assistant, or other appropriate health care provider with appropriate physician collaboration should, to the extent feasible, include:<section prefix="(i)">Total health assessment including history, physical examination, and neurological evaluation for all entering students and handicapped students, provided however, that existing health records of the student shall be used if available;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Referral to and follow-up with identified primary care sources for each student in the targeted population;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Follow-up on treated sports injuries;</section><section prefix="(iv)">Management of selected minor illnesses and injuries in the school according to treatment protocols which will be developed; and</section><section prefix="(v)">Establishment of working relationships with all teachers, especially health education teachers.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The nurse practitioner, physician assistant, or other appropriate health care provider shall, to the extent practicable:<section prefix="(1)">Participate actively in the School Screening Committee;</section><section prefix="(2)">Be responsible for the basic medical evaluation and certification for student placement;</section><section prefix="(3)">Concentrate on early identification, health counseling, and referral for:<section prefix="(i)">Venereal disease;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Drug abuse;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Alcoholism;</section><section prefix="(iv)">Handicapping conditions; and</section><section prefix="(v)">Mental health problems;</section></section><section prefix="(4)">Evaluate the relationship between use of the school health clinic services and use of hospital emergency room services;</section><section prefix="(5)">Establish working relationships with parents, students, and community organizations to demonstrate the efficacy of involving parents, students, and community organizations in school health clinics to enhance recruitment and retention of students;</section><section prefix="(6)">Evaluate, to the extent possible, the effect of participation in the program on the physical and mental well-being and school performance of the students;</section><section prefix="(7)">Assess, to the extent possible, whether school health programs could be used as a basis for advising other family members of the student of other sources of primary care;</section><section prefix="(8)">Be responsible to the Bureau of School Health of the Baltimore City Health Department; and work closely with the school principal and staff;</section><section prefix="(9)">Continue to function within the Baltimore City Health Department when the schools are not in session, by managing his or her caseload of school-age children in the community, including follow-through on referrals made during the school year, and the assessment of selected children in summer programs for certification of school placement; and</section><section prefix="(10)">Be a part of the well-child clinic delivery system provided by the Baltimore City Health Department.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Physician consultation and collaboration in medical management of care shall be available at all times on site or by telephone.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Other consultant services in the school health program, in the maternal child health program, or in the community health nursing program will be available as needed by the nurse practitioner, physician assistant, or other appropriate health care provider.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
