<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="ged" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="24-801" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ged-24-801</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, "Council" means the Governor's P-20 Leadership Council of Maryland.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">There is a Governor's P-20 Leadership Council of Maryland.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Council is a partnership between the State, educators, and the business community to better prepare Maryland students for the jobs of the 21st century while enhancing the State's economic competitiveness by creating a workforce with 21st century skills.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Council shall consist of the following members:<section prefix="(1)">The Governor or the Governor's designee;</section><section prefix="(2)">The Secretary of Higher Education;</section><section prefix="(3)">The Secretary of Labor, Licensing, and Regulation;</section><section prefix="(4)">The Secretary of Business and Economic Development;</section><section prefix="(5)">The Chancellor of the University System of Maryland;</section><section prefix="(6)">The State Superintendent of Schools;</section><section prefix="(7)">The Chairman of the Maryland Higher Education Commission;</section><section prefix="(8)">The Chair and the Executive Director of the Governor's Workforce Investment Board;</section><section prefix="(9)">Two members of the House of Delegates, appointed by the Speaker of the House;</section><section prefix="(10)">Two members of the Senate of Maryland, appointed by the President of the Senate; and</section><section prefix="(11)">The following members appointed by the Governor:<section prefix="(i)">A member of the State Board of Education;</section><section prefix="(ii)">A representative of local superintendents of education;</section><section prefix="(iii)">A representative of local boards of education;</section><section prefix="(iv)">Two members of employee organizations that represent elementary and secondary school personnel in the State;</section><section prefix="(v)">A representative of elementary and secondary school principals;</section><section prefix="(vi)">Two representatives of nonpublic elementary and secondary schools;</section><section prefix="(vii)">An expert in early childhood education;</section><section prefix="(viii)">An expert in career and technology education;</section><section prefix="(ix)">Two representatives of community colleges;</section><section prefix="(x)">Two representatives of independent colleges or universities;</section><section prefix="(xi)">A representative of public institutions of higher education outside the University System of Maryland;</section><section prefix="(xii)">A representative of college or university deans who has responsibility for a science, technology, engineering, and math (STEM) discipline;</section><section prefix="(xiii)">Four representatives of the University System of Maryland;</section><section prefix="(xiv)">A representative of a for-profit institution of higher education;</section><section prefix="(xv)">Three representatives of the business community; and</section><section prefix="(xvi)">Six additional members with experience and knowledge that will benefit the work of the Council.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Governor or the Governor's designee shall chair the Council.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">Members of the Council appointed by the Governor shall serve at the pleasure of the Governor.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">A member of the Council may not receive compensation as a member of the Council, but is entitled to reimbursement for expenses under the Standard State Travel Regulations, as provided in the State budget.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">There is an Executive Committee of the Council that shall direct the Council in its work.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Executive Committee shall include the following members:<section prefix="(i)">The Governor or the Governor's designee;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The Secretary of Higher Education;</section><section prefix="(iii)">The Secretary of Labor, Licensing, and Regulation;</section><section prefix="(iv)">The Secretary of Business and Economic Development;</section><section prefix="(v)">The Chancellor of the University System of Maryland; and</section><section prefix="(vi)">The State Superintendent of Schools.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(h)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Council may establish other committees or task forces as are necessary to accomplish its work.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A committee or task force may include as a member an individual who is not a Council member.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(i)">The Council shall investigate ways to improve education, advance workforce creation, and make the State more competitive through some or all of the following strategies:<section prefix="(1)">Ensuring that all students have the basic, critical thinking, and technical skills necessary to succeed in the modern workplace;</section><section prefix="(2)">Reducing dropout rates and increasing retention and graduation rates in high school and college;</section><section prefix="(3)">Improving student achievement and closing student achievement gaps;</section><section prefix="(4)">Improving teaching quality;</section><section prefix="(5)">Improving teacher retention;</section><section prefix="(6)">Strengthening and expanding educational leadership programs;</section><section prefix="(7)">Redesigning career and technology education programs to meet college expectations and employer needs;</section><section prefix="(8)">Expanding the availability of career and technology programs and high school centers;</section><section prefix="(9)">Strengthening STEM programs at the high school and college levels;</section><section prefix="(10)">Connecting high school expectations and college expectations with employer needs;</section><section prefix="(11)">Creating pathways for all students to obtain college degrees;</section><section prefix="(12)">Providing teachers the resources and professional training they need to help students reach higher standards;</section><section prefix="(13)">Expanding opportunities for continuous learning;</section><section prefix="(14)">Aligning high school graduation requirements with college readiness requirements;</section><section prefix="(15)">Improving the connections between the pre-kindergarten, primary, secondary, and higher education systems;</section><section prefix="(16)">Creating programs and incentives to encourage mutually beneficial relationships between schools, school systems, higher education, and the business community; and</section><section prefix="(17)">Any other strategies requested by the Governor or General Assembly.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(j)">Members of the Executive Committee shall provide the primary staff support necessary for the Council.</section>
    <section prefix="(k)">The Council shall meet at least quarterly at such times and places as it determines.</section>
    <section prefix="(l)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Council shall report to the Governor and, in accordance with &#xA7; 2-1246 of the State Government Article, the General Assembly on or before December 15 of each year.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The report shall set forth any recommendations from the Council and summarize the Council's activities during the preceding year.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
