<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="ged" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="7-424.1" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ged-7-424.1</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Bullying, harassment, or intimidation" means intentional conduct, including verbal, physical, or written conduct, or an intentional electronic communication, that:<section prefix="(i)">Creates a hostile educational environment by substantially interfering with a student's educational benefits, opportunities, or performance, or with a student's physical or psychological well-being and is:</section><section prefix="(ii)"/></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Electronic communication" means a communication transmitted by means of an electronic device, including a telephone, cellular phone, computer, or pager.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">By March 31, 2009, the State Board, after consultation with and input from local school systems, shall develop a model policy prohibiting bullying, harassment, or intimidation in schools.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The model policy developed under paragraph (1) of this subsection shall include:<section prefix="(i)">A statement prohibiting bullying, harassment, and intimidation in schools;</section><section prefix="(ii)">A statement prohibiting reprisal or retaliation against individuals who report acts of bullying, harassment, or intimidation;</section><section prefix="(iii)">A definition of bullying, harassment, or intimidation that is either the same as set forth in subsection (a)(2) of this section or a definition that is not less inclusive than that definition;</section><section prefix="(iv)">Standard consequences and remedial actions for persons committing acts of bullying, harassment, or intimidation and for persons engaged in reprisal or retaliation;</section><section prefix="(v)">Standard consequences and remedial actions for persons found to have made false accusations;</section><section prefix="(vi)">Model procedures for reporting acts of bullying, harassment, and intimidation;</section><section prefix="(vii)">Model procedures for the prompt investigation of acts of bullying, harassment, and intimidation;</section><section prefix="(viii)">Information about the types of support services available to the student bully, victim, and any bystanders; and</section><section prefix="(ix)">Information regarding the availability and use of the bullying, harassment, or intimidation form under &#xA7; 7-424 of this subtitle.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Each county board shall establish a policy prohibiting bullying, harassment, or intimidation at school based on the model policy.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The policy shall address the components of the model policy specified in subsection (b)(2) of this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A county board shall develop the policy in consultation with representatives of the following groups:<section prefix="(i)">Parents or guardians of students;</section><section prefix="(ii)">School employees and administrators;</section><section prefix="(iii)">School volunteers;</section><section prefix="(iv)">Students; and</section><section prefix="(v)">Members of the community.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Each county board shall publicize its policy in student handbooks, school system websites, and any other location or venue the county board determines is necessary or appropriate.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">Each county board policy shall include information on the procedure for reporting incidents of bullying, harassment, or intimidation, including:<section prefix="(1)">A chain of command in the reporting process; and</section><section prefix="(2)">The name and contact information for an employee of the Department, designated by the Department, who is familiar with the reporting and investigation procedures in the applicable school system.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">Each county board shall submit its policy to the State Superintendent by July 1, 2009.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">Each county board shall develop the following educational programs in its efforts to prevent bullying, harassment, and intimidation in schools:<section prefix="(1)">An educational bullying, harassment, and intimidation prevention program for students, staff, volunteers, and parents; and</section><section prefix="(2)">A teacher and administrator development program that trains teachers and administrators to implement the policy.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(h)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A school employee who reports an act of bullying, harassment, or intimidation under this section in accordance with the county board's policy established under subsection (c) of this section is not civilly liable for any act or omission in reporting or failing to report an act of bullying, harassment, or intimidation under this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The provisions of this section may not be construed to limit the legal rights of a victim of bullying, harassment, or intimidation.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
