<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ged" order_by="ged" level="1">Economic Development</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ged-4-304</section_number>
  <catch_line>There is a Chief Executive Officer of the board....</catch_line>
  <order_by>304</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">There is a Chief Executive Officer of the board.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Chief Executive Officer shall:<section prefix="(1)">Be responsible for the overall administration of the Baltimore City Public School System;</section><section prefix="(2)">Report directly to the board;</section><section prefix="(3)">Be a member of the cabinet of the Mayor; and</section><section prefix="(4)">Designate individuals with primary responsibility for each of the following functions:<section prefix="(i)">Management and administration of the Baltimore City Public School System;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Assessment and accountability of the academic performance of the students in the Baltimore City Public School System;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Provision of services to students with disabilities in accordance with federal and State law;</section><section prefix="(iv)">Development and implementation of initiatives for educational reform; and</section><section prefix="(v)">Professional hiring and development.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Notwithstanding the provisions of subsection (b)(4) of this section, the Chief Executive Officer and the board shall be held accountable for the delegated functions.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The board shall employ the Chief Executive Officer and establish the salary of the Chief Executive Officer at an amount commensurate with the credentials, experience, and prior positions of responsibility of the Chief Executive Officer.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The employment contract of the Chief Executive Officer shall provide, at a minimum, that continued employment is contingent on demonstrable improvement in the academic performance of the students in the Baltimore City Public School System and the successful management of the Baltimore City public schools.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The initial contract and any renewal may not exceed 4 years.</section>
  </text>
</law>
