<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="ged" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="17-302" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ged-17-302</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Except as provided in subsections (b) and (f) of this section, each eligible institution shall receive from the State, in the manner and subject to the limitations of this subtitle, with respect to the amounts pledged by eligible private donors as voluntary donations at any time during the previous fiscal year to the eligible institution for eligible programs as follows:<section prefix="(1)">An amount equal to the first $250,000 or any portion thereof of pledged amounts;</section><section prefix="(2)">An amount equal to one-half of the next $1,000,000 or any portion thereof of pledged amounts; and</section><section prefix="(3)">An amount equal to one-third of the amount in excess of $1,250,000 or any portion thereof of pledged amounts.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Bowie State University, Coppin State University, Morgan State University, and University of Maryland Eastern Shore shall receive from the State, in the manner and subject to the limitations of this subtitle, with respect to the amounts pledged by eligible private donors as voluntary donations at any time during the previous fiscal year to the eligible institution for eligible programs as follows:<section prefix="(1)">For amounts pledged on or after July 1, 2001, an amount equal to $2 for every $1 of the first $250,000 or any portion thereof of pledged amounts; and</section><section prefix="(2)">For amounts pledged on or after July 1, 2001, an amount equal to the next $1,000,000 or any portion thereof of pledged amounts.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Payments shall be made by the State:<section prefix="(1)">Only with respect to pledged amounts that are paid by the eligible private donor to:<section prefix="(i)">Bowie State University, Coppin State University, Morgan State University, and University of Maryland Eastern Shore before January 1, 2010; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">All other eligible institutions before July 1, 2004; and</section></section><section prefix="(2)"><section prefix="(i)">To Bowie State University, Coppin State University, Morgan State University, and the University of Maryland Eastern Shore, in the fiscal year following the fiscal year during which the amounts are paid by eligible private donors; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">To all other eligible institutions, in equal installments in fiscal years 2006, 2007, 2008, and 2009.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Payments by the State under this subtitle may not exceed:<section prefix="(1)">$250,000 to each community college campus;</section><section prefix="(2)">$1,250,000 each to the University of Maryland, College Park, the University of Maryland, Baltimore, and the University of Maryland Baltimore County;</section><section prefix="(3)">$1,500,000 each to Bowie State University, Coppin State University, Morgan State University, and University of Maryland Eastern Shore; and</section><section prefix="(4)">$750,000 to each other eligible institution.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">To determine eligibility for State payments, each donation shall be compared to the amount donated during the base year. The following criteria shall be the basis for comparison:<section prefix="(i)">Each donation must be from a new donor; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">Each donation must represent an increase over the amount given by the donor during the base year.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A donation received during the base year that fulfills a pledge made prior to the base year may not be included in the determination of the amount donated during the base year.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Each donation must be specifically designated as an endowment.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">An institution may not receive funds for a donation that qualifies for a contribution by the State under &#xA7; 16-317 of this article.</section>
  </text>
</law>
