<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="ged" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="13-102" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ged-13-102</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">There is a Maryland Statewide Medical Education and Training System in the University of Maryland.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The System includes the centers for training in comprehensive medical care specifically provided for in the State budget by funds designated and identified for the development of these centers.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Each center shall be established cooperatively with an existing medical or educational institution in this State.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Dean of the University of Maryland School of Medicine and each cooperating institution jointly shall appoint a director and faculty for each center.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Each center shall appoint an advisory council to provide the highest possible degree of support and advice from the lay and professional communities.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In cooperation with the director of the center and the staff of the cooperating institution, the University of Maryland School of Medicine shall plan, implement, and expand a medical education and training program at each center.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Dean of the University of Maryland School of Medicine is responsible for the fiscal administration of the program and shall review and approve the budget proposed by each center.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The University of Maryland is responsible for:<section prefix="(i)">Selecting and assigning students to the centers; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Curriculum development and accreditation of the centers.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The University may assign to those centers that it believes have developed appropriate faculty, facilities, and primary care curricula:<section prefix="(i)">Third and fourth year medical students;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Residency trainees; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Students who are in primary care programs of other health professions.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The University of Maryland School of Medicine shall provide for periodic, systematic evaluation of the Maryland Statewide Medical Education and Training System.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This section does not restrict any health care institution from starting or operating any training program jointly with any other person, whether or not the institution participates in this program.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Any institution that participates with the University of Maryland under this section is free to engage in any other educational training programs.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
