<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ged" order_by="" level="1">Economic Development</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ged-8-701</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>701</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"At-risk youth" means an individual who meets at least two of the eligibility criteria determined by the Department and an operator that may include:<section prefix="(1)">Being eligible for free or reduced price meals;</section><section prefix="(2)">A record of suspensions, office referrals, or chronic truancy;</section><section prefix="(3)">A failure to achieve a proficient or advanced level on State assessments in reading or mathematics, or both;</section><section prefix="(4)">Having a disability;</section><section prefix="(5)">A referral from a teacher, counselor, social worker, or community-based service organization;</section><section prefix="(6)">The head of household is a single parent;</section><section prefix="(7)">The head of household is not a custodial parent;</section><section prefix="(8)">The adjusted gross family income is below the federally established poverty guidelines;</section><section prefix="(9)">The family receives temporary cash assistance under the State Family Investment Program; or</section><section prefix="(10)">A member of the family has been incarcerated.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Board" means the Board of Trustees of Residential Boarding Education Programs.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">"Operator" means a private nonprofit or public entity that develops and operates a program.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"Program" means a residential boarding education program that includes:<section prefix="(1)">A remedial curriculum for middle school grades;</section><section prefix="(2)">A college-preparatory curriculum for high school grades;</section><section prefix="(3)">Extracurricular activities such as athletics and cultural events;</section><section prefix="(4)">College admissions counseling;</section><section prefix="(5)">Health and mental health services;</section><section prefix="(6)">Tutoring;</section><section prefix="(7)">Community service opportunities; and</section><section prefix="(8)">A residential student life program.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
