<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="ged" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="12-108" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ged-12-108</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Board of Regents shall appoint a Chancellor of the University System of Maryland.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Chancellor is the Chief Executive Officer of the University System of Maryland and the Chief of Staff for the Board.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Chancellor shall:<section prefix="(i)">Advise the Board of Regents on systemwide policy;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Conduct systemwide planning;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Coordinate and arbitrate among the institutions and centers of the University;</section><section prefix="(iv)">Assist the institutions in achieving performance goals in accordance with their adopted performance accountability plan;</section><section prefix="(v)">Provide technical assistance to institutions and centers such as legal and financial services;</section><section prefix="(vi)">Perform the duties the Board assigns; and</section><section prefix="(vii)">See that the policies of the Board are carried out.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Chancellor serves at the pleasure of the Board.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Chancellor is entitled to the compensation established by the Board.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Chancellor may:<section prefix="(1)">Have the additional staff provided in the University budget; and</section><section prefix="(2)"><section prefix="(i)">Create any position within the system administration office and within existing funds available to the system administration office, to the extent the cost of the position, including the cost of any fringe benefits, is funded from existing funds.</section><section prefix="(ii)">This paragraph may not be construed to require any additional State General Fund support.</section><section prefix="(iii)">The total number of positions authorized under this paragraph shall be limited as specified annually in the State budget bill.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Each employee of the Board shall join the Teachers' Pension System of the State of Maryland or the Employees' Pension System of the State of Maryland.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">As an alternative, any employee in a position determined by the Board to be a professional position may join the optional retirement program under Title 30 of the State Personnel and Pensions Article.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
