<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ged" order_by="" level="1">Economic Development</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ged-18-402</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>402</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, each applicant for a senatorial scholarship shall:<section prefix="(i)">Take a competitive examination administered by the Office; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Be accepted for admission in the regular undergraduate, graduate, or professional program at an eligible institution; or be enrolled in a 2-year terminal certificate program in which the course work is acceptable for transfer credit for an accredited baccalaureate program in an eligible institution.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">An applicant is exempt from the examination if the applicant:<section prefix="(i)">Is attending an eligible institution and has completed at least 1 year in good academic standing at the institution;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Graduated from high school at least 5 years before application for a senatorial scholarship;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Is accepted for admission to a private career institution, if the institution's curriculum is approved by the Commission, and the institution is accredited by a national accrediting association approved by the United States Department of Education; or</section><section prefix="(iv)">Is planning to attend or is attending a Maryland community college.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Each applicant shall:<section prefix="(1)">Be a resident of this State; and</section><section prefix="(2)">At the time of the applicant's initial application, be a resident of the legislative district from which the applicant seeks an award.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Each applicant shall demonstrate to the Office a definite financial need, and each Senator shall consider the financial need of each applicant.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Each Senator is the final judge of the financial need of each applicant to whom he awards a scholarship, and the Office may not negate this judgment or impose requirements of time or procedure.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Each applicant shall accept any other conditions attached to the award.</section>
  </text>
</law>
