<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="ged" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="23-405" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ged-23-405</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In addition to any other powers granted or duties imposed by this subtitle, each board of library trustees has the powers and duties set forth in this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, each board of library trustees:<section prefix="(i)">Shall establish and operate the library to provide free services to residents of the county in which it is located; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">May permit persons outside of the county to use the library facilities on the terms and conditions it determines.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">In Baltimore City and Baltimore, Charles, Montgomery, and Prince George's counties, the board of library trustees in each of these counties may permit a library to charge fees for the rental of video cassettes.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Each board of library trustees may:<section prefix="(1)">Establish and operate libraries at any location in the county;</section><section prefix="(2)">Determine the policy of the library; and</section><section prefix="(3)">Adopt reasonable rules, regulations, and bylaws for the use of the library and the conduct of its business.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Each board of library trustees may:<section prefix="(1)">Advise in the preparation of, and approve, the library budget;</section><section prefix="(2)">Receive, account for, control, and supervise, under the rules and regulations of the county governing body, the spending of all public funds received by the library; and</section><section prefix="(3)">Use the services of the fiscal agencies of the county governing body.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">Each board of library trustees shall:<section prefix="(1)">Provide for an audit at least annually, by an accountant approved by the State Superintendent of its business and financial transactions and of the accounts of its treasurer;</section><section prefix="(2)">Make public the results of the annual audit; and</section><section prefix="(3)">Make an annual report to the county governing body and the State Superintendent on or before November 1 of each year, except that a county having a population of more than 500,000 and having a county library agency as provided by &#xA7; 23-401(b) of this subtitle shall submit their report by January 1. The report shall show:<section prefix="(i)">The amounts of money received from the library fund and other sources;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The itemized expenses;</section><section prefix="(iii)">The number of books and periodicals the library has;</section><section prefix="(iv)">The results of the annual audit; and</section><section prefix="(v)">Any other information the Department requires.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">Each board of library trustees may:<section prefix="(1)">Accept any gift, grant, or appropriation for library purposes from any person under any appropriate terms and conditions;</section><section prefix="(2)">Own and dispose of these gifts, grants, and appropriations;</section><section prefix="(3)">Recommend to the county governing body the acquisition, use, or conveyance of property, for any purpose valid under this subtitle;</section><section prefix="(4)">Select the location of and approve plans for the erection of library buildings, subject to the approval of the county governing body;</section><section prefix="(5)">Make contracts for any library service with any person; and</section><section prefix="(6)">Do anything else necessary for the proper control and development of the library.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
