<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="ged" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="11-106.1" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ged-11-106.1</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>// EFFECTIVE UNTIL JUNE 30, 2022 PER CHAPTER 327 OF 2012 //<section prefix="(a)">There is a Student Transfer Advisory Committee.</section><section prefix="(b)">The Committee consists of the following members:<section prefix="(1)">The Secretary of Higher Education, or the Secretary's designee;</section><section prefix="(2)">The Chancellor of the University System of Maryland, or the Chancellor's designee;</section><section prefix="(3)">The President of St. Mary's College of Maryland, or the President's designee;</section><section prefix="(4)">The President of Morgan State University, or the President's designee;</section><section prefix="(5)">The Executive Director of the Maryland Association of Community Colleges, or the Executive Director's designee;</section><section prefix="(6)">The President of the Maryland Independent College and University Association, or the President's designee;</section><section prefix="(7)">The Assistant Secretary for the Division of Workforce Development and Adult Learning in the Department of Labor, Licensing, and Regulation, or the Assistant Secretary's designee;</section><section prefix="(8)">The Assistant State Superintendent for Career and College Readiness in the State Department of Education, or the Assistant State Superintendent's designee;</section><section prefix="(9)">A representative of the Student Advisory Council, appointed by the Secretary;</section><section prefix="(10)">A representative from the Maryland Association of Private Career Schools, appointed by the Secretary; and</section><section prefix="(11)">A representative from a for-profit institution of higher education that operates in the State, appointed by the Secretary.</section></section><section prefix="(c)">The members of the Committee may elect a chair and other officers of the Committee, as needed.</section><section prefix="(d)">The Commission shall provide staff for the Committee.</section><section prefix="(e)">A member of the Committee:<section prefix="(1)">May not receive compensation as a member of the Committee; but</section><section prefix="(2)">Is entitled to reimbursement for expenses under the Standard State Travel Regulations, as provided in the State budget.</section></section><section prefix="(f)">The Committee shall review and analyze:<section prefix="(1)">Articulation and student support services, including admission and advising practices; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Any other student transfer related issues as referred to the Committee by the Commission.</section></section><section prefix="(g)">The Committee shall meet at least four times per year.</section><section prefix="(h)">On or before December 1, 2013, and in each odd-numbered year thereafter, the Committee shall report its findings and recommendations to the Governor and, in accordance with &#xA7; 2-1246 of the State Government Article, the General Assembly.</section></text>
</law>
