<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ged" order_by="ged" level="1">Economic Development</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ged-24-202</section_number>
  <catch_line>The Maryland Public Broadcasting Commission consists of 11 members appointed by the Governor....</catch_line>
  <order_by>202</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Maryland Public Broadcasting Commission consists of 11 members appointed by the Governor.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Each member of the Commission shall be a resident of this State.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The members shall be broadly representative of this State as a whole and shall include individuals skilled in:<section prefix="(i)">Public or private elementary, secondary, or higher education;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Art, music, or drama;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Radio and television;</section><section prefix="(iv)">Libraries; and</section><section prefix="(v)">Any other field that the Governor considers appropriate for the Commission.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Commission shall include two members nominated by the State Board of Education.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The State Superintendent of Schools shall serve ex officio.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Each appointed member of the Commission serves for a term of 5 years and until a successor is appointed and qualifies. These terms are staggered as required by the terms of the members serving on the Commission as of July 1, 1978.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A member appointed to fill a vacancy in an unexpired term serves only for the remainder of that term and until a successor is appointed and qualifies.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A member may be reappointed.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Each member of the Commission:<section prefix="(1)">Serves without compensation; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Is entitled to reimbursement for expenses in accordance with the Standard State Travel Regulations.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
