<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="ged" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="6-401" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ged-6-401</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Employee organization" means an organization that:<section prefix="(1)">Includes certificated employees of a public school employer or individuals of equivalent status in Baltimore City; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Has as one of its main purposes the representation of the employees in their relations with that public school employer.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Home and hospital teacher" means a teacher employed by a public school employer to provide instructional services to a public school student who is unable to function effectively in the classroom setting due to the student's medical, physical, or emotional condition.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A home and hospital teacher may teach in:<section prefix="(i)">A private home;</section><section prefix="(ii)">A hospital;</section><section prefix="(iii)">A therapeutic center;</section><section prefix="(iv)">A school; or</section><section prefix="(v)">Any other appropriate site.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Public school employee" means a certificated professional individual who is employed by a public school employer or an individual of equivalent status in Baltimore City, except for a county superintendent or an individual designated by the public school employer to act in a negotiating capacity as provided in &#xA7; 6-408(b) of this subtitle.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">In Montgomery County, "public school employees" include:<section prefix="(i)">Certificated and noncertificated substitute teachers employed by the public school employer for at least 7 days before March 1 of the school fiscal year ending June 30, 1978, and each year after; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Home and hospital teachers employed by the public school employer for at least 7 days before March 1 of the school fiscal year ending June 30, 2000, and each year after.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">In Baltimore County, "public school employee" includes a secondary school nurse, an elementary school nurse, and a special school nurse.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">In Frederick County, "public school employee" includes a social worker employed by a public school employer.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">In Prince George's County, "public school employee" includes home and hospital teachers and Junior Reserve Officer Training Corps (JROTC) instructors.</section>
      <section prefix="(6)">In Calvert County, Charles County, and Garrett County, "public school employee" includes Junior Reserve Officer Training Corps (JROTC) instructors.</section>
      <section prefix="(7)">In Carroll County, "public school employee" includes:<section prefix="(i)">A registered nurse; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Supervisory noncertificated employees as defined under &#xA7; 6-501(h) of this title.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"Public school employer" means a county board of education or the Baltimore City Board of School Commissioners.</section>
  </text>
</law>
