<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ged" order_by="ged" level="1">Economic Development</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ged-13-511</section_number>
  <catch_line>There is a statewide Emergency Medical Services Advisory Council to advise and assist the EMS Board ...</catch_line>
  <order_by>511</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">There is a statewide Emergency Medical Services Advisory Council to advise and assist the EMS Board in performing its functions.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Advisory Council consists of 31 members. The members shall be appointed by the Board from a list of three qualified nominees submitted to the Board by their respective organizations or associations represented on the Council. The appointments by the Board shall be subject to the approval of the Governor.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Of the 31 members:<section prefix="(i)">One shall be a representative of the Maryland Chapter of the American College of Emergency Physicians;</section><section prefix="(ii)">One shall be a representative of MedChi, The Maryland State Medical Society;</section><section prefix="(iii)">One shall be a representative of the Maryland Hospital Association;</section><section prefix="(iv)">One shall be a representative of the Maryland State Council of the Emergency Nurses Association;</section><section prefix="(v)">One shall be a representative of the Maryland Fire and Rescue Institute;</section><section prefix="(vi)">One shall be a representative of the Maryland State Firemen's Association;</section><section prefix="(vii)">One shall be a representative of the Aviation Division of the Department of State Police;</section><section prefix="(viii)">One shall be a representative of the Office of Traffic and Safety of the Maryland Department of Transportation;</section><section prefix="(ix)">One shall be a representative from each of the five regional emergency medical services advisory councils;</section><section prefix="(x)">One shall be a representative of the Maryland Trauma Center Network;</section><section prefix="(xi)">One shall be a representative of a Maryland commercial ambulance service;</section><section prefix="(xii)">One shall be a representative of the Board of Physicians;</section><section prefix="(xiii)">One shall be a representative of the Maryland Chapter, American College of Surgeons;</section><section prefix="(xiv)">One shall be a regional medical director;</section><section prefix="(xv)">One shall be a representative of the Maryland Chapter (Chesapeake Bay), American Association of Critical Care Nurses;</section><section prefix="(xvi)">One shall be a representative of the Professional Fire Fighters of Maryland;</section><section prefix="(xvii)">One shall be a representative of the volunteer field providers;</section><section prefix="(xviii)">One shall be a representative of the Maryland Metropolitan Fire Chiefs;</section><section prefix="(xix)">One shall be a representative of the Emergency Number Systems Board;</section><section prefix="(xx)">One shall be the Director of the R Adams Cowley Shock Trauma Center;</section><section prefix="(xxi)">One shall be the Director of the National Study Center;</section><section prefix="(xxii)">Three shall be members of the general public, one of whom shall reside in a county with a population of less than 175,000;</section><section prefix="(xxiii)">One shall be a representative of the Committee on Pediatric Emergency Medicine of the American Academy of Pediatrics, Maryland Chapter;</section><section prefix="(xxiv)">One shall be a representative of the Maryland Society of Anesthesiologists; and</section><section prefix="(xxv)">One shall be a helicopter pilot.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Each appointed member of the Council shall have demonstrated interest or experience in the delivery of emergency medical services.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The members of the Advisory Council shall annually elect the chairperson of the Advisory Council, with the approval of the Governor. The Governor shall have 60 days to approve the elected chairperson. If the Governor has not acted within 60 days of being notified of the election of the chairperson, the elected chairperson shall be deemed approved.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The Advisory Council shall:<section prefix="(1)">Serve as a principal advisory body to the EMS Board on matters concerning finances, policies, guidelines, regulations, and procedures necessary for the efficient and effective operation of the statewide Emergency Medical Services System and the Institute;</section><section prefix="(2)">Provide a means by which regional emergency medical services interests can be represented at a statewide level;</section><section prefix="(3)">Assist in the development of goals for and facilitate the implementation of a comprehensive emergency medical services plan;</section><section prefix="(4)">Provide assistance in the resolution of interregional and interstate emergency medical services system problems and concerns; and</section><section prefix="(5)">Perform any other duties as may be requested by the EMS Board or the Governor.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The staff for the Advisory Council will be provided by the Institute.</section>
  </text>
</law>
