<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ged" order_by="ged" level="1">Economic Development</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ged-2-205</section_number>
  <catch_line>In addition to the other powers granted and duties imposed under this article, the State Board has t...</catch_line>
  <order_by>205</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In addition to the other powers granted and duties imposed under this article, the State Board has the powers and duties set forth in this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The State Board shall:<section prefix="(1)">Determine the elementary and secondary educational policies of this State; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Cause to be carried out those provisions of this article that are within its jurisdiction.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The State Board shall adopt bylaws, rules, and regulations for the administration of the public schools.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">These bylaws, rules, and regulations have the force of law when adopted and published.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The bylaws, rules, and regulations apply to each county. However, they do not apply to Baltimore City to the extent that they relate to matters that are the subject of other provisions of this article that do not apply to Baltimore City.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The State Board may institute legal proceedings to enforce:<section prefix="(1)">The provisions of this article that are within its jurisdiction; and</section><section prefix="(2)">The bylaws, rules, and regulations adopted by the Board.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Without charge and with the advice of the Attorney General, the State Board shall explain the true intent and meaning of the provisions of:<section prefix="(i)">This article that are within its jurisdiction; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">The bylaws, rules, and regulations adopted by the Board.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Board shall decide all controversies and disputes under these provisions.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The decision of the Board is final.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">As Secretary to the State Board, the State Superintendent may administer oaths to witnesses in any matter before the Board.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This subsection does not apply to Baltimore City to the extent that it relates to matters that are the subject of other provisions of this article that do not apply to Baltimore City.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Through the State Superintendent, the State Board shall exercise general control and supervision over the public schools and educational interests of this State.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Through the State Superintendent, the Board shall consult with and advise county boards, county superintendents and their staffs, principals, teachers, and interested citizens.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The Board shall seek in every way to direct and develop public sentiment in support of public education.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(h)">
      <section prefix="(1)">With the advice of the State Superintendent, the State Board shall establish basic policy and guidelines for the program of instruction for the public schools.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The policy and guidelines shall be printed in sufficient quantities to provide copies to:<section prefix="(i)">Public school officials and teachers;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Private schools; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Interested citizens of this State.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The State Board of Education shall require the establishment of criteria in each county for the selection of applicants for enrollment in public secondary school career and technology education programs. Enrollment criteria developed for this purpose shall ensure equal access to programs.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(i)">
      <section prefix="(1)">With the advice of the State Superintendent, the State Board shall investigate:<section prefix="(i)">The educational needs of this State; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Methods to improve educational conditions.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If necessary, the Board may employ additional expert assistance for these investigations.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(j)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The State Board shall send the Governor an annual State public school budget including, subject to the Maryland Constitution and existing laws, the appropriation for:<section prefix="(i)">The Department; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">State aid to the counties for current expenses, for student transportation and for the construction of school buildings.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The budget shall be certified by the State Superintendent before it is sent to the Governor.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(k)">The State Board shall:<section prefix="(1)">Consider the educational needs of this State; and</section><section prefix="(2)">With the advice of the State Superintendent, recommend to the Governor and the General Assembly any legislation that it considers necessary.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(l)">
      <section prefix="(1)">On the recommendation of the State Superintendent, the State Board shall establish standards and guides for planning and constructing school building projects.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">These standards and guides shall be used as the basis for reviewing plans and specifications submitted to the State Superintendent for approval.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The State Board shall maintain a school construction planning service to:<section prefix="(i)">Assist in the development and review of preliminary and final plans and specifications for any public school building project and the educational program that it is designed to house; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Advise county boards as to the suitability of these construction plans on the basis of educational effectiveness, construction, and reasonable economy of costs.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The State Board shall collect, publish, and distribute to the county boards information on school construction procedures, methods, and materials.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(m)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this subsection, "professional employee" means an employee:<section prefix="(i)">For whom a certificate has been issued by the State Superintendent; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">For whom a salary scale has been established by law for the position or who meets or exceeds the qualifications required for an established salary scale.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">From time to time, the State Board shall adopt bylaws, rules, and regulations that establish a minimum ratio of professional employees to students enrolled in the public schools or any combination of grades in these schools.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The ratio established by the State Board for the total number of professional employees for each county, calculated to the nearest whole position on a pro rata basis, may not be more than:<section prefix="(i)">46 for each 1,000 of the first 5,000 students enrolled as of September 30 of each year; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">45 for each additional 1,000 students.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">A county may employ more professional employees than the number permitted in this subsection as it considers necessary.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">At least 95 percent of the permitted number of professional employees shall be assigned to public schools.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(n)">With the advice of the State Superintendent, the State Board shall require each private educational association, corporation, and institution to report annually, on or before August 31, its enrollment and courses of study on the forms that the Board provides.</section>
    <section prefix="(o)">
      <section prefix="(1)">With the advice of the State Superintendent, the State Board shall specify the information each county board, school official, and teacher is to record and shall require the following information to be recorded:<section prefix="(i)">All financial accounts, including the annual budget; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">All educational records.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The reports containing this information shall be made on the form that the State Board, with the advice of the State Superintendent, requires.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">If the State Superintendent agrees, the required information may be sent in automatic data processing, machine-usable form.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(p)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The State Board shall submit an annual report to the Governor on:<section prefix="(i)">All operations of the Department;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The support, conditions, progress, and needs of elementary and secondary education in this State; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">The overall plan for elementary and secondary education in this State.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">This annual report shall be printed in sufficient quantities for general distribution in this State.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(q)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The State Board shall coordinate the overall growth and development of elementary and secondary education in this State.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">In consultation with the State Superintendent, the State Board shall develop and periodically update an overall plan consistent with the bylaws that shall identify:<section prefix="(i)">The present and future needs of elementary and secondary education throughout the State, including a discussion of the demographic composition of the elementary and secondary population;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The present and future capabilities of the public elementary and secondary education system in this State;</section><section prefix="(iii)">The short-range and long-range objectives and priorities for elementary and secondary education and methods and timelines for achieving and maintaining them;</section><section prefix="(iv)">Whether current programs adequately prepare graduates for employment opportunities in this State, or postsecondary education opportunities;</section><section prefix="(v)">The status and needs of the career and technology education program, the vocational rehabilitation program, and the library system of these programs;</section><section prefix="(vi)">The technological advancements that would enhance elementary and secondary education throughout the State;</section><section prefix="(vii)">Methods to upgrade and improve teacher education and teacher certification programs;</section><section prefix="(viii)">The school systems that have dropped below the statewide test averages and shall assess the options available to improve the test averages of these school systems;</section><section prefix="(ix)">The methods to improve the diagnosis of basic reading skill deficiencies of elementary and secondary school students and to improve the literacy rates of these students;</section><section prefix="(x)">The methods to increase the rate of retention and graduation of secondary school students;</section><section prefix="(xi)">The short-range and long-range objectives for the resolution of the problem of substance abuse by elementary and secondary school students; and</section><section prefix="(xii)">The short-range and long-range objectives for the resolution of the problems of youth and teenage pregnancy.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
