<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ged" order_by="" level="1">Economic Development</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ged-24-511</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>511</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">There is a Historic St. Mary's City Fund.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The State Treasurer shall hold the Historic St. Mary's City Fund. The funds in the account shall be invested and reinvested by the Treasurer in accordance with the written investment policies of the Commission. Any investment earnings on the funds in the account shall be paid into the Fund.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">All unexpended or unencumbered balances of the Fund:<section prefix="(i)">Shall be reported to the Comptroller at the end of the fiscal year for which the appropriation was made;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Do not revert to the General Fund or any other special fund of the State; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Shall be available for expenditure through an appropriation contained in a budget bill or through an approved budget amendment.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The Commission shall use the Fund as a continuing, nonlapsing, revolving fund for carrying out the purposes of this subtitle.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Fund consists of:<section prefix="(1)">Any general funds appropriated to the Commission;</section><section prefix="(2)">Any fees collected by the Commission; and</section><section prefix="(3)">Any additional moneys received or paid to the Commission from any other source authorized by law.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Commission shall pay all expenses and make all expenditures from the Fund.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Expenditures from the Fund shall be made pursuant to an appropriation approved by the General Assembly in the annual State budget or by the budget amendment procedure provided for in &#xA7; 7-209 of the State Finance and Procurement Article.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Commission may pledge and charge all or a portion of the receipts of the Fund for the payment of:<section prefix="(i)">Debt service on bonds of the authority; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">All reasonable charges and expenses related to borrowing by the Commission and management of the obligations of the Commission.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A pledge made under paragraph (1) of this subsection is effective as provided in &#xA7; 24-520 of this subtitle and any applicable resolution of the Commission.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">For each fiscal year, the Governor shall include in the annual budget bill a proposed General Fund appropriation to the Commission in an amount not less than the amount of the General Fund operating appropriation to the Commission included in the State budget for fiscal year 1998 as passed by the General Assembly.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Commission is authorized to make use of its facilities, equipment, and other resources to provide services and charge appropriate fees therefore to generate income for the benefit of Historic St. Mary's City.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">All fees collected shall be deposited in the Historic St. Mary's City Fund.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Commission has the responsibility for the governance and management of Historic St. Mary's City, including the care, control, and maintenance of all of its property and assets.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Commission annually shall adopt and implement both a capital and operating budget for the maintenance, operation, and development of Historic St. Mary's City.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Commission shall submit the budget it has adopted annually to the Governor for inclusion in the State budget.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">Subject to the budget amendment procedure provided for in &#xA7; 7-209 of the State Finance and Procurement Article, the Commission may spend or encumber, within the fiscal year they are received or any time thereafter, any income, revenues, or other funds received in excess of those estimated by the Commission in the capital or operating budget adopted by the Commission for that fiscal year.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
