<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ged" order_by="" level="1">Economic Development</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ged-18-2002</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>2002</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">There is a program of Maryland Science and Technology Scholarships in this State that are awarded under this subtitle. The Office shall annually select students who have the greatest potential for academic success in higher education and offer a scholarship to each student to be used at a Maryland higher education institution of the student's choice, if the recipient meets the following qualifications:<section prefix="(1)">Qualifies academically as follows:<section prefix="(i)">Has a secondary school transcript indicating an overall grade point average of at least 3.0 on a 4.0 scale or its equivalent after completion of the first semester of the senior year;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Intends to enroll or is enrolled as a full-time student in an academic program as designated by the Maryland Higher Education Commission; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Has graduated from a secondary school;</section></section><section prefix="(2)">Is a Maryland resident and was a Maryland resident at the time of graduating from secondary school;</section><section prefix="(3)">Is accepted for admission in a regular undergraduate program at a Maryland higher education institution in the State;</section><section prefix="(4)">Begins attending an eligible Maryland higher education institution within 5 years of completing secondary school or, failing to do so, provides evidence satisfactory to the Office of extenuating circumstances;</section><section prefix="(5)">Agrees to the conditions provided in subsection (c) of this section; and</section><section prefix="(6)">Accepts any other conditions attached to the award and satisfies any additional criteria the Commission may establish.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The annual scholarship award shall be in the amount of $1,000 for a student enrolled at a 2-year eligible institution or $3,000 for a student enrolled at a 4-year eligible institution.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If accepted by the eligible student, each award may be renewed on an annual basis for a maximum of 3 years after the original award if the recipient:<section prefix="(i)">Remains a resident of the State;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Attends a Maryland higher education institution in the State;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Is enrolled as a full-time undergraduate student and takes at least 12 semester hours of courses each semester or its equivalent as determined by the Office;</section><section prefix="(iv)">Maintains a 3.0 grade point average on an academic year basis or, failing to do so, provides evidence satisfactory to the Office, of extreme extenuating circumstances;</section><section prefix="(v)">Is making satisfactory progress toward a degree as determined by the institution; and</section><section prefix="(vi)">Maintains the standards of the institution.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Subject to the provisions of paragraph (2) of this subsection, each recipient of a Maryland Science and Technology Scholarship who is enrolled in a baccalaureate degree program may renew the annual award four times if the recipient is enrolled in an undergraduate academic program that, as determined by the institution, requires 5 years to complete.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">Subject to the provisions of paragraph (2) of this subsection, each award may be renewed on an annual basis for a maximum of 2 years for students enrolled in an associate degree program.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A recipient of an award made under this section shall receive the award for each year indicated in which the recipient is eligible if:<section prefix="(1)">The recipient signs an agreement at the time of the initial award to:<section prefix="(i)">Commence employment in the State within 1 year after completion of undergraduate studies for 1 year for each year that the scholarship was awarded; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Repay the State the amounts awarded under this subtitle as set forth in &#xA7; 18-112 of this title if the recipient does not:<section prefix="1.">Satisfy the degree requirements of the eligible academic program or fulfill other requirements as provided in this subtitle; and</section><section prefix="2.">Perform the service obligation for 1 year for each year that the recipient has a scholarship awarded under this subtitle; and</section></section></section><section prefix="(2)">The service obligation begins after graduation and cannot be fulfilled prior to graduation from an eligible institution.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
