<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ged" order_by="" level="1">Economic Development</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ged-16-409</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>409</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Boards of Directors of the Harford Educational Foundation and of the Harford Community College Foundation, Inc. have the authority to effect a merger of the two corporations under the provisions of Title 3 of the Corporations and Associations Article.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The articles of merger shall:<section prefix="(1)">Be in writing;</section><section prefix="(2)">Be filed with the State Department of Assessments and Taxation;</section><section prefix="(3)">Be recorded with the corporate records of the Circuit Court in Harford County; and</section><section prefix="(4)">Otherwise conform to the requirements of the State Department of Assessments and Taxation, as provided in the Corporations and Associations Article.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">After the merger, the Harford Community College Foundation, Inc. shall be the sole surviving corporation.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The articles of merger shall provide that:<section prefix="(1)">The Board of Directors of the Harford Educational Foundation transfer the corporate assets to the Harford Community College Foundation, Inc.;</section><section prefix="(2)">The Harford Community College Foundation, Inc. administer the assets of the Harford Educational Foundation as a revolving loan fund;</section><section prefix="(3)">The Harford Community College pay all the costs to administer the revolving loan fund;</section><section prefix="(4)">In the event of a default by a student on a loan from the revolving loan fund, at the end of the fiscal year in which the default occurred, the Harford Community College Foundation, Inc. shall transfer to the revolving loan fund an amount equal to the amount of the defaulted loan; and</section><section prefix="(5)">In addition to any other powers granted and duties imposed on it, the Harford Community College Foundation, Inc. shall:<section prefix="(i)">Act as trustee for the funds transferred from the Harford Educational Foundation under the trust agreements made between the donors and the Harford Educational Foundation;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Rename the Harford Educational Foundation the Harford Community College Student Loan Fund;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Accept funds by grant, gift, devise, or bequest from individuals and corporations to the Harford Community College Student Loan Fund to ensure the ability to promote scholarship; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">Administer funds accepted into the Harford Community College Student Loan Fund strictly in accordance with the purposes of the Fund.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Harford Community College Foundation, Inc. shall report its activities for the preceding year annually to the County Executive and County Council of Harford County.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The finances of the Foundation are subject to annual audit, including the preparation of separate balance sheets for the Harford Community College Foundation, Inc. and the Harford Community College Student Loan Fund.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The Harford Community College Foundation, Inc. is exempt from the provisions of:<section prefix="(1)">Bank licensing acts; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Title 11, Subtitles 2 and 3 of the Financial Institutions Article.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
