<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ged" order_by="ged" level="1">Economic Development</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ged-18-307</section_number>
  <catch_line>Except as provided in subsection (d) of this section, the Office shall compile and certify lists for...</catch_line>
  <order_by>307</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Except as provided in subsection (d) of this section, the Office shall compile and certify lists for the entire State that rank applicants by financial need.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">All funds for annual initial grants shall be awarded from the statewide list on the basis of greatest financial need.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">On or before May 1 of each year, the Office shall send each Senator and each Delegate a list of individuals in each legislative district to whom Delegate Howard P. Rawlings Educational Excellence Awards are awarded.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">If State funds are available for this purpose, institutions of higher education in the State may provide Delegate Howard P. Rawlings Educational Excellence Awards to students who otherwise meet the requirements for receiving a Delegate Howard P. Rawlings Educational Excellence Award but who apply after the March 1 deadline or have other extenuating circumstances.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">Each year the Commission shall transfer at least $2 million of the funds available under &#xA7; 18-107(b) of this title for the purposes of this subsection.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Commission shall:<section prefix="(i)">Establish guidelines for the awarding of Delegate Howard P. Rawlings Educational Excellence Awards by the institutions of higher education to the students; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Adopt regulations necessary for the implementation of this subsection.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The Commission shall allocate available funds to institutions of higher education based on the proportion of State residents enrolled at each institution who receive federal Pell Grants.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">An institution of higher education that receives funds under this paragraph shall provide the Commission with an annual audit describing the disposition of the funds.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
