<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="ged" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="14-402" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ged-14-402</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The government of St. Mary's College of Maryland is vested in the Board of Trustees of St. Mary's College of Maryland.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Board of Trustees consists of 26 members.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Of the 26 members:<section prefix="(i)">23 members shall be appointed by the Governor upon the recommendation of the Board of Trustees, with the advice and consent of the Senate;</section><section prefix="(ii)">1 member shall be the Chairman of the Historic St. Mary's City Commission, or the Chairman's designee;</section><section prefix="(iii)">1 member shall be the President of the St. Mary's Alumni Association; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">1 member shall be a student in good academic standing at the College.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except for the Chairman of the Historic St. Mary's City Commission, the President of the St. Mary's College Alumni Association, and the student member, each member serves for a term of 6 years and until a successor is appointed and qualifies. These terms are staggered as required by the terms of the members serving on July 1, 1978.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Chairman of the Historic St. Mary's City Commission serves on the Board of Trustees of St. Mary's College of Maryland for as long as that individual serves as Chairman of the Commission.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The President of the St. Mary's College Alumni Association serves on the Board of Trustees of St. Mary's College of Maryland for as long as that individual serves as President of the Association.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The student member serves for a term of 1 year and until a successor is appointed and qualifies.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">A member appointed to fill a vacancy in an unexpired term serves only for the remainder of that term and until a successor is appointed and qualifies.</section>
      <section prefix="(6)">
        <section prefix="(i)">A majority of the voting members shall constitute a quorum for the transaction of business.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">No formal action may be taken by the Board without the approval of a majority of the voting members of the Board.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Each member of the Board:<section prefix="(1)">Serves without compensation; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Is entitled to reimbursement for expenses in accordance with the Standard State Travel Regulations.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
