<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="ged" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="18-601" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ged-18-601</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Disabled public safety employee" means a State or local public safety employee who sustains an injury in the line of duty that:<section prefix="(i)">Precludes the individual from continuing to serve or be employed as a State or local public safety employee; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">In the case of a volunteer member of a fire department or ambulance or rescue company or squad, precludes the member from continuing to be employed in the nonpublic safety occupation in which the member is engaged at the time of the injury.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Surviving spouse" means a person who has not remarried.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">"State or local public safety employee" means a person who is:<section prefix="(i)">A career or volunteer member of a:</section><section prefix="(ii)">A law enforcement officer;</section><section prefix="(iii)">A correctional officer; or</section><section prefix="(iv)">A member of the Maryland National Guard who was a resident of this State at the time of death.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(5)">"Victim of the September 11, 2001, terrorist attacks" means a Maryland resident who was killed as a result of the attacks on the World Trade Center in New York City, the attack on the Pentagon in Virginia, or the crash of United Airlines Flight 93 in Pennsylvania.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">There is a program of scholarships that are awarded by eligible postsecondary institutions under this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Program is the Edward T. Conroy Memorial Scholarship Program.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A person may apply to an eligible postsecondary institution for a scholarship under this section if the person:<section prefix="(1)"><section prefix="(i)">Is a resident of Maryland at the time of application; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">Was a resident of Maryland when an event described in paragraph (3) of this subsection occurred;</section></section><section prefix="(2)"><section prefix="(i)">Is accepted for admission or enrolled in the regular undergraduate, graduate or professional program at an eligible institution; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">Is enrolled in a 2-year terminal certificate program in which the course work is acceptable for transfer credit for an accredited baccalaureate program in an eligible institution; and</section></section><section prefix="(3)"><section prefix="(i)">Is at least 16 years old and a son or daughter of a member of the armed forces who:</section><section prefix="(ii)">Was a prisoner of war or missing in action, if that occurred on or after January 1, 1960, as a result of the Vietnam conflict and was a resident of this State at the time the person was declared to be a prisoner of war or missing in action;</section><section prefix="(iii)"/><section prefix="(iv)"/><section prefix="(v)">Is a veteran, as defined under &#xA7; 9-901 of the State Government Article, who:</section><section prefix="(vi)">Is the surviving spouse of a member of the armed forces who suffered a service connected 100% permanent disability; or</section><section prefix="(vii)">Is at least 16 years old and a son or daughter of or the surviving spouse of a victim of the September 11, 2001, terrorist attacks.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">A scholarship awarded under this section:<section prefix="(1)">May be used for the tuition and mandatory fees at any eligible institution; and</section><section prefix="(2)">May not:<section prefix="(i)">Exceed the equivalent annual tuition and mandatory fees of a resident undergraduate student at the 4-year public institution of higher education within the University System of Maryland, other than the University of Maryland University College and University of Maryland, Baltimore, with the highest annual expenses for a full-time resident undergraduate; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Be less than the lesser of:</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Each postsecondary institution shall determine the eligibility of persons who apply to the institution for the Edward T. Conroy Memorial Scholarship Program.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Funds for the Edward T. Conroy Memorial Scholarship Program shall be allocated by the Commission to each postsecondary institution based on the number of eligible recipients attending each institution.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">In October and February of each year, each postsecondary institution shall report to the Commission the number of eligible recipients attending the institution.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The Commission shall allocate funds for awards to postsecondary institutions upon verification of eligible recipients attending the institutions.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">If funds cannot be allocated in the fiscal year in which awards are made, priority shall be given to allocating funds for those awards in the following fiscal year.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Each recipient of a scholarship under this section may hold the award for 5 years of full-time study or 8 years of part-time study.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The number of eligible recipients under subsection (d)(3)(v) of this section shall be limited to 15 each year.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">An award provided under subsection (d)(3)(vi) of this section may not exceed the amount specified in subsection (e)(2) of this section when combined with any other scholarship received by a student based on the student's status as a child or spouse of a victim of the September 11, 2001, terrorist attacks.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(h)">The Commission:<section prefix="(1)">May accept any gift or grant from any person for the Edward T. Conroy Scholarship Fund;</section><section prefix="(2)">Shall use any gift or grant that it receives for a scholarship from the Program; and</section><section prefix="(3)">Shall deposit any gift or grant that it receives for the Program with the State Treasurer in a nonbudgeted account.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
