<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ged" order_by="ged" level="1">Economic Development</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ged-16-507</section_number>
  <catch_line>For each fiscal year, the President shall prepare and the Board of Trustees shall review, modify, as...</catch_line>
  <order_by>507</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">For each fiscal year, the President shall prepare and the Board of Trustees shall review, modify, as necessary, and approve an operating budget and a capital budget for the College.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The operating budget shall indicate:<section prefix="(1)">All revenues estimated for the next fiscal year classified by funds and sources of income; and</section><section prefix="(2)">All expenditures requested, including specification of expenditures for each major function established by the Commission under &#xA7; 16-304 of this title.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The President and Board of Trustees shall submit the operating and capital budgets to the Commission in accordance with the provisions of &#xA7; 11-105(i) of this article.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">All income of the College shall be deposited:<section prefix="(i)">In the State Treasury; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">As the State Treasurer directs.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">By an approved budget amendment, the College may spend or encumber within the fiscal year in which they are received, revenues received in excess of those estimated for any fiscal year.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The unexpended or unencumbered balances of the College's revenues:<section prefix="(i)">Shall be reported to the Comptroller and to the Secretary at the end of the fiscal year for which the appropriation was made;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Do not revert to the State Treasury at the end of each fiscal year; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Shall be available for expenditure through an appropriation contained in the budget bill or through an approved budget amendment.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The interest or other income from the investment of any funds of the College shall be credited to the College, provided that any interest estimated to be earned on the State appropriation must be offset by an equivalent reduction in State General Fund support, and that amount will be reported annually to the General Assembly.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The Legislative Auditor shall audit all expenditures and accounts of the College in accordance with &#xA7;&#xA7; 2-1220 through 2-1227 of the State Government Article.</section>
  </text>
</law>
