<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ged" order_by="" level="1">Economic Development</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ged-18-2504</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>2504</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The annual amount of the Community College Transfer Scholarship awarded under this subtitle shall be $3,000.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A Community College Transfer Scholarship may be used for tuition and mandatory fees.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Subject to paragraphs (2) and (3) of this subsection, to retain a Community College Transfer Scholarship, the recipient shall:<section prefix="(i)">Remain a resident of the State;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Continue to be enrolled as an undergraduate student in a degree program at a 4-year public or private nonprofit institution of higher education in the State;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Maintain a 3.0 grade point average on a 4.0 scale each academic year the individual is enrolled at a 4-year public or private nonprofit institution of higher education in the State or provide evidence satisfactory to the Office of extenuating circumstances; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">Maintain the standards of the eligible institution that the individual attends.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A recipient of a Community College Transfer Scholarship awarded under this subtitle shall receive the award for each year that the recipient is eligible if the recipient signs an agreement at the time of the initial award to:<section prefix="(i)">Remain a resident of the State and:<section prefix="1.">Except as provided in paragraph (3)(ii) of this subsection, continue full-time employment in the State after completion of undergraduate studies for 1 year for each year that the Scholarship was awarded; or</section><section prefix="2.">Except as provided in paragraph (3)(ii) of this subsection, commence full-time employment in the State within 1 year after completion of undergraduate studies and thereafter continue employment in the State for 1 year for each year that the Scholarship was awarded; and</section></section><section prefix="(ii)">Repay the State the amounts awarded under this subtitle as set forth in &#xA7; 18-112 of this title for any portion of the award if the recipient does not:<section prefix="1.">Satisfy the degree requirements of the eligible institution or fulfill other requirements as provided in this subtitle; and</section><section prefix="2.">Maintain State residency and satisfy the employment obligation required under this paragraph.</section></section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The residency and employment obligation required by paragraph (2) of this subsection begins after graduation and cannot be fulfilled prior to graduation from an eligible institution.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">A recipient of a Community College Transfer Scholarship awarded under this subtitle may fulfill the employment obligation required under paragraph (2)(i)1 and 2 of this subsection out of State if the recipient:<section prefix="1.">Was employed out of State at the time the recipient received the Scholarship;</section><section prefix="2.">Continues employment with the same employer while receiving the Scholarship; and</section><section prefix="3.">Continues employment with the same employer after completion of the recipient's undergraduate studies.</section></section>
      </section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
