<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="ged" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="13-205" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ged-13-205</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Within 5 days from the date on which the employee receives the charges for removal as evidenced by the return receipt or other evidence of delivery of the charges to the employee an employee who is suspended under charges for removal may request an opportunity to be heard in his own defense. Within 30 days if possible after receipt, the president or the president's designated representative shall investigate the charges and give the employee an opportunity to be heard. Testimony shall be taken under oath and both the department head or chairman or designee and the employee have the right of representation by counsel and the right to present witnesses and give evidence. Within 15 days following the conclusion of the conference, the written decision shall be rendered to the employee. In the case of appeals from charges pending removal, the department head or chairman or designee may request through appropriate channels the Attorney General's representative to the University to serve as counsel. In case no hearing is timely requested, the Campus Director of Personnel shall act upon the charges or order such other actions as are indicated by the findings in the case. If a hearing is timely requested and the removal is upheld, step three of the grievance procedure shall be available to the removed individual. The appeal shall be submitted within 10 days after receipt of the written University decision.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Within 5 days, an employee who is notified of demotion may file a written answer with the president or the president's designated representative and request an investigation of the demotion. Within 20 days, if possible, after receipt, the president or the president's designated representative shall investigate the demotion and give the employee an opportunity to be heard. Within 15 days following the conclusion of the investigation, the written decision shall be rendered to the employee. If an investigation is timely requested and the demotion is upheld, step three of the grievance procedure is available to the demoted employee. The appeal shall be submitted within 10 days after receipt of the written University decision.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Rejection on Original Probation. Within 5 days of the notice of rejection, an employee who is rejected on original probation may file a written request with the president or the president's designated representative for a hearing. Within 20 days, if possible, after receipt, the president or the president's designated representative shall conduct a hearing. Within 15 days following the conclusion of the hearing, the written decision shall be rendered to the employee. If the hearing is timely requested and the rejection is upheld, step three of the grievance procedure is available. The appeal shall be submitted within 10 days after receipt of the written University decision. Rejection for cause is not required in the case of an employee rejected on original probation.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Rejection on Promotional, Transfer, or Horizontal Change Probation. Within 5 days of receipt of the recommendation of the department head or chairman to reject, an employee who is promoted and then rejected within the probationary period for the new class and for whom a vacancy in the former class is not available may file an answer with the president or the president's designated representative and request an investigation of the proposed rejection. Within 20 days, if possible, after receipt, the president or the president's designated representative shall investigate the proposed rejection. The same rule applies to an employee who has completed a probationary period in one classification and makes a horizontal change to a new classification, and is rejected in the new classification or who transfers to another department in the same classification and is rejected. Within 15 days following the conclusion of the investigation, the written decision shall be rendered to the employee. If the investigation is timely requested and the rejection is upheld, step three of the grievance procedure is available to the rejected employee. The appeal shall be submitted within 10 days after receipt of the written University decision.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This subsection does not apply to suspensions pending charges for removal.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Alleged infractions shall be investigated by the responsible supervisor or administrator or designee at the earliest opportunity following knowledge of it, and the investigation shall be promptly completed. All suspensions of employees shall be implemented within 3 days of the alleged infraction or knowledge of the alleged infraction by the responsible supervisor or administrator. All suspension days shall be consecutive.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The employee or the employee's designated representative may submit a written appeal on a disciplinary suspension to the president or the president's designated representative within 5 days of notification of the suspension, or the employee or the employee's designated representative may appeal the suspension within 3 days of notification of the suspension to the department head or chairman or designee. The department head or chairman or designee shall hear the case within 3 days from the receipt of the written appeal. If the appeal is unheard or unanswered as a result of management delay, the employee shall be reinstated with full back pay.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">If the suspension is upheld by the president or the president's designated representative, step three of the grievance procedure is available to the employee. If the employee chooses to appeal to the department head or chairman or designee, any further appeals shall proceed through steps two and three of the grievance procedure.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If an employee is suspended without pay pending a hearing on disposition of charges for removal, the president or the president's designated representative shall notify the employee in writing of the reasons for the suspension at the time of the notice of the suspension.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Within 5 working days of the notice of suspension, the employee may request in writing that the president or the president's designated representative, in addition to conducting a hearing on the merits, conduct a preliminary hearing to determine whether or not the employee may continue to work with pay pending the disposition of the charges.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The president or the president's designated representative shall conduct a preliminary hearing within 5 working days after the president or the president's designated representative receives in writing the request from the suspended employee for the preliminary hearing.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The preliminary hearing shall be limited to the issues of:<section prefix="(i)">Whether suspension without pay is necessary to protect the interests of the University of Maryland or the employee pending final disposition of the charges; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Whether other employment and status alternatives should be considered.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(5)">At the preliminary hearing, the employee may:<section prefix="(i)">Rebut the reasons given for the suspension;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Allege mitigating circumstances; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Offer alternatives to the suspension, including:</section></section>
      <section prefix="(6)">Within 5 days after the preliminary hearing is completed, the president or the president's designated representative shall render a written decision that is conclusive as to the issue of whether or not the employee may continue to work with pay pending the disposition of the charges.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
