<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ged" order_by="ged" level="1">Economic Development</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ged-7-417</section_number>
  <catch_line>In Caroline County the nurse practitioner, physician assistant, or other appropriate health care pro...</catch_line>
  <order_by>417</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In Caroline County the nurse practitioner, physician assistant, or other appropriate health care provider will be assigned, to the extent practicable, to elementary and middle schools.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The services provided by the nurse practitioner, physician assistant, or other appropriate health care provider shall, to the extent practicable, include:<section prefix="(1)">Assessment of the health status of all targeted students in the selected elementary and middle schools including history, physical examination, neuro-developmental evaluation, and all required early and periodic screening, diagnosis, and treatment programs;</section><section prefix="(2)">Provision of health care including well-child care and treatment of common injuries and illnesses; and</section><section prefix="(3)">Integration of health care with existing health care providers and health education programs directed at students, teachers, and parents.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The nurse practitioner, physician assistant, or other appropriate health care provider shall:<section prefix="(1)">Collaborate with board certified or board eligible pediatricians in the health management of the school children;</section><section prefix="(2)">Concentrate on the early identification, health counseling, and referral for mental health problems, with an emphasis on suicide prevention; and</section><section prefix="(3)">Assess, to the extent possible, whether school health programs could be used as a basis for advising other family members of the student of other sources of primary care.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
