<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="ged" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="16-305" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ged-16-305</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The formula used for the distribution of funds to the community colleges in the State shall be known as the Senator John A. Cade Funding Formula.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Assessed valuation of real property" means assessed valuation of real property as determined for purposes of the State aid calculated under &#xA7; 5-202 of this article.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Board" means:<section prefix="(i)">In a county that has one or more community colleges, the board of community college trustees for the county; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">Where two or more counties establish a region to support a regional community college, the board of regional community college trustees.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">"Community college" means a community college established under this title but does not include Baltimore City Community College.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">"County share" means the total amount of money for operating funds to be provided each fiscal year to a board by the county that supports the community college or colleges or, in the case of a regional community college, the total amount of money for operating funds to be provided each fiscal year to the board by all counties that support the regional community college.</section>
      <section prefix="(6)">"Direct grants" means the sum of the following components of the State share:<section prefix="(i)">Fixed costs;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Marginal costs; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Size factor.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(7)">"Full-time equivalent student" is the quotient of the number of student credit hours produced in the fiscal year 2 years prior to the fiscal year for which the State share is calculated divided by 30, as certified by the Maryland Higher Education Commission.</section>
      <section prefix="(8)">"Population" means population as determined for purposes of calculating the State share of the library program using the definition in &#xA7; 23-501 of this article.</section>
      <section prefix="(9)">"Region" means the counties supporting a regional community college established under Subtitle 2 of this title.</section>
      <section prefix="(10)">"Small community college" means:<section prefix="(i)">Allegany College of Maryland;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Garrett College;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Hagerstown Community College;</section><section prefix="(iv)">Carroll Community College;</section><section prefix="(v)">Cecil Community College;</section><section prefix="(vi)">Chesapeake College; or</section><section prefix="(vii)">Wor-Wic Community College.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(11)">"State share" means the amount of money for community college operating funds to be provided each fiscal year to a board by the State.</section>
      <section prefix="(12)">"Student credit hours" means student credit hours or contact hours which are eligible, under the regulations issued by the Maryland Higher Education Commission, for inclusion in State funding calculations.</section>
      <section prefix="(13)">"Total State operating fund" means the sum of community college State appropriations for direct grants.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The total State operating fund per full-time equivalent student to the community colleges for each fiscal year other than fiscal year 2013, as requested by the Governor shall be:</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">For purposes of this subsection, the State's General Fund appropriation per full-time equivalent student to the 4-year public institutions of higher education in the State for a fiscal year shall include noncapital appropriations from the Higher Education Investment Fund.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">Notwithstanding the provisions of subparagraph (i) of this paragraph, the total State operating funds to be distributed under this subsection to the community colleges for each of fiscal years 2011 and 2012 shall be $194,407,432.</section>
        <section prefix="(iv)">In fiscal year 2013, the total State operating funds for community colleges shall be $199,176,114, to be distributed as follows:</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The State share shall be distributed to each board and shall be limited by the provisions of subsection (d) of this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Subject to subsection (d) of this section, the total State share for each board shall be the sum of:<section prefix="(i)">The fixed costs component;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The marginal costs component;</section><section prefix="(iii)">The size factor component; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">A hold harmless component.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The funds available for the fixed costs component shall be a set percentage of the year's total State operating fund as follows:</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The funds available for the fixed costs component shall be divided and distributed to the community colleges in the same proportion in which the direct grants were distributed in the prior fiscal year.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(5)">
        <section prefix="(i)">For each board, the marginal costs component shall be the product of the dollar amount per full-time equivalent student multiplied by the number of full-time equivalent students at the board's community college or colleges.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The dollar amount per full-time equivalent student shall be calculated by dividing 60% of the total State operating fund for the fiscal year by the total number of full-time equivalent students at community colleges statewide.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">In determining the marginal costs component for a board, the number of full-time equivalent students at all campuses and colleges operated by the board shall be added together.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(6)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The size factor component shall be 2% of the year's total State operating fund.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">Except as provided in subparagraph (iii) of this paragraph, the funds available for the size factor component shall be divided and distributed equally to each board that operates a community college or colleges at which the total number of full-time equivalent students is less than or equal to 80% of the statewide median.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)"/>
        <section prefix="(iv)">In determining the eligibility of a board for a size factor component, the number of full-time equivalent students at all campuses and colleges operated by the board shall be added together.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(7)">
        <section prefix="(i)">A board shall be eligible for a hold harmless component beginning in fiscal year 1998 if the sum of the board's fixed costs, marginal costs, and size factor components for the fiscal year is less than the board's total State share in the prior fiscal year.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The hold harmless component amount shall be determined by subtracting the sum of an eligible board's fixed costs, marginal costs, and size factor components for the fiscal year from the board's total State share for the prior fiscal year.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(8)">Any employer Social Security contributions required by federal law for any employee of a board of community college trustees shall remain the obligation of the employer.</section>
      <section prefix="(9)">The State contribution to retirement and fringe benefit costs is not included in the calculations of amounts under this subsection.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">In each fiscal year, in order for a board to receive an increase in the State share of support, the county share, in the aggregate, that supports the community college or colleges shall equal or exceed the aggregate amount of operating fund appropriations made to the board by the county or all of the counties supporting the college in the previous fiscal year.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Beginning in fiscal year 1996, a grant in the amount provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection shall be distributed to each board in order to provide instruction and services to students enrolled in an English for Speakers of Other Languages ("ESOL") program.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">To qualify for a grant under this subsection, each participant in the program shall be a student:</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Subject to the provisions of subparagraph (ii) of this paragraph, the amount of the grant shall be $800 times the number of qualified full-time equivalent students who are enrolled in a county ESOL program and at the community college.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)"/>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">If the amount that is appropriated to a board under this subsection for any fiscal year is more than the actual cost of providing ESOL programs to students enrolled at the community college in that county or region, the excess funds shall be paid back to the State and credited to the General Fund of the State.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">A board may not transfer State funds received under this subsection to any other program or category.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(4)">Subject to the provisions of paragraph (2) of this subsection, for any fiscal year in which the State appropriation is insufficient to fully fund all grants eligible under this section, the Governor shall include in the budget bill for the following fiscal year a deficiency appropriation to fund all unfunded grants.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Beginning in fiscal year 2003, unrestricted grants in the amounts specified in paragraphs (2) and (3) of this subsection shall be distributed to the board of each small community college.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Subject to paragraph (4) of this subsection, the unrestricted grants shall be distributed as follows:<section prefix="(i)">$500,000 to Allegany College of Maryland;</section><section prefix="(ii)">$500,000 to Garrett College;</section><section prefix="(iii)">$500,000 to Hagerstown Community College;</section><section prefix="(iv)">$250,000 to Carroll Community College;</section><section prefix="(v)">$250,000 to Cecil Community College;</section><section prefix="(vi)">$250,000 to Chesapeake College; and</section><section prefix="(vii)">$250,000 to Wor-Wic Community College.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">In addition to the amounts specified in paragraph (2) of this subsection, the boards of Allegany College of Maryland and Garrett College shall receive the following unrestricted grants:<section prefix="(i)">$360,000 to Allegany College of Maryland; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">$240,000 to Garrett College.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The grant amounts specified in paragraph (2) of this subsection shall increase in fiscal year 2004 and each fiscal year thereafter by the same percentage as the percentage increase in funding per full-time equivalent student to the 4-year public institutions of higher education in the State, as designated by the Commission for the purpose of administering the Joseph A. Sellinger Program under Title 17 of this article in that fiscal year.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
