<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ged" order_by="" level="1">Economic Development</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ged-16-403</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>403</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Board of Community College Trustees for Baltimore County shall:<section prefix="(1)">Establish an orderly procedure for the classified employees of the county community colleges and their representatives to participate in the formulation of labor relations and personnel policies; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Recognize the right of classified employees to organize and bargain collectively through representatives of their own choosing.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Board of Trustees shall adopt rules and regulations that specify with respect to classified employees:<section prefix="(1)">The manner of establishing appropriate collective bargaining units and of designating exclusive bargaining representatives;</section><section prefix="(2)">The rights of the employer, the employees, and the exclusive bargaining representative;</section><section prefix="(3)">The procedure for negotiating a collective bargaining agreement with respect to wages, hours, and working conditions and the manner for resolving any impasse;</section><section prefix="(4)">The right of the exclusive bargaining representative to a checkoff of union dues;</section><section prefix="(5)">The designation of unfair labor practices and remedies for them;</section><section prefix="(6)">The definition of a grievance and the procedure for resolving grievances, which may include binding arbitration of grievances; and</section><section prefix="(7)">Any other matter necessary to carry out the purposes of this section.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">This section does not authorize a strike by any classified employees.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The authority granted by this section, and any procedures, decisions, actions, or agreements made under it, shall expire if a general law on collective bargaining applicable to community colleges becomes effective.</section>
  </text>
</law>
