<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="ged" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="18-1502" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ged-18-1502</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">There is a program of loan assistance repayment known as the Janet L. Hoffman Loan Assistance Repayment Program in the State.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Office of Student Financial Assistance shall assist in the repayment of the amount of any higher education loan owed by an individual who:<section prefix="(1)"><section prefix="(i)">Receives a graduate, professional, or undergraduate degree from:</section><section prefix="(ii)">Receives a Resident Teacher Certificate (RTC) from the Department after completing an alternative teaching preparation program approved by the State Superintendent;</section></section><section prefix="(2)">Obtains eligible employment;</section><section prefix="(3)">Receives an income that is less than the maximum eligible total income levels established by the Office, including any additional sources of income; and</section><section prefix="(4)">Satisfies any other criteria established by the Office.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Subject to the provisions of subsection (b) of this section, the Office shall assist in the repayment of the amount of any higher education loan owed by a public school teacher in the State who:<section prefix="(1)">Has taught in Maryland for at least 2 years:<section prefix="(i)">In science, technology, engineering, or math subjects; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">In a school in which at least 75% of the students are enrolled in the free and reduced lunch program in the State for 2 years; and</section></section><section prefix="(2)">Has received the highest performance evaluation rating for the most recent year available in the county in which the teacher taught (the grant to be known as the Nancy Grasmick Teacher Award).</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A recipient of a Nancy Grasmick Teacher Award shall be known as a Nancy Grasmick Teacher Scholar.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">An applicant for assistance in the repayment of a commercial loan shall demonstrate to the Office that the commercial loan was used for tuition, educational expenses, or living expenses for graduate or undergraduate study.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">Assistance in the repayment of a loan from an entity set forth in &#xA7; 18-1501(c)(2) of this subtitle shall require the approval of the Office.</section>
  </text>
</law>
