<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ged" order_by="ged" level="1">Economic Development</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ged-10-203</section_number>
  <catch_line>It is the goal of the State that public senior higher education institutions be funded at 100 percen...</catch_line>
  <order_by>203</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">It is the goal of the State that public senior higher education institutions be funded at 100 percent of funding guidelines developed by the Maryland Higher Education Commission.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Funding policies shall allocate State resources efficiently while providing incentives for quality and institutional diversity.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Funding proposals for public senior higher education institutions shall include:<section prefix="(1)">Base funding in accordance with the role and mission of the institution, as approved by the Maryland Higher Education Commission;</section><section prefix="(2)">Special initiative funding:<section prefix="(i)">For academic programs at historically African American colleges and universities; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">For the reward of academic innovation and enhancement; and</section></section><section prefix="(3)">Capital funding to support construction, operation, and maintenance of a physical plant that is consistent with each institution's mission.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Funding proposals for regional higher education centers may include:<section prefix="(i)">Ongoing operating support to provide access to affordable postsecondary education in unserved and underserved areas of the State;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Incentive funding to promote collaboration among the institutions of higher education and regional higher education centers; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Capital funding to support construction, operation, and maintenance of a physical plant consistent with the approved mission statement of the center.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Operating funds for each regional higher education center that is administered by the University System of Maryland shall be included in the appropriation of the system office as a separate line item in the Governor's operating budget.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">Student financial aid programs should be developed in order to provide reasonable access to the appropriate academic programs for individuals who exhibit financial need, who are educationally disadvantaged, or who exhibit special merit.</section>
  </text>
</law>
