<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="ged" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="5-306" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ged-5-306</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">This section supplements the provisions of &#xA7;&#xA7; 5-101 through 5-107 of this title and does not supersede or impair those provisions.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Before December 1 of each odd-numbered calendar year, the Montgomery County Board shall prepare and submit to the Montgomery County Executive a 6-year capital improvements program.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The capital improvements program shall include:<section prefix="(1)">A statement of the objectives of the capital programs and the relationship of these programs to the long-range development plans adopted by the county;</section><section prefix="(2)">Recommended capital projects and a proposed construction schedule;</section><section prefix="(3)">An estimate of cost and a statement of all funding sources; and</section><section prefix="(4)">All anticipated capital projects and programs of the county board, including substantial improvements and extensions of projects previously authorized.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The County Executive shall include the 6-year program of the county board, with the recommended revisions and modifications of the County Executive, in the comprehensive 6-year program submitted each even-numbered calendar year to the Montgomery County Council under &#xA7; 302 of the Montgomery County charter.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">On or before adoption of its annual budget and appropriations resolution in each even-numbered calendar year, the County Council shall adopt a 6-year capital improvements program for the county board as a part of the comprehensive 6-year program.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">This 6-year capital improvements program shall be adopted after public hearings on the 6-year programs or capital budgets of the county and other agencies.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">In its adoption, the County Council may make amendments, revisions, and modifications.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The County Council may amend an approved capital improvements program at any time by an affirmative vote of six council members.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">Any amendment, revision, or modification may not become final until it is submitted to the county board for written comment with at least 30 days' notice.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
