<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ged" order_by="ged" level="1">Economic Development</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ged-21-101</section_number>
  <catch_line>There is a county advisory council on career and technology education in each county....</catch_line>
  <order_by>101</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">There is a county advisory council on career and technology education in each county.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The county board shall determine the number of members on the council.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The councils may include educators and administrators in the field of education as ex officio, nonvoting members of the councils.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The county board of education shall appoint the council in any county that does not have an institution of postsecondary education that receives federal support for career and technology education programs.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">In any other county, the county school board and the governing bodies of the institutions of postsecondary education that receive federal support for a career and technology education program shall agree on the procedure for appointment of the council.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The members of the council shall be members of the general public, especially representatives of:<section prefix="(1)">Business;</section><section prefix="(2)">Industry;</section><section prefix="(3)">Organized labor;</section><section prefix="(4)">Each sex;</section><section prefix="(5)">Racial and ethnic minorities; and</section><section prefix="(6)">The geographic regions of the county.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">Each county advisory council shall advise the county board of education and each institution of postsecondary education in the county that receives federal support for a career and technology education program on:<section prefix="(1)">The distribution of career and technology education funds;</section><section prefix="(2)">County career and technology education program accountability reports;</section><section prefix="(3)">County job needs; and</section><section prefix="(4)">The adequacy of career and technology education programs being offered.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
