<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ged" order_by="" level="1">Economic Development</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ged-13-517</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>517</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Automated external defibrillator (AED)" means a medical heart monitor and defibrillator device that:<section prefix="(i)">Is cleared for market by the federal Food and Drug Administration;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Recognizes the presence or absence of ventricular fibrillation or rapid ventricular tachycardia;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Determines, without intervention by an operator, whether defibrillation should be performed;</section><section prefix="(iv)">On determining that defibrillation should be performed, automatically charges; and</section><section prefix="(v)"><section prefix="1.">Requires operator intervention to deliver the electrical impulse; or</section><section prefix="2.">Automatically continues with delivery of electrical impulse.</section></section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Certificate" means a certificate issued by the EMS Board to a registered facility.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">"Facility" means an agency, association, corporation, firm, partnership, or other entity.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">"Jurisdictional emergency medical services operational program" means the institution, agency, corporation, or other entity that has been approved by the EMS Board to provide oversight of emergency medical services for each of the local government and State and federal emergency medical services programs.</section>
      <section prefix="(6)">"Program" means the Public Access Automated External Defibrillator Program.</section>
      <section prefix="(7)">"Regional administrator" means the individual employed by the Institute as regional administrator in each EMS region.</section>
      <section prefix="(8)">"Regional council" means an EMS advisory body as created by the Code of Maryland Regulations 30.05.</section>
      <section prefix="(9)">"Regional council AED committee" means a committee appointed by the regional council consisting of:<section prefix="(i)">The regional medical director;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The regional administrator; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Three or more individuals with knowledge of and expertise in AEDs.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(10)">"Registered facility" means an organization, business association, agency, or other entity that meets the requirements of the EMS Board for registering with the Program.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">There is a Public Access Automated External Defibrillator Program.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The purpose of the Program is to coordinate an effective statewide public access defibrillation program.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Program shall be administered by the EMS Board.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The EMS Board may:<section prefix="(1)">Adopt regulations for the administration of the Program;</section><section prefix="(2)">Issue and renew certificates to facilities that meet the requirements of this section;</section><section prefix="(3)">Deny, suspend, revoke, or refuse to renew the certificate of a registered facility for failure to meet the requirements of this section;</section><section prefix="(4)">Approve educational and training programs required under this section that:<section prefix="(i)">Are conducted by any private or public entity;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Include training in cardiopulmonary resuscitation and automated external defibrillation; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">May include courses from nationally recognized entities such as the American Heart Association, the American Red Cross, and the National Safety Council;</section></section><section prefix="(5)">Approve the protocol for the use of an AED; and</section><section prefix="(6)">Delegate to the Institute any portion of its authority under this section.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Each facility that desires to make automated external defibrillation available shall possess a valid certificate from the EMS Board.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">This subsection does not apply to:<section prefix="(i)">A jurisdictional emergency medical services operational program;</section><section prefix="(ii)">A licensed commercial ambulance service;</section><section prefix="(iii)">A health care facility as defined in &#xA7; 19-114 of the Health - General Article; or</section><section prefix="(iv)">A place of business for health care practitioners who are licensed as dentists under Title 4 of the Health Occupations Article or as physicians under Title 14 of the Health Occupations Article and are authorized to use an AED in accordance with that license.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">To qualify for a certificate a facility shall:<section prefix="(1)">Comply with the written protocol approved by the EMS Board for the use of an AED which includes notification of the emergency medical services system through the use of the 911 universal emergency access number as soon as possible on the use of an AED;</section><section prefix="(2)">Have established automated external defibrillator maintenance, placement, operation, reporting, and quality improvement procedures as required by the EMS Board;</section><section prefix="(3)">Maintain each AED and all related equipment and supplies in accordance with the standards established by the device manufacturer and the federal Food and Drug Administration; and</section><section prefix="(4)">Ensure that each individual who is expected to operate an AED for the registered facility has successfully completed an educational training course and refresher training as required by the EMS Board.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">A registered facility shall report the use of an AED to the Institute for review by the regional council AED committee.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">A facility that desires to establish or renew a certificate shall:<section prefix="(1)">Submit an application on the form that the EMS Board requires; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Meet the requirements under this section.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(h)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The EMS Board shall issue a new or a renewed certificate to a facility that meets the requirements of this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Each certificate shall include:<section prefix="(i)">The type of certificate;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The full name and address of the facility;</section><section prefix="(iii)">A unique identification number; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">The dates of issuance and expiration of the certificate.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A certificate is valid for 3 years.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(i)">The EMS Board may issue a cease and desist order or obtain injunctive relief if a facility makes automated external defibrillation available in violation of this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(j)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In addition to any other immunities available under statutory or common law, a registered facility is not civilly liable for any act or omission in the provision of automated external defibrillation if the registered facility:<section prefix="(i)">Has satisfied the requirements for making automated external defibrillation available under this section; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Possesses a valid certificate at the time of the act or omission.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">In addition to any other immunities available under statutory or common law, a member of the regional council AED committee is not civilly liable for any act or omission in the provision of automated external defibrillation.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">In addition to any other immunities available under statutory or common law, an individual is not civilly liable for any act or omission if:<section prefix="(i)">The individual is acting in good faith while rendering automated external defibrillation to a person who is a victim or reasonably believed by the individual to be a victim of a sudden cardiac arrest;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The assistance or aid is provided in a reasonably prudent manner; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">The automated external defibrillation is provided without fee or other compensation.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The immunities in this subsection are not available if the conduct of the registered facility or an individual amounts to gross negligence, willful or wanton misconduct, or intentionally tortious conduct.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">This subsection does not affect, and may not be construed as affecting, any immunities from civil or criminal liability or defenses established by any other provision of the Code or by common law to which a registered facility, a member of the regional council AED committee, or an individual may be entitled.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(k)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A registered facility aggrieved by a decision of the Institute acting under the delegated authority of the EMS Board under this section shall be afforded an opportunity for a hearing before the EMS Board.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A registered facility aggrieved by a decision of the EMS Board under this section shall be afforded an opportunity for a hearing in accordance with Title 10, Subtitle 2 of the State Government Article.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
