<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="ged" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="7-1001" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ged-7-1001</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">There is a Maryland Technology Academy in the Department.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The purpose of the Academy is to:<section prefix="(1)">Provide intensive learning opportunities for teachers in the State each year on how to use technology to significantly impact student learning; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Promote the overall improvement of public schools in the State.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Under the direction and supervision of the Department, the Academy shall arrange for the conducting of 3- to 5-week summer sessions each year for elementary, middle, and high school teachers in the State.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The summer sessions shall utilize an intensive curriculum in technology that is structured in such a manner to require the participating teachers to:<section prefix="(1)">Examine and discuss technological research and engage in practicing the use of technology in the classroom and school setting;</section><section prefix="(2)">Participate in and critique demonstrations of the use of technology;</section><section prefix="(3)">Prepare and present a technology-based project in an area of interest; and</section><section prefix="(4)">Develop an understanding and knowledge of how to collect and analyze student data to determine effective uses of technology and how the use of technology impacts student learning.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The Academy shall organize the summer sessions on the basis of:<section prefix="(1)">Creating participant teams of elementary, middle, and high school teachers as well as instructors from colleges of education; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Utilizing instructors from institutions of higher education as well as teacher experts, national experts, and outside consultants.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The Academy shall provide opportunities for teachers, after their completion of a summer session, to continue to learn about the uses and impact of technology in the classroom through the establishment of appropriate conferences, study groups, distance-learning activities, and peer coaching sessions.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">The Department shall establish guidelines for the application and selection of participants in the Academy and any other appropriate matter to implement the provisions of this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">Funds for the Academy shall be as provided in the annual budget of the Department.</section>
  </text>
</law>
