<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="ged" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="16-312" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ged-16-312</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Bonus points" means established bonus or percentage points used during the bid evaluation process to adjust the bid price submitted by minority business enterprises for the purpose of ascertaining the lowest bidder.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Mandatory set-asides" means a procedure designating a certain percentage of total contract dollars for award to minority business enterprises.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">"Mandatory subcontracting" means a procedure mandating that a certain percentage of the dollar amount of designated contracts be subcontracted to minority business enterprises.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">"Minority business enterprise" means any business enterprise:<section prefix="(i)"/><section prefix="(ii)">Whose management and daily business operations are controlled by 1 or more minority individuals.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(6)">"Percentage points" means established percentage points given for minority business enterprise participation in a sealed proposal process.</section>
      <section prefix="(7)">"Restrictive bidding" means competitive bidding of designated contracts that are restricted to minority business enterprises.</section>
      <section prefix="(8)">"Restrictive price quotations" means negotiated small procurements that are restricted to minority business enterprises.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Board of Trustees of the Prince George's Community College shall undertake and complete an internal and market fact-finding process by January 1, 1990, to assess the appropriate scope of a minority business enterprise program for the Board. The results of the fact-finding process, including statistical data, supporting documentation, and reports, shall be reported to the Prince George's County Delegation of the General Assembly by January 31, 1990.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">If the fact-finding required by subsection (b) of this section demonstrates a compelling governmental interest to adopt a remedial minority business enterprise program, the Board of Trustees, by resolution and by implementing rules and regulations, shall establish a minority business enterprise program to facilitate the participation of certified minority business enterprises in contracts awarded by the Board. The program shall include specific goals and the definition of "minority individual".</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">In establishing a minority business enterprise program, the Board of Trustees is authorized to use incentives to achieve the designated goals of the program, including but not limited to:<section prefix="(1)">Mandatory set-aside procedures;</section><section prefix="(2)">Mandatory subcontracting procedures with reasonable waiver provisions;</section><section prefix="(3)">The application of bonus points;</section><section prefix="(4)">The application of percentage points;</section><section prefix="(5)">Restrictive bidding;</section><section prefix="(6)">Restrictive price quotations;</section><section prefix="(7)">The reduction or waiver of bonding requirements; and</section><section prefix="(8)">Incentives to encourage maximum participation by:<section prefix="(i)">Small businesses;</section><section prefix="(ii)">A variety of different businesses; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Businesses located within Prince George's County.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Board of Trustees may appoint a minority business enterprise officer to administer any minority business enterprise program established, who shall submit reports to the Board of Trustees.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">It is the responsibility of the minority business enterprise officer to conduct outreach programs to assist the minority business enterprise community in participating in any minority business enterprise program established under this section.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The Board of Trustees shall advise the Prince George's County Delegation of the General Assembly regarding the substance of any minority business enterprise program that it establishes.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The program shall be evaluated every 2 years.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The results of any evaluation under this subsection shall be submitted to the Prince George's County Delegation of the General Assembly.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
