<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="ged" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="13-514" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ged-13-514</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The R Adams Cowley Shock Trauma Center is the primary adult clinical resource center for the State Emergency Medical Services Systems.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The chief administrative officer of the Center is the Director who:<section prefix="(1)">Shall be appointed by the Board of Directors of the Medical System Corporation, subject to the approval of the Governor or the passage of 60 days from the date of the appointment, whichever occurs first; and</section><section prefix="(2)">May not hold concurrently the position of Executive Director of the Institute.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Director of the Center shall:<section prefix="(1)">Report through the Medical System Corporation Chief Executive Officer to the Board of Directors;</section><section prefix="(2)">Provide a monthly report to the Board of Directors and the EMS Board on the overall progress of programs;</section><section prefix="(3)">Render reports to appropriate committees of the Board of Directors; and</section><section prefix="(4)">Develop the budget and, after approval of the Medical System Corporation Chief Executive Officer, present the budget to the EMS Board for review and comment and through the appropriate committees of the Board of Directors for approval by the Board of Directors.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Director of the Center shall:<section prefix="(1)">Advise and provide the opportunity for the EMS Board to comment prior to the adoption of any proposed change in the budget, services, mission, or other policies of the Center that would affect the ability of the Center to continue to fulfill its mission as the statewide primary adult clinical resource for emergency medical services; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Submit to the EMS Board an annual report on the budget and on the operations of the Center.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
