<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ged" order_by="ged" level="1">Economic Development</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ged-5-402</section_number>
  <catch_line>Subject to paragraph (2) of this subsection, the Department shall  evaluate the effect of increased ...</catch_line>
  <order_by>402</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Subject to paragraph (2) of this subsection, the Department shall  evaluate the effect of increased State aid for education on student and school  performance in each local school system.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Department may contract with a public or private entity to  conduct or assist in conducting the evaluation required by this subsection.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Department shall submit an initial report on the results of the  evaluation required by this section to the Governor and, subject to &#xA7; 2-1246 of the  State Government Article, the General Assembly on or before December 31, 2006.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Department shall submit an interim report on the results of the evaluation required by this section to the Governor and, subject to &#xA7; 2-1246 of the State Government Article, the General Assembly on or before December 31, 2007.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Department shall submit a final report on the results of the evaluation required by this section to the Governor and, subject to &#xA7; 2-1246 of the  State Government Article, the General Assembly on or before December 31, 2008.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The reports required by this section shall include:<section prefix="(1)">A detailed description of how local school systems are using State  education aid;</section><section prefix="(2)">A comparison of school systems that show significant  improvements in student and school performance to school systems that do not show  significant improvements in student and school performance;</section><section prefix="(3)">An assessment of the extent to which county boards are successful  in implementing the comprehensive master plans required by &#xA7; 5-401 of this subtitle;</section><section prefix="(4)">An analysis of the amount of funding that local governments  provide for education each year;</section><section prefix="(5)">A list of programs or factors that consistently produce positive  results for students, schools, and school systems; and</section><section prefix="(6)">Any other information that the State Superintendent determines  to be relevant to the evaluation of student and school performance in each local school  system.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Governor shall include an appropriation for the Department in the  State budget for each fiscal year sufficient to cover the costs associated with  implementing this section.</section>
  </text>
</law>
