<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="ged" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="8-501" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ged-8-501</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Child in State-supervised care" means a child who is in the custody of, committed to, or otherwise placed by a placement agency.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Child in State-supervised care" does not mean a child at the Charles H. Hickey, Jr. School in Baltimore County who receives an educational program under &#xA7; 22-308 of this article.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Noncollegiate educational institution" has the meaning stated in &#xA7; 2-206 of this article.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">"Notice" means that written, verbal, or other communication regarding the identification of a child in State-supervised care has been effectuated.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"Placement agency" means:<section prefix="(1)">A local department of social services;</section><section prefix="(2)">The Department of Health and Mental Hygiene;</section><section prefix="(3)">The Department of Juvenile Services; or</section><section prefix="(4)">A private agency that:<section prefix="(i)">Engages in the placement of children in homes or with individuals; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Is licensed by the Social Services Administration under &#xA7; 5-507 of the Family Law Article.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">"Receiving school" means a public school or a noncollegiate educational institution affiliated with a residential child care program or treatment facility that has an educational program approved by the Department in which a child in State-supervised care is newly enrolled or seeks to enroll.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">"Sending school" means a public school or a noncollegiate educational institution affiliated with a residential child care program or treatment facility that has an educational program approved by the Department in which a child in State-supervised care was enrolled prior to enrolling, or seeking to enroll, in a receiving school.</section>
  </text>
</law>
