<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ged" order_by="ged" level="1">Economic Development</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ged-4-303</section_number>
  <catch_line>In order to establish a new partnership between the City of Baltimore and the State to improve the q...</catch_line>
  <order_by>303</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In order to establish a new partnership between the City of Baltimore and the State to improve the quality of public education in Baltimore City and to encourage more efficient use of the resources of the State and Baltimore City, the Baltimore City Board of School Commissioners is established in accordance with the provisions of this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The purpose of the board is to:<section prefix="(1)">Raise the level of academic achievement of the students in the Baltimore City Public School System; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Improve the management and administration of the public school system in Baltimore City.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The board shall be held accountable for the academic achievement of the public school students in Baltimore City.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The board shall have the authority and be responsible for all functions relating to the Baltimore City Public School System.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Notwithstanding any provision of local law governing the Baltimore City Public School System, the board may adopt rules and regulations and prescribe policies and procedures for the management, maintenance, operation, and control of the Baltimore City Public School System.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The board shall assume responsibility for all of the functions formerly performed by the Superintendent of Public Instruction of Baltimore City and the Board of School Commissioners of Baltimore City.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The board may not be deemed an agency of the State.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
