<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="ged" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="9-104" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ged-9-104</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">An application to establish a public charter school shall be submitted to the county board of the county in which the charter school will be located.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">An application to establish a public charter school may be submitted to a county board by:<section prefix="(i)">The staff of a public school;</section><section prefix="(ii)">A parent or guardian of a student who attends a public school in the county;</section><section prefix="(iii)">A nonsectarian nonprofit entity;</section><section prefix="(iv)">A nonsectarian institution of higher education in the State; or</section><section prefix="(v)">Any combination of persons specified in items (i) through (iv) of this paragraph.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A public chartering authority may not grant a charter under this title to:<section prefix="(i)">A private school;</section><section prefix="(ii)">A parochial school; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">A home school.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Except as provided in subparagraph (ii) of this paragraph, the county board shall review the application and render a decision within 120 days of receipt of the application.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">For a restructured school:</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If the county board denies an application to establish a public charter school, the applicant may appeal the decision to the State Board, in accordance with &#xA7; 4-205(c) of this article.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The State Board shall render a decision within 120 days of the filing of an appeal under this subsection.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">If the county board denies an application to establish a public charter school and the State Board reverses the decision, the State Board may direct the county board to grant a charter and shall mediate with the county board and the applicant to implement the charter.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
