<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ged" order_by="ged" level="1">Economic Development</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ged-7-203.2</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this section the following words have the meanings indicated....</catch_line>
  <order_by>203.2</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">"Four-year adjusted cohort" means a group of students who are entering the ninth grade for the first time from a cohort that is subsequently adjusted by adding any students who transfer into the cohort later during the ninth grade and the next three years and subtracting any students who transfer out, emigrate to another country, or die during that same period.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">"Four-year adjusted cohort" also includes students retained in grade and only counted once as members of their original cohort.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Graduation rate" means the percentage obtained from applying the graduation rate formula.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">
        <section prefix="(i)">"Graduation rate formula" means the number of students who graduate on time with a Maryland high school diploma divided by the number of students in the four-year adjusted cohort.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">"Graduation rate formula" does not include students who graduate on time with a GED or other certificate not aligned with State standards.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(5)">
        <section prefix="(i)">"On time" means on or before the conclusion of a four-year adjusted cohort's fourth year of high school.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">"On time" includes a senior summer session in a jurisdiction that offers senior summer sessions.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(6)">
        <section prefix="(i)">"Transfer out" means a student who the county board confirms, via written documentation, has enrolled in another high school or other educational program from which that student is expected to receive a Maryland high school diploma.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">"Transfer out" does not include a student enrolled in:<section prefix="1.">A GED program; or</section><section prefix="2.">An alternative education program that does not issue or provide credits toward a Maryland high school diploma.</section></section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The purpose of this section is to:<section prefix="(1)">Initiate a process by which the State may achieve the goal of collecting, maintaining, analyzing, and publicly reporting data relating to the graduation rates of students in public high schools as an essential step in addressing gaps in educational achievement among a diverse student population; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Explicitly delineate the duties and responsibilities of the Department and the county boards in this regard.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Beginning on or before September 1, 2011, and each year thereafter, a county board shall:<section prefix="(i)">Collect, maintain, and analyze graduation rates for public schools, local school systems, and the State; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Report the information required under item (i) of this paragraph to the public and the Department in the aggregate and disaggregated by:<section prefix="1.">Hispanic or Latino of any race;</section><section prefix="2.">For individuals who are nonHispanic or nonLatino only:</section><section prefix="3.">Students who are limited English proficient;</section><section prefix="4.">Students who receive free and reduced priced meals; and</section><section prefix="5.">Students who receive special education services.</section></section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Beginning on or before October 1, 2011, and each year thereafter, the Department shall:<section prefix="(i)">Compile the information received under paragraph (1) of this subsection and calculate a graduation rate for the State; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Post the information obtained under this subsection for each county on its website in the aggregate and disaggregated by:<section prefix="1.">Hispanic or Latino of any race;</section><section prefix="2.">For individuals who are nonHispanic or nonLatino only:</section><section prefix="3.">Students who are limited English proficient;</section><section prefix="4.">Students who receive free and reduced priced meals; and</section><section prefix="5.">Students who receive special education services.</section></section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The county boards and the Department may develop and implement additional indicators to collect, maintain, analyze, and publicly report data regarding alternative high school completions.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Department shall ensure that the information collected under paragraph (1) of this subsection is comparable for public schools and local school systems in the State.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The Department shall:<section prefix="(1)">Implement training for administrators and other personnel responsible for collecting, maintaining, analyzing, and publicly reporting data regarding four-year adjusted cohorts and graduation rates;</section><section prefix="(2)">Implement a standard process for verifying the accuracy of data including:<section prefix="(i)">Statistical checks and analyses; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">On-site audits of record-keeping procedures;</section></section><section prefix="(3)">Implement a public awareness campaign including outreach to civic associations, community-based groups, and parent organizations and the solicitation of suggestions and community support regarding the need for collecting, maintaining, analyzing, and publicly reporting accurate data regarding four-year adjusted cohorts and graduation rates;</section><section prefix="(4)">Provide technical support to the county boards with collecting, maintaining, analyzing, and publicly reporting graduation rate data; and</section><section prefix="(5)">Serve as a central repository for this data.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
