<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="ged" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="11-903" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ged-11-903</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">On the request of an eligible blind or print disabled student, the Library shall request that a publisher that offers for sale electronic or print instructional materials used by students enrolled in institutions of higher education in the State provide the instructional materials to the Library in an electronic format.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Except as otherwise provided in this subtitle, on or after January 1, 2008, on the receipt of a request under subsection (a) of this section, a publisher shall have 15 business days from the date of the request to:<section prefix="(1)">Provide the requested instructional materials in an electronic format; or</section><section prefix="(2)">Provide the reason that an electronic format cannot be provided within 15 business days.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Except as provided in subsection (d) of this section, if a publisher responds under subsection (b)(2) of this section that an electronic format cannot be provided within 15 business days, the publisher shall indicate to the Library:<section prefix="(1)">When the instructional materials will be provided in an electronic format; or</section><section prefix="(2)">The specific reason, consistent with the guidelines established under &#xA7; 11-902(g) of this subtitle, why the instructional materials may not be provided to the Library within the required time frame.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A publisher is not required to provide instructional materials in an electronic format if the instructional materials were:<section prefix="(1)">Generated by faculty; or</section><section prefix="(2)">Copyrighted before July 1, 2004.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
