<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ged" order_by="" level="1">Economic Development</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ged-23-503</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>503</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The entire capital and operating cost of the minimum library program for this State as a whole shall be shared as provided in this subsection.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The State shall provide:<section prefix="(i)">Approximately 40 percent of the total cost of the minimum program; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Not less than 20 percent of the cost of the minimum program in any county.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The counties participating in the program together shall provide through local taxes approximately 60 percent of the total statewide cost of the minimum program.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Each county public library system that participates in the minimum library program shall be provided for each resident of the county, to be used for operating and capital expenses:<section prefix="(i)">For each of fiscal years 2011 through 2016 - $14.00;</section><section prefix="(ii)">For fiscal year 2017 - $14.30;</section><section prefix="(iii)">For fiscal year 2018 - $14.60; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">For fiscal year 2019 and each fiscal year thereafter - $15.00.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The State shall share in this amount.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">Any county may provide an amount greater than its share under the cooperative program, but the State may not share in the excess.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Any employer Social Security contributions required by federal law for any employee in a county public library system shall remain the obligation of the employer.</section>
  </text>
</law>
