<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ged" order_by="ged" level="1">Economic Development</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ged-11-901</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated....</catch_line>
  <order_by>901</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Committee" means the Instructional Materials Access Guidelines Committee.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Instructional material" means textbooks and other materials written and published primarily for use by students in  postsecondary instruction that are required or essential to a student's success in a course of study in which a student with a disability is enrolled.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Instructional material" does not include materials for which software is not commercially available at a reasonable  price to permit the conversion of existing electronic files of the  materials into a format that is compatible with braille translation software or alternative media for students with disabilities, including mathematics and science materials.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">"Library" means the Maryland Library for the Blind and Physically Handicapped.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"Printed instructional material" means instructional material in book or other printed form.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Structural integrity" means material composed of all of the textual printed instructional material.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Structural integrity" includes the text of the material, sidebars, the table of contents, chapter headings and subheadings, footnotes, indexes, glossaries, and bibliographies.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Structural integrity" does not include material composed of nontextual elements such as pictures, illustrations, graphs, or charts.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
