<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ged" order_by="ged" level="1">Economic Development</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ged-11-202.2</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated....</catch_line>
  <order_by>202.2</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Distance education" means course work taught by an institution of postsecondary education through electronic distribution of instruction to a site other than the principal location of the institution and advertised or described as leading to the formal award of a certificate or degree.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Fully online distance education program in the State" means a program in which:<section prefix="(i)">100% of the program is offered through electronic distribution of instruction to one or more sites other than the principal location of an institution; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">51% or more of the program is offered through electronic distribution of instruction to one or more sites other than the principal location of an institution and the Commission has determined that the portion of the program offered at a location in the State, if any, does not require a certificate of approval for the institution to operate, do business, or function in the State.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in paragraphs (2) and (3) of this subsection, an institution of postsecondary education that enrolls Maryland students in a fully online distance education program in the State shall file an application to register with the Commission within 3 months of enrollment.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">This section does not apply to an institution of postsecondary education that enrolls Maryland students in a fully online distance education program in the State that has been approved or received a favorable recommendation by the Commission under &#xA7; 11-206 or &#xA7; 11-206.1 of this subtitle.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Notwithstanding the requirements of &#xA7; 11-202(c-1) of this subtitle, an institution that has enrolled Maryland students before obtaining registration under this section may continue to operate without a registration while the Commission considers the institution's application, conducts a hearing concerning the institution's application, or participates in judicial review regarding an institution's application.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">An institution that continues to operate without a registration under subparagraph (i) of this paragraph shall furnish a performance bond or other form of financial guarantee to the State in an amount set by regulation that is in addition to and separate from a performance bond or other form of financial guarantee required under &#xA7; 11-203 of this subtitle.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Each institution required to register under subsection (b) of this section shall:<section prefix="(1)">Be accredited by an accrediting body recognized and approved by the United States Department of Education;</section><section prefix="(2)">Submit to the Commission:<section prefix="(i)">Every 2 years, a financial statement reviewed by an independent accountant retained by the institution;</section><section prefix="(ii)">An affidavit from the president or chief executive officer of the institution affirming:<section prefix="1.">That the institution has not filed for bankruptcy protection under Title 11 of the United States Code during its existence; and</section><section prefix="2.">The willingness of the president or the chief executive officer to abide by the provisions of this section;</section></section><section prefix="(iii)">Proof of good business standing in the state in which the central administration of the institution is incorporated; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">Proof of good academic standing submitted by:<section prefix="1.">The regulatory higher education entity in the state in which the central administration of the institution is located; or</section><section prefix="2.">If the state in which the institution is located does not have a regulatory higher education entity, the accrediting body that accredited the institution;</section></section></section><section prefix="(3)">Promptly notify the Commission of a change in ownership or a change in majority control;</section><section prefix="(4)">Comply with the Principles of Good Practice for distance education established by the Commission through regulation;</section><section prefix="(5)">Make public and post on the institution's Web site:<section prefix="(i)">Whether the institution is registered in Maryland; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">The process by which to make complaints against the institution;</section></section><section prefix="(6)">Comply with the refund policy and procedures established by the Commission; and</section><section prefix="(7)">Be subject to complaint investigation by the Office of the Attorney General or the Commission or both.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The refund policy and procedures established by the Commission shall allow for:<section prefix="(1)"><section prefix="(i)">At least 2 weeks of required orientation or preenrollment instruction in a fully online distance education program in the State at no charge for a student who has completed less than 24 credits of college-level learning from an accredited institution; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">A prorated refund methodology that provides a refund to any student not covered by item (i) of this paragraph who has completed 60% or less of a course, term, or program within the applicable billing period; or</section></section><section prefix="(2)">A prorated refund methodology that provides a refund to any student who has completed 60% or less of a course, term, or program within the applicable billing period.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Subject to paragraph (2) of this subsection, the Commission shall require the payment of a fee set by regulation, as a condition of registration.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The fees charged shall be:<section prefix="(i)">A fixed amount for all institutions regardless of type, location, or student enrollment; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Set to cover the approximate cost of implementing a system of registration.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The Commission shall make public and post on its Web site:<section prefix="(1)">A list of registered institutions of postsecondary education that offer fully online distance education programs in the State; and</section><section prefix="(2)">If the Commission denies or revokes the registration of an institution, the name of the denied or revoked institution.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(g)">On or before December 1 each year, the Commission shall report to the Governor and, in accordance with &#xA7; 2-1246 of the State Government Article, the General Assembly:<section prefix="(1)">The number of institutions of postsecondary education that apply for registration under this section;</section><section prefix="(2)">The type and size of the institutions that apply;</section><section prefix="(3)">The number of institutions approved for registration;</section><section prefix="(4)">The number of institutions denied registration; and</section><section prefix="(5)">The number of Maryland students enrolled in institutions required to register under this section.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
