<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="ged" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="18-1803" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ged-18-1803</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">A grant may be awarded under this subtitle to:<section prefix="(1)">An employer or consortium of employers;</section><section prefix="(2)">An industrial trade association;</section><section prefix="(3)">A trade union;</section><section prefix="(4)">A registered apprenticeship sponsor; or</section><section prefix="(5)">A combination of the entities specified in items (1) through (4) of this subsection.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A grant recipient shall use the grant in an apprenticeship training program that is:<section prefix="(1)">A registered apprenticeship program approved by the Apprenticeship and Training Council within the Department of Labor, Licensing, and Regulation;</section><section prefix="(2)">A youth apprenticeship program approved by the State Superintendent of Schools that involves students attending the public schools of the State; or</section><section prefix="(3)">A youth apprenticeship program approved by the Secretary of Juvenile Services that involves clients of the Department of Juvenile Services.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Secretary of Labor, Licensing, and Regulation may ensure that the youth apprenticeship programs approved under this subtitle:<section prefix="(1)">Foster the expansion of structured, school-to-work transition programs that link secondary school applied learning experiences with:<section prefix="(i)">Skilled, high wage, workplace jobs and professions; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Postsecondary technical and occupational work experiences;</section></section><section prefix="(2)">Foster enrollment in apprenticeship programs that target youth, including general education degree recipients;</section><section prefix="(3)">Foster enrollment of inexperienced, unskilled, first time hires in long-term programs leading to a credential in emerging, technology based occupations that are projected as high growth areas in the State economy; and</section><section prefix="(4)">Support the development of competency based instructional programs that encompass secondary and postsecondary institutions and are based on specific skill standards that are identified by the industry through accepted models.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
