<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ged" order_by="" level="1">Economic Development</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ged-5-115</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>115</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">"Payee" means any party who receives from the Montgomery County Board of Education an aggregate payment of $25,000 in a fiscal year.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">"Payee" does not include:<section prefix="1.">A Montgomery County public school employee with respect to the employee's compensation; or</section><section prefix="2.">A Montgomery County public school retiree with respect to the retiree's retirement allowance.</section></section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Searchable website" means a website created in accordance with this section that displays and searches payment data of the Montgomery County Board of Education.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">On or before January 1, 2011, the  Montgomery County Board of Education shall develop and operate a single searchable website accessible to the public at no cost through the Internet.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The searchable website shall contain Montgomery County Board of Education payment data including:<section prefix="(1)">The name of a payee receiving a payment;		</section><section prefix="(2)">The location of a payee by postal zip code; and</section><section prefix="(3)">The amount of a payment.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The searchable website shall allow the user to:<section prefix="(1)">Search data for fiscal year 2010 and each year thereafter; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Search by the following data fields:<section prefix="(i)">A payee receiving a payment; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">The zip code of a payee receiving a payment.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">This section may not be construed to require the disclosure of information that is confidential under federal, State, or local law.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">This section shall be known and may be cited as the "Montgomery County Public Schools Funding Accountability and Transparency Act".</section>
  </text>
</law>
