<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ged" order_by="" level="1">Economic Development</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ged-24-304</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>304</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In addition to the other powers expressly granted and duties imposed by this title, and subject to the authority of the Commission, the Board has only the powers and duties set forth in this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Board shall:<section prefix="(1)">Exercise general control over the Center;</section><section prefix="(2)">Keep separate records and minutes; and</section><section prefix="(3)">Adopt reasonable rules, regulations, or bylaws to carry out the provisions of this subtitle.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Board may fix the salaries and terms of employment of the Director and other employees of the Center.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Board may purchase, lease, or otherwise acquire any property it considers necessary for the operation of the Center, with the approval of the St. Mary's County Board of County Commissioners.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Board may sell, lease, or otherwise dispose of Center assets or property, with the approval of the St. Mary's County Board of County Commissioners.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Director of the Center or the chair of the Board may execute a conveyance or other legal document under an appropriate resolution of the Board.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The Board shall ensure that all academic programs and policies of the Center are in compliance with the policies of and approved by the Commission.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">The Board shall submit an adopted mission statement to the Commission subject to the policies and guidelines of the Commission.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">The Board may enter into contracts or other agreements with any institution of higher education for the provision of upper division undergraduate and graduate programs to meet the higher education needs of Southern Maryland, subject to the approval of the Commission.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">The Board may apply, accept, and expend any gift, appropriation, or grant from the State, county, or federal government or any other person.</section>
    <section prefix="(j)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Board shall ensure that the tuition and fees charged to students by any participating institutions are reasonable.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Board may also charge reasonable fees to cover the overhead costs associated with providing these programs.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(k)">The Board may sue and be sued.</section>
    <section prefix="(l)">The Board may make agreements with the federal, State, or county governments or any other person, if it considers the agreement advisable for the operation of the Center.</section>
    <section prefix="(m)">The Board may adopt a corporate seal.</section>
    <section prefix="(n)">In addition to other reports that may be required by the Commission, the Board shall:<section prefix="(1)">Keep records that are consistent with sound business practices and accounting records using generally accepted accounting principles;</section><section prefix="(2)">Cause an audit by an independent certified public accountant to be made of the accounts and transactions of the Center at the conclusion of each fiscal year; and</section><section prefix="(3)">For any State moneys, be subject to an audit by the Office of Legislative Audits, in accordance with &#xA7;&#xA7; 2-1220 through 2-1227 of the State Government Article.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(o)">The Board shall enter into an agreement with St. Mary's County to establish guidelines for the use and operation of the Center.</section>
  </text>
</law>
