<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ged" order_by="ged" level="1">Economic Development</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ged-6-201</section_number>
  <catch_line>The county board shall employ individuals in the positions that the county board considers necessary...</catch_line>
  <order_by>201</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The county board shall employ individuals in the positions that the county board considers necessary for the operation of the public schools in the county.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The county superintendent shall nominate for appointment by the county board:<section prefix="(i)">All professional assistants of the office of county superintendent; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">All principals, teachers, and other certificated personnel.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">As to these personnel, the county superintendent shall:<section prefix="(i)">Assign them to their positions in the schools;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Transfer them as the needs of the schools require;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Recommend them for promotion; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">Suspend them for cause and recommend them for dismissal in accordance with &#xA7; 6-202 of this subtitle.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except in Worcester County and Baltimore City, the county superintendent shall appoint clerical and other nonprofessional personnel.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">In Worcester County, the County Superintendent shall appoint clerical and other nonprofessional personnel with the advice and consent of the county board.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Notwithstanding any provision of local law, in Baltimore City, the appointment, tenure, and compensation of clerical and other nonprofessional personnel shall be determined in accordance with the personnel system established by the Baltimore City Board of School Commissioners under &#xA7; 4-311 of this article.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Supervisory and administrative personnel shall be appointed in each county in accordance with ratios established by the rules and regulations of the State Board and within the ratio established under &#xA7; 2-205(m) of this article.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">These personnel shall include:<section prefix="(i)">Supervising or helping teachers;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Supervisors of pupil personnel I;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Supervisors of pupil personnel II; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">Visiting teachers.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">An individual may not be appointed as a professional assistant or to any position listed in subsection (d) of this section unless he holds the appropriate certificate from the State Superintendent issued in accordance with the rules and regulations of the State Board.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">Subject to the provisions of this article, the qualifications, tenure, and compensation of each appointee shall be determined by the county board.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">The county superintendent shall see that each regular appointee of the county board devotes his entire time to his duties.</section>
  </text>
</law>
