<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="ged" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="24-204" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ged-24-204</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Commission annually shall prepare a budget request to provide funds to perform its duties under this subtitle.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Commission may receive and spend any grant or gift budgeted or provided for it.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The Commission is encouraged to make use of its facilities, equipment, and other resources to provide services that may generate additional income. Any income earned in that manner shall be considered special funds for use by the Commission.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">Unexpended funds may be carried forward and expended in any subsequent fiscal year, subject to the approval of the Board of Public Works.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Commission shall appoint a President who shall serve as chief executive officer for the Commission.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The President serves at the pleasure of the Commission and is entitled to the compensation established by the Commission.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The President shall direct the staff of the Commission and carry out the policies and duties established by the Commission.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The secretarial, stenographic, clerical, and custodial employees of the Commission are in the skilled service, with the exception of special appointments, in the State Personnel Management System.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">All other employees of the Commission are in the executive service, management service, or are special appointments in the State Personnel Management System.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Notwithstanding &#xA7; 4-201 of the State Personnel and Pensions Article, the Commission shall fix the compensation of the executive service, management service, and special appointment employees:<section prefix="(i)">Upon the recommendation of the President; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">When possible, in accordance with the State pay plan.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">
        <section prefix="(i)">At least 45 days before the effective date of the change, the President shall submit to the Secretary of Budget and Management each change to the Commission's salary plan that involves increases or decreases in salary ranges other than those associated with routine reclassifications and promotions or general salary increases approved by the General Assembly.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The Secretary of Budget and Management shall:</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">Failure of the Secretary of Budget and Management to respond in a timely manner is deemed to be a statement that the change will have no adverse effect.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(5)">The budget submitted by the Governor to the General Assembly shall include personnel detail for the Commission in such form and manner as provided for any agency in the State Personnel Management System.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
