<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ged" order_by="ged" level="1">Economic Development</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ged-21-304</section_number>
  <catch_line>There is a Division of Rehabilitation Services in the State Department of Education....</catch_line>
  <order_by>304</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">There is a Division of Rehabilitation Services in the State Department of Education.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The State Board of Education shall:<section prefix="(1)">Disburse all funds provided, and administer all programs established under this subtitle, for the rehabilitation of disabled individuals;</section><section prefix="(2)">Appoint and fix the compensation of the personnel necessary to administer this subtitle;</section><section prefix="(3)">Rehabilitate and place in gainful occupations individuals eligible for the benefits of this subtitle;</section><section prefix="(4)">Rehabilitate eligible individuals to function more independently;</section><section prefix="(5)">Adopt rules and regulations necessary to administer this subtitle;</section><section prefix="(6)">Report annually to the Governor on the administration of this subtitle; and</section><section prefix="(7)">Cooperate with other public and private departments, agencies, and institutions to:<section prefix="(i)">Provide for the rehabilitation of disabled individuals;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Provide for the independent living rehabilitation of severely disabled individuals;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Study the problems of rehabilitation; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">Develop and provide programs, facilities, and services necessary or desirable to implement this subtitle.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The State Department of Education shall, in addition to licensing vending facility managers in federal buildings in this State under &#xA7; 21-302(c) of this subtitle pursuant to the federal acts, license blind persons to manage vending facilities in all State, county, and municipal buildings and in all privately owned buildings and premises in this State in the event of contract with such person. The Division of Rehabilitation Services in the State Department of Education shall be the licensing agency for all vending facilities within this State licensed under this subtitle.</section>
  </text>
</law>
