<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="ged" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="11-104" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ged-11-104</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In accordance with paragraph (2) of this subsection, the Governor shall appoint, with the advice and consent of the Senate, a Secretary of Higher Education.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The Commission shall submit to the Governor the names of 3 nominees for the position of Secretary from which the Governor shall make the appointment.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The Governor may reject the list and request the Commission to submit the names of additional nominees.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Secretary shall:<section prefix="(i)">Select, organize, and direct the staff of the Commission;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Perform the duties the Commission assigns;</section><section prefix="(iii)">See that the policies and decisions of the Commission are carried out;</section><section prefix="(iv)">Serve at the pleasure of the Commission; and</section><section prefix="(v)">Be a member of the Governor's Executive Council.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">After consideration of the recommendations of the Commission, the Governor shall include in the annual budget request the salary for the Secretary.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The Secretary is entitled to the salary provided in the State budget.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Secretary may hire the additional staff provided in the State budget.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Each employee of the Commission shall join the Teachers' Pension System of the State of Maryland or the Employees' Pension System of the State of Maryland.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Any employee of the Commission who is determined by the Secretary to hold a professional position may join the optional retirement program under Title 30 of the State Personnel and Pensions Article.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
