<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ged" order_by="ged" level="1">Economic Development</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ged-18-306</section_number>
  <catch_line>Subject to the provisions of subsection (d) of this section, each recipient of a Delegate Howard P. ...</catch_line>
  <order_by>306</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Subject to the provisions of subsection (d) of this section, each recipient of a Delegate Howard P. Rawlings Educational Excellence Award may hold the award for 5 years if the recipient:<section prefix="(1)">Continues to be a resident of this State;</section><section prefix="(2)">Continues to be a full-time student at an eligible institution and takes at least 12 semester hours of courses each semester, or its equivalent as determined by the Office;</section><section prefix="(3)">In the judgment of the institution, is making satisfactory progress toward a degree; and</section><section prefix="(4)">Maintains the standards of the institution.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Each recipient of a Delegate Howard P. Rawlings Educational Excellence Award who is enrolled in an associate degree program as permitted in &#xA7; 18-303(a)(1) of this subtitle may hold the award for 3 years if the same conditions of subsection (a) of this section are met.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Each recipient of a Delegate Howard P. Rawlings Educational Excellence Award may hold the award for a 5th year if the recipient:<section prefix="(1)">Is enrolled in an academic program that, as determined by the institution, requires 5 years to complete; or</section><section prefix="(2)">Provides evidence, satisfactory to the Office, of extenuating financial, academic, or other circumstances that prevent the recipient from completing the academic program in 4 years.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">In addition to the requirements for renewal of a Delegate Howard P. Rawlings Educational Excellence Award under subsections (a), (b), and (c) of this section, a recipient of a Guaranteed Access Grant shall hold the grant for not more than 5 consecutive years or, failing to do so, provide evidence satisfactory to the Office of extenuating circumstances.</section>
  </text>
</law>
