<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ged" order_by="" level="1">Economic Development</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ged-15-106.6</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>106.6</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Fund" means the Higher Education Investment Fund.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Public Senior Higher Education Institution" has the meaning stated in &#xA7; 10-101(m) of this article.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">"Trust Account" means the Tuition Stabilization Trust Account.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">"Tuition" means the charges and fees approved by the governing board of a public senior higher education institution which are required of all undergraduate resident students by the institution as a condition of enrollment regardless of the student's degree program, field of study, or selected courses.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">There is a Higher Education Investment Fund.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The purpose of the Fund is to:<section prefix="(i)">Invest in public higher education and workforce development; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Keep tuition affordable for Maryland students and families.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Fund is a special, nonlapsing fund that is not subject to &#xA7; 7-302 of the State Finance and Procurement Article.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The Treasurer shall hold the Fund and the Comptroller shall account for the Fund.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">The proceeds of the Fund shall be invested and reinvested.</section>
      <section prefix="(6)">Any investment earnings shall be paid into the Fund.</section>
      <section prefix="(7)">The Fund consists of:<section prefix="(i)">Money appropriated in the State budget for the Fund; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Any other money from any other source accepted for the benefit of the Fund.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(8)">The Commission shall administer the Fund.</section>
      <section prefix="(9)">Money in the Fund may be expended only:<section prefix="(i)">To supplement General Fund appropriations to research institutes of the University System of Maryland and public senior higher education institutions;</section><section prefix="(ii)">For capital projects for research institutes of the University System of Maryland and public senior higher education institutions;</section><section prefix="(iii)">For workforce development initiatives administered by the Commission; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">For initiatives to address higher education needs related to the United States Department of Defense Base Realignment and Closure process.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(10)">Expenditures from the Fund may be made only in accordance with an appropriation approved by the General Assembly in the annual State budget.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Within the Fund there is a Tuition Stabilization Trust Account.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The Trust Account is established to retain revenues for stabilizing tuition costs for resident undergraduate students.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">In years of increasing corporate tax revenues that are allocated to the Fund under &#xA7; 2-613.1 of the Tax - General Article, funds shall be deposited into the Trust Account.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">Funds in the Trust Account shall be used only to stabilize tuition at public senior higher education institutions.</section>
        <section prefix="(iv)">It is the goal of the State that any increase in resident undergraduate tuition and academic fees at public senior institutions of higher education in any given year should be limited to a percent not to exceed the increase in the 3-year rolling average of the State's median family income.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Trust Account consists of:<section prefix="(i)">Money appropriated in the State budget for the Trust Account; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Any other money from any other source accepted for the benefit of the Trust Account.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">A balance of between 1% and 5% of resident undergraduate tuition revenues received by public senior higher education institutions in the prior fiscal year should be maintained in the Trust Account.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">Money in the Trust Account may be expended only to supplement General Fund appropriations to public senior higher education institutions for the purpose of stabilizing tuition costs of resident undergraduate students.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
