<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ged" order_by="ged" level="1">Economic Development</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ged-10-101</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this division the following words have the meanings indicated....</catch_line>
  <order_by>101</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this division the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Charter" means the Maryland Charter for Higher Education.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Commission" means the Maryland Higher Education Commission.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">"For-profit institution of higher education" means an institution of higher education that generally limits enrollment to graduates of secondary schools, awards degrees at the associate, baccalaureate, or graduate level, and is not a public or private nonprofit institution of higher education.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"Governing board" means:<section prefix="(1)">The Board of Regents of the University System of Maryland;</section><section prefix="(2)">The Board of Regents of Morgan State University;</section><section prefix="(3)">The Board of Trustees of St. Mary's College of Maryland; and</section><section prefix="(4)">The Board of Trustees of Baltimore City Community College.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">"Governing body" means:<section prefix="(1)">A governing board;</section><section prefix="(2)">A board of trustees of a community college;</section><section prefix="(3)">The governing entity of private nonprofit institutions of higher education;</section><section prefix="(4)">The governing entity of a for-profit institution of higher education; or</section><section prefix="(5)">The governing entity of a regional higher education center.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(g)">"Independent institution of higher education" means a private nonprofit institution of higher education that generally limits enrollment to graduates of secondary schools, serves a public purpose, and awards degrees at the associate, baccalaureate, or graduate level.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Institution of higher education" means an institution of postsecondary education that generally limits enrollment to graduates of secondary schools, and awards degrees at either the associate, baccalaureate, or graduate level.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Institution of higher education" includes public, private nonprofit, and for-profit institutions of higher education.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(i)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Institution of postsecondary education" means a school or other institution that offers an educational program in the State for individuals who are at least 16 years old and who have graduated from or left elementary or secondary school.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Institution of postsecondary education" does not include:<section prefix="(i)">Any adult education, evening high school, or high school equivalence program conducted by a public school system of the State; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">Any apprenticeship or on-the-job training program subject to approval by the Apprenticeship and Training Council.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(j)">"Private career school" means a privately owned and privately operated institution of postsecondary education other than an institution of higher education that furnishes or offers to furnish programs, whether or not requiring a payment of tuition or fee, for the purpose of training, retraining, or upgrading individuals for gainful employment as skilled or semiskilled workers or technicians in recognized occupations or in new and emerging occupations.</section>
    <section prefix="(k)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Private nonprofit institution of higher education" means a private nonprofit institution of higher education that generally limits enrollment to graduates of secondary schools and awards degrees at the associate, baccalaureate, or graduate level.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Private nonprofit institution of higher education" includes an independent institution of higher education.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(l)">"Program" or "educational program" means an organized course of study that leads to the award of a certificate, diploma, or degree.</section>
    <section prefix="(m)">"Public senior higher education institution" means:<section prefix="(1)">The constituent institutions of the University System of Maryland;</section><section prefix="(2)">Morgan State University; and</section><section prefix="(3)">St. Mary's College of Maryland.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(n)">"Regional higher education center" means a higher education facility in the State that:<section prefix="(1)">Is operated by a public institution of higher education in the State or a private nonprofit institution of higher education operating under a charter granted by the General Assembly and includes participation by two or more institutions of higher education in the State;</section><section prefix="(2)">Consists of an array of program offerings from institutions of higher education approved to operate in the State by the Commission or by an act of the General Assembly that specifically satisfies the criteria set forth in &#xA7; 10-212(b) of this title;</section><section prefix="(3)">Offers multiple degree levels; and</section><section prefix="(4)">Is either approved by the Commission to operate in the State or is established by statute.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(o)">"Secretary" means the Secretary of Higher Education.</section>
    <section prefix="(p)">"State Plan for Higher Education" means the plan for postsecondary education and research required to be developed by the Maryland Higher Education Commission under &#xA7; 11-105(b) of this article.</section>
  </text>
</law>
