<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="ged" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="18-2203" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ged-18-2203</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Office shall annually select eligible students and offer a scholarship to each student selected to be used at an eligible institution of their choice.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Subject to paragraph (2) of this subsection, a recipient of the Maryland Teacher Scholarship shall:<section prefix="(i)">Be a Maryland resident;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Except as provided in subsection (c) of this section, be accepted for admission or currently enrolled at an eligible institution as a full-time or part-time undergraduate or graduate student pursuing a course of study or program in an academic discipline leading to a Maryland professional teacher's certificate;</section><section prefix="(iii)"/><section prefix="(iv)">Sign a letter of intent to perform the service obligation upon completion of the recipient's required studies;</section><section prefix="(v)">Accept any other conditions attached to the award; and</section><section prefix="(vi)">Satisfy any additional criteria the Commission may establish.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Notwithstanding paragraph (1) of this subsection, an individual who, at the time the individual is scheduled to matriculate at an eligible institution, will have been employed as a teaching assistant at a public elementary or secondary school in the State for at least 2 years:<section prefix="(i)">May apply for a Maryland Teacher Scholarship under this subtitle; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Is eligible to hold a Maryland Teacher Scholarship as a full-time or part-time undergraduate or graduate student.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A recipient of the Maryland Teacher Scholarship may not hold a Maryland professional teacher's certificate.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Applicants who are secondary school students shall provide a high school transcript after completion of the first semester of their senior year.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Applicants who are currently enrolled in an eligible institution shall provide the most recent college transcript, or if not applicable, the applicant may submit a final high school transcript.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Applicants who are not currently enrolled in an eligible institution, but who are high school graduates, shall provide a final high school transcript.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">Applicants who are high school graduates and are not currently enrolled in an eligible institution, but have completed some courses at an eligible institution, shall provide the most recent college transcript.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">Applicants who are not currently enrolled in an eligible institution, but who are college graduates, shall provide a final college transcript.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
