<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="ged" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="25-103" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ged-25-103</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">There is a Maryland Education Council.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Council consists of seven members.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">One member shall be the Governor, ex officio.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Two members shall be from the Senate and House of Delegates of the General Assembly, appointed by the respective presiding officers.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">One member shall be the State Superintendent, ex officio.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">Three members shall be residents of this State appointed by the Governor. These members shall have knowledge of and interest in educational matters and by virtue of their training, experience, knowledge, or affiliation shall be in a position collectively to reflect broadly the interests of the State government, higher education, the State education system, county education, and lay and professional, public and nonpublic educational leadership.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The three members appointed by the Governor serve for terms that coincide with that of the Governor.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Any member of the Council appointed by the Governor may be reappointed to one or more successive terms.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Governor shall designate a chairman of the Council from among its members.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Council shall meet:<section prefix="(i)">On the call of its Chairman or the request of a majority of its members; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">At least three times in each year.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The Council may consider all matters relating to:<section prefix="(1)">Public educational policy;</section><section prefix="(2)">Recommendations of the Education Commission of the States; and</section><section prefix="(3)">The activities of the representatives from this State on the Education Commission of the States.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The members of the Maryland Education Council shall be the representatives from this State on the Education Commission of the States.</section>
  </text>
</law>
