<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="ged" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="21-501" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ged-21-501</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>// EFFECTIVE UNTIL JUNE 30, 2013  PER CHAPTER 571 OF 2008 //<section prefix="(a)"><section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section><section prefix="(2)">"Eligible party" means:<section prefix="(i)">An employer;</section><section prefix="(ii)">A group of employers;</section><section prefix="(iii)">An industry trade association;</section><section prefix="(iv)">A labor organization;</section><section prefix="(v)">An operator of a registered apprenticeship program; or</section><section prefix="(vi)">Any other entity that the Department approves to establish a paid work-based learning program under this section.</section></section><section prefix="(3)">"Student" means an individual who:<section prefix="(i)"/><section prefix="(ii)">Is enrolled in a public or private secondary school or public or private nonprofit postsecondary institution in the State.</section></section><section prefix="(4)">"Multicraft construction site" means a construction site where more than one construction trade operation is taking place at the same time.</section></section><section prefix="(b)"><section prefix="(1)">An eligible party may establish a paid work-based learning program for students that is consistent with current State and federal employment of minors laws and approved by the Department as provided under this section.</section><section prefix="(2)">A work-based learning program shall provide for approved paid work-based learning arrangements between employers and schools to provide students with structured employer-supervised learning that:<section prefix="(i)">Occurs in the workplace in conformance with established safety standards;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Integrates with classroom instruction to result in the acquisition of at least one unit of academic credit; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Links to each student's career interest.</section></section><section prefix="(3)">An approved paid work-based learning program for students shall be set forth in writing and shall include:<section prefix="(i)">A description of the knowledge and skills to be developed;</section><section prefix="(ii)">A description of the methodology to be used;</section><section prefix="(iii)">A description of the criteria for monitoring, assessing, and credentialing; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">Evidence of approval by appropriate school personnel.</section></section><section prefix="(4)">The program shall:<section prefix="(i)">Provide approved paid work-based learning experiences for students that are consistent with the strategic economic development goals established for the State; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Strive to achieve a geographic representation of students participating in paid work-based learning experiences.</section></section><section prefix="(5)">A contractor at a multicraft construction site may not qualify for the tax credit authorized under this section for more than two students.</section></section><section prefix="(c)"><section prefix="(1)">In order for an employer to be eligible to claim a tax credit, each student must be employed by the employer for 200 hours or more.</section><section prefix="(2)">An employer may claim a tax credit in an amount equal to 15% of the wages paid to each student during the taxable year under a work-based learning program that has been approved by the Department as qualifying for the tax credit under this section.</section><section prefix="(3)">The cumulative credit allowed under this section to an employer in the current taxable year and all previous taxable years may not exceed $1,500 per student.</section><section prefix="(4)">If the credit allowed under this subsection in any taxable year exceeds the total tax otherwise payable by the employer for that taxable year, the excess may be carried forward and applied as a credit for succeeding taxable years until the earlier of:<section prefix="(i)">The full amount of excess is used; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">The expiration of the 5th taxable year in which the contribution was made.</section></section></section><section prefix="(d)">The tax credit authorized under this section shall be allowed only for taxable years beginning on or before December 31, 2012.</section><section prefix="(e)"><section prefix="(1)">The Department shall adopt regulations to implement this section.</section><section prefix="(2)"><section prefix="(i)">The regulations adopted under this subsection shall include a process for approval of paid work-based learning programs as qualifying for the tax credit under this section.</section><section prefix="(ii)">The number of eligible paid work-based learning program students approved by the Department may not exceed 1,000 for each taxable year.</section></section><section prefix="(3)">The regulations adopted under this subsection shall include a process for certifying employers' eligibility for the tax credit under this section.</section><section prefix="(4)">The Department may delegate the approval authority for programs under this section to one or more private industry councils.</section></section></text>
</law>
