<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ged" order_by="ged" level="1">Economic Development</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ged-21-309</section_number>
  <catch_line>// EFFECTIVE UNTIL JUNE 30, 2013 PER CHAPTER 467 OF 2012 //...</catch_line>
  <order_by>309</order_by>
  <text>// EFFECTIVE UNTIL JUNE 30, 2013 PER CHAPTER 467 OF 2012 //<section prefix="(a)"><section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section><section prefix="(2)">"Business entity" means:<section prefix="(i)">A person conducting or operating a trade or business in Maryland; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">An organization operating in Maryland that is exempt from taxation under &#xA7; 501(c)(3) or (4) of the Internal Revenue Code.</section></section><section prefix="(3)">"Division" means the Division of Rehabilitation Services of the Maryland State Department of Education.</section><section prefix="(4)">"Qualified child care or transportation expenses" means:<section prefix="(i)">State regulated child care expenses that are incurred by a business entity to enable a qualified employee with a disability to be gainfully employed; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">Transportation expenses that are incurred by a business entity to enable a qualified employee with a disability to travel to and from work.</section></section><section prefix="(5)"><section prefix="(i)">"Qualified employee with a disability" means an individual who:<section prefix="1.">Meets the definition of an individual with a disability as defined by the Americans with Disabilities Act;</section><section prefix="2.">Has a disability that presently constitutes an impediment to obtaining or maintaining employment or to transitioning from school to work;</section><section prefix="3.">Is ready for employment; and</section><section prefix="4.">Has been determined by the Division or the Department of Labor, Licensing, and Regulation, in consultation with the Division, as having met the criteria of a qualified employee with a disability established under this section.</section></section><section prefix="(ii)">"Qualified employee with a disability" includes:<section prefix="1.">An individual who has been determined by the Department of Labor, Licensing, and Regulation, in consultation with the United States Veterans Administration, as having been discharged or released from active duty in the armed forces of the United States for a service-connected disability; and</section><section prefix="2.">Any other individual meeting the definition of subparagraph (i) of this paragraph, whether or not the individual receives services from the Division.</section></section></section><section prefix="(6)">"Wages" means wages, within the meaning of &#xA7; 51(c)(1), (2), and (3) of the Internal Revenue Code without regard to &#xA7; 51(c)(4) of the Internal Revenue Code that are paid by a business entity to an employee for services performed in a trade or business of the employer.</section></section><section prefix="(b)"><section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in subsection (e) of this section, a business entity may claim a tax credit in the amounts determined under subsections (c) and (d) of this section for the wages and qualified child care or transportation expenses with respect to a qualified employee with a disability that are paid in the taxable year for which the business entity claims the credit.</section><section prefix="(2)">The same tax credit cannot be applied more than once against different taxes by the same taxpayer.</section></section><section prefix="(c)">For each taxable year, for the wages paid to each qualified employee with a disability, a credit is allowed in an amount equal to:<section prefix="(1)">30% of up to the first $6,000 of the wages paid to the qualified employee with a disability during the 1st year of employment; and</section><section prefix="(2)">20% of up to the first $6,000 of the wages paid to the qualified employee with a disability during the 2nd year of employment.</section></section><section prefix="(d)">For each taxable year, for child care provided or paid for by a business entity for the children of a qualified employee with a disability, or transportation expenses that are incurred by a business entity to enable a qualified employee with a disability to travel to and from work, a credit is allowed in an amount equal to:<section prefix="(1)">Up to $600 of the qualified child care or transportation expenses incurred for each qualified employee with a disability during the first year of employment; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Up to $500 of the qualified child care or transportation expenses incurred for each qualified employee with a disability during the second year of employment.</section></section><section prefix="(e)"><section prefix="(1)">A business entity may not claim the credit under this section for an employee:<section prefix="(i)">Who is hired to replace a laid-off employee or to replace an employee who is on strike; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">For whom the business entity simultaneously receives federal or State employment training benefits.</section></section><section prefix="(2)">A business entity may not claim the credit under this section until it has notified the Division that a qualified employee with a disability has been hired.</section><section prefix="(3)">A business entity may claim a credit in the amount provided in paragraph (5) of this subsection for an employee whose employment lasts less than 1 year if the employee:<section prefix="(i)">Voluntarily terminates employment with the employer;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Is unable to continue employment due to a further disability or death; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">Is terminated for cause.</section></section><section prefix="(4)">A business entity may not claim the credit under this section if the business entity is claiming a tax credit for the same employee under &#xA7; 10-704.3 of the Tax - General Article.</section><section prefix="(5)"><section prefix="(i)">If a business entity is entitled to a tax credit for an employee who is employed for less than 1 year because the employee voluntarily terminates employment with the employer to take another job, the business entity may claim a tax credit of 30% of up to the first $6,000 of the wages paid to the employee during the course of employment.</section><section prefix="(ii)">If a business entity is entitled to a tax credit for an employee who is employed for less than 1 year for a reason other than that described in subparagraph (i) of this paragraph, the amount of the credit shall be reduced by the proportion of a year that the employee did not work.</section></section></section><section prefix="(f)">If the credit allowed under this section in any taxable year exceeds the total tax otherwise payable by the business entity for that taxable year, a business entity may apply the excess as a credit for succeeding taxable years until the earlier of:<section prefix="(1)">The full amount of the excess is used; or</section><section prefix="(2)">The expiration of the 5th taxable year after the taxable year in which the wages or qualified child care or transportation expenses for which the credit is claimed are paid.</section></section><section prefix="(g)">If a credit is claimed under this section, the claimant must make the addition required in &#xA7; 10-205 or &#xA7; 10-306 of the Tax - General Article.</section><section prefix="(h)"><section prefix="(1)">Subject to the provisions of this subsection, the Department of Labor, Licensing, and Regulation and the State Department of Education shall jointly adopt regulations necessary to carry out the provisions of this section.</section><section prefix="(2)">The Comptroller shall adopt regulations to provide for the computation and carryover of the credit under &#xA7; 10-704.7 of the Tax - General Article.</section><section prefix="(3)">The State Department of Assessments and Taxation shall adopt regulations to provide for the computation and carryover of the credit under &#xA7;&#xA7; 8-216 and 8-413 of the Tax - General Article.</section><section prefix="(4)">The Maryland Insurance Commissioner shall adopt regulations to provide for the computation and carryover of the credit under &#xA7; 6-115 of the Insurance Article.</section></section><section prefix="(i)">The Department of Labor, Licensing, and Regulation shall administer the tax credit and report to the Governor, and, subject to &#xA7; 2-1246 of the State Government Article, to the General Assembly, before January 15 of each year on:<section prefix="(1)">Marketing activities for the credit under this section;</section><section prefix="(2)">The number of business entities who hired a qualified employee with a disability during the preceding year;</section><section prefix="(3)">The number of qualified employees with disabilities:<section prefix="(i)">Hired in each business sector for the preceding year; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Hired during the preceding year and employed for less than 1 year;</section></section><section prefix="(4)">A summary of the average hourly wages paid to qualified employees with disabilities for the preceding year;</section><section prefix="(5)">The number and amount of credits claimed during the preceding year; and</section><section prefix="(6)">The number and amount of credits claimed for child care or transportation expenses, including a summary of the types of transportation expenses incurred by business entities.</section></section></text>
</law>
