<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ged" order_by="ged" level="1">Economic Development</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ged-5-213</section_number>
  <catch_line>After notification from the State Superintendent that a county is not complying with the provisions ...</catch_line>
  <order_by>213</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">After notification from the State Superintendent that a county is not complying with the provisions of the State program of public education, the State Comptroller shall withhold any installment due the county from the General State School Fund.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If the Superintendent finds that a county fails to meet the requirements of Subtitle 4 of this title, the Superintendent shall notify the county of such noncompliance.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If a county disputes the finding within 30 days of the issuance of such notice, the dispute shall be promptly referred to the State Board of Education which shall make a final determination.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Upon receipt of certification of noncompliance by the Superintendent or the State Board, the Comptroller shall suspend, until notification of compliance is received, payment of any funds due the county for the current fiscal year, as provided under &#xA7; 5-202 of this subtitle which are appropriated in the General State School Fund, to the extent that the State's aid due the county in the current fiscal year under that section in the Fund exceeds the amount which the county received in the prior fiscal year.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If the Superintendent finds that a county is not complying with the maintenance of local effort provisions of &#xA7; 5-202(d)(1)(ii) of this subtitle, the Superintendent shall notify the county of such noncompliance.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If a county disputes the finding within 15 days after the issuance of a notice under paragraph (1) of this subsection, the dispute shall be referred promptly to the State Board, which shall make a final determination.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Within 15 days of receipt of certification of noncompliance by the Superintendent or the State Board and subject to subparagraph (ii) of this paragraph, the Comptroller shall, under &#xA7; 2-608 of the Tax - General Article, withhold income tax revenue from the county so that the total amount withheld is equal to the amount by which a county failed to meet the maintenance of effort requirement.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The Comptroller shall distribute the amount withheld under subparagraph (i) of this paragraph directly to the county board.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
