<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ged" order_by="ged" level="1">Economic Development</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ged-7-433</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this section the following words have the meanings indicated....</catch_line>
  <order_by>433</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Concussion" means a traumatic injury to the brain causing an immediate and, usually, short-lived change in mental status or an alteration of normal consciousness resulting from:<section prefix="(i)">A fall;</section><section prefix="(ii)">A violent blow to the head or body; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">The shaking or spinning of the head or body.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Youth sports program" means a program organized for recreational athletic competition or instruction for participants who are under the age of 19 years.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Department shall develop policies and implement a program to provide awareness to coaches, school personnel, students, and the parents or guardians of students, in collaboration with the Department of Health and Mental Hygiene, each county board, the Maryland Public Secondary Schools Athletic Association, the Maryland Athletic Trainers' Association, the Brain Injury Association of Maryland, and representatives of licensed health care providers who treat concussions, on:<section prefix="(i)">The nature and risk of a concussion or head injury;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The criteria for removal from and return to play;</section><section prefix="(iii)">The risks of not reporting injury and continuing to play; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">Appropriate academic accommodations for students diagnosed as having sustained a concussion or head injury.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The program shall include a process to verify that a coach has received information on the program developed under paragraph (1) of this subsection.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Before a student enrolled in a public school system in the State may participate in an authorized interscholastic athletic activity, the county board shall provide a concussion and head injury information sheet to the student and a parent or guardian of the student.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The student and the parent or guardian of the student shall sign a statement acknowledging receipt of the information sheet.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">The Department shall create the information sheet and acknowledgment statement required under this paragraph.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The Department may use materials available from the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, the Brain Injury Association of Maryland, or any other appropriate entity to carry out the requirements of this subsection.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A student who is suspected of sustaining a concussion or other head injury in a practice or game shall be removed from play at that time.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A student who has been removed from play may not return to play until the student has obtained written clearance from a licensed health care provider trained in the evaluation and management of concussions.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Before an individual participates in an authorized athletic activity on school property, the county board shall provide, or require that a third party provide:<section prefix="(i)">Information on concussions and head injuries to the individual and, if applicable, a parent or guardian of the individual; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Notice that acknowledgment of the receipt of the information by the individual and, if applicable, the parent or guardian of the individual, is required.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The information required under paragraph (1) of this subsection shall be in the form of:<section prefix="(i)">A separate information sheet; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">A notice on the registration form for a youth sports program stating that information on concussion and head injury is available, including directions on how to receive the information electronically.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The individual and, if applicable, the parent or guardian of the individual shall:<section prefix="(i)">Acknowledge receipt of the information by:<section prefix="1.">Signature;</section><section prefix="2.">Checking an acknowledgment box on the registration form; or</section><section prefix="3.">Another method of written or electronic acknowledgment; and</section></section><section prefix="(ii)">Return the acknowledgment to the county board or third party.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">A youth sports program that uses a public school facility shall provide annually to the county board or the board's agent a statement of intent to comply for all of its athletic activities with the requirements for the management of a concussion or other head injury of a participant under this section.</section>
  </text>
</law>
