<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ged" order_by="ged" level="1">Economic Development</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ged-24-505</section_number>
  <catch_line>The Historic St. Mary's City Commission consists of seventeen members....</catch_line>
  <order_by>505</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Historic St. Mary's City Commission consists of seventeen members.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Of the Commission members:<section prefix="(1)">Thirteen shall be appointed by the Governor with the advice and consent of the Senate as follows:<section prefix="(i)">Three shall be distinguished scholars, one of whom shall be an archaeologist, one of whom shall be a colonial historian, and one of whom shall be an educator;</section><section prefix="(ii)">One shall be a representative from a prominent historical museum;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Three shall be members of the Maryland business community, one of whom is in business in the St. Mary's County community;</section><section prefix="(iv)">Six shall be members of the general public, at least two of whom are residents of the St. Mary's County community;</section></section><section prefix="(2)">Two shall be ex officio voting members as follows:<section prefix="(i)">The chairman of the St. Mary's College of Maryland Board of Trustees or the chairman's designee; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">The President of the Historic St. Mary's Foundation; and</section></section><section prefix="(3)">Two shall be ex officio nonvoting members as follows:<section prefix="(i)">The President of the Senate of Maryland or the President's designee; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">The Speaker of the House of Delegates or the Speaker's designee.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Governor shall consider statewide, regional, and minority representation in making appointments to the Commission.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The term of a member of the Commission, excluding an ex officio member, is 4 years and until a successor is appointed and qualifies. These terms are staggered as required by the terms of members as of July 1, 1997.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A member appointed to fill a vacancy in an unexpired term serves only for the remainder of that term and until a successor is appointed and qualifies.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A member may be appointed to no more than two full consecutive terms. A member who has served less than a full 4-year term may be reappointed to two full terms.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
