<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ged" order_by="ged" level="1">Economic Development</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ged-5-112</section_number>
  <catch_line>This section does not apply to:...</catch_line>
  <order_by>112</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">This section does not apply to:<section prefix="(1)">Contracts for the purchase of books and other materials of instruction as defined in the State Department of Education Financial Reporting Manual;</section><section prefix="(2)">Emergency repairs; and</section><section prefix="(3)">Except as provided in subsection (e) of this section, a county board's participation in contracts for goods or commodities that are awarded by other public agencies or by intergovernmental purchasing organizations if the lead agency for the contract follows public bidding procedures.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, if the cost of any school building, improvement, supplies, or equipment is more than $25,000, the county board, at least 2 weeks before bids are to be filed, shall advertise for bids in a medium accessible to the general public, which includes:<section prefix="(i)">A newspaper of general circulation in the region;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The Maryland Contract Weekly or comparable State publication; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">An electronic posting on a bid board and physical posting on the local school system bid board.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If the amount specified in paragraph (1) of this subsection differs from the amount in &#xA7; 13-109(a) of the State Finance and Procurement Article, the amount in &#xA7; 13-109(a) of the State Finance and Procurement Article shall apply under paragraph (1) of this subsection.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The county board shall draft specifications that provide a clear and accurate description of the functional characteristics or the nature of an item to be procured, without modifying the county board's requirements.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The specifications may:<section prefix="1.">Include a statement of any of the county board's requirements; and</section><section prefix="2.">Provide for the submission of samples, inspection, or testing of the item before procurement.</section></section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(4)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Except as provided in subparagraph (ii) of this paragraph, specifications that use one or more manufacturer's product to describe the standard of quality, performance, or other characteristics needed to meet the county board's requirements, must allow for the submission of equivalent products.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">Subparagraph (i) of this paragraph does not apply if the county board determines in the written specification that:<section prefix="1.">A particular manufacturer's product is required to maintain compatibility of service or equipment;</section><section prefix="2.">A particular manufacturer's product is required to meet the health needs of students;</section><section prefix="3.">Replacement parts or maintenance are a paramount consideration; or</section><section prefix="4.">A product is purchased for resale.</section></section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A contract for the school building, improvements, supplies, or other equipment shall be awarded to the lowest responsible bidder who conforms to specifications with consideration given to:<section prefix="(i)">The quantities involved;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The time required for delivery;</section><section prefix="(iii)">The purpose for which required;</section><section prefix="(iv)">The competency and responsibility of the bidder;</section><section prefix="(v)">The ability of the bidder to perform satisfactory service; and</section><section prefix="(vi)">The plan for utilization of minority contractors.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The county board may reject any and all bids and readvertise for other bids.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this subsection, the term "minority business enterprise" has the meaning stated in &#xA7; 14-301 of the State Finance and Procurement Article.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">In Montgomery County, by resolution and by implementing regulations, the Montgomery County Board of Education shall establish a minority business utilization program to facilitate the participation of responsible certified minority business enterprises in contracts awarded by the Montgomery County Board of Education in accordance with competitive bidding procedures.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">In this subsection, "green product cleaning supplies" means environmentally preferable cleaning and cleaning maintenance products and supplies intended for routine cleaning and cleaning maintenance that perform well and that have positive health and environmental attributes, including:<section prefix="1.">Biodegradability;</section><section prefix="2.">Low toxicity;</section><section prefix="3.">Low volatile organic compound content;</section><section prefix="4.">Reduced packaging;</section><section prefix="5.">Low life cycle energy use; and</section><section prefix="6.">Lesser or reduced effects on human health and the environment when compared to competing products that serve the same purpose.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">"Green product cleaning supplies" includes:<section prefix="1.">General purpose cleaners;</section><section prefix="2.">Bathroom cleaners;</section><section prefix="3.">Carpet cleaners;</section><section prefix="4.">Glass cleaners;</section><section prefix="5.">Floor cleaners, floor finishes, and floor strippers;</section><section prefix="6.">Wall cleaners;</section><section prefix="7.">Desk cleaners;</section><section prefix="8.">Surface cleaners;</section><section prefix="9.">Window cleaners;</section><section prefix="10.">Whiteboard cleaners; and</section><section prefix="11.">Soap.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">"Green product cleaning supplies" does not include:<section prefix="1.">Room deodorizers;</section><section prefix="2.">Air fresheners;</section><section prefix="3.">Toilet deodorizers; or</section><section prefix="4.">Hand cleaners.</section></section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Subject to subsection (f) of this section, to the extent practicable, and economically feasible, a county board shall procure green product cleaning supplies for use in its schools.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">In accordance with subsection (b)(3) of this section, a county board shall draft specifications that provide a clear and accurate description of the functional characteristics or nature of the green product cleaning supplies that are to be procured.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">The specifications drafted by a county board under subparagraph (ii) of this paragraph:<section prefix="1.">May not preclude the use when necessary of a disinfectant, disinfecting cleaner, sanitizer, or other antimicrobial product regulated by the Federal Insecticide, Fungicide, and Rodenticide Act under 7 U.S.C. &#xA7; 136 et seq.; and</section><section prefix="2.">Shall allow for multiple avenues to obtain green product cleaning supplies certification, including:</section></section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Except as provided in paragraph (2)(i) of this subsection, on or before July 1, 2013, a county board shall adopt written policies for the procurement of green product cleaning supplies for use in its schools.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The written policies shall:<section prefix="1.">Require the use of green product cleaning supplies;</section><section prefix="2.">On or before July 1, 2014, establish guidelines for purchasing green product cleaning supplies that meet the certification requirements of any established and nationally recognized independent third-party entity that certifies environmentally preferable products and adheres to consensus standards for lesser or reduced effects on human health and the environment when compared to competing products that serve the same purpose;</section><section prefix="3.">Establish green cleaning practices, including storage, application, frequency of use, and disposal of the supplies to ensure that the occupants of a school building do not suffer any adverse health effects as the result of these practices; and</section><section prefix="4.">Require staff training on implementing the policy.</section></section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">On or before June 30 each year, a county board that does not procure green product cleaning supplies for use in its schools because doing so is not practicable or economically feasible shall provide annual written notice of this fact to the Department.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">Nonpublic schools may participate under any contracts for goods or commodities that are awarded by county boards, other public agencies, or intergovernmental purchasing organizations, if the lead agency for the contract award follows public bidding procedures.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">A contract entered into or purchase made in violation of this section is void.</section>
  </text>
</law>
