<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ged" order_by="ged" level="1">Economic Development</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ged-6-203</section_number>
  <catch_line>For all proceedings before a county board under &#xA7;&#xA7; 4-205(c), 6-202, and 7-305 of this article, the...</catch_line>
  <order_by>203</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">For all proceedings before a county board under &#xA7;&#xA7; 4-205(c), 6-202, and 7-305 of this article, the county board may have the proceedings heard first by a hearing examiner.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, for proceedings before a county board under &#xA7; 6-202 of this subtitle, the hearing examiner shall be an attorney admitted to practice before the Maryland Court of Appeals.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">In Anne Arundel County, for proceedings before the Anne Arundel County Board under &#xA7; 6-202 of this subtitle, the hearing examiner may, but need not, be an attorney.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The hearing examiner shall be chosen by the county board.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">In Calvert and Charles counties, the hearing examiner may not be the attorney to the county board or be connected in any way with that attorney.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">In Carroll and Howard counties, the hearing examiner may not be a partner or an employee of the law firm representing the county board.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The hearing examiner shall submit to the county board and appellant:<section prefix="(1)">A record of the proceedings and exhibits; and</section><section prefix="(2)">The hearing examiner's findings of fact, conclusions of law, and recommendation.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Parties to the proceedings before the hearing examiner may make arguments before the county board.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">After it reviews the record and the recommendation of the hearing examiner, the county board shall make a decision.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The decision may be appealed to the State Board as provided in this article.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">Each county board shall adopt reasonable rules and regulations to regulate the proceedings before the hearing examiner.</section>
  </text>
</law>
