<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="ged" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="14-102" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ged-14-102</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The government of the University is vested in the Board of Regents.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Board of Regents consists of 15 members appointed by the Governor with the advice and consent of the Senate.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">One member of the Board of Regents shall be a student in good academic standing at the University who:<section prefix="(i)">Is at least 18 years old; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Has the qualifications required to be student body president.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The student member serves for a term of 1 year and until a successor is appointed and qualifies.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">	The student may be a resident of a state other than Maryland, but the residency status of the student may not be considered in determining the number of resident or nonresident regents as provided for in subsection (d)(2) of this section.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except for the student member, each member serves for a term of 6 years and until a successor is appointed and qualifies. The terms are staggered as required by the terms of the members serving on July 1, 1978.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Except for the student member, at least 8 members of the Board of Regents shall be residents of the State.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A member appointed to fill a vacancy in an unexpired term serves only for the remainder of that term and until a successor is appointed and qualifies.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">Each member of the Board of Regents:<section prefix="(1)">Serves without compensation; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Is entitled to reimbursement for expenses in accordance with the Standard State Travel Regulations.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
