<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ged" order_by="" level="1">Economic Development</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ged-4-116</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>116</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If there is a commission or agency with legal responsibility for county planning for land use, the county board shall:<section prefix="(i)">Consult with the commission or agency; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Ask its advice in choosing land for a school site.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The site shall conform as far as practicable to development plans for land use in the county.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If a county board gives preliminary approval of a school site, the county board shall hold a public hearing if:<section prefix="(i)">It considers it desirable;</section><section prefix="(ii)">100 or more adult residents of the county petition in writing for a hearing; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">The county commissioners or county council asks for a hearing.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The hearing shall be held on at least 10 days' notice, published at least once in a newspaper of general circulation in the county, to give all interested persons an opportunity to present their views.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Any petition by residents of the county shall be filed at the office of the county board within 15 days after the board gives preliminary approval of the site.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">If a hearing is held, minutes shall be kept and, after deliberation, the county board shall send the minutes of the hearing and its recommendation to the State Superintendent for use in making a decision on his approval of the site.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">A request for site approval may not be made to the State Superintendent by a county board until 15 days pass after its action recommending the site or, if a hearing is held, until after the hearing, whichever occurs last.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
