<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ged" order_by="" level="1">Economic Development</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ged-13-509</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>509</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In addition to the duties set forth elsewhere in this subtitle, the EMS Board shall develop and adopt an Emergency Medical System plan to ensure effective coordination and evaluation of emergency medical services delivered in this State.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Emergency Medical System plan shall include:<section prefix="(i)">Criteria for the designation of trauma and specialty referral facilities, including all echelons of care;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Criteria and guidelines for the delivery of emergency medical services including provisions to assure proper medical direction of emergency medical services;</section><section prefix="(iii)">A plan designed to maintain and enhance the communications and transportation systems for emergency medical services;</section><section prefix="(iv)">Provisions for the evaluation of emergency medical services personnel training programs;</section><section prefix="(v)">Provisions for the establishment of public information and education programs designed to enhance the public's understanding of the Emergency Medical System;</section><section prefix="(vi)">Criteria and methodologies to evaluate the System's effectiveness in delivering quality emergency medical services needed by the citizens of Maryland; and</section><section prefix="(vii)">Provisions for the evaluation and monitoring of the Emergency Medical System plan to ensure compliance with this subtitle by all segments of the Emergency Medical System.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The EMS Board shall adopt regulations to implement the Emergency Medical System plan required under this section, subject to paragraph (3) of this subsection.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Prior to adopting regulations under this section, the EMS Board shall consult with and provide opportunity for comment from local jurisdictions, volunteer and career fire companies, emergency medical technicians, rescue squad personnel, and hospitals and consider:<section prefix="(i)">The fiscal impact of the proposed regulations on local jurisdictions, volunteer and career fire companies, emergency medical technicians, rescue squad personnel, and hospitals; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">The effect of the proposed regulations on the ability of local jurisdictions, volunteer and career fire companies, emergency medical technicians, rescue squad personnel, and hospitals to continue to deliver emergency medical services.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The EMS Board shall consult with the Advisory Council in the development of the Emergency Medical System plan.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The EMS Board may adopt regulations that assure that helicopters transporting patients between hospitals or to or from specialty centers notify the System's communication center in the State Emergency Medical Communications System.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">Each State agency and department shall cooperate with the EMS Board in implementing the State Emergency Medical System plan.</section>
  </text>
</law>
