<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ged" order_by="" level="1">Economic Development</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ged-7-804</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>804</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, "school vehicle" has the meaning stated in &#xA7; 11-154 of the Transportation Article.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in paragraphs (2) and (3) of this subsection, unless it fails to meet the applicable school bus and motor vehicle safety standards, a school vehicle may be operated for 12 years.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">In Calvert, Caroline, Charles, Dorchester, St. Mary's, Somerset, Talbot, Wicomico, and Worcester counties, unless it fails to meet the applicable school bus and motor vehicle safety standards, a school vehicle may be operated for 15 years.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">A school vehicle operating under subparagraph (i) of this paragraph shall be maintained as provided in subsection (c) of this section.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Any school vehicle in operation or accepted before July 1, 2004, or under contract to be purchased before July 1, 2004, that meets the specifications of the Department and of the Motor Vehicle Administration for transit style school vehicles may be operated for 15 years.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Notwithstanding the 12-year limitation in subsection (b)(1) of this section, a school vehicle may be operated for additional years if:<section prefix="(1)">The school vehicle is maintained under a preventive maintenance plan approved by the Motor Vehicle Administration and the Automotive Safety Enforcement Division of the Department of State Police that includes an inspection at the end of the 12th year and a minimum of 2 inspections by the Motor Vehicle Administration each year thereafter;</section><section prefix="(2)">Any structural repairs to the school vehicle necessitated by accident, metal fatigue, or any other cause are certified by an independent expert approved by the Motor Vehicle Administration to meet or exceed the manufacturer's original manufacturing standards;</section><section prefix="(3)">The school vehicle is equipped with:<section prefix="(i)">The body originally placed on the chassis by the manufacturer;</section><section prefix="(ii)">An 8 light warning system;</section><section prefix="(iii)">A left side stop arm;</section><section prefix="(iv)">A fire-retardant driver's seat;</section><section prefix="(v)">Fire-retardant barriers in the case of a school vehicle with a front engine; and</section><section prefix="(vi)">A fire-retardant rear seating area in the case of a school vehicle with a rear engine; and</section></section><section prefix="(4)">The State Superintendent grants approval.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">If a school vehicle passes an inspection that is required under subsection (c)(1) of this section:<section prefix="(1)">The inspection shall be valid in the county in which the inspection was completed; and</section><section prefix="(2)">If ownership of the school vehicle is transferred to a person who operates the school vehicle in a county in which school vehicles are authorized under subsection (b)(2) of this section to be operated for 15 years, the inspection shall be valid in that county for the length of time that the inspection would have been valid in the county where the inspection was completed.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
