<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ged" order_by="" level="1">Economic Development</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ged-3-1101</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>1101</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The St. Mary's Board consists of:<section prefix="(1)">Five voting members; and</section><section prefix="(2)">One student member.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The student member shall:<section prefix="(1)">Be an 11th or 12th grade student in the St. Mary's County Public School System;</section><section prefix="(2)">Serve for 1 year;</section><section prefix="(3)">Be a nonvoting member; and</section><section prefix="(4)">Advise the county board on the thoughts and feelings of the students.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Unless invited to attend by an affirmative vote of a majority of the county board, the student member may not attend an executive session of the county board.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">A candidate elected to the county board shall be a resident and registered voter of St. Mary's County. A member who is no longer a resident and a registered voter of St. Mary's County may not continue as a member of the county board.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">A candidate who files to represent one of the commissioner election districts must be a resident of that election district.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">Candidates filing for office to represent the county at large may reside anywhere in the county.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">An individual subject to the authority of the county board at the time of filing is ineligible to be a candidate.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The St. Mary's County Board consists of five voting members who shall be elected as follows:<section prefix="(i)">One member shall be elected from the county at large; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">One member shall be elected from each of the four commissioner districts.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Voting members of the county board shall be elected:<section prefix="(i)">At a general election as required by this section; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">On a general countywide ticket.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Members of the county board elected in the 1996 general election from Commissioner Districts One and Three shall serve for an initial term of 2 years. An election shall be conducted in 1998 and every 4 years thereafter.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">Members of the county board elected in the 1996 general election from Commissioner Election Districts Two and Four and from the county at large shall serve for an initial term of 4 years. An election shall be conducted in 2000 and every 4 years thereafter.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">Except as specified in this section, elections shall be conducted in accordance with Title 8, Subtitle 8 of the Election Law Article.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The student member of the county board shall be elected by qualified students of the St. Mary's County Public School System. The student member shall not be subject to approval by the county board.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The voting members of the county board shall:<section prefix="(i)">Determine which students in the St. Mary's County Public School System may elect the student member of the county board; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Develop nomination and election procedures governing the election of the student member.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as specified in this section, an elected member shall serve for a term of 4 years. The term of each member shall commence on the first Monday in December after the member's election and shall continue until a successor is elected and qualifies.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The term of the student member shall commence on the first Monday in July and continue for 1 year.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">If a vacancy occurs on the county board, the St. Mary's Board of County Commissioners shall appoint a qualified individual to serve for the remainder of that term and until a successor is elected and qualifies.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(h)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The State Board may remove a member of the county board for:<section prefix="(i)">Immorality;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Misconduct in office;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Incompetence; or</section><section prefix="(iv)">Willful neglect of duty.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Before removing a member, the State Board shall send the member a notice, by registered mail, return receipt requested, that specifies the charges against the member.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Within 15 days from the date the State Board sends the notice, the member may request a public hearing. The member shall send this request to the county board by registered mail, return receipt requested.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">If the member requests a hearing, the State Board shall conduct a hearing promptly, but not before the 11th day from the date the State Board sent notice to the member.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">The member shall have the right to a public hearing and to representation by counsel at the hearing.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(4)">A member removed under this subsection has the right to a de novo review of the removal by the Circuit Court of St. Mary's County.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
