<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ged" order_by="ged" level="1">Economic Development</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ged-8-504</section_number>
  <catch_line>Within 2 school days after receiving notice under &#xA7; 8-503 of this subtitle, a receiving school shal...</catch_line>
  <order_by>504</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Within 2 school days after receiving notice under &#xA7; 8-503 of this subtitle, a receiving school shall:<section prefix="(1)">Inform the sending school of the enrollment or imminent enrollment of the child in State-supervised care;</section><section prefix="(2)">Request, in writing, the educational records of the child in State-supervised care from the sending school;</section><section prefix="(3)">Provide a copy of the request made under item (2) of this subsection to the child in State-supervised care or the responsible adult acting on behalf of the child in State-supervised care; and</section><section prefix="(4)">Inform the child in State-supervised care, or the responsible adult acting on behalf of the child in State-supervised care, of the rights conferred by this subtitle.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">After receiving notice under subsection (a) of this section, a sending school shall:<section prefix="(1)">Immediately inform the receiving school orally of the grade level in which the child in State-supervised care was last enrolled;</section><section prefix="(2)">Immediately inform the receiving school orally of the status of the child in State-supervised care under the federal Rehabilitation Act of 1973 codified at 29 U.S.C. &#xA7; 794 (&#xA7; 504) or under the federal Individuals with Disabilities Education Act codified at 20 U.S.C. &#xA7; 1400; and</section><section prefix="(3)">Within 3 school days following receipt of notice from the receiving school, send by mail or transmit electronically to the receiving school a copy of:<section prefix="(i)">A completed student withdrawal or transfer record of the child in State-supervised care;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The academic records of the child in State-supervised care;</section><section prefix="(iii)">The immunization records of the child in State-supervised care; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">If applicable, the most recent individualized education plan or &#xA7; 504 plan and the most recent assessment of the child in State-supervised care.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Notwithstanding subsection (b)(3) of this section, a placement agency or school employee may hand carry the documents listed in subsection (b)(3) of this section from a sending school to a receiving school.</section>
  </text>
</law>
