<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ged" order_by="" level="1">Economic Development</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ged-24-401</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>401</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, "violence prevention program" means a course in which education and training is offered in the areas of recognizing, addressing, and resolving issues of violence in the home and the community.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Board of Regents of the University System of Maryland has established at Bowie State University a State Center for Alternative Dispute Resolution and Violence Prevention. The Maryland General Assembly hereby recognizes that Center.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The General Assembly recognizes that the Center:<section prefix="(1)">Shall serve as the central repository for materials, data, and information related to violence prevention programs operating in the State or available to the State;</section><section prefix="(2)">May serve as a referral source for violence prevention programs and services operating in the State or available to the State;</section><section prefix="(3)">May implement volunteer prevention networks throughout the State;</section><section prefix="(4)">May provide research and evaluation services in the area of violence prevention;</section><section prefix="(5)">May provide information services regarding violence prevention programs and services;</section><section prefix="(6)">May provide or facilitate violence prevention education and training programs;</section><section prefix="(7)">May provide media and media-related services in the area of violence prevention; and</section><section prefix="(8)">May provide educational and academic support to disruptive youth.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">An individual or group operating a violence prevention program in the State shall be encouraged to submit to the Center:<section prefix="(1)">A written description of the program; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Any other information relating to the program required by the Center.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">An individual or group may submit a request to the Center for information on any violence prevention program operating in the State or available to the State.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">On request, the Center shall distribute information relating to a violence prevention program.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The operation of the Center shall be supported by funds:<section prefix="(1)">As provided by the Governor in the annual budget of Bowie State University; and</section><section prefix="(2)">From any other source.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
