<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ged" order_by="" level="1">Economic Development</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ged-10-209</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>209</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The University System of Maryland shall provide through its various campuses and programs a continuum of educational services, including undergraduate education, graduate education, professional programs, and research.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The goal of the University System of Maryland is to achieve and sustain national eminence with each component fulfilling a distinct and complementary mission.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The University System of Maryland shall:<section prefix="(1)">Promote excellence at each campus, in accordance with the skills of the faculty, the needs of the region, and the academic programs offered;</section><section prefix="(2)">Develop a mission for each campus which builds upon the unique strength of the campus and embodies a diversity of programs;</section><section prefix="(3)">Recruit and retain nationally and internationally prominent and diverse faculty members;</section><section prefix="(4)">Actively pursue research funding and private support;</section><section prefix="(5)">Promote economic development by creating a well educated work force through undergraduate, graduate, and professional education, targeted research, education extension services, and technical assistance;</section><section prefix="(6)">Increase access for economically disadvantaged and minority students;</section><section prefix="(7)">Stimulate outreach to the community and the State through close relationships with public elementary and secondary schools, business and industry, and governmental agencies;</section><section prefix="(8)">Encourage collaboration among institutions for the benefit of the students; and</section><section prefix="(9)">Address and respond to continuing higher education needs in order to maintain an educated work force in the State.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Board of Regents of the University System of Maryland shall appoint a Chancellor who shall be the Chief Executive Officer of the University System of Maryland and the Chief of Staff for the Board. The Chancellor and the staff of the Board shall serve as coordinators and system planners for the University.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Chancellor shall:<section prefix="(i)">Advise the Board of Regents on systemwide policy;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Conduct systemwide planning;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Coordinate and arbitrate among the institutions and centers of the University;</section><section prefix="(iv)">Assist the institutions in achieving performance goals in accordance with the Accountability Reporting Program; and</section><section prefix="(v)">Provide technical assistance to institutions and centers such as legal and financial services.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">Each campus of the University System of Maryland shall have a president who is the chief executive officer of the institution.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The University System of Maryland shall:<section prefix="(1)">Maintain and enhance the College Park campus as the State's flagship campus with programs and faculty nationally and internationally recognized for excellence in research and the advancement of knowledge;</section><section prefix="(2)">Admit as freshmen to the College Park campus highly qualified students who have academic profiles that suggest exceptional ability;</section><section prefix="(3)">Provide access to the upper division undergraduate level of the College Park campus for students who have excelled in completing lower division study; and</section><section prefix="(4)">Provide the College Park campus with the level of operating funding and facilities necessary to place it among the upper echelon of its peer institutions.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(g)">The University System of Maryland shall maintain and enhance a coordinated Higher Education Center for Research and Graduate and Professional Study, in the Baltimore area. Based on their joint graduate and research programs, the University of Maryland, Baltimore and the University of Maryland Baltimore County shall be considered a single research institution for the purposes of determining peer institutions. Funding guidelines for the professional schools of the University of Maryland, Baltimore shall be based on peer comparisons separately established for each school.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">The University System of Maryland may recognize University College as a campus for continuing higher education.</section>
  </text>
</law>
