<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ged" order_by="" level="1">Economic Development</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ged-8-315</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>315</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Maryland School for the Blind shall establish and operate a program of enhanced services for blind students who have other severe disabilities.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Maryland School for the Blind shall include a description of the program in the written agreement with the Department of Education required under &#xA7; 8-316 of this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The costs of providing enhanced services to a child under the program shall be shared by the State and by the county in which the child is domiciled as provided in subsection (d) of this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Subject to subparagraphs (ii) and (iii) of this paragraph, the Department, in consultation with the Maryland School for the Blind, shall determine on an individual basis those students who are eligible for the enhanced program described in this section.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">Students served in the enhanced program shall be students who are at risk of requiring nonpublic placement in an out-of-state special education facility, including students who are blind/deaf or students with other severe and multiple disabilities.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">For fiscal year 1999, the number of students enrolled in the enhanced program shall not exceed 20 Maryland students.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The county in which a child placed in the enhanced program is domiciled shall pay the local share of the "basic cost", as defined in &#xA7; 8-415(d)(1) of this title, of the education for that child.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">A county which pays the local share of the "basic cost" as provided in subparagraph (i) of this paragraph shall not pay the tuition required in &#xA7; 8-310 of this subtitle.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Subject to subparagraph (ii) of this paragraph, the State shall pay the cost of serving a student in the enhanced program based on an individual cost sheet completed by the Department for each student enrolled in the program.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">For fiscal year 1999, the State's share of the total cost of the enhanced program shall not exceed $750,000.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
