<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ged" order_by="" level="1">Economic Development</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ged-24-512</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>512</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Notwithstanding the provisions of Title 10, Subtitle 3 of the State Finance and Procurement Article, the Commission may sell, convey, assign, lease, or otherwise transfer or dispose of any real property acquired or held by it, and enter into any contracts incident thereto, for such term and such conditions as the Commission deems appropriate, except:<section prefix="(1)">Real property valued in excess of $5,000.00 may not be sold without the prior approval of the Board of Public Works; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Leases entered into by the Commission must be made in furtherance of the purposes of the Commission.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as otherwise set forth in this subtitle, the Commission is exempt from the provisions of Division II of the State Finance and Procurement Article, Division I of the State Personnel and Pensions Article, and the State Administrative Procedure Act.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Capital projects of the Commission are subject to Titles 3 and 4 of the State Finance and Procurement Article to the extent of any appropriation of capital funds by the General Assembly.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Commission and its officers and employees are subject to the Public Ethics Law, the Public Information Act, and the Open Meetings Law.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Commission shall procure noncapital goods and services in accordance with the procurement policies and procedures established by St. Mary's College of Maryland pursuant to &#xA7; 14-405 of this article.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">For purposes of applying for, receiving, and entering into agreements in connection with loans, grants, insurance, or other forms of financial assistance from the State or its agencies or instrumentalities, the Historic St. Mary's City Commission may be deemed to be a:<section prefix="(1)">Public body within the meaning of the Maryland Industrial Development Financing Authority Act;</section><section prefix="(2)">Political subdivision within the meaning of the Maryland Industrial Land Act and the Maryland Industrial and Commercial Redevelopment Fund Act; and</section><section prefix="(3)">State or local project eligible under &#xA7;&#xA7; 5-904 and 5-905 of the Natural Resources Article.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">All gifts of tangible or intangible property as well as cash donations to the Commission are charitable contributions eligible as a deduction against income taxes as permitted by State and federal law.</section>
  </text>
</law>
