<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="ged" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="6-302" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ged-6-302</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">An individual who is employed as a teacher, librarian, principal, director of education, or supervisor of vocational education on the staffs of the following institutions or in the following programs, or an individual who is employed as a central office director, superintendent, specialist, or coordinator of education for the following institutions or programs, shall be paid the annual salary determined under subsection (b) of this section:<section prefix="(1)">Any institution that is under the jurisdiction of:<section prefix="(i)">The Department of Juvenile Services; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">The Department of Health and Mental Hygiene;</section></section><section prefix="(2)">Any vocational rehabilitation program operated by the State Department of Education; and</section><section prefix="(3)">Any correctional education program operated by the Department of Labor, Licensing, and Regulation in a facility of the Department of Public Safety and Correctional Services.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">There shall be a single, statewide institutional educator pay plan for the positions described under subsection (a) of this section. The pay plan shall be established by the Department of Budget and Management as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">In establishing and administering the pay plan, the Secretary of Budget and Management on an annual basis shall review the salaries of public school teachers, librarians, and administrators in the six jurisdictions with the highest number of institutional educator positions and shall recommend salaries at levels that will be adequate to recruit and retain qualified institutional educators. The pay plan shall include classifications and pay grades based on the duties, responsibilities, education, and training required. The Secretary's recommendations shall be made by December 1 of each year for implementation on July 1 of the following fiscal year.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Secretary of Budget and Management shall submit any recommendations to the Governor for approval.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
