<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="ged" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="18-802" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ged-18-802</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Medical education center" means an institution:<section prefix="(i)">Whose objectives include the education of medical and allied health personnel; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">That has residency programs or full departments in at least three primary care areas.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Nurse practitioner" means a nurse practitioner as defined by the rules and regulations of the State Board of Nursing.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">"Physician assistant" means an individual to whom duties are delegated by a licensed physician under the rules and regulations of the State Board of Physicians.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">"Primary care" means family practice, general internal medicine, and general pediatrics.</section>
      <section prefix="(6)">"Eligible organization" means an institution, including a licensed hospital, nursing home, adult day care center, public health agency, home health agency, or other organization authorized by the Secretary of Health and Mental Hygiene.</section>
      <section prefix="(7)">"Eligible institution" means an institution of postsecondary education:<section prefix="(i)">Approved to operate by the Maryland Higher Education Commission; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">That awards nursing degrees or diplomas.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(8)">"Nursing shortage area" means a recognized area of nursing service or specialization determined by the Secretary of Health and Mental Hygiene to be an area where there exists a shortage of qualified nurses in eligible organizations.</section>
      <section prefix="(9)">"Nursing student" means a student enrolled in a postsecondary nursing education degree or diploma program at an eligible institution.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">There is a Maryland Physician Assistant-Nurse Practitioner Training Program that provides financial support to institutions with training programs for physician assistants and nurse practitioners in primary care in this State administered by the Office. An institution may participate if its program:<section prefix="(i)">Is accredited by the American Medical Association, the American Nurses Association, or the National League of Nursing;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Produces graduates eligible to take:</section><section prefix="(iii)">Is part of, or has a formal arrangement with, a medical education center;</section><section prefix="(iv)">Focuses on developing primary care skills and includes substantial clinical experience in primary care; and</section><section prefix="(v)">Is not a specialty program in a discipline other than primary care.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Physician Assistant-Nurse Practitioner Training Program consists of grants to an eligible medical education center for each individual who completes the program in physician assistant or nurse practitioner training in the amount of:<section prefix="(i)">$3,000 for each physician assistant; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">$1,500 for each nurse practitioner.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">If the total amount of the grants to be made under this section for physician assistants-nurse practitioners is more than $72,000 annually, then the amount of a medical education center's grant for that period shall be equal to the product of:<section prefix="(1)">The amount required to pay grants for that center; times</section><section prefix="(2)">The ratio of the total amount appropriated to the total amount required to pay grants under this section to all centers.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A grant may not be awarded to a medical education center that has discontinued its program in physician assistant or nurse practitioner training.</section>
  </text>
</law>
