<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="ged" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="3-1002" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ged-3-1002</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this subtitle, "elected member" means a member of the Prince George's County Board elected from one of the nine school board districts described in &#xA7; 3-1001 of this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Prince George's County Board consists of 10 members as follows:<section prefix="(1)">Nine elected members, each of whom resides in a different school board district; and</section><section prefix="(2)">One student member selected under subsection (f)(2) of this section.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">One member of the county board shall be elected from each of the nine school board districts described in &#xA7; 3-1001 of this subtitle.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">From the time of filing as a candidate for election, each candidate shall be a registered voter of the county and a resident of the school board district the candidate seeks to represent.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">An elected county board member shall forfeit the office if the member:<section prefix="(i)">Fails to reside in the school board district from which the member was elected, unless this change is caused by a change in the boundaries of the district; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">Fails to be a registered voter of the county.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">A county board member may not hold another office of profit in county government during the member's term.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">Each elected member of the county board shall be nominated by the registered voters of the member's school board district.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The elected members of the county board shall be elected:<section prefix="(1)">At the general election every 4 years as required by subsection (g) of this section; and</section><section prefix="(2)">By the voters of the school board district that each member represents.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If a candidate for the county board dies or withdraws the candidacy during the period beginning with the date of the primary and ending 70 days before the date of the general election, the Board of Elections shall:<section prefix="(i)">Replace the name of the deceased or withdrawn candidate on the ballot for the general election with the name of the candidate who received the next highest number of votes in the primary election; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">If a contested primary was not held, reopen the filing process to allow other persons to file as candidates.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Except as otherwise provided in subparagraph (ii) of this paragraph, the Board of Elections shall add to the ballot for the general election the name of any person who files as a candidate in accordance with paragraph (1)(ii) of this subsection.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The Board of Elections may not add additional candidates to the ballot for the general election within 70 days before the date of the election.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The student member shall be an eleventh or twelfth grade student in the Prince George's County public school system during the student's term in office.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">An eligible student shall file a nomination form at least 2 weeks before a special election meeting of the Prince George's Regional Association of Student Governments. Nomination forms shall be made available in the administrative offices of all public senior high schools in the county, the office of student concerns, and the office of the president of the regional association. The delegates to the regional association annually shall elect the student member to the board at a special election meeting to be held each school year.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The student member may vote on all matters before the board except those relating to:<section prefix="(i)">Capital and operating budgets;</section><section prefix="(ii)">School closings, reopenings, and boundaries;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Collective bargaining decisions;</section><section prefix="(iv)">Student disciplinary matters;</section><section prefix="(v)">Teacher and administrator disciplinary matters as provided under &#xA7; 6-202(a) of this article; and</section><section prefix="(vi)">Other personnel matters.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">On an affirmative vote of a majority of the elected members of the county board, the board may determine if a matter before the board relates to a subject that the student member may not vote on under paragraph (3) of this subsection.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">Unless invited to attend by an affirmative vote of a majority of the elected members of the county board, the student member may not attend an executive session that relates to hearings on appeals of special education placements, hearings held under &#xA7; 6-202(a) of this article, or collective bargaining.</section>
      <section prefix="(6)">The Prince George's Regional Association of Student Governments may establish procedures for the election of the student member of the county board.</section>
      <section prefix="(7)">The election procedures established by the Prince George's Regional Association of Student Governments are subject to the approval of the elected members of the county board.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, an elected member serves for a term of 4 years beginning on the first Monday in December after the member's election and until the member's successor is elected and qualifies.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The terms of the elected members are staggered as follows:<section prefix="(i)">The five elected members who received the lowest percentage of votes, as determined by the final vote count of the 2010 General Election as certified by the Board of Elections, shall serve for a term of 2 years; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">The other four members elected in the 2010 General Election shall serve for a term of 4 years.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The student member serves for a term of 1 year beginning at the end of a school year.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">
        <section prefix="(i)"/>
        <section prefix="(ii)"/>
        <section prefix="(iii)"/>
        <section prefix="(iv)"/>
        <section prefix="(v)"/>
        <section prefix="(vi)">A special election under this paragraph shall be governed by Title 8, Subtitle 8 of the Election Law Article and all other relevant provisions of law relating to the conduct of elections except as otherwise provided in this subtitle or where such construction would be unreasonable.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(h)">
      <section prefix="(1)">With the approval of the Governor, the State Board may remove a member of the county board for any of the following reasons:<section prefix="(i)">Immorality;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Misconduct in office;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Incompetency; or</section><section prefix="(iv)">Willful neglect of duty.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Before removing a member, the State Board shall send the member a copy of the charges pending and give the member an opportunity within 10 days to request a hearing.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">If the member requests a hearing within the 10-day period:<section prefix="(i)">The State Board promptly shall hold a hearing, but a hearing may not be set within 10 days after the State Board sends the member a notice of the hearing; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">The member shall have an opportunity to be heard publicly before the State Board in the member's own defense, in person or by counsel.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">A member removed under this subsection has the right to judicial review of the removal by the Circuit Court for Prince George's County based on an administrative record and such additional evidence as would be authorized by &#xA7; 10-222(f) and (g) of the State Government Article.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(i)">While serving on the county board, a member may not be a candidate for a public office other than a position on the county board.</section>
  </text>
</law>
