<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="ged" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="7-401" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ged-7-401</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">With the assistance of the county health department, each county board shall provide:<section prefix="(1)">Adequate school health services;</section><section prefix="(2)">Instruction in health education, including the importance of physical activity in maintaining good health; and</section><section prefix="(3)">A healthful school environment.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Department of Education and the Department of Health and Mental Hygiene jointly shall:<section prefix="(1)">Develop public standards and guidelines for school health programs; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Offer assistance to the county boards and county health departments in their implementation.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Each county board shall designate a school health services program coordinator.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">A county board may authorize the county health department to designate the school health services program coordinator.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The school health services program coordinator shall:<section prefix="(i)">Implement State and local health policies in the public schools;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Ensure that public schools adhere to local health services guidelines; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Communicate State and local health policies to the parents and guardians of public school students.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The county board shall grant the school health services program coordinator the authority to carry out the provisions of this subsection.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The Department of Education shall conduct at least two meetings annually with all school health services program coordinators in the State.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">On or before December 1, 2015, and every 5 years thereafter, the Department shall report to the Governor and, subject to &#xA7; 2-1246 of the State Government Article, to the General Assembly a summary of the information reported to the State Superintendent during the COMAR certification process.</section>
  </text>
</law>
