<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ged" order_by="" level="1">Economic Development</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ged-21-310</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>310</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"DORS" means the Division of Rehabilitation Services in the State Department of Education.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"DORS consumer" means an individual determined eligible for rehabilitation services under &#xA7; 21-306 of this subtitle who is placed by DORS in an unpaid work-based learning experience.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">"Unpaid work-based learning experience" means a program that provides a DORS consumer with structured employer-supervised learning that:<section prefix="(i)">Occurs in the workplace;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Links with an individualized plan for employment;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Is coordinated by a DORS rehabilitation specialist; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">Is conducted in accordance with the terms of an individual written work-based learning experience agreement between DORS and the employer of that participating DORS consumer.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A DORS consumer who is placed with an employer in an unpaid work-based learning experience is a covered employee of that employer, as defined in Title 9 of the Labor and Employment Article for the purpose of coverage for medical services and treatment under the State workers' compensation laws.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The participating employer where a DORS consumer is placed in an unpaid work-based learning experience shall secure workers' compensation coverage for that DORS consumer.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The State Department of Education shall reimburse the employer in an amount equal to the lesser of:<section prefix="(i)">The cost of the premium for the workers' compensation coverage; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">$250.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
