<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="ged" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="24-903" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ged-24-903</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Board consists of the following voting members:<section prefix="(1)">One representative of each of the 4-year institutions of higher education offering a Commission-approved program at the Center and at a site, appointed by the institution; and</section><section prefix="(2)">The following  10 representatives, appointed in accordance with the bylaws of the Board:<section prefix="(i)">Three representatives of regional businesses, industries, or corporations;</section><section prefix="(ii)">One representative of the Cecil County Office of Economic Development;</section><section prefix="(iii)">One representative of the Harford County Office of Economic Development;</section><section prefix="(iv)">One representative of Cecil College;</section><section prefix="(v)">One representative of Harford Community College;</section><section prefix="(vi)">One representative of the Northeast Maryland University Research Park; and</section><section prefix="(vii)">	Two representatives chosen from the community at large.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Each member serves for a term of 3 years and until a successor is appointed and qualifies.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A member may not serve more than two full consecutive terms.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A member appointed to fill a vacancy in an unexpired term serves only for the remainder of that term and until a successor is appointed and qualifies.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Subject to subparagraph (ii) of this paragraph, the chair of the Board shall be elected by the Board from among its members.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">A member who is a representative of an out-of-state institution may not serve as chair.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The voting members may elect other officers and establish committees, including advisory committees, as needed.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">In addition to the voting members, the following individuals shall serve as ex officio, nonvoting members:<section prefix="(1)">The Senior Mission Commander of the Aberdeen Proving Ground, or the Commander's designee;</section><section prefix="(2)">The Garrison Commander of the Aberdeen Proving Ground, or the Commander's designee; and</section><section prefix="(3)">The Center Coordinator.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">Each member of the Board:<section prefix="(1)">Serves without compensation; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Is entitled to reimbursement for expenses in accordance with the Standard State Travel Regulations.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
