<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="ged" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="24-904" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ged-24-904</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In addition to the other powers expressly granted and duties imposed by this title, and subject to the authority of the Commission, the Board has only the powers and duties set forth in this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Board shall:<section prefix="(1)">Assist and support the development of higher education in Cecil County and Harford County;</section><section prefix="(2)">Assist in setting the missions of and accomplishing the goals and objectives of the sites in Cecil County and Harford County;</section><section prefix="(3)">Advise the Center, site coordinators, and the supervisory staff to whom the coordinators report on programs offered and facility utilization;</section><section prefix="(4)">Provide guidance and support in identifying institutions and programs to serve higher education and workforce needs in Cecil County and Harford County;</section><section prefix="(5)">Assist with the marketing and promotion of programs offered at the Center and sites;</section><section prefix="(6)">Facilitate interactions among the business, nonprofit, education, and military communities;</section><section prefix="(7)">Keep separate records and minutes; and</section><section prefix="(8)">Adopt reasonable rules, regulations, or bylaws to carry out the provisions of this subtitle.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Board shall ensure that all academic programs and policies of the Center and sites are in compliance with the policies of and approved by the Commission.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Board may apply, accept, and expend any gift, appropriation, or grant from the State, county, or federal government or any other person.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The Board may make agreements with the federal, State, or a county government or any other person, if it considers the agreement advisable for the operation of the Center.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The Board may adopt a corporate seal.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">In addition to other reports that may be required by the Commission, the Board shall:<section prefix="(1)">Keep records that are consistent with sound business practices and accounting records using generally accepted accounting principles;</section><section prefix="(2)">Cause an audit by an independent certified public accountant to be made of the accounts and transactions of the Center at the conclusion of each fiscal year; and</section><section prefix="(3)">For any State money, be subject to an audit by the Office of Legislative Audits, in accordance with &#xA7;&#xA7; 2-1220 through 2-1227 of the State Government Article.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
