<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ged" order_by="ged" level="1">Economic Development</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ged-16-314.1</section_number>
  <catch_line>This section applies to contracts in amounts not exceeding $100,000....</catch_line>
  <order_by>314.1</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">This section applies to contracts in amounts not exceeding $100,000.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Board of Trustees of the Community College for Baltimore County may award a procurement contract on the basis of noncompetitive negotiation:<section prefix="(1)">For unsolicited offers that:<section prefix="(i)">Are in writing;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Are sufficiently detailed to allow a judgment regarding the potential utility of the offer;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Are unique or innovative;</section><section prefix="(iv)">Demonstrate the proprietary character of the offering warranting consideration of the use of competitive negotiation;</section><section prefix="(v)">May be subject to testing under terms and conditions specified by the Director of Purchasing; and</section><section prefix="(vi)">Cannot be procured through competitive methodologies;</section></section><section prefix="(2)">For the procurement of goods or services related to instruction or curriculum development;</section><section prefix="(3)">For the procurement of services related to private fund-raising activities; or</section><section prefix="(4)">Under other circumstances when the Director of Purchasing determines that noncompetitive negotiation is in the best interests of the College and the State.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Board of Trustees of the Community College for Baltimore County shall establish standards and procedures for the application of subsection (b) of this section to a particular transaction.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The standards and procedures shall require:<section prefix="(i)">The office, division, or department requesting noncompetitive negotiation to submit a written justification to the Director of Purchasing;</section><section prefix="(ii)">A written determination by the Director of Purchasing that noncompetitive negotiation is in the best interest of the College and the State; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">The written approval of the award of the contract on the basis of noncompetitive negotiation by the Board of Trustees.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
