<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ged" order_by="ged" level="1">Economic Development</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ged-2-207</section_number>
  <catch_line>There is a Public Education Partnership Fund....</catch_line>
  <order_by>207</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">There is a Public Education Partnership Fund.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Fund shall be used to:<section prefix="(i)">Enhance cooperation between the private sector and public education entities;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Facilitate the expansion and development of new partnership initiatives;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Encourage the donation of corporate and foundation money to expand the outreach capacity of the Department; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">Strengthen the development of family and community involvement in public education.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Comptroller shall credit to the Public Education Partnership Fund any money that is received from public grants and private contributions.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The State Board, upon the recommendation of the State Superintendent, may use money that is credited to the Public Education Partnership Fund for any activity or program that furthers the purposes listed in subsection (a)(2) of this section, including:<section prefix="(1)">Preparation and distribution of information packets and brochures;</section><section prefix="(2)">Development of public service announcements;</section><section prefix="(3)">Development of seminars and training programs focusing on public education priorities;</section><section prefix="(4)">Development of a family and community involvement hot line;</section><section prefix="(5)">Establishing appropriate award systems for the recognition of educators and business contributors; and</section><section prefix="(6)">Evaluating and recommending methods to improve the efficiency and promote the growth of private sector and public education partnerships.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Treasurer shall invest money from the Public Education Partnership Fund for the use of the Fund, and all earnings shall be credited to the Fund.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">Expenditures from the Fund shall be made pursuant to an appropriation approved by the General Assembly in the annual State budget or by the budget amendment procedure provided for in &#xA7; 7-209 of the State Finance and Procurement Article.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The Fund is a continuing, nonlapsing fund that:<section prefix="(1)">Is not subject to &#xA7; 7-302 of the State Finance and Procurement Article; and</section><section prefix="(2)">May not be used as a substitute for State General Fund appropriations.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(g)">The Public Education Partnership Fund is subject to audit by the Legislative Auditor as provided under &#xA7; 2-1220 of the State Government Article.</section>
  </text>
</law>
