<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ged" order_by="" level="1">Economic Development</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ged-7-305</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>305</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in subsection (b) of this section, in accordance with the rules and regulations of the county board, each principal of a public school may suspend for cause, for not more than 10 school days, any student in the school who is under the direction of the principal.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The student or the student's parent or guardian promptly shall be given a conference with the principal and any other appropriate personnel during the suspension period.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The student or the student's parent or guardian promptly shall be given a community resources list provided by the county board in accordance with &#xA7; 7-310 of this subtitle.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, a student may not be suspended or expelled from school solely for attendance-related offenses.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Paragraph (1) of this subsection does not apply to in-school suspensions for attendance-related offenses.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">At the request of a principal, a county superintendent may suspend a student for more than 10 school days or expel the student.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If a principal finds that a suspension of more than 10 school days or expulsion is warranted, the principal immediately shall report the matter in writing to the county superintendent.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The county superintendent or the county superintendent's designated representative promptly shall make a thorough investigation of the matter.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">If after the investigation the county superintendent finds that a longer suspension or expulsion is warranted, the county superintendent or the county superintendent's designated representative promptly shall arrange a conference with the student and his parent or guardian.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The student or the student's parent or guardian promptly shall be given a community resources list provided by the county board in accordance with &#xA7; 7-310 of this subtitle.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">If after the conference the county superintendent or the county superintendent's designated representative finds that a suspension of more than 10 school days or expulsion is warranted, the student or the student's parent or guardian may:<section prefix="(i)">Appeal to the county board within 10 days after the determination;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Be heard before the county board, its designated committee, or a hearing examiner, in accordance with the procedures established under &#xA7; 6-203 of this article; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Bring counsel and witnesses to the hearing.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(6)">Unless a public hearing is requested by the parent or guardian of the student, a hearing shall be held out of the presence of all individuals except those whose presence is considered necessary or desirable by the board.</section>
      <section prefix="(7)">The appeal to the county board does not stay the decision of the county superintendent.</section>
      <section prefix="(8)">The decision of the county board is final.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Any student expelled or suspended from school:<section prefix="(i)">Shall remain away from the school premises during those hours each school day when the school the student attends is in session; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">May not participate in school sponsored activities.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The expelled or suspended student may return to the school premises during the prohibited hours only for attendance at a previously scheduled appointment, and if the student is a minor then only if accompanied by his parent or guardian.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Any person who violates paragraph (1) or (2) of this subsection is guilty of a misdemeanor and on conviction is subject to a fine not exceeding $100 for each violation.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">
        <section prefix="(i)">If a student has been suspended or expelled, the principal or a designee of the principal may not return the student to the classroom without conferring with the teacher who referred the student to the principal, if the student was referred by a teacher, other teachers as appropriate, other appropriate school personnel, the student, and the student's parent or guardian.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">If the disruptive behavior results in action less than suspension, the principal or a designee of the principal shall confer with the teacher who referred the student to the principal prior to returning the student to that teacher's classroom.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(5)">A county superintendent may deny attendance to any student who is currently expelled from another school system for a length of time equal to that expulsion.</section>
      <section prefix="(6)">A school system shall forward information to another school system relating to the discipline of a student, including information on an expulsion of the student, on receipt of the request for information.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The discipline of a child with a disability, including the suspension, expulsion, or interim alternative placement of the child for disciplinary reasons, shall be conducted in conformance with the requirements of the Individuals with Disabilities Education Act of the United States Code.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If a child with a disability is being considered for suspension or expulsion, the child or the child's parent or guardian shall be given a community resources list attached to the procedural safeguards notice required by regulation of the State Board.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This subsection does not apply if the student is referred to the Department of Juvenile Services.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If a student violates a State or local law or regulation and during or as a result of the commission of that violation damaged, destroyed, or substantially decreased the value of school property or property of another that was on school property at the time of the violation, as part of a conference on the matter with the student, the student's parent or guardian and any other appropriate person, the principal shall require the student or the student's parent to make restitution.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The restitution may be in the form of monetary restitution not to exceed the lesser of the fair market value of the property or $2,500, or the student's assignment to a school work project, or both.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
