<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ged" order_by="ged" level="1">Economic Development</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ged-18-1808</section_number>
  <catch_line>The Department of Labor, Licensing, and Regulation may establish a Youth Apprenticeship Program Advi...</catch_line>
  <order_by>1808</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Department of Labor, Licensing, and Regulation may establish a Youth Apprenticeship Program Advisory Board.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Advisory Board shall include:<section prefix="(1)">The Secretary of Labor, Licensing, and Regulation;</section><section prefix="(2)">The State Superintendent of Schools;</section><section prefix="(3)">The Secretary of Higher Education;</section><section prefix="(4)">The chair of the Maryland Business Roundtable, or the chair's designee;</section><section prefix="(5)">The President of the Maryland AFL-CIO, or the President's designee;</section><section prefix="(6)">The chair of the Maryland Apprenticeship and Training Council, or the chair's designee;</section><section prefix="(7)">The chair of the Partnership for Workforce Quality Advisory Board, or the chair's designee;</section><section prefix="(8)">The chair of the Vocational Education Advisory Council, or the chair's designee;</section><section prefix="(9)">The chair of the Governor's Workforce Investment Board, or the chair's designee;</section><section prefix="(10)">The chair of the Maryland Association of Community Colleges, or the chair's designee;</section><section prefix="(11)">One member of the Senate of Maryland, appointed by the President of the Senate; and</section><section prefix="(12)">One member of the House of Delegates, appointed by the Speaker of the House.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Advisory Board shall, from time to time, review the program and advise the Secretary of Labor, Licensing, and Regulation, the State Superintendent of Schools, and the Secretary of Higher Education about matters regarding the program.</section>
  </text>
</law>
