<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ged" order_by="" level="1">Economic Development</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ged-14-104</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>104</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In addition to any other powers granted and duties imposed by this subtitle, and subject to the provisions of Title 11 of this article and any other restrictions imposed by law by specific reference to the University or by any trust agreement involving a pledge of property or money, the Board of Regents:<section prefix="(1)">Is responsible for the management of the University and has all the powers, rights, and privileges that go with that responsibility, including the powers and duties set forth in this section;</section><section prefix="(2)">May not be superseded in its authority by any other State agency or office in managing the affairs of the University; and</section><section prefix="(3)">Shall have all the powers of a Maryland corporation which are not limited by law by specific reference to the University.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">In addition to the powers set forth elsewhere in this subtitle, the University may:<section prefix="(1)">Adopt and alter an official seal;</section><section prefix="(2)">Maintain an office at the place the Board of Regents may designate;</section><section prefix="(3)">Enter into contracts of any kind, and execute all instruments necessary or convenient with respect to its carrying out the powers in this subtitle to accomplish the purposes of the University; and</section><section prefix="(4)">In accordance with subsection (p)(6) of this section, acquire, hold, lease, use, encumber, transfer, exchange, or dispose of real and personal property.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">In addition to the powers set forth in Title 19 of this article and subject to the approval of the Board of Public Works, the University may borrow money from any source for any corporate purpose, including working capital for its operations, reserve funds or interest, and mortgage, pledge, or otherwise encumber the property or funds of the University, and contract with or engage the services of any person in connection with any financing, including financial institutions, issuers of credit, or insurers.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Board of Regents may adopt rules and regulations not inconsistent with law for the government and management of the University.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Subject to Title 10, Subtitle 5 of the State Government Article ("Meetings"), the Board of Regents may adopt rules and regulations and prescribe policies and procedures for the management, maintenance, operation, and control of the University.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Except with respect to classified employee grievance appeals, Title 10, Subtitles 1 and 2 of the State Government Article ("Administrative Procedure Act") are not applicable to the Board of Regents.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The Board of Regents may review or adopt policies and procedures of the University with respect to:<section prefix="(1)">Accreditation;</section><section prefix="(2)">Programs and functions;</section><section prefix="(3)">Actual and potential capabilities;</section><section prefix="(4)">Admissions;</section><section prefix="(5)">Curricula;</section><section prefix="(6)">Graduation;</section><section prefix="(7)">The awarding of degrees; and</section><section prefix="(8)">General policymaking.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The Board of Regents may prepare and submit annual budgets and spend funds budgeted for nonsalary items on appropriate activities.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">Subject to any applicable State law, rule, or regulation, the Board of Regents may contract with any person to receive or provide services, research, training, or demonstrations.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">On the recommendation of the President, and in accordance with the requirements of Title 3 of the State Personnel and Pensions Article, the Board of Regents shall establish general standards and guidelines governing the appointment, compensation, advancement, tenure, and termination of all faculty, executive staff, and professional administrative personnel in the University.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">Subject to such standards and guidelines, and in accordance with the requirements of Title 3 of the State Personnel and Pensions Article, the President may:<section prefix="1.">Adopt additional personnel policies; and</section><section prefix="2.">Approve individual personnel actions affecting the terms and conditions of academic and administrative appointments.</section></section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Except as otherwise provided by law, appointments of the University are not subject to or controlled by the provisions of the State Personnel and Pensions Article that govern the State Personnel Management System.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Board of Regents may create any position to the extent that the cost of the position, including any fringe benefit costs, is funded from existing funds.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">Nothing in this paragraph may be construed to require any additional State General Fund support.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">By September 1 of each year, the Board of Regents shall submit an annual position accountability report to the Department of Budget and Management, the Department of Legislative Services, and the Maryland Higher Education Commission reporting the total positions created and the cost and the funding source for any positions created by the University in the previous fiscal year.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(4)">On the recommendation of the President, the Board of Regents shall designate one or more representatives to participate as a party in collective bargaining on behalf of the University in accordance with Title 3 of the State Personnel and Pensions Article.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(i)">In accordance with the requirements of Title 3 of the State Personnel and Pensions Article, the Board of Regents shall establish general policies and guidelines governing the appointment, compensation, advancement, tenure, and termination of all classified personnel.</section>
    <section prefix="(j)">The Board of Regents shall:<section prefix="(1)">Fix tuition and other fees paid by resident and nonresident students;</section><section prefix="(2)">Except for tuition, use the receipts of the fees for the purpose for which they were collected without fiscal year limitation;</section><section prefix="(3)">Review and approve before implementation each proposal for:<section prefix="(i)">Any new program; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Any substantial expansion, curtailment, or discontinuance of any existing program; and</section></section><section prefix="(4)">Review, modify as it deems necessary, and approve any operating or capital budget requests.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(k)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Board of Regents shall appoint a President of the University who shall be the Chief Executive Officer of the University and the Chief of Staff for the Board of Regents.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The President serves at the pleasure of the Board of Regents.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The President shall:<section prefix="(i)">Be responsible and accountable to the Board of Regents for the discipline and successful conduct of the University and supervision of each of its departments; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Take every initiative in:<section prefix="1.">Implementing the policies of the Board of Regents; and</section><section prefix="2.">Promoting the University's development and efficiency.</section></section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">Subject to the authority and applicable policies of the Board of Regents, the President shall:<section prefix="(i)">Develop a plan of institutional mission, goals, and priorities;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Have the authority to develop new academic programs and curtail or eliminate existing programs;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Formulate operating and capital budget requests;</section><section prefix="(iv)">Appoint, promote, fix salaries, grant tenure, assign duties, and terminate personnel;</section><section prefix="(v)">Establish admissions standards;</section><section prefix="(vi)">Set tuition and fees;</section><section prefix="(vii)">Administer financial aid;</section><section prefix="(viii)">Enter into contracts and cooperative agreements;</section><section prefix="(ix)">Have the authority to accept gifts and grants and maintain and manage endowment income;</section><section prefix="(x)">Have the authority to recommend a change in the name or status of the institution;</section><section prefix="(xi)">Regulate and administer athletic and student activities;</section><section prefix="(xii)">In compliance with State, federal, and Board of Regents mandates and policies, oversee affirmative action and equal employment opportunities;</section><section prefix="(xiii)">Establish organizations for the administration of campus alumni affairs;</section><section prefix="(xiv)">Establish traffic regulations for the campus; and</section><section prefix="(xv)">Perform any other duties assigned by the Board of Regents.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(5)">The President may delegate authority to appoint and remove personnel to the vice presidents and program directors of the University.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(l)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Board of Regents may apply for, accept, and spend any gift or grant from the federal government, any foundation, or any other person.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Any gift or grant the Board of Regents accepts shall be deposited with the State Treasurer in a nonbudgeted account and may be invested as the Board of Regents directs in accordance with law.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(m)">The Board of Regents may perform any other duty necessary to carry out its powers.</section>
    <section prefix="(n)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The President shall develop an overall plan that is consistent with the statewide plan for higher education and the Charter that:<section prefix="(i)">Sets forth both long-range and short-range goals, objectives, and priorities for postsecondary education, research, and service provided by the University;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Subject to &#xA7; 11-105 of this article, identifies the role, function, and mission of the University;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Provides for the enhancement of the University as the State's public urban university;</section><section prefix="(iv)">Encourages and supports high quality undergraduate and graduate programs on its campuses; and</section><section prefix="(v)">Stimulates outreach to the community and State through close relationships with public elementary and secondary schools, business and industry, and governmental agencies.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Board of Regents shall review, modify as it deems necessary, and approve the plan.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">By July 1 of each year, the Board of Regents shall submit to the Maryland Higher Education Commission, to the Governor and, subject to &#xA7; 2-1246 of the State Government Article, to the General Assembly an annual review of the plan.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(o)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, and except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, the University shall use the statewide Financial Management Information System administered by the Department of Budget and Management as its accounting, budgeting, personnel, and payroll systems.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The University may use an internal financial management information system software program and State-approved interfaces for its accounting, budgeting, personnel, and payroll systems.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(p)">The Legislative Auditor shall audit all expenditures and accounts of the University in accordance with &#xA7;&#xA7; 2-1220 through 2-1227 of the State Government Article.</section>
    <section prefix="(q)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Board of Regents:<section prefix="(i)">Has the power to sue or be sued; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">May carry comprehensive liability insurance to protect the Board of Regents, its agents, and employees.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The determination whether to purchase insurance, and its scope and limitations, shall be within the Board of Regents' discretion, taking into account commercial availability and affordability and the existence and extent of insurance secured by the State Treasurer.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Title 12, Subtitle 1 of the State Government Article ("Maryland Tort Claims Act") applies to claims or actions against the University, the Board of Regents, and employees of the University.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">Subject to all exclusions and limitations in that subtitle, the immunity of the University is waived to the extent of any insurance coverage purchased under this subsection.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(4)">This subsection may not be construed to waive or abrogate sovereign immunity with respect to any claim that is not covered by or exceeds the limits of an insurance policy.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">This subsection may not be construed to waive or abrogate the immunity of the University under the Eleventh Amendment to the United States Constitution.</section>
      <section prefix="(6)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Subject to the approval of the Board of Public Works, the Board of Regents may acquire, lease, encumber, sell, or otherwise dispose of real property held by the State for the use of the University.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The Board of Regents may acquire, lease, encumber, sell, or otherwise dispose of personal property.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">All property of the University is the property of the State.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(r)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in subsection (k)(1) of this section, the Board of Regents may delegate any part of its authority over the affairs of the University to the President.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Board of Regents may modify or rescind at any time in whole or in part any delegation of authority granted by it to the President.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
