<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ged" order_by="ged" level="1">Economic Development</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ged-7-426.2</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this section the following words have the meanings indicated....</catch_line>
  <order_by>426.2</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Anaphylaxis" means a sudden, severe, and potentially life-threatening allergic reaction that occurs when an individual is exposed to an allergen.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Auto-injectable epinephrine" means a portable, disposable drug delivery device that contains a premeasured single dose of epinephrine that is used to treat anaphylaxis in an emergency situation.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Each county board shall establish a policy for public schools within its jurisdiction to authorize the school nurse and other school personnel to administer auto-injectable epinephrine, if available, to a student who is determined to be or perceived to be in anaphylaxis, regardless of whether the student:<section prefix="(1)">Has been identified as having an anaphylactic allergy, as defined in &#xA7; 7-426.1 of this subtitle; or</section><section prefix="(2)">Has a prescription for epinephrine as prescribed by an authorized licensed health care practitioner under the Health Occupations Article.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The policy established under subsection (b) of this section shall include:<section prefix="(1)">Training for school personnel on how to recognize the symptoms of anaphylaxis;</section><section prefix="(2)">Procedures for the emergency administration of auto-injectable epinephrine;</section><section prefix="(3)">The proper follow-up emergency procedures; and</section><section prefix="(4)">A provision authorizing a school nurse to obtain and store at a public school auto-injectable epinephrine to be used in an emergency situation.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Each public school shall submit, on the form that the Department requires, a report to the Department on each incident at the school or at a related school event that required the use of auto-injectable epinephrine.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Department shall develop and disseminate a standard form to report each incident requiring the use of auto-injectable epinephrine at a public school.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
