<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ged" order_by="" level="1">Economic Development</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ged-7-303</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>303</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Criminal gang" has the meaning stated in &#xA7; 9-801 of the Criminal Law Article.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Law enforcement agency" means the law enforcement agencies listed in &#xA7; 3-101(e) of the Public Safety Article.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">"Local school system" means the schools and school programs under the supervision of the local superintendent.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">"Local superintendent" means:<section prefix="(i)">The county superintendent, for the county in which a student is enrolled, or a designee of the superintendent, who is an administrator; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">The superintendent of schools for the:<section prefix="1.">Archdiocese of Baltimore;</section><section prefix="2.">Archdiocese of Washington; and</section><section prefix="3.">Catholic Diocese of Wilmington.</section></section></section>
      <section prefix="(6)">"Reportable offense" means:<section prefix="(i)">A crime of violence, as defined in &#xA7; 14-101 of the Criminal Law Article;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Any of the offenses enumerated in &#xA7; 3-8A-03(d)(4) of the Courts Article;</section><section prefix="(iii)">A violation of &#xA7; 4-101, &#xA7; 4-102, &#xA7; 4-203, or &#xA7; 4-204 of the Criminal Law Article;</section><section prefix="(iv)">A violation of &#xA7;&#xA7; 5-602 through 5-609, &#xA7;&#xA7; 5-612 through 5-614, &#xA7; 5-617, &#xA7; 5-618, &#xA7; 5-627, or &#xA7; 5-628 of the Criminal Law Article;</section><section prefix="(v)">A violation of &#xA7; 4-503, &#xA7; 9-504, or &#xA7; 9-505 of the Criminal Law Article;</section><section prefix="(vi)">A violation of &#xA7; 6-102, &#xA7; 6-103, &#xA7; 6-104, or &#xA7; 6-105 of the Criminal Law Article;</section><section prefix="(vii)">A violation of &#xA7; 9-802 or &#xA7; 9-803 of the Criminal Law Article;</section><section prefix="(viii)">A violation of &#xA7; 3-203 of the Criminal Law Article;</section><section prefix="(ix)">A violation of &#xA7; 6-301 of the Criminal Law Article;</section><section prefix="(x)">A violation of &#xA7; 9-302, &#xA7; 9-303, or &#xA7; 9-305 of the Criminal Law Article; or</section><section prefix="(xi)">A violation of &#xA7; 7-105 of the Criminal Law Article.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(7)">"School principal" means the principal of the public or nonpublic school in which a student is enrolled, or a designee of the principal, who is an administrator.</section>
      <section prefix="(8)">
        <section prefix="(i)">"School security officer" includes a school principal, another school administrator, a law enforcement officer, or other individual employed by a local school system or a local government who is designated by the county superintendent or a school principal to help maintain the security and safety of a school.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">"School security officer" does not include a teacher.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(9)">"Student" means an individual enrolled in a public school system or nonpublic school in the State who is 5 years of age or older and under 22 years of age.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">If a student is arrested for a reportable offense or an offense that is related to the student's membership in a criminal gang, the law enforcement agency making the arrest:<section prefix="(1)">Shall notify the following individuals of the arrest and the charges within 24 hours of the arrest or as soon as practicable:<section prefix="(i)">The local superintendent;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The school principal; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">For a school that has a school security officer, the school security officer; and</section></section><section prefix="(2)">May notify the State's Attorney of the arrest and charges.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The State's Attorney shall promptly notify either the local superintendent or the school principal of the disposition of the reportable offense required to be reported under subsection (b) of this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Except by order of a juvenile court or other court upon good cause shown, the information obtained by an individual pursuant to subsections (b) and (c) of this section:<section prefix="(1)">Is confidential and may not be redisclosed by subpoena or otherwise except as provided pursuant to subsections (e) and (f) of this section; and</section><section prefix="(2)">May not be made part of the student's permanent educational record.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Notwithstanding the provisions of subsection (d) of this section, nothing shall prohibit a local superintendent or school principal from transmitting the information obtained pursuant to subsections (b) and (c) of this section as a confidential file to the local superintendent of another public school system in the State or another nonpublic school in the State in which the student has enrolled or been transferred in order to carry out the purposes of this section if the disposition of the reportable offense was a conviction or an adjudication of delinquency or the criminal charge or delinquency petition is still pending.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A local superintendent or school principal who transmits information about a student under this subsection shall include in the transmittal information regarding any educational programming and related services provided to the student.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The State Board shall adopt regulations to ensure that information obtained by a local superintendent, a school principal, or a school security officer under subsections (b), (c), and (e) of this section is:<section prefix="(1)">Used to provide appropriate educational programming and related services to the student and to maintain a safe and secure school environment for students and school personnel;</section><section prefix="(2)">Transmitted only to school personnel of the school in which the student is enrolled as necessary to carry out the purposes set forth in item (1) of this subsection; and</section><section prefix="(3)">Destroyed when the student graduates or otherwise permanently leaves school or turns 22 years old, whichever occurs first.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as otherwise provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, the local superintendent and the school principal shall consider prohibiting a student who is arrested for a reportable offense involving rape or a sexual offense from attending the same school or riding on the same school bus as the alleged victim of the reportable offense if such action is necessary or appropriate to protect the physical or psychological well-being of the alleged victim.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If a student is arrested for a reportable offense involving rape or a sexual offense and is convicted of or adjudicated delinquent for the rape or sexual offense, the student may not attend the same school or ride on the same school bus as the victim.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(h)">Nothing in this section is intended to limit the manner in which a local school obtains information or uses information obtained by any lawful means other than that set forth in subsections (b), (c), and (e) of this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">Each public school that enrolls students in grades six through twelve in the State shall designate at least one school security officer.</section>
  </text>
</law>
