<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ged" order_by="" level="1">Economic Development</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ged-6-803</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>803</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Board shall consist of the following five members appointed by the Governor, with the advice and consent of the Senate:<section prefix="(1)">One member who:<section prefix="(i)">Represents the public;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Has experience in labor relations;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Is not an officer or employee of a board of education or an employee organization representing public school system employees;</section><section prefix="(iv)">Is not an elected official of the State, a county, or an employee organization representing public school employees; and</section><section prefix="(v)">Is known for objective and independent judgment;</section></section><section prefix="(2)">Two members, including one member chosen from a list of candidates submitted by the organization representing a majority of public school employees in the State for collective bargaining purposes and another member chosen from a list of candidates submitted by a statewide organization representing public school employees in at least one jurisdiction within the State for collective bargaining purposes other than the majority organization under this paragraph, who:<section prefix="(i)">Are not employees of the State or a public school employee organization; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Are known for objective and independent judgment; and</section></section><section prefix="(3)">Two members chosen from a list of candidates submitted by the Maryland Association of Boards of Education and the State Superintendents Association of Maryland, who:<section prefix="(i)">Are not officers or employees of the State or county or State boards of education and are not officers or employees of employee organizations representing employees of public school systems in Maryland; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Are known for objective and independent judgment.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Before taking office each member shall take the oath required by Article I, Section 9 of the Maryland Constitution.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Public School Labor Relations Board shall elect a chair from among its members.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The term of a member is 5 years.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The terms of members are staggered as required by the terms provided for members of the Board on July 1, 2010.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">At the end of a term a member continues to serve until a successor is appointed and qualifies.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">A member who is appointed after a term has begun serves only for the remainder of that term.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The Governor may remove a member only for incompetence or misconduct.</section>
  </text>
</law>
