<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ged" order_by="" level="1">Economic Development</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ged-5-114</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>114</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, "deficit" means a negative fund balance in the General Fund of 1% or more of General Fund revenue at the end of the fiscal year.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The State Superintendent and the Department shall monitor the financial status of each local school system.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">If a local school system does not file the annual audit results in a timely manner with the State Superintendent as required by &#xA7; 5-109 of this subtitle, the State Superintendent shall:<section prefix="(1)">Immediately notify:<section prefix="(i)">The Department of Legislative Services;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The county governing body; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">The local board and local superintendent or chief executive officer of the local school system; and</section></section><section prefix="(2)">Order that the audit report be filed within 10 days.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A local school system may not carry a deficit as reported in the annual audit under &#xA7; 5-109 of this subtitle.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If a local school system has a deficit, the State Superintendent shall immediately notify the Governor, the General Assembly, the Department of Legislative Services, and county governing body and shall require the local school system to:<section prefix="(i)">Develop and submit for approval a corrective action cost containment plan within 15 days;</section><section prefix="(ii)">File monthly status reports with the State Superintendent and county governing body demonstrating actions taken to close the deficit and the effect of the actions taken on the deficit; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Include information on the corrective action cost containment plan, actions taken to close the deficit, and status of the deficit in the annual audit under &#xA7; 5-109 of this subtitle filed with the State Superintendent and county governing body.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The State Superintendent shall include information on any local school system deficit, corrective action cost containment plan, actions taken to close a local school system deficit, and status of any local school system deficit in a quarterly report to the Governor and the General Assembly, in accordance with &#xA7; 2-1246 of the State Government Article.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">If a local school system has a deficit:<section prefix="(i)">The Office of Legislative Audits may request any financial information pertaining to the deficit and the corrective action cost containment plan; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">The local superintendent or chief executive officer of a local school system shall provide the requested information.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">If a local school system fails to comply with the requirements of this section, the State Superintendent, with the approval of the State Board of Education, shall notify the State Comptroller, who shall withhold 10% of the next installment and each subsequent installment due the local school system from the General State School Fund until the State Superintendent notifies the Comptroller that the local school system is in full compliance with the requirements of this section.</section>
  </text>
</law>
