<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="ged" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="6-703" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ged-6-703</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Board consists of 25 members.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Of the 25 Board members:<section prefix="(i)">8 shall be public school classroom teachers, as follows:</section><section prefix="(ii)">1 shall be a certified nonpublic school classroom teacher, chosen from a list of nominees provided by the Association of Independent Schools;</section><section prefix="(iii)">6 shall be teacher education faculty members from colleges of the State, chosen from a list of nominees provided by:</section><section prefix="(iv)">4 shall be administrative or supervisory staff members of public schools, as follows:</section><section prefix="(v)">2 shall be administrative or supervisory staff of the approved nonpublic schools of the State, chosen from a list of nominees provided by the Association of Independent Schools;</section><section prefix="(vi)">1 shall be a member of a local board of education, chosen from a list of nominees provided by the Maryland Association of Boards of Education;</section><section prefix="(vii)">2 shall be representatives of the general public, as follows:</section><section prefix="(viii)">1 shall be the State Superintendent or a designee of the State Superintendent.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Board shall include all the members of the Professional Standards and Teacher Education Advisory Board serving on July 1, 1991.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Governor, with the advice and consent of the Senate of Maryland, shall appoint the members of the Board described in subsection (a)(2)(i) through (vii) of this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">In making the appointments required under this subsection, the Governor shall ensure that the Board is representative of:<section prefix="(i)">The geographic regions of the State; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Minority populations of the State as defined in &#xA7; 9-301 of the State Government Article.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The term of an appointed member is 3 years.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The terms of the appointed members are staggered as required by the terms provided for members of the Board on October 1, 1991.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">At the end of a term, a member continues to serve until a successor is appointed.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">A member who is appointed after a term has begun serves only for the remainder of the term and until a successor is appointed and qualifies.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Governor may remove a member for incompetence or misconduct.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">From among its members, the Board annually shall elect a chairman.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">A majority of the members of the Board then serving on the Board is a quorum.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">The staff for the Board shall be provided by the State Board.</section>
  </text>
</law>
