<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ged" order_by="" level="1">Economic Development</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ged-13-101</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>101</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">It is the intent of the General Assembly that the University of Maryland University College:<section prefix="(1)">Operate as Maryland's open university serving nontraditional students who reside in Maryland, the United States, and throughout the world;</section><section prefix="(2)">Provide the citizens of Maryland with affordable, open access higher education; and</section><section prefix="(3)">Continue as a leader in distributed higher education.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">There is a University of Maryland University College which is not a new constituent institution of the University System of Maryland.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">As a constituent institution of the University System of Maryland, the University of Maryland University College is an instrumentality of the State.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The exercise by the University of Maryland University College of its powers, including its overseas operations, is the performance of an essential public function.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The provisions of &#xA7; 12-105(a) of this article do not apply to the overseas operations of the University of Maryland University College. The institution may spend the appropriation without the approval of the Board of Public Works and without submitting a detailed budget schedule to the Board of Public Works.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The University of Maryland University College shall prepare an annual financial information statement for the next following fiscal year and shall submit the statement to the Department of Budget and Management each year before October 1. The annual financial information statement shall include for the next following fiscal year:<section prefix="(1)">An estimate of the total revenues of the University of Maryland University College, including revenues from tuitions, fees, gifts, grants, and interest income;</section><section prefix="(2)">An estimate of the value of services which the other units of the University of Maryland and other State agencies provide to the University of Maryland University College; and</section><section prefix="(3)">An estimate of the total cost of salaries and personnel benefits for employees of the University of Maryland University College.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The interest or income from the investment of the funds of the University of Maryland University College by the State Treasurer shall be credited to the University of Maryland University College.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Any unexpended or unencumbered balance of the annual appropriation for the University of Maryland University College, except any appropriation from the General Fund of the State, shall not revert to the General Fund of the State at the end of the State's fiscal year.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The University of Maryland University College may:<section prefix="(1)">Purchase, lease, or rent motor vehicles for use in overseas programs; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Purchase, lease, or rent mechanical or electronic data or information processing equipment and related services for its overseas programs.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Each year the University of Maryland University College shall cause an independent certified public accountant to prepare audited financial statements of the University of Maryland University College in accordance with generally accepted auditing standards accompanied by the auditor's report on the statements.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The provisions of &#xA7; 12-105(f) of this article do not apply to the University of Maryland University College overseas programs.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
