<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ged" order_by="ged" level="1">Economic Development</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ged-11-601</section_number>
  <catch_line>By August 1, 1993, the governing board of each institution of higher education shall adopt and submi...</catch_line>
  <order_by>601</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">By August 1, 1993, the governing board of each institution of higher education shall adopt and submit to the Commission a written policy on sexual assault.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The policy adopted under paragraph (1) of this subsection shall apply to each student, faculty member, and employee of the institution and inform the students, faculty members, and employees of their rights and duties under the policy.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Each institution of higher education shall post at appropriate locations on each campus and distribute to its students, faculty members, and employees a copy of the policy adopted under subsection (a) of this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Each institution of higher education shall implement the policy adopted under subsection (a) of this section.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The sexual assault policy required under subsection (a) of this section shall conform with &#xA7; 485(f) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 as amended by &#xA7; 486(c)(2) of the Higher Education Amendments of 1992 and shall include procedures for reporting an incident of sexual assault and for taking disciplinary actions against a violator of the policy, including provisions for:<section prefix="(1)">Informing a victim of a sexual assault of the right to file criminal charges with the appropriate law enforcement official;</section><section prefix="(2)">The prompt assistance of campus authorities, at the request of the victim, in notifying the appropriate law enforcement officials and disciplinary authorities of an incident of sexual assault;</section><section prefix="(3)">Designation of the nearest hospitals equipped with the Department of State Police Sexual Assault Evidence Collection Kit;</section><section prefix="(4)">Full and prompt cooperation from campus personnel in obtaining appropriate medical attention, including transporting the victim to the nearest designated hospital;</section><section prefix="(5)">Offering counseling to a victim of sexual assault from mental health services provided by the institution, other victim service entities, or the nearest State designated rape crisis program; and</section><section prefix="(6)">After a campus sexual assault has been reported, and upon the request of the alleged victim, the transfer of the alleged victim to alternative classes or housing, if such alternatives are available and feasible.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Commission shall:<section prefix="(1)">Coordinate the development of the sexual assault policies; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Periodically review and make recommendations for changes in these policies.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">Nothing in this subtitle shall be construed to confer a private cause of action upon any person to enforce the provisions of this subtitle.</section>
  </text>
</law>
