<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ged" order_by="" level="1">Economic Development</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ged-16-317</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>317</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Base year" means July 1, 2001 through June 30, 2002.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Contribution" means monetary and equipment donations that have been assessed a monetary value amount for the purposes of determining the State payment.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">
        <section prefix="(i)">"Eligible donor" means any individual, corporation, partnership, or other form of business organization, public or private foundation, or other nonprofit organization.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">"Eligible donor" does not include a local government, the State, the federal government, or any foreign government.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(5)">"Eligible institution" refers to the following community college campuses:<section prefix="(i)">Allegany;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Anne Arundel;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Baltimore City;</section><section prefix="(iv)">Carroll;</section><section prefix="(v)">Catonsville;</section><section prefix="(vi)">Cecil;</section><section prefix="(vii)">Chesapeake;</section><section prefix="(viii)">Dundalk;</section><section prefix="(ix)">Essex;</section><section prefix="(x)">Frederick;</section><section prefix="(xi)">Garrett;</section><section prefix="(xii)">Germantown;</section><section prefix="(xiii)">Hagerstown;</section><section prefix="(xiv)">Harford;</section><section prefix="(xv)">Howard;</section><section prefix="(xvi)">La Plata;</section><section prefix="(xvii)">Leonardtown;</section><section prefix="(xviii)">Prince Frederick;</section><section prefix="(xix)">Prince George's;</section><section prefix="(xx)">Rockville;</section><section prefix="(xxi)">Takoma Park; and</section><section prefix="(xxii)">Wor-Wic.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(6)">"Eligible program" means any contribution for technology which does not contain unreasonable restrictions as to use as further defined by the Maryland Higher Education Commission.</section>
      <section prefix="(7)">"First eligible period" means fiscal years 2003 and 2004.</section>
      <section prefix="(8)">"Second eligible period" means fiscal years 2005 and 2006.</section>
      <section prefix="(9)">
        <section prefix="(i)">"Technology" means the hardware, software, communications infrastructure, and associated training and contracted services that enable local or global presentation, exchange, and transmission of information in digital or analog form for teaching, learning, student support services, and administration.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">"Technology" may include capital expenditures.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">"Technology" does not include staff.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Each eligible institution shall receive from the State, in the manner and subject to the limitations of this section, with respect to the contributions made by eligible donors as voluntary donations at any time during the first eligible period to the eligible institution for eligible programs, an amount equal to the first $150,000 or any portion thereof from contributions by eligible donors.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If an eligible institution qualifies for the maximum State contribution of $150,000 in the first eligible period, the eligible institution shall receive from the State, in the manner and subject to the limitations of this section, with respect to the contributions made by eligible donors as voluntary donations at any time during the second eligible period to the eligible institution for eligible programs, an amount equal to the first $150,000 or any portion thereof from contributions by eligible donors.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Payments shall be made by the State:<section prefix="(1)">In the first eligible period, only with respect to contributions which are paid by the eligible donors to the eligible institution before July 1, 2004;</section><section prefix="(2)">In the second eligible period, only with respect to contributions which are paid by the eligible donors to the eligible institution before July 1, 2006; and</section><section prefix="(3)">In the third fiscal year following the fiscal year during which the contributions are made.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Contributions made by the State under this section may not exceed $150,000 during each eligible period to each eligible institution.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">To determine eligibility for State payments, each contribution shall be compared to the amount contributed during the base year. The following criteria shall be the basis for comparison:<section prefix="(i)">Each contribution must be from a new donor; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">Each contribution must represent an increase over the amount contributed by the donor during the base year.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A contribution received during the base year that fulfills a pledge made prior to the base year may not be included in the determination of the contribution made during the base year.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Each contribution must be specifically designated for technology.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">Contributions made by the State under this section may be applied to any eligible technology expense at an eligible institution to which the payment is made.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">Contributions made by the State to any eligible institution under this section may not directly or indirectly reduce the State General Fund or capital fund support for the eligible institution.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">The Maryland Higher Education Commission shall:<section prefix="(1)">Adopt regulations necessary for the administration of this section; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Submit to the Governor and, in accordance with &#xA7; 2-1246 of the State Government Article, to the General Assembly an annual report summarizing the total amount of funds pledged by eligible donors and total amount of funds raised.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
