<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ged" order_by="ged" level="1">Economic Development</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ged-16-512</section_number>
  <catch_line>The total State operating fund per full-time equivalent student appropriated to Baltimore City Commu...</catch_line>
  <order_by>512</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The total State operating fund per full-time equivalent student appropriated to Baltimore City Community College for each fiscal year other than fiscal year 2013, as requested by the Governor shall be:<section prefix="(i)">In fiscal year 2009, not less than an amount equal to 67.25% of the State's General Fund appropriation per full-time equivalent student to the 4-year public institutions of higher education in the State as designated by the Commission for the purpose of administering the Joseph A. Sellinger Program under Title 17 of this article in the previous fiscal year;</section><section prefix="(ii)">In fiscal year 2010, not less than an amount equal to 65.1% of the State's General Fund appropriation per full-time equivalent student to the 4-year public institutions of higher education in the State as designated by the Commission for the purpose of administering the Joseph A. Sellinger Program under Title 17 of this article in the same fiscal year;</section><section prefix="(iii)">In fiscal year 2011, not less than an amount equal to 65.5% of the State's General Fund appropriation per full-time equivalent student to the 4-year public institutions of higher education in the State as designated by the Commission for the purpose of administering the Joseph A. Sellinger Program under Title 17 of this article in the same fiscal year;</section><section prefix="(iv)">In fiscal year 2012, not less than an amount equal to 63% of the State's General Fund appropriation per full-time equivalent student to the 4-year public institutions of higher education in the State as designated by the Commission for the purpose of administering the Joseph A. Sellinger Program under Title 17 of this article in the same fiscal year;</section><section prefix="(v)">In fiscal year 2014, an amount that is the greater of 61% of the State's General Fund appropriation per full-time equivalent student to the 4-year public institutions of higher education in the State as designated by the Commission for the purpose of administering the Joseph A. Sellinger Program under Title 17 of this article in the same fiscal year or $5,695.63 per full-time equivalent student;</section><section prefix="(vi)">In fiscal year 2015, an amount that is the greater of 61% of the State's General Fund appropriation per full-time equivalent student to the 4-year public institutions of higher education in the State as designated by the Commission for the purpose of administering the Joseph A. Sellinger Program under Title 17 of this article in the same fiscal year or $5,695.63 per full-time equivalent student;</section><section prefix="(vii)">In fiscal year 2016, an amount that is the greater of 58% of the State's General Fund appropriation per full-time equivalent student to the 4-year public institutions of higher education in the State as designated by the Commission for the purpose of administering the Joseph A. Sellinger Program under Title 17 of this article in the same fiscal year or $5,695.63 per full-time equivalent student;</section><section prefix="(viii)">In fiscal year 2017, an amount that is the greater of 58% of the State's General Fund appropriation per full-time equivalent student to the 4-year public institutions of higher education in the State as designated by the Commission for the purpose of administering the Joseph A. Sellinger Program under Title 17 of this article in the same fiscal year or $5,695.63 per full-time equivalent student;</section><section prefix="(ix)">In fiscal year 2018, not less than an amount equal to 60% of the State's General Fund appropriation per full-time equivalent student to the 4-year public institutions of higher education in the State as designated by the Commission for the purpose of administering the Joseph A. Sellinger Program under Title 17 of this article in the same fiscal year;</section><section prefix="(x)">In fiscal year 2019, not less than an amount equal to 61% of the State's General Fund appropriation per full-time equivalent student to the 4-year public institutions of higher education in the State as designated by the Commission for the purpose of administering the Joseph A. Sellinger Program under Title 17 of this article in the same fiscal year;</section><section prefix="(xi)">In fiscal year 2020, not less than an amount equal to 62.5% of the State's General Fund appropriation per full-time equivalent student to the 4-year public institutions of higher education in the State as designated by the Commission for the purpose of administering the Joseph A. Sellinger Program under Title 17 of this article in the same fiscal year;</section><section prefix="(xii)">In fiscal year 2021, not less than an amount equal to 64.5% of the State's General Fund appropriation per full-time equivalent student to the 4-year public institutions of higher education in the State as designated by the Commission for the purpose of administering the Joseph A. Sellinger Program under Title 17 of this article in the same fiscal year;</section><section prefix="(xiii)">In fiscal year 2022, not less than an amount equal to 66.5% of the State's General Fund appropriation per full-time equivalent student to the 4-year public institutions of higher education in the State as designated by the Commission for the purpose of administering the Joseph A. Sellinger Program under Title 17 of this article in the same fiscal year; and</section><section prefix="(xiv)">In fiscal year 2023 and each fiscal year thereafter, not less than an amount equal to 68.5% of the State's General Fund appropriation per full-time equivalent student to the 4-year public institutions of higher education in the State as designated by the Commission for the purpose of administering the Joseph A. Sellinger Program under Title 17 of this article in the same fiscal year.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">For purposes of this subsection, the State's General Fund appropriation per full-time equivalent student to the 4-year public institutions of higher education in the State for a fiscal year shall include noncapital appropriations from the Higher Education Investment Fund.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Notwithstanding the provisions of paragraph (1) of this subsection, the total State operating fund appropriated to Baltimore City Community College under this section for each of fiscal years 2011 and 2012 shall be $40,187,695.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">In fiscal year 2013, the total State operating funds appropriated to Baltimore City Community College under this section shall be $39,863,729.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Notwithstanding subsection (a) of this section, the State appropriation to Baltimore City Community College requested by the Governor may not be less than the State appropriation to the College in the previous fiscal year.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The State shall distribute the State appropriation under this subsection to the Board of Trustees of Baltimore City Community College on a quarterly basis.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Through June 30, 1999, the City of Baltimore shall be responsible for providing at least $600,000 in each fiscal year to support education at the College.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">Of this amount, in each fiscal year, at least $300,000 shall be expended and administered by the College for tuition reimbursement or scholarships to attend classes at the College, and the remaining balance shall be expended in a manner consistent with the educational mission of the College.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">The source of the $600,000 is not limited to tax or fee revenues generated by the City of Baltimore.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Beginning on July 1, 1999, the City of Baltimore shall be responsible for providing at least $800,000 in each fiscal year to support education at the College.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">Of this amount, in each fiscal year, at least $500,000 shall be expended and administered by the College for tuition reimbursement or scholarships to attend classes at the College, and the remaining balance shall be expended in a manner consistent with the educational mission of the College.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">The source of the $800,000 is not limited to tax or fee revenues generated by the City of Baltimore.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Beginning on July 1, 2006, the City of Baltimore shall be responsible for providing at least $1,000,000 in each fiscal year to support education at the College.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">Of this amount, in each fiscal year, at least $400,000 shall be expended and administered by the College for tuition reimbursement or scholarships to attend classes at the College, and the remaining balance shall be expended in a manner consistent with the educational mission of the College.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">The source of the $1,000,000 is not limited to tax or fee revenues generated by the City of Baltimore.</section>
        <section prefix="(iv)">The Board of Trustees shall submit an annual report on or before December 31 to the Director of Finance for the City of Baltimore regarding the expenditures made under this paragraph.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
