<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ged" order_by="" level="1">Economic Development</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ged-6-303</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>303</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">There is an Institutional Educator Pay Plan Advisory Committee.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Advisory Committee shall consist of:<section prefix="(i)">Five employee educators whose positions are included in the Institutional Educator Pay Plan established under &#xA7; 6-302 of this subtitle from each of the following units:<section prefix="1.">The Division of Workforce Development and Adult Learning in the Department of Labor, Licensing, and Regulation;</section><section prefix="2.">The Division of Rehabilitative Services in the Department of Education;</section><section prefix="3.">The Department of Juvenile Services;</section><section prefix="4.">The Department of Health and Mental Hygiene; and</section><section prefix="5.">The Juvenile Services Education Program in the Department of Education; and</section></section><section prefix="(ii)">Any additional agency representatives appointed by the Secretary of Budget and Management.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The State Director of the Correctional Education Association shall recommend to the Secretary of Budget and Management individuals to serve as the institutional educator members of the Advisory Committee. The Secretary shall take these recommendations into consideration, but may appoint any individual who is an institutional educator under &#xA7; 6-302(a) of this subtitle.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Each member of the Advisory Committee:<section prefix="(1)">Shall serve a 3-year term; and</section><section prefix="(2)"><section prefix="(i)">Shall serve without compensation; but</section><section prefix="(ii)">Is entitled to reimbursement for expenses in accordance with the Standard State Travel Regulations.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Advisory Committee shall designate:<section prefix="(1)">One member as chairperson; and</section><section prefix="(2)">The time and place of its meetings.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The Advisory Committee shall review and comment on the Institutional Educator Pay Plan recommendations made by the Secretary of Budget and Management prior to the submission of the recommendations to the Governor.</section>
  </text>
</law>
