<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="ged" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="5-208" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ged-5-208</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Aggregate State funding for the LEP formula" means the product of the LEP per pupil amount and the statewide LEP enrollment count.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Full-time equivalent enrollment" has the meaning stated in &#xA7; 5-202 of this subtitle.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">"LEP" means limited English proficiency.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Except as provided in subparagraph (ii) of this paragraph, "LEP enrollment count" means the number of students with limited English proficiency for the prior fiscal year.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">For fiscal year 2004, "LEP enrollment count" means the greater of:</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(6)">"LEP per pupil amount" means 99% of the annual per pupil foundation amount calculated under &#xA7; 5-202 of this subtitle multiplied by the State share of LEP funding.</section>
      <section prefix="(7)">"Limited English proficiency" means non-English or limited English proficiency under the reporting requirements established by the Department for the Maryland School Performance Program.</section>
      <section prefix="(8)">"Local wealth per pupil" means a county's wealth divided by the county's full-time equivalent enrollment.</section>
      <section prefix="(9)">"State share of LEP funding" means:<section prefix="(i)">0.29 in fiscal year 2004;</section><section prefix="(ii)">0.37 in fiscal year 2005;</section><section prefix="(iii)">0.41 in fiscal year 2006;</section><section prefix="(iv)">0.46 in fiscal year 2007; and</section><section prefix="(v)">0.50 in fiscal year 2008 and each fiscal year thereafter.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(10)">"Statewide wealth per pupil" means the sum of the wealth of all counties divided by the statewide full-time equivalent enrollment.</section>
      <section prefix="(11)">"Tier I LEP funding" means:<section prefix="(i)">For fiscal year 2008 and each fiscal year thereafter, $0; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">For fiscal years 2004 through 2007, the result obtained by multiplying $1,350 by the statewide LEP enrollment count, and multiplying this product by:</section></section>
      <section prefix="(12)">"Tier II LEP funding" means the difference between aggregate State funding for the LEP formula and Tier I LEP funding.</section>
      <section prefix="(13)">"Tier II LEP per pupil amount" means the result obtained by dividing Tier II LEP funding by the statewide LEP enrollment count.</section>
      <section prefix="(14)">"Wealth" has the meaning stated in &#xA7; 5-202 of this subtitle.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">For fiscal years 2004 through 2007, the State shall distribute Tier I LEP grants and Tier II LEP grants to county boards.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">For fiscal year 2008 and each fiscal year thereafter, the State shall distribute Tier II LEP grants to county boards.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">For fiscal years 2004 through 2007, the amount of the Tier I LEP grant distributed to a county board shall be equal to the result obtained by multiplying $1,350 by the county's LEP enrollment count, and multiplying this product by:<section prefix="(i)">1.0 for fiscal year 2004;</section><section prefix="(ii)">0.75 for fiscal year 2005;</section><section prefix="(iii)">0.50 for fiscal year 2006; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">0.25 for fiscal year 2007.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">For fiscal year 2008 and each fiscal year thereafter, the State may not make Tier I LEP grants to county boards.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The amount of the Tier II LEP grant distributed to a county board shall be calculated as provided in this subsection.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">For each county, multiply the county's LEP enrollment count by the Tier II LEP per pupil amount.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">For each county, divide the result calculated under paragraph (2) of this subsection by the ratio, rounded to seven decimal places, of local wealth per pupil to statewide wealth per pupil.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">For each county, multiply the result calculated under paragraph (3) of this subsection for the county by the result, rounded to seven decimal places, that results from dividing Tier II LEP funding by the sum of all of the results calculated under paragraph (3) of this subsection for all counties.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If the amount calculated under subsection (d)(4) of this section for any county is less than the minimum Tier II LEP grant amount determined under paragraph (2) of this subsection, the State shall distribute an additional grant to the county in the amount by which the minimum Tier II LEP grant amount exceeds the result calculated under subsection (d)(4) of this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">For purposes of paragraph (1) of this subsection, the minimum Tier II LEP grant amount for each county is the result obtained by multiplying the Tier II LEP per pupil amount by the county's LEP enrollment count, and multiplying this product by:<section prefix="(i)">0.50 for fiscal year 2004;</section><section prefix="(ii)">0.66 for fiscal year 2005;</section><section prefix="(iii)">0.70 for fiscal year 2006;</section><section prefix="(iv)">0.76 for fiscal year 2007; and</section><section prefix="(v)">0.80 for fiscal year 2008 and each fiscal year thereafter.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
