<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ged" order_by="" level="1">Economic Development</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ged-23-106</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>106</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">There is a Maryland Advisory Council on Libraries.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Advisory Council consists of 12 members, 7 of whom are appointed by the Governor. Each member is entitled to participate fully and equally in the activities of the Council.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Each member shall:<section prefix="(i)">Be a resident of this State;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Be an individual of ability and integrity who is experienced in public or library affairs; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Represent the interests of the citizens of this State in better library services.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Of the appointed members:<section prefix="(i)">Five shall be selected from the public at large;</section><section prefix="(ii)">One shall be a professional librarian; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">One shall be a library trustee.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The following officials serve ex officio and each may designate someone to serve in his place:<section prefix="(i)">The Secretary of Higher Education;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The President of the Board of Trustees of Enoch Pratt Free Library;</section><section prefix="(iii)">The President of the Maryland Library Association;</section><section prefix="(iv)">The Dean of the University of Maryland College of Library and Information Services; and</section><section prefix="(v)">The President of the Maryland Educational Media Organization.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(5)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Each appointed member serves for a term of 5 years and until a successor is appointed and qualifies. These terms are staggered as required by the terms of the members serving on July 1, 1978.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">An appointed member may not serve more than two consecutive terms.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">A member appointed to fill a vacancy in an unexpired term serves only for the remainder of that term and until a successor is appointed and qualifies.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(6)">Each member of the Advisory Council:<section prefix="(i)">Serves without compensation; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Is entitled to reimbursement for expenses in accordance with the Standard State Travel Regulations.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Each year:<section prefix="(i)">The Governor shall appoint a member of the Advisory Council as its Chairman; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">The Advisory Council shall elect one of its members as its vice chairman.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Assistant Superintendent for Libraries shall:<section prefix="(i)">Serve as secretary to the Advisory Council;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Record the proceedings of the Council; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Provide necessary staff services.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Advisory Council shall meet at least once a year at the times and places its Chairman designates.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">Seven members of the Advisory Council are a quorum and at least 7 affirmative votes are required for any recommendation to:<section prefix="(i)">The Division of Library Services;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The State Superintendent;</section><section prefix="(iii)">The State Board; or</section><section prefix="(iv)">The Governor.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Advisory Council shall:<section prefix="(1)">Gather information on the needs of libraries throughout this State;</section><section prefix="(2)">Advise the Division of Library Development and Services, the State Superintendent, the State Board, and the Governor on library matters; and</section><section prefix="(3)">Promote improvement of library services in this State.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The Advisory Council may be funded annually as provided in the budget of the Division of Library Development and Services.</section>
  </text>
</law>
