<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ged" order_by="ged" level="1">Economic Development</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ged-4-319</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this section the following words have the meanings indicated....</catch_line>
  <order_by>319</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Baltimore City School System" means the system of free public schools in Baltimore City.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Center" means the Baltimore City Alternative Learning Center.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">There is a Baltimore City Alternative Learning Center in the Baltimore City School System.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Chief Executive Officer of the Baltimore City Board of School Commissioners shall appoint a Director of the Center.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Director may employ a staff or retain consultants, including psychologists, social workers, guidance counselors, and teachers.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as otherwise provided in &#xA7; 7-305(f) of this article, a student in the Baltimore City School System may be transferred to the Center if the student:<section prefix="(i)">Assaults a teacher, teacher's aide, student teacher, other professional or paraprofessional school employee, or other student;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Carries a gun, rifle, knife, or other deadly weapon onto school property; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">Commits any other act that would be a crime if committed by an adult.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Director shall review recommendations for admission of students to the Center and admit or deny admission for each student based on an assessment of the student's amenability to the services, programs, and treatment available in the Center.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Subject to paragraph (2) of this subsection, a student who is admitted to the Center shall attend classes at the Center until the Director orders the student to be transferred to another school in the Baltimore City School System.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A student may not attend the Center for more than one calendar year.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The Director shall develop and provide the following programs within the Center:<section prefix="(1)">Elementary and secondary education programs;</section><section prefix="(2)">Special education programs that meet the social and emotional needs of the students at the Center and that require the participation of the parents or guardians of the students; and</section><section prefix="(3)">Vocational and rehabilitative training programs.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(g)">The Chief Executive Officer shall report annually to the members of the Baltimore City Delegation in the General Assembly on the progress of the students in the Center.</section>
  </text>
</law>
