<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ged" order_by="" level="1">Economic Development</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ged-7-434</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>434</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Heat acclimatization" means enhancing an individual's exercise heat tolerance and ability to exercise safely and effectively in warm to hot conditions.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Practice" means a period of time a student athlete engages in physical activity during a coach-supervised, school-approved sports- or conditioning-related activity, including warm-up, stretching, weight training, and cool-down periods.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">"Preseason practice" means the initial 14 days of practice for a student athlete.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">"Recovery period" means the time between the end of one practice or walk-through and the beginning of the next practice or walk-through.</section>
      <section prefix="(6)">"Student athlete" means a student who participates in an athletic program for high school students in a State secondary school that is a member of the Maryland Public Secondary Schools Athletic Association.</section>
      <section prefix="(7)">
        <section prefix="(i)">"Walk-through" means a teaching opportunity when an athlete is not wearing protective equipment, including helmets, shoulder pads, catcher's gear, or shin guards, or using other sports-related equipment.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">"Walk-through" does not include any part of a practice period.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Department, in collaboration with the Department of Health and Mental Hygiene, each county board, the Maryland Public Secondary Schools Athletic Association, the Maryland Athletic Trainers' Association, and representatives of licensed health care providers who treat student athletes, shall develop a model policy for preseason-practice heat acclimatization guidelines for student athletes.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Each local board shall adopt preseason-practice heat acclimatization guidelines for student athletes.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The preseason-practice heat acclimatization guidelines shall include requirements for the duration of a practice time, a walk-through, and a recovery period during preseason practice.</section>
  </text>
</law>
