<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ged" order_by="ged" level="1">Economic Development</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ged-3-801</section_number>
  <catch_line>The Kent County Board consists of five members....</catch_line>
  <order_by>801</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Kent County Board consists of five members.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A candidate elected to the county board shall be a resident and registered voter of Kent County. Any member who no longer resides in Kent County may not continue as a member of the board.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The incumbent members of the Kent County Board who hold office on July 1, 2010 shall hold office until their successors are elected and qualify.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Members of the Kent County Board shall be elected from Kent County at large as follows:<section prefix="(i)">Two members of the county board shall be elected in the November general election of 2012 and every 4 years thereafter; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Three members of the county board shall be elected in the November general election of 2014 and every 4 years thereafter.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Each member serves for a term of 4 years beginning on January 1 after his election and until a successor is elected and qualifies. The terms of members are staggered and elections shall be held as provided in subsection (c) of this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Any vacancy on the county board shall be filled by a qualified individual appointed by the County Commissioners of Kent County to serve until a successor is elected and qualifies at the general election next following the creation of the vacancy and for which the deadline for the filing of candidates has not expired.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">An individual may serve for more than 2 consecutive terms.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The State Board may remove a member of the county board for:<section prefix="(i)">Immorality;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Misconduct in office;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Incompetency; or</section><section prefix="(iv)">Willful neglect of duty.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Before removing a member, the State Board shall send the member a copy of the charges against him and give him an opportunity within 10 days to request a hearing.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">If the member requests a hearing within the 10-day period:<section prefix="(i)">The State Board promptly shall hold a hearing, but a hearing may not be set within 10 days after the State Board sends the member a notice of the hearing; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">The member shall have an opportunity to be heard publicly before the State Board in his own defense, in person or by counsel.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">A member removed under this subsection has the right to a de novo review of the removal by the Circuit Court for Kent County.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
