<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="ged" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="7-120" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ged-7-120</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, "multiple-birth children" means twins, triplets, quadruplets, quintuplets, or more.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">This section applies only to children entering kindergarten through second grade.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The parent or guardian of multiple-birth children may request that the multiple-birth children or certain groups of the multiple-birth children be placed in the same classroom or separate classrooms if the children are in the same grade level at the same school.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The parent or guardian shall make the request in writing to the school principal within 14 days after:<section prefix="(i)">The first day of school; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">If the children were enrolled in the school after the school year has commenced, the first day of attendance of the children.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Except as provided in subsection (e) of this section, a school shall provide the classroom placement requested by the parent or guardian under subsection (c) of this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">At the end of 30 days, if the principal of the school, in consultation with the teacher of each classroom in which the children are placed, determines that the requested classroom placement is disruptive to the school, the principal may determine the appropriate classroom placement for the children.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The school may:<section prefix="(1)">Recommend to a parent or guardian the appropriate classroom placement for the multiple-birth children; or</section><section prefix="(2)">Provide professional educational advice to assist a parent or guardian regarding classroom placement for the multiple-birth children.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(g)">A county board may not adopt a classroom placement policy of automatically separating or placing together multiple-birth children.</section>
  </text>
</law>
