<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="ged" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="13-513" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ged-13-513</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Study Center's primary mission is research, with particular emphasis on establishing national policies related to prevention, treatment, acute care and rehabilitation, trauma and emergency medical care delivery systems, disaster epidemiology and management, injury surveillance, and data collection. It shall serve as the primary research center for the State Emergency Medical Services System.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Director of the Study Center shall work closely with the MIEMSS Director in the development of a research plan and the budget.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Director of the Study Center shall submit the budget and research plan to the EMS Board for review and comment.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Director of the Study Center shall advise and provide the opportunity for the EMS Board to comment prior to the adoption of any proposed change in the budget, mission, research plan, or other policies of the Study Center that would affect the ability of the Study Center to continue to fulfill its mission as the primary research center for the State Emergency Medical Services System.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The Director of the Study Center shall submit to the EMS Board an annual report on the budget and research plan.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">Subject to the approval of the Governor, the President of the University of Maryland, Baltimore shall appoint the Director of the Study Center. The Governor shall have 60 days to approve the appointment. If the Governor has not acted within 60 days of being notified of the appointed director, the appointed director shall be deemed approved.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">The University of Maryland, Baltimore shall receive indirect cost recoveries as stipulated in grants received by the National Study Center.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">The University System of Maryland may not transfer funds for the Study Center to any other program or purpose.</section>
  </text>
</law>
