<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="ged" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="16-603" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ged-16-603</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">There is a College of Southern Maryland, formerly known as the Charles County Community College, located in Calvert, Charles, and St. Mary's counties, Maryland.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">With other educational institutions, the College shall provide the services and programs described in &#xA7; 10-210 of this article.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The College is an institution of higher education of the State of Maryland.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Notwithstanding any other provision of this subtitle, the College shall be classified as a "local educational agency (LEA)", as defined in federal law, for purposes of federal subsidies, grants, contracts, and other programs of support for which a community college is eligible.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Calvert, Charles, and St. Mary's counties may appropriate money to pay the cost of operating the College according to the provisions of this article.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Each southern Maryland county may borrow money to purchase land and construct capital improvements for the College.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Money may be borrowed on terms and conditions the county commissioners consider proper, subject to any requirements of local law applicable to the creation of public debt.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Unless otherwise agreed to by the county commissioners, the capital expenditures for each campus are the responsibility of the county in which the campus is located.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The distribution of shared costs will be that of a regional community college as designated in &#xA7; 11-105(j)(6)(i) of this article.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
