<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ged" order_by="" level="1">Economic Development</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ged-6-202</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>202</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">On the recommendation of the county superintendent, a county board may suspend or dismiss a teacher, principal, supervisor, assistant superintendent, or other professional assistant for:<section prefix="(i)">Immorality;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Misconduct in office, including knowingly failing to report suspected child abuse in violation of &#xA7; 5-704 of the Family Law Article;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Insubordination;</section><section prefix="(iv)">Incompetency; or</section><section prefix="(v)">Willful neglect of duty.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Before removing an individual, the county board shall send the individual a copy of the charges against him and give him an opportunity within 10 days to request a hearing.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">If the individual requests a hearing within the 10-day period:<section prefix="(i)">The county board promptly shall hold a hearing, but a hearing may not be set within 10 days after the county board sends the individual a notice of the hearing; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">The individual shall have an opportunity to be heard before the county board, in person or by counsel, and to bring witnesses to the hearing.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The individual may appeal from the decision of the county board to the State Board.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">Notwithstanding any provision of local law, in Baltimore City the suspension and removal of assistant superintendents and higher levels shall be as provided by the personnel system established by the Baltimore City Board of School Commissioners under &#xA7; 4-311 of this article.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in paragraph (3) of this subsection, the probationary period of employment of a certificated employee in a local school system shall cover a period of 3 years from the date of employment and shall consist of a 1-year employment contract that may be renewed by the county board.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">A county board shall evaluate annually a nontenured certificated employee based on established performance evaluation criteria.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">Subject to subparagraph (iii) of this paragraph, if the nontenured certificated employee is not on track to qualify for tenure at any formal evaluation point:<section prefix="1.">A mentor promptly shall be assigned to the employee to provide the employee comprehensive guidance and instruction; and</section><section prefix="2.">Additional professional development shall be provided to the employee, as appropriate.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">Nothing in this paragraph shall be construed to prohibit a county board from assigning a mentor at any time during a nontenured certificated employee's employment.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Subject to subparagraph (ii) of this paragraph, if a certificated employee has achieved tenure in a local school system in the State and moves to another local school system in the State, that employee shall be tenured if the employee's contract is renewed after 1 year of probationary employment in the local school system to which the employee relocated if:<section prefix="1.">The employee's final evaluation in the local school system from which the employee departed is satisfactory or better; and</section><section prefix="2.">There has been no break in the employee's service between the two systems of longer than 1 year.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">A local school system may extend the probationary period for a certificated employee subject to subparagraph (i) of this paragraph for a second year from the date of employment if:<section prefix="1.">The employee does not qualify for tenure at the end of the first year based on established performance evaluation criteria; and</section><section prefix="2.">The employee demonstrates a strong potential for improvement.</section></section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(4)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The State Board shall adopt regulations that implement the provisions of paragraphs (1) and (2) of this subsection and define the scope of a mentoring program and professional development that will be aligned with the 3-year probationary period.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The State Board shall adopt regulations to establish standards for effective mentoring, including provisions to ensure that mentors provide mentoring that:<section prefix="1.">Is focused;</section><section prefix="2.">Is systematic;</section><section prefix="3.">Is ongoing;</section><section prefix="4.">Is of high quality;</section><section prefix="5.">Is geared to the needs of each employee being mentored;</section><section prefix="6.">Includes observations; and</section><section prefix="7.">Includes feedback.</section></section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this subsection, "student growth" means student progress assessed by multiple measures and from a clearly articulated baseline to one or more points in time.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Subject to subparagraph (iii) of this paragraph, the State Board shall adopt regulations that establish general standards for performance evaluations for certificated teachers and principals that include observations, clear standards, rigor, and claims and evidence of observed instruction.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The regulations adopted under subparagraph (i) of this paragraph shall include model performance evaluation criteria.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">Before the proposal of the regulations required under this paragraph, the State Board shall solicit information and recommendations from each local school system and convene a meeting wherein this information and these recommendations are discussed and considered.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Subject to paragraph (6) of this subsection:<section prefix="(i)">A county board shall establish performance evaluation criteria for certificated teachers and principals in the local school system based on the general standards adopted under paragraph (2) of this subsection that are mutually agreed on by the local school system and the exclusive employee representative.</section><section prefix="(ii)">Nothing in this paragraph shall be construed to require mutual agreement under subparagraph (i) of this paragraph to be governed by Subtitles 4 and 5 of this title.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The performance evaluation criteria developed under paragraph (3) of this subsection:<section prefix="(i)">Shall include data on student growth as a significant component of the evaluation and as one of multiple measures; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">May not be based solely on an existing or newly created single examination or assessment.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(5)">
        <section prefix="(i)">An existing or newly created single examination or assessment may be used as one of the multiple measures.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">No single criterion shall account for more than 35% of the total performance evaluation criteria.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(6)">If a local school system and the exclusive employee representative fail to mutually agree under paragraph (3) of this subsection, the model performance evaluation criteria adopted by the State Board under paragraph (2)(ii) of this subsection shall take effect in the local jurisdiction 6 months following the final adoption of the regulations.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
