<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ged" order_by="" level="1">Economic Development</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ged-11-102</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>102</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Commission consists of 12 members appointed by the Governor with the advice and consent of the Senate.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">One member of the Commission shall be:<section prefix="(i)">A regularly enrolled student in good standing at a Maryland institution of higher education to which the Commission has issued a certificate of approval under this title or that may operate without a certificate of approval under &#xA7; 11-202.1 of this title; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">A resident of Maryland.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">To the extent possible, the position of student member shall be rotated among all segments of higher education on an equal basis.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The student member may not be the Chairperson of the Student Advisory Council.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In making appointments to the Commission, the Governor shall consider representation from all parts of the State.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Except as provided in subsection (b) of this section, the members of the Commission shall be residents of the State and shall be appointed from the general public.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Except for the student member, each member of the Commission serves for a term of 5 years and until a successor is appointed and qualifies.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The student member serves for a term of 1 year, beginning July 1 and ending June 30, and until a successor is appointed and qualifies.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A member appointed to fill a vacancy in an unexpired term serves only for the remainder of that term and until a successor is appointed and qualifies.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">Except for the student member, a member may be reappointed but may not serve more than 2 consecutive full terms.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">Each member of the Commission:<section prefix="(1)">Serves without compensation; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Is entitled to reimbursement for expenses in accordance with the Standard State Travel Regulations.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(g)">During a term of service on the Commission, a member may not be employed, except for the student member as a part-time student employee, by any agency or institution of postsecondary education or be a member of the governing board of any agency or institution of postsecondary education that is subject to the jurisdiction of the Commission.</section>
  </text>
</law>
