<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ged" order_by="ged" level="1">Economic Development</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ged-6-112</section_number>
  <catch_line>// EFFECTIVE UNTIL JUNE 30, 2013 PER CHAPTER 309 OF 2007 //...</catch_line>
  <order_by>112</order_by>
  <text>// EFFECTIVE UNTIL JUNE 30, 2013 PER CHAPTER 309 OF 2007 //<section prefix="(a)">There is a program of State and local aid to teachers who pursue certification or renewal of certification by the National Board for Professional Teaching Standards known as the State and Local Aid Program for Certification by the National Board for Professional Teaching Standards.</section><section prefix="(b)">Each school year, the State Board shall select, consistent with the amount provided in the State budget for the Program, a maximum of 1,000 teachers to participate in the Program.</section><section prefix="(c)">The State Board may provide aid under the Program to a participant for up to one retake of an unsuccessful entry on the National Board for Professional Teaching Standards assessment.</section><section prefix="(d)">The State Board shall adopt regulations to implement and administer the Program established under this section, including:<section prefix="(1)">Procedures for submitting applications for aid; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Criteria for the selection of recipients of aid.</section></section><section prefix="(e)"><section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in subsection (c) of this section, each teacher selected by the State Board to receive aid shall receive from the State an amount equal to the certification fee charged by the National Board for Professional Teaching Standards.</section><section prefix="(2)">Each county shall pay to the State one-third of the cost of certification for each teacher who participates in the Program who teaches in the county.</section><section prefix="(3)"><section prefix="(i)">A teacher who does not complete all the requirements for assessment by the National Board for Professional Teaching Standards shall reimburse the State the full amount of the aid received to participate in the Program.</section><section prefix="(ii)">The State shall reimburse the county the amount received under paragraph (2) of this subsection on receipt of the reimbursement of aid from a teacher under this paragraph.</section><section prefix="(iii)">The provisions of subparagraph (i) of this paragraph do not apply to a teacher who completes all the requirements for assessment by the National Board for Professional Teaching Standards but who does not receive certification.</section></section></section><section prefix="(f)">The State Board shall establish a statewide staff development plan that utilizes the skills and knowledge of teachers who have obtained National Board certification.</section></text>
</law>
