<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ged" order_by="" level="1">Economic Development</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ged-7-424</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>424</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Bullying, harassment, or intimidation" means intentional conduct, including verbal, physical, or written conduct, or an intentional electronic communication, that:<section prefix="(i)">Creates a hostile educational environment by substantially interfering with a student's educational benefits, opportunities, or performance, or with a student's physical or psychological well-being and is:<section prefix="1.">Motivated by an actual or a perceived personal characteristic including race, national origin, marital status, sex, sexual orientation, gender identity, religion, ancestry, physical attributes, socioeconomic status, familial status, or physical or mental ability or disability; or</section><section prefix="2.">Threatening or seriously intimidating; and</section></section><section prefix="(ii)"><section prefix="1.">Occurs on school property, at a school activity or event, or on a school bus; or</section><section prefix="2.">Substantially disrupts the orderly operation of a school.</section></section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Electronic communication" means a communication transmitted by means of an electronic device, including a telephone, cellular phone, computer, or pager.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Department shall require a county board to report incidents of bullying, harassment, or intimidation against students attending a public school under the jurisdiction of the county board.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">An incident of bullying, harassment, or intimidation may be reported by:<section prefix="(i)">A student;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The parent, guardian, or close adult relative of a student; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">A school staff member.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Department shall create a standard victim of bullying, harassment, or intimidation report form.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Each victim of bullying, harassment, or intimidation report form shall:<section prefix="(i)">Identify the victim and the alleged perpetrator, if known;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Indicate the age of the victim and alleged perpetrator;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Describe the incident, including alleged statements made by the alleged perpetrator;</section><section prefix="(iv)">Indicate the location of the incident;</section><section prefix="(v)">Identify any physical injury suffered by the victim and describe the seriousness and any permanent effects of the injury;</section><section prefix="(vi)">Indicate the number of days a student is absent from school, if any, as a result of the incident;</section><section prefix="(vii)">Identify any request for psychological services initiated by the victim or the victim's family due to psychological injuries suffered; and</section><section prefix="(viii)">Include instructions on how to fill out the form and the mailing address to where the form shall be sent.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A county board shall distribute copies of the victim of bullying, harassment, or intimidation report form to each public school under the county board's jurisdiction.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Each county board shall submit summaries of report forms filed with the county board to the State Board on or before January 31 each year.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A county board shall delete any information that identifies an individual.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The information contained in a victim of bullying, harassment, or intimidation report form in accordance with subsection (c) of this section:<section prefix="(1)">Is confidential and may not be redisclosed except as otherwise provided under the Family Education Rights and Privacy Act or this section; and</section><section prefix="(2)">May not be made a part of a student's permanent educational record.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Department shall submit a report on or before March 31 each year to the Senate Education, Health, and Environmental Affairs Committee and the House Ways and Means Committee, in accordance with &#xA7; 2-1246 of the State Government Article, consisting of a summary of the information included in the victim of bullying, harassment, or intimidation report forms filed with the county boards the previous year.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The report submitted by the Department shall include, to the extent feasible:<section prefix="(i)">A description of the act constituting the bullying, harassment, or intimidation;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The age of the victim and alleged perpetrator;</section><section prefix="(iii)">The allegation of the alleged perpetrator's motive;</section><section prefix="(iv)">A description of the investigation of the complaint and any corrective action taken by the appropriate school authorities;</section><section prefix="(v)">The number of days a student is absent from school, if any, as a result of the incident; and</section><section prefix="(vi)">The number of false allegations reported.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
