<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="ged" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="16-414.1" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ged-16-414.1</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Agreement" means a written contract between the public employer and an employee organization.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Arbitration" means a procedure whereby parties involved in a grievance dispute submit their differences to an impartial third party for a final and binding decision.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">
        <section prefix="(i)">"Collective bargaining" means:</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">In collective bargaining, a party may not be compelled to agree to a proposal or be required to make a concession to the other party.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(5)">"Commissioner" means the State Commissioner of Labor and Industry or the Commissioner's designee.</section>
      <section prefix="(6)">"Confidential employee" means a public employee whose unrestricted access to personnel, budgetary, or fiscal data subject to use by the public employer in collective bargaining, or whose close, continuing working relationship with those responsible for negotiating on behalf of the public employer, would make the employee's membership in an employee organization as a rank and file employee incompatible with the employee's duties.</section>
      <section prefix="(7)">"Employee organization" means an organization of public employees which has as one of its primary purposes representing those employees in collective bargaining.</section>
      <section prefix="(8)">"Exclusive representative" means an employee organization which has been certified by the Commissioner as representing the employees of a bargaining unit.</section>
      <section prefix="(9)">"Fact-finding" means a process which includes:<section prefix="(i)">The identification of the major issues in a particular impasse;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The review of the positions of the parties;</section><section prefix="(iii)">A resolution of factual differences by an impartial individual or panel; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">The making of recommendations for settlement of the impasse.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(10)">"Grievance" means a dispute concerning the application or interpretation of the terms of a collective bargaining agreement.</section>
      <section prefix="(11)">"Impasse" means a failure by the public employer and an exclusive representative to achieve agreement in the course of collective bargaining.</section>
      <section prefix="(12)">"Mediation" means assistance by an impartial third party to reconcile a dispute arising out of collective bargaining through interpretation, suggestion, and advice.</section>
      <section prefix="(13)">"Public employee" means an employee employed by the public employer, except:<section prefix="(i)">Employees involved directly in the determination of policy;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Supervisory or confidential employees;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Student assistants; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">Faculty.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(14)">"Public employer" means the Board of Community College Trustees for Prince George's County.</section>
      <section prefix="(15)">"Strike" means a public employee's refusal, in concerted action with others, to report for duty, or willful absence from the position, or stoppage of work, or abstinence in whole or in part from the proper performance of the duties of employment, for the purpose of inducing, influencing, or coercing a change in the wages, hours, or other terms and conditions of employment.</section>
      <section prefix="(16)">"Supervisory employee" means a public employee who has the authority to act on behalf of the public employer to:<section prefix="(i)">Hire, transfer, suspend, lay off, recall, promote, discharge, assign, reward, or discipline other employees;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Direct employees responsibly;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Adjust employee grievances; or</section><section prefix="(iv)">Recommend effectively one of the actions set forth in items (i) through (iii) of this paragraph, if:</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The public employer shall determine whether a public employee is to be considered a public employee for collective bargaining purposes. Either party or an employee organization may appeal the determination to the Commissioner for a final and binding decision.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">After receiving a petition for an election for exclusive representative, the Commissioner shall:<section prefix="(i)">Investigate the petition for purposes of verification and validation;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Conduct a public hearing, receiving written and oral testimony; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">File an order defining the most appropriate bargaining unit.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)"/>
        <section prefix="(ii)">In defining a bargaining unit, the Commissioner shall consider, in addition to other relevant factors:</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">After October 1, 2001, an election or recognition of an exclusive representative shall be conducted by the Commissioner for each unit after the requirements of subsections (b) and (c) of this section have been met by that unit.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A petition for an election may be submitted by:<section prefix="(i)">An employee organization that demonstrates that 30 percent of the employees in a bargaining unit wish to be represented for collective bargaining by an exclusive representative;</section><section prefix="(ii)">A public employee, a group of public employees, or an employee organization that demonstrates that 30 percent of the employees assert the designated exclusive representative is no longer the representative of the majority of employees in the unit; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">If the Commissioner finds, on investigation of the public employer's petition, that a valid question of representation exists, a public employer that demonstrates that one or more employee organizations has presented to it a claim, supported by substantial proof, to be certified as the exclusive representative.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">There shall be on the ballot:<section prefix="(i)">The name or names of the employee organization submitting the valid petition;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The name of any other employee organization designated in a valid petition signed by more than 10 percent of the employees in the appropriate bargaining unit; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">A provision for "no representation".</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">
        <section prefix="(i)">In any election where none of the choices on the ballot receives a majority of the votes cast, a runoff election shall be conducted, with the ballot providing for a selection between the two choices receiving the highest number of ballots cast in the election.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">An employee organization receiving a majority of votes cast in an election shall be certified by the Commissioner as the exclusive representative for collective bargaining purposes.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">An employee organization may be certified as an exclusive representative only as provided under this section.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(5)">The election of an exclusive representative shall be conducted by:<section prefix="(i)">Secret ballot; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">The Commissioner or the Commissioner's designee.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(6)">The election of an exclusive representative may not be conducted in any unit in which a valid election has been held within the preceding 2 years.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The public employer shall extend to an employee organization certified as exclusive representative the right to represent the public employees of the unit involved in collective bargaining and in the settlement of grievances.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">An employee organization certified as the exclusive representative for a bargaining unit shall:<section prefix="(i)">Serve as the bargaining agent for all public employees in the bargaining unit; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Represent fairly and without discrimination each public employee in the unit without regard to whether the employee is a member of the employee organization.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">On behalf of the exclusive representative for payment to the exclusive representative, the public employer shall automatically deduct from the paycheck of each public employee in a bargaining unit represented by an employee organization certified as an exclusive representative for that bargaining unit:<section prefix="(i)">Any union dues authorized and owed by the employee to the organization; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Any service fees authorized and owed by the employee to the organization.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Every employee organization which has or seeks certification as an exclusive representative shall file, with the public employer and the Commissioner, a copy of the employee organization's constitution and bylaws.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">Each change and amendment to the constitution and bylaws shall be promptly reported.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(5)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Each employee organization shall file with the public employer and the Commissioner an annual report.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The annual report shall include a financial report, signed by the organization's president and treasurer or corresponding principal officers, that contains information in the detail necessary to accurately disclose the financial condition and operations of the organization.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(6)">The constitution or bylaws of an employee organization shall require that the employee organization:<section prefix="(i)">Pledge that the organization will accept members without regard to age, race, sex, religion, marital status, disability, or national origin;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Keep accurate accounts of all income and expenses and prepare an annual financial report;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Keep organization accounts open for inspection by any member of the organization;</section><section prefix="(iv)">Make any loans to officers and agents of the organization only on the same terms and conditions that loans are made available to all other members;</section><section prefix="(v)">Ensure that periodic elections are by secret ballot and subject to recognized safeguards concerning the equal right of all members to nominate, seek office, and vote;</section><section prefix="(vi)">Ensure that individual members have the right to participate in the affairs of the organization; and</section><section prefix="(vii)">Develop and maintain procedures for disciplinary actions that are fair and equitable.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(7)">The Commissioner may not certify an employee organization for the purpose of negotiating with the public employer if:<section prefix="(i)">The organization has not filed an annual report; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">The organization's constitution and bylaws do not conform to the requirements of paragraph (6) of this subsection.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">Collective bargaining shall include all matters relating to:<section prefix="(1)">Wages, hours, and other terms and conditions of employment; and</section><section prefix="(2)">The procedures for the employee organization to receive membership dues and service fees through payroll deduction.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(g)">In the course of collective bargaining, the public employer and the exclusive representative shall make every reasonable effort to conclude negotiations prior to the budget submission date of the public employer, in order that the governing body of Prince George's County may act on the operating budget of the public employer.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If in the course of collective bargaining a party deems that an impasse exists, that party may request the services of the Commissioner in mediation or engage another mutually agreed upon mediator.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">By mutual agreement, the parties may engage in fact-finding.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)"/>
        <section prefix="(iii)">The parties shall bear equally the costs of fact-finding.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(i)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A public employee may not engage in a strike.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A public employee may not receive pay or compensation from the public employer for any period during which the public employee is engaged in a strike.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">If a strike of public employees occurs in Prince George's County, a court of competent jurisdiction may enjoin the strike at the request of the public employer.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">If an employee organization certified as an exclusive representative engages in a strike, the Commissioner shall revoke the organization's certification as exclusive representative.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">An employee organization which engages in a strike and has its certification revoked shall be ineligible to be certified as an exclusive representative for a period of 1 year following the end of the strike.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(j)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The public employer and the exclusive representative shall execute a written agreement by incorporating any matters of agreement reached on wages, hours, and other terms and conditions of employment.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A collective bargaining agreement may include a provision for the arbitration of grievances arising under an agreement.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">A collective bargaining agreement may not include matters relating to the employees' or teachers' retirement systems otherwise covered by the Annotated Code of Maryland.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">Subparagraph (i) of this paragraph does not prohibit a discussion of the terms of the retirement systems in the course of collective bargaining.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The terms of a collective bargaining agreement shall supersede any conflicting regulations or administrative policies of the public employer.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">A request for funds necessary to implement a collective bargaining agreement shall be submitted by the public employer in a timely fashion for consideration in the budget process of the county.</section>
      <section prefix="(6)">Not later than 20 days after final budget action by the governing body of Prince George's County, if a request for funds necessary to implement a collective bargaining agreement is reduced, modified, or rejected by the governing body, either party to the agreement may reopen the agreement.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(k)">The public employer has the right to:<section prefix="(1)">Determine how the statutory mandate and goals of the college, including the functions and programs of the college, its overall budget, and its organizational structure, are to be carried out; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Direct college personnel.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(l)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Public employees have the right to:<section prefix="(i)">Organize;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Form, join, or assist any employee organization;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Bargain collectively through representatives they have chosen;</section><section prefix="(iv)">Engage in other lawful concerted activity for the purpose of collective bargaining; or</section><section prefix="(v)">Refrain from engaging in the activities listed under this paragraph.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">A public employee or group of public employees has the right, at any time, to:</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The exclusive representative has the right to be present during any meeting involving the presentation or adjustment of a grievance.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">The public employer has the duty to hear a grievance and participate in the adjustment of the grievance.</section>
        <section prefix="(iv)">The adjustment of a grievance may not be inconsistent with the terms of the collective bargaining agreement then in effect.</section>
        <section prefix="(v)">The public employer shall give prompt notice of any adjustment of a grievance to the exclusive representative.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The public employer and a public employee organization may not interfere with, intimidate, restrain, coerce, or discriminate against a public employee because the employee exercises rights granted under this subsection.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(m)">If a public general law on collective bargaining generally applicable to community colleges becomes effective, the authority granted under this section, any procedures adopted under this section, and any decision, action, or agreement made under this section shall expire and become void.</section>
    <section prefix="(n)">Except as provided in this section, this section may not be interpreted to render the provisions of Title 4, Subtitles 1 through 3 of the Labor and Employment Article applicable to employment at Prince George's Community College.</section>
  </text>
</law>
