<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ged" order_by="" level="1">Economic Development</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ged-24-508</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>508</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Historic St. Mary's City Commission and the Board of Trustees of St. Mary's College of Maryland are hereby authorized to undertake joint programs and otherwise to work collaboratively under contract or other agreement acceptable to the governing boards of each institution, for the purpose of furthering the missions of both institutions.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Commission and the College may contract or otherwise agree to work jointly to sponsor high quality education programs and activities for both the academic and general communities and for all age groups, including elementary, secondary, college, and adult education programs as well as teacher training programs in curriculum areas of joint focus, such as archaeology, colonial American history, and Chesapeake culture and ecology.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Commission and College may develop jointly beneficial, promotional, marketing, fundraising, tourism, special events, and other outreach efforts.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The College and Commission may by contract or mutual agreement perform administrative tasks by one institution for the other including, but not limited to, personnel, procurement and insurance claim processing, purchasing, accounting, information system design, acquisition, installation and service, security, maintenance, historic landscape design, catering and general food services, and archaeological survey and mitigation services.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">Provided they are supportive of the distinctive mission of each institution, the Commission and College may undertake any other joint activity or action by formal or informal agreement or contract.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">Notwithstanding any joint activities or programs carried out by the College and the Commission, or administrative action undertaken by the College or the Commission for the benefit of the other institution, neither the College nor the Commission shall be liable for any direct or indirect actions of the other institution, or its trustees, Commissioners, employees, or agents as the case may be.</section>
  </text>
</law>
