<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="ged" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="3-901" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ged-3-901</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Elected member" means 1 of the 7 elected and voting members of the Montgomery County Board or a member appointed to fill a vacancy of 1 of these 7 members.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Board of Education District" means a geographic area of Montgomery County in which an elected member of the Montgomery County Board of Education must be a legal resident. The geographic area of each district is described in subsection (f) of this section. Each district shall be substantially equal in population, and the districts shall be reapportioned on the basis of each decennial census of the United States.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Montgomery County Board consists of:<section prefix="(1)">5 elected members, each of whom resides in a different board of education district;</section><section prefix="(2)">2 elected members who may reside anywhere in the county; and</section><section prefix="(3)">1 student member.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">An elected member of the county board shall be a registered voter of Montgomery County.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Members of the Montgomery County Board shall be elected at the general election every 2 years as required by subsection (f) of this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The student member shall be a bona fide resident of Montgomery County and a regularly enrolled junior or senior year student from a Montgomery County public high school.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The nomination and election process shall be as agreed on by the county board and the Montgomery County region of the Maryland Association of Student Councils. This agreement shall include a process by which to replace one or both of the final candidates if they are unable to proceed in the election. Any student enrolled in a middle or high school in the Montgomery County public schools may:<section prefix="(i)">Nominate a student member candidate;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Vote for delegates from the student's school, who in turn vote in a nominating convention to reduce to 2 the number of candidates for student board member if there are 3 or more candidates; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Vote directly for 1 of the 2 remaining student board member candidates.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The candidate receiving the second highest number of votes in the direct election shall become the alternate student member. The alternate shall serve if the student member is unable to complete his elected term.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">Except as provided in paragraphs (5), (6), and (7) of this subsection, the student member has the same rights and privileges of an elected member.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">Unless invited to attend by the affirmative vote of a majority of the county board, the student member may not attend an executive session that relates to:<section prefix="(i)">Hearings held under &#xA7; 6-202(a) of this article; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">Collective bargaining.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(6)">As provided in paragraph (7) of this subsection, the student member shall vote on all matters except those relating to:<section prefix="(i)">&#xA7; 6-202(a) of this article;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Collective bargaining;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Capital and operating budgets; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">School closings, reopenings, and boundaries.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(7)">On a majority vote of the elected members, the board may determine, on a case by case basis, whether a matter under consideration is covered by the exclusionary provisions listed in paragraph (6) of this subsection.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Each elected member serves for a term of 4 years beginning on December 1 after the member's election and until a successor is elected and qualifies. The terms of elected members are staggered as required by the terms of the members serving on the county board as of July 1, 1978 so that 4 members are elected in gubernatorial election years and 3 members are elected in presidential election years.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Elected members of the county board shall be elected by the voters of the entire county.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Of the 3 members elected in 1992 and every 4 years thereafter, 1 shall reside in Board of Education District 2 and 1 shall reside in Board of Education District 4. The third member may reside in any part of the county.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">Of the 4 members elected in 1990 and every 4 years thereafter, 1 shall reside in Board of Education District 1, 1 shall reside in Board of Education District 3, and 1 shall reside in Board of Education District 5. The fourth member may reside in any part of the county.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">The descriptions of board of education districts in this subsection refer to the geographical boundaries of the election districts and the precincts:</section>
        <section prefix="(iv)">Where precincts are split between Board of Education Districts, census tract and block numbers, as indicated in the P.L. 94-171 data or shown on the P.L. 171 census block maps provided by the U.S.  Bureau of the Census and referred to in this subtitle, are used to define the boundaries of the education districts.</section>
        <section prefix="(v)">Board of Education District 1 consists of:</section>
        <section prefix="(vi)">Board of Education District 2 consists of:</section>
        <section prefix="(vii)">Board of Education District 3 consists of:</section>
        <section prefix="(viii)">Board of Education District 4 consists of:</section>
        <section prefix="(ix)">Board of Education District 5 consists of:</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(4)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The student member serves for a term of 1 year beginning on July 1 after the election.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The student member shall be replaced for the remainder of the term by the alternate student member if the student member:</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">The elected members of the county board shall select a student to complete the remainder of the term if the student member is replaced as provided in subparagraph (ii) of this paragraph and the alternate member:</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(5)">The remaining members of the county board shall select a qualified individual to fill any vacancy on the elected board for the remainder of that term and until a successor is elected and qualifies.</section>
      <section prefix="(6)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Subject to subparagraph (ii) of this paragraph, an elected county board member shall forfeit the office if the member fails to reside in the board of education district from which the member was elected.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">If the failure to continue to reside in the district is caused by an alteration in the board of education district boundaries because of reapportionment, the member may complete the term for which the member was elected.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">In the event of a vacancy caused by a member who is required to reside in a particular board of education district, the person appointed to fill the vacancy shall reside in the same district at the time of appointment and while filling out the unexpired term.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Montgomery County Council may remove a member of the county board for:<section prefix="(i)">Immorality;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Misconduct in office;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Incompetency; or</section><section prefix="(iv)">Willful neglect of duty.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Before removing a member, the County Council shall provide the member a copy of the charges against him and give him an opportunity within 10 days to request a hearing.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">If the member requests a hearing within the 10-day period:<section prefix="(i)">The County Council promptly shall hold a hearing, but a hearing may not be set within 10 days after the County Council sends the member a notice of the hearing; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">The member shall have an opportunity to be heard publicly before the County Council in the member's own defense, in person or by counsel.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">A member removed under this subsection has the right to a de novo review of the removal by the Circuit Court for Montgomery County.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
