<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ged" order_by="" level="1">Economic Development</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ged-16-202</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>202</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Two or more counties may agree to establish a region and to support a regional community college.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Commission may authorize a regional community college for the region.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this subsection, "county board of community college trustees" means:<section prefix="(i)">The board of community college trustees, if any; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">The county board of education in any county that does not have a board of community college trustees.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Except as otherwise provided in this subsection, the county boards of community college trustees for each county in a region constitute the board of regional community college trustees.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">If the counties in a region have different numbers of members on their county board of community college trustees, each county board of community college trustees shall elect, to serve as regional community college trustees, the number of its members equal to the number of members on the smallest board of community college trustees in the region.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">A board of regional community college trustees:<section prefix="(i)">May not have more than 12 members; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Shall have an equal number of members from each county in the region.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(5)">If requested to do so by a county government, the Governor shall appoint the regional community college trustees from that county.</section>
      <section prefix="(6)">The county superintendent of each county in the region is, ex officio, a member of the board of regional community college trustees, and shall attend meetings but may not vote.</section>
      <section prefix="(7)">Each board of regional community college trustees shall:<section prefix="(i)">Elect one of its members as its chairman;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Designate the president of the regional community college as its secretary-treasurer; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Determine the time and place of its meetings and may adopt rules for the conduct of its meetings.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Any board of regional community college trustees established under subsection (b) of this section may request the Governor to appoint a new board.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">After a request is made, the Governor, with the advice and consent of the Senate, shall appoint seven individuals to the new board.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The initial members shall be appointed as provided in &#xA7; 16-101 of this title.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
