<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ged" order_by="ged" level="1">Economic Development</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ged-16-311</section_number>
  <catch_line>Except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, this section applies to every contract for a...</catch_line>
  <order_by>311</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, this section applies to every contract for any building, improvement, equipment, or supplies.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">This section does not apply to:<section prefix="(i)">The purchase of books or other materials for instruction;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Emergency repairs;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Any contract or purchase made by a county for a community college under procedures authorized by the county charter or an act of the General Assembly; or</section><section prefix="(iv)">Any contract or purchase that qualifies as a "small procurement" as defined in the State Procurement Regulations.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">All procurements shall be by competitive sealed bids, as described in this section, unless one of the following methods is specifically authorized:<section prefix="(1)">Competitive sealed proposals under &#xA7; 16-313 of this subtitle;</section><section prefix="(2)">Sole source procurement under &#xA7; 16-314 of this subtitle; or</section><section prefix="(3)">Noncompetitive negotiation under &#xA7; 16-314.1 of this subtitle.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The board of trustees, at least 2 weeks before bids are to be filed, shall advertise for bids in at least one newspaper published in the county.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The board of trustees may name in the specifications and advertisements for bids the particular make, kind, or brand of article to be contracted for or purchased.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The board of trustees of each community college may provide for the prequalification of persons as prospective responsible bidders for procurements other than leases of real property.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If a board of trustees uses a prequalification procedure for awarding a procurement contract:<section prefix="(i)">A person who is not prequalified may submit a bid or proposal; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">After bid opening or receipt of proposals and before awarding the procurement contract, a procurement officer may determine that:<section prefix="1.">A person who was not prequalified at the time of bid opening or receipt of proposals is a responsible bidder; or</section><section prefix="2.">A prequalified person is not a responsible bidder.</section></section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in subsection (f) of this section, the contract shall be awarded to the lowest responsible bidder, who conforms to the specifications, with consideration given to:<section prefix="(i)">The quantities involved;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The time required for delivery;</section><section prefix="(iii)">The purpose for which required;</section><section prefix="(iv)">The competence and responsibility of the bidder; and</section><section prefix="(v)">The ability of the bidder to perform the contract satisfactorily.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The board of trustees may reject any and all bids and readvertise for other bids.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this subsection, the term "minority business enterprise" has the meaning stated in &#xA7; 14-301 of the State Finance and Procurement Article.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">In Montgomery County, by resolution and by implementing rules and regulations, the Board of Trustees of Montgomery Community College shall establish a mandatory minority business utilization program to facilitate the participation of responsible certified minority business enterprises in contracts awarded by the Board of Trustees of Montgomery Community College in accordance with competitive bidding requirements.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">Repealed.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">A contract entered into or purchase made in violation of this section is void.</section>
  </text>
</law>
