<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ged" order_by="" level="1">Economic Development</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ged-13-305</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>305</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The medical system will serve as the primary clinical setting for University students in health care fields to receive educational and research experiences. The clinical faculties of the School of Medicine and Dental School will be the sources for the medical staff of the medical system. The same persons will serve both as Chairmen of the Clinical Science Departments of the School of Medicine and chiefs of the corresponding clinical services of the medical system. The University and the Medical System Corporation will institute appropriate procedures to effect such appointments.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Medical System Corporation shall utilize both Medical System Corporation employees and medical system University personnel.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Prior to the transfer date, each University employee working in the medical system shall elect to be either a Medical System Corporation employee or a part of medical system University personnel. No University employee may be required to become an employee of the Medical System Corporation as a condition of employment or promotion. All medical system University personnel are University employees in all respects.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">With respect to promotion opportunities, the Medical System Corporation shall treat medical system University personnel on the same basis as Medical System Corporation employees.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The Medical System Corporation shall establish an integrated seniority list composed of Medical System Corporation employees and medical system University personnel. Each listed employee's seniority will be calculated by including all employment with the University or the Medical System Corporation or both.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Sections 15-501 through 15-504 of the State Government Article shall not bar an official or employee of the University from becoming a director, official, or employee of the Medical System Corporation or participating in matters involving the Corporation and shall not prevent the Executive Director of the Maryland Institute for Emergency Medical Services Systems from becoming a voting Director of the Medical System Corporation.</section>
  </text>
</law>
