<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ged" order_by="ged" level="1">Economic Development</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ged-5-602</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this subtitle, "construction or improvement" means the planning, design, engineering, alteration,...</catch_line>
  <order_by>602</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this subtitle, "construction or improvement" means the planning, design, engineering, alteration, construction, reconstruction, enlargement, expansion, extension, improvement, replacement, rehabilitation, renovation, upgrading, repair, or capital equipping.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A county may issue bonds to finance any or all of the costs of construction or improvement of public schools in the county provided that the construction and improvement contracts and subcontracts comply with the requirements of Title 17, Subtitle 2 and Title 14 of the State Finance and Procurement Article if the requirements would otherwise be applicable.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Bonds shall be authorized by a resolution of the governing body of the county.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The resolution shall:<section prefix="(i)">Generally describe the public school construction or improvements to be financed through the sale of the bonds;</section><section prefix="(ii)">State the maximum principal amount of the bonds;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Describe the sources of repayment of the bonds;</section><section prefix="(iv)">State the maximum term of the bonds, which may not exceed 30 years; and</section><section prefix="(v)">Describe any terms or conditions under which the bonds may be redeemed before maturity.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The bonds shall:<section prefix="(1)">Be dated and bear interest at a rate specified in the resolution;</section><section prefix="(2)">Mature within 30 years of the date of issuance of the bonds;</section><section prefix="(3)">Be issued at, above, or below par value, for cash or other consideration;</section><section prefix="(4)">Be payable at a time, in the denomination, in registered form, within the meaning of Article 31, &#xA7; 30 of the Code, as specified in the resolution;</section><section prefix="(5)">Carry the registration and privileges as to conversion and for the replacement of mutilated, lost, or destroyed bonds, as specified in the resolution;</section><section prefix="(6)">Be payable in lawful money of the United States of America at a designated place;</section><section prefix="(7)">Be subject to the terms and conditions specified in the resolution; and</section><section prefix="(8)">Be sold in the manner, including private or negotiated sale, and upon the terms, specified in the resolution.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The county may enter into agreements with agents, banks, fiduciaries, insurers, or others to:<section prefix="(1)">Enhance the marketability of and security for the bonds; or</section><section prefix="(2)">Secure any tender option granted to the holders of the bonds.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">If any officer whose signature appears on a bond ceases to be an officer before delivery of the bonds, the signature is valid and sufficient for all purposes.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">The bonds, their issue, and their sale may be exempt from the provisions of Sections 9, 10, and 11 of Article 31 of the Code.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, the net proceeds of the sale of the bonds may only be applied to the construction or improvement of public school facilities, as described in the resolution authorizing the issuance of the bonds.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If the net proceeds of the sale of any bonds exceeds the amount needed for the construction or improvement of the public school facilities, as described in the resolution, the excess funds shall be applied to:<section prefix="(i)">The payment of interest on the bonds;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The payment of the next principal maturity of the bonds;</section><section prefix="(iii)">The redemption of any part of the bonds that are redeemable before maturity; or</section><section prefix="(iv)">If authorized by a resolution issued by the governing body of the county, the construction or improvement of other public school facilities.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(i)">Bonds issued under this subtitle are negotiable instruments under the laws of this State.</section>
    <section prefix="(j)">Before the preparation of bonds, the county may issue bond anticipation notes in accordance with Article 31, &#xA7; 12 of the Code.</section>
  </text>
</law>
