<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="ged" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="7-103" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ged-7-103</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Except as provided in subsections (b), (e), and (f) of this section, each public school under the jurisdiction of a county board:<section prefix="(1)"><section prefix="(i)">Shall be open for pupil attendance for at least 180 actual school days and a minimum of 1,080 school hours during a 10-month period in each school year; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">If normal school attendance is prevented because of conditions described in subsection (b) of this section, shall be open for at least 1,080 hours during a 10-month period;</section></section><section prefix="(2)">Shall be open for pupil attendance a minimum of 3 hours during each school day; and</section><section prefix="(3)">May not be open on Saturdays, Sundays, or holidays in order to meet the 180-day or 1,080-hour requirement of this subsection.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If a county board submits a written application to the State Board that describes a demonstrated effort by the county board to comply with subsection (a) of this section, the State Board may permit:<section prefix="(i)">Adjustments in the length of the school year;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Exceptions from the requirement that the school year be completed within a 10-month period;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Adjustments in the length of the school day; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">Schools to be open on holidays.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">These adjustments may be granted only if normal school attendance is prevented because of:<section prefix="(i)">Natural disaster;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Civil disaster; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">Severe weather conditions.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Education funding from State or local sources may not be reduced if there are less than 180 school days in any year because of an approved application under this subsection.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">In case of emergency, the State Board may open schools on holidays.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The following days are public school holidays:<section prefix="(i)">Thanksgiving Day and the day after;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Christmas Eve and from then through January 1;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Martin Luther King, Jr. Day;</section><section prefix="(iv)">Presidents' Day;</section><section prefix="(v)">The Friday before Easter and from then through the Monday after Easter;</section><section prefix="(vi)">Memorial Day; and</section><section prefix="(vii)">Primary and general election days.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If the federal and State observances of a holiday are on different days, the board of education of each county shall determine which date shall be the date of observance for the public schools within the county.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The public schools shall devote a part of the day to appropriate exercises for the following days:<section prefix="(i)">Washington's Birthday;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Lincoln's Birthday;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Veterans' Day;</section><section prefix="(iv)">Columbus Day;</section><section prefix="(v)">Arbor Day; and</section><section prefix="(vi)">Any other day of national significance.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">Notwithstanding any other provisions of this article, the public schools, in the following counties, may remain open and in session on primary and general election days:<section prefix="(i)">Calvert;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Caroline;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Dorchester;</section><section prefix="(iv)">Kent;</section><section prefix="(v)">Talbot; and</section><section prefix="(vi)">Worcester.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Except as provided in subsection (e) of this section, the State Board shall divide the school year into the terms it considers appropriate.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The county boards of Allegany, Anne Arundel, Calvert, Howard, Montgomery, and Prince George's counties, and the Board of School Commissioners of Baltimore City, may elect to operate one or more schools within the county or Baltimore City on a year-round basis, provided that the 180-day and the minimum hour requirements under this section are met.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Nothing in this section precludes a county board from conducting a year-round pilot study or program that is funded by the county board.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">Publicly funded prekindergarten programs are not subject to the requirements of subsection (a) of this section.</section>
  </text>
</law>
