<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ged" order_by="ged" level="1">Economic Development</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ged-7-307</section_number>
  <catch_line>A principal, teacher, school security guard, or other school system personnel in any public school m...</catch_line>
  <order_by>307</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A principal, teacher, school security guard, or other school system personnel in any public school may take reasonable action necessary to prevent violence on school premises or on a school-sponsored trip, including intervening in a fight or physical struggle that takes place in his or her presence, whether the fight is among students or other individuals.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The degree and force of the intervention may be as reasonably necessary to prevent violence, restore order and to protect the safety of the combatants and surrounding individuals.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A principal, teacher, school security guard, or other school system personnel who is hurt while taking preventive action or intervening in a fight under this section:<section prefix="(1)">Shall be compensated by the county board for any necessary medical expenses that result directly from the preventive action or intervention; and</section><section prefix="(2)">May not lose any compensation for time lost from school duties that results directly from the preventive action or intervention, but compensation may be reduced by any payments made under the Maryland Workers' Compensation Act.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">In any suit, claim, or criminal charge brought by a parent or other claimant of one of the combatants against the principal, teacher, school security guard, or other school system personnel because of the preventive action or intervention, the county board:<section prefix="(1)">Shall provide legal counsel for the principal, teacher, school security guard, or other school system personnel or may provide reimbursement for the reasonable expenses of the legal defense of any criminal charge if the county board considers it appropriate; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Shall save the principal, teacher, school security guard, or other school system personnel harmless from any award or decree against him.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
