<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="ged" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="13-803" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ged-13-803</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">There is a Budget and Program Review Board.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Board is responsible for determining annually the resource needs of the professional instructional program of the College.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Board shall consist of the following seven members:<section prefix="(1)">The Dean of the Virginia-Maryland Regional College of Veterinary Medicine, who shall serve as Chairman of the Board;</section><section prefix="(2)">The Dean of the College of Agriculture and Natural Resources of the University of Maryland, College Park;</section><section prefix="(3)">The Senior Vice President and Provost of the Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University;</section><section prefix="(4)">The Vice President and Provost of the University of Maryland, College Park;</section><section prefix="(5)">The Executive Vice President and Chief Business Officer of the Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University;</section><section prefix="(6)">An appointee of the President of the Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University; and</section><section prefix="(7)">The Vice Chancellor for Administration and Finance of the University System of Maryland or the Vice Chancellor's successor.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Board shall:<section prefix="(1)">Determine the cost share for each state;</section><section prefix="(2)">Set the proportion of costs to be funded by tuition; and</section><section prefix="(3)">Periodically review and adjust the building use fees charged to the students of the College.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The appropriate fiscal support staff of each university, which shall include the Vice Chancellor for Administration and Finance of the University System of Maryland, shall provide fiscal support to the Board.</section>
  </text>
</law>
