<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ged" order_by="" level="1">Economic Development</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ged-18-1503</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>1503</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Office of Student Financial Assistance shall adopt regulations to establish:<section prefix="(1)">The maximum starting income for eligibility in the Janet L. Hoffman Loan Assistance Repayment Program;</section><section prefix="(2)">The maximum total income for eligibility in the Janet L. Hoffman Loan Assistance Repayment Program, including any additional sources of income;</section><section prefix="(3)">That priority for participation in the Program shall be given to an individual who:<section prefix="(i)">Graduated from an institution of higher education in the last 3 years;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Is a resident of the State;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Is employed on a full-time basis; and</section><section prefix="(iv)"><section prefix="1.">Provides, as the principal part of the individual's employment, legal services to low-income residents in the State who cannot afford legal services, nursing services in nursing shortage areas in the State as defined in &#xA7; 18-802 of this title, or other services in an eligible field of employment in which there is a shortage of qualified practitioners to low-income or underserved residents or areas of the State; or</section><section prefix="2.">For teacher applicants only, qualifies for a Nancy Grasmick Teacher Award;</section></section></section><section prefix="(4)">A limit on the total amount of assistance provided by the Office of Student Financial Assistance in repaying the loan of an eligible individual, based on the individual's total income and outstanding higher education loan balance;</section><section prefix="(5)">A procedure and schedule for the payment of the amount of loan assistance provided by the Office of Student Financial Assistance to the eligible individual; and</section><section prefix="(6)">An annual review of the eligibility of each individual participating in the Program.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Office of Student Financial Assistance may not approve more than 50% of the total number of awards for teacher applicants to Nancy Grasmick Teacher Scholars.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Office of Student Financial Assistance shall adopt any other regulations necessary to implement this subtitle.</section>
  </text>
</law>
