<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ged" order_by="ged" level="1">Economic Development</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ged-7-424.2</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this section, "school security officer" includes a school principal, another school administrator...</catch_line>
  <order_by>424.2</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section, "school security officer" includes a school principal, another school administrator, a law enforcement officer, or other individual employed by a local school system or a local government who is designated by the county superintendent or a school principal to help maintain the security and safety of a school.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"School security officer" does not include a teacher.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">By March 31, 2011, the State Board, after consultation with and input from the Department of Juvenile Services, the Department of State Police, the Department of Human Resources, and local school systems, shall develop a model policy to address gangs, gang activity, and similar destructive or illegal group behavior in schools.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The model policy developed under subsection (b) of this section shall include:<section prefix="(1)">A statement prohibiting gang activity in schools;</section><section prefix="(2)">A statement prohibiting reprisal or retaliation against individuals who report suspected gang activity;</section><section prefix="(3)">A definition of gang and gang activity;</section><section prefix="(4)">Standard consequences and remedial actions for individuals engaged in gang activity or similar destructive or illegal group behavior;</section><section prefix="(5)">Standard consequences and remedial actions for individuals found to have made false accusations;</section><section prefix="(6)">Model procedures for reporting suspected gang activity or similar destructive or illegal group behavior;</section><section prefix="(7)">Model procedures for the prompt investigation of suspected gang activity or similar destructive or illegal group behavior;</section><section prefix="(8)">Information about the types of support services, including family support services, for a student suspected of participating in gang activity; and</section><section prefix="(9)">Recommendations concerning gang prevention and intervention services and programs for students that maximize community participation and the use of federal funding.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Each local school system shall establish a policy or regulations to address gangs, gang activity, and similar destructive or illegal group behavior in schools based on the model policy.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The policy or regulations shall address the components of the model policy specified in subsection (c) of this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Each local school system shall develop the policy or regulations in consultation with representatives of the following groups:<section prefix="(i)">Parents or guardians of students;</section><section prefix="(ii)">School employees and administrators;</section><section prefix="(iii)">School volunteers;</section><section prefix="(iv)">Students;</section><section prefix="(v)">Local law enforcement;</section><section prefix="(vi)">Gang prevention and intervention programs;</section><section prefix="(vii)">The Office of the Public Defender;</section><section prefix="(viii)">The Maryland State's Attorneys Association; and</section><section prefix="(ix)">Members of the community.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">Each local school system shall submit its policy or regulations to the State Superintendent by September 1, 2011.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">Each local school system shall publicize its policy or regulations in student handbooks, on school system websites, and at any other location or venue the local school system determines is necessary or appropriate.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">Each local school system shall develop the following educational programs in its efforts to address gangs, gang activity, and similar destructive or illegal group behavior in schools:<section prefix="(1)">An educational gang awareness program for students, staff, volunteers, and parents; and</section><section prefix="(2)">A teacher and administrator development program that trains teachers and administrators to implement the policy or regulations.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(h)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A school employee shall report any incidence of suspected gang activity or similar destructive or illegal group behavior promptly to the principal and, for a school that has a school security officer, to the school security officer.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The principal and the school security officer may take appropriate action to maintain a safe and secure school environment, including the provision of appropriate intervention services.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(i)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Each county superintendent shall require regular school security meetings for each middle school and high school to ensure coordination of gang prevention, intervention, and suppression efforts.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The following individuals shall participate in the meetings described in paragraph (1) of this subsection:<section prefix="(i)">School principals;</section><section prefix="(ii)">School security officers;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Guidance counselors;</section><section prefix="(iv)">Local law enforcement officers;</section><section prefix="(v)">Representatives from the county State's Attorney's Office;</section><section prefix="(vi)">Representatives from the Office of the Public Defender;</section><section prefix="(vii)">Gang prevention and intervention program representatives; and</section><section prefix="(viii)">Any other individuals that the county superintendent considers appropriate.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(j)">Each county superintendent shall enter into a memorandum of understanding with the county State's Attorney's Office to foster coordination of gang prevention, intervention, and suppression efforts.</section>
    <section prefix="(k)">On or before January 1, 2011, and each year thereafter, the Department shall submit a report to the General Assembly, in accordance with &#xA7; 2-1246 of the State Government Article, on the implementation of State and local policies and regulations to address gangs, gang activity, and similar destructive or illegal group behavior described in this section.</section>
  </text>
</law>
