<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="ged" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="18-303" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ged-18-303</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Subject to subsection (d) of this section, each recipient of a Delegate Howard P. Rawlings Educational Excellence Award shall:<section prefix="(1)">Be accepted for admission in the regular undergraduate program at an eligible institution or be enrolled in a 2-year associate degree program in which the course work is acceptable for transfer credit for an accredited baccalaureate program in an eligible institution;</section><section prefix="(2)">Be a resident of this State;</section><section prefix="(3)">Demonstrate to the Office a definite financial need; and</section><section prefix="(4)">Accept any other conditions attached to the award.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Each recipient of a Guaranteed Access Grant shall:<section prefix="(1)">Have attained a grade point average of at least 2.5 on a 4.0 scale or its equivalent at the end of the first semester of the senior year in high school and  have completed high school or, failing to do so, on the recommendation of the  recipient's high school principal, provide evidence satisfactory to the Office of  extenuating circumstances;</section><section prefix="(2)">Begin college within 1 year of completing high school or, failing to  do so, provide evidence satisfactory to the Office of extenuating circumstances;</section><section prefix="(3)">Be under the age of 22 years at the time of receiving the first  award;</section><section prefix="(4)">Have successfully completed a college preparatory program in high school;</section><section prefix="(5)">Enroll in college as a full-time student;</section><section prefix="(6)">Subject to subsection (c) of this section, have an annual family income below a poverty index determined by the Commission; and</section><section prefix="(7)">Satisfy any additional criteria the Commission may establish.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">To determine the annual family income eligibility of an applicant for a Guaranteed Access Grant, the Office may not consider an amount received by the applicant as an earned income credit under &#xA7; 32 of the Internal Revenue Code.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A student in grade 9 or grade 10 who applies and qualifies for a  Guaranteed Access Grant on the basis of financial need as established by the  Commission shall prequalify for a Guaranteed Access Grant to be used at the time of  enrollment in an institution of higher education by agreeing in writing, as a secondary  and undergraduate student, to:<section prefix="(1)">Satisfy the attendance policy of the applicable school;</section><section prefix="(2)">Refrain from substance abuse;</section><section prefix="(3)">Provide information required by the Commission or the State  Board of Education;</section><section prefix="(4)">Complete and file on a timely basis applications for federal student  aid for each year that the student plans to enroll in postsecondary education;</section><section prefix="(5)">Participate in the College Readiness Outreach Program  established in &#xA7; 18-303.1 of this subtitle until the student graduates from high school  and matriculates at an institution of higher education; and</section><section prefix="(6)">Satisfy any other program requirements set by the Office, the  Commission, the State Board of Education, or the State Department of Education.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
