<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="ged" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="3-3A-02" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ged-3-3A-02</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Caroline County Board of Education consists of:<section prefix="(1)">Three elected members;</section><section prefix="(2)">Two appointed members; and</section><section prefix="(3)">Two nonvoting student members.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">One elected member shall be elected from each of the three board of education districts established in Caroline County.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">An elected member shall be:<section prefix="(i)">A resident of the district from which the member is elected; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Elected only by the voters of that district.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)"/>
        <section prefix="(ii)">In appointing members to the county board, the Governor shall ensure, to the extent practicable, that the total makeup of the county board reflects gender, ethnic, and racial diversity.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The board of education districts shall:<section prefix="(i)">Be established by the County Commissioners of Caroline County; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Be substantially equal in population and reapportioned on the basis of each decennial census of the United States.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Reapportioned districts shall become effective for the term of office commencing after the first regular primary election held at least 15 months after the official report on population is received by the State from the Bureau of the Census.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">As applicable for that board of education district, at the general election the ballot shall provide the voter with the choice to cast a vote "For" a candidate for election from that district.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">After the election results are certified, the State Board of Elections shall declare for each district whether a candidate has been elected.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">An individual elected to the county board shall be at least 21 years old and a registered voter and resident of Caroline County for at least 3 years.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A member may not continue as a member of the county board if the member:<section prefix="(i)">No longer resides in the board of education district that the member is designated to represent; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">Is not a registered voter of Caroline County.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">An individual employed by, or under the direction of, the county board or the Caroline County Superintendent of Schools is not eligible to serve on the county board.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A student member of the county board shall:<section prefix="(i)">Be a regularly enrolled eleventh or twelfth grade student of good character and in good standing in a Caroline County public high school during the student's term in office;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Be selected in the student's tenth or eleventh grade in accordance with paragraph (3) of this subsection; and</section><section prefix="(iii)"/></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Each high school in the county shall be represented by a student member of the county board.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">For nomination to the county board, the student body shall submit to the principal of the high school a list of nominees that contains the names of eligible students.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The principal of the high school shall select the student member from the list of nominees submitted to the principal under subparagraph (i) of this paragraph.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(4)">If a vacancy in the position of student member occurs during the term of a student member, the principal of the high school represented on the county board shall select another student member using the method set forth under paragraph (3) of this subsection.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Subject to paragraph (2) of this subsection, each elected member serves for a term of 4 years beginning on the first Monday in December after the member's election and until a successor is elected and qualifies.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The initial terms of the elected members are staggered as follows:<section prefix="(i)">The two members elected to the county board at the general election in November 2012 who receive the highest number of votes cast from among the successful candidates at that election shall serve for a term of 4 years; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">The member elected to the county board at the general election in November 2012 who receives the least number of votes cast from among the successful candidates at that election shall serve for a term of 2 years.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(h)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In the event of a vacancy of an elected member on the county board due to death, resignation, disqualification, or removal, the remaining voting members shall select a qualified individual to fill the vacancy for the remainder of the term of the vacating member and until a successor is elected and qualifies.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">An individual appointed to fill a vacancy for an elected member shall be a resident of the same board of education district as that of the vacating member.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Before filling a vacancy for an elected member, the remaining voting members of the county board shall conduct an interview of each applicant at an open meeting.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The county board shall publish a list of the names of the applicants for a vacancy on the county board at least 2 weeks before the interview of the first applicant is scheduled to occur.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The county board shall cause public notice of the date, time, and location of the interview for each applicant to be published:</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(5)">The county board is not required to conduct discussions of the applicants or make the final selection of the elected member to fill the vacancy at an open meeting.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(i)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Subject to paragraph (2) of this subsection, each appointed member serves for a term of 4 years beginning on the first Monday in December 2012.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The initial terms of the appointed members are staggered as follows:<section prefix="(i)">One appointed member shall serve for a term of 6 years; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">One appointed member shall serve for a term of 4 years.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">In the event of a vacancy of an appointed member due to death, resignation, disqualification, or removal, the Governor shall appoint another individual to complete the term of the vacating appointed member.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
