<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="ged" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="8-316" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ged-8-316</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Department of Education and the Maryland School for the Blind shall enter into a written agreement.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The agreement shall provide for monitoring and review by the Department of the Maryland School for the Blind, including:<section prefix="(1)">Review by the Department of the annual budget approved by the Board of the Maryland School for the Blind;</section><section prefix="(2)">Monitoring by the Department of the Maryland School for the Blind's program of enhanced services for blind students who have severe disabilities, including the criteria approved by the Board of the Maryland School for the Blind for the admission of students to the program;</section><section prefix="(3)">Consultation between the Department and the Maryland School for the Blind on issues of blind education;</section><section prefix="(4)">Assistance from the Department in developing agreements between the Maryland School for the Blind and local school systems and other State and local agencies for provision of services to blind children; and</section><section prefix="(5)">Monitoring by and assistance from the Department regarding other aspects of the Maryland School for the Blind's educational program and services to blind children as required by federal or State law.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Maryland School for the Blind may enter into written agreements with State and local agencies, including local school systems, for the purpose of providing services to blind children.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">This subsection in no way abrogates the obligation of the local school systems to provide alternative programs for blind students.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
