<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ged" order_by="ged" level="1">Economic Development</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ged-16-103</section_number>
  <catch_line>In addition to the other powers granted and duties imposed by this title, and subject to the authori...</catch_line>
  <order_by>103</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In addition to the other powers granted and duties imposed by this title, and subject to the authority of the Maryland Higher Education Commission, each board of community college trustees has the powers and duties set forth in this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">With the approval of the Maryland Higher Education Commission, each board of trustees may establish and operate one or more community colleges.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Each board of trustees shall exercise general control over the community college, keep separate records and minutes, and adopt reasonable rules, regulations, or bylaws to carry out the provisions of this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Each board of trustees may fix the salaries and tenure of the president, faculty, and other employees of the community college.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">Each board of trustees may purchase, lease, condemn, or otherwise acquire any property it considers necessary for the operation of the community college.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Each board of trustees may sell, lease, or otherwise dispose of community college assets or property.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Except as provided in &#xA7; 16-105(h) of this subtitle, the president of the community college and the chairman of the board of trustees may execute a conveyance or other legal document under an appropriate resolution of the board.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">Each board of trustees may:<section prefix="(1)">With the approval of the Commission, permit the county board of education to use the lands, buildings, or other facilities of the community college; and</section><section prefix="(2)">With the approval of the county board of education, use any land, buildings, assets, or other facilities of the county board of education.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(h)">Each board of trustees may apply for and accept any gift or grant from the federal government or any other person.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">Subject to the minimum standards of the Commission, each board of trustees may determine entrance requirements and approve offerings that consist of:<section prefix="(1)">Transfer programs offering the equivalent of the first 2 years of a bachelor's degree program;</section><section prefix="(2)">Career programs offering technical, vocational, and semiprofessional education; and</section><section prefix="(3)">Continuing education programs.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(j)">Each board of trustees may charge students reasonable tuition and fees set by it with a view to making college education available to all qualified individuals at low cost.</section>
    <section prefix="(k)">Each board of trustees may sue and be sued.</section>
    <section prefix="(l)">Each board of trustees may make agreements with the federal government or any other person, including agreements between counties to support a regional community college, if the board considers the agreement advisable for the establishment or operation of the community college.</section>
    <section prefix="(m)">Except as provided in &#xA7; 16-105(i) of this subtitle, each board of trustees shall be styled "the board of trustees of ................. community (or junior) college".</section>
    <section prefix="(n)">Each board of trustees may adopt a corporate seal.</section>
  </text>
</law>
