<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="ged" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="5-101" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ged-5-101</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Subject to the rules and regulations of the State Board and with the advice of the county superintendent, each county board shall prepare an annual budget according to:<section prefix="(i)">The major categories listed in this section; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Any other major category required by the State Board.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">In addition to the information required by this section, the county fiscal authorities may require the county board to provide details to the service areas and activities levels in the account structure within the "Financial Reporting Manual for Maryland Public Schools".</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">With the annual budget, each county board shall provide:<section prefix="(i)">The number of full-time equivalent positions included within each major category; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">A description of any fund balances or other moneys held by any outside source, including an insurer, that are undesignated or unreserved and are under the direction and control of the county board.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The budget shall be prepared to include the following categories:<section prefix="(1)">Current expense fund, estimated receipts:<section prefix="(i)">Revenue from local sources;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Revenue from State sources;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Revenue from federal sources;</section><section prefix="(iv)">Unliquidated surplus, the actual from the previous fiscal year and the estimated from the current fiscal year, whether accrued from revenues or expenditures; and</section><section prefix="(v)">Revenue from all other sources with identification of the source.</section></section><section prefix="(2)">Current expense fund, requested appropriations:<section prefix="(i)">Administration, which means those activities associated with the general regulations, direction, and control of the county board, including:</section><section prefix="(ii)">Mid-level administration, including:</section><section prefix="(iii)">Instructional salaries, which means those activities which deal directly with teaching students, including:</section><section prefix="(iv)">Textbooks and classroom instructional supplies;</section><section prefix="(v)">Other instructional costs;</section><section prefix="(vi)">Special education with subcategories and items budgeted in this category to be determined by the State Board with the advice of the county board;</section><section prefix="(vii)">Student personnel services;</section><section prefix="(viii)">Health services;</section><section prefix="(ix)">Student transportation;</section><section prefix="(x)">Operation of plant and equipment;</section><section prefix="(xi)">Maintenance of plant;</section><section prefix="(xii)">Fixed charges;</section><section prefix="(xiii)">Food services; and</section><section prefix="(xiv)">Capital outlay.</section></section><section prefix="(3)">School construction fund, estimated receipts:<section prefix="(i)">Revenue from local sources;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Sale of bonds;</section><section prefix="(iii)">State General Public School Construction Loan;</section><section prefix="(iv)">Revenue from State sources;</section><section prefix="(v)">Revenue from federal sources;</section><section prefix="(vi)">Unliquidated surplus, the actual from the previous fiscal year and the estimated for the current fiscal year, whether accrued from revenues or expenditures; and</section><section prefix="(vii)">Funds from all other sources, with identification of the source.</section></section><section prefix="(4)">School Construction Fund, requested appropriations:<section prefix="(i)">Land for school sites;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Buildings and the equipment that will be an integral part of a building by project;</section><section prefix="(iii)">School site improvement by project;</section><section prefix="(iv)">Remodeling by project;</section><section prefix="(v)">Additional equipment by project;</section><section prefix="(vi)">Debt service; and</section><section prefix="(vii)">An amount that is adequate to satisfy a final court judgment that, after exhaustion of the rights of appeal, is rendered against the county board of education or any of its officers or employees.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">In addition to all other information required by this section, the Montgomery County Board of Education, on request of the County Executive and County Council, shall provide with the annual budget the program implications of recommendations for reductions to or increases in its annual budget, at whatever different levels of funding and accompanied by whatever reasonable supporting detail and analysis, as may be specified by the County Executive and County Council. Prior to the submission of the annual budget, similar information shall be submitted by the Superintendent of Schools upon request by the County Executive or County Council.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The budget document shall contain an addendum showing estimated expenditures for special education as defined by the "Financial Reporting Manual for Maryland Public Schools".</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">In addition to all other information required by this section, the Cecil County Board of Education, on request of the Cecil County Board of Estimates, shall provide with the annual budget separate information on the number of and costs associated with school-based noninstructional personnel.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In addition to all other information required by this section, the Prince George's County Board of Education shall provide to the County Executive and County Council with the annual budget, information relating to each of the following categories:<section prefix="(i)">Instructional supplies and materials;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Additional equipment; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Replacement equipment.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">For the categories specified in paragraph (1) of this subsection, the following information shall be provided for the public school system in the county:<section prefix="(i)">Proposed expenditures for the next school year based on the annual budget;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Estimated expenditures for the current school year; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Actual expenditures for the prior school year.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
