<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ged" order_by="ged" level="1">Economic Development</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ged-4-104</section_number>
  <catch_line>Except in Baltimore County, each county board may:...</catch_line>
  <order_by>104</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except in Baltimore County, each county board may:<section prefix="(i)">Retain counsel to represent it in legal matters that affect the board; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Contract for the payment of a reasonable fee to the counsel.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Funds for these fees shall be included in the annual budget.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Baltimore County Board may retain counsel to represent it in legal matters that involve disputes with the Baltimore County government.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Each county board may pay all or part of the counsel fees for the defense of a county board member who is involved in litigation because of his service and in his official capacity on that board. These payments are a valid educational expense.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In any suit or claim brought against a principal, teacher, school security guard, or other agent or employee of a county board by a parent or other claimant with respect to an action taken by the agent or employee, the board shall provide for counsel for that individual if:<section prefix="(i)">The action was taken in the performance of his duties, within the scope of his employment, and without malice; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">The board determines that he was acting within his authorized official capacity in the incident.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The counsel required by this section may be provided through the office of the county attorney or city solicitor.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">This subsection does not require a county board to provide or reimburse the cost of counsel to a plaintiff or claimant in a suit or claim against a county board or its members, agents, or employees.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
