<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ged" order_by="" level="1">Economic Development</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ged-12-115</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>115</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, "candidate", "contribution", and "political committee" have the meanings stated in &#xA7; 1-101 of the Election Law Article.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The restrictions in this section apply from the date of a member's appointment to the Board of Regents until the end of the member's tenure on the Board.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A member of the Board of Regents may not, for the benefit of the Governor, Lieutenant Governor, Attorney General, or Comptroller, a member of the General Assembly, or a candidate for election to the office of Governor, Lieutenant Governor, Attorney General, Comptroller, or member of the General Assembly, engage in the following activities:<section prefix="(i)">Soliciting or transmitting a political contribution from any person, including a political committee;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Serving on a fund-raising committee or a political committee;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Acting as a treasurer for a candidate or official or as treasurer or chair of a political committee;</section><section prefix="(iv)">Organizing or establishing a political committee for the purpose of soliciting or transmitting contributions from any person; or</section><section prefix="(v)">Forwarding tickets for fund-raising activities, or other solicitations for political contributions, to a potential contributor.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">This section does not prohibit a member of the Board of Regents from:<section prefix="(i)">Making a personal political contribution;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Informing any entity of a position taken by a candidate or official; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">Engaging in other activities not specifically prohibited under paragraph (1) of this subsection.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A member of the Board of Regents may not be a candidate for a public office while serving on the Board.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
