<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="ged" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="11-205" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ged-11-205</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Commission may summarily order the revocation or suspension of a certificate of approval of a private career school if:<section prefix="(1)">The school's owner or director, or any person in whose name the approval is issued, is convicted of a crime of moral turpitude or a crime relating to the operation of the school if:<section prefix="(i)">The conviction is final; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">The period for appeal has expired;</section></section><section prefix="(2)">An agency that exercises concurrent authority over the private career school has revoked any approval to operate required by law; or</section><section prefix="(3)">Without prior approval of the Commission, the certificate of approval of a school is sold, pledged, or transferred, or there is a change of ownership of a school.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Commission may summarily order a revocation or suspension of a certificate of approval of a private career school under subsection (a) of this section only if it gives the school:<section prefix="(1)">Prior oral or written notice of the proposed revocation or suspension and a brief, informal opportunity for response;</section><section prefix="(2)">Prior or prompt subsequent written notice of the revocation or suspension and the findings on which the revocation or suspension is based; and</section><section prefix="(3)">After the revocation or suspension is effective, an opportunity to be heard promptly before the Commission.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In any hearing held on the grounds for revocation under subsection (a) of this section, the Commission may limit the issues to be determined to whether:<section prefix="(i)">The alleged conviction in fact occurred;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The alleged revocation under subsection (a)(2) of this section in fact occurred; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">The alleged sale, pledge, or transfer, or change of ownership of the private career school in fact occurred.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Notwithstanding paragraph (1) of this subsection, in any hearing held on the grounds for revocation under subsection (a) of this section, a private career school may present matters in mitigation of the offense alleged by the Commission.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
