<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ged" order_by="" level="1">Economic Development</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ged-16-105</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>105</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Notwithstanding the provisions of &#xA7; 16-104 of this subtitle, the provisions of this section shall apply only in Baltimore County.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">There is a Community College of Baltimore County consisting of the following three campuses:<section prefix="(1)">The Catonsville Campus;</section><section prefix="(2)">The Dundalk Campus; and</section><section prefix="(3)">The Essex Campus.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Board of Trustees for Baltimore County shall appoint a President of the Community College of Baltimore County who shall serve at the pleasure of the Board.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The President:<section prefix="(1)">Shall report directly to the Board of Trustees;</section><section prefix="(2)">Shall recommend the appointment by the Board of qualified faculty members and other employees necessary for the efficient administration of the Community College of Baltimore County;</section><section prefix="(3)">Shall recommend the discharge of employees for good cause; however, any employee with tenure shall be given reasonable notice of the grounds for dismissal and an opportunity to be heard;</section><section prefix="(4)">Is responsible for the administration and supervision of the administrators, employees, and departments of the campuses of the Community College of Baltimore County in accordance with the policy manual of the Community College of Baltimore County as adopted from time to time by the Board of Trustees; and</section><section prefix="(5)">Shall attend all meetings of the Board, except those involving the President's personal position.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">Upon the recommendation of the President, the Board of Trustees may appoint a vice president, provost, and administrator of each campus under its jurisdiction.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The vice presidents, provosts, and administrators of each campus shall report directly to the President.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">Notwithstanding the provisions of &#xA7; 16-102(a)(2) of this subtitle, the Board of Trustees may choose the President to serve as Secretary-Treasurer of the Board.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Notwithstanding the provisions of &#xA7; 16-103(f)(2) of this subtitle, the Board of Trustees may, by resolution, authorize the President to sign legal documents on behalf of the Board of Trustees including documents related to the disposition of assets or property of the community college.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The resolution may:<section prefix="(i)">Authorize the President to delegate the authority given to the President under paragraph (1) of this subsection to designees that the Board of Trustees considers appropriate; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Limit the type of legal documents that the President may delegate to a designee for signature.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(i)">Notwithstanding the provisions of &#xA7; 16-103(m) of this subtitle, the Board of Trustees shall be styled "the Board of Trustees of the Community College of Baltimore County".</section>
  </text>
</law>
