<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ged" order_by="" level="1">Economic Development</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ged-12-102</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>102</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">There is a body corporate and politic known as the University System of Maryland.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The University is an instrumentality of the State and a public corporation.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The University is an independent unit of State government.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The exercise by the University of the powers conferred by this subtitle is the performance of an essential public function.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The government of the University System of Maryland is vested in the Board of Regents of the University System of Maryland.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Board of Regents consists of 17 members as follows:<section prefix="(1)"><section prefix="(i)">Except as provided in subparagraph (ii) of this paragraph, one member shall be a full-time student in good academic standing at an institution under the jurisdiction of the Board; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">A student member who is in good academic standing at the University of Maryland University College shall be exempt from the full-time student requirement in subparagraph (i) of this paragraph;</section></section><section prefix="(2)">One member shall be the State Secretary of Agriculture ex officio; and</section><section prefix="(3)">The remaining members of the Board shall be residents of the State and shall be appointed from the general public.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">In making appointments to the Board, the Governor shall consider representation from all parts of the State.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">Except for the Secretary of Agriculture, each member of the Board shall be appointed by the Governor, with the advice and consent of the Senate.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except for the student member, each appointed member serves for a term of 5 years from July 1 of the year of appointment and until a successor is appointed and qualifies. These members may be reappointed.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The student member shall be appointed for a term of 1 year, from July 1, and may be reappointed if the student remains a student at any campus of the University System of Maryland.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A member appointed to fill a vacancy in an unexpired term serves only for the remainder of that term and until a successor is appointed and qualifies.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">Except for the Secretary of Agriculture, a member may not serve more than 2 consecutive full terms.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">Each member of the Board:<section prefix="(1)">Serves without compensation; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Is entitled to reimbursement for expenses in accordance with the Standard State Travel Regulations.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
