<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ged" order_by="" level="1">Economic Development</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ged-3-401</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>401</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Carroll County Board consists of:<section prefix="(1)">Five voting members; and</section><section prefix="(2)">The County Commissioners, who are nonvoting ex officio members.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A candidate elected to the county board shall be a resident and registered voter of Carroll County. Any member who no longer resides in Carroll County may not continue as a member of the board.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Members of the Carroll County Board shall be elected as follows:<section prefix="(i)">Two members of the board shall be elected in the November general election of 1994 and every 4 years thereafter;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Two members of the county board shall be elected in the November general election of 1996 and every 4 years thereafter; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">One member of the county board shall be elected in the November general election of 1998 and every 4 years thereafter.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Members of the county board shall be elected:<section prefix="(i)">At a general election as required by this section; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">On a general countywide ticket.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Each member serves for a term of 4 years beginning the first Monday in December immediately following the member's election and until a successor is elected and qualifies. The terms of the members are staggered as required for the elections to the county board in subsection (c)(1) of this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Governor shall appoint a new member to fill any vacancy on the board for the remainder of that term and until a successor is elected and qualifies.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A member of the county board as of October 1, 1993, and any member appointed to fill a vacancy in an unexpired term of such member, shall hold office during his term and until a successor is elected and qualifies.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The State Board may remove a member of the county board for:<section prefix="(i)">Immorality;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Misconduct in office;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Incompetency; or</section><section prefix="(iv)">Willful neglect of duty.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Before removing a member, the State Board shall send the member a copy of the charges against him and give him an opportunity within 10 days to request a hearing.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">If the member requests a hearing within the 10-day period:<section prefix="(i)">The State Board promptly shall hold a hearing, but a hearing may not be set within 10 days after the State Board sends the member a notice of the hearing; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">The member shall have an opportunity to be heard publicly before the State Board in his own defense, in person or by counsel.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">A member removed under this subsection has the right to a de novo review of the removal by the Circuit Court for Carroll County.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
