<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="ged" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="5-118" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ged-5-118</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>** TAKES EFFECT JULY 1, 2013 PER CHAPTER 394 OF 2012 **<section prefix="(a)"><section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section><section prefix="(2)"><section prefix="(i)">"Payee" means any party who receives from the Prince George's County Board of Education an aggregate payment of $25,000 in a fiscal year.</section><section prefix="(ii)">"Payee" does not include:</section></section><section prefix="(3)">"Searchable Web site" means a Web site created in accordance with this section that displays and searches payment and budget data of the Prince George's County Board of Education.</section></section><section prefix="(b)">On or before January 1, 2013, the Prince George's County Board of Education shall develop and operate a single searchable Web site accessible to the public at no cost through the Internet.</section><section prefix="(c)">The searchable Web site shall contain Prince George's County Board of Education annual data including:<section prefix="(1)">The name of a payee receiving a payment;</section><section prefix="(2)">The location of a payee by zip code;</section><section prefix="(3)">The amount of a payment; and</section><section prefix="(4)">The budget data prepared under &#xA7; 5-101 of this subtitle.</section></section><section prefix="(d)">The searchable Web site shall allow the user to:<section prefix="(1)">Search data for fiscal year 2012 and each fiscal year thereafter; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Search by the following data fields:<section prefix="(i)">A payee receiving a payment;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The zip code of a payee receiving a payment; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Individual schools.</section></section></section><section prefix="(e)">This section may not be construed to require the disclosure of information that is confidential under federal, State, or local law.</section><section prefix="(f)">This section shall be known and may be cited as the "Prince George's County Public Schools Funding Accountability and Transparency Act".</section></text>
</law>
