<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ged" order_by="ged" level="1">Economic Development</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ged-18-1907</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this section, "fiduciary" means:...</catch_line>
  <order_by>1907</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, "fiduciary" means:<section prefix="(1)">A member of the Board; or</section><section prefix="(2)">An employee of the Program or the Trust who exercises any discretionary authority or control over:<section prefix="(i)">The management or administration of the Trust; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">The management or disposition of the assets of the Trust.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A fiduciary shall discharge the fiduciary's duties with respect to the Trust:<section prefix="(1)">Solely in the interest of the participants;</section><section prefix="(2)">For the exclusive purposes of providing benefits to the participants and providing reasonable expenses of administering the Trust;</section><section prefix="(3)">With the care, skill, prudence, and diligence under the circumstances then prevailing, that a prudent person acting in a like capacity and familiar with such matters would use in the conduct of an enterprise of a like character with like aims;</section><section prefix="(4)">By diversifying the investments of the Trust so as to minimize the risk of large losses, unless under the circumstances it is clearly prudent not to do so;</section><section prefix="(5)">In accordance with the laws governing the Trust; and</section><section prefix="(6)">In accordance with the documents and instruments governing the Trust to the extent that the documents and instruments are consistent with this subtitle.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">In exercising authority, control, or discretion with respect to the Trust, a fiduciary may not:<section prefix="(1)">Use the assets of the Trust for the fiduciary's own interest or account;</section><section prefix="(2)">Act in a transaction involving the Trust on behalf of a person, or represent a person, if the interests of the person are adverse to the interests of the Trust or the interests of participants;</section><section prefix="(3)">Receive any consideration for the fiduciary's own account from a person dealing with the Trust in connection with a transaction involving the assets of the Trust; or</section><section prefix="(4)">Become an endorser or surety or, in any manner, an obligor, for money lent to or borrowed from the Board.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
