<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="ged" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="4-308" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ged-4-308</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">There is a Parent and Community Advisory Board in the Baltimore City Public School System.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Advisory Board consists of 14 members, a majority of whom shall be parents of students enrolled in the Baltimore City public schools.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The plaintiffs (parents of students with disabilities) in Vaughn G., et al v. Mayor and City Council, et al case no. MJG-84-1911, United States District Court for the District of Maryland shall appoint three members of the Advisory Board.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The plaintiffs (parents of students in general education) in Bradford, et al v. Maryland State Board of Education, et al, case no. 94340058/CE189672, Circuit Court for Baltimore City shall appoint two members of the Advisory Board.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">Subject to the approval of the board, the Chief Executive Officer shall appoint seven members of the Advisory Board as follows:</section>
        <section prefix="(iv)">The Chief Executive Officer shall appoint two members of the Advisory Board from other parent and community groups in Baltimore City.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(4)">If one of the groups specified in paragraph (3)(iii) of this subsection fails to submit a list with a sufficient number of nominees to fill a position, the board shall appoint an individual from other parent and community groups in Baltimore City.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The board and the Chief Executive Officer shall:<section prefix="(1)">Regularly consult with the Advisory Board;</section><section prefix="(2)">Ensure parental involvement in the development and implementation of the education policies and procedures in the Baltimore City Public School System; and</section><section prefix="(3)">Ensure increased community involvement and outreach in support of the public schools in the city.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Chief Executive Officer shall meet with the Parent and Community Advisory Board on at least a quarterly basis.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Each member serves for a term of 2 years.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A member may not serve for more than two consecutive terms.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A member whose term has expired shall remain in office until a successor is appointed.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
