<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="ged" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="5-401" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ged-5-401</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Local performance standards" means standards for student and school performance developed by a county board.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Plan" means a comprehensive master plan.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">"State performance standards" means standards for student and school performance approved by the State Board.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">"Update" means an annual update to a county board's comprehensive master plan.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Each county board shall develop and implement a comprehensive master plan that describes the goals, objectives, and strategies that will be used to improve student achievement and meet State performance standards and local performance standards in each segment of the student population.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Each county board shall submit a plan to the Department on or before October 1, 2003.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">Each county board shall submit an update to the plan required under subparagraph (i) of this paragraph for review and approval by the State Superintendent of Schools on or before:</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">On or before October 15, 2015, each county board shall submit a plan to the Department.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">Beginning in 2016, each county board shall submit an annual update for review and approval by the State Superintendent of Schools on or before October 15 of each year.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(4)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Subject to subsection (i) of this section, the plan and updates required under paragraph (3) of this subsection shall cover a 5-year period.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">At least 30 days before submitting a plan or update to the Department, a county board shall provide a copy of the proposed plan or update, with a copy of the final plan or update to follow, to the:</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(5)">Each county board shall submit with the update required under paragraph (3)(ii) of this subsection:<section prefix="(i)">A detailed summary of how the board's current year approved budget and increases in expenditures over the prior year are consistent with the master plan; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">A summary of how the board's actual prior year budget and additional expenditures in the prior year's budget aligned with the master plan.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The plan or update shall include:<section prefix="(1)">Goals and objectives as required under subsections (d) through (f) of this section that are aligned with State performance standards and local performance standards;</section><section prefix="(2)">Implementation strategies for meeting goals and objectives;</section><section prefix="(3)">Methods for measuring progress toward meeting goals and objectives;</section><section prefix="(4)">Time lines for implementation of the strategies for meeting goals and objectives;</section><section prefix="(5)">Time lines for meeting goals and objectives;</section><section prefix="(6)">A description of the alignment of the county board's budget with goals, objectives, and strategies for improving student achievement;</section><section prefix="(7)">The impact of the proposed goals, objectives, and implementation strategies on public school facilities and capital improvements that may be needed to implement the plan or update;</section><section prefix="(8)">A description of how the county board plans to ensure and measure the academic proficiency of students in the core academic subjects listed in &#xA7; 7-203 of this article at various points during the elementary and secondary education of the students; and</section><section prefix="(9)">Any other information required by the State Superintendent.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The plan or update shall include goals, objectives, and strategies regarding the performance of:<section prefix="(1)">Students requiring special education, as defined in &#xA7; 5-209 of this title;</section><section prefix="(2)">Students with limited-English proficiency, as defined in &#xA7; 5-208 of this title;</section><section prefix="(3)">Prekindergarten students;</section><section prefix="(4)">Kindergarten students;</section><section prefix="(5)">Gifted and talented students, as defined in &#xA7; 8-201 of this article;</section><section prefix="(6)">Students enrolled in career and technology courses;</section><section prefix="(7)">Students failing to meet, or failing to make progress toward meeting, State performance standards, including any segment of the student population that is, on average, performing at a lower achievement level than the student population as a whole; and</section><section prefix="(8)">Any other segment of the student population identified by the State Superintendent.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">With regard to subsection (d)(7) of this section, the plan or update shall include strategies to address any disparities in achievement identified for any segment of the student population.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The State Superintendent shall review each plan or update to determine whether the plan or update complies with the requirements of subsections (b) through (e) of this section.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">If the State Superintendent determines that a plan or update does not comply with the requirements of subsections (b) through (e) of this section, the State Superintendent may require specific revisions to the plan or update.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The State Superintendent may review the content of each plan or update to assess whether the plan or update will have the effect of improving student achievement and increasing progress toward meeting State performance standards.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">If the State Superintendent determines that a plan or update will not have the effect of improving student achievement and increasing progress toward meeting State performance standards, the State Superintendent may require specific revisions to the plan or update.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A county board may not implement a plan or update unless it has been approved by the State Superintendent.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A county board may submit a preexisting management plan to the Department as the county board's plan or update under subsection (b) of this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If the State Superintendent determines that the preexisting management plan meets the requirements set forth in this section, the State Superintendent shall approve the preexisting management plan as the county board's plan or update.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(h)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The State Superintendent annually shall review how each county board's current year approved budget and actual prior year budget align with the master plan and any updates to the master plan. This review may be based on the information required to be submitted by the county board under subsection (b)(5) of this section and any other information required by the State Superintendent.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The State Superintendent annually shall report the results of the budget review by December 31 to the Governor, the county governing body, and, subject to &#xA7; 2-1246 of the State Government Article, the General Assembly.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(i)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If a school system fails to demonstrate progress toward improving student achievement and meeting State performance standards in each segment of the student population during a school year, the State Superintendent shall review the content of the plan, any updates to the plan, and the results of the annual review required under subsection (h)(1) of this section to assess whether the plan or update will have the effect of improving student achievement and increasing progress toward meeting State performance standards.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If the State Superintendent determines that a plan or update will not have the effect of improving student achievement and increasing progress toward meeting State performance standards, the State Superintendent shall require specific revisions to the plan or update.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(j)">The State Superintendent shall advise the Governor and the General Assembly concerning the distribution of State funds to a county that fails to make progress toward improving student achievement and meeting State performance standards in each segment of the student population.</section>
    <section prefix="(k)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The State Superintendent shall review academic intervention programs and behavior modification programs to identify best practices.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The State Superintendent shall periodically report on the best practices to the State Board, the county boards, the Governor, and, subject to &#xA7; 2-1246 of the State Government Article, the General Assembly.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(l)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Subject to paragraph (2) of this subsection, the Department shall adopt regulations as necessary to implement this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Department shall consult with county superintendents and county boards before promulgating proposed regulations to implement this section.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(m)">The Department may provide technical assistance to county boards in developing and implementing a plan.</section>
    <section prefix="(n)">The Governor shall include an appropriation for the Department in the State budget for each fiscal year in amount sufficient to cover the costs associated with implementing this section.</section>
  </text>
</law>
