<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ged" order_by="" level="1">Economic Development</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ged-6-306</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>306</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"County grant for national certification" means an annual grant distributed to a teacher certified by the National Board for Professional Teaching Standards established:<section prefix="(i)">Outside of the collective bargaining process; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">As part of a collective bargaining agreement with the local employee organization.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"School-based employee" means a certificated employee who works directly with students or teachers at a public school.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">For fiscal year 2000 and each subsequent fiscal year, the Governor shall include in each year's operating budget funding for the stipends and bonuses provided in this subsection.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A classroom teacher or other nonadministrative school-based employee in a public school identified by the State Board as having comprehensive needs who holds a standard professional certificate or an advanced professional certificate who is employed by a county board and who holds a certificate issued by the National Board for Professional Teaching Standards shall receive a stipend from the State in an amount equal to the county grant for national certification, up to a maximum of $2,000 per qualified individual.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A classroom teacher or other nonadministrative school-based employee in a school not identified by the State Board as having comprehensive needs who holds a standard professional certificate or an advanced professional certificate who is employed by a county board and who holds a certificate issued by the National Board for Professional Teaching Standards shall receive a stipend from the State in an amount equal to the county grant for national certification, up to a maximum of $1,000 per qualified individual.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">A classroom teacher who holds an advanced professional certificate and teaches in a public school identified by the State Board as a school having comprehensive needs shall receive a stipend from the State in the amount of $1,500 for each year that the teacher performs satisfactorily in the classroom.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">
        <section prefix="(i)">
          <section prefix="1.">The State Board shall establish a program to support locally negotiated incentives, governed under Subtitles 4 and 5 of this title, for highly effective classroom teachers and principals to work in public schools that are:</section>
          <section prefix="2.">The program established under subsubparagraph 1 of this subparagraph may include financial incentives, leadership changes, or other incentives.</section>
        </section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">
          <section prefix="1.">The State Board shall adopt guidelines to implement this paragraph.</section>
          <section prefix="2.">Nothing in this paragraph shall be construed to prohibit a local school system from employing more stringent standards than the guidelines adopted under this subparagraph.</section>
        </section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">An individual who receives a stipend or bonus under subsection (b) of this section may not be deemed an employee of the State.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The employer of an individual who receives a stipend or bonus under subsection (b) of this section shall pay the increase in fringe benefit costs associated with the stipend or bonus.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The Department shall act as fiscal agent for funds disbursed under this section.</section>
  </text>
</law>
