<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ged" order_by="ged" level="1">Economic Development</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ged-8-604</section_number>
  <catch_line>The Program shall lend a suitable hearing aid to a parent or legal guardian of an eligible child on ...</catch_line>
  <order_by>604</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Program shall lend a suitable hearing aid to a parent or legal guardian of an eligible child on receipt of:<section prefix="(1)">A prescription from an otolaryngologist or a licensed audiologist; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Any documents required by the Program to prove that the child is an eligible child.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, the loan period shall be for not more than 6 months.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Program may extend the original loan period for additional 3-month periods if, prior to each extension, the Program determines that:<section prefix="(i)">The child does not have immediate access to another hearing aid under Medicaid, the Maryland Children's Health Program, or private health insurance;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The child's parent or legal guardian currently does not have the financial means to obtain immediate access to another hearing aid; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">The child's parent or legal guardian is making reasonable efforts to obtain access to another hearing aid.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A parent or legal guardian who borrows a hearing aid for an eligible child shall:<section prefix="(1)">Be the custodian of the hearing aid;</section><section prefix="(2)">Return the hearing aid immediately to the Loan Bank on the expiration of the loan period or receipt of a suitable permanent hearing aid, whichever occurs first;</section><section prefix="(3)">Be responsible for the proper care and use of the hearing aid;</section><section prefix="(4)">Be responsible for any damage to or loss of the hearing aid; and</section><section prefix="(5)">Sign a written agreement provided by the State Superintendent that states the term and conditions of the loan.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Program shall ensure that the eligible child's otolaryngologist or licensed audiologist instructs the parent or legal guardian about the proper care and use of a hearing aid provided under the Program.</section>
  </text>
</law>
