<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ged" order_by="ged" level="1">Economic Development</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ged-24-207</section_number>
  <catch_line>It is the public policy of the State that gifts, donations, bequests, private endowments, and privat...</catch_line>
  <order_by>207</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">It is the public policy of the State that gifts, donations, bequests, private endowments, and private grants may be received by the Commission.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Commission is encouraged to promote private fund-raising by strengthening institutional development activities and by maintaining relationships with affiliated foundations.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Affiliated foundations that are independently established for this purpose shall operate subject to policies adopted by the Commission and be approved for form and legal sufficiency by the Attorney General.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">Those policies regarding or pertaining to conflict of interest, financial disclosure, or lobbying shall be reviewed and approved by the State Ethics Commission.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Sections 15-501 through 15-504 of the State Government Article do not bar an official or employee of the Commission from becoming a director or official of an independent foundation organized to foster fund-raising and provide related services for the benefit of the Commission.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">An official or employee of the Commission who serves as a director or official of an independent foundation organized to foster fund-raising and provide related services for the benefit of the Commission:<section prefix="1.">May not be compensated by the foundation; and</section><section prefix="2.">May be reimbursed for bona fide expenses incurred in the performance of activities undertaken on behalf of the foundation as authorized by the board of directors of that foundation.</section></section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(4)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The Commission may not accept funds from an affiliated foundation unless the fiscal affairs of the affiliated foundation are audited annually by an independent certified public accountant.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The independent certified public accountant shall send copies of each annual audit report to the Commission and, subject to &#xA7; 2-1246 of the State Government Article, to the Department of Legislative Services.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, the Commission shall keep confidential the name, address, telephone number, contribution amount, and all other personal and financial information of any individual who makes a donation to the Commission.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">To the extent the Commission determines that the sharing of information will contribute to the fund-raising efforts of the Commission, the Commission may share information about an individual who makes a donation to the Commission with nonprofit or governmental entities under terms set by the Commission.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
