<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ged" order_by="ged" level="1">Economic Development</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ged-11-902</section_number>
  <catch_line>On or before December 1, 2007, in order to coordinate the distribution of instructional materials to...</catch_line>
  <order_by>902</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">On or before December 1, 2007, in order to coordinate the distribution of instructional materials to blind and other print disabled students, the Maryland Library for the Blind and Physically Handicapped shall convene an Instructional Materials Access Guidelines Committee.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Committee consists of:<section prefix="(1)">The Secretary of Higher Education, or the  Secretary's designee;</section><section prefix="(2)">The Secretary of Disabilities, or the Secretary's  designee;</section><section prefix="(3)">The State Superintendent, or the State  Superintendent's designee; and</section><section prefix="(4)">The following 14 members appointed by the Governor:<section prefix="(i)">One member representing the Library;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Five members representing  publishers of textbooks used in higher education who may include representatives of the Association of American Publishers;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Three members, one representing each of the following institutions of higher education:<section prefix="1.">The University System of Maryland;</section><section prefix="2.">A community college; and</section><section prefix="3.">A 4-year private nonprofit institution of higher education;</section></section><section prefix="(iv)">Two representatives who have knowledge regarding accessible formats for blind and other print disabled individuals;</section><section prefix="(v)">One representative of the student population at institutions of higher education in the State who is blind or print disabled; and</section><section prefix="(vi)">Two members from Maryland organizations representing blind or  other persons with print disabilities.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">At least two of the members of the Committee, in addition to the student member, shall be blind or print disabled.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Governor shall designate the Chair of the  Committee.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A member of the Committee shall serve for a period of 3 years.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Committee shall expire on December 1, 2010.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The Department, the Department of Disabilities, and the Maryland Higher Education Commission shall provide staff for the  Committee.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Committee shall:<section prefix="(i)">Assist the Library in establishing guidelines to facilitate the delivery of instructional materials to blind and print disabled students at institutions of higher education in the State;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Review the guidelines established under item (i) of this paragraph each year; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Assist the Library in revising the guidelines as necessary based on changes in technology or any other pertinent  factors.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The guidelines shall include:<section prefix="(i)">A method by which a course instructor, in  consultation with the individual at the Library or institution designated to make the request for materials under this subtitle, designates which course materials are considered required or essential to student success;</section><section prefix="(ii)">A determination of the availability of technology for the conversion of mathematics and science  materials;</section><section prefix="(iii)">The procedures and standards relating to distribution of files and materials;</section><section prefix="(iv)">Available electronic formats;</section><section prefix="(v)">A list of justifications for which a publisher  may reasonably be exempted from complying with the provisions of  this subtitle;</section><section prefix="(vi)">Procedures for granting a publisher an  exemption when it is determined that a publisher is unable to comply with the requirements of this subtitle for a justifiable  reason included in the list required under item (v) of this  paragraph;</section><section prefix="(vii)">A requirement that the review of the future recommendations of the Alternative Formats Solutions Initiative of the Association of American Publishers determine whether to recommend the incorporation of these recommendations into the  guidelines; and</section><section prefix="(viii)">Any other information the Committee determines to be relevant.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
