<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ged" order_by="ged" level="1">Economic Development</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ged-23-205</section_number>
  <catch_line>Each year, the Department may include in its budget operating funds for:...</catch_line>
  <order_by>205</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Each year, the Department may include in its budget operating funds for:<section prefix="(1)">The State Library Resource Center;</section><section prefix="(2)">Each regional resource center; and</section><section prefix="(3)">Each metropolitan cooperative service program.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The State shall pay all capital expenses for:<section prefix="(i)">The State Library Resource Center; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Each regional resource center.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Before any money is spent under this subsection, the appropriate board of library trustees shall:<section prefix="(i)">Have the project approved by the Department;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Through the Department, submit the request to the Department of Budget and Management for consideration under Title 3, Subtitle 6 of the State Finance and Procurement Article; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Agree to reimburse the Department an amount the Department determines if the facility ceases to be used for a resource center or cooperative service program.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Each year each participating regional resource center shall receive a minimum amount of funding for each resident of the area served, to be used for operating and capital expenses.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The allocation shall be calculated as follows:<section prefix="(i)">For each of fiscal years 2011 through 2016............$6.75 per each resident of the area served;</section><section prefix="(ii)">For fiscal year 2017............$7.00 per each resident of the area served;</section><section prefix="(iii)">For fiscal year 2018............$7.25 per each resident of the area served; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">For fiscal year 2019 and each fiscal year thereafter............$7.50 per each resident of the area served.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Each year the State Library Resource Center shall receive a minimum amount of funding for each State resident in the previous fiscal year, to be used for operating and capital expenses.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The allocation shall be calculated as follows:<section prefix="(i)">For each of fiscal years 2010 through 2016............$1.67 per State resident;</section><section prefix="(ii)">For fiscal year 2017............$1.73 per State resident;</section><section prefix="(iii)">For fiscal year 2018............$1.79 per State resident; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">For fiscal year 2019 and each fiscal year thereafter............$1.85 per State resident.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Department shall:<section prefix="(i)">Disburse funds to the State and regional resource centers and metropolitan cooperative service programs; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Require that these funds be used subject to any conditions specified by the appropriating agency or imposed under this subtitle.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Department may authorize the State Comptroller to withhold funds from any regional resource center or metropolitan cooperative service program that fails to meet the standards adopted by the Department.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
