<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ged" order_by="ged" level="1">Economic Development</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ged-14-406</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this section the following words have the meanings indicated....</catch_line>
  <order_by>406</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Senior citizen" means any resident of this State who is:<section prefix="(i)">60 years of age or older;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Retired and whose chief income is derived from retirement benefits; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Not employed full time.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Institution" means St. Mary's College of Maryland.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">"Tuition" means the basic instructional charge and does not pertain to self-supporting programs or include fees, such as those for registration, application, or laboratory work.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Except as provided in subsection (c) of this section, an institution shall admit a senior citizen to any scheduled course and waive the tuition involved:<section prefix="(1)">Only when regularly scheduled course space is available;</section><section prefix="(2)">For any credit or noncredit course; and</section><section prefix="(3)">For as many as 3 courses per term.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">An institution may not:<section prefix="(1)">Allow a senior citizen to enroll in a degree granting program, unless the senior citizen meets the admission standards of the institution; or</section><section prefix="(2)">Permit the full-time equivalent enrollment of senior citizens for whom tuition has been waived to exceed 2 percent of its undergraduate full-time equivalent enrollment.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">At the termination of each semester, the institution shall furnish to its governing board a statement of the number of senior citizens participating under the provisions of this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">This section does not prohibit an institution from offering senior citizens educational opportunities free of charge beyond these minimum requirements.</section>
  </text>
</law>
