<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="ged" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="24-510" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ged-24-510</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Commission shall appoint an executive director and such additional professional, administrative, and clerical personnel as it considers necessary to carry out the purposes of this subtitle.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Commission shall employ or contract with such other consultants, accountants, engineers, architects, or financial advisors as it deems prudent to the carrying out of the purposes of this subtitle.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Commission may delegate to the executive director any or all of its power to appoint and remove staff.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The executive director shall:<section prefix="(1)">Act as the chief executive officer for the Commission with full authority to direct the activities and supervise the employees of Historic St. Mary's City, in accordance with the policies, plans, and projects approved by the Commission;</section><section prefix="(2)">Represent the Commission with the Governor, the General Assembly, the Historic St. Mary's Foundation, and all other State, local and federal governmental agencies and generally act as the chief spokesperson for all purposes, including solicitation of public and private funds for the advancement of Historic St. Mary's City;</section><section prefix="(3)">Act as secretary to the Commission and prepare or have prepared minutes of each action taken by the Commission and the executive committee; and</section><section prefix="(4)">Perform any other duty that the Commission requires for carrying out the provisions of this subtitle.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Notwithstanding any other provision of law to the contrary, employees of the Commission, including the executive director, may accept, subject to the approval of the Commission, faculty status at St. Mary's College of Maryland, including remunerated teaching or other professional responsibilities.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">As the Commission considers appropriate, the Commission may request other units of State government to detail staff to the Commission.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Attorney General shall provide legal counsel and services to the Commission.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Other units of State government may detail staff or technical assistance to the Commission on request of the Commission.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">An employee of the Commission:<section prefix="(i)">Is subject to the rules and procedures of the personnel system established under &#xA7; 14-408 of this article; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Is entitled to participate in the health benefit plans, including medical, prescription, dental, mental health, substance abuse, and vision plans, term life and personal accident and dismemberment insurance plans, flexible spending accounts, and any other benefits established under &#xA7; 14-408 of this article.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">An employee of the Commission is entitled to participate in the employee pension plans authorized by and in accordance with &#xA7; 14-408(c) of this article.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The Commission's obligation for retirement costs for Commission employees shall be computed, charged, and paid in accordance with &#xA7; 21-308(b)(1) and (c)(1) of the State Personnel and Pensions Article.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
