<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ged" order_by="ged" level="1">Economic Development</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ged-7-308</section_number>
  <catch_line>A principal, assistant principal, or school security guard of a public school may make a reasonable ...</catch_line>
  <order_by>308</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">A principal, assistant principal, or school security guard of a public school may make a reasonable search of a student on the school premises or on a school-sponsored trip if the searcher has a reasonable belief that the student has in the student's possession an item, the possession of which is a criminal offense under the laws of this State or a violation of any other State law or a rule or regulation of the county board.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Subject to the provisions of paragraph (2) of this subsection, a county board may authorize a teacher of a public school to make a reasonable search of a student on a school-sponsored trip if the teacher has a reasonable belief that the student has in the student's possession an item, the possession of which is a criminal offense under the laws of this State or a violation of any other State law or a rule or regulation of the county board.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">To qualify to conduct a search under this subsection, a teacher shall be designated in writing by a principal and receive training to conduct a search commensurate with the training received by a principal.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A search under subsection (a) or (b) of this section shall be made in the presence of a third party.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A principal, assistant principal, or school security guard of a public school may make a search of the physical plant of the school and its appurtenances including the lockers of students.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The right of the school official to search the locker shall be announced or published previously in the school.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The Department shall adopt rules and regulations relating to the searches permitted under this section.</section>
  </text>
</law>
