<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ged" order_by="ged" level="1">Economic Development</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ged-26-102</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this section, "school resource officer" means a law enforcement officer as defined under &#xA7; 3-101...</catch_line>
  <order_by>102</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, "school resource officer" means a law enforcement officer as defined under &#xA7; 3-101(e) of the Public Safety Article who has been assigned to a school in accordance with a memorandum of understanding between the chief of a law enforcement agency as defined under &#xA7; 3-101(b) of the Public Safety Article and the local education agency.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The governing board, president, superintendent, principal, or school resource officer of any public institution of elementary, secondary, or higher education, or a person designated in writing by the board or any of these persons, may deny access to the buildings or grounds of the institution to any other person who:<section prefix="(1)">Is not a bona fide, currently registered student, or staff or faculty member at the institution, and who does not have lawful business to pursue at the institution;</section><section prefix="(2)">Is a bona fide, currently registered student at the institution and has been suspended or expelled from the institution, for the duration of the suspension or expulsion; or</section><section prefix="(3)">Acts in a manner that disrupts or disturbs the normal educational functions of the institution.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Administrative personnel, authorized employees of any public institution of elementary, secondary, or higher education, and persons designated in subsection (b) of this section may demand identification and evidence of qualification from any person who desires to use or enter the premises of the institution.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The governing board of any public institution of elementary, secondary, or higher education may enter into an agreement with appropriate law enforcement agencies to carry out the responsibilities of this section when:<section prefix="(1)">The institution is closed; or</section><section prefix="(2)">None of the persons designated in subsection (b) of this section are present in the buildings or on the grounds of the institution.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">A person is guilty of a misdemeanor and on conviction is subject to a fine not exceeding $1,000, imprisonment not exceeding 6 months, or both if he:<section prefix="(1)">Trespasses on the grounds of any public institution of elementary, secondary, or higher education;</section><section prefix="(2)">Fails or refuses to leave the grounds of any of these institutions after being requested to do so by a person designated in subsection (b) of this section as being authorized to deny access to the buildings or grounds of the institution; or</section><section prefix="(3)">Willfully damages or defaces any building, furnishing, statue, monument, memorial, tree, shrub, grass, or flower on the grounds of any of these institutions.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
