<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ged" order_by="" level="1">Economic Development</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ged-18-204</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>204</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In addition to any other powers granted and duties imposed by this title, the Office has the powers and duties set forth in this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Except as otherwise provided in this title, the Office shall:<section prefix="(1)">Administer student financial assistance programs;</section><section prefix="(2)">Issue and disseminate public information about student financial assistance;</section><section prefix="(3)">Regulate the form and submission of applications for student financial assistance under this title; and</section><section prefix="(4)">Conduct conferences and interviews with applicants to evaluate their eligibility.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Office may adopt any rule or regulation necessary to carry out its powers and duties.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The rules and regulations adopted by the Office under paragraph (1) of this subsection may include provisions for:<section prefix="(i)">The performance of a service obligation for a program that as a condition of award requires a recipient of student financial assistance to perform a service obligation;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The repayment of student financial assistance funds received should a recipient fail to perform a service obligation; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Waiver and deferment of a service obligation or repayment in circumstances determined by the Commission.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Office:<section prefix="(1)">Shall administer any federal program of scholarships or grants to students or institutions except for the Christa McAuliffe Fellowship which shall be administered by the Maryland State Department of Education; and</section><section prefix="(2)">May do anything necessary to comply with any federal law relating to these scholarships or grants.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The Office shall:<section prefix="(1)">Arrange for the competitive examination required of applicants for certain scholarships; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Send the results of the examination to the appropriate institutions and to the person who awards the scholarship.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The Office shall:<section prefix="(1)">Analyze under uniform standards the financial need of each applicant for a scholarship for which financial need is a consideration; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Send its analysis to the appropriate institution and the person who awards the scholarship.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
