<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="ged" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="18-303.1" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ged-18-303.1</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, "Program" means the College Readiness Outreach Program.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Commission and the Department, in collaboration with county boards of education, county superintendents, and institutions of higher education, shall jointly administer the College Readiness Outreach Program.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Program shall provide guidance to students who qualify for a Guaranteed Access Grant in 9th or 10th grade to assist the students in successfully:<section prefix="(1)">Completing a college preparatory curriculum;</section><section prefix="(2)">Graduating from high school; and</section><section prefix="(3)">Matriculating at an institution of higher education as defined in &#xA7;&#xA7; 18-305 and 18-308 of this subtitle.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Commission and the Department shall designate statewide and regional coordinators for the Program.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The statewide and regional coordinators shall:<section prefix="(i)">Work with county boards of education and county superintendents to provide guidance and one-on-one mentoring to participating students in high school; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Publicize the Program through community outreach and marketing materials.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The Commission and the Department may enter into agreements with existing organizations that provide counseling and mentoring services to fulfill the requirements of this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The Commission and the Department may supplement professional mentors with:<section prefix="(1)">Postsecondary students receiving work-study assistance at Maryland institutions of higher education; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Secondary students in 11th and 12th grades who are successfully completing high school graduation requirements.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Funds for the Program shall be as provided in the State budget.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">To the extent that funds are provided, the State shall provide 50 percent of the costs associated with the local administration and one-on-one mentoring components of the Program, except that in a county that meets the requirements of a "qualified distressed county" under &#xA7; 1-101 of the Economic Development Article the State shall provide 75 percent of the costs.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(h)">The Commission and the Department may adopt regulations necessary to implement this section.</section>
  </text>
</law>
