<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="ged" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="3-1201" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ged-3-1201</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Somerset County Board shall be elected and consists of one member elected from each commissioner district in the county.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A member from a commissioner district shall be a resident of that district.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A candidate for the county board shall be a registered voter of the county.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A member from a commissioner district who no longer resides in that district may not continue as a member of the county board.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Members of the board shall be elected at a general election as required by subsection (d) of this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Subject to the provisions of paragraph (2) of this subsection, each member serves for a term of 4 years beginning on January 1 after the member's election and until a successor is elected and qualifies.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The terms of members are staggered as provided in this paragraph.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)"/>
        <section prefix="(iii)"/>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Governor shall appoint a qualified individual to fill any vacancy on the board for the remainder of the term and until a successor is elected and qualifies.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The State Board may remove a member of the county board for:<section prefix="(i)">Immorality;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Misconduct in office;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Incompetency; or</section><section prefix="(iv)">Willful neglect of duty.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Before removing a member, the State Board shall send the member a copy of the charges against him and give him an opportunity within 10 days to request a hearing.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">If the member requests a hearing within the 10-day period:<section prefix="(i)">The State Board promptly shall hold a hearing, but a hearing may not be set within 10 days after the State Board sends the member a notice of the hearing; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">The member shall have an opportunity to be heard publicly before the State Board in his own defense, in person or by counsel.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">A member removed under this subsection has the right to a de novo review of the removal by the Circuit Court for Somerset County.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
