<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ged" order_by="ged" level="1">Economic Development</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ged-12-109</section_number>
  <catch_line>In consultation with the Chancellor and after a thorough search, the Board of Regents shall appoint ...</catch_line>
  <order_by>109</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In consultation with the Chancellor and after a thorough search, the Board of Regents shall appoint a qualified person as president of each constituent institution.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The president of each constituent institution is entitled to the compensation established by the Board of Regents.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The president of each constituent institution serves at the pleasure of the Board of Regents.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The president of each constituent institution shall:<section prefix="(1)">Serve as the chief executive officer of the institution;</section><section prefix="(2)">Be responsible and accountable to the Board for the discipline and successful conduct of the institution and supervision of each of its departments; and</section><section prefix="(3)">Take every initiative in:<section prefix="(i)">Implementing the policies of the Board and the constituent institution; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Promoting the institution's development and efficiency.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">Subject to the authority and applicable regulations and policies of the Board of Regents, each president shall:<section prefix="(1)">Develop a plan of institutional mission in accordance with Title 11, Subtitle 3 of this article;</section><section prefix="(2)">Have the authority to develop new academic programs and curtail or eliminate existing programs in accordance with the procedures set forth in &#xA7;&#xA7; 11-206 and 11-206.1 of this article;</section><section prefix="(3)">Formulate operating and capital budget requests designed to further the mission of the institution;</section><section prefix="(4)">Appoint, promote, fix salaries, grant tenure, assign duties, and terminate personnel;</section><section prefix="(5)">Subject to the provisions of subsection (g) of this section, have authority to create any position within existing funds available to the University, to the extent the cost of the position, including the cost of any fringe benefits, is funded from existing funds;</section><section prefix="(6)">Establish admissions standards;</section><section prefix="(7)">Set tuition and fees;</section><section prefix="(8)">Administer financial aid;</section><section prefix="(9)">Enter into contracts and cooperative agreements;</section><section prefix="(10)">Have the authority to accept gifts and grants and maintain and manage endowment income;</section><section prefix="(11)">Have the authority to recommend change in the name or status of the institution;</section><section prefix="(12)">Regulate and administer athletic and student activities;</section><section prefix="(13)">In compliance with State, federal, and Board mandates and policies, oversee affirmative action and equal employment opportunities;</section><section prefix="(14)">Establish organizations for the administration of campus alumni affairs;</section><section prefix="(15)">Be responsible for all academic matters;</section><section prefix="(16)">Have the authority to establish and appoint an institutional board to:<section prefix="(i)">Provide advice to the president;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Assist in community relations;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Assist in institutional development; or</section><section prefix="(iv)">Provide any other assistance requested by the president;</section></section><section prefix="(17)">Establish traffic regulations for the campus;</section><section prefix="(18)">Designate one or more representatives to participate as a party in collective bargaining on behalf of the institution in accordance with Title 3 of the State Personnel and Pensions Article; and</section><section prefix="(19)">Perform any other duties assigned by the Board.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The institutional boards established under subsection (e)(16) of this section shall be known as boards of visitors. Each board shall submit a report by October 1 of each year to:<section prefix="(i)">The Governor;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The Chairman of the Board of Regents of the University System of Maryland;</section><section prefix="(iii)">The Secretary of the Maryland Higher Education Commission; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">The presiding officers of the Maryland General Assembly.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Except as provided in paragraph (3) of this subsection, each report submitted under paragraph (1) of this subsection shall include the comments of the appropriate board on the institution's progress toward meeting its goals consistent with its mission.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The report of the University of Maryland, College Park Board of Visitors shall include:<section prefix="(i)">The Board of Visitors' evaluation of the status of the effort by the University System of Maryland and the State in meeting the requirements of the Maryland Charter for Higher Education set forth in &#xA7; 10-209 of this article which require the University System of Maryland to:<section prefix="1.">Provide the College Park campus with the level of operating funding and facilities necessary to place it among the upper echelon of its peer institutions;</section><section prefix="2.">Maintain and enhance the College Park campus as the State's flagship campus with programs and faculty nationally and internationally recognized for excellence in research and the advancement of knowledge;</section><section prefix="3.">Admit as freshmen to the College Park campus highly qualified students who have academic profiles that suggest exceptional ability; and</section><section prefix="4.">Provide access to the upper division undergraduate level of the College Park campus for students who have excelled in completing lower division study;</section></section><section prefix="(ii)">A status report on the University's effort to achieve national eminence;</section><section prefix="(iii)">A status report on success in attaining federal research grants, private gifts, and other sources of nonstate revenue; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">Other matters in support of institutional priorities as determined by the Board of Visitors.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The institutional boards of visitors are encouraged to meet periodically with the Chancellor and Board of Regents to develop close working relationships.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">Subsection (e)(5) of this section may not be construed to require any additional State General Fund support.</section>
  </text>
</law>
