<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ged" order_by="ged" level="1">Economic Development</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ged-2-302</section_number>
  <catch_line>The State Superintendent shall be appointed by the State Board for a term of 4 years beginning on Ju...</catch_line>
  <order_by>302</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The State Superintendent shall be appointed by the State Board for a term of 4 years beginning on July 1 after his appointment and serves until a successor is appointed and qualifies.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The State Board shall fix his salary and pay it from the appropriation for the expenses and maintenance of the Department.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The State Superintendent shall:<section prefix="(1)">Be an experienced and competent educator;</section><section prefix="(2)">Be a graduate of an accredited college or university;</section><section prefix="(3)">Have at least 2 years of special academic and professional graduate preparation in an accredited college or university; and</section><section prefix="(4)">Have at least 7 years of experience in teaching and administration.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The State Board may remove the State Superintendent for:<section prefix="(i)">Immorality;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Misconduct in office;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Insubordination;</section><section prefix="(iv)">Incompetency; or</section><section prefix="(v)">Willful neglect of duty.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Before removing the State Superintendent, the State Board shall send the Superintendent a copy of the charges against him and give him an opportunity within 10 days to request a hearing.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">If the State Superintendent requests a hearing within the 10-day period:<section prefix="(i)">The State Board promptly shall hold a hearing, but a hearing may not be set within 10 days after the State Board sends the State Superintendent a notice of the hearing; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">The State Superintendent shall have an opportunity to be heard publicly before the State Board in his own defense, in person or by counsel.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The State Board shall appoint a new State Superintendent to fill a vacancy in that office for the remainder of the unexpired term.</section>
  </text>
</law>
