<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ged" order_by="ged" level="1">Economic Development</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ged-16-508</section_number>
  <catch_line>Beginning with fiscal year 1996, the Governor shall include in the annual budget submission a Genera...</catch_line>
  <order_by>508</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Beginning with fiscal year 1996, the Governor shall include in the annual budget submission a General Fund appropriation for Baltimore City Community College in the amount provided in subsection (b) of this section to provide instruction and services to students enrolled in an English for Speakers of Other Languages ("ESOL") program.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">To qualify for a grant under this section, each participant in the program shall be a student:<section prefix="(i)">Born outside of the United States or whose native language is not English;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Who comes from an environment where a language other than English is dominant; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">Who is an American Indian or Alaskan native and comes from an environment where a language other than English has had a significant impact on the student's level of English language proficiency.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Subject to the provisions of paragraph (2) of this subsection, the amount of the grant shall be $800 times the number of qualified full-time equivalent students who are enrolled in a Baltimore City Community College ESOL program, as certified by the Maryland Higher Education Commission.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The total amount of the grant under this subsection may not exceed $1,000,000 for any fiscal year.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Baltimore City Community College may not transfer State funds received under this subsection to any other program or category.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Subject to the provisions of subsection (b) of this section, for any fiscal year in which the State appropriation is insufficient to fully fund all grants eligible under this section, the Governor shall include in the budget bill for the following fiscal year a deficiency appropriation to fund all unfunded grants.</section>
  </text>
</law>
