<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="ged" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="3-108.1" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ged-3-108.1</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, "board" means the Baltimore City Board of School Commissioners of the Baltimore City Public School System.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">There is a Baltimore City Board of School Commissioners of the Baltimore City Public School System.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The board consists of:<section prefix="(1)">Nine voting members jointly appointed by the Mayor of Baltimore City and the Governor from a list of qualified individuals submitted to the Mayor and the Governor by the State Board; and</section><section prefix="(2)">One voting student member appointed as provided in subsection (o) of this section.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Each member of the board shall be a resident of Baltimore City.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">To the extent practicable, the membership of the board shall reflect the demographic composition of Baltimore City.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">At least four of the voting members shall possess a high level of knowledge and expertise concerning the successful administration of a large business, nonprofit, or governmental entity and shall have served in a high level management position within such an entity.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">At least three of the voting members shall possess a high level of knowledge and expertise concerning education.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">At least one voting member shall be a parent of a student enrolled in the Baltimore City Public School System as of the date of appointment of the member.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Among the nine voting members, at least one member shall also possess knowledge or experience in the education of children with disabilities.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The knowledge or experience may be derived from being the parent of a child with a disability.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(j)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The term of a voting member is 3 years.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The terms of the voting members are staggered as required by the terms provided for members of the board on June 1, 1997.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">At the end of a term, a voting member continues to serve until a successor is appointed and qualifies.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">A voting member who is appointed after a term has begun serves only for the remainder of the term and until a successor is appointed and qualifies.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">A voting member may not serve more than two consecutive full terms.</section>
      <section prefix="(6)">To the extent practicable, the Governor and the Mayor shall fill any vacancy on the board within 60 days of the date of the vacancy from a list of qualified individuals submitted to the Mayor and the Governor by the State Board.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(k)">On the joint approval of the Mayor of Baltimore City and the Governor, a member may be removed only for cause in accordance with &#xA7; 3-108 of this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(l)">Each member of the board serves without compensation.</section>
    <section prefix="(m)">On appointment of the board, the Governor and the Mayor shall jointly select one of the voting members to serve as the chairman of the board who shall serve through June 30, 1999.</section>
    <section prefix="(n)">Beginning on July 1, 1999 and every 2 years thereafter, from among its voting members the board shall elect a chairman.</section>
    <section prefix="(o)">
      <section prefix="(1)">One student member shall be a student enrolled in the Baltimore City Public School System who shall be selected by the Associated Student Congress of Baltimore City.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The term of a student member is 1 year.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A student member may not serve more than two consecutive full terms.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The student member may vote on all matters before the board except those relating to:<section prefix="(i)">Personnel;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Capital and operating budgets;</section><section prefix="(iii)">School closings, reopenings, and boundaries;</section><section prefix="(iv)">Collective bargaining decisions;</section><section prefix="(v)">Student disciplinary matters; and</section><section prefix="(vi)">Appeals to the board as provided under &#xA7;&#xA7; 4-205 and 6-202 of this article.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(5)">The student member may not attend or participate in an executive or special session of the board.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(p)">Any action by the board shall require:<section prefix="(1)">A quorum of a majority of the voting members then serving; and</section><section prefix="(2)">The affirmative vote of a majority of the voting members then serving.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
