<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="ged" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="24-303" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ged-24-303</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Board consists of 13 voting members appointed by the Governor.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Governor shall appoint at least two members each from St. Mary's, Charles, and Calvert counties.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Each member serves for a term of 4 years and until a successor is appointed and qualifies.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The terms of members are staggered as required by the terms provided for members of the Board on July 1, 1994.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A member may not serve more than two full consecutive terms.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">A member appointed to fill a vacancy in an unexpired term serves only for the remainder of that term and until a successor is appointed and qualifies.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Governor shall appoint one of the voting members to act as chair.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The voting members may elect other officers and establish committees, including advisory committees, as needed.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">In addition to the 13 voting members, the following individuals shall serve as ex officio, nonvoting members:<section prefix="(1)">The commanding officer of the Naval Air Warfare Center - Aircraft Division at Patuxent River, or the commanding officer's designee;</section><section prefix="(2)">A member of the St. Mary's County Building Authority recommended by the St. Mary's County Board of Commissioners; and</section><section prefix="(3)">A representative of the Tri-County Council for Southern Maryland.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">Each member of the Board:<section prefix="(1)">Serves without compensation; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Is entitled to reimbursement for expenses in accordance with the Standard State Travel Regulations.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
