<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ged" order_by="" level="1">Economic Development</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ged-7-1101</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>1101</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this subtitle the following terms have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Behavior intervention plan" means a proactive plan designed to address problem behavior exhibited by a student in the educational setting through the use of positive behavioral interventions, strategies, and supports.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Exclusionary time out" means the circumstance in which a student is removed to a designated time-out room or other area for a fixed period not to exceed 30 minutes.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">"Functional behavior assessment" means the systematic process of:<section prefix="(1)">Describing problematic behavior exhibited in the educational setting, including identification of environmental and other factors and settings that contribute to or predict:<section prefix="(i)">The occurrence or nonoccurrence of the behavior; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">The maintenance of the behavior over time; and</section></section><section prefix="(2)">Using the information gathered to guide the development of an effective and efficient behavior intervention plan.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Mechanical restraint" means the use of any device or material attached or adjacent to the student's body that restricts freedom of movement or normal access to any portion of the student's body and that the student cannot easily remove.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Mechanical restraint" does not include a protective or stabilizing device ordered by a physician when it is used as prescribed.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">"Nonpublic school" means a school that receives funds from the Department for the purpose of providing special education and related services to students with disabilities.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Physical restraint" means the use of physical force, without the use of any device or material, to restrict the free movement of all or a portion of a student's body.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Physical restraint" does not include:<section prefix="(i)">Briefly holding a student in order to calm or comfort the student;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Holding a student's hand or arm to escort the student safely from one area to another;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Moving a disruptive student who is unwilling to leave the area when other methods such as counseling have been unsuccessful; or</section><section prefix="(iv)">Breaking up a fight in the school building or on school grounds.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(h)">"Seclusion" means the confinement of a student in a locked room, closet, box, or other space from which the student is physically prevented from leaving.</section>
  </text>
</law>
