<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ged" order_by="" level="1">Economic Development</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ged-23-202</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>202</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The boards of library trustees of at least three public library systems outside the standard metropolitan statistical areas defined by the United States Bureau of the Census may request the Department to establish and maintain a regional resource center.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Each regional resource center shall provide, through mutual cooperation and coordination, books, information, and other material and service resources that an individual library cannot provide adequately by itself.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A region to be served by a regional resource center shall have a population of at least 100,000.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Subject to approval by the Department, the boards of library trustees of the participating library systems shall designate the library to serve as the resource center.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">If possible, the library selected as the regional resource center shall be:<section prefix="(i)">The strongest library in the region; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Located so as to be of greatest service to the entire region.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">There is a board of advisors for each regional resource center.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The board of advisors consists of two individuals selected by the board of trustees of each participating library system to represent its library.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The board of advisors for each regional resource center shall:<section prefix="(i)">Gather information on the resource needs of its region and this State;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Before State funds are distributed to it, make an annual report to the Department and the State Advisory Council on Libraries that evaluates and makes recommendations on the operation of the center;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Recommend to the board of trustees of the library designated as the regional resource center and to the Department policies and procedures for the development and use of the regional resource center;</section><section prefix="(iv)">Promote the use of the regional resource center;</section><section prefix="(v)">Recommend the purchase, condemnation, rental, use, sale, or conveyance of property for any purpose valid under this section; and</section><section prefix="(vi)">Recommend plans for the regional resource centers, which may include the use of facilities of participating libraries, additions to the facilities of participating libraries, or new facilities separate from the existing facilities of participating libraries.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The head of each regional resource center is the administrator of the library designated as the center.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The administrator shall operate the regional resource center under standards adopted by the Department.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The policies and procedures of the regional resource center shall be:<section prefix="(i)">Recommended by the board of trustees of the library designated as the center; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Approved by the board of advisors of the center.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">Each regional resource center shall:<section prefix="(1)">Make interlibrary loans of books and materials;</section><section prefix="(2)">Supply collections and exhibits of specialized materials;</section><section prefix="(3)">Provide consultant services;</section><section prefix="(4)">Organize inservice training for library staffs; and</section><section prefix="(5)">Develop and operate cooperative services among libraries.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
