<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="ged" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="4-107" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ged-4-107</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Each county board shall hold an annual meeting on or as near as possible to the second Tuesday in July, except that:<section prefix="(1)">In Allegany County, the annual meeting shall be held on the second Tuesday in January;</section><section prefix="(2)">In Montgomery County, the annual meeting shall be held on or before January 10;</section><section prefix="(3)">In Prince George's County, the annual meeting shall be held on the first Monday in December;</section><section prefix="(4)">In St. Mary's County, the annual meeting shall be held following the first Monday in December; and</section><section prefix="(5)">In Washington County, the annual meeting shall be held in December, on or before the 16th day.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A county board may hold any other meetings that its duties and business require.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Except as provided in Title 3 of this article, each county board, at its annual meeting, shall elect a president and a vice president from among its members by means of an individually recorded vote.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">All final actions of a county board shall be taken at a public meeting. The minutes of the meeting shall be available to the public.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A county board may meet and deliberate in executive session if the matter under consideration is:<section prefix="(i)">Land and site acquisitions; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">Personnel and labor relations.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as otherwise provided in this article, a member of a county board may not receive compensation.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Each member shall be reimbursed for traveling and other expenses incurred in the performance of his duties.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Each member of the county board of the counties specified in this paragraph shall receive the enumerated amounts annually for traveling and other expenses.<section prefix="(i)">Calvert County:</section><section prefix="(ii)">Caroline County:</section><section prefix="(iii)">Cecil County:</section><section prefix="(iv)">Charles County:</section><section prefix="(v)">Dorchester County:</section><section prefix="(vi)">Frederick County:</section><section prefix="(vii)">Queen Anne's County:</section><section prefix="(viii)">Talbot County:</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">Each member of the Charles County Board shall receive the following amounts annually as compensation:<section prefix="(i)">Member:</section><section prefix="(ii)">Vice chairman:</section><section prefix="(iii)">Chairman:</section></section>
      <section prefix="(5)">Each member of the St. Mary's County Board shall receive the following amounts annually as compensation:<section prefix="(i)">Member $6,000with an annual increase of $250 for each additional year of service; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Chairman $7,000with an annual increase of $250 for each additional year of service.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(6)">Each member of the Wicomico County Board shall receive the following amounts annually as compensation:<section prefix="(i)">Member$3,700; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Chairman$4,000.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(7)">Each member of the Worcester County Board shall receive an amount annually for traveling and other expenses as determined by the County Commissioners, but in the amount of at least:<section prefix="(i)">Member$2,000; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Chairman$2,400.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
