<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ged" order_by="ged" level="1">Economic Development</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ged-3-701</section_number>
  <catch_line>The Howard County Board consists of:...</catch_line>
  <order_by>701</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Howard County Board consists of:<section prefix="(1)">Seven elected members; and</section><section prefix="(2)">One student member.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A candidate who becomes an elected member of the county board shall be a resident and registered voter of Howard County. Any elected member who no longer resides in Howard County may not continue as a member of the board.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The seven elected members of the Howard County Board shall be elected:<section prefix="(1)">At the general election every 2 years as required by subsection (d) of this section; and</section><section prefix="(2)">From Howard County at large.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The terms of the elected members are staggered as provided in this subsection.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">Each term of office begins on the first Monday in December after the election of a member and until a successor is elected and qualifies.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The term of office of the member elected at the 2002 election is 4 years.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The successor to this office shall serve for a term of 4 years.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Two members shall be elected at the 2004 election.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The successors to these offices elected at the 2008 election shall serve a term of 4 years.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(4)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Five members shall be elected at the 2006 election.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">Subject to paragraph (5) of this subsection, the successors to these offices shall be elected at the 2010 election and shall serve for a term of 4 years.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(5)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Except as provided in subparagraph (ii) of this paragraph, as of the 2006 election, the term of each office is 4 years.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">
          <section prefix="1.">At the 2006 election, the individual elected as a member who receives the lowest number of votes among the five members elected in that election shall serve for a term of 2 years.</section>
          <section prefix="2.">The successor to the office for the member elected at the 2006 election who receives the lowest number of votes among the five members elected in that election shall be elected at the 2008 election and shall serve for a term of 4 years.</section>
        </section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(6)">Except as provided in paragraph (7) of this subsection and subject to the confirmation of the County Council, the County Executive of Howard County shall appoint a qualified individual to fill any vacancy on the county board for the remainder of that term and until a successor is appointed and qualifies.</section>
      <section prefix="(7)">If a vacancy occurs before the date that is 1 year following the date of the member's election, the individual appointed under paragraph (6) of this subsection shall serve only until a successor is elected by the voters at the next general election.</section>
      <section prefix="(8)">Candidates for the vacated office may be nominated at a primary election in the same manner as for any other position on the Howard County Board.</section>
      <section prefix="(9)">When more than two members of the county board are to be elected at an election and the terms of the offices to be filled at the election vary, the elected candidates receiving the greater number of votes shall fill the offices with the longer terms.</section>
      <section prefix="(10)">The candidate receiving the vacated position shall take office on the first Monday in December after the election and shall continue to serve for the remainder of the vacated term and until a successor is elected and qualifies.</section>
      <section prefix="(11)">Except as provided in this subsection, an election to fill a vacancy on the Howard County Board of Education shall be governed by &#xA7;&#xA7; 8-801 through 8-806 of the Election Law Article.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The student member shall be a bona fide resident of Howard County and a regularly enrolled junior or senior year student from a Howard County public high school.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The student member shall serve for a term of 1 year beginning on July 1 after the member's election, subject to confirmation of the election results by the county board.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The nomination and election process for the student member:<section prefix="(i)">Shall be approved by the Howard County Board of Education;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Shall include a provision that provides for the replacement of one or both of the final candidates if one or both of them are unable, ineligible, or disqualified to proceed in the election; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Shall allow for any student in grades 6 through 11 enrolled in a Howard County public school to vote directly for one of the two student member candidates.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The student member candidate who receives the second highest number of votes in the direct election:<section prefix="(i)">Shall become the alternate student member; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Shall serve if the student member who is elected is unable, ineligible, or disqualified to complete the student member's term of office.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(5)">Except as provided in paragraphs (6) and (7) of this subsection, the student member has the same rights and privileges as an elected member.</section>
      <section prefix="(6)">Unless invited to attend by the affirmative vote of a majority of the county board, the student member may not attend a closed session addressing a matter on which a student member is prohibited from voting under paragraph (7) of this subsection.</section>
      <section prefix="(7)">The student member shall vote on all matters except those relating to:<section prefix="(i)">Geographical attendance areas under &#xA7; 4-109 of this article;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Acquisition and disposition of real property and matters pertaining to school construction under &#xA7; 4-115 of this article;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Employment of architects under &#xA7; 4-117 of this article;</section><section prefix="(iv)">Donations under &#xA7; 4-118 of this article;</section><section prefix="(v)">Condemnation under &#xA7; 4-119 of this article;</section><section prefix="(vi)">Consolidation of schools and transportation of students under &#xA7; 4-120 of this article;</section><section prefix="(vii)">Appointment and salary of a county superintendent under &#xA7;&#xA7; 4-201 and 4-202 of this article;</section><section prefix="(viii)">Employee discipline and other appeals under &#xA7; 4-205(c) of this article;</section><section prefix="(ix)">Budgetary matters under Title 5 of this article;</section><section prefix="(x)">Appointment and promotion of staff under &#xA7; 6-201 of this article;</section><section prefix="(xi)">Discipline of certificated staff under &#xA7; 6-202 of this article;</section><section prefix="(xii)">Collective bargaining for certificated employees under Title 6, Subtitle 4 of this article;</section><section prefix="(xiii)">Collective bargaining for noncertificated employees under Title 6, Subtitle 5 of this article; and</section><section prefix="(xiv)">Student suspension and expulsion under &#xA7; 7-305 of this article.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(8)">The student member may not receive compensation but, after submitting expense vouchers, shall be reimbursed for out-of-pocket expenses incurred in connection with official duties, in accordance with the procedures and regulations established by the county board.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">Passage of a motion by the county board requires the affirmative vote of:<section prefix="(1)">Five members if the student member is authorized to vote; or</section><section prefix="(2)">Four members if the student member is not authorized to vote.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The State Board may remove a member of the county board for:<section prefix="(i)">Immorality;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Misconduct in office;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Incompetency; or</section><section prefix="(iv)">Willful neglect of duty.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Before removing a member, the State Board shall send the member a copy of the charges against the member and give the member an opportunity within 10 days to request a hearing.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">If the member requests a hearing within the 10-day period:<section prefix="(i)">The State Board promptly shall hold a hearing, but a hearing may not be set within 10 days after the State Board sends the member a notice of the hearing; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">The member shall have an opportunity to be heard publicly before the State Board in the member's own defense, in person or by counsel.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">A member removed under this subsection has the right to a de novo review of the removal by the Circuit Court for Howard County.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
