<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ged" order_by="" level="1">Economic Development</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ged-8-304</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>304</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">There is a Maryland School for the Deaf.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The governance of the Maryland School for the Deaf is vested in the Board of Trustees of the Maryland School for the Deaf.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Board of Trustees shall consist of 19 members appointed by the Governor with the advice and consent of the Senate.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Of the 19 members, at least 6 members shall be deaf.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Each member of the Board shall:<section prefix="(i)">Be a resident of the State;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Be a member of the general public; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Have demonstrated an active interest in the education of deaf children.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">Each geographic region of the State shall be represented by at least 1 member of the Board.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The term of a member is 6 years.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The terms of the members are staggered as required by the terms provided for the members of the Board on October 1, 1992.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">At the end of a term, a member continues to serve until a successor is appointed and qualifies.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">A member may not serve more than 2 consecutive terms.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The Board may:<section prefix="(1)">Apply for, accept, and spend any gift or grant from the federal government, any foundation, or any other person; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Maintain, manage, and invest any gifts or grants that it accepts.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The Board shall establish an annual operating budget.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">There is a branch of the Maryland School for the Deaf.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">This branch shall be located near the population center of this State.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The branch shall be administered and operated as part of and is subject to the Maryland School for the Deaf.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(h)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Maryland School for the Deaf shall adopt written standards for the admission of students.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The standards shall define and distinguish between students who are bona fide Maryland residents and those who are out-of-state students, for purposes of admission and tuition.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(i)">The Maryland School for the Deaf shall admit free of charge students who:<section prefix="(1)">Are bona fide Maryland residents; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Meet its admission standards.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(j)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Maryland School for the Deaf may admit for tuition out-of-state students who meet its admission standards.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The School shall establish tuition rates on an annual basis.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
