<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ged" order_by="ged" level="1">Economic Development</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ged-8-406</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this section, "wraparound services":...</catch_line>
  <order_by>406</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, "wraparound services":<section prefix="(1)">Means individualized services, excluding regular school programs or services, that are provided to a child with a disability and the child's family; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Includes the following services:<section prefix="(i)">Behavioral aide in home;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Education tutoring;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Family therapy;</section><section prefix="(iv)">Medication management;</section><section prefix="(v)">Respite care;</section><section prefix="(vi)">Vocational mentoring; and</section><section prefix="(vii)">Environmental accessibility adaptations.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A child with a disability who needs special education and related services that cannot be provided in a public county, regional, or State program shall be placed in an appropriate nonpublic educational program that offers these services.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A child with a disability who needs special education and related services is eligible for an appropriate nonpublic educational placement under this section if a State or local agency provides documentation that the child cannot attend a public school in the local school system:<section prefix="(i)">Because of the child's home circumstances; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">Subject to subsection (d)(1) and (2) of this section, because of medical necessity.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The cost of the nonpublic educational program shall be paid by the State and the county in which the child is domiciled in accordance with &#xA7; 8-415(d) of this subtitle, as appropriate.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Subject to availability of funding in the State budget, for a child who qualifies for a nonpublic educational program under subsection (b)(2) of this section and who requires wraparound services in order to receive special education and related services in the least restrictive environment, the cost of providing the services shall be paid by the State and the county in which the child is domiciled in accordance with &#xA7; 8-415(d) of this subtitle, if a State or local agency documents that the child's parent or legal guardian is unable to provide the wraparound services.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Payment or reimbursement for a nonpublic program may not be provided if the payment or reimbursement would require an additional contribution from the State under &#xA7; 8-415(d)(2) of this subtitle unless the Department approves:<section prefix="(i)">The nonpublic program;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The placement of the child in the program;</section><section prefix="(iii)">The cost of the program; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">The amount of payment or reimbursement.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">For wraparound services, payment or reimbursement may not be provided in accordance with &#xA7; 8-415(d) of this subtitle if:<section prefix="(i)">The child is eligible for funding for out-of-state placement of children under departmental regulations; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">Alternative federal, State, or local funding is available.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Department approval is not required for a nonpublic program if:<section prefix="(i)">The local school system approves the placement of the child in the program; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">The local school system makes the payment or reimbursement from local funds.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The State Board shall adopt regulations that establish standards and guidelines for approvals required by paragraph (3) of this subsection.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">A nonpublic placement recommended by a local school system for approval under subsection (d)(1) of this section shall be approved or disapproved pursuant to the regulations of the State Board. However, the Department may not disapprove a nonpublic placement recommended by a local school system for a child unless the Department provides an appropriate alternative placement in conformity with the regulations of the State Board and applicable federal laws and regulations. The Department may not terminate funding for the last approved nonpublic placement of a child during the pendency of an administrative or judicial review of a recommended placement change.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">In addition to meeting the requirements of this subtitle, a local school system seeking nonpublic tuition payment shall obtain funding approval from the local coordinating council and the State Coordinating Council in accordance with departmental regulations.</section>
  </text>
</law>
