<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ged" order_by="" level="1">Economic Development</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ged-11-206.1</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>206.1</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Public institution of higher education" means:<section prefix="(i)">A public senior higher education institution; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">A community college.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Private nonprofit institution of higher education" has the meaning stated in &#xA7; 10-101(k) of this article.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A president of a public institution of higher education may propose to establish a new program or abolish an existing program if the action:<section prefix="(i)">Is consistent with the institution's adopted mission statement under Subtitle 3 of this title; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Can be implemented within the existing program resources of the institution.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A president of a private nonprofit institution of higher education may propose to establish a new program if the action:<section prefix="(i)">Is consistent with the mission statement published in the official catalog of the private nonprofit institution; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Can be implemented within the existing resources of the institution.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The president of a public institution of higher education shall report any programs that are proposed to be established or abolished in accordance with paragraph (1) of this subsection to:<section prefix="(i)">The institution's governing board; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">The Maryland Higher Education Commission.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The president of a private nonprofit institution of higher education shall report any programs that are proposed to be established in accordance with paragraph (2) of this subsection to the Commission.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">Upon receipt of a proposed new program, the Commission shall notify all other institutions of higher education in the State.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The governing board of a public institution of higher education shall:<section prefix="(1)">Review the actions taken under subsection (b) of this section;</section><section prefix="(2)">Ensure that any new program proposed to be established by a president:<section prefix="(i)">Is consistent with the institution's approved mission statement under Subtitle 3 of this title;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Meets a regional or statewide need consistent with the Maryland State Plan for Postsecondary Education;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Meets criteria for the quality of new programs, developed in consultation with the Commission; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">Can be implemented within the existing program resources of the institution, verified by a process established in consultation with the Commission.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Board of Regents of the University System of Maryland shall approve the proposed new program within 60 days if the program meets the criteria in subsection (c)(2) of this section, subject to the provisions of subsections (e) and (f) of this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">Within 30 days of receipt of a notice of an institution's intent to establish a new program in accordance with subsection (b) of this section, the Commission may file, or the institutions of higher education in the State may file with the Commission, an objection to implementation of a proposed program provided the objection is based on:<section prefix="(1)">Inconsistency of the proposed program with the institution's approved mission for a public institution of higher education and the mission statement published in the official catalog of a private nonprofit institution of higher education;</section><section prefix="(2)">Not meeting a regional or statewide need consistent with the Maryland State Plan for Postsecondary Education;</section><section prefix="(3)">Unreasonable program duplication which would cause demonstrable harm to another institution; or</section><section prefix="(4)">Violation of the State's equal educational opportunity obligations under State and federal law.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If an objection is filed under subsection (e) of this section by the Commission or an institution within 30 days of receipt of a notice of an institution's intent to establish a new program, the Commission shall immediately notify the institution's governing board and president.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Commission shall determine if an institution's objection is justified based on the criteria in subsection (e) of this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">An objection shall be accompanied by detailed information supporting the reasons for the objection.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">If the Commission determines that an objection is justified, the Commission shall negotiate with the institution's governing board and president to modify the proposed program in order to resolve the objection.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">If the objection cannot be resolved within 30 days of receipt of an objection, the Commission shall make a final determination on approval of the new program for a public institution of higher education or a final recommendation on implementation for a private nonprofit institution of higher education.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Commission shall:<section prefix="(i)">Identify programs established under subsection (b) of this section that are inconsistent with the State Plan for Higher Education; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Identify low productivity programs at public institutions of higher education.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If the Commission identifies any programs that meet the criteria set forth in paragraph (1) of this subsection, the Commission shall notify the president of the institution.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">If the Commission notifies a president of an institution under paragraph (2) of this subsection, within 60 days the president of the institution shall provide to the Commission in writing:<section prefix="(i)">An action plan to abolish or modify the program; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">Justification for the continuation of the program.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(h)">The Commission and the governing boards of the public institutions of higher education shall jointly develop a definition and accepted criteria for determining low productivity programs.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">The Commission shall:<section prefix="(1)">Monitor the program development and review process established under this section;</section><section prefix="(2)">Report annually to the Governor and, in accordance with &#xA7; 2-1246 of the State Government Article, the General Assembly on the nature and extent of any duplication or proliferation of programs; and</section><section prefix="(3)">Make available a copy of the report under item (2) of this subsection to the public institutions of higher education and the private nonprofit institutions of higher education.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
