<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ged" order_by="ged" level="1">Economic Development</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ged-7-420</section_number>
  <catch_line>The Department shall establish procedures for the administration of the Centers for Disease Control ...</catch_line>
  <order_by>420</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Department shall establish procedures for the administration of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention Youth Risk Behavior Surveillance System survey.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Department may omit up to a maximum of one-third of the survey questions if the Department considers the content of the questions inappropriate.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Department shall require a local school system to utilize passive parental consent before administering the survey.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The local school system shall provide each parent with:<section prefix="(i)">A statement that:<section prefix="1.">Notifies the parent that:</section><section prefix="2.">Explains how a parent can obtain a copy of the survey questions that will be administered and more information regarding the survey, including the mailing address, telephone number, and website address of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention; and</section></section><section prefix="(ii)">Subject to subsection (d) of this section, a denial of permission form that may be returned by the parent to the school.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">For the academic year during which the survey will be conducted, the denial of permission form shall be a part of the request for emergency contact information that is distributed by the public school to each student or parent or guardian of the student.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The denial of permission form shall be distributed only to a student or the parent or guardian of a student who may be subject to the survey administered under this section.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
