<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ged" order_by="" level="1">Economic Development</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ged-23-406</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>406</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Each board of library trustees:<section prefix="(1)">Shall select and appoint a professional librarian eligible for certification as director of the library to serve at the pleasure of the board; and</section><section prefix="(2)">May delegate to the director its authority to appoint any other necessary employees.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Each board of library trustees shall establish policies for:<section prefix="(1)">Staff classification;</section><section prefix="(2)">Salaries;</section><section prefix="(3)">Work conditions;</section><section prefix="(4)">Suspension with pay;</section><section prefix="(5)">Grievance procedures;</section><section prefix="(6)">Benefits, including vacation and sick leave;</section><section prefix="(7)">Hours of work; and</section><section prefix="(8)">Any other personnel procedures and practices necessary for the efficient operation of the library.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Each professional public librarian appointee to the professional library staff:<section prefix="(1)">Shall hold a certificate of library qualifications issued by the State Superintendent; or</section><section prefix="(2)"><section prefix="(i)">Shall be eligible for State certification as a professional public librarian; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Shall apply for certification within 6 months of starting employment.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The director or the director's designee may suspend a library employee without pay for a specified period up to 10 working days, for the following reasons:<section prefix="(i)">Misconduct in office;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Insubordination;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Incompetency; or</section><section prefix="(iv)">Willful neglect of duty.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The director or the director's designee shall give the suspended employee a written statement that specifies the reasons for the suspension.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The director or the director's designee shall place a copy of the written statement that specifies the reasons for the suspension in the employee's official personnel file.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The employee shall have the opportunity to reply in writing to the director within 10 working days after the employee receives notice of the suspension.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The employee may request a hearing before the board of trustees within 10 working days after receiving notice of the suspension.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">If the employee requests a hearing within the 10-day period, the board shall promptly hold a hearing, but a hearing may not be set within 10 working days after the board sends the employee a notice of the hearing.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(4)">If an employee is suspended without pay and found not guilty of the reasons for the suspension, the board shall refund all pay benefits lost by reason of the suspension to the employee.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">Suspension of an employee with pay shall be as provided by the library's personnel policy.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">On written recommendation of the library director, each board of library trustees may dismiss any library employee under its jurisdiction for any of the following reasons:<section prefix="(i)">Misconduct in office;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Insubordination;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Incompetency; or</section><section prefix="(iv)">Willful neglect of duty.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Before removing an employee, the director shall send the employee a written copy of the charges against the employee and give the employee an opportunity to request a hearing before the board within 10 working days.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">If the employee requests a hearing within the 10-day period the board promptly shall hold a hearing, but a hearing may not be set within 10 working days after the board sends the employee a notice of the hearing.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">The employee shall have an opportunity to be heard publicly before the board in his own defense, in person or by counsel and to bring witnesses to the hearing.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">If the board votes to remove the employee and:<section prefix="(i)">The decision is unanimous, the decision of the board is final; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">The decision is not unanimous, the employee may appeal to the State Board of Education through the State Superintendent.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The director of each library shall:<section prefix="(1)">Act as the general executive officer of the library and be responsible for the management of its operations in accordance with policies approved by the board of library trustees;</section><section prefix="(2)">Prepare the annual budget of the library, and present it to the board for approval;</section><section prefix="(3)">Nominate for appointment all library employees in the county library system; and</section><section prefix="(4)">Establish reasonable rules and adopt regulations for the use of the library system subject to approval by the board of library trustees.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
