<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ged" order_by="ged" level="1">Economic Development</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ged-24-704</section_number>
  <catch_line>There is a Governing Board of the Center....</catch_line>
  <order_by>704</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">There is a Governing Board of the Center.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Governing Board shall include the following members:<section prefix="(1)">The Secretary of Higher Education, or the Secretary's designee;</section><section prefix="(2)">The Chancellor of the University System of Maryland, or the Chancellor's designee;</section><section prefix="(3)">The President of Morgan State University, or the President's designee;</section><section prefix="(4)">The State Superintendent of Schools, or the Superintendent's designee;</section><section prefix="(5)">The Secretary of Labor, Licensing, and Regulation, or the Secretary's designee;</section><section prefix="(6)">A representative of local superintendents of schools, appointed by the Governor with the advice and consent of the Senate;</section><section prefix="(7)">The Executive Director of the Maryland Association of Community Colleges, or the Executive Director's designee; and</section><section prefix="(8)">Four members of the public, appointed by the Governor with the advice and consent of the Senate.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">One of the public members of the Governing Board shall have expertise in large data systems and data security.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Governor shall appoint a chair of the Governing Board from among its members.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">A member appointed by the Governor:<section prefix="(1)">Serves at the pleasure of the Governor;</section><section prefix="(2)">Serves for a term of 3 years and until a successor is appointed and qualifies; and</section><section prefix="(3)">May be reappointed but may not serve more than two consecutive terms.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">A member of the Governing Board:<section prefix="(1)">May not receive compensation as a member of the Governing Board; but</section><section prefix="(2)">Is entitled to reimbursement for expenses under the Standard State Travel Regulations, as provided in the State budget.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(g)">The Governing Board shall:<section prefix="(1)">Establish the organizational placement and location of the Center after seeking and evaluating proposals from interested entities based on criteria that shall include:<section prefix="(i)">The ability of the entity to support the operation of a large data system;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Strength of funding support; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Expertise in data security;</section></section><section prefix="(2)">Develop an implementation plan to phase in the establishment and operation of the Maryland Longitudinal Data System and the Center;</section><section prefix="(3)">Provide general oversight and direction to the Center;</section><section prefix="(4)">Approve the annual budget for the Center;</section><section prefix="(5)">Establish the policy and research agenda of the Center;</section><section prefix="(6)">Before the incorporation of any individual data in the Maryland Longitudinal Data System:<section prefix="(i)">Create an inventory of the individual student data:<section prefix="1.">Proposed to be maintained in the system; and</section><section prefix="2.">Required to be reported by State and federal education mandates;</section></section><section prefix="(ii)">Develop and implement policies to comply with the federal Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act and any other privacy measures, as required by law or the Governing Board; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Develop a detailed data security and safeguarding plan that includes:<section prefix="1.">Authorized access and authentication for authorized access;</section><section prefix="2.">Privacy compliance standards;</section><section prefix="3.">Privacy and security audits;</section><section prefix="4.">Breach notification and procedures; and</section><section prefix="5.">Data retention and disposition policies;</section></section></section><section prefix="(7)">Oversee routine and ongoing compliance with the federal Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act and other relevant privacy laws and policies;</section><section prefix="(8)">Ensure that any contracts that govern databases that are outsourced to private vendors include express provisions that safeguard privacy and security and include penalties for noncompliance;</section><section prefix="(9)">Designate a standard and compliance timeline for electronic transcripts that includes the use of SASID to ensure the uniform and efficient transfer of student data between local education agencies and institutions of higher education; and</section><section prefix="(10)">Review research requirements and set policies for the approval of data requests from State and local agencies, the Maryland General Assembly, and the public.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
