<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ged" order_by="ged" level="1">Economic Development</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ged-3-109</section_number>
  <catch_line>The Baltimore County Board consists of 12 members who shall be appointed as follows:...</catch_line>
  <order_by>109</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Baltimore County Board consists of 12 members who shall be appointed as follows:<section prefix="(1)">Four from the county at large;</section><section prefix="(2)">One from each of the seven councilmanic districts in Baltimore County; and</section><section prefix="(3)">One student member from the county at large.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The student member shall:<section prefix="(i)">Be an eleventh or twelfth grade student in the Baltimore County public school system;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Serve for 1 year; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Advise the board on the thoughts and feelings of students.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Unless invited to attend by an affirmative vote of a majority of the county board, the student member may not attend an executive session that relates to:<section prefix="(i)">Hearings on appeals of special education placements;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Hearings held under &#xA7; 6-202(a) of this article; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">Collective bargaining.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">As provided in paragraph (4) of this subsection, the student member may vote on all matters except those relating to:<section prefix="(i)">&#xA7; 6-202(a) of this article;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Collective bargaining;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Capital and operating budgets; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">School closings, reopenings, and boundaries.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">On a majority vote of the nonstudent members, the board may determine, on a case-by-case basis, whether a matter under consideration is covered by the exclusionary provisions listed in paragraph (3) of this subsection.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A board member who does not maintain his residential qualification shall be replaced as a member.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">If the boundary line of a councilmanic district is changed, the term of an incumbent member of the county board who no longer resides in the councilmanic district because of the change is not affected during this term.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">There is a School Shared Space Council in Baltimore County consisting of 12 employees of the county appointed by the County Executive for a term coterminous with that of the board as follows:<section prefix="(1)">Two from the staff of the county board of education;</section><section prefix="(2)">Two from the County Executive's administrative staff, one of whom shall be the Director of Central Services;</section><section prefix="(3)">One from the Department of Social Services;</section><section prefix="(4)">One from the Department of Recreation and Parks;</section><section prefix="(5)">One from the Department of Aging;</section><section prefix="(6)">One from the Health Department;</section><section prefix="(7)">One from the county community colleges, subject to the following conditions:<section prefix="(i)">Representation shall be determined on a rotating basis by alphabetical order by community college name; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Each such member shall serve for 1 year;</section></section><section prefix="(8)">One from the Department of Juvenile Services;</section><section prefix="(9)">One from the county public libraries; and</section><section prefix="(10)">One from the Department of Planning.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">A county employee Council member who does not maintain his employment in the county shall be replaced.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">In addition to the county employee members, there shall be eight county citizens selected as members of the Council as follows and with the following duties:<section prefix="(1)">The county citizen members shall be selected by the County Executive. One member shall be selected from each legislative district of Baltimore County with the approval of the State Senator from that district. Each legislative district representative shall reside in that district;</section><section prefix="(2)">The initial members selected to represent legislative districts 5, 7, 9, and 11 shall each serve for a 2-year term beginning June 1, 1979, and ending May 31, 1981. Thereafter all members shall be selected to serve 2-year terms. The initial members selected to represent legislative districts 8, 10, 12, and 13 shall each serve for a 1-year term beginning June 1, 1979, and ending May 31, 1980, and thereafter all members shall be selected for 2-year terms;</section><section prefix="(3)">A citizen member shall be entitled to attend and vote at a Council session where an issue before the Council concerns the school or schools in the citizen member's respective district; and</section><section prefix="(4)">When the Council meets to consider countywide issues, all selected citizen members shall be entitled to attend such sessions and vote.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(h)">The Council shall:<section prefix="(1)">Meet as needed to compile the number of spaces in the public schools of the county that are not filled and to evaluate the feasibility of the utilization of the spaces by the community and county departments; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Report its findings and recommendations to the county board of education and the County Executive at least twice during the school year.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(i)">The County Executive may, by executive order, appoint up to two additional members to the Council from agencies of the county government.</section>
  </text>
</law>
