<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="ged" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="6-501" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ged-6-501</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Confidential employee" includes an individual whose employment responsibilities require knowledge of the public school employer's posture in the collective negotiation process, as determined by the public school employer in negotiations with an employee organization that requests negotiation on this issue.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Employee organization" means an organization that:<section prefix="(1)">Includes noncertificated employees of a public school employer; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Has as one of its main purposes the representation of the employees in their relations with that public school employer.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">"Management personnel" includes an individual who is engaged mainly in executive and managerial functions, as determined by the public school employer in negotiation with an employee organization that requests negotiation on this issue.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"Noncertificated employee", in Montgomery County, means only a full-time employee.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Public school employee" means a noncertificated individual who is employed for at least 9 months a year on a full-time basis by a public school employer.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Public school employee" includes a noncertificated employee in Baltimore City notwithstanding that the noncertificated employee does not work for at least 9 months a year on a full-time basis.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Public school employee" does not include:<section prefix="(i)">Management personnel;</section><section prefix="(ii)">A confidential employee; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">Any individual designated by the public school employer to act in a negotiating capacity as provided in &#xA7; 6-510(b) of this subtitle.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Public school employer" means the county board in each county.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Public school employer" includes the Baltimore City Board of School Commissioners.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(h)">"Supervisory employee" includes any individual who responsibly directs the work of other employees, as determined by the public school employer in negotiation with an employee organization that requests negotiation on this issue.</section>
  </text>
</law>
