<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ged" order_by="ged" level="1">Economic Development</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ged-13-703</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this section the following words have the meanings indicated....</catch_line>
  <order_by>703</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Recyclable materials" means materials that:<section prefix="(i)">If not recycled, would become solid waste for disposal in a refuse disposal system; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">May be collected, separated, or processed and returned to the marketplace in the form of raw materials or products.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Recyclable materials" includes paper, glass, metals, plastics, and cardboard.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Recyclable materials that are separated for collection at the University of Maryland, College Park become the property of the University of Maryland, College Park when placed for collection in or near designated bins or locations.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A person may not remove or cause the removal of any recyclable materials that are owned by the University of Maryland, College Park unless authorized by:<section prefix="(1)">The University of Maryland, College Park; or</section><section prefix="(2)">The owner or operator of a company that is authorized by the University of Maryland, College Park to remove recyclable materials.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">This section may not be construed to prohibit a law enforcement officer from searching and seizing any recyclable materials owned by the University of Maryland, College Park.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">A person who violates any provision of this section is guilty of a misdemeanor and on conviction is subject to a fine not to exceed $500 for each violation.</section>
  </text>
</law>
