<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ged" order_by="" level="1">Economic Development</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ged-2-305</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>305</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Agency" means a local education agency serving a population of students at least 80% of which are minority students.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Minority student" has the meaning stated in regulations adopted by the State Superintendent.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">There is a Lacrosse Opportunities Program in the Department.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The purpose of the Lacrosse Opportunities Program is to increase opportunities for minority students to participate in lacrosse in their communities.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The State Superintendent shall develop and administer the Lacrosse Opportunities Program.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">An agency may submit an application to the Department to receive a grant for a program that is in furtherance of the purpose of the Lacrosse Opportunities Program.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">An application shall include:<section prefix="(i)">A description of the scope and purpose of the proposed program;</section><section prefix="(ii)">A business plan that includes the estimated total cost of the proposed program; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Any other information required by the Department.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">In awarding a grant under the Lacrosse Opportunities Program, the Department shall:<section prefix="(1)">Require the grantee to provide matching funds from any combination of federal, county, municipal, or private sources; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Ensure that the grant does not exceed 50% of the total annual cost of the grantee's program.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The State Superintendent or the State Superintendent's designee shall:<section prefix="(1)">Review grant applications submitted in accordance with subsection (d) of this section; and</section><section prefix="(2)">To the extent funds are available, provide grants to agencies that meet the requirements for a grant under this section.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(g)">For fiscal year 2014 and each fiscal year thereafter, the Governor shall include in the annual budget submission at least $40,000 for the Lacrosse Opportunities Program.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">The State Superintendent shall adopt regulations to implement this section.</section>
  </text>
</law>
