<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="ged" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="7-105" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ged-7-105</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">This section is enacted so that the love of freedom and democracy, shown in the devotion of all true and patriotic Americans to their flag and country, shall be instilled in the hearts and minds of the youth of America.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Each county board shall:<section prefix="(1)">Require the display of an American flag on the site of each public school building in its county while the school is in session;</section><section prefix="(2)">Buy all necessary flags, staffs, and appliances for the flags; and</section><section prefix="(3)">Adopt rules and regulations for the proper custody, care, and display of the flag.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Each county board shall:<section prefix="(1)">Provide each public school classroom with an American flag;</section><section prefix="(2)">Prepare a program for each public school classroom for the beginning of each school day that provides for the salute to the flag and other patriotic exercises that are approved by the United States government; and</section><section prefix="(3)">Require all students and teachers in charge to stand and face the flag and while standing give an approved salute and recite in unison the pledge of allegiance as follows: "I pledge allegiance to the flag of the United States of America and to the Republic for which it stands, one nation under God, indivisible, with liberty and justice for all."</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Any student or teacher who wishes to be excused from the requirements of subsection (c)(3) of this section shall be excused.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">Each county board may provide for any other patriotic exercises it considers appropriate under the regulations and instruction that best meet the requirements of the different grades in the schools.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">Any individual who commits an act of disrespect, either by word or action, is in violation of the intent of this section.</section>
  </text>
</law>
