<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="ged" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="3-6A-05" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ged-3-6A-05</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">There is a School Shared Space Council in Harford County.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The School Shared Space Council consists of eleven employees of the county appointed by the County Executive for a term coterminous with that of the County Executive as follows:<section prefix="(i)">Two from the staff of the county board of education;</section><section prefix="(ii)">One from the administrative staff of the County Executive;</section><section prefix="(iii)">One from the Department of Public Works;</section><section prefix="(iv)">One from the Department of Recreation and Parks;</section><section prefix="(v)">One from the Committee on Aging;</section><section prefix="(vi)">One from the Health Department;</section><section prefix="(vii)">One from Harford County Community College;</section><section prefix="(viii)">One from the Department of Juvenile Services;</section><section prefix="(ix)">One from the county public libraries; and</section><section prefix="(x)">One from the Department of Planning.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">In addition to the county employee members, the County Executive shall appoint, upon the recommendation of the County Council, seven county citizen members to the Council as follows:<section prefix="(i)">One from each councilmanic district of the county; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">One from the county at large.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A county employee member of the Council who does not maintain his employment in the county shall be replaced on the Council.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A county citizen member who does not maintain his residence in the county shall be replaced on the Council.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Each citizen member may attend and vote at a Council session.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Council shall:<section prefix="(1)">Meet not less than three times a year during each year to compile the number of spaces in the public schools of the county that are not filled and to evaluate the feasibility of the utilization of the spaces by the community and county departments; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Report its findings and recommendations to the county board of education and the County Executive at least once during the school year.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The County Executive, by executive order, may appoint up to two additional members to the Council from agencies of the county government.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Council shall elect a president from among its members.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A quorum is 2/3 of the members appointed.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
