<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="ged" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="7-9A-05" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ged-7-9A-05</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The MDK12 Digital Library is a purchasing consortium for the acquisition of digital content.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The MDK12 Digital Library shall be administered by a steering committee that consists of:</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">Each representative from each of the member local school systems shall be a school library administrator or the designee of a school library administrator.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">The steering committee shall:</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Subject to paragraph (4) of this subsection, members of the MDK12 Digital Library may include the public school systems of the State and private nonprofit schools that are approved by the Department.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The MDK12 Digital Library members shall agree to:<section prefix="(i)">Report digital content usage data to the steering committee;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Solely utilize the pricing agreements established by the steering committee;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Not place independent orders with identified vendors for prices less than those negotiated by the steering committee; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">Notify the steering committee and the Department if a vendor verbally or by writing offers a better price than that negotiated by the steering committee.	</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The State Board and the State Superintendent shall encourage local school systems and member private nonprofit schools to:<section prefix="(1)">Provide professional development for school librarians and other educators to effectively use digital content in teaching and learning;</section><section prefix="(2)">Support student use of digital content through school libraries in collaboration with classroom and resource teachers;</section><section prefix="(3)">Promote the availability of digital content to students, educators, and parents; and</section><section prefix="(4)">Instruct students and educators how to access digital content.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The MDK12 Digital Library may develop programs to support all residents of the State in collaboration with the State Library Resource Center under &#xA7; 23-201 of this article and the Maryland Digital Library under &#xA7; 11-801 of this article.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Department shall employ one half-time position to coordinate the MDK12 Digital Library.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">On or before October 1 of each year, the MDK12 Digital Library Steering Committee shall submit a report regarding the financial status and operations of the MDK12 Digital Library during the prior fiscal year to the Department.</section>
  </text>
</law>
