<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="ged" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="18-1102" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ged-18-1102</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>** IN EFFECT UNTIL JULY 1, 2015 PER CHAPTER 397 OF 2011**<section prefix="(a)">The Office shall annually select the 350 secondary school students who have the greatest potential for academic success in higher education as determined by criteria established by the Office and offer a scholarship to each of these students to be used at any Maryland postsecondary institution of the student's choice, if the student meets the following qualifications:<section prefix="(1)">Qualifies academically as follows:<section prefix="(i)">Has a secondary school transcript indicating an overall academic grade point average of at least 3.7 on a 4.0 scale or its equivalent grade point average;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Is a finalist of the National Merit Scholarship Program or the Achievement Scholarship Program administered by the National Merit Scholarship Corporation; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">Has a superior creative talent or skill in art, music, dance, or the theater, as determined by an audition or portfolio review process established by the Office;</section></section><section prefix="(2)">Has matriculated at a postsecondary educational institution in the State; and</section><section prefix="(3)">Qualifies as a Maryland resident.</section></section><section prefix="(b)"><section prefix="(1)">At least 150 of the 350 awards shall be granted to superior academic achievers whose secondary school transcripts indicate after the first semester of the junior year an overall academic grade point average of at least 3.7 on a 4.0 scale, or its equivalent grade point average.</section><section prefix="(2)">At least 2 recipients who meet the qualifications specified under this section shall be selected from each county of the State.</section></section><section prefix="(c)"><section prefix="(1)"><section prefix="(i)">Subject to subparagraph (ii) of this paragraph, the scholarship award shall be in the amount of $3,000 for use in the next ensuing academic year.</section><section prefix="(ii)">A recipient's award may not exceed the cost of attendance at the institution, including:</section></section><section prefix="(2)">If it is accepted by the eligible student, each award shall be renewable, on an annual basis, for a maximum of 3 years subsequent to the original award if the recipient:<section prefix="(i)">Remains a resident of the State;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Attends an accredited postsecondary institution in the State;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Is enrolled as a full-time undergraduate student; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">Maintains a 3.0 grade average on an academic year basis or, failing to do so, provides evidence, satisfactory to the Secretary, of extenuating circumstances of extreme personal hardship.</section></section></section></text>
</law>
