<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ged" order_by="" level="1">Economic Development</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ged-15-106.1</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>106.1</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">"Foster care recipient" means an individual who:<section prefix="1.">Was placed in an out-of-home placement by the Maryland Department of Human Resources; and</section><section prefix="2."/></section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">"Foster care recipient" includes a younger sibling of an individual described in subparagraph (i) of this paragraph if the younger sibling is concurrently adopted out of an out-of-home placement by the same adoptive family.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Out-of-home placement" has the meaning stated in &#xA7; 5-501 of the Family Law Article.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">
        <section prefix="(i)">"Tuition" means the charges imposed by a public institution of higher education for enrollment at the institution.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">"Tuition" includes charges for registration and all fees required as a condition of enrollment.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, a foster care recipient is exempt from paying tuition at a public institution of higher education if:<section prefix="(i)">The foster care recipient is enrolled at the institution on or before the date that the foster care recipient reaches the age of 25 years;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The foster care recipient is enrolled as a candidate for an associate's degree or a bachelor's degree; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">The foster care recipient has filed for federal and State financial aid by March 1 each year.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If a foster care recipient receives a scholarship or grant for postsecondary study and is enrolled before the recipient's 25th birthday as a candidate for an associate's degree or bachelor's degree at a public institution of higher education, the foster care recipient may not be required to pay the difference between the amount of the scholarship or grant and the amount of the tuition.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A foster care recipient who is exempt from tuition under this section continues to be exempt until the earlier of:<section prefix="(i)">5 years after first enrolling as a candidate for an associate's degree or a bachelor's degree at a public institution of higher education in the State; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">The date that the foster care recipient is awarded a bachelor's degree.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
