<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ged" order_by="" level="1">Economic Development</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ged-18-1905</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>1905</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Board, from among the members of the Board, shall elect a chairman and may elect additional officers that the Board considers necessary.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Board shall determine the times and places of meetings.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A member of the Board:<section prefix="(1)">May not receive compensation;</section><section prefix="(2)">Is entitled to reimbursement for expenses under the Standard State Travel Regulations; and</section><section prefix="(3)">Shall file a public disclosure of financial interests as required under the Maryland Public Ethics Law.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Board:<section prefix="(i)">Shall appoint a Program executive director who is in the executive service of the State Personnel Management System; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">May employ additional staff in accordance with the budget.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Except for employees described in subparagraph (ii) or (iii) of this paragraph, the employees shall be skilled service employees subject to the provisions of the State Personnel and Pensions Article that govern skilled service employees.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">An employee is in the professional service and subject to the provisions of the State Personnel and Pensions Article that govern professional service employees if the position:<section prefix="1.">Requires knowledge of an advanced type in a field of science or learning customarily acquired by a course of specialized intellectual instruction and study; and</section><section prefix="2.">Normally requires a professional license, an advanced degree, or both.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">An employee is in the management service and subject to the provisions of the State Personnel and Pensions Article that govern management service employees if the position:<section prefix="1.">Primarily involves direct responsibility for the oversight and management of personnel and financial resources;</section><section prefix="2.">Requires the exercise of discretion and independent judgment; and</section><section prefix="3.">Is not in the executive service.</section></section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Board may retain the services of consultants, administrators, and other personnel, as necessary, to administer the Trust, the Plan, or the Broker-Dealer Plan.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The budget for the Program, the Board, and its staff is subject to review by the General Assembly for information purposes only.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The Board may adopt any regulations that the Board considers necessary to carry out the provisions of this subtitle or Subtitle 19A or Subtitle 19B of this title.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">In addition, the Board may:<section prefix="(1)">Adopt an official seal;</section><section prefix="(2)">Sue and be sued;</section><section prefix="(3)">Execute contracts and other necessary instruments;</section><section prefix="(4)">Hold, buy, and sell instruments, obligations, securities, and other investments consistent with its comprehensive investment plan;</section><section prefix="(5)">Enter into agreements with eligible institutions of higher education and other public or private entities for the promotion, administration, or marketing of the Program, the Trust, the Plan, or the Broker-Dealer Plan;</section><section prefix="(6)">Invest funds not required for immediate disbursement;</section><section prefix="(7)">Solicit and accept gifts, grants, loans, or other aid from any source or participate in any government program for purposes consistent with this subtitle and Subtitles 19A and 19B of this title;</section><section prefix="(8)">Subject to the review of the General Assembly, impose and collect reasonable administrative fees for any transactions under the Trust, the Plan, or the Broker-Dealer Plan or involving prepaid contracts or transactions affecting the Program, the Trust, the Plan, or the Broker-Dealer Plan;</section><section prefix="(9)">Procure insurance against any loss of assets of the Program, the Trust, the Plan, or the Broker-Dealer Plan;</section><section prefix="(10)">Endorse insurance coverage written exclusively for the purpose of protecting:<section prefix="(i)">A prepaid contract under the Trust and the account holder and the qualified beneficiary of the contract; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">An investment account under the Plan, or the Broker-Dealer Plan, and the account holder and qualified designated beneficiary of the investment account;</section></section><section prefix="(11)">Designate terms under which money may be withdrawn from the Program, the Trust, the Plan, or the Broker-Dealer Plan;</section><section prefix="(12)">Establish additional procedural and substantive requirements for participation in and the administration or marketing of the Program, the Trust, the Plan, or the Broker-Dealer Plan;</section><section prefix="(13)">Appear on the Board's own behalf before other boards, commissions, or other governmental agencies; and</section><section prefix="(14)">Take any other action that the Board considers appropriate to implement and administer the Program, the Trust, the Plan, or the Broker-Dealer Plan.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
