<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ged" order_by="ged" level="1">Economic Development</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ged-5-109</section_number>
  <catch_line>Each county board shall provide for an annual audit of its financial transactions and accounts....</catch_line>
  <order_by>109</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Each county board shall provide for an annual audit of its financial transactions and accounts.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">At the request of the Department, a county board shall conduct an audit under &#xA7; 5-203 of this title.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The audit shall be made by a certified public accountant or a partnership of certified public accountants who are:<section prefix="(i)">Licensed by the State Board of Public Accountancy; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Approved by the State Superintendent.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The audit shall be made in accordance with the standards and regulations adopted by the State Board.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The results of the audit, including the letter of recommendation submitted by the auditor, are a matter of public record.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The results shall be reported within 3 months after the close of the fiscal year for the county board on the form and in the manner required by the State Board to:<section prefix="(i)">The State Superintendent;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The county fiscal authority;</section><section prefix="(iii)">The Joint Audit Committee of the General Assembly;</section><section prefix="(iv)">The Senate Budget and Taxation Committee;</section><section prefix="(v)">The Senate Education, Health, and Environmental Affairs Committee;</section><section prefix="(vi)">The House Appropriations Committee; and</section><section prefix="(vii)">The House Committee on Ways and Means.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">In addition to the audit required by this section, the county commissioners or county council may conduct an audit using auditors employed by the county.</section>
  </text>
</law>
