<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="ged" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="7-421" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ged-7-421</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Health practitioner" means a physician or other individual authorized by law to prescribe prescription drugs or devices.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Medication" means an asthma inhaler or other emergency drug that is dispensed for a student only on the prescription of a health practitioner and pertains to the student's asthma or other airway-constricting disease.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">"Self-administer" means the application or consumption of medication in a manner directed by the health practitioner without additional assistance or direction.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Subject to the provisions of this subsection, each public school system shall adopt a written policy authorizing a student to possess and self-administer medication while:<section prefix="(i)">In school;</section><section prefix="(ii)">At school-sponsored activities; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">On a school bus or other school property.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">A student who self-administers medication must have a prior written order from the student's health care provider and, if the student is a minor, the prior written approval of the student's parent or guardian.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The health care provider's order must be maintained in the student's educational record at the school.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A student's parent or guardian must obtain written verification from the student's health care provider confirming that the student has the knowledge and skills to safely possess and self-administer the medication.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The written statements required under this subsection shall be provided to the school at least annually.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">The school nurse shall assess the student's ability to demonstrate the skill level necessary to ensure proper and effective use of the medication in school.</section>
      <section prefix="(6)">A student may be subject to disciplinary action if the student does not use the medication in a safe and proper manner.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Department shall provide each public school system with written State guidelines to implement this section.</section>
  </text>
</law>
