<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="ged" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="14-104.1" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ged-14-104.1</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, "high impact economic development activity" means an initiative, transaction, or other undertaking by Morgan State University to create or facilitate:<section prefix="(1)">20 or more new jobs in the State;</section><section prefix="(2)">The award or completion of at least $1,000,000 in externally funded research or other projects;</section><section prefix="(3)">The establishment or relocation of one or more new companies to be registered or incorporated in the State and doing business in the State;</section><section prefix="(4)">The production of at least $1,000,000 of annual gross revenue;</section><section prefix="(5)">The licensing and potential commercialization of a promising new technology or other product; or</section><section prefix="(6)">An academic program to meet workforce demand in a documented labor shortage field.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">To promote the economic interests of the State as mandated in &#xA7;&#xA7; 10-205(a) and 15-107 of this article, the Morgan State University shall utilize its powers as a public corporation established in &#xA7; 14-104 of this subtitle to undertake high impact economic development activities that support:<section prefix="(1)">Job creation and workforce development;</section><section prefix="(2)">Technology transfer, commercialization, and entrepreneurship; and</section><section prefix="(3)">Increased sponsored research funding and other revenues.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">In order for an activity to qualify as a high impact economic development activity:<section prefix="(1)">The President or the President's designee, shall certify that the activity meets the criteria defined in subsection (a) of this section; and</section><section prefix="(2)">The President or the President's designee, shall notify the Board of Regents and the Board of Public Works of any certified activity for review.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, for any high impact economic activity within the scope of &#xA7; 5-310 or &#xA7; 10-305 of the State Finance and Procurement Article, the Board of Regents shall be fully responsible for administering the review and comment process prescribed in those sections.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">In administering the review and comment process prescribed in &#xA7;&#xA7; 5-310 and 10-305 of the State Finance and Procurement Article, the Board of Regents shall include in the process the appropriate legislative committees and units of State government, which may include:<section prefix="(i)">Committees of the General Assembly;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The Board of Public Works;</section><section prefix="(iii)">The Maryland Historic Trust;</section><section prefix="(iv)">The Department of Planning;</section><section prefix="(v)">The Department of the Environment; and</section><section prefix="(vi)">The Department of Natural Resources.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Board of Regents shall adopt policies and procedures to ensure that the notice and opportunity for review are conducted in a manner that provides a reasonable period to complete while not impairing the institution's capacity for the expeditious and successful pursuit of a high impact economic development activity.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">On or before October 1 of each year, the Board of Regents shall report to the Board of Public Works and, in accordance with &#xA7; 2-1246 of the State Government Article, the Senate Finance Committee, the House Economic Matters Committee, the Senate Budget and Taxation Committee, and the House Appropriations Committee on the high impact economic development activities undertaken under this section during the preceding fiscal year.</section>
  </text>
</law>
