<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="ged" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="16-310" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ged-16-310</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Subject to paragraphs (2), (3), (4), (5), and (6) of this subsection and subsection (f) of this section, any student who attends a community college in this State and is not a resident of this State shall pay, in addition to the student tuition and fees payable by a county resident, an out-of-state fee, at least equal to:<section prefix="(i)">60% of the county share per full-time equivalent student as determined under &#xA7; 16-305 of this subtitle; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">The marginal cost component of the State share per full-time equivalent student as determined under &#xA7; 16-305(c)(5) of this subtitle.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">A resident of the state of West Virginia who attends Garrett College under a negotiated reciprocity agreement between the states of Maryland and West Virginia is an in-county resident for tuition purposes.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">For each full-time equivalent student participating in the reciprocity agreement, the State shall pay to Garrett College an amount equal to the net State support per full-time equivalent student as provided in &#xA7; 16-305 of this subtitle. For any fiscal year, if State appropriations for reimbursement of any reciprocity agreements under this paragraph do not provide sufficient funds to fully reimburse the college, the Governor shall include in the budget bill for the next fiscal year a deficiency appropriation to provide the additional funds to fully reimburse the college.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">The Commission may make payments to effectuate the provisions of this paragraph from funds specifically appropriated for this purpose as provided in the State budget or any supplemental budget request.</section>
        <section prefix="(iv)">The payments authorized by this paragraph are in addition to the State operating fund to community colleges authorized in &#xA7; 16-305(c) of this subtitle.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Any student attending a community college in this State who is not a resident of this State and is enrolled in an education program leading to licensure in nursing shall be included as an in-county resident for tuition purposes and shall be included as an in-State resident for computation of the State aid to community colleges in accordance with &#xA7; 16-305 of this subtitle.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The student shall furnish a surety bond or promissory note to the State with security satisfactory to the Maryland Higher Education Commission, that on completion of the nursing education program, the student will work for at least 2 years in a hospital or related institution as defined in &#xA7; 19-301 of the Health - General Article in this State.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">The Secretary of Health and Mental Hygiene may determine if there is a shortage of nurses.</section>
        <section prefix="(iv)">Subject to subparagraphs (v) and (vi) of this paragraph, if the Secretary determines that there is no shortage of nurses, the Nonresident Student Tuition Reduction and State Aid Program established under this paragraph may not be applied to any courses required for the nursing program.</section>
        <section prefix="(v)">Subparagraph (iv) of this paragraph applies only to students who enroll in a nursing education program subsequent to the determination made under subparagraph (iv) of this paragraph.</section>
        <section prefix="(vi)">Subparagraph (v) of this paragraph may not affect any student who is participating in the Nonresident Tuition Reduction and State Aid Program prior to the determination under subparagraph (iii) of this paragraph.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(4)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Each board of community college trustees may waive the out-of-state fee as determined in paragraph (1) of this subsection for a student who is employed by a business located in the county that supports the community college.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">Any student attending a community college in this State who receives a tuition waiver as provided by this paragraph shall not be included as an in-State resident for computation of State aid to community colleges in accordance with &#xA7; 16-305 of this subtitle.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(5)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Each board of community college trustees shall waive the out-of-state fee as determined in paragraph (1) of this subsection for a student who resides in this State but does not meet the in-State residency requirement for tuition purposes and is a public school teacher employed by a county board if:</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">A public school teacher is responsible for the difference between in-State and out-of-state tuition if:</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">Any public school teacher attending a community college in this State who satisfies the requirements established in this paragraph shall be included as an in-State resident for computation of the State aid to community colleges in accordance with &#xA7; 16-305 of this subtitle.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(6)">
        <section prefix="(i)">In this paragraph, "BRAC" means the Base Realignment and Closure process as announced by the United States Department of Defense.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">Each board of community college trustees may waive the out-of-state fee as determined in paragraph (1) of this subsection for a student who resides in the State but does not meet the in-State residency requirement for tuition purposes and has moved to the State as an employee or a family member of an employee as part of BRAC.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">Any BRAC employee or family member of a BRAC employee attending a community college in the State who satisfies the requirements established in this paragraph shall be included as an in-State resident for computation of the State aid to community colleges in accordance with &#xA7; 16-305 of this subtitle.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Subject to the provisions of paragraphs (2), (3), and (4) of this subsection and subsection (g) of this section, any student who attends a community college not supported by the county in which the student resides shall pay, in addition to the student tuition and fees payable by a resident of a county that supports the community college, an out-of-county or out-of-region fee at least equal to 60% of the county share per full-time equivalent student as determined under &#xA7; 16-305 of this subtitle.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Any student who resides in an incorporated municipality whose corporate limits extend into 2 counties in the State is considered an in-county resident for tuition purposes at a community college campus located within that municipality that is supported by either county.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">If a student is considered an in-county resident under this paragraph and the student does not reside in the county that supports the community college, the county in which the student resides shall pay the difference between the out-of-county tuition and the in-county tuition.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Each board of community college trustees may waive the out-of-county or out-of-region fee, as determined in paragraph (1) of this subsection, for a student who is employed by a business located in the county that supports the community college.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">
        <section prefix="(i)">In this paragraph, "BRAC" means the Base Realignment and Closure process as announced by the United States Department of Defense.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">Each board of community college trustees may waive the out-of-county fee or out-of-region fee as determined in paragraph (1) of this subsection for a student who resides in the county but does not meet the in-county residency requirement for tuition purposes and has moved to the State as an employee or a family member of an employee as part of BRAC.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Any county may appropriate money to pay the out-of-county or out-of-region fees for county residents who attend a community college in this State that is not supported by that county.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)"/>
        <section prefix="(ii)">For any fiscal year beginning on or after July 1, 2011, if State appropriations to the Commission for payment of any applicable out-of-county fee under this paragraph do not provide sufficient funds to fully reimburse applicable out-of-county fees, the Commission shall prorate the reimbursement for the out-of-county fees.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Commission may make payments to effectuate the provisions of this section from funds specifically appropriated for this purpose as provided in the State budget or any supplemental budget request.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Notwithstanding subsection (b) of this section, if any student resides in a county where the per capita wealth is below the State average and the county does not support a community college or a branch campus of a community college, except for Baltimore City, the student may enroll at a community college or a branch campus in the State, either of which is located in a county adjacent to the one in which the student resides, and pay only the tuition and fees applicable to a county resident that supports the community college.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">For any student determined to be eligible under paragraph (1) of this subsection, the Commission shall pay:<section prefix="(i)">In fiscal year 1992, 75% of any applicable out-of-county fee provided that the county in which the student resides pays 25 percent of that fee; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">In fiscal year 1993, and each fiscal year thereafter, 50% of any applicable out-of-county fee provided that the county in which the student resides pays 50 percent of that fee.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Commission may make payments to effectuate the provisions of this section from funds specifically appropriated for this purpose in the State budget or any supplemental budget request.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The provisions of this section shall be subject to any reciprocal interstate agreement entered into by the Maryland Higher Education Commission under &#xA7; 11-105(m)(2) of this article.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Notwithstanding subsection (b) of this section, any student who resides in Howard County or in Prince George's County and attends the Laurel College Center, a partnership equally supported by the Howard and Prince George's community colleges, is deemed to be an in-county student and may not be subject to out-of-county fees established in subsection (b) of this section, by Howard Community College or Prince George's Community College for courses taken at the Laurel College Center.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Paragraph (1) of this subsection applies to any student who attends the Laurel College Center on or after August 1, 2001.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
