<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ged" order_by="ged" level="1">Economic Development</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ged-22-306</section_number>
  <catch_line>The Council shall develop, recommend, and approve an educational program for each residential facili...</catch_line>
  <order_by>306</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Council shall develop, recommend, and approve an educational program for each residential facility.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The educational programs shall meet the special needs and circumstances of the children in the residential facility.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Council shall adopt regulations consistent with State law for the conduct and management of the educational programs.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">On or before October 30 of each year, the Council shall report its activities to the Governor and, in accordance with &#xA7; 2-1246 of the State Government Article, to the General Assembly.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The Council shall actively advocate and promote the interests of educational programs and opportunities in programs of the Department of Juvenile Services.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The Council shall seek to ensure that a quality education and equal educational opportunities are available to all children in the custody of the Department.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">On a regular basis, the Council shall review the effectiveness of the program of educational instruction used in the residential facilities to ensure that the unique educational needs of the children under the jurisdiction of the Department of Juvenile Services are being satisfactorily met.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Council shall include in the Council's review students' ability to:<section prefix="(i)">Maintain and improve educational achievement in core subjects;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Acquire course credits that qualify as State requirements for graduation; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Make the transition to a regular program or other educational program operated by a Maryland school system.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">Based on its review, the Council shall recommend and advocate improvements to the educational services for residential facilities.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
