<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ged" order_by="" level="1">Economic Development</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ged-7-404</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>404</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Each county board or county health department shall provide hearing and vision screenings for all students in the public schools.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Each county health department shall provide and fund hearing and vision screenings for all students:<section prefix="(i)">In any private school that has received a certificate of approval under &#xA7; 2-206 of this article; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">In any nonpublic educational facility in this State approved as a special education facility by the Department.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Unless evidence is presented that a student has been tested within the past year, the screenings required under subsection (a) of this section shall be given in the year that a student enters a school system, enters the first grade, and enters the eighth or ninth grade.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Further screening shall be done in accordance with:<section prefix="(i)">The bylaws adopted by the State Board; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">Policies adopted by a county board or a county health department.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The results of the hearing and vision screenings required by this section shall be:<section prefix="(1)">Made a part of the permanent record file of each student;</section><section prefix="(2)">Given to the parents of any student who fails the screenings; and</section><section prefix="(3)">Reported to the county board or the county health department.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">On a form provided by the county board or the county health department, a parent or guardian shall report to the county board or the county health department on the recommended services received by a student who failed the screenings.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The county board or the county health department shall report to the Department of Health and Mental Hygiene the results of the hearing and vision screenings and, to the extent practicable, the number of students receiving the recommended services.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">In cooperation with the Department of Health and Mental Hygiene, the Department of Education shall adopt standards, rules, and regulations to carry out the provisions of this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">A student whose parent or guardian objects in writing to hearing and vision screening on the ground that it conflicts with the tenets and practice of a recognized church or religious denomination of which he is an adherent or member may not be required to take these screenings.</section>
  </text>
</law>
