<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ged" order_by="ged" level="1">Economic Development</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ged-13-401</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated....</catch_line>
  <order_by>401</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Medical System Corporation" means the University of Maryland Medical System Corporation or, at the Medical System Corporation's option, a subsidiary or affiliate of the Medical System Corporation.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Montebello" means the Montebello Center.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">"Montebello assets" means all assets allocated to Montebello as shown on the financial statements of Montebello at the transfer date and as more particularly or additionally identified or supplemented by the Medical System Corporation and approved by the Board of Public Works and transferred to the Medical System Corporation and includes:<section prefix="(1)">All land, buildings, and other real property at the Montebello site owned by the State, with the exception of the Maryland Rehabilitation Center;</section><section prefix="(2)">All accounts receivable for patient care services rendered by Montebello regardless of when the patient care services were rendered; and</section><section prefix="(3)">All personal property at the Montebello site owned by the State except for personal property owned by the Department of Education or the University of Maryland, Baltimore.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Montebello liabilities" means only liabilities arising from agreements or contracts entered into before the transfer date in the ordinary course of business by the Medical System Corporation on behalf of Montebello under the Medical System Corporation's management of Montebello and which are allocated to Montebello as shown on the financial statements of Montebello at the transfer date.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Montebello liabilities" includes liabilities whenever asserted, incurred, or arising in connection with Montebello before the transfer date to the extent they are covered by professional liability or general liability insurance obtained by the Medical System Corporation before the transfer date.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Montebello liabilities" does not include any liabilities whenever asserted, incurred, or arising in connection with Montebello University employees or their employment by the University System of Maryland prior to the transfer date.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">"Montebello site" means the real property owned by the State, a campus located in Baltimore City, on which Montebello and other State-owned facilities are located.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">"Montebello University employees" means those employees of the University System of Maryland who work at Montebello and who are paid by the Medical System Corporation.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">"Transfer date" means any date determined by the Board of Public Works and filed with the Secretary of State and the Department of Legislative Services.</section>
  </text>
</law>
