<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ged" order_by="" level="1">Economic Development</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ged-7-203</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>203</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The State Board, the State Superintendent, each county board, and each public school shall implement a program of education accountability for the operation and management of the public schools.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this subsection, "grade band assessment" means one assessment of a middle school student's knowledge in a core academic subject area during grades 6 through 8.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The education accountability program shall include the following:<section prefix="(i)">The State Board and the State Superintendent shall assist each county board to establish educational goals and objectives that conform with statewide educational objectives for subject areas including reading, writing, mathematics, science, and social studies;</section><section prefix="(ii)">With the assistance of its county board, each public school shall survey current student achievement in reading, language, mathematics, science, social studies, and other areas to assess its needs;</section><section prefix="(iii)"><section prefix="1.">The State Board and the State Superintendent shall implement assessment programs in reading, language, mathematics, science, and social studies that include written responses;</section><section prefix="2.">The assessment program required in this subsection shall:</section><section prefix="3.">Beginning in the 2014-2015 school year, the following assessments shall be implemented and administered annually:</section></section><section prefix="(iv)">Each public school shall establish as the basis for its assessment of its needs, project goals and objectives that are in keeping with the goals and objectives established by its county board and the State Board;</section><section prefix="(v)">With the assistance of its county board, the State Board, and the State Superintendent, each public school shall develop programs to meet its needs on the basis of the priorities it sets;</section><section prefix="(vi)">Evaluation programs shall be developed at the same time to determine if the goals and objectives are being met; and</section><section prefix="(vii)">A reevaluation of programs, goals, and objectives shall be undertaken regularly.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">After the 2014-2015 school year, the State Board shall determine whether the assessments at the middle school and high school levels required under paragraph (2)(iii)3 of this subsection adequately measure the skills and knowledge set forth in the State's adopted curricula for the core content areas of reading, language, mathematics, science, and social studies.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">If the State Board makes a determination under subparagraph (i) of this paragraph that an assessment does not adequately measure the skills and knowledge set forth in the State's adopted curricula for a core content area, the Department shall develop a State-specific assessment in that core content area to be implemented in the 2016-2017 school year.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">National standardized testing may not be the only measure for evaluating educational accountability.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Department shall assist each county board to establish an education accountability program by providing:<section prefix="(1)">Guidelines for development and implementation of the program by the county boards; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Assistance and coordination where it is needed and requested by the county boards.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Department shall survey a statewide, representative sample of public schools and public school teachers annually to measure:<section prefix="(i)">The amount of instructional time spent on social studies and science instruction in elementary schools;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The availability and use of appropriate instructional resources and teaching technology in social studies and science classrooms;</section><section prefix="(iii)">The availability and use of appropriate professional development for social studies and science teachers; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">The number of secondary school social studies and science classes that are taught by teachers who are:<section prefix="1.">Certified in the subject being taught; and</section><section prefix="2.">Not certified in the subject being taught.</section></section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Department shall:<section prefix="(i)">Compile the results of the survey conducted under paragraph (1) of this subsection; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Publish the results on the Department's Web site.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The State Superintendent shall send the Governor and, subject to &#xA7; 2-1246 of the State Government Article, the General Assembly a report each January that includes:<section prefix="(1)">Documentation of the progress of the Department, the county boards, and each public school in this State towards their respective goals and objectives; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Recommendations for legislation that the State Board and the State Superintendent consider necessary to improve the quality of education in this State.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(g)">On the recommendation of the State Superintendent, the State Board shall include in its annual budget request the funds it considers necessary to carry out the provisions of this section.</section>
  </text>
</law>
