<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ged" order_by="" level="1">Economic Development</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ged-14-205</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>205</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">A vice president or program director may remove a classified employee who has completed probation only for cause.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Subject to paragraph (2) of this subsection, the Board of Regents shall prescribe what may constitute cause for removal after probation of classified employees.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The causes for removal shall conform to the causes for removal of skilled service or professional service employees, with the exception of special appointments, that the Secretary of Budget and Management adopts by regulation.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">A classified employee may not be removed for any cause prohibited by &#xA7; 2-302 of the State Personnel and Pensions Article.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A vice president or program director may remove a classified employee for cause only if:<section prefix="(1)">Written charges for removal are submitted to the President:<section prefix="(i)">By the vice president or program director; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">Subject to the approval of the President, by any resident of the State;</section></section><section prefix="(2)">The employee is given a copy of the charges; and</section><section prefix="(3)">The employee is given an opportunity to be heard on appeal.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A classified employee may appeal the charges for removal to the President within the time and in the manner specified in policies adopted by the Board of Regents.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If the classified employee fails to appeal within the time and in the manner required, the removal is final.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If a classified employee appeals the charges for removal, the President shall hold a hearing to determine whether there is cause for removal.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The hearing shall be held within 90 days after the charges for removal are submitted to the President.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The President shall make findings and issue a proposed written decision for approval by the Secretary of Budget and Management on a charge for removal within 45 days after the later of:<section prefix="(i)">The conclusion of the hearing; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">The day when all briefs or memoranda have been submitted.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Secretary of Budget and Management shall provide a copy of the findings and decision to each party.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The decision of the Secretary of Budget and Management is final.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">The University immediately shall enforce a final decision issued under this section.</section>
  </text>
</law>
