<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ged" order_by="" level="1">Economic Development</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ged-6-704</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>704</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In accordance with Title 10, Subtitle 1 of the State Government Article, both the State Board and the Board shall develop for consideration rules and regulations for:<section prefix="(i)">Except as provided in item (iii) of this paragraph, the certification of teachers and other professional personnel in accordance with this article;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Requirements for preparation of teachers and other education personnel; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">The certification of social workers employed by a local school employer as professional personnel.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Rules and regulations developed by the State Board shall be reviewed by the Board.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Rules and regulations developed by the Board shall be reviewed by the State Board.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">Rules and regulations that are initiated by either the State Board or the Board and submitted for review to each other shall be acted upon within 60 days of their receipt by the other party.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">Recommendations on rules and regulations that are initiated by the Board shall be implemented unless disapproved by three-fourths of the members of the State Board.</section>
      <section prefix="(6)">Recommendations on rules and regulations that are initiated by the State Board shall be implemented unless disapproved by the Board.</section>
      <section prefix="(7)">If the rules or regulations are disapproved under paragraph (6) of this subsection, the rules or regulations shall be implemented if they are approved by three-fourths of the members of the State Board.</section>
      <section prefix="(8)">An individual who is otherwise qualified may not be denied the right to receive credentials from the Board, to receive training to become a teacher, or to practice teaching in any school because that individual is totally or partially blind.</section>
      <section prefix="(9)">A county board may not refuse to contract with or engage a teacher because of blindness if the blind teacher is capable of performing the duties of the position for which he has applied.</section>
      <section prefix="(10)">The right of a school psychologist, who is certified by the Board to practice school psychology consistent with the provisions of that certification, may not be limited by Title 18 of the Health Occupations Article with respect to the practice of school psychology in an educational institution.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Board may establish a fee, not to exceed $10, for issuance or renewal of a teacher certificate.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Board may not require a fee:<section prefix="(i)">For the addition of any new area of certification to a currently valid certificate; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">Except for the fee authorized under this subsection, for the evaluation of credentials for the certification of teachers.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
