<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ged" order_by="" level="1">Economic Development</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ged-7-309</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>309</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section, "residential child care program" means a program that:<section prefix="(i)">Provides care for children 24 hours a day within a structured set of services and activities designed to achieve objectives related to the needs of the children served; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Is licensed by the Department of Health and Mental Hygiene, the Department of Human Resources, or the Department of Juvenile Services.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A "residential child care program" includes:<section prefix="(i)">Group homes;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Alternative living units; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Emergency shelter care.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Each licensed operator of a residential child care program who has legal custody or care and control of a child who is at least 5 years old and under the age of 16 years and receives State funding as provided in &#xA7; 5-526 of the Family Law Article:<section prefix="(1)">Shall enroll the child in the local school system where the residential child care program is located unless the residential child care program operates an approved educational program in accordance with the licensing regulations that govern the residential child care program;</section><section prefix="(2)">Shall expeditiously initiate and monitor the transfer of the academic records of a child in the operator's care from the transferring school to insure that the academic records are transferred to the school that the child will be attending while living in the operator's care;</section><section prefix="(3)"><section prefix="(i)">May request a meeting with the child's teachers; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Shall meet the child's teachers at the time of enrollment and at any other time the school or a teacher requests; and</section></section><section prefix="(4)">Shall sign the child's report card, insure that the report card is returned to school, and include a copy of the report card in the child's case record.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
