<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="ged" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="4-318" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ged-4-318</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, "Baltimore City school police officer" means any person who, when acting in an official capacity, is authorized by law to make arrests and who is a member of the Baltimore City School Police Force.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">There is a Baltimore City School Police Force.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The members of the Baltimore City School Police Force shall be employees of and be appointed by the Baltimore City Board of School Commissioners.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in paragraph (3) of this subsection, a Baltimore City school police officer has all the powers of a law enforcement officer in the State.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">A Baltimore City school police officer may act in an official capacity only on the premises of schools and any other property used for educational purposes owned, leased, or operated by, or under the control of the Baltimore City Board of School Commissioners.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">A Baltimore City school police officer may not act in an official capacity on any other property unless:</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, a Baltimore City school police officer whose permanent or temporary assignment is at a school or on school property may carry a firearm on the premises of the school to which the officer is assigned before or after regular school hours on school days and on days other than school days.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The Baltimore City Board of School Commissioners shall establish policies to implement the provisions of subparagraph (i) of this paragraph.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In consultation with the Maryland Police Training Commission, the Civil Service Commission of Baltimore City shall adopt:<section prefix="(i)">Requirements for education, training, human and public relations skills, and moral character that an applicant must meet to qualify for employment as a Baltimore City school police officer; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Standards for the performance of duties.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Any requirements adopted by the Civil Service Commission on or after July 1, 1991 may not affect the status of any individual who is a qualified Baltimore City school police officer on that date.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The Baltimore City Board of School Commissioners shall adopt regulations governing the:<section prefix="(1)">Operation of the Baltimore City School Police Force; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Conduct of each Baltimore City school police officer.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(g)">This section does not:<section prefix="(1)">Make a Baltimore City school police officer a member of the Baltimore City Police Department; or</section><section prefix="(2)">Affect the salary, benefits, or retirement program of an employee of Baltimore City or the Baltimore City Board of School Commissioners.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
