<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ged" order_by="ged" level="1">Economic Development</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ged-5-217</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this section the following words have the meanings indicated....</catch_line>
  <order_by>217</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Accreditation" means the determination that a program meets quality standards defined by the accrediting agency beyond State child care regulations.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Accrediting agency" means a State agency or national organization that has developed a recognized accrediting process.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">"Credentialing" means the process through which an individual is awarded a professional certificate based on education and experience.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">"Early Child Care and Education Enhancement Grant" means a grant that is distributed under subsection (e) of this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(6)">"Full day" means a period of time during the day that:<section prefix="(i)">Meets the needs of families; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Is not less than 7 hours or more than 12 hours per day.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(7)">"Judy Center" means a site where comprehensive early child care and education services are provided to young children and their families for the purpose of promoting school readiness through collaboration with participating agencies and programs.</section>
      <section prefix="(8)">"Judy Center Grant" means a grant that is distributed under subsection (d) of this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(9)">"Local management board" means a local management board as defined under &#xA7; 8-101(j)(l) of the Human Services Article.</section>
      <section prefix="(10)">"Participating agencies and programs" includes:<section prefix="(i)">Public prekindergarten and kindergarten programs;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Head Start programs;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Family literacy programs and services;</section><section prefix="(iv)">Local infants and toddlers programs;</section><section prefix="(v)">Child care centers and family child care homes;</section><section prefix="(vi)">Family support centers;</section><section prefix="(vii)">Healthy family sites;</section><section prefix="(viii)">Parent involvement programs;</section><section prefix="(ix)">Early childhood programs affiliated with institutions of higher education; and</section><section prefix="(x)">Other home visiting, community health, family support services, and child care resource and referral agencies.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(11)">"Program" means the Judith P. Hoyer Early Child Care and Education Enhancement Program established under this section.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">There is a Judith P. Hoyer Early Child Care and Education Enhancement Program in the Department.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The purpose of the Program is to promote school readiness through the development and expansion of collaborative approaches to the delivery of high quality, comprehensive, full-day early child care and education programs and family support services.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Program shall be funded as provided in the State budget.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Funds that are allocated to the Program in the State budget may be used:<section prefix="(i)">To cover the costs incurred by the Department in implementing and administering the Program;</section><section prefix="(ii)">For Judy Center Grants, as provided under subsection (d) of this section;</section><section prefix="(iii)">For Early Child Care and Education Enhancement Grants, as provided under subsection (e) of this section; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">To fund the statewide implementation of the Department's Early Childhood Assessment System, as provided under subsection (f) of this section.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Department may distribute a Judy Center Grant to a county board if the county board submits an application to the Department that includes:<section prefix="(1)">A memorandum of understanding between the county board, the participating agencies and programs, and, in the discretion of the county board, the local management board that includes:<section prefix="(i)">The terms of the collaboration to be undertaken by the county board, the participating agencies and programs, and, if applicable, the local management board, including the roles and responsibilities of each of these entities; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">A plan for establishing ongoing communication between private service providers and public school early education programs; and</section></section><section prefix="(2)">Documentation that shows that:<section prefix="(i)">The Department's Early Childhood Assessment System will be implemented at the Center;</section><section prefix="(ii)">All participating agencies and programs that provide early child care and education services through the Center have voluntarily obtained accreditation or, by the date of the Grant application, have voluntarily initiated and are actively pursuing the process of obtaining accreditation; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">The Center will provide comprehensive, full-day early child care and education services and family support services.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Department may distribute an Early Child Care and Education Enhancement Grant to a county board to be used to purchase early child care and education services and family support services from providers that have voluntarily obtained accreditation or have voluntarily initiated and are actively pursuing accreditation.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Department may distribute an Early Child Care and Education Enhancement Grant to a private provider of early child care and education services to be used:<section prefix="(i)">To assist the provider in voluntarily obtaining accreditation; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">For professional development activities leading to increased competency and appropriate credentialing that is related to early child care and education services.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The Department may distribute funds to a county board for the purpose of implementing the Department's Early Childhood Assessment System in the county's public schools.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Department shall:<section prefix="(i)">Establish application procedures for obtaining Judy Center Grants and Early Child Care and Education Enhancement Grants as provided under this section;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Supervise and monitor the use of Grant funds distributed under this section; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Evaluate whether Grant recipients are meeting annual benchmarks established by the Department.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">For Judy Center Grants, the Department may award multiyear funding.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(h)">A county board that is selected to receive a Judy Center Grant or an Early Child Care and Education Enhancement Grant for the purpose of purchasing early child care and education services shall:<section prefix="(1)">Administer the Grant award;</section><section prefix="(2)">Submit fiscal and program reports as required by the Department; and</section><section prefix="(3)">Coordinate the involvement of participating agencies and programs in any evaluation process conducted by the Department.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(i)">Grants awarded under this section may not be used:<section prefix="(1)">To supplant existing funding for any services provided by participating agencies and programs; or</section><section prefix="(2)">For capital improvements.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(j)">The Department shall select through a competitive bidding process and supervise an evaluator who shall design and implement an evaluation process to measure the effectiveness of:<section prefix="(1)">The Judy Centers; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Early child care and education services and family support services that are purchased with funds from Early Child Care and Education Enhancement Grants.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(k)">The Department shall submit to the Governor and, subject to &#xA7; 2-1246 of the State Government Article, the General Assembly:<section prefix="(1)">On or before November 1 of each year, a report on the implementation of the Program and the participating agencies and programs, including a description of the Program's and the participating agencies' and programs' expenditures, enrollment, and statewide performance data, including school readiness data disaggregated by program and by jurisdiction; and</section><section prefix="(2)">On or before January 1, 2004, a separate report that includes an evaluation, based on objective performance criteria established by the Department, of the effectiveness of:<section prefix="(i)">The Judy Centers; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Early child care and education services and family support services that are purchased with funds from Early Child Care and Education Enhancement Grants.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(l)">The Department may adopt regulations as necessary to implement the Program.</section>
  </text>
</law>
