<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="ged" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="11-203" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ged-11-203</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Commission may require any institution of postsecondary education that is required to obtain a certificate of approval or required to register under &#xA7; 11-202.2 of this subtitle to furnish a performance bond or other form of financial guarantee for either the certificate of approval or the registration to the State conditioned that the institution will:<section prefix="(1)">Perform faithfully all agreements or contracts it makes with its students; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Comply with this article.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Any bond or guarantee required under this section shall be in the form and amount the Secretary requires.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The total liability of a surety on a bond or guarantee under this section may not exceed the amount of the bond or guarantee.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If the total amount of claims filed against a bond or guarantee exceeds the amount of the bond or guarantee, the surety shall pay the amount of the bond or guarantee to the Secretary for distribution to the claimants.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">By rule and regulation, the Commission may create and provide for the operation of three separate guaranty funds for:<section prefix="(i)">For-profit institutions of higher education;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Private career schools; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Institutions of postsecondary education that are required to register under &#xA7; 11-202.2 of this subtitle.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The private career school fund shall be used:</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The for-profit institution of higher education fund shall be used to reimburse any student at a for-profit institution of higher education who is entitled to a refund of tuition and fees because the institution has failed to perform faithfully any agreement or contract with the student or failed to comply with any provision of this article.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)"/>
        <section prefix="(iv)"/>
        <section prefix="(v)">The Commission shall be subrogated to and may enforce the claim of any student to the extent of any actual or authorized reimbursement from the funds.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Each for-profit institution of higher education or private career school that is required to obtain a certificate of approval and, subject to paragraph (2)(iii)2 of this subsection, each institution of postsecondary education required to register under &#xA7; 11-202.2 of this subtitle shall pay an annual fee into the appropriate fund.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The Commission shall determine the amount of the fee based on the probable amount of money needed for the funds for each fiscal year. If the moneys in the guaranty funds are insufficient to satisfy duly authorized claims, the participating institutions may be reassessed and shall pay the additional amounts required.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">The Commission may not issue a certificate of approval or registration to, and shall revoke any certificate of approval or registration previously issued to, an institution that fails to pay any annual fee or reassessment.</section>
        <section prefix="(iv)">The Commission shall deposit into the appropriate fund any penalty assessed against a for-profit institution of higher education, institution of postsecondary education required to register under &#xA7; 11-202.2 of this subtitle, or private career school, respectively, under the terms of &#xA7; 11-204 of this subtitle.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(4)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The funds shall be maintained by the State Comptroller who may deposit the assets of the funds in any manner that is consistent with the purposes of the funds.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">All interest or other return on fund investments shall be credited to the funds.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(5)">The Commission, through the Attorney General, may enforce any claim to which the Commission has been subrogated under this subsection.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">On or before December 1 each year, the Commission shall report to the Governor and, in accordance with &#xA7; 2-1246 of the State Government Article, the General Assembly, regarding:<section prefix="(1)">The number of claims made against each guaranty fund established under this section;</section><section prefix="(2)">The type, size, and program of the institutions against which the claims are made;</section><section prefix="(3)">The number of claims that are approved and the associated payouts from the funds; and</section><section prefix="(4)">The number of claims that are denied.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
