<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ged" order_by="" level="1">Economic Development</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ged-7-302</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>302</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The principal or head teacher of each public or private school in this State shall report immediately to the county superintendent, the supervisor of pupil personnel, or any other official designated by the county superintendent the name of each child enrolled in his school who has been absent or irregular in attendance, without lawful excuse, or who shows evidence of maladjustment, so that the causes may be studied and solutions worked out.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">On receipt of a report from a principal or head teacher of a public school that a student has been habitually truant without lawful excuse, the appropriate representative of the school system:<section prefix="(1)">Shall initiate an investigation into the cause of the child's truancy;</section><section prefix="(2)">May provide counseling regarding the availability of social, health, and educational services; and</section><section prefix="(3)">Following the investigation or intervention:<section prefix="(i)">May notify the Department of Juvenile Services that the student has been habitually truant, without lawful excuse;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Shall notify the appropriate local department that the student has been habitually truant, without lawful excuse, if a court has given the notice authorized by &#xA7; 3-819(b-1) of the Courts Article; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Shall notify the Department of Juvenile Services that the student has been habitually truant, without lawful excuse, if a court has given the notice authorized by &#xA7; 3-8A-19(d)(5) of the Courts Article.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The county superintendent, the superintendent's designee, or the supervisor of pupil personnel shall provide to the local education agency information regarding the number of students identified as being habitually truant.</section>
  </text>
</law>
