<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ged" order_by="ged" level="1">Economic Development</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ged-8-416</section_number>
  <catch_line>There is a Maryland Infants and Toddlers Program in the Department....</catch_line>
  <order_by>416</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">There is a Maryland Infants and Toddlers Program in the Department.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The purpose of the Program is to provide a statewide, community-based interagency system of comprehensive early intervention services to eligible infants and toddlers, birth through age 2, and their families.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Department shall be the lead agency for supervising and monitoring the Program.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Program shall include the early intervention services provided or supervised by the Department, the Department of Health and Mental Hygiene, including the Program for Hearing-Impaired Infants established under Title 13, Subtitle 6 of the Health - General Article, the Department of Human Resources, and the Governor's Office for Children.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Program shall be administered in accord with the applicable requirements of Part C of the Individuals with Disabilities Education Act and other applicable federal and State laws.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">An interagency coordinating council shall be appointed by the Governor, with the advice and consent of the Senate, and shall:<section prefix="(1)">Advise and assist the Department in the supervision and monitoring of the Program; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Submit an annual report to the Governor and the federal government.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">Local lead agencies shall be established or designated in each county and Baltimore City to administer the Program in their subdivision, under the direction of the Department.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In each county, the county executive or county commissioners, as appropriate, or in Baltimore City, the Mayor, shall establish a local interagency coordinating council to advise and assist the local lead agency in the development and implementation of policies that constitute the local Program.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">In each county, the county executive or county commissioners, as appropriate, or in Baltimore City, the Mayor, may designate the local management board to serve as the local interagency coordinating council or establish the local interagency coordinating council as a part of that board.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">Where a local management board and a local interagency coordinating council coexist, they shall work cooperatively.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(h)">
      <section prefix="(1)">For fiscal year 2004, the annual per child cost of the Program is $4,044.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">For fiscal year 2005 and each succeeding fiscal year, the annual per child cost of the Program shall be the amount in paragraph (1) of this subsection increased by the same percentage as the increase in the implicit price deflator for State and local government expenditures, as of July of the second fiscal year preceding the year for which the amount is being calculated.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">For each fiscal year, if sufficient funds are not available to provide grants in accordance with the formula under paragraph (4) of this subsection, the Governor shall include in the annual budget bill an appropriation for the Maryland Infants and Toddlers Program in an amount not less than the amount of the appropriation for the Program as approved in the State budget as enacted by the General Assembly for the prior fiscal year.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">Subject to the availability of funding for the Program in the State budget, the Department shall distribute a grant to the local lead agency for the Program in each county in an amount equal to the product of:<section prefix="(i)">The annual per child cost multiplied by the number of children in the county who received services under the Program in the second fiscal year preceding the year for which the amount is being calculated; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">.20 for fiscal year 2007 and each succeeding fiscal year.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(i)">The Department shall adopt regulations necessary to carry out the provisions of this section.</section>
  </text>
</law>
