<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="ged" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="6-107" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ged-6-107</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">A county board may make an agreement or financial arrangement with an institution of higher education that satisfies the conditions of &#xA7; 11-202 of this article, to provide classroom or administrative office experience for student teachers and student interns.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The institution of higher education and the county board where the student teaching center program is adopted shall:<section prefix="(1)">Approve or select jointly the supervising teachers, who are employees of the county board, to serve in the program; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Adopt an agreed, continuing, in-service improvement program for the supervising teachers.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">While the student teacher is assigned as a student teacher, he shall be given the same authority as if he were a certificated employee of the county board to which he is assigned.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The authority of the student teacher extends to:<section prefix="(i)">Every aspect of student management or discipline;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The handling of records of students; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Any other aspect of authority granted to a certificated employee of a county board.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Student teachers and student interns are considered agents of the county board for the limited purposes of:<section prefix="(1)">Comprehensive liability insurance coverage under &#xA7; 4-105 of this article; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Workers' compensation coverage under the Maryland Workers' Compensation Act, but this coverage is not to exceed the salary of a first year teacher in the county school system.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
