<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ged" order_by="ged" level="1">Economic Development</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ged-5-210</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this section the following terms have the meanings indicated....</catch_line>
  <order_by>210</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following terms have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Additional education appropriation" means the difference between a county's education appropriation for the prior fiscal year and the county's local share of the foundation program calculated under &#xA7; 5-202 of this subtitle.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Additional education effort" means a county's additional education appropriation divided by the county's wealth, rounded to seven decimal places.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">"Full-time equivalent enrollment" has the meaning stated in &#xA7; 5-202 of this subtitle.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">"Guaranteed tax base program per pupil amount" means the lesser of:<section prefix="(i)">20% of the annual per pupil foundation amount calculated under &#xA7; 5-202 of this subtitle; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">The product of a county's additional education effort and the difference between guaranteed wealth per pupil and local wealth per pupil.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(6)">"Guaranteed wealth per pupil" means 80% of the statewide wealth per pupil.</section>
      <section prefix="(7)">"Local wealth per pupil" means a county's wealth divided by the county's full-time equivalent enrollment.</section>
      <section prefix="(8)">"Statewide wealth per pupil" means the sum of the wealth of all counties divided by the statewide full-time equivalent enrollment.</section>
      <section prefix="(9)">"Wealth" has the meaning stated in &#xA7; 5-202 of this subtitle.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">For fiscal year 2005 and each fiscal year thereafter, the State shall distribute guaranteed tax base grants to county boards as provided in this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A county board is eligible to receive a guaranteed tax base grant if the county's:<section prefix="(1)">Additional education effort is greater than zero; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Local wealth per pupil is less than the guaranteed wealth per pupil.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The amount of the guaranteed tax base grant shall be equal to the product of the county's guaranteed tax base program per pupil amount and the county's full-time equivalent enrollment multiplied by:<section prefix="(1)">0.25 in fiscal year 2005;</section><section prefix="(2)">0.50 in fiscal year 2006;</section><section prefix="(3)">0.75 in fiscal year 2007; and</section><section prefix="(4)">1.00 in fiscal year 2008 and each fiscal year thereafter.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
