<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ged" order_by="" level="1">Economic Development</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ged-11-402</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>402</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">"School" means a private career school located outside the State.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">"School" does not include a private career school that operates in the State pursuant to a certificate of approval issued under &#xA7; 11-202(b) of this title.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Solicitor" means a person engaged in the business, for compensation, of soliciting or offering to solicit students in this State to enroll in or apply for a program offered by a school.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A person may not act as a solicitor unless such person has a permit issued under this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A person wishing to act as a solicitor shall apply to the Commission for a permit.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The application shall be made on the forms the Commission provides, shall contain the information the Commission requires, and shall be accompanied by:<section prefix="(i)">A copy of each type of contract offered by the solicitor to prospective students; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Any advertising materials and other representations that are made by the school to its students or prospective students.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Each permit issued under this section expires on June 30 after its issuance and may be renewed annually on application and payment of the required fee.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Commission shall consider the application and accompanying material.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If the Commission approves the application, it shall issue a permit to the solicitor, on payment of an initial fee of $25. The renewal fee is $25.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">After notice to the solicitor and an opportunity for a hearing, the Commission may revoke the solicitor's permit for:<section prefix="(1)">Violation of a contract with a student; or</section><section prefix="(2)">Any other good cause.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
