<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="ged" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="14-207" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ged-14-207</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">This section does not apply to a suspension pending the disposition of a charge for removal of a classified employee.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A vice president or program director may suspend a classified employee for disciplinary purposes.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The vice president or program director shall notify the classified employee in writing of the suspension and the reasons for it.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A suspension for disciplinary purposes under this section shall be without pay.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A suspension for disciplinary purposes:<section prefix="(i)">Shall be served on consecutive days; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Shall begin within 2 days from the close of the classified employee's next shift after:</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The time limits in paragraph (1) of this subsection do not apply to a classified employee whose duties include mandatory appearances before a court, regulatory unit, or administrative body, if the limits:<section prefix="(i)">Would conflict with a scheduled appearance of the employee before a court, regulatory unit, or administrative body; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Would thereby hamper the effective administration of the University's business.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The vice president or program director may authorize a designee to receive appeals under this subsection.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A suspended classified employee or a representative of the employee may submit a written appeal of a disciplinary suspension:<section prefix="(i)">Within 3 workdays after receipt of a notice of suspension, to the vice president or program director; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">Within 5 workdays after receipt of a notice of suspension, to the President, in accordance with procedures established in policies adopted by the Board of Regents.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The vice president or program director may authorize a designee to hear appeals under this subsection.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If an appeal is made to the vice president or program director, the vice president or program director shall:<section prefix="(i)">Hold a hearing within 3 workdays after receiving the appeal; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Issue a written decision within the time established in policies adopted by the Board of Regents.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">If, as a result of management delay, the appeal is not heard and decided within the times required by this subsection, the vice president or program director shall reinstate the suspended classified employee with full back pay.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">If a classified employee appeals under this subsection, the employee may not further appeal the suspension except in accordance with step three of the grievance procedures under &#xA7; 14-306 of this title.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If an appeal is made to the President, the President shall issue a proposed written decision for approval by the Secretary of Budget and Management within 45 days after the later of:<section prefix="(i)">The conclusion of the hearing; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">The day when all briefs or memoranda have been submitted.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If the Secretary of Budget and Management disapproves the suspension, the Secretary of Budget and Management may grant back pay to the classified employee.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
