<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="ged" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="14-208" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ged-14-208</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">If a classified employee is transferred involuntarily to a different class that has a lower maximum rate of pay, the transfer is a demotion.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A transfer that is a demotion under this section may be made only for cause, on written charges submitted to the President.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The classified employee may appeal the proposed demotion to the President within the time and in the manner required by policies adopted by the Board of Regents.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">If the classified employee fails to appeal within the time and in the manner required, the demotion is final.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If the classified employee appeals the demotion, the President shall hold a hearing to determine whether there is cause for the demotion.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The hearing shall be held within 90 days after the written charges for the demotion are submitted to the President.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The President shall make findings and issue a proposed written decision on an appeal for approval by the Secretary of Budget and Management within 45 days after the later of:<section prefix="(i)">The conclusion of the hearing; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">The day when all briefs or memoranda have been submitted.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Secretary of Budget and Management shall provide a copy of the findings and decision to each party.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The decision of the Secretary of Budget and Management is final.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The University authority immediately shall enforce a final decision issued under this section.</section>
  </text>
</law>
