<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ged" order_by="" level="1">Economic Development</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ged-18-2601</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>2601</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In cooperation with the institutions of higher education in the State, the Commission shall establish and administer a Graduate and Professional Scholarship Program to provide financial assistance to full-time and part-time students in the fields of medicine, dentistry, law, pharmacy, nursing, social work, and veterinary medicine.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A recipient of a graduate and professional scholarship shall:<section prefix="(1)">Be a resident of the State;</section><section prefix="(2)">Demonstrate financial need according to criteria established by the Commission; and</section><section prefix="(3)">Attend one of the following institutions:<section prefix="(i)">The University of Maryland School of:<section prefix="1.">Medicine;</section><section prefix="2.">Dentistry;</section><section prefix="3.">Law;</section><section prefix="4.">Pharmacy; or</section><section prefix="5.">Social Work;</section></section><section prefix="(ii)">The University of Baltimore School of Law;</section><section prefix="(iii)">The Johns Hopkins University School of Medicine;</section><section prefix="(iv)">Virginia-Maryland Regional College of Veterinary Medicine;</section><section prefix="(v)">Any institution of higher education in the State offering a master's degree in nursing;</section><section prefix="(vi)">Any institution of higher education in the State offering a master's degree in social work; or</section><section prefix="(vii)">Any institution of higher education in the State offering a first professional degree in pharmacy.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A graduate and professional scholarship award for a single school year may not be less than $1,000 or more than $5,000.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A recipient may not receive an award for longer than 8 semesters.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Commission shall allocate grants for the Program to the institutions of higher education specified in subsection (b)(3) of this section based on the proportion of State residents enrolled in eligible programs at each institution.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">An institution of higher education that receives a grant under this section shall provide the Commission with an annual audit describing the disposition of the funds.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The Commission shall:<section prefix="(1)">Establish guidelines for the awarding of graduate and professional scholarships by the institutions of higher education to the students; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Adopt regulations necessary for the implementation of this section.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(g)">Funds for the Maryland Graduate and Professional Scholarship Program shall be as provided in the State budget and as set forth in &#xA7; 13-613 of the Transportation Article.</section>
  </text>
</law>
