<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="ged" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="24-703" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ged-24-703</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">There is a Maryland Longitudinal Data System Center.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Center is an independent unit within State government.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The organizational placement and location of the Center shall be determined by the Governing Board.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The head of the Center is the Executive Director, who shall be appointed by the Governing Board.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Center may employ the additional staff necessary to carry out the Center's functions as provided in the State budget.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The Center shall be considered an authorized representative of the State Department of Education and the Maryland Higher Education Commission under applicable federal and State statutes for purposes of accessing and compiling student record data for research purposes.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The Center shall perform the following functions and duties:<section prefix="(1)">Serve as a central repository of student data and workforce data in the Maryland Longitudinal Data System, including data sets provided by:<section prefix="(i)">The State Department of Education;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Local education agencies;</section><section prefix="(iii)">The Maryland Higher Education Commission;</section><section prefix="(iv)">Institutions of higher education; and</section><section prefix="(v)">The Department of Labor, Licensing, and Regulation;</section></section><section prefix="(2)">Oversee and maintain the warehouse of the Maryland Longitudinal Data System data sets;</section><section prefix="(3)">Ensure routine and ongoing compliance with the federal Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act and other relevant privacy laws and policies, including:<section prefix="(i)">The required use of de-identified data in data research and reporting;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The required disposition of information that is no longer needed;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Providing data security, including the capacity for audit trails;</section><section prefix="(iv)">Providing for performance of regular audits for compliance with data privacy and security standards; and</section><section prefix="(v)">Implementing guidelines and policies that prevent the reporting of other potentially identifying data;</section></section><section prefix="(4)">Conduct research using timely and accurate student data and workforce data to improve the State's education system and guide decision making by State and local governments, educational agencies, institutions, teachers, and other education professionals;</section><section prefix="(5)">Conduct research relating to:<section prefix="(i)">The impact of State and federal education programs;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The performance of educator preparation programs; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Best practices regarding classroom instruction, education programs and curriculum, and segment alignment;</section></section><section prefix="(6)">Fulfill information and data requests to facilitate State and federal education reporting with existing State agencies as appropriate; and</section><section prefix="(7)">Fulfill approved public information requests.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Direct access to data in the Maryland Longitudinal Data System shall be restricted to authorized staff of the Center.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Center may only use de-identified data in the analysis, research, and reporting conducted by the Center.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Center may only use aggregate data in the release of data in reports and in response to data requests.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">Data that may be identifiable based on the size or uniqueness of the population under consideration may not be reported in any form by the Center.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">The Center may not release information that may not be disclosed under the federal Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act and other relevant privacy laws and policies.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(h)">The Center may receive funding from the following sources:<section prefix="(1)">State appropriations;</section><section prefix="(2)">Grants or other assistance from local education agencies and institutions of higher education;</section><section prefix="(3)">Federal grants;</section><section prefix="(4)">User fees; and</section><section prefix="(5)">Any other grants or contributions from public or private entities received by the Center.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
