<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ged" order_by="ged" level="1">Economic Development</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ged-18-803</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this section the following words have the meanings indicated....</catch_line>
  <order_by>803</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Grant" means the Health Personnel Shortage Incentive Grant for eligible institutions offering educational programs leading to licensure, certification, or registration in health occupations determined to be in short supply.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Eligible institution" means an institution of postsecondary education that:<section prefix="(i)">Is approved to operate by the Maryland Higher Education Commission; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Produces graduates eligible to take the appropriate national examination for licensure, certification, or registration in the relevant health occupation determined to be in short supply.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">"Health occupation" means a:<section prefix="(i)">Physical therapist or a physical therapist assistant who has at least an Associate degree in physical therapy;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Occupational therapist or an occupational therapist assistant who has at least an Associate degree in occupational therapy;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Radiographer;</section><section prefix="(iv)">Respiratory therapist;</section><section prefix="(v)">Laboratory technician;</section><section prefix="(vi)">Medical technologist;</section><section prefix="(vii)">Pharmacist;</section><section prefix="(viii)">Registered nurse or licensed practical nurse; or</section><section prefix="(ix)">Physician who engages in family practice or pediatrics.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">There is a Health Personnel Shortage Incentive Grant Program for eligible institutions.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Office of Student Financial Assistance shall administer the Grant Program as provided in this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">In consultation with the Secretary of Health and Mental Hygiene, the Office shall adopt regulations to implement the Grant Program.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">An eligible institution is qualified to receive a grant under this section if the institution:<section prefix="(1)">Has an approved education program leading to licensure, certification, or registration in a health occupation determined to be in short supply; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Funds the approved education program at an amount not less than the preceding fiscal year.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in subsection (e) of this section, an eligible institution shall receive a grant in the amount of $1,500 for each student who graduates from an approved education program leading to licensure, certification, or registration in a health occupation determined to be in short supply, that is in excess of the lowest number of students who graduated from the approved education program at that eligible institution commencing in the academic year 1990-91.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">For purposes of paragraph (1) of this subsection, the Commission shall establish, in consultation with each appropriate eligible institution, that institution's threshold number of students.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If the total amount of the grant to be issued under subsection (d) of this section is more than the amount appropriated in the annual State budget, including the amount that is collected under the Board of Physicians Fund under &#xA7; 14-207(c)(2)(i) of the Health Occupations Article and transferred to this program, the amount of an eligible institution's grant for that period shall be equal to the product of the amount required to pay grants under subsection (d) multiplied by the ratio of the total amount appropriated to the eligible institution.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Any unspent portions of the money that is transferred to the Office for use under this section by the Comptroller may not be transferred to or revert to the General Fund of the State, but shall remain in the Fund maintained by the Office to administer these programs to be used for the purposes specified in this section.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The eligible institution shall use the grant to enhance or expand approved education programs leading to licensure or certification in health occupations determined to be in short supply.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In accordance with &#xA7; 1-204 of the Health Occupations Article, the Secretary of Health and Mental Hygiene shall certify annually to the Maryland Higher Education Commission those health occupations in short supply.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">In any year in which a health occupation is determined by the Secretary of Health and Mental Hygiene to be no longer in short supply, the Office shall discontinue issuing new grants under this section for that health occupation, provided that the existing grants shall continue for the students who are enrolled in prior to and who subsequently graduate from the approved education program after the determination is made by the Secretary.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
