<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ged" order_by="ged" level="1">Economic Development</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ged-16-504</section_number>
  <catch_line>The government of the College is vested in the Board of Trustees of the College....</catch_line>
  <order_by>504</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The government of the College is vested in the Board of Trustees of the College.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Board of Trustees consists of nine members appointed by the Governor with the advice and consent of the Senate.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Of the members:<section prefix="(i)">Each shall be a resident of the State;</section><section prefix="(ii)">A majority shall be residents of Baltimore City; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">One shall be a regularly enrolled student in good standing at the College.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The student member shall have a term of 1 year beginning July 1 and ending on June 30.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Except for the student member, the term is 6 years from July 1 of the year of appointment and until a successor is appointed and qualifies.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The terms of the members are staggered, as required by the terms provided for members of the Board on July 1, 1992.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">A member appointed to fill a vacancy in an unexpired term serves only for the remainder of that term or until a successor is appointed and qualifies.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">A member may be reappointed but may not serve more than 2 consecutive full terms.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Each member of the Board of Trustees:<section prefix="(1)">Serves without compensation; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Is entitled to reimbursement for expenses in accordance with the Standard State Travel Regulations.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">Each year the Board of Trustees:<section prefix="(1)">Shall elect one of its nonstudent members as its chairman; and</section><section prefix="(2)">May elect any other officers it requires.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Board of Trustees shall meet regularly at such times and places as it determines.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Board of Trustees may adopt rules for the conduct of its meetings and the transaction of business.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">A majority of the voting members shall constitute a quorum for the transaction of business.</section>
  </text>
</law>
