<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="ged" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="13-103" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ged-13-103</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">There is a Maryland Fire and Rescue Institute in the University of Maryland.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The head of the Institute is the Director.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Director:<section prefix="(i)">Shall report directly to the President of the University of Maryland, College Park; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">May adopt rules and regulations necessary to carry out this section.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Institute shall:<section prefix="(1)">Provide classroom education and training for career and volunteer fire and rescue personnel, both at the Institute and throughout this State;</section><section prefix="(2)">Cooperate with other agencies that provide training for fire and rescue personnel;</section><section prefix="(3)">Train instructors;</section><section prefix="(4)">Prepare or adopt materials for training fire and rescue personnel;</section><section prefix="(5)">Develop new fire and rescue training techniques;</section><section prefix="(6)">Develop and implement specialized courses in fire fighting, including industrial fire fighting;</section><section prefix="(7)">Maintain statistics and records on fire and rescue education, training, and related matters;</section><section prefix="(8)">Develop programs to inform the public about the tasks performed by fire and rescue personnel;</section><section prefix="(9)">Establish guidelines for instructional material to school systems in the State concerning fire and rescue education;</section><section prefix="(10)">Provide disaster training for fire and rescue personnel; and</section><section prefix="(11)">Cooperate with the Maryland Institute for Emergency Medical Services Systems to provide basic training for rescue personnel and emergency medical technicians.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Institute shall have the funds provided in the State budget.</section>
  </text>
</law>
