<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ged" order_by="ged" level="1">Economic Development</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ged-8-401</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated....</catch_line>
  <order_by>401</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Child with a disability" means a child who has been determined through appropriate assessment as having autism, deaf-blindness, hearing impairment, including deafness, emotional disability, intellectual disability, multiple disabilities, orthopedic impairment, other health impairment, specific learning disability, speech or language impairment, traumatic brain injury, visual impairment, including blindness, and who because of that impairment needs special education and related services.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Free appropriate public education" means special education and related services that:<section prefix="(i)">Are provided at public expense, under public supervision and direction, at no cost to the parents;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Meet the standards of the State Board regulations and the Individuals with Disabilities Education Act (20 U.S.C. 1400 et seq.);</section><section prefix="(iii)">Includes preschool, elementary, and secondary education; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">Are provided in conformance with the requirements of the child's individualized education program.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">
        <section prefix="(i)">"Related services" means transportation and such developmental, corrective, and other supportive services as may be required to assist a child with a disability to benefit from special education.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">"Related services" includes the early identification and assessment of disabling conditions in children.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">"Related services" does not include a surgically implanted medical device or the replacement of the device.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(5)">"Special education" means specially designed instruction, at no cost to parents, to meet the unique needs of a child with a disability, including:<section prefix="(i)">Instruction in the classroom, in the home, in hospitals and institutions, and in other settings; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Instruction in physical education.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">In this subtitle the domicile of a child with a disability is the county in which the parent or guardian who has legal custody of the child is domiciled.</section>
  </text>
</law>
