<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ged" order_by="ged" level="1">Economic Development</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ged-11-406</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this section, "cultural diversity" means the inclusion of those racial and ethnic groups and indi...</catch_line>
  <order_by>406</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, "cultural diversity" means the inclusion of those racial and ethnic groups and individuals that are or have been underrepresented in higher education.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Each public institution of higher education in the State shall develop and implement a plan for a program of cultural diversity.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">If an institution of higher education already has a program of cultural diversity, the institution of higher education shall develop and implement a plan for improving the program.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">A plan developed and implemented under this subsection shall include an implementation strategy and a time line for meeting goals within the plan.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A plan developed under paragraph (1) of this subsection shall include:<section prefix="(i)">A description of the way the institution addresses cultural diversity among its student, faculty, and staff populations;</section><section prefix="(ii)">A description of how the institution plans to enhance cultural diversity, if improvement is needed;</section><section prefix="(iii)">A process for reporting campus-based hate crimes, as defined under Title 10, Subtitle 3 of the Criminal Law Article and consistent with federal requirements under 20 U.S.C. 1092(f), known as the Jeanne Clery Disclosure of Campus Security Policy and Campus Crime Statistics Act; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">A summary of any resources, including State grants, needed by the institution to effectively recruit and retain a culturally diverse student body.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A plan developed under paragraph (1) of this subsection shall enhance cultural diversity programming and sensitivity to cultural diversity through instruction and training of the student body, faculty, and staff at the institution of higher education.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">On or before July 1 of each year, each institution shall submit the plan developed under subsection (b) of this section to the governing body of the institution for the governing body's review.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">On or before September 1 of each year, the governing body of an institution shall submit a progress report regarding the institution's implementation of its plan to the Commission.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Commission shall review the progress report submitted by each governing body under subsection (c) of this section to monitor compliance with the diversity goals of the State Plan for Higher Education.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">On or before December 1 of each year, the Commission shall submit a report, in accordance with &#xA7; 2-1246 of the State Government Article, to the Senate Education, Health, and Environmental Affairs Committee, the Senate Budget and Taxation Committee, the House Appropriations Committee, and the House Committee on Ways and Means on the extent to which the institutions of higher education in the State are in compliance with the diversity goals of the State Plan for Higher Education.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
