<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ged" order_by="" level="1">Economic Development</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ged-4-205</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>205</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In addition to the other powers granted and duties imposed under this article, the county superintendent has the powers and duties set forth in this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The county superintendent may administer oaths to witnesses in all appeals or cases that come before the county board.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Subject to the authority of the State Board under &#xA7; 2-205(e) of this article, each county superintendent shall explain the true intent and meaning of:<section prefix="(i)">The school law; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">The applicable bylaws of the State Board.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Subject to the provisions of &#xA7; 6-203 and Title 6, Subtitle 4 of this article and without charge to the parties concerned, each county superintendent shall decide all controversies and disputes that involve:<section prefix="(i)">The rules and regulations of the county board; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">The proper administration of the county public school system.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A decision of a county superintendent may be appealed to the county board if taken in writing within 30 days after the decision of the county superintendent. The decision may be further appealed to the State Board if taken in writing within 30 days after the decision of the county board.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A contract made by a county board is not valid without the written approval of the county superintendent.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Acting as the executive officer of the county board, the county superintendent shall:<section prefix="(i)">Conduct all correspondence;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Receive all reports from principals and teachers; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">See that all reports are made and submitted properly.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The county superintendent shall prepare and submit to the county board for adoption:<section prefix="(i)">All reports required of the county board by the State Board or the State Superintendent; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">The annual report to the people of the county required by &#xA7; 5-111(b) of this article.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The county superintendent:<section prefix="(1)">Shall advise teachers as to their further study and professional improvement;</section><section prefix="(2)">Shall develop a program of in-service training for all public school personnel; and</section><section prefix="(3)">May require attendance at an institution of higher education for future certification and professional improvement instead of in-service training.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(g)">The county superintendent and his professional assistants shall:<section prefix="(1)">Visit the schools;</section><section prefix="(2)">Observe their management and instruction;</section><section prefix="(3)">Give suggestions for their improvement;</section><section prefix="(4)">Consult with and advise principals and teachers; and</section><section prefix="(5)">Try in every way to awaken public interest and improve educational conditions in the county.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(h)">In accordance with the applicable rules and regulations of the State Board, the county superintendent periodically shall:<section prefix="(1)">Evaluate the program of instruction in the public schools of the county; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Report his findings and recommendations to the county board.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(i)">The county superintendent shall prepare and recommend for adoption by the county board:<section prefix="(1)">Curriculum guides;</section><section prefix="(2)">Courses of study;</section><section prefix="(3)">Resource material; and</section><section prefix="(4)">Other teaching aids.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(j)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The county superintendent shall prepare lists of the following items needed by the schools:<section prefix="(i)">Textbooks;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Supplementary readers;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Materials of instruction;</section><section prefix="(iv)">Visual and auditory aids;</section><section prefix="(v)">Stationery and school supplies; and</section><section prefix="(vi)">School furniture, equipment, and apparatus.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The county superintendent shall recommend the purchase and distribution of these items by the county board.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(k)">The county superintendent shall:<section prefix="(1)">Take the initiative in the preparation and presentation of the annual school budget; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Seek in every way to secure adequate funds from local authorities for the support and development of the public schools in the county.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(l)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The county superintendent shall recommend to the county board:<section prefix="(i)">Condemnation of any school building that is unsanitary and unfit for use; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Any repairs of or the purchase and sale of land, school sites, or buildings.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Subject to the provisions of &#xA7; 2-303(f) of this article that relate to approval by the State Superintendent, the county superintendent shall prepare all plans and specifications for remodeling an old building or constructing a new building.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The county superintendent shall recommend to traffic safety officials of the State Highway Administration or of the county appropriate locations for posting flashing caution signs at or near the site of:<section prefix="(i)">A school;</section><section prefix="(ii)">School construction; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">School condemnation.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(m)">The county superintendent shall provide the clerical help that is needed to issue work permits in accordance with &#xA7; 3-206 of the Labor and Employment Article.</section>
  </text>
</law>
