<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ged" order_by="ged" level="1">Economic Development</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ged-11-208</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this section, "national accreditation" means teacher education accreditation by an accrediting ag...</catch_line>
  <order_by>208</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, "national accreditation" means teacher education accreditation by an accrediting agency recognized by the U.S. Department of Education and endorsed by the Department.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">After July 1, 2004, an institution of higher education in this State may not offer a program of undergraduate or graduate studies that would certify a recipient to teach unless the institution has received:<section prefix="(i)">National accreditation; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">A waiver under paragraph (2) of this subsection.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The State Superintendent may grant a waiver from the national accreditation requirements to:<section prefix="(i)">Any liberal arts college with a full-time equivalent enrollment of not more than 2,000 students; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Any nationally recognized professional school of fine arts specializing in music or art.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">By July 1, 2000, an institution of higher education in the State that offers a program of undergraduate or graduate studies that would certify a recipient to teach must:<section prefix="(i)">File its intent to seek national accreditation;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Certify to the Department that it has national accreditation; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">Have received a waiver under subsection (b)(2) of this section.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The accreditation process for an institution of higher education subject to this section shall be conducted in accordance with the protocol established by a nationally recognized accrediting agency and the Department.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In conjunction with accrediting agencies, the Department shall develop and administer a program of technical support to assist institutions of higher education in the State that seek accreditation under this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">In addition to the technical support provided to an institution of higher education under paragraph (1) of this subsection, the Department shall pay:<section prefix="(i)">Any fee that an accrediting agency charges an institution of higher education in connection with the accreditation process;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Any training fee that an accrediting agency charges a State representative who serves with a review team of an accrediting agency in conjunction with an accreditation visit to an institution of higher education in the State; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">One-half of the expenses incurred by an institution of higher education in connection with the accreditation visit of a review team of an accrediting agency.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The Department shall adopt regulations to implement this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The Governor shall provide sufficient funds in the Department's annual budget for the additional costs incurred by the Department under this section.</section>
  </text>
</law>
