<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ged" order_by="" level="1">Economic Development</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ged-18-2306</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>2306</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Each recipient of a Maryland HOPE Scholarship may hold the award for 5 years if the recipient:<section prefix="(1)">Continues to be a resident of the State;</section><section prefix="(2)">Continues to be a full-time student at an eligible institution in the State and takes at least 12 semester hours of courses each semester or its equivalent as determined by the Office;</section><section prefix="(3)">Upon completion of the freshman year, has achieved a cumulative grade point average of at least 3.0 on a 4.0 scale, and maintains this minimum cumulative grade point average throughout the remainder of the award, or failing to do so, provides evidence satisfactory to the Office of extenuating circumstances;</section><section prefix="(4)">In the judgment of the institution, is making satisfactory progress toward a degree; and</section><section prefix="(5)">Maintains the standards of the institution.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Each recipient of a Maryland HOPE Scholarship who is enrolled in an associate degree program as permitted in this subtitle may hold the award for 3 years if the same conditions of subsection (a) of this section are met.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Each recipient of a Maryland HOPE Scholarship who transfers from a 2-year eligible institution to a 4-year eligible institution may hold the award for a total of 5 years, including the years at both the 2-year eligible institution and the 4-year eligible institution, if the same conditions of subsection (a) of this section are met.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A recipient of an award made under this section shall receive the award for each year indicated in which the recipient is eligible if the recipient signs an agreement at the time of the initial award to:<section prefix="(1)">Commence employment in the State within 1 year after completion of undergraduate studies for 1 year for each year that the scholarship was awarded; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Repay the State the amounts awarded under this subtitle as set forth in &#xA7; 18-112 of this title if the recipient does not:<section prefix="(i)">Satisfy the degree requirements of the eligible institution or fulfill other requirements as provided in this subtitle; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Perform the service obligation for 1 year for each year that the recipient has a scholarship awarded under this subtitle.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The service obligation begins after graduation and cannot be fulfilled prior to graduation from an eligible institution.</section>
  </text>
</law>
