<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ged" order_by="ged" level="1">Economic Development</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ged-12-104</section_number>
  <catch_line>In addition to any other powers granted and duties imposed by this title, and subject to the provisi...</catch_line>
  <order_by>104</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In addition to any other powers granted and duties imposed by this title, and subject to the provisions of Title 11 of this article and any other restriction imposed by law by specific reference to the University System of Maryland, or by any trust agreement involving a pledge of property or money, the Board of Regents has the powers and duties set forth in this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">In addition to the powers set forth elsewhere in this title, the University may:<section prefix="(1)">Exercise all the corporate powers granted Maryland corporations under the Maryland General Corporation Law;</section><section prefix="(2)">Adopt and alter an official seal;</section><section prefix="(3)">Sue and be sued, complain, and defend in all courts;</section><section prefix="(4)">Maintain an office at the place the Board of Regents may designate;</section><section prefix="(5)">Enter into contracts of any kind, and execute all instruments necessary or convenient with respect to its carrying out the powers in this subtitle to accomplish the purposes of the University;</section><section prefix="(6)">Subject to the provisions of subsection (h) of this section, acquire, hold, lease, use, encumber, transfer, exchange, or dispose of real and personal property;</section><section prefix="(7)">Borrow money from any source to acquire personal property as provided in &#xA7; 12-105(c) of this subtitle; and</section><section prefix="(8)">In addition to the powers set forth in Title 19 of this article and subject to the approval of the Board of Public Works, borrow money from any source for any corporate purpose, including working capital for its operations, reserve funds or interest, and mortgage, pledge, or otherwise encumber the property or funds of the University, and contract with or engage the services of any person in connection with any financing, including financial institutions, issuers of credit, or insurers.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Board of Regents:<section prefix="(1)">Is responsible for the management of the University System of Maryland and has all the powers, rights, and privileges that go with that responsibility, including the power to conduct or maintain any institutions, schools, or departments in the University at the locations the Board determines;</section><section prefix="(2)">Shall consult with the presidents in developing policies, guidelines, and plans for the University System of Maryland; and</section><section prefix="(3)">May not be superseded in its authority by any other State agency or office in managing the affairs of the University System of Maryland or of any constituent institutions and centers under the Board's jurisdiction.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">In addition to the powers conferred on it by this title, the Board has all the powers conferred on it by:<section prefix="(1)">The act of incorporation of the Maryland College of Agriculture;</section><section prefix="(2)">The Charter of the University of Maryland; and</section><section prefix="(3)">The charter of any constituent institution.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Board may:<section prefix="(i)">Apply for, accept, and spend any gift or grant from the federal government, any foundation, or any other person; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Maintain and manage gift and endowment funds.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">On or before November 1 each year, the Board shall submit to the Governor, the Comptroller, the State Treasurer, and, in accordance with &#xA7; 2-1246 of the State Government Article, the General Assembly, an annual investment performance report comparing the various components of the University's gift and endowment investment portfolio to appropriate benchmarks.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Board may establish new institutions, regional higher education centers, and branches subject to:<section prefix="(i)">The concurrence of the Maryland Higher Education Commission; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">The approval of the Governor and the General Assembly.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Without the approval of the Governor and the General Assembly, the Board may not change the name of any constituent institution.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Subject to the approval of the Governor and the General Assembly, the Board may merge, consolidate, or close any constituent institution.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">In its discretion, the Board may establish, merge, consolidate, or close any center or institute.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">With the approval of the Board of Public Works, the Board of Regents may sell or exchange any part of its properties.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Money received from the sale of property may be used, if approved by the Board of Public Works, only to purchase or improve property and facilities. This money may not be applied to the Annuity Bond Fund Account.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(h)">With the approval of the Board of Public Works, the Board of Regents may acquire by purchase or exchange, any real property or interests in real property.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Title 12, Subtitle 1 of the State Government Article ("Maryland Tort Claims Act") applies to claims or actions against the University System of Maryland and its employees.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Subject to all exclusions and limitations in that subtitle, the immunity of the University System of Maryland is waived to the extent of any applicable liability insurance purchased by the University or the State Treasurer.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Nothing in this subsection shall be construed to waive or abrogate sovereign immunity with respect to any claim that is not covered by or exceeds the limits of an insurance policy.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">Nothing in this subsection shall be construed to waive or abrogate the immunity of the University System of Maryland under the Eleventh Amendment to the United States Constitution.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(j)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Subject to Title 10, Subtitle 5 of the State Government Article ("Open Meetings" Law), the Board may make rules and regulations, and prescribe policies and procedures, for the management, maintenance, operation, and control of the University System of Maryland.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Except with respect to grievance appeals under Title 13, Subtitle 2 of this article, Title 10, Subtitles 1 and 2 of the State Government Article ("Administrative Procedure Act") are not applicable to the University.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(k)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in subsections (f) and (g) of this section, the Board:<section prefix="(i)">May delegate any part of its authority over the affairs of the University to the Chancellor or the presidents, or to any advisory bodies that the Board establishes under &#xA7; 12-201 of this title; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Consistent with the goals, objectives, and priorities of the Board of Regents and its legal responsibility for the efficient management of the University, shall delegate to the president of each constituent institution authority needed to manage that institution, including authority to make and implement policies promoting the mission of that institution, including the authority to establish policies appropriate to the institution's mission, size, location, and financial resources.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Any delegation of authority may be modified or rescinded by the Board of Regents at any time in whole or in part.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Board of Regents shall develop policies and guidelines that:<section prefix="(i)">Provide direction to the presidents of the constituent institutions on compliance with applicable law and policy;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Establish and monitor high standards of operation, including meeting appropriate quality benchmarks, using resources wisely and efficiently, managing personnel equitably, adhering to institutional mission, and meeting the educational needs of the students; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Hold each president accountable for meeting the objectives in the institution's performance accountability plan developed in accordance with Title 11, Subtitle 3 of this article.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(l)">By September 1 of each year, the Board shall submit an annual position accountability report to the Department of Budget and Management, Department of Legislative Services, the Maryland Higher Education Commission, and, in accordance with &#xA7; 2-1246 of the State Government Article, the General Assembly, reporting the total positions created and the cost and the funding source for any positions created by the University in the previous fiscal year.</section>
    <section prefix="(m)">The Board of Regents shall distribute appropriated strategic incentive funds to constituent institutions to encourage attainment of their approved mission.</section>
    <section prefix="(n)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Board of Regents and the Chancellor are encouraged to meet periodically with the boards of visitors of the constituent institutions to develop close working relationships.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">To the extent possible and appropriate, the Board of Regents should include members of boards of visitors actively in all searches for campus presidents and invite members of boards of visitors to participate in meetings of the Board of Regents and its committees.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
