<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ged" order_by="" level="1">Economic Development</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ged-6-116</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>116</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Eligible school" means a public school identified for restructuring under the accountability regulations of the State Board.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Employer school system" means the local school system where an applicant to the Program is employed at the time of selection as a fellow.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">"Fellow" means an individual selected to participate in the Program.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">"Program" means the Principal Fellowship and Leadership Development Program.</section>
      <section prefix="(6)">"Receiving school" means a public school where a fellow is placed.</section>
      <section prefix="(7)">"Receiving school system" means the local school system in which the public school where a fellow is placed is located.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">There is a statewide elementary and secondary education Principal Fellowship and Leadership Development Program in the Department.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Department shall develop criteria for the selection of:<section prefix="(i)">Fellows; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Receiving schools.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Subject to the approval of the State Board, the State Superintendent may require a school system in corrective action to participate in the Program.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A principal in a local school system in the State may not participate in the Program in an eligible school within the same local school system.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">
        <section prefix="(i)">A county superintendent may nominate a principal or assistant principal from within the local school system to participate in the Program in an eligible school within a different local school system.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">A county superintendent may not nominate a principal or assistant principal from within the local school system to participate in the Program in an eligible school within the local school system.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(5)">The placement of a fellow in an eligible school satisfies the alternative governance requirement of the accountability regulations of the State Board.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A fellow shall receive an annual compensation that consists of:<section prefix="(i)">A salary at the level and step the fellow would have received according to the salary scale of the employer school system; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">A $20,000 annual stipend.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">For each year of the fellow's placement in a receiving school, the Department shall issue a grant to the receiving school system in an amount that covers:<section prefix="(i)">The annual stipend; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">If the fellow's salary at the level and step on the salary scale of the receiving school system as of July 1 is less than that of the level and step on the salary scale of the employer school system, the amount of the difference.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The receiving school system shall reimburse the employer school system for:<section prefix="(i)">The salary of the fellow;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The annual stipend; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">The fringe benefit costs associated with the fellow's annual salary including the stipend.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Each year the State Superintendent shall select from a list of qualified applicants a maximum of 10 fellows and place them in public schools identified for restructuring in accordance with the selection criteria.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Each fellow shall make a commitment to serve for 3 years if selected.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Subject to the approval of both the State Superintendent and the county superintendent, the fellow may select, from among qualified employees of the receiving school system, the assistant principals in the receiving school where the fellow is placed.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">In order to address orderly succession in school leadership, the fellow shall, subject to the approval of both the State Superintendent and the county superintendent of the receiving school system, select a qualified employee of the receiving school system, on or before the start of the third year of the fellow's placement, to serve as the assistant principal in the receiving school who will assume leadership of the school after the fellow's departure.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Provided that the assistant principal selected under paragraph (2) of this subsection has demonstrated satisfactory performance, the assistant principal shall become the principal of the school after the departure of the fellow.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">The Department shall act as a fiscal agent for State funds appropriated under this section.</section>
  </text>
</law>
