<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ged" order_by="ged" level="1">Economic Development</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ged-3-5A-01</section_number>
  <catch_line>The Dorchester County Board consists of:...</catch_line>
  <order_by>01</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Dorchester County Board consists of:<section prefix="(1)">Five voting members, elected in accordance with subsection (b) of this section; and</section><section prefix="(2)">One nonvoting student member from each public high school in the county.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The elected members of the county board shall be elected at the general election.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">One member shall be elected from each of the five councilmanic districts only by the voters of that councilmanic district.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A member elected from a councilmanic district shall be a resident of the district.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A member elected or appointed from a councilmanic district who no longer resides in the district may not continue as a member of the county board.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Each voting member serves for a term of 4 years beginning at noon on the first Monday in December after the member's election and until a successor is elected and qualifies.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A voting member may not serve for more than three consecutive terms.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The terms of the voting members are staggered as follows:<section prefix="(1)">One member elected from each of the councilmanic districts 1, 3, and 5 at the 2004 general election, and every 4 years thereafter; and</section><section prefix="(2)">One member elected from each of the councilmanic districts 2 and 4 at the 2006 general election, and every 4 years thereafter.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The County Council shall appoint a new member to fill any vacancy on the county board for the remainder of that term and until a successor is elected and qualifies.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A resident of the district in which a vacancy exists may apply for appointment by the County Council to fill the vacancy.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The County Council shall adopt rules governing the procedure through which an individual may apply to fill a vacancy on the county board.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Each student member shall:<section prefix="(i)">Be a twelfth grade student in the Dorchester County public school system elected by the high school students of the public school that the student attends, in accordance with procedures established by the school system;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Serve for 1 year beginning on July 1 after the election of the member;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Be a nonvoting member; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">Advise the board on the interests of students.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Unless invited to attend by an affirmative vote of a majority of the county board, the student members may not attend an executive session.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
