<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="ged" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="18-708" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ged-18-708</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Advisory Council" means the Advisory Council on Workforce Shortage.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Eligible institution" means a public or private nonprofit institution of higher education in this State that possesses a certificate of approval from the Commission.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">"Grant" means the Workforce Shortage Student Assistance grant.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">"Public good or benefit" means service to low-income or underserved residents or areas of the State in an occupation in the public sector or in an organization, institution, association, society, or corporation that is exempt from taxation under &#xA7; 501(c)(3) or (4) of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">There is a program of Workforce Shortage Student Assistance grants under this section for students who pledge to work in fields of critical shortage in the State on completion of their studies.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The purpose of the program is to:<section prefix="(1)">Provide financial assistance to students enrolled at institutions of higher education in the State; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Address the workforce shortage needs of the State.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A recipient of a Workforce Shortage Student Assistance grant under this section shall:<section prefix="(1)">Be a resident of the State;</section><section prefix="(2)">Be selected by the Office from qualified applicants;</section><section prefix="(3)">Sign a letter of intent to enroll at an eligible institution in the State in an eligible program as specified for each field in which there is a critical shortage in this State as provided in this section;</section><section prefix="(4)">Sign a letter of intent to perform the service obligation on completion of the recipient's required studies;</section><section prefix="(5)">Accept any other conditions attached to the grant;</section><section prefix="(6)">Satisfy any additional criteria the Commission may establish; and</section><section prefix="(7)">After completion of studies in an eligible program, perform the service obligation as specified for each field in which there is a critical shortage, as provided in this section.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in paragraph (5) of this subsection, the Commission shall on a biennial basis:<section prefix="(i)">Identify workforce shortage fields in the State;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Designate eligible workforce shortage fields under the grant program; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Remove from the grant program any field that the Commission determines no longer qualifies as a workforce shortage.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Secretary shall appoint an Advisory Council on Workforce Shortage to:<section prefix="(i)">Identify workforce shortage fields in the State; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Recommend to the Commission:</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">In making recommendations to the Commission, the Advisory Council shall consider whether a workforce shortage field provides a public good or benefit to the citizens of Maryland.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The Advisory Council shall include the following members:<section prefix="(i)">The Secretary of Higher Education or designee;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The Secretary of Labor, Licensing, and Regulation or designee;</section><section prefix="(iii)">One representative from the Governor's Workforce Investment Board, appointed by the Governor;</section><section prefix="(iv)">The Secretary of Business and Economic Development or designee;</section><section prefix="(v)">The Secretary of Health and Mental Hygiene or designee;</section><section prefix="(vi)">The State Superintendent of Schools or designee;</section><section prefix="(vii)">One representative of the Senate of Maryland, appointed by the President of the Senate;</section><section prefix="(viii)">One representative of the Maryland House of Delegates, appointed by the Speaker of the House;</section><section prefix="(ix)">Two representatives from the University System of Maryland, appointed by the Chancellor;</section><section prefix="(x)">The President of Morgan State University or designee;</section><section prefix="(xi)">The President of St. Mary's College or designee; and</section><section prefix="(xii)">Representatives nominated by the following organizations and appointed by the Secretary of Higher Education:</section></section>
      <section prefix="(5)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Except as provided in subparagraph (ii) of this paragraph, the following workforce shortage fields shall be included in the grant program:</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The Commission may remove a shortage field specified in subparagraph (i) of this paragraph if in the Commission's judgment the field no longer qualifies as a workforce shortage field.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(6)">A grant recipient in a workforce shortage field that is removed from the grant program may continue to receive renewal awards under the program.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">Each fiscal year, the Commission shall determine the number of grants to be awarded in eligible workforce shortage fields based on the:<section prefix="(1)">Priority of the workforce shortage field;</section><section prefix="(2)">Severity of the workforce shortage in the field; and</section><section prefix="(3)">Availability of funds.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Office shall annually select eligible students and offer a grant to each student selected to be used at an eligible institution of the student's choice.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Eligible students shall be selected based on academic accomplishment and financial need, as determined by standards established and approved by the Commission.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Each grant shall be renewable for a maximum of 5 years subsequent to the original grant if the recipient:<section prefix="(i)">Continues to meet the qualifications specified in subsection (d) of this section; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Meets satisfactory academic progress standards as determined by the eligible institution.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(h)">A grant recipient:<section prefix="(1)">May be enrolled at an eligible institution on a part-time or full-time basis;</section><section prefix="(2)">Shall earn at least 12 undergraduate or 9 graduate credit hours in each academic year, including summer sessions;</section><section prefix="(3)">Except as provided in paragraph (4) of this subsection, shall be an undergraduate student at an eligible institution; and</section><section prefix="(4)">May be a graduate student if the Office determines that the shortage field requires employees with a graduate level education.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(i)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this subsection, "cost of attendance" means the equivalent annual tuition and mandatory fees of a resident undergraduate student at the 4-year public institution of higher education within the University System of Maryland, other than the University of Maryland University College and University of Maryland, Baltimore, with the highest annual expenses for a full-time resident undergraduate.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Subject to paragraphs (3), (4), and (5) of this subsection, the Commission shall establish in guidelines the annual grant awards under this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Annual grant awards shall be within the following ranges:<section prefix="(i)">For a part-time student attending a 2-year eligible institution - $1,000 and 12.5% of cost of attendance;</section><section prefix="(ii)">For a full-time student attending a 2-year eligible institution - $2,000 and 25% of cost of attendance;</section><section prefix="(iii)">For a part-time student attending a 4-year eligible institution - $2,000 and 25% of cost of attendance; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">For a full-time student attending a 4-year eligible institution - $4,000 and 50% of cost of attendance.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">For a student taking courses during a summer session to meet the minimum number of credit hours for full-time or part-time status, the Commission shall distribute grant awards to the student in the spring and summer sessions in amounts it determines to be appropriate.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">A student who is enrolled in an academic program that includes a mandatory summer academic session as part of the approved curriculum may receive an additional award not to exceed $1,000 per calendar year.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(j)">The grant award may be used at any eligible institution for educational expenses as defined by the Commission, including tuition, mandatory fees, and room and board.</section>
    <section prefix="(k)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A grant recipient shall perform a service obligation in the recipient's field of critical shortage in:<section prefix="(i)">A full-time position at a rate of 1 year for each year that the recipient receives a grant awarded under this section; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">A part-time position at a rate of 2 years for each year that the recipient receives a grant awarded under this section.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Commission may establish alternative service obligation requirements for designated workforce shortage fields to address statewide and regional needs.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(l)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A grant recipient shall repay the Commission the funds received as set forth in &#xA7; 18-112 of this title if the recipient does not:<section prefix="(i)">Earn at least 12 undergraduate or 9 graduate credit hours in each academic year in which the student receives assistance, including summer sessions;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Complete the specified degree, attain the licensure or certification required, or fulfill other requirements as provided in this section; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">Perform the service obligation required under subsection (k) of this section.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Office shall waive the repayment of a grant award at a rate of:<section prefix="(i)">1 year for each year that the recipient performs the service obligation on a full-time basis; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">6 months for each year that the recipient performs the service obligation on a part-time basis.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A recipient shall begin repayment at any time during the period that the recipient is no longer performing the service obligation.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">A recipient may delay repayment as long as the recipient remains a student enrolled at least part-time in a degree-granting program.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">Except as otherwise provided in this section, repayment shall be made to the State within 6 years after the repayment period begins and shall follow a repayment schedule established by the Office.</section>
      <section prefix="(6)">The Office may waive or defer repayment in the event of disability or extended sickness which prevents the recipient from fulfilling the service obligation required under this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(7)">The Office shall grant a deferment from the service obligation required under this section to:<section prefix="(i)">An individual who has been assigned military duty outside the State; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">The spouse of an individual who has been assigned military duty outside the State.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(m)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This subsection applies to recipients of the William Donald Schaefer Scholarship specified in subsection (e)(5) of this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Commission shall annually select eligible students and offer grants to students who demonstrate outstanding potential for and who plan to pursue a career in public service to assist in providing legal services to low-income residents in the State.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">In making William Donald Schaefer Scholarship awards under this section, the Commission shall endeavor to select award recipients who are representative of the State's rich cultural, geographic, racial, ethnic, and gender diversity.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">Each individual awarded a William Donald Schaefer Scholarship under this section must have indicated and demonstrated to the Commission a serious intent to enter public service on the completion of the student's educational program.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(n)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This subsection applies to recipients of the Parren J. Mitchell Public Service Scholarship specified in subsection (e)(5) of this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Commission shall annually select eligible students and offer grants to students who demonstrate outstanding potential for and who plan to pursue a career in public service and assist in providing:<section prefix="(i)">Social work services to low-income residents in the State;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Nursing services in nursing shortage areas in the State as defined in &#xA7; 18-802 of this title; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">Other services in the public or nonprofit sectors in which there is a shortage of qualified practitioners to low-income or underserved residents or areas of the State.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">In making Parren J. Mitchell Public Service Scholarship awards under this section, the Commission shall endeavor to select award recipients who are representative of the State's rich cultural, geographic, racial, ethnic, and gender diversity.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">Each individual awarded a Parren J. Mitchell Public Service Scholarship under this section must have indicated and demonstrated to the Commission a serious intent to enter public service on the completion of the student's educational program.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(o)">
      <section prefix="(1)">There is a Workforce Shortage Student Assistance Grant Fund in the Commission.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Commission:<section prefix="(i)">May accept any gift or grant from any person or corporation for the Workforce Shortage Student Assistance Grant Fund;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Shall use any gift or grant that it receives for a grant award from the Fund; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Shall deposit any gift or grant that it receives for the Fund with the State Treasurer in a nonbudgeted account.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">At the end of the fiscal year, the Commission shall prepare an annual report on the Workforce Shortage Student Assistance Grant Fund that includes an accounting of all financial receipts and expenditures to and from the Fund.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The Commission shall submit a copy of the report to the General Assembly as provided under &#xA7; 2-1246 of the State Government Article.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(p)">A recipient may hold a Workforce Shortage Student Assistance grant and any other State grant or scholarship awarded by the Office provided that the total of all grants and scholarships does not exceed:<section prefix="(1)">The student's total cost of attendance, as certified by the institution where the student is enrolled; and</section><section prefix="(2)">The cost of attendance, as defined in subsection (i) of this section.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(q)">Funds for the Workforce Shortage Student Assistance grant program shall be as provided in the annual budget of the Commission by the Governor.</section>
    <section prefix="(r)">The Commission shall adopt guidelines or regulations necessary to implement this section.</section>
  </text>
</law>
