<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="ged" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="13-505" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ged-13-505</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The EMS Board consists of 11 members appointed by the Governor.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Of the 11 members:<section prefix="(i)">One shall be the Secretary of Health and Mental Hygiene or the Secretary's designee;</section><section prefix="(ii)">One shall be a representative of the University of Maryland, Baltimore, nominated by the Board of Regents;</section><section prefix="(iii)">One shall be the chairperson of the Advisory Council;</section><section prefix="(iv)">One shall be a physician knowledgeable in the delivery of emergency medical services;</section><section prefix="(v)">One shall be a physician experienced in the clinical care of trauma patients;</section><section prefix="(vi)">One shall be a nurse experienced in the clinical care of emergency patients;</section><section prefix="(vii)">One shall be a career firefighter, emergency medical technician, or rescue squad person knowledgeable in the delivery of emergency medical services;</section><section prefix="(viii)">One shall be a volunteer firefighter, emergency medical technician, or rescue squad person knowledgeable in the delivery of emergency medical services;</section><section prefix="(ix)">One shall be a hospital administrator knowledgeable in the management and delivery of emergency medical services; and</section><section prefix="(x)">Two shall be from the public at large, one of whom shall reside in a county with a population of less than 175,000.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Each appointed member shall have demonstrated interest or experience in the delivery of emergency medical services.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">In appointing members to the EMS Board, the Governor shall take into consideration the five emergency medical service regions of the State to assure a geographic balance in the Board's membership.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">In appointing members to the EMS Board, the Governor shall take into consideration persons:<section prefix="(i)">Recommended by the Advisory Council; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">Recommended by any statewide organization or association which is interested and involved in the delivery of emergency medical services.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">Except as authorized under this section, the Governor may not appoint to the EMS Board any other person who is:<section prefix="(i)">A member of the Board of Regents;</section><section prefix="(ii)">A member of the Board of Directors of the Medical System Corporation; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">An officer or full-time employee of the Medical System Corporation or the University.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The term of an appointed member is 4 years.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">At the end of a term, an appointed member continues to serve until a successor is appointed and qualifies.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A member who is appointed after a term has begun serves only for the rest of the term and until a successor is appointed and qualifies.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Annually, from among the members of the EMS Board:<section prefix="(1)">The Governor shall appoint a chairperson; and</section><section prefix="(2)">The chairperson shall appoint a vice chairperson.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
