<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="ged" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="7-704" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ged-7-704</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, "Program" means the Maryland Meals for Achievement In-Classroom Breakfast Program.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">There is a school breakfast program in the State, known as the Maryland Meals for Achievement In-Classroom Breakfast Program.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Program is a joint effort of the Department and the county boards or sponsoring agencies for eligible nonpublic schools.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The purpose of the Program is to provide funding for a school that makes an in-classroom breakfast available to all students in the school.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The funding is intended to complement the funding received by a school from the federal government for a school breakfast program.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Department shall:<section prefix="(1)">Develop an application form for a school that desires to participate in the Program;</section><section prefix="(2)">Ensure that the schools that participate in the Program represent geographic and socioeconomic balance statewide;</section><section prefix="(3)">Ensure that a school that participates in the Program is a school at which at least 40% of the registered students are eligible for the federal free or reduced price meal program;</section><section prefix="(4)">Select schools to participate in the Program, ensuring that an annual evaluation of the Program is conducted by the Department;</section><section prefix="(5)">Annually review and set the meal reimbursement rate for schools that participate in the Program to complement the federal meal reimbursement rate determined under &#xA7; 7-703 of this subtitle; and</section><section prefix="(6)">Disburse the Program funds to the county board or the sponsoring agency.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">A county board or a sponsoring agency for an eligible nonpublic school shall:<section prefix="(1)">Apply to the Department for funds for schools within the jurisdiction of the board or for schools that are under the sponsoring agency that:<section prefix="(i)">Are eligible to participate in the Program; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Apply to the board or to the sponsoring agency to participate in the Program; and</section></section><section prefix="(2)">Submit an annual report to the Department on the Program, including the manner in which the funds have been expended.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">A school that participates in the Program shall:<section prefix="(1)">Implement an in-classroom breakfast program in which all students in the school may participate regardless of family income;</section><section prefix="(2)">Serve a breakfast that meets the guidelines of the Department and the nutritional standards of the United States Department of Agriculture for schools that participate in the federal school breakfast program;</section><section prefix="(3)">Serve the breakfast in the classroom upon the arrival of students to the school;</section><section prefix="(4)">Collect the data that the county board or the sponsoring agency and the Department require from participants in the Program; and</section><section prefix="(5)">Submit an annual report to the county board or the sponsoring agency.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(g)">The employee organization that is the exclusive representative of the certificated public school employees of a county board and the employee organization that is the exclusive representative of the noncertificated employees of a county board and the county board shall negotiate the terms of the participation of the employees in the Program.</section>
  </text>
</law>
