<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ged" order_by="" level="1">Economic Development</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ged-2-202</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>202</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The State Board consists of 11 regular members, and 1 student member, appointed by the Governor with the advice and consent of the Senate.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In making appointments to the State Board, the Governor shall consider representation from:<section prefix="(i)">All parts of this State; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Areas of this State with concentrations of population or unique needs.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The members of the Board shall be appointed from the general public.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The following individuals may not be appointed to the Board:<section prefix="(i)">Except for the student member, any individual who is subject to the authority of the Board;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The Governor; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">The State Superintendent.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The student member shall be selected by the Governor from a list of 2 persons nominated by the Maryland Association of Student Councils.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The student member shall be:<section prefix="(i)">A regularly enrolled student; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">In good standing in a public high school in the State.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The student member may attend and participate in an executive session of the Board.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">	The student member may not vote on any matter that relates to:<section prefix="(i)">The dismissal of or other disciplinary action involving personnel; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">Appeals to the State Board under &#xA7; 2-205, &#xA7; 4-205, or &#xA7; 6-202 of this article.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Each regular member serves for a term of 4 years and until a successor is appointed and qualifies. These terms are staggered as required by the terms of the members serving on the State Board as of July 1, 1989.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Governor shall appoint a new member to fill any vacancy on the Board for the remainder of that term and until a successor is appointed and qualifies.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A member is eligible for reappointment but may not serve for more than two full 4-year terms.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The student member shall serve for a term of 1 year. A student member is eligible for reappointment but may not serve more than two full 1-year terms.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
