<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ged" order_by="ged" level="1">Economic Development</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ged-18-1909</section_number>
  <catch_line>The Board shall establish prepaid contracts under the Trust to provide for the advance payment of tu...</catch_line>
  <order_by>1909</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Board shall establish prepaid contracts under the Trust to provide for the advance payment of tuition at:<section prefix="(1)">A community college;</section><section prefix="(2)">A 4-year college;</section><section prefix="(3)">A university; or</section><section prefix="(4)">Any combination of a community college, college, or university.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">For the purpose of entering into a prepaid contract, either the account holder or the qualified beneficiary must be a resident of Maryland or of the District of Columbia at the time that the account holder enters into the prepaid contract.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">For the purposes of determining residency for the purchase of a prepaid contract:<section prefix="(i)">For residency in Maryland, "resident" has the meaning stated in &#xA7; 10-101 of the Tax - General Article; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">For residency in the District of Columbia, "resident" has the meaning stated in &#xA7; 47-1801.04 of the District of Columbia Code Annotated.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The cost of a prepaid contract shall be based on:<section prefix="(1)">The average current in-State tuition costs at the time the prepaid contract is purchased at public institutions of higher education in the State;</section><section prefix="(2)">The number of years expected to elapse between the purchase of a prepaid contract and the use of the benefits of the prepaid contract; and</section><section prefix="(3)">The projected tuition costs at the time that the benefits will be exercised.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Each prepaid contract made under the provisions of this subtitle shall include the following provisions:<section prefix="(1)">The amount of each payment and the number of payments required from an account holder;</section><section prefix="(2)">The terms and conditions under which account holders shall remit payments, including the dates of the payments;</section><section prefix="(3)">Provisions for late payment charges and defaults;</section><section prefix="(4)">Penalties for early withdrawal from the Trust;</section><section prefix="(5)">The amount and terms of any administrative fees that must be paid by the account holder or the beneficiary;</section><section prefix="(6)">The name and date of birth of the qualified beneficiary on whose behalf the contract is made;</section><section prefix="(7)">Terms and conditions for a substitution for the qualified beneficiary originally named;</section><section prefix="(8)">Terms and conditions for the termination of the prepaid contract;</section><section prefix="(9)">The time period during which the qualified beneficiary may claim benefits from the Trust;</section><section prefix="(10)">The maximum number of undergraduate semester hours that are prepaid under the prepaid contract, based on in-State tuition at a public institution of higher education in the State;</section><section prefix="(11)">All other rights and obligations of the account holder and the Trust; and</section><section prefix="(12)">Any other terms and conditions that the Board considers necessary or appropriate.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The Board shall allow the conversion of a prepaid contract from one tuition plan or payment option to a different tuition plan or payment option.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The Board shall allow excess prepaid contract benefits due to receipt of a scholarship, tuition remission, or early graduation from college to be used toward the payment of other qualified higher education expenses, as specified by the Board, at an eligible institution of higher education.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">The Board shall allow the transfer of funds from the Trust to any other qualified State tuition program or from any other qualified State tuition program to the Trust, in accordance with federal law.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">The Board shall set procedures to ensure that contributions to the Trust plus contributions or payments to other qualified State tuition programs do not exceed a total maximum amount determined by &#xA7; 529 of the Internal Revenue Code for contributions to multiple qualified State tuition programs.</section>
  </text>
</law>
