<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ged" order_by="" level="1">Economic Development</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ged-7-424.3</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>424.3</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Bullying, harassment, and intimidation" means any intentional written, verbal, or physical act, including an electronic communication, that:<section prefix="(i)"><section prefix="1.">Physically harms an individual;</section><section prefix="2.">Damages an individual's property;</section><section prefix="3.">Substantially interferes with an individual's education or learning environment; or</section><section prefix="4.">Places an individual in reasonable fear of harm to the individual's person or property; and</section></section><section prefix="(ii)"><section prefix="1.">Occurs on school property, at a school activity or event, or on a school bus; or</section><section prefix="2.">Substantially disrupts the orderly operation of a school.</section></section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Electronic communication" means a communication transmitted by means of an electronic device, including a telephone, cellular phone, computer, or pager.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">"Nonpublic school" means a nonpublic school that participates in State-funded education programs.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">By March 31, 2012, each nonpublic school shall adopt a policy prohibiting bullying, harassment, and intimidation.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The policy adopted under subsection (b) of this section shall include:<section prefix="(1)">A statement prohibiting bullying, harassment, and intimidation in the school;</section><section prefix="(2)">A statement prohibiting reprisal or retaliation against individuals who report acts of bullying, harassment, or intimidation;</section><section prefix="(3)">A definition of bullying, harassment, and intimidation that is either the same as set forth in subsection (a) of this section or a definition that is not less inclusive than that definition;</section><section prefix="(4)">Standard consequences and remedial actions for persons committing acts of bullying, harassment, or intimidation and for persons engaged in reprisal or retaliation, including:<section prefix="(i)">Specific penalties for persons who repeatedly commit acts of bullying, harassment, or intimidation; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">A requirement that persons who commit acts of bullying, harassment, or intimidation receive educational and therapeutic services concerning bullying prevention;</section></section><section prefix="(5)">Standard consequences and remedial actions for persons found to have made false accusations;</section><section prefix="(6)">Standard procedures for reporting acts of bullying, harassment, or intimidation, including a chain of command in the reporting process;</section><section prefix="(7)">Standard procedures for the prompt investigation of acts of bullying, harassment, or intimidation;</section><section prefix="(8)">Standard procedures for protecting victims of bullying, harassment, or intimidation from additional acts of bullying, harassment, or intimidation, and from retaliation; and</section><section prefix="(9)">Information about the types of support services available to a student bully or victim and any bystanders.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A nonpublic school is encouraged to develop the policy adopted under subsection (b) of this section in consultation with the following groups:<section prefix="(1)">Parents or guardians of students;</section><section prefix="(2)">School employees and administrators;</section><section prefix="(3)">School volunteers; and</section><section prefix="(4)">Students.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">A nonpublic school is encouraged to publicize the policy adopted under subsection (b) of this section in student handbooks, on the school's Web site, and any other location or venue the school determines is necessary or appropriate.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">A nonpublic school is encouraged to develop the following educational programs in its efforts to prevent bullying, harassment, and intimidation:<section prefix="(1)">An educational bullying, harassment, and intimidation prevention program for students, staff, volunteers, and parents; and</section><section prefix="(2)">A teacher and administrator development program that trains teachers and administrators to implement the policy adopted under subsection (b) of this section.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(g)">An employee of a nonpublic school who reports an act of bullying, harassment, or intimidation in accordance with the nonpublic school's policy adopted under subsection (b) of this section is not civilly liable for any act or omission in reporting or failing to report an act of bullying, harassment, or intimidation in accordance with the policy.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">The provisions of this section may not be construed to:<section prefix="(1)">Limit the legal rights of a victim of bullying, harassment, or intimidation; or</section><section prefix="(2)">Require a statewide policy in nonpublic schools relating to bullying, harassment, and intimidation.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
