<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="ged" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="3-110" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ged-3-110</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Anne Arundel County Board consists of 9 members who shall be appointed as follows:<section prefix="(i)">3 from the county at large;</section><section prefix="(ii)">1 each from legislative districts 30, 31, 32, 33, and that portion of legislative district 21 that lies within Anne Arundel County; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">1 student member.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Except for the student member, the Governor shall appoint a member of the county board from a list of nominees submitted by the School Board Nominating Commission of Anne Arundel County as provided in subsection (b) of this section.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">There is a School Board Nominating Commission of Anne Arundel County.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The purpose of the Commission is to select nominees to be recommended to the Governor as qualified candidates for appointment to the Anne Arundel County Board of Education.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">The Commission shall hold at least two public hearings on the selection of nominees before recommending to the Governor nominees for appointment to the county board.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The Commission consists of 11 members who shall be appointed in accordance with this paragraph.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The Governor shall appoint five members, one from each legislative district that lies in whole or in part in Anne Arundel County.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">The County Executive of Anne Arundel County shall appoint one member from the county at large.</section>
        <section prefix="(iv)">The following organizations shall each appoint one member:</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The Governor shall designate as chair of the Commission one of the five members appointed by the Governor under subsection (b)(2)(ii) of this section.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The term of the chair of the Commission is 4 years.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">The Governor may reappoint the chair of the Commission for a second term.</section>
        <section prefix="(iv)">The term of a member of the Commission is 4 years.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The Department of Legislative Services shall provide staff for the Commission.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">Beginning January 1, 2008, for each nomination to the county board, the Commission shall submit to the Governor a list of nominees that contains:<section prefix="(i)">At least two names for each vacancy; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">If there are fewer than two applicants for a vacancy, the number of names that is equal to the number of applicants for the vacancy.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Following the appointment of a member of the Anne Arundel County Board of Education by the Governor, a member may serve for the remainder of the member's term, as provided in &#xA7; 3-108(c) of this subtitle, subject to the approval or rejection of the registered voters of the county at the next general election.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A member of the county board is eligible for nomination and reappointment for a second consecutive term in accordance with the provisions of subsections (a) and (b) of this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The approval or rejection of a member of the county board by the registered voters of the county provided for in subparagraph (ii) of this paragraph shall be a vote for the member's retention or removal.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">On receipt of the notice required under &#xA7; 5-301(h) of the Election Law Article, the name of the member of the county board shall be placed on the appropriate ballot and shown, without opposition, and the voters shall vote for or against the member's retention as a member of the county board.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(4)">If the voters reject the retention of the member, or the vote is tied:<section prefix="(i)">The position shall become vacant 10 days after certification of the election returns; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">The member serves until a successor is appointed and qualifies.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The student member shall:<section prefix="(i)">Be a regularly enrolled senior year student of good character and in good standing in an Anne Arundel County public high school;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Be selected in the student's junior year by a method selected by the Chesapeake Regional Association of Student Councils of Anne Arundel County;</section><section prefix="(iii)"/></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If a vacancy in the position of the student member occurs during the term of the student member, the Chesapeake Regional Association of Student Councils shall:<section prefix="(i)">Conduct a special election at its next general meeting; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">By utilizing the same method that it used to select the previous student member of the board, select another student member to fill the vacancy.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">A board member who does not maintain the residency qualification shall be replaced as a member.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">If the boundary line of a legislative district changes, an incumbent member of the county board who, because of the change, no longer resides in the legislative district from which the member was appointed may complete the term.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The President of the Anne Arundel County Board of Education is entitled to receive $8,000 annually as compensation and, except for the student member, the other board members are entitled to receive $6,000 each annually as compensation.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A student member who completes a full term on the board shall be granted a scholarship of $6,000 to be applied toward the student's higher education costs.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
