<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="ged" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="11-302" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ged-11-302</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The president of each public institution of higher education is responsible for developing a mission statement.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The president shall submit the mission statement to the institution's governing board.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Upon the direction of the governing board, the president shall update the mission statement every 4 years in the year immediately following the quadrennial review of the State Plan for Higher Education as set forth in &#xA7; 11-105 of this title.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The governing board:<section prefix="(i)">Shall review the mission statement and may require the president to prepare a revised mission statement;</section><section prefix="(ii)">May adopt the mission statement as submitted or with amendments; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Shall submit the statement to the Commission.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">In the case of constituent institutions of the University System of Maryland, the Chancellor of the University System of Maryland shall review the statement prior to its consideration by the Board of Regents and make recommendations.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">Before adopting the mission statements, the Board of Regents shall review the statements individually and on a systemwide basis to assure that:</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">The Board shall consolidate the statements into an adopted systemwide statement.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Each regional higher education center shall:<section prefix="(i)">Develop a mission statement;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Submit the mission statement to the governing body of the center; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Upon direction of the governing body, update the mission statement every 4 years in the year immediately following the quadrennial review of the State Plan for Higher Education as set forth in &#xA7; 11-105 of this title.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The governing body of each regional higher education center:<section prefix="(i)">Shall review the mission statement and may require the preparation of a revised mission statement;</section><section prefix="(ii)">May adopt the mission statement as submitted or with amendment; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Shall submit the statement to the Commission.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Commission shall review the mission statement to determine whether the mission statement is consistent with the State Plan for Higher Education.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The mission statement shall be deemed approved within 30 days of receipt unless the Commission finds the statement is not consistent with the State Plan for Higher Education.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">If the Commission finds that the statement is not consistent with the State Plan for Higher Education, the Commission shall return the statement together with its objections that include the specific areas of inconsistency with the State Plan for Higher Education to the governing board.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The governing board and the institution president shall negotiate with the Commission and amend the statement or prepare a new statement.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
