<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ged" order_by="ged" level="1">Economic Development</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ged-16-106</section_number>
  <catch_line>Any full-time classified employee of a community college who enrolls, during his nonworking hours, i...</catch_line>
  <order_by>106</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Any full-time classified employee of a community college who enrolls, during his nonworking hours, in any class at the community college that has at least 10 regularly enrolled students:<section prefix="(1)">Is exempt from payment of tuition; and</section><section prefix="(2)">May not be counted in computing full-time equivalent enrollment at the community college under &#xA7; 16-305 of this title.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">In this subsection, "tuition" means the basic instructional charge for courses offered at a community college.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">"Tuition" does not include:<section prefix="1.">Any fees or costs associated with a self-supporting program; or</section><section prefix="2.">Any fees for:</section></section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Except as provided in paragraph (3) of this subsection, any resident of this State who is 60 years old or older and who enrolls in any class, which is eligible under &#xA7; 16-305 of this title for State support, at the community college:<section prefix="(i)">Shall be exempt from payment of tuition; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Shall be counted in computing full-time equivalent enrollment under &#xA7; 16-305 of this title if enrolled in any class that is eligible for State support.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A community college is required to waive the tuition for a course for senior citizens under this subsection only when course space is available.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">This subsection may not be construed to prohibit a community college board of trustees from offering senior citizens other educational opportunities free of charge, provided that the senior citizen is not counted in computing full-time equivalent enrollment for the purpose of receiving State support.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Any resident of this State who is out of the work force by reason of total and permanent disability who enrolls at a community college in a class that has at least 10 regularly enrolled students:<section prefix="(i)">Is exempt from payment of tuition:<section prefix="1.">For up to 6 credits per semester or up to 12 credits per semester if the individual is enrolled in classes as part of a degree or a certificate program designed to lead to employment; or</section><section prefix="2.">For continuing education instruction designed to lead to employment, including life skills instruction; and</section></section><section prefix="(ii)">Shall be counted in computing full-time equivalent enrollment under &#xA7; 16-305 of this title.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">In order to receive this exemption, an individual who meets the requirements of paragraph (1) of this subsection shall provide the community college with certification from the Social Security Administration, the Railroad Retirement Board, or in the case of a former federal employee, from the individual's federal retirement or pension authority of the individual's:<section prefix="(i)">Total and permanent disability; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Receipt of disability or retirement benefits based on a standard that is at least as stringent as the standard applied by the Social Security Act.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Certification from the Social Security Administration of an individual's receipt of disability or retirement benefits under either Title II or Title XVI of the federal Social Security Act shall satisfy the requirement in paragraph (2)(ii) of this subsection.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">
        <section prefix="(i)">In order to receive this exemption, an individual who meets the requirements of paragraph (1) of this subsection and is enrolled in a degree or certificate program shall submit a timely application for any State or federal student financial aid, other than a student loan, for which the student may qualify.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">Any student financial aid, other than a student loan, received by the student shall be applied first to pay the student's tuition.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">Under this exemption, the waiver shall apply to the difference, if any, between the charge for tuition and the financial aid award, not including a student loan, that the student receives.</section>
        <section prefix="(iv)">On request, the community college shall assist any individual required to submit an application for State or federal student financial aid under this paragraph.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">For purposes of this subsection, "displaced homemaker" is an individual who:<section prefix="(i)">Is 30 years of age or older;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Has worked for the family in the family home;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Is not gainfully employed;</section><section prefix="(iv)">Has had, or would have, difficulty finding employment;</section><section prefix="(v)"><section prefix="1.">Has depended on the income of a family member and has lost that income as the result of separation, divorce, or the death or disability of that family member; or</section><section prefix="2.">Has depended on government assistance as the parent of dependent children and is no longer eligible for such assistance; and</section></section><section prefix="(vi)">Has an annual income that does not exceed:<section prefix="1.">The federal Office of Management and Budget poverty income guidelines; or</section><section prefix="2.">The United States Department of Labor, Bureau of Labor Statistics, 70 percent lower living standard income level.</section></section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Any resident of this State who is a displaced homemaker and who enrolls in any class which is eligible under &#xA7; 16-305 of this title for State support at the community college:<section prefix="1.">Shall be exempt from payment of tuition; and</section><section prefix="2.">Shall be counted in computing full-time equivalent enrollment under &#xA7; 16-305 of this title if enrolled in any class that is eligible for State support.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The exemption of tuition under this section is contingent on the availability of funds under the federal Workforce Investment Act.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Department of Labor, Licensing, and Regulation shall coordinate funds for this Displaced Homemakers Program according to the provisions of Title II of the federal Workforce Investment Act, with the funds to be provided by service delivery areas.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The Secretary of Higher Education shall:<section prefix="(i)">Allocate a minimum of 200 positions for the Displaced Homemakers Program among the community colleges of the State that are located in geographic areas that have been designated by the Governor as service delivery areas in accordance with Section 101 of the federal Workforce Investment Act; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Base the allocation of positions on the number of displaced homemakers in the service delivery area.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(5)">Before January 1 of each year, the State Council for the Maryland Workforce Investment Act shall prepare a report on the Program for the General Assembly.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
