<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ged" order_by="" level="1">Economic Development</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ged-18-406</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>406</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Except as otherwise provided in this section, each recipient of a senatorial scholarship may hold the scholarship for 4 undergraduate academic years and 4 graduate academic years if he:<section prefix="(1)">Is a full-time student;</section><section prefix="(2)">Continues to be a resident of this State; and</section><section prefix="(3)">Continues to be a student at the institution and takes at least 12 semester hours of courses as an undergraduate or 9 semester hours of courses as a graduate student each semester leading to a degree.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A recipient of an undergraduate or graduate senatorial scholarship may hold the scholarship, appropriately prorated, for 8 academic years if he:<section prefix="(1)">Is a part-time student;</section><section prefix="(2)">Continues to be a resident of this State; and</section><section prefix="(3)">Continues to be a student at the institution and takes at least 6 semester hours of courses each semester leading to a degree.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Any recipient of a senatorial scholarship may use up to one-half of the yearly award for summer school.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A recipient of a senatorial scholarship who is enrolled in a terminal certificate program as provided in &#xA7; 18-402(a) of this subtitle may hold the scholarship for 2 years if he is a full-time student and otherwise meets the conditions of subsection (a) of this section, or may hold the scholarship for 4 years if he is a part-time student and otherwise meets the conditions of subsection (b) of this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">Each recipient of a senatorial scholarship who is enrolled in a private postsecondary proprietary institution that is accredited by a national accrediting association approved by the United States Department of Education:<section prefix="(1)">May hold the scholarship for the completion of 1 program if the student otherwise meets the conditions of paragraphs (1) and (2) of subsection (a) of this section; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Shall complete the program within the length of time prescribed by the institution for the completion of the program.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
