<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ged" order_by="ged" level="1">Economic Development</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ged-11-502</section_number>
  <catch_line>There is a Maryland Fire-Rescue Education and Training Commission in the Maryland Higher Education C...</catch_line>
  <order_by>502</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">There is a Maryland Fire-Rescue Education and Training Commission in the Maryland Higher Education Commission.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Commission consists of 13 members appointed by the Governor with the advice and consent of the Senate. Of the members:<section prefix="(i)">Each shall be qualified to deal with the matters within the authority of the Commission;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Six shall be volunteer emergency services personnel or instructors;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Three shall be emergency services instructors who are career personnel representing the academies;</section><section prefix="(iv)">Three shall be career emergency services personnel who are not instructors; and</section><section prefix="(v)">One shall be a member of the general public.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Each member serves for a term of 4 years and until a successor is appointed and qualifies. These terms are staggered as required by the terms of the members serving on July 1, 1978.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A member appointed to fill a vacancy in an unexpired term serves only for the remainder of that term and until a successor is appointed and qualifies.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">A member may be removed by the Governor:<section prefix="(i)">For neglect of duty; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">If the Governor believes the member's continued membership is not in the public interest.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(5)">Each member of the Commission:<section prefix="(i)">Serves without compensation; but</section><section prefix="(ii)">Is entitled to reimbursement for expenses in accordance with the Standard State Travel Regulations.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Governor shall designate one of the members of the Commission as the chairman of the Commission. The chairman serves at the pleasure of the Governor.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Each year, the Commission shall elect a vice chairman and any other officer it requires.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Commission:<section prefix="(i)">Shall meet at least once every 2 months;</section><section prefix="(ii)">May meet at any other time the chairman designates; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">May adopt rules for the conduct of its meetings.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">A quorum consists of 7 members, one of whom shall be the chairman or vice chairman.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
