<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ged" order_by="ged" level="1">Economic Development</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ged-15-106.4</section_number>
  <catch_line>This section applies to the following individuals:...</catch_line>
  <order_by>106.4</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">This section applies to the following individuals:<section prefix="(1)">An active duty member of the United States armed forces;</section><section prefix="(2)">The spouse of an active duty member of the United States armed forces;</section><section prefix="(3)">A financially dependent child of an active duty member of the United States armed forces;</section><section prefix="(4)">An honorably discharged veteran of the United States armed forces; or</section><section prefix="(5)">A member of the National Guard as defined in &#xA7; 13-405(a)(3) of the Public Safety Article.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Notwithstanding any other provision of this article, an individual described in subsection (a) of this section who attends a public institution of higher education in the State is exempt from paying nonresident tuition at a public institution of higher education in this State if:<section prefix="(1)">The active duty member referred to in subsection (a) of this section:<section prefix="(i)">Is stationed in this State;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Resides in this State; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">Is domiciled in this State;</section></section><section prefix="(2)">The honorably discharged veteran presents the following documentation within 4 years after the veteran's discharge:<section prefix="(i)">Evidence that the veteran attended a public or private secondary school in this State for at least 3 years; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Documentation that the veteran graduated from a public or private secondary school in this State or received the equivalent of a high school diploma in this State; or</section></section><section prefix="(3)">The National Guard member described in subsection (a)(5) of this section is a member of the Maryland National Guard and joined or subsequently serves in the Maryland National Guard to:<section prefix="(i)">Provide a Critical Military Occupational Skill; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">Be a member of the Air Force Critical Specialty Code as determined by the National Guard.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Notwithstanding any other provision of this article, a spouse or financially dependent child of an active duty member who enrolls as an entering student in a public institution of higher education and is exempt from paying nonresident tuition under subsection (b) of this section shall continue to be exempt from paying nonresident tuition if:<section prefix="(1)">The active duty member no longer meets the requirements of subsection (b)(1) of this section; and</section><section prefix="(2)">The spouse or financially dependent child remains continuously enrolled at the public institution of higher education.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Commission shall adopt regulations in accordance with Title 10, Subtitle 1 of the State Government Article to implement the provisions of this section.</section>
  </text>
</law>
