<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ged" order_by="" level="1">Economic Development</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ged-23-301</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>301</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Depository library" means a library designated for the receipt and maintenance of State publications.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Depository library" includes:<section prefix="(i)">The State Library Resource Center;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The Maryland Department of Legislative Services Library;</section><section prefix="(iii)">The State Archives;</section><section prefix="(iv)">The Maryland State Law Library;</section><section prefix="(v)">The McKeldin Library of the University of Maryland;</section><section prefix="(vi)">The Library of Congress; and</section><section prefix="(vii)">Any other library designated by the Commission on State Publications Depository and Distribution Program as a depository library.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Program" means the State Publications Depository and Distribution Program.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">"State agency" means any permanent or temporary State office, department, division or unit, bureau, board, commission, task force, authority, institution, State college or university, and any other unit of State government, whether executive, legislative, or judicial, and includes any subunits of State government.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"State publication" means informational materials produced, regardless of format, by the authority of, or at the total or partial expense of any State agency.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"State publication" includes a publication sponsored by a State agency, issued in conjunction with, or under contract with the federal government, local units of government, private individuals, institutions, corporations, research firms, or other entities.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"State publication" does not include correspondence, interoffice and intraoffice memoranda, routine forms or other internal records, publications of bicounty agencies which comply with this program as required in &#xA7; 23-304 of this subtitle, or any informational listing which any State statute provides shall be sold to members of the public for a fee.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
