<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="ged" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="5-207" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ged-5-207</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Aggregate State funding level for the compensatory education formula" means the product of the compensatory education per pupil amount and the statewide compensatory education enrollment count.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Except as provided in subparagraph (ii) of this paragraph, "compensatory education enrollment count" means the number of students eligible for free or reduced price meals for the prior fiscal year.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">For fiscal year 2004, "compensatory education enrollment count" means the greater of:</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(4)">"Compensatory education per pupil amount" means 97% of the annual per pupil foundation amount calculated under &#xA7; 5-202 of this subtitle multiplied by the State share of compensatory education funding.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">"Eligible for free or reduced price meals" means eligible for free or reduced price meals based on eligibility requirements established by the United States Department of Agriculture.</section>
      <section prefix="(6)">"Full-time equivalent enrollment" has the meaning stated in &#xA7; 5-202 of this subtitle.</section>
      <section prefix="(7)">"Local wealth per pupil" means a county's wealth divided by the county's full-time equivalent enrollment.</section>
      <section prefix="(8)">"State share of compensatory education funding" means:<section prefix="(i)">0.29 in fiscal year 2004;</section><section prefix="(ii)">0.37 in fiscal year 2005;</section><section prefix="(iii)">0.41 in fiscal year 2006;</section><section prefix="(iv)">0.46 in fiscal year 2007; and</section><section prefix="(v)">0.50 in fiscal year 2008 and each fiscal year thereafter.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(9)">"Statewide wealth per pupil" means the sum of the wealth of all counties divided by the statewide full-time equivalent enrollment.</section>
      <section prefix="(10)">"Wealth" has the meaning stated in &#xA7; 5-202 of this subtitle.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Each year the State shall distribute compensatory education grants to county boards.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The amount of the compensatory education grant distributed to a county board shall be calculated as provided in this subsection.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">For each county, multiply the compensatory education per pupil amount by the county's compensatory education enrollment count.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">For each county, divide the result calculated under paragraph (2) of this subsection by the ratio, rounded to seven decimal places, of local wealth per pupil to statewide wealth per pupil.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">For each county, multiply the result calculated under paragraph (3) of this subsection for the county by the result, rounded to seven decimal places, that results from dividing the aggregate State funding level for the compensatory education formula by the sum of all of the results calculated under paragraph (3) of this subsection for all counties.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If the amount calculated under subsection (c)(4) of this section for any county is less than the minimum compensatory education grant amount determined under paragraph (2) of this subsection, the State shall distribute an additional grant to the county in the amount by which the minimum compensatory education grant amount exceeds the result calculated under subsection (c)(4) of this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">For purposes of paragraph (1) of this subsection, the minimum compensatory education grant amount for each county is the result obtained by multiplying the compensatory education per pupil amount by the county's compensatory education enrollment count, and multiplying this product by:<section prefix="(i)">0.50 for fiscal year 2004;</section><section prefix="(ii)">0.66 for fiscal year 2005;</section><section prefix="(iii)">0.70 for fiscal year 2006;</section><section prefix="(iv)">0.76 for fiscal year 2007; and</section><section prefix="(v)">0.80 for fiscal year 2008 and each fiscal year thereafter.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
