<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ged" order_by="" level="1">Economic Development</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ged-7-504</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>504</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Department shall adopt regulations that set eligibility guidelines for State funding of Youth Suicide Prevention School Programs under this subtitle.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The regulations shall:<section prefix="(i)">Establish procedures for developing local programs, in cooperation with local education agencies, youth service bureaus, and community mental health centers; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Establish standards and policies for programs to offer:<section prefix="1.">Individual, family, and group counseling related to youth suicide prevention;</section><section prefix="2.">Referral, crisis intervention, and information for students, parents, and school personnel; and</section><section prefix="3.">Training for school personnel, and others responsible for counseling or supervising student activities.</section></section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A Youth Suicide Prevention School Program established under this subtitle shall plan, fund, and implement educational programs, which may include any of the following:<section prefix="(1)">Classroom instruction designed to achieve any of the following objectives:<section prefix="(i)">Encourage sound decision making and promote ethical development;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Increase pupils' awareness of the relationship between drug and alcohol use and youth suicide;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Teach pupils to recognize signs of suicidal tendencies, and other facts about youth suicide;</section><section prefix="(iv)">Inform pupils of available community youth suicide prevention services;</section><section prefix="(v)">Enhance school climate and relationships between teachers, counselors, and pupils; and</section><section prefix="(vi)">Further cooperative efforts of school personnel and community youth suicide prevention program personnel;</section></section><section prefix="(2)">School or community based alternative programs outside of the classroom, including:<section prefix="(i)">Positive peer group programs;</section><section prefix="(ii)">A 24-hour "hotline" telephone service, staffed by trained professional counselors;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Programs to collect data on youth suicide attempts;</section><section prefix="(iv)">Intervention and follow-up;</section><section prefix="(v)">Mental health programs to promote mental health awareness and encourage pupils to seek help as soon as it is needed; and</section><section prefix="(vi)">Parent education and training programs; and</section></section><section prefix="(3)">Teacher training programs.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Any program established under this subtitle shall:<section prefix="(1)">Assist in increasing the awareness, among school personnel and community leaders, of the incidence of teenage suicide;</section><section prefix="(2)">Train school personnel in individual and schoolwide strategies for teenage suicide prevention;</section><section prefix="(3)">Develop and implement school-based teenage suicide prevention programs and pilot projects;</section><section prefix="(4)">Develop and implement school-based pilot mental health programs and peer-to-peer support to address the needs of students suffering from mental illness; and</section><section prefix="(5)">Through cooperative efforts, utilize community resources in the development and implementation of teenage suicide prevention programs under this subtitle.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Department may assist local school systems in implementing pilot peer-to-peer mental health awareness programs.</section>
  </text>
</law>
