<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ged" order_by="ged" level="1">Economic Development</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ged-18-1904</section_number>
  <catch_line>There is a College Savings Plans of Maryland Board....</catch_line>
  <order_by>1904</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">There is a College Savings Plans of Maryland Board.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Board shall administer:<section prefix="(1)">The Maryland Prepaid College Trust established under this subtitle;</section><section prefix="(2)">The Maryland College Investment Plan established under Subtitle 19A of this title; and</section><section prefix="(3)">The Maryland Broker-Dealer College Investment Plan established under Subtitle 19B of this title.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Board consists of the following 10 members:<section prefix="(1)">The Secretary of the Maryland Higher Education Commission;</section><section prefix="(2)">The State Superintendent of Schools;</section><section prefix="(3)">The State Treasurer;</section><section prefix="(4)">The State Comptroller;</section><section prefix="(5)">The Chancellor of the University System of Maryland; and</section><section prefix="(6)">Five members of the public who shall be appointed by the Governor and shall have significant experience in finance, accounting, investment management, or other areas that can be of assistance to the Board.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A member of the Board designated under subsection (c)(1) through (5) of this section may designate an employee from the member's staff to represent the member of the Board, with the full voting rights, powers, and duties of the member.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">Before taking office, each appointee to the Board shall take the oath required by Article I, &#xA7; 9 of the Maryland Constitution.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except for the terms of the initial members of the Board, the term of a public member of the Board is 4 years.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The terms of the public members of the Board are staggered as required by the terms of the members of the Board on October 1, 1998.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">At the end of a term, a public member continues to serve until a successor is appointed and qualifies.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">A public member who is appointed after a term has begun serves only for the remainder of the term and until a successor is appointed and qualifies.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">A public member is eligible for reappointment.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">The Governor may remove a public member for incompetence or misconduct.</section>
  </text>
</law>
