<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="ged" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="5-301" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ged-5-301</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this subtitle, "Interagency Committee" means the Interagency Committee on School Construction established under &#xA7; 5-302 of this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">For the purposes of this section other than subsection (c), the Board of Public Works shall define by regulation what constitutes an eligible and ineligible public school construction or capital improvement cost.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The Board of Public Works shall include modular construction as an approved public school construction or capital cost.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The Board of Public Works, at the recommendation of the Interagency Committee on School Construction, shall adopt regulations that:</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The cost of acquiring land may not be considered a construction or capital improvement cost and may not be paid by the State.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b-1)">The Board of Public Works, in consultation with the Department of General Services and the Department of Housing and Community Development, shall adopt regulations establishing criteria designed to enhance indoor air quality for the occupants of relocatable classrooms purchased or leased using State or local funds, including specifications that:<section prefix="(1)">Require each unit to include appropriate air barriers to limit infiltration;</section><section prefix="(2)">Require that each unit be constructed in a manner that provides protection against water damage through the use of proper roofing materials, exterior sheathing, water drainage systems, and flashing;</section><section prefix="(3)">Require that each unit provide continuous forced ventilation when the unit is occupied;</section><section prefix="(4)">Require each unit to include a programmable thermostat;</section><section prefix="(5)">Require each unit to be outfitted with energy efficient lighting and heating and air-conditioning systems; and</section><section prefix="(6)">Mandate that each unit be constructed with building materials that contain low amounts of volatile organic compounds (VOC).</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The State shall pay the costs in excess of available federal funds of the State share of public school construction projects and public school capital improvements in each county if:<section prefix="(1)">The projects or improvements have been approved by the Board of Public Works; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Contracts have been executed on or after July 1, 1971 for the projects or improvements.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Board of Public Works may adopt regulations for the administration of the programs provided for in this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The regulations adopted by the Board of Public Works may contain requirements for:<section prefix="(i)">The development and submission of long range plans;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The submission of annual plans and plans for specific projects;</section><section prefix="(iii)">The submission of other data or information that is relevant to school construction or capital improvement;</section><section prefix="(iv)">The approval of sites, plans, and specifications for the construction of new school buildings or the improvement of existing buildings;</section><section prefix="(v)">Site improvements;</section><section prefix="(vi)">Competitive bidding;</section><section prefix="(vii)">The hiring of personnel in connection with school construction or capital improvements;</section><section prefix="(viii)">The actual construction of school buildings or their improvements;</section><section prefix="(ix)">The relative roles of different State and local governmental agencies in the planning and construction of school buildings or school capital improvements;</section><section prefix="(x)">School construction and capital improvements necessary or appropriate for the proper implementation of this section;</section><section prefix="(xi)">At the recommendation of the Interagency Committee, the establishment of priority public school construction programs;</section><section prefix="(xii)">Development of cooperative arrangements that permit the sharing of facilities among two or more school systems;</section><section prefix="(xiii)">The selection of architects and engineers by school systems;</section><section prefix="(xiv)">The award of contracts by school systems; and</section><section prefix="(xv)">Method of payments made by the State under the Public School Construction Program.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The regulations adopted by the Board of Public Works shall contain provisions:<section prefix="(i)">Establishing a State and local cost-share formula for each county that identifies the factors used in establishing the formulas;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Requiring local education agencies to adopt educational facilities master plans and annual capital improvement programs;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Providing a method for establishing a maximum State construction allocation for each project approved for State funding;</section><section prefix="(iv)">Referencing the policies stated in &#xA7; 5-7B-07 of the State Finance and Procurement Article;</section><section prefix="(v)">Requiring local school systems to adopt procedures consistent with the minority business enterprise policies of the State as required under the Code of Maryland Regulations;</section><section prefix="(vi)">Establishing a process for the appeal of decisions by the Interagency Committee to the Board of Public Works;</section><section prefix="(vii)">Requiring local education agencies to adopt, implement, and periodically update comprehensive maintenance plans; and</section><section prefix="(viii)">Authorizing the Board of Public Works to withhold State public school construction funds from a local education agency that fails to comply with the requirements of item (vii) of this paragraph.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">In adopting any of these requirements, the State Board and the Board of Public Works shall provide for the maximum exercise of initiative by school personnel in each county to insure that the school buildings and improvements meet both the needs of the local communities and the rules and regulations necessary to insure the proper operation of this section and the prudent expenditure of State funds.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The Board of Public Works shall develop the rules, regulations, and procedures authorized by this section in consultation with representatives of the county boards and the county governing bodies.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The regulations and procedures of the Board of Public Works adopted under this section and their promulgation are exempt from &#xA7; 8-127(b) of the State Finance and Procurement Article.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">With respect to public school construction or public school capital improvements, including sites for school buildings, the authority, responsibilities, powers, and duties of the following are subject to the regulations adopted by the Board of Public Works under this section:<section prefix="(i)">The State Board;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The State Superintendent;</section><section prefix="(iii)">The county governments;</section><section prefix="(iv)">The county boards; and</section><section prefix="(v)">All other State or local governmental agencies under this article.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If, as to public school construction or public school capital improvements, there is any conflict between the regulations and procedures of the Board of Public Works and the authority, responsibilities, powers, and duties of the individuals and agencies specified in paragraph (1) of this subsection, the regulations and procedures of the Board of Public Works shall prevail.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(h)">The obligation of the State to pay the costs of public school construction and public school capital improvements extends only to those projects or parts of projects that comply with the regulations and procedures of the Board of Public Works.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This subsection does not apply to the proceeds from the sale, lease, or disposition of public school buildings constructed under contracts executed before February 1, 1971.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Consistent with &#xA7; 4-115 of this article and regulations adopted by the Board of Public Works to implement &#xA7; 4-126 of this article, the Board of Public Works may require by regulation that the portion of the proceeds received by a county from the sale, lease, or disposal of any public school building that represent State funds provided within 15 years prior to the date of the transaction shall be used solely as part of the State funding of the construction of future public school buildings in the county in which the sale, lease, or disposal occurred, if the public school building was constructed under a contract executed on or after February 1, 1971.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The part of the proceeds from the sale, lease, or disposal of a public school building that fairly represents the appraised value of land and that part of the cost of the public school building that was funded by the county shall remain as the funds of the county.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(j)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Whether by budget bill or supplementary appropriation bill, all money appropriated to carry out the purposes of this section is a separate fund that shall be administered by the State Comptroller in accordance with the regulations adopted by the Board of Public Works.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Except as provided in subparagraph (ii) of this paragraph, any funds approved for a project that has not been contracted for within 2 years of the approval of the project shall revert to the fund established under paragraph (1) of this subsection.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The Interagency Committee, with the approval of the Board of Public Works, may extend the time period under subparagraph (i) of this paragraph if the Interagency Committee determines that unusual circumstances exist.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Any unexpended allocations of funds for previously approved projects shall be transferred to the fund established under paragraph (1) of this subsection.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">On or before March 30, June 30, September 30, and December 31 of each year, the Interagency Committee shall report to the General Assembly, in accordance with &#xA7; 2-1246 of the State Government Article, and the Department of Legislative Services on the balance in the fund as of the reporting date as the result of transfers or reversions required under this subsection and any expenditures.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
