<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="ged" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="15-106.8" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ged-15-106.8</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, "individual":<section prefix="(1)">Includes an undocumented immigrant individual; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Does not include a nonimmigrant alien within the meaning of 8 U.S.C. &#xA7; 1101(a)(15).</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Notwithstanding any other provision of this article, an individual shall be exempt from paying the out-of-state tuition rate at a community college in the State, if the individual:<section prefix="(1)">Beginning with the 2005-2006 school year, attended a public or nonpublic secondary school in the State for at least 3 years;</section><section prefix="(2)">Beginning with the 2007-2008 school year, graduated from a public or nonpublic secondary school in the State or received the equivalent of a high school diploma in the State;</section><section prefix="(3)">Registers as an entering student in a community college in the State not earlier than the 2011 fall semester;</section><section prefix="(4)">Provides to the community college documentation that the individual or the individual's parent or legal guardian has filed a Maryland income tax return:<section prefix="(i)">Annually for the 3 years while the individual attended a public or nonpublic secondary school in the State in accordance with item (1) of this subsection;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Annually during the period, if any, between graduation from a public or nonpublic secondary school in the State and registration at a community college in the State; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Annually during the period of attendance at the community college;</section></section><section prefix="(5)">In the case of an individual who is not a permanent resident, provides to the community college an affidavit stating that the individual will file an application to become a permanent resident within 30 days after the individual becomes eligible to do so;</section><section prefix="(6)">In the case of an individual who is required to register with the Selective Service System, provides to the community college documentation that the individual has complied with the registration requirement; and</section><section prefix="(7)">Registers in a community college in the State not later than 4 years after graduating from a public or nonpublic secondary school in the State or receiving the equivalent of a high school diploma in the State.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Notwithstanding any other provision of this article and subject to subsection (h) of this section, an individual shall be eligible to pay a rate that is equivalent to the resident tuition rate at a public senior higher education institution, if the individual:<section prefix="(1)">Attended a community college not earlier than the 2010 fall semester and met the requirements of subsection (b) of this section, except for the requirement set forth in subsection (b)(3) of this section;</section><section prefix="(2)">Was awarded an associate's degree by or achieved 60 credits at a community college in the State;</section><section prefix="(3)">Provides the public senior higher education institution a copy of the affidavit submitted under subsection (b)(5) of this section;</section><section prefix="(4)">Provides to the public senior higher education institution documentation that the individual or the individual's parent or legal guardian has filed a Maryland income tax return:<section prefix="(i)">Annually while the individual attended a community college in the State;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Annually during the period, if any, between graduation from or achieving 60 credits at a community college in the State and registration at a public senior higher education institution in the State; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Annually during the period of attendance at the public senior higher education institution; and</section></section><section prefix="(5)">Registers at a public senior higher education institution in the State not later than 4 years after graduating from or achieving 60 credits at a community college in the State.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Notwithstanding any other provision of this article, an individual shall be eligible to pay a rate that is equivalent to the in-county tuition rate at a community college in the State if the individual:<section prefix="(1)">Meets the requirements of subsection (b) of this section; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Attends a community college supported by the county in which:<section prefix="(i)">The secondary school from which the individual graduated is located; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">In the case of an individual who received the equivalent of a high school diploma in the State, the secondary school most recently attended by the individual is located.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">Information collected under this section as part of a student's registration shall remain confidential.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A community college or public senior higher education institution that admits an individual who qualifies for the tuition rate under this section shall:<section prefix="(i)">Keep a record of the number of individuals who pay the tuition rate in accordance with the requirements under subsection (b), (c), or (d) of this section; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Report the information required in item (i) of this paragraph to the Commission each year.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Commission shall submit to the General Assembly, in accordance with &#xA7; 2-1246 of the State Government Article, an annual report consisting of a compilation of the reports submitted to the Commission under paragraph (1) of this subsection.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">The governing board of each public institution of higher education shall adopt appropriate policies to implement the provisions of this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">The students that are receiving the tuition rate in subsection (c) of this section may not be counted as in-State students for the purposes of determining the number of Maryland undergraduate students enrolled at a public senior higher education institution.</section>
  </text>
</law>
