<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="ged" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="7-10B-06" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ged-7-10B-06</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Council shall make recommendations regarding:<section prefix="(1)">High quality professional development for teachers and principals regarding digital instruction or blending digital content with traditional classroom instruction;</section><section prefix="(2)">Funding strategies to provide high quality, innovative options in course providers and delivery;</section><section prefix="(3)">Student assessment and accountability;</section><section prefix="(4)">Infrastructure necessary to support digital learning;</section><section prefix="(5)">Mobile learning and mobile learning applications;</section><section prefix="(6)">Aligning resources and digital learning initiatives of all State agencies;</section><section prefix="(7)">Coordination of digital learning programs to prevent redundancy and inefficiency;</section><section prefix="(8)">Planning for changes in technology and digital learning;</section><section prefix="(9)">Expanded curriculum for mathematics, science, foreign language, and advanced placement courses;</section><section prefix="(10)">Increasing education opportunities for at-risk, home-bound, special needs, and alternative education students; and</section><section prefix="(11)">Implementation plans for providing digital learning opportunities to all students in the State</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Council shall perform any other tasks to carry out the mission of the Council.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">On or before December 1 of each year, the Council shall report its recommendations to the State Superintendent and, in accordance with &#xA7; 2-1246 of the State Government Article, the House Committee on Ways and Means and the Senate Education, Health, and Environmental Affairs Committee.</section>
  </text>
</law>
