<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="ged" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="3-501" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ged-3-501</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Charles County Board consists of:<section prefix="(1)">Seven voting members; and</section><section prefix="(2)">One nonvoting student member.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">An individual nominated for a voting membership on the county board shall be a resident and registered voter of Charles County. Any member who no longer resides in Charles County or who is not a registered voter of Charles County may not continue as a voting member of the board.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">All voting members of the Charles County Board shall be elected:<section prefix="(1)">At a general election as required by subsection (d) of this section; and</section><section prefix="(2)">From Charles County at large.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Each voting member serves for a term of 4 years beginning on the third Monday in December after the gubernatorial election and until a successor is elected and qualifies. If the third Monday in December is a legal holiday, the term begins on the first day after the third Monday in December that is not a legal holiday.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The voting members of the county board shall select a qualified individual to fill any vacancy on the board for the remainder of that term and until a successor is elected and qualifies.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">An interview of an applicant for a vacancy on the board shall be conducted by the board at a meeting open to the public.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The board shall publish a list of the names of the applicants for a vacancy on the board at least 2 weeks before the interview of the first applicant is scheduled to occur.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">Public notice of the date, time, and location of each interview shall be published:</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The board is not required to conduct discussions of the applicants or make the final selection of the voting member at a meeting open to the public.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">With the approval of the Governor, the State Board may remove a voting member of the county board for any of the following reasons:<section prefix="(i)">Immorality;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Misconduct in office;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Incompetency; or</section><section prefix="(iv)">Willful neglect of duty.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Before removing a voting member, the State Board shall send the voting member a copy of the charges pending and give the voting member an opportunity within 10 days to request a hearing.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">If the voting member requests a hearing within the 10-day period:<section prefix="(i)">The State Board shall promptly hold a hearing, but a hearing may not be set within 10 days after the State Board sends the voting member a notice of the hearing; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">The voting member shall have an opportunity to be heard publicly before the State Board in the voting member's own defense, in person or by counsel.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">A voting member removed under this subsection has the right to a de novo review of the removal by the Circuit Court for Charles County.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The student member of the Charles County Board shall be an 11th or 12th grade student in the Charles County Public School System.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The student member, and an alternate, shall be selected in accordance with procedures approved by the board. These procedures shall reflect recommendations by and involvement of the Charles County Association of Student Councils.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The term of the student member shall be 1 year.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The student member may not vote, but may indicate a preference for or against any question before the board.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">Unless invited to attend by an affirmative vote of a majority of the county board, the student member may not attend an executive session that relates to special education placements, collective bargaining, or hearings held under &#xA7; 6-202 of this article.</section>
      <section prefix="(6)">The student member may not receive compensation but, after submitting expense vouchers, may be reimbursed for out-of-pocket expenses incurred in connection with official duties approved by the board.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
