<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ged" order_by="" level="1">Economic Development</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ged-18-1106</section_number>
  <catch_line>** IN EFFECT UNTIL JULY 1, 2015 PER CHAPTER 397 OF 2011**...</catch_line>
  <order_by>1106</order_by>
  <text>** IN EFFECT UNTIL JULY 1, 2015 PER CHAPTER 397 OF 2011**<section prefix="(a)">There is a Distinguished Scholar Program for Community College Transfer Students to be awarded by the Office to residents of the State in the manner provided in this section for use at 4-year institutions of higher education in the State.</section><section prefix="(b)">The Office shall annually select the community college students who have the greatest potential for academic success in higher education as determined by criteria established by the Office and offer a scholarship to each of these students to be used at any Maryland 4-year institution of higher education of the student's choice, if the student meets the following qualifications:<section prefix="(1)">Has a community college transcript indicating an overall academic grade point average of at least 3.0 on a 4.0 scale or its equivalent grade point average;</section><section prefix="(2)">Has completed at least 60 credit hours or an associate degree program at a community college in the State;</section><section prefix="(3)">Qualifies as a Maryland resident;</section><section prefix="(4)">Applies the scholarship within 1 year of completing the required credit hours or an associate degree program; and</section><section prefix="(5)">Attends the 4-year institution of higher education as a full-time student.</section></section><section prefix="(c)">The Office shall award scholarships under this section to recipients who have attended community colleges from across the State.</section><section prefix="(d)"><section prefix="(1)">The scholarship award shall be in the amount of $3,000 per academic year.</section><section prefix="(2)">Each award shall be renewable for a maximum of 1 year subsequent to the original award if the recipient:<section prefix="(i)">Continues to meet the qualifications specified in subsection (b) of this section; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Maintains a 3.0 grade point average on an academic year basis.</section></section></section><section prefix="(e)">An award granted under this subtitle may be used for:<section prefix="(1)">Tuition and mandatory fees;</section><section prefix="(2)">Room and board; and</section><section prefix="(3)">Books and supplies.</section></section><section prefix="(f)">This scholarship award is in addition to any other State scholarships that are available to the student.</section></text>
</law>
