<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gel" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="5-1003" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gel-5-1003</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">This section applies to a vacancy in nomination for Representative in Congress, State Senator, or member of the House of Delegates, if the district includes more than one county.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A vacancy in nomination under this section that occurs because the nominee dies, withdraws the candidacy, or is disqualified for any reason shall be filled by:<section prefix="(i)">a vote of the central committees of the political party in each of the counties included in the district of that nominee; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">a State central committee for a nonprincipal political party that does not have local central committees.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The central committee of each county shall cast a vote that is proportionate to its share of the population in that district as reported in the most recent decennial census of the United States and promptly notify its State central committee of the results of its vote.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">If no person receives a majority of the votes cast under paragraph (2) of this subsection, or if there is a tie vote by the central committees, the vacancy in nomination shall be filled by the State central committee.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">In the event of a tie vote, the nominee selected by the State central committee shall be one of the candidates involved in the tie.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(4)">By the later of the 40th day before the general election or the fifth day following the death, declination, or disqualification of the nominee:<section prefix="(i)">the State central committee shall file a certificate of designation for the nominee with the State Board; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">the successor nominee designated by the State central committee under subparagraph (i) of this paragraph shall file a certificate of candidacy with the State Board.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
