<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gel" order_by="gel" level="1">Education</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gel-13-307</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this section the following words have the meanings indicated....</catch_line>
  <order_by>307</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Donation" means the gift or transfer, or promise of gift or transfer, of money or other thing of value to a person that is made for the purpose of furthering electioneering communications.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">"Electioneering communication" means a broadcast, cable, or satellite communication that:<section prefix="1.">refers to a clearly identified candidate or ballot issue;</section><section prefix="2.">is made within 60 days of an election day on which the candidate or ballot issue is on the ballot;</section><section prefix="3.">is capable of being received by 50,000 or more individuals in the constituency where the candidate or ballot issue is on the ballot; and</section><section prefix="4.">is not made in coordination with, or at the request or suggestion of, a candidate, a campaign finance entity of a candidate, an agent of a candidate, or a ballot issue committee.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">"Electioneering communication" does not include:<section prefix="1.">an independent expenditure;</section><section prefix="2.">a news story, a commentary, or an editorial disseminated by a broadcasting station, including a cable television operator, programmer, or producer, or satellite television or radio provider that is not controlled by a candidate or political party;</section><section prefix="3.">a candidate debate or forum; or</section><section prefix="4.">a communication that proposes a commercial transaction.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">For purposes of this paragraph, "clearly identified" means:<section prefix="1.">the name of a candidate appears;</section><section prefix="2.">a photograph or drawing of a candidate appears; or</section><section prefix="3.">the identity of a candidate or ballot issue is apparent by unambiguous reference.</section></section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(4)">
        <section prefix="(i)">"Person" includes an individual, a partnership, a committee, an association, a corporation, a labor organization, or any other organization or group of persons.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">"Person" does not include a campaign finance entity organized under Subtitle 2, Part II of this title.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">After a person makes aggregate disbursements of $10,000 or more in an election cycle for electioneering communications, the person shall file an electioneering communication report as required in this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If the electioneering communications relate to a candidate, the person shall file an electioneering communication report with the State Board on the next date a campaign finance entity of a candidate is required to file a campaign finance report under &#xA7; 13-309 of this subtitle.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If the electioneering communications relate to a ballot issue, the person shall file an electioneering communication report with the State Board on the next date a ballot issue committee is required to file a campaign finance report under &#xA7; 13-309 of this subtitle.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">An electioneering communication report filed under this subsection shall include the information required by subsection (e) of this section for the period from the beginning of the election cycle through the last day of the reporting period under &#xA7; 13-312 of this subtitle that precedes the report filing date.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A person who files an electioneering communication report under subsection (c) of this section shall file an additional electioneering communication report following a date on which the person makes aggregate disbursements of $10,000 or more for electioneering communications following the closing date of the person's previous electioneering communication report.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">An electioneering communication report under this subsection shall:<section prefix="(i)">be filed with the State Board on the date specified in subsection (c)(1) and (2) of this section; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">include the information required by subsection (e) of this section for the period from the closing date of the previous electioneering communication report through the last day of the reporting period under &#xA7; 13-312 of this subtitle that precedes the report filing date.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">An electioneering communication report shall include the following information:<section prefix="(1)">the identity of the person making disbursements for electioneering communications and of any person exercising direction or control over the activities of the person making the disbursements for electioneering communications;</section><section prefix="(2)">the business address of the person making the disbursements for electioneering communications;</section><section prefix="(3)">the amount and date of each disbursement for electioneering communications during the period covered by the report and the person to whom the disbursement was made;</section><section prefix="(4)">the candidate or ballot issue to which the electioneering communications relate;</section><section prefix="(5)">the identity of each person who made cumulative donations in excess of $51 to the person making the disbursements for electioneering communications during the period covered by the report.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">For purposes of this section, a person shall be considered to have made a disbursement for an electioneering communication if the person has executed a contract to make a disbursement for an electioneering communication.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A person who makes a contribution to a campaign finance entity may not be considered to have made a disbursement for electioneering communications under this section because of the contribution.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">The cost of creating and disseminating electioneering communications, including any design and production costs, shall be considered in determining the aggregate amount of disbursements for electioneering communications made by a person under this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">The treasurer or other individual designated by an entity required to file an electioneering communication report under this section:<section prefix="(1)">shall sign each electioneering communication report; and</section><section prefix="(2)">is responsible for filing electioneering communication reports in full and accurate detail.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(i)">
      <section prefix="(1)">An individual is subject to the sanctions that apply to the responsible officers of a campaign finance entity under Part VII of this subtitle for failure to file properly an electioneering communication report.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The failure to provide on an electioneering communication report all of the information required by this section is deemed a failure to file and renders the report overdue as provided in &#xA7; 13-327(b) of this subtitle.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(j)">
      <section prefix="(1)">An entity required to file an electioneering communication report under this section shall do at least one of the following, unless neither are applicable to the entity:<section prefix="(i)">if the entity submits regular, periodic reports to its shareholders, members, or donors, include in each report in a clear and conspicuous manner, the information specified in subsection (e)(3) through (5) of this section for each disbursement for electioneering communications made during the period covered by the report that must be included in an electioneering communication report; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">if the entity maintains an Internet site, post on that Internet site a hyperlink from its homepage to the Internet site where the entity's electioneering communication report information is publicly available.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">An entity shall post the hyperlink required under paragraph (1)(ii) of this subsection within 24 hours of the entity's electioneering communication report information being made publicly available on the Internet.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The hyperlink shall remain posted on the entity's Internet site until the end of the election cycle during which the entity filed an electioneering communication report.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(k)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A person required to file an electioneering communication report under this section shall keep detailed and accurate records of:<section prefix="(i)">all disbursements for electioneering communications made by the person; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">all donations received by the person that are for the purpose of furthering electioneering communications.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Records required to be kept under this subsection shall be preserved until 2 years after the end of the election cycle in which the person filed the electioneering communication report to which the records relate.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(l)">The State Board may adopt regulations as necessary to implement the requirements of this section.</section>
  </text>
</law>
