<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gel" order_by="gel" level="1">Education</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gel-15-106</section_number>
  <catch_line>In accordance with subsection (c) of this section, the State Board shall authorize distribution on a...</catch_line>
  <order_by>106</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">In accordance with subsection (c) of this section, the State Board shall authorize distribution on a continuing basis of one-half of the money in the Fund to eligible gubernatorial tickets in the primary election.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">Distributions shall begin not later than February 1 of the year of the election.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Promptly after the primary election, the State Board shall authorize distribution of the remaining money in the Fund in accordance with subsection (d) of this section.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">If the State Board determines that there is not, or may not be, sufficient money in the Fund to provide a full public contribution to all eligible gubernatorial tickets in a primary or general election, the State Board shall allocate the available money so that each eligible gubernatorial ticket in that election receives a proportionate share of the full public contribution to which the gubernatorial ticket otherwise would be entitled.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The State Board shall authorize distribution of the money that is designated for distribution in the primary election as provided in this subsection.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">An eligible gubernatorial ticket that is opposed in the primary election shall receive $1 in public contributions for each $1 in eligible private contributions it has received.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">An eligible gubernatorial ticket that is unopposed in the primary election shall receive $1 in public contributions for each $3 in eligible private contributions it has received.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The State Board shall authorize distribution for the general election of all money remaining in the Fund, including money remaining from the part designated for the primary election, as provided in this subsection.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Each eligible gubernatorial ticket that is a nominee shall receive an equal share of the Fund.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">An eligible gubernatorial ticket may not receive a public contribution if it is unopposed on the general election ballot.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">An eligible gubernatorial ticket that did not receive a public contribution in the primary election may receive a public contribution in the general election only if the gubernatorial ticket:<section prefix="(i)">is a nominee in the general election; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">did not exceed the expenditure limit for the primary election.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(5)">The State Board shall authorize distribution of public contributions promptly after the certification of primary election results.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
