<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gel" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="13-207" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gel-13-207</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">This section applies to a political committee other than a political club.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A political committee may not receive or disburse money or any other thing of value unless the political committee is established in accordance with the requirements of this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">To establish a political committee:<section prefix="(1)">a chairman and a treasurer shall be appointed on a form that the State Board prescribes and that is signed by the chairman and treasurer and includes:<section prefix="(i)">the residence addresses of the chairman and the treasurer;</section><section prefix="(ii)">if the chairman and treasurer affirmatively consent to receiving notice under this title only by electronic mail, the electronic mail address of the chairman and the treasurer; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">the information required by &#xA7; 13-208 of this subtitle; and</section></section><section prefix="(2)">the form shall be filed with the board where the political committee is required to file campaign finance reports.</section><section prefix="(3)">The chairman or treasurer of a political committee shall notify the State Board of a change in the residence address of the chairman or treasurer no later than 21 days before the day on which the political committee's next campaign finance report is due under &#xA7; 13-309 of this title.</section><section prefix="(4)">The chairman or treasurer of a political committee shall notify the State Board of a change in the electronic mail address of the chairman or treasurer by the date specified in paragraph (3) of this subsection if the chairman and treasurer of the political committee have affirmatively consented to receiving notice under this title only by electronic mail.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A chairman or treasurer of a political committee may resign by completing a resignation form that the State Board prescribes and filing the form with the board where the political committee was established.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If a vacancy occurs in the office of chairman or the office of treasurer, the political committee promptly shall appoint a new chairman or treasurer in accordance with this section.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
