<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gel" order_by="gel" level="1">Education</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gel-13-304</section_number>
  <catch_line>From the date of its organization until its termination under the provisions of this title, a campai...</catch_line>
  <order_by>304</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">From the date of its organization until its termination under the provisions of this title, a campaign finance entity, except a political club, shall file a campaign finance report at the State Board at the times and for the periods required by &#xA7;&#xA7; 13-309, 13-312, and 13-316 of this subtitle.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A campaign finance report submitted using an electronic format shall:<section prefix="(i)">be made under oath or affirmation;</section><section prefix="(ii)">require an electronic signature from the treasurer at the time of the filing of the campaign finance report; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">be made subject to the penalties for perjury.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A campaign finance report filed by a campaign finance entity under subsection (a) of this section shall include:<section prefix="(1)">the information required by the State Board with respect to all contributions received and all expenditures made by or on behalf of the campaign finance entity during the designated reporting period; and</section><section prefix="(2)">the information regarding the occupations and employers of contributors required to be recorded by the treasurer of a campaign finance entity under &#xA7; 13-221 of this title.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A campaign finance report prescribed by this subtitle for the campaign finance entity of a candidate is required whether or not:<section prefix="(1)">the candidate files a certificate of candidacy;</section><section prefix="(2)">the candidate withdraws, declines a nomination, or otherwise ceases to be a candidate;</section><section prefix="(3)">the candidate's name appears on the primary ballot; or</section><section prefix="(4)">the candidate is successful in the election.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
