<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gel" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="3-101" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gel-3-101</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">There shall be a statewide voter registration list.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The statewide voter registration list shall:<section prefix="(1)">be the official voter registration list for the State;</section><section prefix="(2)">contain the name and other information for every legally registered voter in the State;</section><section prefix="(3)">allow each local board to obtain immediate electronic access to the information contained in the list;</section><section prefix="(4)">be coordinated with other agency databases in the State;</section><section prefix="(5)">be used to produce precinct registers for use in polling places on election day; and</section><section prefix="(6)">include voting history information on a current basis for a period covering at least the 5 preceding years.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The State Administrator shall:<section prefix="(1)">define, maintain, and administer the statewide voter registration list;</section><section prefix="(2)">with the local boards, ensure the currency and accuracy of each individual voter's registration record;</section><section prefix="(3)">instruct the local boards on:<section prefix="(i)">processing voter registration applications and name and address changes;</section><section prefix="(ii)">entering voter registration information into the statewide voter registration list; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">removing from the statewide voter registration list information about voters who are no longer eligible to be registered voters; and</section></section><section prefix="(4)">subject to relevant federal law and to regulations adopted by the State Board, establish and conduct a program to identify voters who have changed their addresses.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Registration shall be conducted continuously under the supervision of the State Administrator and in accordance with the provisions of this title, applicable federal law, and regulations adopted by the State Board.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A State agency shall provide any data to the State Board that the State Administrator determines is necessary to maintain an accurate statewide voter registration list.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Subject to paragraph (3) of this subsection, the State Board may not disclose data provided under paragraph (1) of this subsection except as provided in Title 10, Subtitle 6, Part III of the State Government Article.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The State Board may enter into agreements with other states to exchange any data that the State Administrator determines is relevant to maintaining accurate voter registration lists.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The State Board may exchange data that is not subject to public disclosure under Title 10, Subtitle 6, Part III of the State Government Article with other persons as the State Administrator determines is necessary for the sole purpose of maintaining accurate voter registration lists.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">A person who receives data that is not subject to public disclosure under Title 10, Subtitle 6, Part III of the State Government Article under this paragraph may not use or redisclose that data except for the purpose of maintaining accurate voter registration lists.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">A registered voter:<section prefix="(1)">shall remain registered when the voter moves to another county in the State; and</section><section prefix="(2)">may not be required to register again unless the voter's registration is canceled in accordance with Subtitle 5 of this title.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
