<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gel" order_by="gel" level="1">Education</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gel-3-505</section_number>
  <catch_line>The State Board shall adopt regulations for the retention and storage of and reasonable access to or...</catch_line>
  <order_by>505</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The State Board shall adopt regulations for the retention and storage of and reasonable access to original voter registration applications and other voter registration records the State Board considers appropriate.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Voter registration records stored and retained in a local board office shall be open to public inspection.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">For the purpose of public inspection, original voter registration records:<section prefix="(i)">subject to &#xA7; 4-527(b) of the Family Law Article and except upon the special order of the local board, shall be available at all times when a local board is open; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">may not be removed from the office of the local board except:<section prefix="1.">on order of a court; or</section><section prefix="2.">for temporary removal solely for purposes of data processing.</section></section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Consistent with regulations adopted by the State Board, local boards shall maintain for at least 2 years all records concerning programs to ensure the accuracy and currency of the statewide voter registration list.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Except for records concerning a declination to register or the identity of a voter registration agency through which a particular voter applies for registration, the records described in paragraph (1) of this subsection are accessible under Title 10, Subtitle 6, Part III of the State Government Article (Access to Public Records).</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
