<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gel" order_by="" level="1">Education</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gel-13-218</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>218</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">All assets received by or on behalf of a campaign finance entity shall be:<section prefix="(1)">delivered to the treasurer; and</section><section prefix="(2)">maintained by the treasurer for the purposes of the campaign finance entity.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Assets of a campaign finance entity may be disbursed only:<section prefix="(i)">if they have passed through the hands of the treasurer; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">in accordance with the purposes of the entity.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Subject to &#xA7; 13-220(b)(2) and (c) of this subtitle and except as provided in subsection (d) of this section, the treasurer shall make all disbursements for the campaign finance entity.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The treasurer of a State or county central committee of a political party may not make any disbursement of the central committee's assets, or incur any liability on its behalf, without authority and direction from the chairman of the central committee.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If the treasurer of a campaign finance entity is temporarily unable to perform the duties of the office, the chairman of the campaign finance entity may make a disbursement on behalf of the campaign finance entity in the same manner as the treasurer.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If the chairman makes a disbursement under this subsection, within 7 days after making the disbursement, the chairman shall submit a report to the treasurer for the account book of the campaign finance entity, including:<section prefix="(i)">a statement of the expenditure made under the authority of the chairman;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the name and address of the person to whom the expenditure was made;</section><section prefix="(iii)">the purpose for which the expenditure was made; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">a copy of the receipt for the expenditure that was made.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A chairman who is a candidate may not make a disbursement for a campaign finance entity.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
