<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gel" order_by="" level="1">Education</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gel-9-102</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>102</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, a "voter-verifiable paper record"  includes:<section prefix="(1)">a paper ballot prepared by the voter for the  purpose of being read by a precinct-based optical scanner;</section><section prefix="(2)">a paper ballot prepared by the voter to be mailed to  the applicable local board, whether mailed from a domestic or an  overseas location; and</section><section prefix="(3)">a paper ballot created through the use of a ballot  marking device.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The State Board shall adopt regulations for the review,  certification, and decertification of voting systems.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The State Board shall periodically review and evaluate alternative  voting systems.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The State Board may not certify a voting system unless the State  Board determines that:<section prefix="(1)">the voting system will:<section prefix="(i)">protect the secrecy of the ballot;</section><section prefix="(ii)">protect the security of the voting process;</section><section prefix="(iii)">count and record all votes accurately;</section><section prefix="(iv)">accommodate any ballot used under this article;</section><section prefix="(v)">protect all other rights of voters and candidates;</section><section prefix="(vi)">be capable of creating a paper record of all votes cast in  order that an audit trail is available in the event of a recount, including a manual  recount; and</section><section prefix="(vii)">provide a voter-verifiable paper record that:<section prefix="1.">is an individual document that is  physically separated from any other similar document and not part  of a continuous roll;</section><section prefix="2.">is sufficiently durable to withstand  repeated handling for the purposes of mandatory random audits  and recounts; and</section><section prefix="3.">uses ink that does not fade, smear, or  otherwise degrade and obscure or obliterate the paper record  over time;</section></section></section><section prefix="(2)">the voting system has been:<section prefix="(i)">examined by an independent testing laboratory that is  approved by the U.S. Election  Assistance Commission; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">shown by the testing laboratory to meet the performance  and test standards for electronic voting systems established by the Federal Election  Commission or the U.S. Election Assistance Commission; and</section></section><section prefix="(3)">the public interest will be served by the certification of the voting  system.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">In determining whether a voting system meets the required  standards, the State Board shall consider:<section prefix="(1)">the commercial availability of the system and its replacement parts  and components;</section><section prefix="(2)">the availability of continuing service for the system;</section><section prefix="(3)">the cost of implementing the system;</section><section prefix="(4)">the efficiency of the system;</section><section prefix="(5)">the likelihood that the system will malfunction;</section><section prefix="(6)">the system's ease of understanding for the voter;</section><section prefix="(7)">the convenience of voting afforded by the system;</section><section prefix="(8)">the timeliness of the tabulation and reporting of election returns;</section><section prefix="(9)">the potential for an alternative means of verifying the tabulation;</section><section prefix="(10)">accessibility for all voters with disabilities recognized by the Americans with Disabilities Act; and</section><section prefix="(11)">any other factor that the State Board considers relevant.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">A voting system selected, certified, and implemented under this section shall:<section prefix="(1)">provide access to voters with disabilities that is equivalent to access afforded voters without disabilities without creating a segregated ballot for voters with disabilities;</section><section prefix="(2)">ensure the independent, private casting, inspection, verification, and correction of secret ballots by voters with disabilities in an accessible media by both visual and nonvisual means, including synchronized audio output and enhanced visual display; and</section><section prefix="(3)">comply with both the Americans with Disabilities Act, P.L. 101-336, and the Help America Vote Act, P.L. 107-252, including accessibility standards adopted as part of the Voluntary Voting System Guidelines pursuant to the Help America Vote Act.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">At least one voting system in each polling place  on election day shall provide access for voters with disabilities in compliance with subsection (f) of this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The State Board shall ensure that adequate backup equipment is available and contingency plans are established to ensure compliance with paragraph (1) of this subsection.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(h)">Before the selection of a voting system, the State Board shall:<section prefix="(1)">ensure that an accessible voting system conforms to the access requirements of the Voluntary Voting System Guidelines developed in accordance with the Help America Vote Act in effect at the time of selection; and</section><section prefix="(2)">conduct an accessibility and usability evaluation of the voting system to assess its accessibility and usability by voters with disabilities, including:<section prefix="(i)">a public demonstration of the system; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">an evaluation by individuals representing a cross-section of voters with disabilities.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(i)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The State Board shall adopt regulations relating to  requirements for each voting system selected and certified under &#xA7; 9-101 of this  subtitle.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The regulations shall specify the procedures necessary to assure  that the standards of this title are maintained, including:<section prefix="(i)">a description of the voting system;</section><section prefix="(ii)">a public information program by the local board, at the time  of introduction of a new voting system, to be directed to all voters, candidates,  campaign groups, schools, and news media in the county;</section><section prefix="(iii)">local election officials' responsibility for management of the  system;</section><section prefix="(iv)">the actions required to assure the security of the voting  system;</section><section prefix="(v)">the supplies and equipment required;</section><section prefix="(vi)">the storage, delivery, and return of the supplies and  equipment necessary for the operation of the voting system;</section><section prefix="(vii)">standards for training election officials in the operation and  use of the voting system;</section><section prefix="(viii)">before each election and for all ballot styles to be used,  testing by the members of the local board to ensure the accuracy of tallying,  tabulation, and reporting of the vote, and observing of that testing by representatives  of political parties and of candidates who are not affiliated with political parties;</section><section prefix="(ix)">the number of voting stations or voting booths required in  each polling place, in relation to the number of registered voters assigned to the  polling place;</section><section prefix="(x)">the practices and procedures in each polling place  appropriate to the operation of the voting system;</section><section prefix="(xi)">assuring ballot accountability in systems using a document  ballot;</section><section prefix="(xii)">the actions required to tabulate votes; and</section><section prefix="(xiii)">postelection review and audit of the system's output.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Certification of a voting system is not effective until the  regulations applicable to the voting system have been adopted.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
