<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gel" order_by="gel" level="1">Education</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gel-13-241</section_number>
  <catch_line>An employer may establish a program for collecting from employees by means of payroll deductions vol...</catch_line>
  <order_by>241</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">An employer may establish a program for collecting from employees by means of payroll deductions voluntary contributions to one or more campaign finance entities selected by the employer.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Periodic contributions collected by payroll deductions under a program established under subsection (a) of this section shall be combined and accumulated in a segregated escrow account maintained solely for that purpose.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">An employer shall keep detailed and accurate records of each payroll deduction made under subsection (a) of this section, including:<section prefix="(1)">the name and address of the contributor;</section><section prefix="(2)">the date on which the contribution is withheld;</section><section prefix="(3)">the amount of the contribution; and</section><section prefix="(4)">the disposition of the contribution.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Within 3 months after withholding a contribution under this section, the employer shall transmit the contribution to the appropriate campaign finance entity, together with the information recorded under subsection (c)(1), (2), and (3) of this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">In soliciting an employee to make a contribution to a campaign finance entity by payroll deduction, an employer shall inform the employee of:<section prefix="(1)">the political purposes of the campaign finance entity; and</section><section prefix="(2)">the employee's right to refuse to contribute to the campaign finance entity without reprisal.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">An employer may not receive or use money or anything of value under this section if it is obtained:<section prefix="(1)">by actual or threatened:<section prefix="(i)">physical force;</section><section prefix="(ii)">job discrimination; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">financial reprisal; or</section></section><section prefix="(2)">as:<section prefix="(i)">a result of a commercial transaction; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">dues, fees, or other assessment required as a condition of membership in a labor organization or employment.</section></section></section>
  </text>
</law>
