<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gel" order_by="gel" level="1">Education</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gel-5-301</section_number>
  <catch_line>An individual may become a candidate for a public or party office only if:...</catch_line>
  <order_by>301</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">An individual may become a candidate for a public or party office only if:<section prefix="(1)">the individual files a certificate of candidacy in accordance with this subtitle; and</section><section prefix="(2)">the individual does not file a certificate of withdrawal under Subtitle 5 of this title.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The appropriate board shall determine whether an individual filing a certificate of candidacy meets the requirements of this article, including:<section prefix="(1)">the voter registration and party affiliation requirements under Subtitle 2 of this title; and</section><section prefix="(2)">the campaign finance reporting requirements under Title 13 of this article.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">On the certificate of candidacy, a candidate shall designate how the candidate's name is to appear on the ballot.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Except as provided in paragraph (3) of this subsection, a candidate shall file a certificate of candidacy in which the candidate lists any given name, an initial letter of any other given name, and surname.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A candidate may file a certificate of candidacy in a name different than that specified under paragraph (2) of this subsection if the candidate files an affidavit, under penalties of perjury, attesting that the candidate is generally known by that other name in:<section prefix="(i)">press accounts concerning the candidate, if any; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">if press accounts do not exist, the candidate's everyday encounters with members of the community.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">Except for the use of quotation marks to enclose a portion of a name, the use of symbols, titles, degrees, or other professional designations on a certificate of candidacy is prohibited.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A candidate who seeks nomination by petition shall file a certificate of candidacy as provided in &#xA7; 5-703 of this title.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">A write-in candidate shall file a certificate of candidacy as provided under this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">On or before August 31 in the year in which a judge of the Court of Appeals must stand for continuance in office, the Clerk of the Court of Appeals shall provide written notice to the State Board of the name of the judge that is to be placed on the ballot at the next succeeding general election together with the identification of the judicial circuit from which the qualified voters of that circuit may cast a vote for the judge's continuance in office.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">On or before August 31 in the year in which a judge of the Court of Special Appeals must stand for continuance in office, the Clerk of the Court of Special Appeals shall provide written notice to the State Board of the name of the judge that is to be placed on the ballot at the next succeeding general election together with:<section prefix="1.">the identification of the judicial circuit from which the qualified voters of that circuit may cast a vote for the judge's continuance in office; or</section><section prefix="2.">a statement that the voters of the entire State may cast a vote for the judge's continuance in office.</section></section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">An incumbent judge of the Court of Appeals or Court of Special Appeals is not required to file a certificate of candidacy for an election for continuance in office.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A candidate for President or Vice President of the United States nominated by a national party convention is not required to file a certificate of candidacy under this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If more than one written notice naming different presidential and vice presidential nominees is provided to the State Board by persons purporting to be the presiding officer of the same party convention, the State Board shall require the chairman of the State party to provide written reaffirmation of the party's nominees within 5 days after the State Board's demand.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(h)">
      <section prefix="(1)">On or before August 31 in the year in which a member of the Anne Arundel County Board of Education must stand for continuance in office, the Anne Arundel County Board of Education shall provide written notice to the State Board of the name of the member that is to be placed on the ballot at the next succeeding general election.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">An incumbent member of the Anne Arundel County Board of Education is not required to file a certificate of candidacy for an election for continuance in office.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
