<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gel" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="13-221" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gel-13-221</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The treasurer of a campaign finance entity shall keep a detailed and accurate account book of all assets received, expenditures made, and obligations incurred by or on behalf of the entity.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Except as provided in &#xA7; 13-240 of this subtitle, as to each asset received or expenditure made, the account book shall state:<section prefix="(i)">its amount or value;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the date of the receipt or expenditure;</section><section prefix="(iii)">the name and address of the person from whom the asset was received or to whom the expenditure was made; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">a description of the asset received or the purpose for which the expenditure was made.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">To the extent practicable, the treasurer of a campaign finance entity shall record the occupation and employer of an individual who makes contributions to the campaign finance entity in a cumulative amount of $500 or more during an election cycle.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The State Board shall:</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(4)">Each expenditure made from a campaign account shall be supported by a receipt.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The account books and related records of a campaign finance entity shall be preserved until the earlier of:<section prefix="(1)">10 years after the creation of an account book entry or related record; or</section><section prefix="(2)">2 years after the campaign finance entity files a final campaign finance report under Subtitle 3 of this title.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
