<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gel" order_by="gel" level="1">Education</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gel-4-202</section_number>
  <catch_line>A principal political party shall elect the members of the county central committee at a primary ele...</catch_line>
  <order_by>202</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A principal political party shall elect the members of the county central committee at a primary election.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Except as otherwise provided in this section or &#xA7; 4-203 of this subtitle, the central committee for a county shall consist of the number of members determined by the party's constitution.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, the party central committee for each county shall select the chairman of that county's party central committee.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">In Baltimore County, the Chairman of the Republican Party Central Committee shall be elected by the members of the central committee from among its members and in accordance with its bylaws.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">An individual elected to serve as a member of a party central committee shall be a resident of the county in which that central committee is located.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">An individual elected from a county who ceases to reside in that county shall be considered to have resigned and may not continue to serve on the central committee.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">An individual elected from a specific legislative district who ceases to reside in that district shall be considered to have resigned and may not continue to serve on the central committee.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">An individual selected to fill a vacancy in a party central committee shall be a resident of the county in which that central committee is located.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">An individual selected to fill a vacancy of a member elected from a specific legislative district in a party central committee shall be a resident of that legislative district.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Upon relinquishing residency in the county or legislative district in which a member of a party central committee was selected to fill a vacancy, the member shall be considered to have resigned.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, a vacancy in the party central committee for a county, or for a legislative district of Baltimore City, Anne Arundel County, or Baltimore County, shall be filled by the remaining members of the committee elected from that county or legislative district.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If a political party does not have county central committees or central committees for legislative districts, vacancies shall be filled in accordance with party rules.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, the tenure in office of a member of the central committee of any political party shall:<section prefix="(i)">begin at the time the results of that election are certified; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">continue to the extent of any extension in time between primary elections by reason of any change in the date of holding primary elections by a political party in the State.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The tenure in office of a member of the Republican Party Central Committee shall begin on the 14th day following the gubernatorial general election.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">For purposes of this subsection, upon relinquishing residency in the county, a member of a party central committee shall be considered to have resigned.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
