<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gel" order_by="gel" level="1">Education</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gel-13-401</section_number>
  <catch_line>Except as otherwise provided in this section, each item of campaign material shall contain, set apar...</catch_line>
  <order_by>401</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as otherwise provided in this section, each item of campaign material shall contain, set apart from any other message, an authority line that states:<section prefix="(i)">as to campaign material published or distributed by a campaign finance entity:<section prefix="1.">the name and address of the treasurer of each campaign finance entity responsible for the campaign material; and</section><section prefix="2.">as to each treasurer named under item 1 of this item, the name of each campaign finance entity for which the treasurer is acting; and</section></section><section prefix="(ii)">as to campaign material published or distributed by any other person, the name and address of the person responsible for the campaign material.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The authority line may omit an address that is on file with the State Board or a local board.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">If the campaign material is too small to include all the information specified in paragraph (1) of this subsection in a legible manner, the authority line need only contain the name and title of the treasurer or other person responsible for it.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The authority line for campaign material that is a commercial advertisement need only contain the information specified in paragraphs (1) and (2) of this subsection for one campaign finance entity or other person responsible for the advertisement.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Campaign material that is published or distributed in support of or in opposition to a candidate, but is not authorized by the candidate, shall include the following statement:</section>
  </text>
</law>
