<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gel" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="10-205" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gel-10-205</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A local board may fix the compensation of election judges within the limits authorized for this purpose by the county's governing body.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A local board shall pay an election judge for each election day and each early voting day that the election judge actually serves.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In Allegany County, the compensation for each day actually served may not be less than:<section prefix="(i)">$100 per day for each chief election judge; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">$80 per day for every other election judge.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">In Baltimore City, the compensation for each election day or early voting day actually served shall be:</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)"/>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">In Baltimore County, the compensation for each election day or early voting day actually served shall be:<section prefix="(i)">$225 per day for each chief election judge; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">$162.50 per day for every other election judge.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">In Calvert County, the compensation for each election day or early voting day actually served shall be:<section prefix="(i)">$125 per day for each chief election judge; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">$100 per day for every other election judge.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(5)">In Harford County, the compensation for each election day or early voting day actually served shall be:<section prefix="(i)">not less than $160 per day for each chief election judge; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">not less than $125 per day for every other election judge.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(6)">
        <section prefix="(i)">In Prince George's County, the compensation for each election day or early voting day actually served shall be not less than:</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)"/>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(7)">
        <section prefix="(i)">In Washington County, the compensation for each election day or early voting day actually served shall be:</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">In Washington County, a chief election judge or election judge who successfully completes a course of instruction in poll working shall be eligible for additional compensation, if approved by the Washington County Board and provided for in the county budget.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
