<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gel" order_by="gel" level="1">Education</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gel-3-506</section_number>
  <catch_line>A copy of a list of registered voters shall be provided to a Maryland registered voter on receipt of...</catch_line>
  <order_by>506</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A copy of a list of registered voters shall be provided to a Maryland registered voter on receipt of:<section prefix="(i)">a written application; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">a statement, signed under oath, that the list is not intended to be used for:<section prefix="1.">commercial solicitation; or</section><section prefix="2.">any other purpose not related to the electoral process.</section></section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">In consultation with the local boards, the State Board shall adopt regulations that specify:<section prefix="(i)">the time for a list to be provided under this subsection;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the authorization to be required for providing a list;</section><section prefix="(iii)">the fee to be paid for providing a list;</section><section prefix="(iv)">the information to be included on a list;</section><section prefix="(v)">the format of the information; and</section><section prefix="(vi)">the medium or media on which the information is to be provided.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The State Administrator or a designee shall provide a copy of the statewide voter registration list and voter registration records to a jury commissioner on request and without charge by means agreed to with the Administrative Office of the Courts.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">On application of the Attorney General, a circuit court may compel compliance with paragraph (1) of this subsection.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A person who knowingly allows a list of registered voters, under the person's control, to be used for any purpose not related to the electoral process is guilty of a misdemeanor and, on conviction, is subject to the penalties under Title 16 of this article.</section>
  </text>
</law>
