<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gel" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="5-903" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gel-5-903</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If a candidate for Lieutenant Governor dies, withdraws the candidacy, or becomes disqualified for any reason after the deadline for filing a certificate of candidacy for a primary election under &#xA7; 5-303 of this title, the remaining candidate for Governor of that unit may designate a successor candidate for Lieutenant Governor.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Provided the successor candidate for Lieutenant Governor files a certificate of candidacy in accordance with subsection (b) of this section, the name of the successor candidate for Lieutenant Governor shall appear on the ballot.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The successor candidate for Lieutenant Governor designated by the candidate for Governor under subsection (a) of this section shall file a certificate of candidacy with the State Board.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The certificate of candidacy shall be filed:<section prefix="(i)">by the fifth day following the withdrawal deadline specified under &#xA7; 5-502 of this title, if the former Lieutenant Governor candidate files a certificate of withdrawal;</section><section prefix="(ii)">by the fifth day following the death or disqualification of the former Lieutenant Governor candidate, if that former candidate dies or is disqualified less than 45 days before the day of the primary election; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">not later than 40 days before the day of the primary, if the former Lieutenant Governor candidate dies or is disqualified 45 days or more before the day of the primary election.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A certificate of candidacy for a successor candidate for Lieutenant Governor under subsection (b)(2)(ii) of this section may not be filed less than 10 days before the day of the primary election.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">If the death or disqualification of a former Lieutenant Governor candidate occurs less than 10 days before the day of the primary election, the existing Governor and Lieutenant Governor unit whose filing is complete:<section prefix="(1)">shall remain on the ballot; and</section><section prefix="(2)">if nominated, a vacancy in the nomination of the candidate for Lieutenant Governor shall be declared and be filled under &#xA7; 5-1005(b) of this title as if the death or disqualification had occurred after the primary election.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
