<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gel" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="9-503" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gel-9-503</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The local board shall establish voting centers for the use of any eligible voter who chooses to cast a ballot in person in a special election in accordance with this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In a special election held in a single county council district, at least  one voting center shall be established in the county council district where the special election is being held.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">In a countywide special election, at least  one voting center shall be established in each county council district.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A  voting center established under this section shall:<section prefix="(1)">provide access to a voting system that is accessible to voters with disabilities in accordance with the federal Americans with Disabilities Act and the federal Help America Vote Act;</section><section prefix="(2)">provide for provisional voting in accordance with Subtitle 4 of this title;</section><section prefix="(3)">satisfy the requirements of &#xA7; 10-101 of this article; and</section><section prefix="(4)">be open for voting  during the days and for the hours that the county council directs in the resolution under &#xA7; 9-501(c) of this subtitle.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">If necessary to expedite the conduct of a special election and subject to the approval of the State Board, the local board may establish a polling place under this section during a period when a change in polling places is prohibited under &#xA7; 2-303 of this article.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The process for applying in person for an absentee ballot at the office of a local board under &#xA7; 9-305(c) of this title does not apply to a special election conducted by mail.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">Except as otherwise provided in this section, any provision of this article that applies to voting at a polling place on election day also applies to voting at a voting center established under this section.</section>
  </text>
</law>
