<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gel" order_by="gel" level="1">Education</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gel-13-604</section_number>
  <catch_line>A person who violates a provision of this title without knowing that the act is illegal shall pay a ...</catch_line>
  <order_by>604</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A person who violates a provision of this title without knowing that the act is illegal shall pay a civil penalty in accordance with subsections (b) through (g) of this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The penalty imposed under this section may not exceed $5,000.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">An infraction described in paragraph (1) of this subsection is a civil offense.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">This section does not apply to a violation of another section in which a penalty is expressly provided.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If the State Prosecutor or the State's Attorney with jurisdiction determines that a person unintentionally, and without criminal intent, has violated a provision of this title, the State Prosecutor, the State's Attorney, or both, shall issue to the person a civil citation that contains:<section prefix="(i)">the name and address of the person cited;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the nature, time, and place of the violation;</section><section prefix="(iii)">the manner in which the violation occurred;</section><section prefix="(iv)">the maximum penalty for the violation;</section><section prefix="(v)">the manner and time in which to pay the penalty;</section><section prefix="(vi)">where to pay the penalty; and</section><section prefix="(vii)">a statement that the person receiving the citation has a right to a trial in the District Court.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The prosecuting authority who issues a citation under paragraph (1) of this subsection shall file it in the District Court.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The citation shall be served in accordance with the Maryland Rules.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">On receipt of the return of service, the District Court shall schedule the case for trial and notify the person named in the citation of the trial date.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The trial in the District Court shall be conducted in the same manner as set forth for municipal infractions under Article 23A, &#xA7; 3(b)(8) through (15) of the Code.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The District Court shall remit to the State Board all late fees collected.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">An adjudication of a violation under this subsection:<section prefix="(i)">is not a criminal conviction; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">does not carry with it any of the civil disabilities that arise from a criminal conviction.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">A person who is adjudicated in violation as set forth in a citation issued under subsection (b) of this section is liable for the cost of the District Court proceedings.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">If a person who has been served with a citation fails to appear for trial, the court, at the request of the prosecutor, may dismiss the citation or enter a civil judgment against the person:<section prefix="(1)">in favor of the State Board;</section><section prefix="(2)">in accordance with the Maryland Rules; and</section><section prefix="(3)">in an amount not exceeding the maximum fine set forth in subsection (a) of this section and any late fees owed to the State Board.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
