<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gel" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="3-203" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gel-3-203</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Motor Vehicle Administration shall provide the opportunity to apply to register to vote or update a voter registration record to each individual who:<section prefix="(1)">applies for or renews a driver's license or identification card; or</section><section prefix="(2)">changes a name or address on an existing driver's license or identification card.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Motor Vehicle Administration shall inquire orally or in writing whether the applicant wishes to register to vote or update a voter registration record during the transactions specified under subsection (a) of this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If the applicant chooses to register to vote or to update a voter registration record:<section prefix="(i)">all applicable information received by the Motor Vehicle Administration in the course of completing a transaction under subsection (a) of this section shall be transferred to a voter registration application;</section><section prefix="(ii)">any additional necessary information shall be obtained by the Motor Vehicle Administration and may not duplicate any information already obtained while completing a transaction under subsection (a) of this section; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">a voter registration application with all of the applicant's voter registration information shall be presented to the applicant to sign or affirm electronically.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">An applicant may decline to register to vote, update the applicant's voter registration record, or change the applicant's name or address by:</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The Motor Vehicle Administration shall maintain declination information in a manner specified jointly by the Motor Vehicle Administration and the State Board.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(4)">Within 5 days of the receipt of an application under subsection (a) of this section, the Motor Vehicle Administration shall forward to the State Board the voter registration information in a manner and format specified jointly by the Motor Vehicle Administration and the State Board.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">In consultation with the Motor Vehicle Administration, the State Board shall prepare a voter registration application to be used for voter registration at the Motor Vehicle Administration.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">Except as provided in this section, the voter registration portion of the application may not require information that duplicates information required in the driver's license or identification card portion of the application.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The voter registration portion of the application shall:<section prefix="(i)">contain the same information as the statewide voter registration application prescribed in &#xA7; 3-202(a) of this subtitle; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">require only the minimum amount of information necessary, including the applicant's telephone number:</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The application shall contain a box for the applicant to check, with the statement, "I do not wish to register to vote at this time".</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Motor Vehicle Administration shall follow the procedures established jointly by the Motor Vehicle Administration and the State Board to process the voter registration information received under this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">Information relating to the failure of an applicant for a driver's license or identification card to register to vote may not be used for any purpose other than the maintenance of registration statistics.</section>
  </text>
</law>
