<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gel" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="2-103" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gel-2-103</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">There is a State Administrator of Elections.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The State Administrator shall:<section prefix="(1)">be appointed by the State Board, with the advice and consent of the Senate of Maryland, and serve at the pleasure of the State Board;</section><section prefix="(2)">receive a salary as provided in the State budget;</section><section prefix="(3)">as provided in the State budget, employ and supervise:<section prefix="(i)">a deputy administrator, who shall serve as State Administrator in the event the State Administrator resigns, becomes disabled, or dies, pending the appointment of a successor State Administrator; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">pursuant to the State Personnel and Pensions Article, other staff of the State Board;</section></section><section prefix="(4)">supervise the operations of the local boards;</section><section prefix="(5)">perform all duties and exercise all powers that are assigned by law to the State Administrator or delegated by the State Board;</section><section prefix="(6)">implement, in a uniform and nondiscriminatory manner, a single, uniform, official, centralized, interactive computerized statewide voter registration list;</section><section prefix="(7)">provided the State Board is fully constituted with five duly confirmed members, be subject to removal by the affirmative vote of four duly confirmed members of the State Board for incompetence, misconduct, or other good cause except that:<section prefix="(i)">prior to removal, the State Board shall set forth written charges stating the grounds for dismissal and afford the State Administrator notice and an ample opportunity to be heard; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">subsequent to a valid vote for removal by at least four duly confirmed members of the State Board, the State Administrator is authorized to continue to serve until a successor is appointed and confirmed by the Senate of Maryland; and</section></section><section prefix="(8)">be the chief State election official.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Before taking office, the appointee to the office of State Administrator shall take the oath required by Article I, &#xA7; 9 of the Maryland Constitution.</section>
  </text>
</law>
