<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gel" order_by="" level="1">Education</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gel-7-104</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>104</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">A petition for the election of a charter board may not be filed unless all of the signatures attached to the petition have been written by the signers within 6 months of the date when the petition is presented to the board.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A petition relating to a question arising under Article XI-A of the Maryland Constitution shall be filed with the appropriate governmental body or officer not later than the second Monday in August in the year of the election at which the question is to be voted on.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">At the time of filing a petition under the provisions of Article XI-A or Article XVI of the Maryland Constitution, the person who files the petition shall also file a signed statement, under penalty of perjury, showing the contributions and expenditures for the petition including:<section prefix="(i)">the name and post office address of every contributor to the expense of the petition;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the amount contributed by each contributor; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">the name and address of each person to whom any money was paid or promised for providing a service related to the petition.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If the statement under paragraph (1) of this subsection is not filed with the petition, the petition may not be certified under &#xA7; 6-208 of this article.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The individual who signed the statement required under paragraph (1) of this subsection shall be a party to any proceeding to test the validity of the petition.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The proceeding shall be filed in the county where the person or association resides or maintains its principal place of business.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
