<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gel" order_by="" level="1">Education</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gel-13-227</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>227</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, a "campaign finance entity" includes a nonfederal out-of-state political committee.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The limit on transfers set forth in subsection (c) of this section does not apply to a transfer:<section prefix="(1)">by a campaign finance entity to a ballot issue committee; and</section><section prefix="(2)">between or among:<section prefix="(i)">political committees that are State or local central committees of the same political party;</section><section prefix="(ii)">a slate and the campaign finance entities of its members; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">the campaign finance entities of a candidate.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">During an election cycle, a campaign finance entity may not directly or indirectly make transfers in a cumulative amount of more than $6,000 to any one other campaign finance entity.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">All affiliated campaign finance entities are treated as a single entity in determining:<section prefix="(i)">the amount of transfers made by a campaign finance entity; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">the amount of transfers received by a campaign finance entity.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Campaign finance entities are deemed to be affiliated if they:<section prefix="(i)">are organized and operated in coordination and cooperation with each other; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">otherwise conduct their operations and make their decisions relating to transfers and other contributions under the control of the same individual or entity.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The limit on transfers to the campaign finance entities of a candidate prescribed in subsection (c) of this section applies regardless of the number of offices sought by the candidate.</section>
  </text>
</law>
