<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gel" order_by="" level="1">Education</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gel-10-206</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>206</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In consultation with the local boards, the State Board shall:<section prefix="(1)">develop a program of instruction of election judges; and</section><section prefix="(2)">oversee the implementation of the program of instruction.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The training materials utilized by the program may include:<section prefix="(1)">an instruction manual and other written directives;</section><section prefix="(2)">curriculum for training sessions; and</section><section prefix="(3)">audiovisuals.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The State Board shall develop a process for the evaluation of the training program and the performance of the polling place staff in each county.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">To the extent appropriate, the training program shall be specific to each of the voting systems used in polling places in the State.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The State Board shall provide election judges with uniform statewide training on the voting system, including:<section prefix="(1)">all features of the voting system that provide access to voters with disabilities; and</section><section prefix="(2)">the rights of voters with disabilities, including those rights guaranteed by State and federal law.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">Each local board shall conduct election judge training based on the program developed by the State Board.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, each election judge shall participate in the training program provided for in subsection (a) of this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">An election judge who is appointed under emergency circumstances is not required to attend the course of instruction.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
