<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gel" order_by="" level="1">Education</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gel-1-303</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>303</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, "voter information material" means:<section prefix="(1)">campaign literature that is campaign material under Title 13, Subtitle 4 of this article; or</section><section prefix="(2)">registration or voting information issued by the State Board or a local board.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">This section applies only:<section prefix="(1)">in Montgomery County; and</section><section prefix="(2)">to apartment buildings, condominiums, or other multifamily residential structures where access to the entrance of individual residential units is restricted by the owner or governing board of the entire structure.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The owner or governing board of a multifamily residential structure shall designate a public area within the structure where, for the 60-day period immediately prior to each primary election and general election, voter information material may be distributed or deposited.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The designated public area shall be readily accessible to the residents of the structure.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Voter information material deposited in the designated public area shall remain available for residents of the structure for a period of at least 10 days.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Upon written notification by a person whose rights under this section were violated, the local board shall:<section prefix="(1)">notify the owner or governing board regarding the apparent violation and the requirements of this section; and</section><section prefix="(2)">request compliance with the requirements of this section.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
