<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gel" order_by="gel" level="1">Education</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gel-3-504</section_number>
  <catch_line>Information from the agencies specified in this paragraph shall be reported to the State Administrat...</catch_line>
  <order_by>504</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Information from the agencies specified in this paragraph shall be reported to the State Administrator in a format and at times prescribed by the State Board.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The Department of Health and Mental Hygiene shall report the names and residence addresses (if known) of all individuals at least 16 years of age reported deceased within the State since the date of the last report.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">The clerk of the circuit court for each county and the administrative clerk for each District Court shall report the names and addresses of all individuals convicted, in the respective court, of a felony since the date of the last report.</section>
        <section prefix="(iv)">The clerk of the circuit court for each county shall report the former and present names and residence addresses (if known) of all individuals whose names have been changed by decree or order of the court since the date of the last report.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The State Administrator shall make arrangements with the clerk of the United States District Court for the District of Maryland to receive reports of names and addresses, if available, of individuals convicted of a felony in that court.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The State Administrator shall transmit to the appropriate local board information gathered pursuant to subsection (a) of this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Every agency or instrumentality of any county which acquires or condemns or razes or causes to be condemned or razed any building used as a residence within the county shall promptly report this fact and the location of the building to the local board in the county or city.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Registration cancellation information provided by an applicant on any voter registration application shall be provided to the appropriate local board by the State Administrator or another local board.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">A local board may:<section prefix="(i)">make arrangements to receive change of address information from an entity approved by the State Board; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">pay a reasonable fee to the entity for the information.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Whenever a local board becomes aware of an obituary or any other reliable report of the death of a registered voter, the election director shall mail a notice to the registered voter, as prescribed by the State Board, to verify whether the voter is in fact deceased.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">On receipt of a verification of the death of a voter, provided in accordance with the notice mailed under paragraph (1) of this subsection, the election director may remove the voter from the statewide voter registration list under &#xA7; 3-501 of this subtitle.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
