<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gel" order_by="gel" level="1">Education</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gel-7-105</section_number>
  <catch_line>A local board shall provide notice of each question to be submitted statewide and each question to b...</catch_line>
  <order_by>105</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">A local board shall provide notice of each question to be submitted statewide and each question to be submitted to the voters of the county, by:<section prefix="(1)">specimen ballot mailed at least 1 week before the general election; or</section><section prefix="(2)">publication or dissemination by mass communication during the 3 weeks immediately preceding the general election at which a question will appear on the ballot.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">For any question submitted under Article XIV or Article XVI of the Maryland Constitution, the notice required by subsection (a) of this section shall contain the information specified in &#xA7; 7-103(b) of this title and a brief statement, prepared in clear and concise language, devoid of technical and legal terms to the extent practicable, summarizing the question.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The statement required under paragraph (1) of this subsection shall be:<section prefix="(i)">prepared by the Department of Legislative Services;</section><section prefix="(ii)">approved by the Attorney General; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">submitted to the State Board by the fourth Monday in August.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The statement required under paragraph (1) of this subsection is sufficient if it is:<section prefix="(i)">contained in an enactment by the General Assembly, and the enactment clearly specifies that the statement is to be used on the ballot; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">consistent with some other process mandated by the Maryland Constitution.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The State Board shall adopt regulations governing notice of questions to appear on the ballot, including the use and content of specimen ballots and the publication or dissemination of notice by mass communication.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The complete text of a question shall be posted or available for public inspection in the office of the State Board and each applicable local board for 30 days prior to the general election.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Copies of the complete text of all statewide questions shall be furnished by the State Board to the local boards in quantities as determined by the State Board, including quantities sufficient to provide one copy of each for posting in each polling place and in each local board office.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">An individual may receive without charge a copy of the complete text of all constitutional amendments and questions from a local board, either in person or by mail.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
