<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gel" order_by="gel" level="1">Education</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gel-13-243</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this section the following words have the meanings indicated....</catch_line>
  <order_by>243</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Membership entity" means an organization that collects dues from its members.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Affiliated political action committee" means a political action committee affiliated with a membership entity.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A membership entity may establish a program for periodically collecting from its members and accumulating voluntary contributions by the members to an affiliated political action committee if those contributions are collected together with:<section prefix="(1)">membership dues invoiced and collected by the membership entity; or</section><section prefix="(2)">contributions by the members to a political action committee established under federal law, if that political action committee is also affiliated with the membership entity.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A membership entity shall keep detailed and accurate records of each contribution received under subsection (b) of this section, including:<section prefix="(1)">the name and address of the contributor;</section><section prefix="(2)">the date on which the contribution is withheld;</section><section prefix="(3)">the amount of the contribution; and</section><section prefix="(4)">the disposition of the contribution.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Within 30 days after being received, a contribution under this section shall be transmitted by the membership entity, with the information recorded under subsection (c)(1), (2), and (3) of this section, to its affiliated political action committee.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">In soliciting a member, by joint invoice for membership dues or for a contribution to an affiliated federal political action committee, to make a contribution to its affiliated political action committee, a membership entity shall inform the member of:<section prefix="(1)">the political purposes of the affiliated political action committee; and</section><section prefix="(2)">the member's right to refuse to contribute to the political action committee without reprisal.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">An employee membership entity or its affiliated political action committee entity may not receive or use money or anything of value under this section if it is obtained:<section prefix="(1)">by actual or threatened:<section prefix="(i)">physical force;</section><section prefix="(ii)">membership discrimination; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">financial or professional reprisal; or</section></section><section prefix="(2)">as dues, fees, or other assessment required as a condition of membership.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
