<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gel" order_by="gel" level="1">Education</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gel-11-202</section_number>
  <catch_line>Each qualified voter present at the polls at 8 p.m. on election day shall be allowed to vote before ...</catch_line>
  <order_by>202</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Each qualified voter present at the polls at 8 p.m. on election day shall be allowed to vote before the election judges commence their duties under this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">In accordance with the provisions of this article and regulations adopted by the State Board, after the last voter has voted in an election, the election judges shall follow the instructions issued by the election director for closing the polls and for performing the tasks required in the postclosing period.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">In accordance with this section, the election judges shall:<section prefix="(1)">secure the voting system to prevent further voting;</section><section prefix="(2)">if appropriate to the voting system, record the vote, produce vote totals for the polling place, and announce results to those present;</section><section prefix="(3)">complete all documents, records, and reports required by law or regulation after the closing of the polls;</section><section prefix="(4)">perform any other tasks assigned by the election director;</section><section prefix="(5)">assemble and account for materials to be returned to the local board, including, if applicable for the voting system used in that election:<section prefix="(i)">removable data storage devices from voting equipment;</section><section prefix="(ii)">voted ballots;</section><section prefix="(iii)">precinct registers;</section><section prefix="(iv)">voting authority cards;</section><section prefix="(v)">signs and posters;</section><section prefix="(vi)">records, reports, logs, affidavits, certificates, and other documents;</section><section prefix="(vii)">keys to voting devices;</section><section prefix="(viii)">poll books; and</section><section prefix="(ix)">any other materials specified by the election director;</section></section><section prefix="(6)">assure that equipment and materials left in the polling place for retrieval at a later time are stored in a secure manner; and</section><section prefix="(7)">deliver materials and equipment to the local board and obtain receipts from the board certifying the delivery of the items.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Judges may be observed, while performing their duties under this section, until they have finished their work and leave the premises by:<section prefix="(1)">authorized challengers, watchers, and observers in accordance with &#xA7; 10-311 of this article;</section><section prefix="(2)">any candidate; and</section><section prefix="(3)">any other person lawfully present.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
