<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gel" order_by="" level="1">Education</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gel-13-230</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>230</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">A loan to a campaign finance entity is considered a contribution in the amount of the outstanding principal balance of the loan unless:<section prefix="(1)">the loan is from a financial institution or other entity in the business of making loans; or</section><section prefix="(2)">the loan is to the campaign finance entity of a candidate and:<section prefix="(i)">repayment of the loan is personally guaranteed by the candidate; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">the election cycle immediately following the election cycle in which the loan was made has not ended.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Subject to subsection (c)(2) of this section, uncharged interest on a loan is a contribution.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Uncharged interest is the amount by which, during a reporting period, the interest actually charged on the loan is less than the interest on the loan computed at the prime rate applicable on the day the loan was made.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Subject to paragraph (2) of this subsection, the terms of a loan to a campaign finance entity shall:<section prefix="(i)">be in writing;</section><section prefix="(ii)">include the lender's name, address, and signature;</section><section prefix="(iii)">state the schedule for repayment of the loan;</section><section prefix="(iv)">state the interest rate of the loan; and</section><section prefix="(v)">be attached to the campaign finance report required of the entity under Subtitle 3 of this title for the reporting period during which the loan was made.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">A loan by a candidate or the candidate's spouse to a campaign finance entity of the candidate is not required to comply with paragraph (1) of this subsection.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">Unless a loan by a candidate or the candidate's spouse to a campaign finance entity of the candidate complies with paragraph (1) of this subsection:<section prefix="1.">the loan may not accrue interest;</section><section prefix="2.">any interest foregone on the loan is not a contribution under subsection (b) of this section; and</section><section prefix="3.">the campaign finance entity is not subject to:</section></section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A loan may not be made to a campaign finance entity of a candidate, or accepted on behalf of the entity, without the express written consent of the candidate.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The written consent of the candidate constitutes the personal guarantee of the candidate for repayment of the loan only if the document expressly so provides.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A copy of the candidate's written consent shall be:<section prefix="(i)">furnished to the lender when the loan is made; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">attached to the campaign finance report required of the entity under Subtitle 3 of this title for the reporting period during which the loan was made.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
