<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gel" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="3-204.1" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gel-3-204.1</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The State Board may operate an online voter registration system that allows an individual to electronically:<section prefix="(1)">apply to become a registered voter; or</section><section prefix="(2)">change the individual's name, address, or party affiliation in the individual's existing voter registration record.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">To apply to register to vote through the online voter registration system, an individual shall:<section prefix="(1)">complete the electronic voter registration application;</section><section prefix="(2)">affirmatively attest, subject to the penalties of perjury, that the information contained in the voter registration application is true and that the applicant meets all of the qualifications to become a registered voter;</section><section prefix="(3)">provide one of the following:<section prefix="(i)">a Maryland driver's license number or Maryland identification card number; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">if the individual is an absent uniformed services voter or overseas voter as defined in the federal Uniformed and Overseas Citizens Absentee Voting Act and does not have a Maryland driver's license or Maryland identification card, a Social Security number; and</section></section><section prefix="(4)">affirmatively consent to the use of one of the following as the individual's signature for the application being submitted:<section prefix="(i)">the electronic copy of the individual's signature that is on file with the Motor Vehicle Administration; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">the individual's Social Security number.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">To change an individual's name, address, or party affiliation in the individual's existing voter registration record, an individual shall:<section prefix="(1)">complete the electronic voter registration application;</section><section prefix="(2)">affirmatively attest, subject to the penalties of perjury, that the information contained in the voter registration application is true and that the applicant meets all of the qualifications to be a registered voter;</section><section prefix="(3)">provide one of the following:<section prefix="(i)">a Maryland driver's license number or Maryland identification card number;</section><section prefix="(ii)">a Maryland voter identification number on the individual's voter notification card; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">if the individual is an absent uniformed services voter or overseas voter as defined in the federal Uniformed and Overseas Citizens Absentee Voting Act and does not have a Maryland driver's license or Maryland identification card, a Social Security number; and</section></section><section prefix="(4)">affirmatively consent to the use of one of the following as the individual's signature for the application being submitted:<section prefix="(i)">the electronic copy of the individual's signature that is on file with the Motor Vehicle Administration;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the electronic copy of the individual's signature that is on file in the statewide voter registration list; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">the individual's Social Security number.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Motor Vehicle Administration shall transmit an electronic copy of an individual's driver's license or identification card signature to the State Board within 5 days of being notified by the State Board that the individual submitted a voter registration application through the online voter registration system.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The State Board may:<section prefix="(1)">take any additional measures it deems necessary to ensure the integrity and accuracy of voter registration applications submitted through the online voter registration system; and</section><section prefix="(2)">adopt any regulations necessary to administer the online voter registration system.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
