<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gel" order_by="gel" level="1">Education</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gel-7-102</section_number>
  <catch_line>A question relating to the holding of a constitutional convention qualifies for the ballot automatic...</catch_line>
  <order_by>102</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A question relating to the holding of a constitutional convention qualifies for the ballot automatically every 20 years pursuant to Article XIV, &#xA7; 2 of the Maryland Constitution.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A question relating to the adoption of a new or altered Constitution qualifies upon its adoption by a duly constituted convention pursuant to Article XIV, &#xA7; 2 of the Maryland Constitution.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">An amendment to the Constitution qualifies upon its passage by the General Assembly pursuant to Article XIV, &#xA7; 1 of the Maryland Constitution.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A question on an act of the General Assembly pursuant to Article XVI of the Maryland Constitution qualifies upon the certification under Title 6 of this article, that the petition has satisfied all the requirements established by Article XVI.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A question relating to the creation of a home rule county government qualifies upon either:<section prefix="(i)">a determination by the appropriate local authority that the applicable petition has satisfied all the requirements established by law relating to the creation of a charter board; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">the adoption by the governing body of a county of an enactment proposing that the county become a code county.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A question relating to the approval of a county charter qualifies upon the adoption of a proposed charter by a charter board pursuant to the requirements prescribed by Article XI-A of the Maryland Constitution.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A question relating to the amendment of a county charter shall qualify either upon:<section prefix="(i)">the passage by the governing body of the county of a resolution proposing the amendment; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">a determination by the governing body of the county that a petition submitted has satisfied all the requirements established by law relating to petitions initiating charter amendments.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A question relating to the creation of a new county or the alteration of county boundaries qualifies upon the enactment of the implementing public general law.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">A question referred to the voters as provided in an enactment of the General Assembly qualifies upon the enactment of the law calling for the question.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A question on an enactment by a charter county qualifies pursuant to local law and Article 25A, &#xA7; 8 of the Code.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A question on an enactment by a code county qualifies pursuant to local law and Article 25B, &#xA7; 10 of the Code.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">A question relating to the incorporation of a new municipal corporation qualifies upon the determination by the county governing body that the applicable petition has satisfied all the requirements established by law for that petition.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">A referendum on a question of issuance of a bond pursuant to &#xA7; 9-934 of the Environment Article qualifies upon submission of the question to the appropriate local board.</section>
  </text>
</law>
