<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gel" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="4-203" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gel-4-203</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In Anne Arundel County, the members of the Democratic and Republican Party Central Committees for the county shall be elected as follows:<section prefix="(1)">three members shall be elected from each legislative district wholly contained within Anne Arundel County; and</section><section prefix="(2)">one member shall be elected from that portion within Anne Arundel County of any legislative district that is partially contained within Anne Arundel County.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">In Baltimore City, the Democratic Party Central Committee consists of seven members elected from each of the six legislative districts of Baltimore City.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">Each member shall reside in, and be elected by the voters of, the legislative district that the member represents.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The members of the Republican Party Central Committee shall be elected from each councilmanic district of Baltimore City.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">Two members shall be elected from each councilmanic district.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In Baltimore County, the Republican Party Central Committee shall consist of four members elected from each councilmanic district in the county.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">For the Baltimore County Democratic Party Central Committee:<section prefix="(i)">twenty-five members, five from each district, shall be elected from legislative districts 6, 8, 10, 11, and 42, each district being located wholly within Baltimore County;</section><section prefix="(ii)">two members shall be elected from that part of legislative district 5 that is located in Baltimore County;</section><section prefix="(iii)">four members shall be elected from that part of legislative district 7 that is located in Baltimore County; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">four members shall be elected from that part of legislative district 12 that is located in Baltimore County.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Only individuals affiliated with the Democratic Party and who are registered to vote in Baltimore County may vote for the election of members to the Baltimore County Democratic Party Central Committee under this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The number of Democratic Party Central Committee members to be elected from each legislative district, or portion of legislative district, in Baltimore County shall be determined upon completion of each legislative districting.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">In Calvert County, the Democratic Party Central Committee consists of nine members elected by the voters of the county at large as follows:<section prefix="(1)">two members who reside in the first election district and receive the largest number of votes cast for candidates from that district;</section><section prefix="(2)">two members who reside in the second election district and receive the largest number of votes cast for candidates from that district;</section><section prefix="(3)">two members who reside in the third election district and receive the largest number of votes cast for candidates from that district; and</section><section prefix="(4)">three members who reside in Calvert County and who receive the highest number of votes cast in Calvert County for the remaining candidates.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">In Carroll County, the Republican Party Central Committee shall consist of nine members elected at large.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In Montgomery County, for the Democratic Party Central Committee:<section prefix="(i)">two members are elected from each of the legislative districts that lie wholly within Montgomery County;</section><section prefix="(ii)">one member is elected from the Montgomery County part of each legislative district that is partially within Montgomery County; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">members shall be elected at large equal to the number of legislative districts that lie wholly within Montgomery County, except that not more than two members at large may reside in the same legislative district.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Any vacancy in a seat on the Democratic Party Central Committee held initially by a member elected from a legislative district shall be filled by a person residing in that district.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Any reference to the Democratic Party Central Committee for Montgomery County or any portion of it means the entire membership of the Montgomery County Democratic Party Central Committee, and in no event do the members of the Central Committee elected from a district comprise a separate central committee.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">In Prince George's County, members of the Republican Party Central Committee:</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The number of members of the Republican Party Central Committee shall consist of two members from each of the eight legislative districts lying within Prince George's County.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">In Prince George's County, the Democratic Party Central Committee consists of 24 members.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)"/>
        <section prefix="(iii)">In addition to the members of the committee elected from legislative districts, eight members of the committee shall be elected by all the eligible voters in the county, and at the time of election, each member shall reside in a different one of the eight legislative districts within Prince George's County.</section>
        <section prefix="(iv)">A candidate for election to the Democratic Party Central Committee shall declare at the time of filing for candidacy which seat on the Central Committee the candidate is seeking.</section>
        <section prefix="(v)">If a member who was elected from a specific legislative district ceases to reside in that district, the member may not continue to serve on the Central Committee.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(h)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In Worcester County, the Democratic Party Central Committee consists of 11 members as follows:<section prefix="(i)">seven members who shall reside in and be elected, respectively, by the eligible voters of each of the seven county commissioner districts; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">four members who shall reside in Worcester County, be elected at large by the eligible voters of the entire county, and receive the highest number of votes cast for candidates in the at large election.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">A candidate for election to the Democratic Party Central Committee shall declare at the time of filing a certificate of candidacy which seat the candidate is seeking.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">A member elected to represent a specific county commissioner district who ceases to reside in that district may not continue to serve on the Central Committee.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Any vacancy in a seat on the Central Committee held by an individual elected from a county commissioner district shall be filled by an individual who resides in that district.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
