<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gel" order_by="gel" level="1">Education</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gel-13-331</section_number>
  <catch_line>In accordance with subsection (b) of this section, the State Board shall assess a late filing fee fo...</catch_line>
  <order_by>331</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In accordance with subsection (b) of this section, the State Board shall assess a late filing fee for a failure to file a campaign finance report or affidavit, as specified in &#xA7; 13-327 of this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The fee is $10 for each day or part of a day, excluding Saturdays, Sundays, and holidays, that a campaign finance report or affidavit is overdue.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">An additional fee of $10 is due for each of the first 6 days, excluding Saturdays, Sundays, and holidays, that a preelection campaign finance report under &#xA7; 13-309 of this subtitle is overdue.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The maximum fee payable for a campaign finance report or affidavit is $250.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The State Board shall accept an overdue campaign finance report or affidavit that is submitted without payment of the late filing fee, but the campaign finance report is not considered filed until the fee has been paid.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">After an overdue campaign finance report or affidavit is received under paragraph (1) of this subsection no further late filing fee shall be incurred.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A late filing fee is the joint and several liability of the responsible officers and:<section prefix="(1)">may not be paid, directly or indirectly, by the campaign finance entity; and</section><section prefix="(2)">is neither a contribution to nor an expenditure of the entity.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
