<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gel" order_by="gel" level="1">Education</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gel-13-324</section_number>
  <catch_line>Except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, campaign finance reports required to be file...</catch_line>
  <order_by>324</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, campaign finance reports required to be filed with the State Board shall be submitted using an electronic storage medium, and in a format, that the State Board approves.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The State Board may exempt a campaign finance entity with de minimis financial activity from the requirement to submit campaign finance reports using an electronic medium.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">On request the State Board shall supply to a person who is required to file campaign finance reports using an electronic medium the computer software and the disks or other media on which the required information is to be entered.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Campaign finance reports received by the State Board in an electronic storage format shall be maintained in accordance with &#xA7; 13-341 of this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The State Board shall make the campaign finance reports that are maintained in an electronic storage format under subsection (c) of this section widely and easily accessible to the public:<section prefix="(1)">using any existing public or private systems for data dissemination;</section><section prefix="(2)">on terms that the State Board determines are consistent with the purposes and requirements of this article; and</section><section prefix="(3)">by making any computer disk submitted by a person available for duplication.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The State Board may refuse to accept or process a campaign finance report that is not submitted in accordance with the requirements of this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The State Board shall:<section prefix="(1)">develop specifications for submitting campaign finance reports using an electronic medium; and</section><section prefix="(2)">adopt regulations to implement this section.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
