<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gel" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="15-109" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gel-15-109</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Subject to &#xA7; 15-103 of this title, the State Board shall administer this title.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The State Board may request the assistance of the Comptroller to administer this title.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The State Board shall adopt comprehensive regulations to implement this title.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The regulations shall include provisions relating to:<section prefix="(i)">the manner and deadline for a gubernatorial ticket to notify the State Board of its intention to qualify for a public contribution;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the deadline for a gubernatorial ticket to submit a request for a public contribution;</section><section prefix="(iii)">the dates when the State Board will authorize, and the Comptroller will make, distributions of public contributions to gubernatorial tickets in accordance with this title;</section><section prefix="(iv)">a proportionate distribution when there is not, or may not be, sufficient money in the Fund;</section><section prefix="(v)">a formula for distributing a supplementary public contribution to the other eligible gubernatorial tickets if additional money becomes available because:</section><section prefix="(vi)">the standards by which expenditures by campaign finance entities with which an eligible gubernatorial ticket is affiliated are applied to the expenditure limit prescribed in &#xA7; 15-105 of this title;</section><section prefix="(vii)">thresholds for in-kind contributions that are not considered contributions or expenditures for the purposes of this title;</section><section prefix="(viii)">distributions to:</section><section prefix="(ix)">the purposes for which a public contribution may not be used.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
