<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gel" order_by="gel" level="1">Education</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gel-6-101</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this title the following words have the meanings indicated....</catch_line>
  <order_by>101</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this title the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Affidavit" means a statement executed under penalty of perjury.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Chief election official" means:<section prefix="(1)">as to the State Board, the State Administrator; or</section><section prefix="(2)">as to a local board, the election director.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">"Circulator" means an individual who attests to one or more signatures affixed to a petition.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"Election authority" means:<section prefix="(1)">the State Board; or</section><section prefix="(2)">as to a local petition, the local board for that county.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">"Legal authority" means:<section prefix="(1)">the Attorney General; or</section><section prefix="(2)">as to a local petition, the counsel to the local board appointed under &#xA7; 2-205 of this article for that county.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(g)">"Local petition" means a petition:<section prefix="(1)">on which the signatures from only one county may be counted; and</section><section prefix="(2)">that does not seek to:<section prefix="(i)">refer a public local law enacted by the General Assembly; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">nominate an individual for an office for which a certificate of candidacy is required to be filed with the State Board.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(h)">"Page" means a piece of paper comprising a part of a petition.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">"Petition" means all of the associated pages necessary to fulfill the requirements of a process established by the law by which individuals affix their signatures as evidence of support for:<section prefix="(1)">placing the name of an individual, the names of individuals, or a question on the ballot at any election;</section><section prefix="(2)">the creation of a new political party; or</section><section prefix="(3)">the appointment of a charter board under Article XI-A, &#xA7; 1A of the Maryland Constitution.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(j)">"Sponsor" means the person who coordinates the collection of signatures for a petition and who, if the petition is filed, is named on the information page as required by &#xA7; 6-201 of this title.</section>
  </text>
</law>
