<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gel" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="11-402" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gel-11-402</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Unless otherwise provided by the Maryland Constitution, and except as provided in subsection (b) of this section, each board of canvassers shall prepare a statement of election results by precinct for each candidate or question voted on at the election and declare:<section prefix="(1)">who is elected or nominated for office:<section prefix="(i)">in county government; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">for any other office voted for only within that county, if the certificate of candidacy for that office was issued by the local board; and</section></section><section prefix="(2)">whether or not a question is adopted or approved.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The statement prepared by the board of canvassers under this section may not report the absentee vote separately by precinct.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Each local board shall publish a sufficient number of copies of the complete election results, tabulated by precinct, and shall make the copies available to the public at cost.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In addition to the statement of election results specified under subsection (a) of this section, the State Board shall make available in an electronic format a report of election results for each candidate or question voted on at the election:<section prefix="(i)">by precinct;</section><section prefix="(ii)">by State legislative district, including any subdistrict;</section><section prefix="(iii)">by county legislative district; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">for each county as a whole.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The State Board may make the report specified under paragraph (1) of this subsection available to the public at cost.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
