<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gel" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="9-210" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gel-9-210</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The offices to be voted on shall be arranged on the ballot in the following order, as applicable:<section prefix="(1)">public offices for which voters of the entire State may vote, in the following order:<section prefix="(i)">President of the United States, or President and Vice President of the United States;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Governor and Lieutenant Governor;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Comptroller;</section><section prefix="(iv)">Attorney General; and</section><section prefix="(v)">United States Senator;</section></section><section prefix="(2)">Representative in Congress;</section><section prefix="(3)">members of the General Assembly of Maryland, in the following order:<section prefix="(i)">Senate of Maryland; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">House of Delegates;</section></section><section prefix="(4)">members of the governing body of a county, in the following order:<section prefix="(i)">county executive; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">county council or county commissioner;</section></section><section prefix="(5)">offices in the government of the City of Baltimore, in the following order:<section prefix="(i)">Mayor;</section><section prefix="(ii)">President of the City Council;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Comptroller; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">member of the City Council;</section></section><section prefix="(6)">judicial offices, in the following order:<section prefix="(i)">judge of the circuit court; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">appellate judges, continuance in office, in the following order:</section></section><section prefix="(7)">public offices for which the voters of a county may vote, in the following order:<section prefix="(i)">county treasurer;</section><section prefix="(ii)">State's Attorney;</section><section prefix="(iii)">clerk of the circuit court;</section><section prefix="(iv)">register of wills;</section><section prefix="(v)">judge of the orphans' court;</section><section prefix="(vi)">sheriff; and</section><section prefix="(vii)">other offices filled by partisan election;</section></section><section prefix="(8)">party offices; and</section><section prefix="(9)">offices filled by nonpartisan election.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Any office not specified in subsection (a) of this section shall be placed on the ballot following the offices specified in subsection (a).</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Within any category of offices, if the ballot contains one or more contests for at large election and one or more contests for election by district, the contest or contests to be voted on at large shall appear first.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">In a prominent position adjacent to the title of each office, there shall be instructions stating the number of candidates for whom the voter lawfully may vote.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A ballot shall contain the name of every candidate who is authorized under the provisions of this article to appear on the ballot.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Each candidate shall be listed on the ballot in the contest for which the candidate has qualified.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In a general election, the voter shall be afforded the opportunity to cast a write-in vote for as many positions as are to be filled in a contest.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">On a document ballot, in each contest a blank line or lines for write-in voting shall follow the printed names on the ballot.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">This subsection does not apply to questions or the continuance in office of appellate judges.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except for contests for judicial office or an office to be filled by nonpartisan election, the party affiliation of a candidate who is a nominee of a political party shall be indicated on the ballot.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">A candidate who is not a nominee of a political party or affiliated with a partisan organization shall be designated as an "unaffiliated".</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">A candidate who is affiliated with a partisan organization shall be designated under "other candidates".</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The names of candidates for judge of the circuit court or for a county board of education, and the names of incumbent appellate judges, shall be placed on the ballot without a party label or other distinguishing mark or location which might indicate party affiliation.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(h)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In an election of a member of the House of Delegates that is subject to the provisions of &#xA7; 2-201(d) of the State Government Article, the name of a candidate shall be identified by the county in which the candidate resides.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A candidate for President of the United States or Vice President of the United States shall be identified by the state in which the candidate resides.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(i)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If there is an election for members of the House of Delegates who are required to live in a specific county and only a certain number of delegates may be elected from that county, the ballot shall provide that a voter may not vote for more than that number of candidates from that specific county.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">In a legislative district where the delegates are to be elected by the voters of a multimember subdistrict that contains more than two counties or parts of more than two counties, a voter may cast a vote for the specified number of delegates to be elected in the subdistrict without regard to the county of residence of the candidate.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(j)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In a primary election:<section prefix="(i)">on a voting machine ballot, the names of the candidates for party nomination shall be grouped together by party; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">on a document ballot, the ballot shall include only the names of candidates for which the voter is entitled to vote.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">In a general election:<section prefix="(i)">on a voting machine ballot, the names of the candidates of a political party shall be grouped together in adjacent rows or columns, and the majority party candidates shall be placed in the first row or column, followed by the candidates of the principal minority party, followed by other political parties in descending order based on the number of voters registered with the party, and finally by candidates not nominees of a political party; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">on a document ballot, for each office the names of candidates shall be grouped together by party, with the majority party candidate or candidates listed first, followed by the candidate or candidates of the principal minority party, followed by the candidate or candidates of other political parties in descending order based on the statewide registration of the party, and finally by candidates who are not nominees of a political party.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">In both primary elections and general elections, when there is more than one candidate of the same political party for nomination or election to an office, the names of the candidates in the group shall be listed in alphabetical order by surname. In the primary election, candidates for Governor and Lieutenant Governor shall be arranged in the order of surnames of the gubernatorial candidates.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(k)">On a voting machine ballot, the arrangement shall use the smallest number of rows or columns necessary, as evenly sized as possible, to accommodate all offices and candidates on the ballot.</section>
  </text>
</law>
