<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gel" order_by="" level="1">Education</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gel-6-210</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>210</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A request for an advance determination under &#xA7; 6-202 of this subtitle shall be submitted at least 30 days, but not more than 2 years and 1 month, prior to the deadline for the filing of the petition.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Within 5 business days of receiving the request for an advance determination, the election authority shall make the determination.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Within 2 business days after an advance determination under &#xA7; 6-202 of this subtitle, or a determination of deficiency under &#xA7; 6-206 or &#xA7; 6-208 of this subtitle, the chief election official of the election authority shall notify the sponsor of the determination.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The verification and counting of validated signatures on a petition shall be completed within 20 days after the filing of the petition.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Within 2 business days of the completion of the verification and counting processes, or, if judicial review is pending, within 2 business days after a final judicial decision, the appropriate election official shall make the certifications required by &#xA7; 6-208 of this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, any judicial review of a determination, as provided in &#xA7; 6-209 of this subtitle, shall be sought by the 10th day following the determination to which it relates.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If the petition seeks to place the name of an individual or a question on the ballot at any election, judicial review shall be sought by the day specified in paragraph (1) of this subsection or the 63rd day preceding that election, whichever day is earlier.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
