<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gel" order_by="" level="1">Education</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gel-3-202</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>202</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The statewide voter registration application shall:<section prefix="(i)">require the signature of the applicant, subject to the penalties of perjury, by which the applicant swears or affirms that the information contained in the registration application is true and that the applicant meets all of the qualifications to become a registered voter;</section><section prefix="(ii)">state the penalties for the submission of a false application; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">provide the applicant with the opportunity to cancel a current registration.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The following information shall be made available to each applicant who is completing a statewide voter registration application:<section prefix="(i)">the qualifications to become a registered voter;</section><section prefix="(ii)">if an individual declines to register, this fact will remain confidential and be used only for voter registration purposes;</section><section prefix="(iii)">if an individual registers to vote, the office at which the application is submitted will remain confidential and will be used only for voter registration purposes; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">notification to the applicant that submission of the form to an individual other than an official, employee, or agent of a local board does not assure that the form will be filed or filed in a timely manner.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The statewide voter registration application may not require:<section prefix="(i)">notarization or other formal authentication; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">any additional information, other than the information necessary to enable election officials to determine the eligibility of the applicant and to administer voter registration and other parts of the election process.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">
        <section prefix="(i)">A statewide voter registration application shall be produced exclusively by the State Board.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">No other registration form may be used for registration purposes except:<section prefix="1.">a voter registration application produced by a local board with the approval of the State Board;</section><section prefix="2.">as provided in subsection (b) of this section;</section><section prefix="3.">as provided in &#xA7; 3-203(b) of this subtitle;</section><section prefix="4.">any other form prescribed by federal law for voter registration; or</section><section prefix="5.">a federal write-in absentee ballot if used by a voter authorized to vote a federal write-in absentee ballot under federal law.</section></section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The voter registration application form prescribed pursuant to the National Voter Registration Act of 1993 shall be accepted by the appropriate election official for purposes of voter registration.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The application described in this section may be used by a registered voter to change the voter's name, address, or party affiliation.</section>
  </text>
</law>
