<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gel" order_by="gel" level="1">Education</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gel-11-302</section_number>
  <catch_line>Following an election, each local board shall meet at its designated counting center to canvass the ...</catch_line>
  <order_by>302</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Following an election, each local board shall meet at its designated counting center to canvass the absentee ballots cast in that election in accordance with the regulations and guidelines established by the State Board.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A local board may not open any envelope of an absentee ballot prior to 8 a.m. on the Wednesday following election day.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A local board may not delay the commencement of the canvass to await the receipt of late-arriving, timely absentee ballots.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">An absentee ballot shall be deemed timely received if it is received in accordance with the regulations and guidelines established by the State Board.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">An absentee ballot that is received after the deadline specified by the regulations and guidelines may not be counted.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The State Board shall adopt regulations that reflect the policy that the clarity of the intent of the voter is the overriding consideration in determining the validity of an absentee ballot or the vote cast in a particular contest.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A local board may not reject an absentee ballot except by unanimous vote and in accordance with regulations of the State Board.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The local board shall reject an absentee ballot if:<section prefix="(i)">before the ballot is canvassed, the local board determines that the voter died before election day;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the voter failed to sign the oath on the ballot envelope;</section><section prefix="(iii)">the local board received more than one ballot from the same individual for the same election in the same ballot envelope; or</section><section prefix="(iv)">the local board determines that an absentee ballot is intentionally marked with an identifying mark that is clearly evident and placed on the ballot for the purpose of identifying the ballot.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">If the local board receives more than one legally sufficient ballot, in separate envelopes, from the same individual, the local board shall:<section prefix="(i)">count only the ballot with the latest properly signed oath; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">reject any other ballot.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(5)">If the intent of the voter is not clearly demonstrated, the local board shall reject only the vote for that office or question.</section>
      <section prefix="(6)">If an absentee voter casts a vote for an individual who has ceased to be a candidate, the vote for that candidate may not be counted, but that vote does not invalidate the remainder of the ballot.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
