<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gel" order_by="" level="1">Education</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gel-14-104</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>104</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">A person doing public business shall file a statement with the State Board as provided in this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">When a contract is made that causes a person to be doing public business, an initial statement shall be filed:<section prefix="(i)">at that time, covering the preceding 24 months, if the person has made an applicable contribution within that period; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">if item (i) of this paragraph does not apply, but the person subsequently makes an applicable contribution during a reporting period specified in paragraph (2) of this subsection, as required by that paragraph.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">A person shall file a semi-annual statement in accordance with this paragraph for each reporting period specified in subparagraph (ii) of this paragraph in which the person has made an applicable contribution if:<section prefix="1.">performance remains uncompleted on any contract that caused the person to be doing public business; or</section><section prefix="2.">the person is doing public business.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">
          <section prefix="1.">The statements required by subparagraph (i) of this paragraph shall cover 6-month reporting periods ending on January 31 and July 31.</section>
          <section prefix="2.">A statement required by subparagraph (i) of this paragraph shall be filed within 5 days after the end of the applicable reporting period.</section>
        </section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The statement required by this section shall be made under oath and shall contain:<section prefix="(i)">the name of each candidate to whom an applicable contribution was made during the reporting period and, if not previously reported, during the preceding reporting period;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the office sought by each candidate named in item (i) of this paragraph;</section><section prefix="(iii)">the amount of aggregate contributions made to each candidate named in item (i) of this paragraph;</section><section prefix="(iv)">the name of each unit of a governmental entity with which the person did public business during the reporting period;</section><section prefix="(v)">the nature and amount of public business done with each unit of a governmental entity; and</section><section prefix="(vi)">if the public business was done or the contribution was made by another person but is attributed to the person filing the statement, the name of the person who did the public business or made the contribution and the relationship of that person to the person filing the statement.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The information required by paragraph (1)(iv) and (v) of this subsection may be omitted on the written approval of the Attorney General if the Attorney General finds that:<section prefix="(i)">requiring the information would be unduly burdensome;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the public interest would not be impaired substantially by the omission of this information; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">the person filing the statement stipulates that the person has done public business during the reporting period.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The State Board shall retain each statement filed under this title as a public record for at least 2 years after its receipt and shall make the statement available for public examination and copying during normal office hours.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The State Board may establish reasonable fees and administrative procedures governing public examination and copying of the statements filed under this section.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The State Board shall prescribe and make available forms for the statements required by this section.</section>
  </text>
</law>
