<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gel" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="10-312" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gel-10-312</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The right of an individual to vote may be challenged at the polls only on the grounds of identity.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">An individual whose right to vote is challenged at the polls may establish the individual's identity by presenting any of the following forms of identification:<section prefix="(i)">the individual's voter registration card;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the individual's Social Security card;</section><section prefix="(iii)">the individual's valid Maryland driver's license;</section><section prefix="(iv)">any identification card issued to the individual by a political subdivision of the State, the State, the federal government, or any unit of a political subdivision of the State, the State, or the federal government;</section><section prefix="(v)">any employee identification card of the individual that contains a photograph of the individual and is issued by the employer of the individual in the ordinary course of the employer's business; or</section><section prefix="(vi)">a copy of a current bill, bank statement, government check, paycheck, or other government document that shows the name and current address of the individual.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">If an individual establishes the individual's identity under paragraph (2) of this subsection, an election judge shall authorize the individual to vote a regular ballot.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A challenge to an individual's right to vote shall be made before the individual is issued a ballot or a voting authority card.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">If a challenge is made, and the challenged individual does not present any of the forms of identification specified under subsection (a)(2) of this section, the election judge receiving the challenge shall:<section prefix="(1)">require the challenger to provide in writing, under penalty of perjury, the reasons for the challenge;</section><section prefix="(2)">offer the challenged individual the opportunity to:<section prefix="(i)">cast a provisional ballot; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">submit an attestation, witnessed by the election judge, of the individual's identity; and</section></section><section prefix="(3)">submit the provisional ballot and other materials related to the challenge to the local board.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">During the canvass of provisional ballots, the local board shall determine, based on the information submitted by the challenger and the challenged individual, whether the challenged individual is:<section prefix="(1)">the registered voter he or she claims to be; and</section><section prefix="(2)">otherwise qualified to vote.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
