<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gel" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="6-206" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gel-6-206</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Promptly upon the filing of a petition with an election authority, the chief election official of the election authority shall review the petition.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Unless a determination of deficiency is made under subsection (c) of this section, the chief election official shall:<section prefix="(1)">make a determination that the petition, as to matters other than the validity of signatures, is sufficient; or</section><section prefix="(2)">defer a determination of sufficiency pending further review.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The chief election official shall declare that the petition is deficient if the chief election official determines that:<section prefix="(1)">the petition was not timely filed;</section><section prefix="(2)">after providing the sponsor an opportunity to correct any clerical errors, the information provided by the sponsor indicates that the petition does not satisfy any requirements of law for the number or geographic distribution of signatures;</section><section prefix="(3)">an examination of unverified signatures indicates that the petition does not satisfy any requirements of law for the number or geographic distribution of signatures;</section><section prefix="(4)">the requirements relating to the form of the petition have not been satisfied;</section><section prefix="(5)">based on the advice of the legal authority:<section prefix="(i)">the use of a petition for the subject matter of the petition is not authorized by law; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">the petition seeks:</section></section><section prefix="(6)">the petition has failed to satisfy some other requirement established by law.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A determination under this section may not be inconsistent with an advance determination made under &#xA7; 6-202 of this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">Notice of a determination under this section shall be provided in accordance with &#xA7; 6-210 of this subtitle.</section>
  </text>
</law>
