<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gel" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="10-303" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gel-10-303</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Under the supervision of a chief judge, an election judge shall:<section prefix="(1)">carry out the tasks assigned by the local board, including those set forth in any election judge instruction manual developed in accordance with &#xA7; 10-206 of this title, during the period of time that begins before the election through the close of the polls and the return of materials to the local board; and</section><section prefix="(2)">take measures throughout election day to assure that:<section prefix="(i)">each voter's right to cast a ballot in privacy is maintained;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the integrity of the voting process is preserved;</section><section prefix="(iii)">the accuracy of the counting process is protected;</section><section prefix="(iv)">order in the polling place is maintained; and</section><section prefix="(v)">all election laws are observed.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">While serving as an election judge on an election day, an election judge shall wear a badge that:<section prefix="(1)">is in plain view;</section><section prefix="(2)">identifies the person as an election judge; and</section><section prefix="(3)">identifies the person by name and by the ward and precinct or election district for which the person is an election judge.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">An election judge shall:<section prefix="(1)">keep the peace; and</section><section prefix="(2)">order the arrest of any person who:<section prefix="(i)">breaches the peace;</section><section prefix="(ii)">breaches any provision of this article; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">interferes with the work of the judges in conducting the election and carrying out their assigned tasks.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">An election judge shall protect a challenger or watcher in the exercise of the rights of a challenger or watcher as provided in &#xA7; 10-311 of this subtitle.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">An election judge is not required to admit a challenger or watcher to a polling place before the polls open if the challenger or watcher was not present at the polling place at least one-half hour before its opening.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">An election judge may require challengers and watchers to leave a polling place before it opens if a majority of the election judges present agrees that the presence of the challengers and watchers will prevent the timely opening of the polling place.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">An election judge shall designate reasonable times for challengers and watchers to examine polling lists.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
