<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gel" order_by="" level="1">Education</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gel-10-301.1</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>301.1</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Except as provided under Title 9, Subtitle 3 of this article, during any regularly scheduled primary or general election a voter may vote:<section prefix="(1)">in the voter's assigned precinct on election day; or</section><section prefix="(2)">at an early voting center in the voter's county of residence on any early voting day in accordance with this section.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Each county shall have at least one early voting center established in the county as prescribed in this subsection.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A county with fewer than 150,000 registered voters shall have one early voting center established in the county.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A county with more than 150,000 but fewer than 300,000 registered voters shall have three early voting centers established in the county.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">A county with more than 300,000 registered voters shall have five early voting centers established in the county.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">No later than 6 months before a primary election, the State Board, in collaboration with the local board in each county, shall designate each early voting center in that county.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Each early voting center shall be open for voting as follows:<section prefix="(1)">for the 2010 gubernatorial primary and general elections:<section prefix="(i)">beginning the second Friday before a primary or general election through the Thursday before the elections, but excluding Sunday; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">during the hours between 10 a.m. and 8 p.m.; and</section></section><section prefix="(2)">for the 2012 presidential primary and general elections:<section prefix="(i)">beginning the second Saturday before a primary or general election through the Thursday before the elections; and</section><section prefix="(ii)"><section prefix="1.">during the hours between 10 a.m. and 8 p.m. on the Saturday and the Monday through the Thursday during the early voting period; and</section><section prefix="2.">during the hours between 12 noon and 6 p.m. on the Sunday during the early voting period.</section></section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">Each early voting center shall satisfy the requirements of &#xA7; 10-101 of this title.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">Beginning 30 days prior to each early voting period the State Board and each local board shall undertake steps to inform the public about early voting and the location of early voting centers in each county, including:<section prefix="(1)">a series of public service media announcements;</section><section prefix="(2)">mailings to all registered voters in each county; and</section><section prefix="(3)">other measures as appropriate.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(g)">Except as expressly provided in this section, any provision of this article that applies to voting on election day also applies to early voting.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">The State Board shall adopt regulations and guidelines in accordance with the requirements of this section for the conduct of early voting.</section>
  </text>
</law>
