<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gel" order_by="gel" level="1">Education</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gel-13-602</section_number>
  <catch_line>A person may not directly or indirectly give, offer, or promise money, aid, a gift, an advantage, a ...</catch_line>
  <order_by>602</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A person may not directly or indirectly give, offer, or promise money, aid, a gift, an advantage, a preferment, an emolument, or any other valuable thing to another person for the purpose of inducing or procuring that person to vote or refrain from voting for or against:<section prefix="(i)">an individual, question, or measure at an election or political convention; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">the election of an officer by the General Assembly.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A person may not directly or indirectly receive, accept, request, or solicit money, aid, a gift, an advantage, a preferment, an emolument, or any other valuable thing from another person for the purpose of inducing or procuring a third person to vote or refrain from voting for or against an individual, question, or measure at an election or political convention.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A person may not vote or refrain from voting for or against an individual, question, or measure at an election or a political convention, in consideration of money, aid, a gift, an advantage, a preferment, an emolument, or any other valuable thing paid, received, accepted, or promised to the advantage of that person or of another person.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">
        <section prefix="(i)">A person, to defray the costs of a campaign finance entity, may not directly or indirectly pay, give, or promise money or any other valuable thing to any person other than a campaign finance entity.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">Subparagraph (i) of this paragraph does not apply to:<section prefix="1.">dues regularly paid for membership in a political club if all of the money that is spent by that political club in connection with any campaign finance activity is paid through a treasurer as provided in this title;</section><section prefix="2.">an individual volunteering the individual's time or personal vehicle in accordance with &#xA7; 13-232 of this title;</section><section prefix="3.">an employer's accumulation of employee contributions in accordance with &#xA7; 13-242 of this title; or</section><section prefix="4.">advertising costs or other expenses incident to the expression of personal views in accordance with &#xA7; 13-102 of this title.</section></section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(5)">A person may not directly or indirectly pay or promise to pay a campaign finance entity in a name other than the person's name.</section>
      <section prefix="(6)">A responsible officer of a campaign finance entity may not knowingly receive a payment or promise of payment and enter it or cause it to be entered in an account book in a name that the responsible officer knows is not the name of the person that made the payment or the promise to pay.</section>
      <section prefix="(7)">An employer who pays employees in envelopes may not mark on or enclose in the envelopes a political motto, device, or argument that contains express or implied threats intended to influence the political opinions or actions of those employees.</section>
      <section prefix="(8)">During the 90 days before an election, an employer may not exhibit in the employer's workplace:<section prefix="(i)">a threat, a notice, or information that, on the election or defeat of a particular ticket or candidate:<section prefix="1.">work will cease, wholly or partly;</section><section prefix="2.">the workplace will close; or</section><section prefix="3.">employees' wages will be reduced; or</section></section><section prefix="(ii)">any other threat, expressed or implied, intended to influence the political opinions or actions of the employer's employees.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(9)">A person may not publish or distribute, or cause to be published or distributed, campaign material that violates &#xA7; 13-401 of this title.</section>
      <section prefix="(10)">A candidate may not make a payment, contribution, or expenditure, or incur a liability to pay, contribute, or expend, from the candidate's personal funds any money or valuable thing in a manner not authorized by &#xA7; 13-230 of this title.</section>
      <section prefix="(11)">An individual may not sign the name of any other individual on any form or other document under this title, without the authority of the individual whose name is signed.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A person who violates this section is guilty of a misdemeanor and on conviction is:<section prefix="(1)">subject to a fine not exceeding $1,000 or imprisonment not exceeding 1 year or both; and</section><section prefix="(2)">ineligible to hold any public or party office for 4 years after the date of the offense.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The State Prosecutor may prosecute, in any jurisdiction of the State, a person that the State Prosecutor believes to be guilty of a willful violation of this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A State's Attorney may prosecute a person that the State's Attorney believes to be guilty of a willful violation of this section in the county in which the State's Attorney serves.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
