<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gel" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="1-101" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gel-1-101</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this article the following words have the meanings indicated unless a different meaning is clearly intended from the context.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Absentee ballot" means a ballot not used in a polling place.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Authorized candidate campaign committee" means a political committee established under Title 13 of this article and authorized by a candidate to promote the candidate's candidacy.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Ballot" or "official ballot" includes:<section prefix="(i)">an absentee ballot;</section><section prefix="(ii)">a provisional ballot;</section><section prefix="(iii)">a document ballot; or</section><section prefix="(iv)">a voting machine ballot.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Ballot" or "official ballot" does not include:<section prefix="(i)">a sample ballot; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">a specimen ballot.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"Ballot face" means a single side of a sheet on which are printed some or all of the contests to be voted on by a voter.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">"Ballot issue committee" means a political committee that is formed to promote the success or defeat of a question to be submitted to a vote at an election.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">"Ballot style" means a unique aggregation of contests that make up the ballot for a particular group of voters identified by common characteristics of residence location, party affiliation, or both.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">"Campaign finance entity" means a political committee established under Title 13 of this article.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">"Campaign finance report" means a report, statement, affidavit, or other document that is:<section prefix="(1)">authorized or required under this article;</section><section prefix="(2)">related to the campaign finance activities of a campaign finance entity or to expenses associated with a legislative newsletter; and</section><section prefix="(3)">filed or submitted on a form prescribed by the State Board under this article.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(j)">"Campaign manager" means a person designated by a candidate, or the candidate's representative, to exercise general overall responsibility for the conduct of the candidate's political campaign.</section>
    <section prefix="(k)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Campaign material" means any material that:<section prefix="(i)">contains text, graphics, or other images;</section><section prefix="(ii)">relates to a candidate, a prospective candidate, or the approval or rejection of a question; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">is published or distributed.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Campaign material" includes:<section prefix="(i)">material transmitted by or appearing on the Internet or other electronic medium; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">an oral commercial campaign advertisement.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(l)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Candidate" means an individual who files a certificate of candidacy for a public or party office.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Candidate" includes:<section prefix="(i)">an incumbent judge of the Court of Appeals or Court of Special Appeals at an election for continuance in office; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">an individual, prior to that individual filing a certificate of candidacy, if a campaign finance entity has been established on behalf of that individual.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(m)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Contest" means:<section prefix="(i)">the aggregate of candidates who run against each other or among themselves for nomination for, or election to, an office or multiple offices of the same category; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">the positive and negative voting options for a question submitted to the voters.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Contest" includes, in a general election for an office, the write-in option.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(n)">"Continuing political committee" means a political committee that is permitted to continue in existence from year to year.</section>
    <section prefix="(o)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Contribution" means the gift or transfer, or promise of gift or transfer, of money or other thing of value to a campaign finance entity to promote or assist in the promotion of the success or defeat of a candidate, political party, or question.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Contribution" includes proceeds from the sale of tickets to a campaign fund-raising event.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(p)">"County" means a county of the State or Baltimore City.</section>
    <section prefix="(q)">"Disabled" means having a temporary or permanent physical disability.</section>
    <section prefix="(r)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Distributor" means a person engaged for profit in the distribution of campaign material by hand delivery or direct mail.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Distributor" does not include salaried employees, agents, or volunteers of the person.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(s)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Document ballot" means a ballot used with a voting system in which the voter individually is issued a ballot on which to indicate one or more votes.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Document ballot" includes:<section prefix="(i)">a machine-read ballot, such as an optically scanned ballot; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">a hand-counted paper ballot.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(t)">"Driver's license" includes an identification card issued by the Motor Vehicle Administration.</section>
    <section prefix="(u)">"Elderly" means 65 years of age or older.</section>
    <section prefix="(v)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Election" means the process by which voters cast votes on one or more contests under the laws of this State or the United States.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Election" includes, unless otherwise specifically provided in this article, all general elections, primary elections, and special elections.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Election" does not include, unless otherwise specifically provided in this article, a municipal election other than in Baltimore City.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(w)">"Election cycle" means the period that begins on the January 1 that follows a gubernatorial election and continues until the December 31 that is 4 years later.</section>
    <section prefix="(x)">"Election register" means the list of voters eligible to vote:<section prefix="(1)">in a precinct on election day; or</section><section prefix="(2)">in a county early voting center during early voting.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(y)">"Electronic signature" means an electronic sound, symbol, or process attached to or logically associated with a record and executed or adopted by a person with the intent to sign the record.</section>
    <section prefix="(z)">"Electronic storage format" means a computer disk or other information storage and retrieval medium approved by the State Board.</section>
    <section prefix="(aa)">"Expenditure" means a gift, transfer, disbursement, or promise of money or a thing of value by or on behalf of a campaign finance entity to:<section prefix="(1)">promote or assist in the promotion of the success or defeat of a candidate, political party, or question at an election; or</section><section prefix="(2)">pay for the publication expense of a legislative newsletter under Title 13, Subtitle 4 of this article.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(bb)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Independent expenditure" means an expenditure by a person expressly advocating the success or defeat of a clearly identified candidate or ballot issue if the expenditure is not made in coordination with, or at the request or suggestion of, a candidate, a campaign finance entity of a candidate, an agent of a candidate, or a ballot issue committee.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">For purposes of this subsection, "clearly identified" means:<section prefix="(i)">the name of the candidate appears;</section><section prefix="(ii)">a photograph or drawing of the candidate appears; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">the identity of the candidate or ballot issue is apparent by unambiguous reference.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(cc)">"Local board" means a county board of elections.</section>
    <section prefix="(dd)">"Majority party" means the political party to which the incumbent Governor belongs, if the incumbent Governor is a member of a principal political party. If the incumbent Governor is not a member of one of the two principal political parties, "majority party" means the principal political party whose candidate for Governor received the highest number of votes of any party candidate at the last preceding general election.</section>
    <section prefix="(ee)">"Partisan organization" means a combination of two or more individuals formed for the purpose of organizing a new political party.</section>
    <section prefix="(ff)">"Political action committee" means a political committee that is not:<section prefix="(1)">a political party;</section><section prefix="(2)">a central committee;</section><section prefix="(3)">a slate;</section><section prefix="(4)">a political committee organized and operated solely to support or oppose a single candidate; or</section><section prefix="(5)">a political committee organized and operated solely to support or oppose a ballot issue.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(gg)">"Political committee" means a combination of two or more individuals that assists or attempts to assist in promoting the success or defeat of a candidate, political party, or question submitted to a vote at any election.</section>
    <section prefix="(hh)">"Political party" means an organized group that is qualified as a political party in accordance with Title 4 of this article.</section>
    <section prefix="(ii)">"Precinct" includes:<section prefix="(1)">an election district in a county that is not divided into precincts;</section><section prefix="(2)">an election precinct in an election district that is divided into precincts; or</section><section prefix="(3)">a precinct in a ward of the City of Baltimore.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(jj)">"Principal minority party" means the principal political party whose candidate for Governor received the second highest number of votes of any party candidate at the last preceding general election.</section>
    <section prefix="(kk)">"Principal political parties" means the majority party and the principal minority party.</section>
    <section prefix="(ll)">"Provisional ballot" means a ballot that is cast by an individual but not counted until the individual's qualifications to vote have been confirmed by the local board.</section>
    <section prefix="(mm)">"Responsible officers" means the chairman and treasurer of a political committee.</section>
    <section prefix="(nn)">"Sample ballot" means a facsimile of a ballot used for informational purposes by a person or entity other than a local board.</section>
    <section prefix="(oo)">"Slate" means a political committee of two or more candidates who join together to conduct and pay for joint campaign activities.</section>
    <section prefix="(pp)">"Specimen ballot" means a facsimile of a ballot used by a local board to provide notice to registered voters of the contents of the ballot.</section>
    <section prefix="(qq)">"State Administrator" means the State Administrator of Elections.</section>
    <section prefix="(rr)">"State Board" means the State Board of Elections.</section>
    <section prefix="(ss)">"Transfer" means a monetary contribution that is made by one campaign finance entity to another campaign finance entity, other than one made by or to a political club.</section>
    <section prefix="(tt)">"Treasurer" means an individual appointed in accordance with Title 13, Subtitle 2 of this article.</section>
    <section prefix="(uu)">"Vote" means to cast a ballot that is counted.</section>
    <section prefix="(vv)">"Voting machine" includes:<section prefix="(1)">a mechanical lever machine; and</section><section prefix="(2)">a direct recording electronic voting device.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(ww)">"Voting machine ballot" means a ballot posted on or in the voting machine and referred to by the voter to indicate the voting locations for each contest.</section>
    <section prefix="(xx)">"Voting system" means a method of casting and tabulating ballots or votes.</section>
    <section prefix="(yy)">"Write-in candidate" means an individual whose name will not appear on the ballot but who files a certificate of candidacy in accordance with &#xA7; 5-303 of this article.</section>
    <section prefix="(zz)">"Write-in vote" means a vote cast, in a contest at a general election, for an individual whose name is not on the ballot for that contest.</section>
  </text>
</law>
