<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gen" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="7-511" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gen-7-511</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Within 75 days after the Department has received a proposed response action plan, the Department, after considering any comments the Department has received under &#xA7; 7-509 of this subtitle, shall notify the participant in writing that:<section prefix="(1)">The response action plan has been approved; or</section><section prefix="(2)">The response action plan has been rejected and shall state the modifications in the response action plan that are necessary to receive the Department's approval.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">If the Department notifies a participant that modifications in a response action plan are necessary to receive the Department's approval, the participant may resubmit the plan within 120 days after receipt of the Department's notification.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">If the participant does not resubmit the plan within 120 days under subparagraph (i) of this paragraph, the participant will be considered to have withdrawn the participant's application in accordance with &#xA7; 7-512 of this subtitle.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Within 30 days after receipt of a resubmitted plan under paragraph (1) of this subsection, the Department shall notify the participant whether the plan has been approved.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The response action plan approval letter shall state that, subject to the requirements of &#xA7; 7-514 of this subtitle:<section prefix="(1)">No further action will be required to accomplish the objectives set forth in the approved response action plan other than those actions described in the approved response action plan; and</section><section prefix="(2)">The participant will receive a certificate of completion subject to the conditions and requirements of &#xA7; 7-514(b) of this subtitle if:<section prefix="(i)">The approved response action plan is implemented to the satisfaction of the Department; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">The response action plan has achieved the cleanup criteria.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A response action plan approval letter, if applicable, shall include a limitation on the permissible uses of the property that is consistent with the response action plan.</section>
  </text>
</law>
