<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gen" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="9-503" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gen-9-503</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Each county shall have a county plan or a plan with adjoining counties that:<section prefix="(1)">Is approved by the Department;</section><section prefix="(2)">Covers at least the 10-year period next following adoption by the county governing body; and</section><section prefix="(3)">Deals with:<section prefix="(i)">Water supply systems;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Sewerage systems;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Solid waste disposal systems;</section><section prefix="(iv)">Solid waste acceptance facilities; and</section><section prefix="(v)">The systematic collection and disposal of solid waste, including litter.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Except as provided in &#xA7; 9-515 of this subtitle, each county governing body shall review its county plan at least once every 3 years in accordance with a schedule set by the Department.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Each county governing body shall adopt and submit to the Department a revision or amendment to its county plan if:<section prefix="(1)">The governing body considers a revision or amendment necessary; or</section><section prefix="(2)">The Department requires a revision or amendment.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Before a county governing body adopts any revision or amendment to its county plan or adopts a new county plan, the governing body shall:<section prefix="(i)">Conduct a public hearing on the county plan, revision, or amendment that may be conducted jointly with other public hearings or meetings; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Give the principal elected official of each municipal corporation that is affected notice of the county plan, revision, or amendment at least 14 days before the hearing.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Notice of the time and place of the public hearing, together with a summary of the plan, revision, or amendment, shall be published in at least 1 newspaper of general circulation in the county once each week for 2 successive weeks, with the first publication of notice appearing at least 14 days before the hearing.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">Notice of the public hearing may be a part of the general notice listing all other items to be considered during the public hearing or meeting.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
