<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gen" order_by="gen" level="1">Environment</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gen-17-101</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this title the following words have the meanings indicated....</catch_line>
  <order_by>101</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this title the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Board" means the Marine Contractors Licensing Board.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Entity" means a business with its principal office in the State that employs more than one individual to provide marine contractor services in the State.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">"License" means a professional license issued by the Board to an individual or entity to perform marine contractor services in the State.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"Licensed marine contractor" means an individual or entity that has received a license from the Board to perform marine contractor services.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Marine contractor services" means construction, demolition, installation, alteration, repair, or salvage activities located in, on, over, or under State or private tidal wetlands.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Marine contractor services" includes:<section prefix="(i)">Dredging and filling;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The construction, demolition, installation, alteration, repair, or salvage of structures, including boathouses, boat or other personal watercraft lifts or ramps, slips, docks, floating platforms, moorings, piers, pier access structures, pilings, wetland observation platforms, wetland walkways, and wharfs; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">The construction, demolition, installation, alteration, repair, or salvage of stabilization and erosion control measures, including revetments, breakwaters, bulkheads, groins, jetties, stone sills, marsh establishments, and beach nourishment or other similar projects.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
