<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gen" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="6-833" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gen-6-833</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">For purposes of this section, a parent or legal guardian of a person at risk who is a minor is unavailable if, following reasonable efforts, the offeror is unable to locate or communicate with the parent or guardian of the minor.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If a parent or legal guardian of the minor is unavailable, the offeror may:<section prefix="(i)">Petition a court in accordance with the provisions of Title 13, Subtitle 7 of the Estates and Trusts Article to appoint a person to respond to the offer on behalf of the minor; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">File the qualified offer with the court.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The court shall appoint a person to act on behalf of the minor within 15 days after the date of filing of the petition.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A person appointed to act on behalf of the minor shall file a response with the court either rejecting or accepting the qualified offer within 30 days after appointment by the court.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The response of the person appointed to respond to the offer on behalf of the minor is subject to approval by the court.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Within 15 days after a response to a qualified offer is filed with a court under subsection (b)(3) of this section, the court:<section prefix="(1)">May hold a hearing; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Shall approve or disapprove the response to the qualified offer.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">If a court disapproves the response to the qualified offer filed by the person acting on behalf of the minor, the court may order:<section prefix="(1)">That an additional response be filed on behalf of the minor; or</section><section prefix="(2)">Any action the court considers necessary and appropriate to protect the interests of the minor.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">If the court approves a response accepting a qualified offer on behalf of the minor, the order of the court shall designate one or more persons who shall be responsible for and authorized to make all decisions on behalf of the minor necessary to implement the qualified offer.</section>
  </text>
</law>
