<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gen" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="9-657" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gen-9-657</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The sanitary commission shall classify each parcel of property on which it may make a benefit assessment as:<section prefix="(1)">Agricultural;</section><section prefix="(2)">Business or industrial;</section><section prefix="(3)">Small acreage;</section><section prefix="(4)">Subdivision; or</section><section prefix="(5)">A subclass of any of those classes.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The sanitary commission may change the classification of a parcel of property when the use of that parcel justifies its classification in another class or subclass.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Except as otherwise provided in this subtitle, the sanitary commission shall assess property:<section prefix="(1)">On a front-foot basis; or</section><section prefix="(2)">Under uniform rules and regulations adopted for the district and approved by the member counties.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as otherwise provided in this section, the sanitary commission shall make front-foot assessments that, each year, are as uniform as is reasonable and practical for each class or subclass of property in each service area.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Unless the parcel has an irregular shape, the sanitary commission shall determine the front-foot assessment for each parcel on the basis of the length of the parcel along the way in which the water pipe or sewer pipe is laid.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">If a parcel has an irregular shape, the sanitary commission shall determine the front-foot assessment in a fair and reasonable manner.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">As to a parcel classified as agricultural:<section prefix="(1)">The sanitary commission may not make a front-foot assessment until a water or sewer connection is made to the parcel; and</section><section prefix="(2)">When the water or sewer connection is made, the sanitary commission may not compute a front-foot assessment on the parcel for more than 300 feet of frontage.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">As to a parcel classified as subdivision:<section prefix="(1)">Even if the water pipe or sewer pipe does not extend along the entire frontage of the parcel, the sanitary commission may make a front-foot assessment;</section><section prefix="(2)">Unless the parcel abuts parallel streets, the sanitary commission may not make a front-foot assessment for more than 1 side of the parcel; and</section><section prefix="(3)">If the parcel is on a corner, the sanitary commission may average the frontage of the parcel and determine the front-foot assessment for the parcel in a fair and reasonable manner.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(g)">The sanitary commission may make for a parcel a front-foot assessment that is less than the assessment levied on other parcels in the service area, if the parcel is served by a system:<section prefix="(1)">That is acquired by the sanitary commission;</section><section prefix="(2)">That was not a municipal system; and</section><section prefix="(3)">Whose cost to the sanitary commission was affected by the fact that the construction costs of the system were any part of the purchase price of the parcels serviced by the system.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(h)">To acquire revenues needed to carry out the purposes of this section, the sanitary commission may change the front-foot assessment for each class and subclass of property.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this subsection "Bonnie Brook Service Area" includes the Bonnie Brook Sanitary District.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">In the Bonnie Brook Service Area, in order to make capital improvements and repairs or to establish a reserve for capital improvements and repairs, the Dorchester County Sanitary Commission may make a uniform assessment on each lot that abuts on a way in which a water main is laid.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">An assessment under this subsection is in addition to any charges made under &#xA7; 9-662 of this subtitle.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">An assessment under this section shall be based on a flat fee for each lot under uniform rules and regulations approved by the Dorchester County Commissioners.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(j)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this subsection, "service area number 1" includes sanitary district number one.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">In service area number 1, the Dorchester County Sanitary Commission shall impose, on each parcel that abuts any way in which a sewer is built, a benefit assessment of at least $50.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(k)">The sanitary commission shall give to the owner of each parcel of property written notice of:<section prefix="(1)">The class and subclass of the parcel;</section><section prefix="(2)">If a front-foot assessment method is used, the number of feet assessed and the assessment for each foot;</section><section prefix="(3)">If a method other than front-foot assessment is used, the assessment made on the parcel; and</section><section prefix="(4)">The time and place of the hearing to which the owner is entitled under this subsection.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(l)">The sanitary commission shall serve the owner with the notice by:<section prefix="(1)">Mailing the notice to the last known address of the owner;</section><section prefix="(2)">Leaving the notice with an adult who occupies the parcel; or</section><section prefix="(3)">Posting a copy of the notice on the parcel, if the parcel is vacant or unimproved.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(m)">Subject to a hearing under subsection (n) of this section, a decision of the sanitary commission as to a classification or a benefit assessment is final.</section>
    <section prefix="(n)">The sanitary commission:<section prefix="(1)">Shall give each property owner an opportunity for a hearing before the sanitary commission;</section><section prefix="(2)">Shall hold the hearing in accordance with the Administrative Procedure Act; and</section><section prefix="(3)">After the hearing, may adjust a classification or benefit assessment as appropriate.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(o)">A benefit assessment shall be paid each year for a period of years that is coextensive with the maturity date of the bonds that financed the construction that was the subject of the benefit assessment.</section>
  </text>
</law>
