<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gen" order_by="" level="1">Environment</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gen-6-414.1</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>414.1</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Except in emergency situations, before any business entity or public unit licensed under this subtitle removes or encapsulates any asbestos, the business entity or public unit shall notify the Department of:<section prefix="(1)">The location of the removal or encapsulation work; and</section><section prefix="(2)">The approximate amount of asbestos or asbestos-containing materials to be removed or encapsulated.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Except in emergency situations and except as provided in subsection (c) of this section, at least 3 days before a business entity or public unit removes or encapsulates asbestos at a work site or asbestos project that is a National Emission Standards for Hazardous Air Pollutants (NESHAP) project, the business entity or public unit shall:<section prefix="(1)">Post the number of signs that the Department requires to inform the public in the immediate vicinity that asbestos abatement is being performed; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Keep the sign posted until the Department receives written notice that the results of air monitoring in the area meet the requirements established in the regulations adopted under this section.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">For any asbestos project conducted at an electric generating station or at any other utility-controlled facility which is not routinely accessible by the public, a utility company shall be exempt from the requirements of subsection (b) of this section but shall be required to comply with any federal requirements regarding the posting of signs.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Department shall adopt regulations concerning the size, type, placement, and numbers of signs that a business entity or public unit shall post at a work site or asbestos project that is a NESHAP project.</section>
  </text>
</law>
