<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gen" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="15-605" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gen-15-605</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">A person may not continue or commence operation of any deep mine as an operator within the State without first obtaining a license from the Department.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The application for a license shall be made in writing on a form the Department furnishes and accompanied by a $200 fee. The application shall contain the information concerning the applicant that the Department requires. If a corporation, partnership, or association submits the application, it shall contain the information concerning officers, directors, and principal owners that the Department requires. Subject to subsection (c) of this section, a license is renewable annually on application made on or before January 1 of the next succeeding year and payment of a $10 renewal fee.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Secretary shall investigate each application for a license or renewal.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Secretary may not issue a license to or renew the license of an applicant if the Secretary finds that the applicant:<section prefix="(i)">Failed to correct a violation of any rule or regulation adopted under this subtitle;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Failed to comply with any provision of this subtitle; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">Forfeited any bond posted in connection with deep mining activities in any state.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">With respect to an application of a corporation, partnership, or association, the Secretary may not issue a license to or renew the license of the applicant, if the Secretary finds that any of its officers, directors, or principal owners:<section prefix="(i)">Failed and continues to fail to comply with any provision of this subtitle;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Is or has been an officer, or principal owner of any other corporation, partnership, or association that previously failed and continues to fail to comply with any provision of this subtitle; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">Forfeited any bond posted in connection with deep mining activity in any state.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The provisions of this subsection are not intended to expand the authority of the Secretary to adopt rules and regulations as otherwise provided by law.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
