<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gen" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="4-116" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gen-4-116</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Any person who violates any provision of this subtitle is guilty of a misdemeanor, and upon conviction in a court of competent jurisdiction is subject to a fine not exceeding $10,000 or imprisonment not exceeding one year or both for each violation with costs imposed in the discretion of the court.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The court may order the person to restore the area unlawfully disturbed.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Each day upon which the violation occurs constitutes a separate offense.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Any agency whose approval is required under this subtitle or any interested person may seek an injunction against any person who violates or threatens to violate any provision of this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In addition to any other sanction under this subtitle, the appropriate State, county, or municipal agency may bring a civil action against a person for a violation of this subtitle.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The action may seek the imposition of a civil penalty up to $10,000 for each violation.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">In imposing a penalty under this paragraph, the court may consider the cost of restoring the area unlawfully disturbed.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">A county or municipal agency that recovers penalties in accordance with this subtitle shall deposit them in a special fund, to be used solely for:</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">A State agency that recovers penalties in accordance with this subtitle shall deposit them into the Maryland Clean Water Fund established under &#xA7; 9-320 of this article.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">If a county or municipality fails to enforce any provision of this subtitle, the Department may request the Attorney General to take appropriate legal action to correct the violation and to recover penalties or fees under this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In addition to any other remedies available at law or in equity and after an opportunity for a hearing which may be waived in writing by the person accused of a violation, the Department may impose a penalty on any person who violates any provision of this subtitle or any regulation or plan adopted, approved, or issued under this subtitle. Any request for a hearing on a penalty issued under this subsection must be made in writing no later than 10 working days after receipt of the notice assessing a penalty.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The penalty imposed on a person under this subsection shall be:<section prefix="(i)">Up to $1,000 for each violation, but not exceeding $20,000 total for any action; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Assessed with consideration given to:</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Each day a violation occurs is a separate violation under this subsection.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">Any penalty imposed under this subsection is payable to the State and collectible in any manner provided at law for the collection of penalties.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">Any penalty collected under this subsection or for a violation of &#xA7; 4-413 of this title shall be placed in the Maryland Clean Water Fund established under &#xA7; 9-320 of this article.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
