<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gen" order_by="gen" level="1">Environment</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gen-6-821</section_number>
  <catch_line>Whenever an owner of an affected property intends to make repairs or perform maintenance work that w...</catch_line>
  <order_by>821</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Whenever an owner of an affected property intends to make repairs or perform maintenance work that will disturb the paint on interior surfaces of an affected property, the owner shall make reasonable efforts to ensure that all persons who are not persons at risk are not present in the area where work is performed and that all persons at risk are removed from the affected property when the work is performed.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A tenant shall allow access to an affected property, at reasonable times, to the owner to perform any work required under this subtitle.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">If a tenant must vacate an affected property for a period of 24 hours or more in order to allow an owner to perform work that will disturb the paint on interior surfaces, the owner shall pay the reasonable expenses that the tenant incurs directly related to the required relocation.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If an owner has made all reasonable efforts to cause the tenant to temporarily vacate an affected property in order to perform work that will disturb the paint on interior surfaces, and the tenant refuses to vacate the affected property, the owner may not be liable for any damages arising from the tenant's refusal to vacate.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If an owner has made all reasonable efforts to gain access to an affected property in order to perform any work required under this subtitle, and the tenant refuses to allow access, even after receiving reasonable advance notice of the need for access, the owner may not be liable for any damages arising from the tenant's refusal to allow access.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">All hazard reduction treatments required to be performed under this subtitle shall be performed by or under the supervision of personnel accredited under &#xA7; 6-1002 of this title.</section>
  </text>
</law>
