<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gen" order_by="gen" level="1">Environment</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gen-9-415</section_number>
  <catch_line>The Department shall give notice and hold hearings under this subtitle in accordance with the Admini...</catch_line>
  <order_by>415</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Department shall give notice and hold hearings under this subtitle in accordance with the Administrative Procedure Act.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Within 30 days after service of the order under this subtitle the person served may request in writing a hearing before the Department.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">If a person served with an order under this subsection makes a timely request for a hearing, the Department shall give the person written notice of the date, time, and place of the hearing, at least 10 days before the hearing date.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The order becomes final when the Department renders its decision following the hearing.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Department may make a verbatim record of the proceedings of any hearing held under this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In connection with any hearing under this subtitle, the Department may:<section prefix="(i)">Subpoena any person or evidence; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Order a witness to give evidence.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A subpoenaed witness shall receive the same fees and mileage reimbursement as if the hearing were part of a civil action.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">If a person fails to comply with a subpoena or order issued under this subsection, on petition of the Department, a circuit court, by order may:<section prefix="(i)">Compel obedience to the Department's order or subpoena; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">Compel testimony or the production of evidence.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The court may punish as contempt any failure to obey its order issued under this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">Any person aggrieved by a final decision of the Department in connection with an order or a permit issued under this subtitle may take judicial appeal in accordance with the Administrative Procedure Act.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
