<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gen" order_by="" level="1">Environment</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gen-9-939</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>939</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">A resolution or trust agreement that provides for the issuance of or secures bonds under this subtitle may:<section prefix="(1)">Include any of the provisions in subsections (c) through (f) of this section; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Require the authority to adopt resolutions or take any other lawful action that is necessary to enforce those provisions.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">If a resolution or trust agreement includes any of the provisions of subsections (c) through (f) of this section, the authority may adopt resolutions and take any other lawful action that is necessary to enforce those provisions.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">If the owner, tenant, or occupant of a parcel of land is obligated to pay rates, fees, or charges for the use of or services furnished by any project of an authority, the authority may require the owner, tenant, or occupant to deposit with the authority, before the use is made or the services are furnished, a reasonable amount:<section prefix="(1)">To insure payment of the rates, fees, or charges; and</section><section prefix="(2)">To be applied to payment of any delinquent rates, fees, or charges.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">If the owner, tenant, or occupant of a parcel of land does not pay any rate, fee, or charge for the use of or services furnished by any project of an authority within 30 days after the rate, fee, or charge becomes due and payable, the authority, at the end of the 30-day period, may:<section prefix="(1)">Disconnect the parcel of land from the water system or sewerage system of the authority or otherwise suspend services; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Recover the amount of the rate, fee, or charge that is delinquent, plus interest:<section prefix="(i)">In a civil action; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">By foreclosure of the lien for the rate, fee, or charge.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">If any rate, fee, or charge for the use of or services furnished to a lot or parcel of land by a sewerage system that is owned, constructed, or operated by an authority under this subtitle is not paid within 30 days after the rate, fee, or charge becomes due and payable, the owner, tenant, or occupant of the parcel of land shall stop disposing of sewage or industrial wastes from the parcel of land directly or indirectly into the sewerage system until the rate, fee, or charge, plus interest, is paid.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If the owner, tenant, or occupant of a parcel of land does not stop disposing of sewage or industrial wastes as required by subsection (e) of this section, any political subdivision or person who supplies or sells water for use on the parcel of land shall stop supplying or selling the water within 5 days after receiving notice of the delinquency from the authority.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If a political subdivision or person does not stop supplying or selling water for use on a parcel of land as required by paragraph (1) of this subsection, the authority may shut off the supply of water to the parcel of land.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
