<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gen" order_by="gen" level="1">Environment</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gen-15-828</section_number>
  <catch_line>At any reasonable time which the Department elects, but at least once a year, the Department shall c...</catch_line>
  <order_by>828</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">At any reasonable time which the Department elects, but at least once a year, the Department shall cause each permit area to be inspected to determine if the permittee has complied with the mining and reclamation plan, the requirements of this subtitle, any rules and regulations adopted under it, the terms and conditions of the permit, and if the current status of the operation conforms with the most recent annual progress report. Accredited representatives of the Department at any reasonable time may enter on the land subject to the permit to inspect and investigate it but while on the property, Department personnel shall comply with all governmental safety regulations.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The permittee shall proceed with reclamation as scheduled in the approved mining and reclamation plan. Following each inspection, the Department shall notify the permittee by certified mail, return receipt requested, bearing a postmark from the United States Postal Service, of any deficiencies noted. The permittee shall proceed with mining and reclamation as scheduled in the approved mining and reclamation plan. Following each inspection, the Department shall notify the permittee of any deficiencies noted. Upon failure by the permittee to correct these deficiencies, the Department may take action to suspend or revoke the permit as provided in &#xA7; 15-821 of this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">If the Department finds that reclamation of the permit area is not proceeding in accordance with the mining and reclamation plan, or if the Department finds that reclamation has not been properly completed in conformance with the mining and reclamation plan within two years or longer if authorized by the Department, after termination of mining on any segment of the permit area, or if the permittee has not complied with corrective requirements following revocation of a permit, it shall initiate forfeiture proceedings against the bond or other security filed by the permittee.</section>
  </text>
</law>
