<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gen" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="13-308" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gen-13-308</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">A license expires on the date set by the Board, unless the license is renewed for an additional term as provided in this section. A license may not be renewed for a term longer than 2 years.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">At least 1 month before the license expires, the Board shall send to the licensee, by first-class mail to the last known address of the licensee, a renewal notice that states:<section prefix="(1)">The date on which the current license expires;</section><section prefix="(2)">The date by which the renewal application must be received by the Board for the renewal to be issued and mailed before the license expires; and</section><section prefix="(3)">The amount of the renewal fee.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Before the license expires, the licensee periodically may renew it for an additional 2-year term if the licensee:<section prefix="(1)">Otherwise is entitled to be licensed;</section><section prefix="(2)">Pays to the Board a renewal fee set by the Board; and</section><section prefix="(3)">Submits to the Board:<section prefix="(i)">A renewal application on the form that the Board requires;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Satisfactory evidence of compliance with the performance bond and contractor's liability insurance requirements of the Board; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Satisfactory evidence of compliance with any continuing education requirement established under this subtitle for license renewal.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Beginning July 1, 1985, within the license renewal period, each licensee shall comply with the continuing education requirements of this section as a precondition for the renewal of that license.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A licensee shall complete 20 hours of approved continuing education instruction covering well drilling subject matter approved by the Board.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The Board shall approve the substance and form of each continuing education course, if the course is:</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The licensee is responsible for the cost of any continuing education course.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The Board may waive the requirements of this subsection if a person can show just cause why that person is not able to meet the requirements.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The Board may not require a licensee who applies for a renewal of the license to take an examination.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The Board shall renew the license of each licensee who meets the requirements of this section.</section>
  </text>
</law>
