<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gen" order_by="gen" level="1">Environment</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gen-9-410</section_number>
  <catch_line>Each supplier of water shall give notice to the Department and the persons served by the system and ...</catch_line>
  <order_by>410</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Each supplier of water shall give notice to the Department and the persons served by the system and shall give written notice to noncollegiate educational institutions, public schools, family child care homes, and child care centers whenever the system:<section prefix="(1)">Fails to comply with an applicable maximum contaminant level, treatment technique requirement, or testing procedure prescribed by a drinking water regulation or fails to perform required monitoring;</section><section prefix="(2)">Is subject to variance granted for an inability to meet a maximum contaminant level;</section><section prefix="(3)">Is subject to an exemption;</section><section prefix="(4)">Fails to comply with the requirements set by a variance or exemption; or</section><section prefix="(5)">Has concentration levels of an unregulated contaminant for which the State may require notice due to the risk to public health.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Each notice shall:<section prefix="(1)">State the nature and possible health effects that may result;</section><section prefix="(2)">Be provided to the persons served by the water system;</section><section prefix="(3)">Be issued in a timely manner by means of radio, television, newspaper of general circulation, written notice, or other means acceptable to the Department; and</section><section prefix="(4)">Be in a form readily understandable by the affected population.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">By rule or regulation, the Secretary shall adopt notice requirements to meet the requirements of this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The rules and regulations shall establish notification standards and procedures that include the manner, frequency, form, and content of the notices.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">For violations with the potential to have serious adverse effects on human health as a result of short-term exposure, the supplier of water shall provide notice as soon as practicable, but not later than 24 hours after the occurrence of the violation.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">For violations other than the violations described in subsection (d) of this section, the supplier of water shall provide written notice to each person served by the system in an annual report, or by mail not later than 1 year after the violation.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Each nontransient noncommunity water system, including those systems that primarily provide bottled water, shall:<section prefix="(i)">At a frequency determined by the Department, test the water provided by the system for the presence of methyl tertiary butyl ether; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Report the test results to the Department.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If a test conducted under this subsection indicates that the level of methyl tertiary butyl ether in the drinking water exceeds the State advisory level, as determined by the Department, the water system shall give notice of that fact to:<section prefix="(i)">The persons regularly served by the water system; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">If the water system serves a child care center, an elementary or secondary school, or any other facility that regularly serves minors, the parents or legal guardians of all minors regularly served by the water system.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
