<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gen" order_by="gen" level="1">Environment</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gen-6-1107</section_number>
  <catch_line>Except as provided in subsection (d) of this section, by January 1, 1995 each unit, and each easily ...</catch_line>
  <order_by>1107</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Except as provided in subsection (d) of this section, by January 1, 1995 each unit, and each easily removable rechargeable battery contained in a product, sold in the State shall be covered by a unit management program approved by the Department. A unit management program may be submitted by or on behalf of any person having responsibilities under this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A unit management program shall:<section prefix="(1)">Provide the name, address and telephone number of each responsible entity;</section><section prefix="(2)">Describe the units and products which each responsible entity shall ensure will be collected and transported under the program; and</section><section prefix="(3)">Generally describe the unit management program including methods of unit collection, transportation, and recycling or proper disposal.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A unit management program shall be submitted to the Department prior to the sale of any unit, or of any product with an easily removable rechargeable battery, by a marketer in this State which takes place after December 31, 1994. Any change in a responsible entity, address or telephone number, covered units or products, or disposition of units under a unit management program shall be reported to the Department within 90 days after the change takes place.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Notwithstanding subsection (a) of this section, nothing in this subtitle may be construed to prohibit the sale to an original equipment manufacturer by a cell manufacturer of a cell not covered under a unit management program.</section>
  </text>
</law>
