<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gen" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="9-401" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gen-9-401</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Administrator" means the Administrator of the United States Environmental Protection Agency.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Community water system" means a public water system that:<section prefix="(1)">Serves at least 15 service connections used by year-round residents of the area served by the system; or</section><section prefix="(2)">Regularly serves at least 25 year-round residents.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">"Contaminant" means any chemical, biological, or radioactive substance that is harmful to health if in the water.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"Federal Act" means the federal Safe Drinking Water Act.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">"Federal agency" means any department, agency, or instrumentality of the United States.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">"National primary drinking water regulations" means the primary drinking water rules or regulations that the Administrator adopts under the federal Act.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">"Noncommunity water system" means a public water system that is not a community water system.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">"Nontransient noncommunity water system" means a public water system that is not a community system and that regularly serves at least 25 of the same individuals over 6 months per year.</section>
    <section prefix="(j)">"Person" includes:<section prefix="(1)">The Washington Suburban Sanitary Commission;</section><section prefix="(2)">Any State, county, municipal corporation, or federal agency;</section><section prefix="(3)">Any special taxing area or district that operates a public water system; and</section><section prefix="(4)">Any officer, agent, or employee of any of these.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(k)">"Primary drinking water regulation" means a rule or regulation that:<section prefix="(1)">Applies to public water systems;</section><section prefix="(2)">Specifies contaminants that, in the judgment of the Secretary, would have an adverse effect on the health of human beings;</section><section prefix="(3)">Specifies for each contaminant either:<section prefix="(i)">A maximum contaminant level if, in the judgment of the Secretary, it is economically and technologically feasible to determine the level of the contaminant in water in public water systems; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">If, in the judgment of the Secretary, it is not economically or technologically feasible to determine the level of the contaminant, each treatment technique known to the Secretary that leads to a reduction in the level of the contaminant sufficient to satisfy the requirements of this subtitle; and</section></section><section prefix="(4)">Contains standards and procedures:<section prefix="(i)">To ensure a supply of drinking water that dependably complies with the maximum contaminant levels, including quality control and testing procedures for compliance with those levels;</section><section prefix="(ii)">To ensure proper operation and maintenance of the system; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">To establish requirements as to:</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(l)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Public water system" means a system that:<section prefix="(i)">Provides to the public water for human consumption through pipes or other constructed conveyances; and</section><section prefix="(ii)"/></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Public water system" includes:<section prefix="(i)">Any collection, treatment, storage, or distribution facility that is under the control of the operator of the system and is used primarily in connection with the system; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Any collection or pretreatment storage facility that is not under the control of the operator of the system and is used primarily in connection with the system.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(m)">"Supplier of water" means any person who owns or operates a public water system.</section>
    <section prefix="(n)">"Transient noncommunity water system" means a noncommunity water system that does not regularly serve at least 25 of the same individuals over 6 months per year.</section>
    <section prefix="(o)">"Tamper" means to:<section prefix="(1)">Introduce a contaminant into a public water system with the intention of harming a person; or</section><section prefix="(2)">Otherwise interfere with the operation of a public water system with the intention of harming a person.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
