<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gen" order_by="" level="1">Environment</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gen-2-101</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>101</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this title the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Air pollution" means the presence in the outdoor atmosphere of any substance that is present in such quantities and is of such duration that it:<section prefix="(1)">May be predicted with reasonable certainty to be injurious to property or to human, plant, or animal life; or</section><section prefix="(2)">Unreasonably interferes with the proper enjoyment of the property of others because of the emission of odors, solids, vapors, liquids, or gases.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Council" means the Air Quality Control Advisory Council.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">"Emergency" means:<section prefix="(1)">A condition of such public gravity and urgency that it requires immediate response; or</section><section prefix="(2)">A condition that is predicted to a reasonable degree of certainty to require immediate action to carry out the provisions of this title.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Emission standard" means a requirement that limits the quantity, quality, rate, or concentration of emissions from a source.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Emission standard" includes any requirement that relates to the operation or maintenance of a source to assure continuous emission reduction.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">"Person" includes any public or municipal corporation and any agency, bureau, department, or instrumentality of federal, State, or local government.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">"Political subdivision" means a county or municipal corporation of this State.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">"Regulated emissions" means the actual rate of emissions, in tons per year, of any registered pollutant emitted by a source, to be calculated using criteria consistent with 40 C.F.R. 70 (Operating Permit Program).</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">"Source" means any person or property that contributes to air pollution.</section>
  </text>
</law>
