<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gen" order_by="" level="1">Environment</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gen-5-911</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>911</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The enforcement provisions in this section are in addition to any other applicable provisions in this title.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">In addition to the enforcement authority granted the Department, the enforcement provisions of this section may be exercised by any county that has program delegation authority.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Department may revoke a permit for cause, including violation of permit conditions, obtaining a permit by misrepresentation, failing to disclose a relevant or material fact, or change in conditions. The Department shall notify the violator in writing and provide an opportunity for a hearing.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Department may issue a stop work order against any person who violates any provision of this subtitle or any regulation, order, or permit under this subtitle related to a regulated activity.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A person who violates any provision of this subtitle or any regulation, order, or permit under this subtitle is liable for a penalty not exceeding $10,000, which may be recovered in a civil action brought by the Department. Each day a violation continues is a separate violation under this subsection.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The court may issue an injunction requiring the person to cease the violation and restore the area unlawfully disturbed.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A person who violates any provision of or fails to perform any duty imposed by this subtitle or by a regulation, order, or permit under this subtitle is guilty of a misdemeanor and on conviction is subject to:<section prefix="(i)">For a first offense, a fine not exceeding $10,000; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">For a second or subsequent offense, a fine not exceeding $25,000.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The court may order the person to restore the area unlawfully disturbed.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
