<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gen" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="16-101" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gen-16-101</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this title the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Board" means the Board of Public Works.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"County" includes Baltimore City unless otherwise indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">"Department" means the Department of the Environment.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"Dredging" means the removal or displacement by any means of soil, sand, gravel, shells, or other material, whether or not of intrinsic value, from any State or private wetlands.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Filling" means:<section prefix="(i)">The displacement of navigable water by the depositing into State or private wetlands of soil, sand, gravel, shells, or other materials; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">The artificial alteration of navigable water levels by any physical structure, drainage ditch, or otherwise.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Filling" includes storm drain projects which flow directly into tidal waters of the State.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Filling" does not include:<section prefix="(i)">Drainage of agricultural land;</section><section prefix="(ii)">In-place replacement or repair of shore erosion control structures using substantially similar materials and construction design; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">Planting of wetlands vegetation when no grading or fill in State or private wetlands is necessary.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">"Landward boundary of wetlands" means the common boundary between wetlands, as defined in this section, and lands not included within the definitions of wetlands appearing in this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">"Licensed marine contractor" has the meaning stated in Title 17, Subtitle 3 of this article.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">"Person" means any natural person, partnership, joint-stock company, unincorporated association or society, the federal government, the State, any unit of the State, a political subdivision, or other corporation of any type.</section>
    <section prefix="(j)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Pier" means any pier, wharf, dock, walkway, bulkhead, breakwater, piles, or other similar structure.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Pier" does not include any structure on pilings or stilts that was originally constructed beyond the landward boundaries of State or private wetlands.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(k)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Private wetlands" means any land not considered "State wetland" bordering on or lying beneath tidal waters, which is subject to regular or periodic tidal action and supports aquatic growth.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Private wetlands" includes wetlands, transferred by the State by a valid grant, lease, patent, or grant confirmed by Article 5 of the Maryland Declaration of Rights, to the extent of the interest transferred.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(l)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Public notice" means the public notice and public informational hearing procedures established in &#xA7; 5-204(b) through (e) of this article.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Public notice" does not mean notice as provided for in &#xA7; 16-303 of this title.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(m)">"Regular or periodic tidal action" means the rise and fall of the sea produced by the attraction of the sun and moon uninfluenced by wind or any other circumstance.</section>
    <section prefix="(n)">"Secretary" means the Secretary of the Environment.</section>
    <section prefix="(o)">"State wetlands" means any land under the navigable waters of the State below the mean high tide, affected by the regular rise and fall of the tide. Wetlands of this category which have been transferred by the State by valid grant, lease, patent or grant confirmed by Article 5 of the Maryland Declaration of Rights shall be considered "private wetland" to the extent of the interest transferred.</section>
  </text>
</law>
