<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gen" order_by="" level="1">Environment</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gen-6-801</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>801</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Affected property" means:<section prefix="(i)">A property constructed before 1950 that contains at least one rental dwelling unit;</section><section prefix="(ii)">On and after January 1, 2015, a property constructed before 1978 that contains at least one rental unit; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">Any residential rental property for which the owner makes an election under &#xA7; 6-803(a)(2) of this subtitle.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Affected property" includes an individual rental dwelling unit within a multifamily rental dwelling.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Affected property" does not include property exempted under &#xA7; 6-803(b) of this subtitle.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Change in occupancy" means a change of tenant in an affected property in which the property is vacated and possession is either surrendered to the owner or abandoned.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">"Child" means an individual under the age of 6 years.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"Commission" means the Lead Poisoning Prevention Commission.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Elevated blood lead" or "EBL" means a quantity of lead in blood, expressed in micrograms per deciliter (&#xB5;g/dl), that exceeds the threshold level specified in this subtitle and is determined in accordance with the following protocols:<section prefix="(i)">A venous blood test; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">Two capillary blood tests taken in accordance with paragraph (2) of this subsection.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If the capillary blood test method is used, an individual shall:<section prefix="(i)">Have a first sample of capillary blood drawn and tested; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Have a second sample of capillary blood drawn and tested within 84 days after the first sample is drawn.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">If the result of one capillary blood test would require action under this subtitle and the other result would not, an individual's elevated blood lead level shall be confirmed by a venous blood test.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">"Exterior surfaces" means:<section prefix="(1)">All fences and porches that are part of an affected property;</section><section prefix="(2)">All outside surfaces of an affected property that are accessible to a child and that are:<section prefix="(i)">Attached to the outside of an affected property; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">Other buildings and structures, including play equipment, benches, and laundry line poles, that are part of the affected property, except buildings or structures that are not owned or controlled by the owner of the affected property; and</section></section><section prefix="(3)">All painted surfaces in stairways, hallways, entrance areas, recreation areas, laundry areas, and garages within a multifamily rental dwelling unit that are common to individual dwelling units and are accessible to a child.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(h)">"Fund" means the Lead Poisoning Prevention Fund.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"High efficiency particle air vacuum" or "HEPA-vacuum" means a device capable of filtering out particles of 0.3 microns or greater from a body of air at an efficiency of 99.97% or greater.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"HEPA-vacuum" includes use of a HEPA-vacuum.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(j)">"Lead-based paint" means paint or other surface coatings that contain lead in excess of the maximum lead content level allowed by the Department by regulation.</section>
    <section prefix="(k)">"Lead-contaminated dust" means dust in affected properties that contains an area or mass concentration of lead in excess of the lead content level determined by the Department by regulation.</section>
    <section prefix="(l)">"Lead-free" means at or below a lead content level deemed to be lead-free in accordance with criteria established by the Department by regulation.</section>
    <section prefix="(m)">"Lead-safe housing" means a rental dwelling unit that:<section prefix="(1)">Is certified to be lead-free in accordance with &#xA7; 6-804 of this subtitle;</section><section prefix="(2)">Was constructed after 1978;</section><section prefix="(3)">Is deemed to be lead-safe by the Department in accordance with criteria established by the Department by regulation; or</section><section prefix="(4)">Is certified to be in compliance with &#xA7; 6-815(a) of this subtitle and:<section prefix="(i)">In which all windows are either lead-free or have been treated so that all friction surfaces are lead-free;</section><section prefix="(ii)">In which lead-contaminated dust levels are determined to be within abatement clearance levels established by the Department by regulation, within a time frame established by the Department by regulation; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Which is subject to ongoing maintenance and testing as specified by the Department by regulation.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(n)">"Multifamily rental dwelling" means a property which contains more than one rental dwelling unit.</section>
    <section prefix="(o)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Owner" means a person, firm, corporation, guardian, conservator, receiver, trustee, executor, or legal representative who, alone or jointly or severally with others, owns, holds, or controls the whole or any part of the freehold or leasehold interest to any property, with or without actual possession.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Owner" includes:<section prefix="(i)">Any vendee in possession of the property; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Any authorized agent of the owner, including a property manager or leasing agent.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Owner" does not include:<section prefix="(i)">A trustee or a beneficiary under a deed of trust or a mortgagee; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">The owner of a reversionary interest under a ground rent lease.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(p)">"Person at risk" means a child or a pregnant woman who resides or regularly spends at least 24 hours per week in an affected property.</section>
    <section prefix="(q)">"Related party" means any:<section prefix="(1)">Person related to an owner by blood or marriage;</section><section prefix="(2)">Employee of the owner; or</section><section prefix="(3)">Entity in which an owner, or any person referred to in paragraph (1) or (2) of this subsection, has an interest.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(r)">"Relocation expenses" means all expenses necessitated by the relocation of a tenant's household to lead-safe housing, including moving and hauling expenses, the HEPA-vacuuming of all upholstered furniture, payment of a security deposit for the lead-safe housing, and installation and connection of utilities and appliances.</section>
    <section prefix="(s)">"Rent subsidy" means the difference between the rent paid by a tenant for housing at the time a qualified offer is made under Part V of this subtitle and the rent due for the lead-safe housing to which the tenant is relocated.</section>
    <section prefix="(t)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Rental dwelling unit" means a room or group of rooms that form a single independent habitable rental unit for permanent occupation by one or more individuals that has living facilities with permanent provisions for living, sleeping, eating, cooking, and sanitation.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Rental dwelling unit" does not include:<section prefix="(i)">An area not used for living, sleeping, eating, cooking, or sanitation, such as an unfinished basement;</section><section prefix="(ii)">A unit within a hotel, motel, or similar seasonal or transient facility;</section><section prefix="(iii)">An area which is secured and inaccessible to occupants; or</section><section prefix="(iv)">A unit which is not offered for rent.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(u)">"Risk reduction standard" means a risk reduction standard established under &#xA7; 6-815 or &#xA7; 6-819 of this subtitle.</section>
  </text>
</law>
