<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gen" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="9-1711" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gen-9-1711</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This section applies only to:<section prefix="(i)">A property owner or manager of an apartment building that contains 10 or more dwelling units; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">A council of unit owners of a condominium that contains 10 or more dwelling units.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">This section does not affect the authority of a county, municipality, or other local government to enact and enforce recycling requirements, including establishing civil penalties, for an apartment building or a condominium that are more stringent than the requirements of this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">This section does not require a county to manage or enforce the recycling activities of an apartment building or condominium that is located within the boundaries of a municipality.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">On or before October 1, 2014, each property owner or manager of an apartment building or a council of unit owners of a condominium shall provide for recycling for the residents of the dwelling units, including:<section prefix="(i)">The collection of recyclable materials from residents of the dwelling units; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">The removal for further recycling of recyclable materials collected from residents of the dwelling units.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A county may require a property owner or manager of an apartment building or a council of unit owners of a condominium that provides for recycling for the residents of the dwelling units in accordance with paragraph (1) of this subsection to report to the county on recycling activities in a manner determined by the county.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The recycling required under subsection (b) of this section shall be carried out in accordance with the recycling plan required under &#xA7; 9-1703 of this subtitle for the county in which the apartment building or condominium that contains 10 or more dwelling units is located.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A person that violates subsection (b) or (c) of this section is subject to a civil penalty not exceeding $50 for each day on which the violation exists.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">An enforcement unit, officer, or official of a county, municipality, or other local government may conduct inspections of an apartment building or condominium to enforce subsection (b) of this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">Any penalties collected under subsection (d) of this section shall be paid to the county, municipality, or other local government that brought the enforcement action.</section>
  </text>
</law>
