<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gen" order_by="" level="1">Environment</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gen-9-692</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>692</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">A district may use the proceeds from bonds issued under this subtitle only:<section prefix="(1)">To pay costs incurred for the projects for which the bonds were issued; or</section><section prefix="(2)">In accordance with this section.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The district shall disburse the proceeds as the sanitary commission provided in its authorizing resolution.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If the proceeds from bonds issued under this subtitle are insufficient to pay the costs incurred for the projects for which the bonds were issued, the district may issue additional bonds to make up the deficit.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Unless the sanitary commission provided otherwise in its authorizing resolution, bonds issued under this subsection:<section prefix="(i)">Are deemed to be from the same series that originally was issued for the project; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Shall be repaid without preference to or priority for the bonds that already were issued for the project.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">If the proceeds from bonds issued under this subtitle exceed the costs incurred for the projects for which the bonds were issued and if the authorizing resolution so requires, the district shall use the surplus to retire bonds of the same series.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">If the proceeds from bonds issued under this subtitle exceed the costs incurred for the projects for which the bonds were issued and if the authorizing resolution does not otherwise require:<section prefix="(1)">The district shall use the surplus to pay the next payment of principal on the bonds;</section><section prefix="(2)">The sanitary commission shall adopt a resolution that authorizes the use of the surplus to pay for other projects that are in the same service areas as the projects for which the bonds were issued and then use the surplus in accordance with the resolution; or</section><section prefix="(3)">The district shall use the surplus to cancel bonds of the same series by buying the bonds on the open market at a price that:<section prefix="(i)">Does not include a premium of more than 5 percent of the par value; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">The sanitary commission determines to be in the best interests of the district and the member counties served by the projects for which the bonds having excess proceeds were issued.</section></section></section>
  </text>
</law>
