<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gen" order_by="gen" level="1">Environment</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gen-15-615</section_number>
  <catch_line>By the twenty-fifth day of each month, a deep mine operator shall file a monthly progress report wit...</catch_line>
  <order_by>615</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">By the twenty-fifth day of each month, a deep mine operator shall file a monthly progress report with the Secretary on a form furnished by the Secretary. In the report, the operator shall indicate the total area affected, number of mine openings, tonnage of coal removed, and changes in this information over previous months. An annual report shall be furnished to the Secretary not later than February 25 of each year for the preceding year covering facts the Secretary may require regarding the production and condition of the operation during the calendar year preceding. The operator also shall update the information on the maps previously supplied with the permit application.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">On the basis of the approved annual and monthly progress or completion reports the Secretary shall assess a 15-cent surcharge for each ton of coal removed during the past year. Nine cents of the amounts collected from each ton of coal removed shall be retained by the Secretary and 6 cents shall be remitted directly to the county in which the coal was removed.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Every six months the operator of each mine shall cause to be accurately shown on the map and on the copies any extension of any portion of the mine, which was made during the intervening period, and any portion of the mine and mine workings, discontinued or abandoned.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">If the district mine inspector reasonably believes that any map of any mine or copy furnished to him under the provisions of this section is inaccurate, he may order a survey of what he believes has been mapped incorrectly. The cost of the survey is recoverable from the operator as other debts are recoverable by law. However, if the map claimed to be inaccurate is found to be sufficiently accurate for its intended purpose, the reasonable cost of the survey is payable by the State.</section>
  </text>
</law>
