<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gen" order_by="gen" level="1">Environment</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gen-7-223</section_number>
  <catch_line>By July 1, 1984, the Department shall publish a master list of all sites at which the Department has...</catch_line>
  <order_by>223</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">By July 1, 1984, the Department shall publish a master list of all sites at which the Department has reason to believe or has been notified that controlled hazardous substances may be present.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The master list shall be updated periodically.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">By July 1, 1984, and each 6 months thereafter, the Department shall publish a list of proposed sites from the master list at which the Department intends to conduct preliminary site assessments.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The list of proposed sites shall contain at least:<section prefix="(i)">A general description of the site, including its geographical location;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The basis for its listing, including the identity and quantity of controlled hazardous substances thought to be present, if known; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">The status or findings of the preliminary site assessment.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Department shall conduct a preliminary site assessment of sites within 6 months of their initial listing. The preliminary site assessment shall provide the basis for listing a site on the disposal site registry.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">By January 1, 1985, the Department shall publish a State Hazardous Substance Response Plan that shall set forth procedures and standards for responding to releases of hazardous substances.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Hazardous Substance Response Plan to the greatest extent practicable shall be consistent with the National Contingency Plan established under &#xA7; 105 of the federal act.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The State Hazardous Substance Response Plan shall set forth the criteria for the final listing of sites and for ranking sites that require site investigation, restoration, and remedial action under this article.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The criteria shall take into account factors relating to public health and the environment, including:<section prefix="(i)">Potential hazards to public health and the environment;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The risk of fire or explosion;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Toxic hazards; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">The criteria established under &#xA7; 105(8) of the federal act.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">By January 1, 1986, the Secretary shall publish and revise at least annually a listing of hazardous waste sites, to be known as the disposal site registry.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The disposal site registry shall rank sites in priority for State remedial action, and include the following information with regard to each site:<section prefix="(i)">A general description of the site, including its location, acreage, adjacent waterways, and estimates of the identity and the quantity of any controlled hazardous substance present;</section><section prefix="(ii)">An assessment by the Department of any threat to public health or natural resources posed by the site;</section><section prefix="(iii)">The status of any removal, restoration, or other remedial actions in progress or recommended by the Department;</section><section prefix="(iv)">An assessment of the relative priority of the need for removal, restoration, or other remedial action at each site; and</section><section prefix="(v)">A proposed time frame for site investigation and any necessary remedial action.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
