<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gen" order_by="gen" level="1">Environment</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gen-6-1101</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated....</catch_line>
  <order_by>1101</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Cell" means a galvanic or voltaic device weighing 25 pounds or less consisting of an enclosed or sealed container which contains a positive and a negative electrode consisting primarily of cadmium or lead, and which contains a gel or liquid starved electrolyte.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Cell manufacturer" means a person who:<section prefix="(1)">Manufactures cells in the United States; or</section><section prefix="(2)">Imports into the United States cells or units for which no unit management program has been put into effect by the actual manufacturer of the cell or unit.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">"Easily removed", with respect to a rechargeable battery which powers a rechargeable product, means removable by hand or by using common household tools.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"Institutional user" means a person conducting medical, commercial, industrial, governmental, or similar operations.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Marketer" means a person who manufactures, assembles, sells, distributes, affixes a brand name or private label to, or licenses the use of a brand name on a unit or product with an easily removable rechargeable battery.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Except for a person who affixes a brand name or private label to a unit or to a product with an easily removable rechargeable battery, "marketer" does not include a person engaged in the retail sale of a unit or of a rechargeable product.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">"Nonremovable", with respect to a rechargeable battery which powers a rechargeable product, means not easily removed.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Rechargeable battery" means any type of enclosed device or sealed container which consists of one or more cells and which weighs 25 pounds or less.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Rechargeable battery" does not include a battery used as a power source for starting a motor vehicle.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(i)">"Rechargeable product" means a device for which the primary power source is a nonremovable rechargeable battery.</section>
    <section prefix="(j)">"Responsible entity" means a person designated in a unit management program, or in the absence of a unit management program, the marketer whose name appears on a unit.</section>
    <section prefix="(k)">"Sell" means to sell, offer for sale, or offer for promotional purposes a unit or a product with an easily removable rechargeable battery.</section>
    <section prefix="(l)">"Unit" means a cell, a rechargeable battery, or a rechargeable product.</section>
    <section prefix="(m)">"Unit management program" means a program or system for the collection, recycling, or disposal of units put in place by a marketer under &#xA7; 6-1107 of this subtitle.</section>
  </text>
</law>
