<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gen" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="9-1606.1" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gen-9-1606.1</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Lender" means a financial institution that:<section prefix="(i)">Is eligible to make commercial loans;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Agrees to receive linked deposits under this subtitle; and</section><section prefix="(iii)"/></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Linked deposit" means a deposit or investment that is placed by the Administration with a lender and earns income below the prevailing market rate for equivalent deposits or investments made with the lender at the time of the deposit or investment.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">"Linked deposit loan" means a loan from a lender to a borrower that:<section prefix="(i)">Is used for the purposes of &#xA7; 9-1605(d)(6) or &#xA7; 9-1605.1(d)(7) of this subtitle; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Is provided at an interest rate below the prevailing market rate to the same extent income earned on the linked deposit is below income paid on equivalent deposits.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(5)">"Linked Deposit Program" means a program established by the Administration whereby a linked deposit is placed with a lender based on the agreement of the lender to provide a linked deposit loan to a borrower.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A borrower desiring to acquire a linked deposit loan shall apply to a lender.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Administration shall certify to a lender that a borrower is eligible for a linked deposit loan consistent with &#xA7; 9-1605(d)(6) or &#xA7; 9-1605.1(d)(7) of this subtitle.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Upon approval of a linked deposit loan by the lender, the Administration and lender shall enter into an agreement under which the amount and term of, and schedule for payment of principal and interest on, the linked deposit shall be determined.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">On receiving a linked deposit from the Administration, the lender shall execute a loan commitment with the borrower.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">A linked deposit loan is not a debt of the State or a pledge of the credit of the State.</section>
  </text>
</law>
