<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gen" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="9-243" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gen-9-243</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">To enforce this Part III of this subtitle and to insure compliance with each sewage sludge utilization permit, a representative of the Department, the local health official, or the local health official's designee may enter and inspect, at any reasonable time, any site where sewage sludge is utilized.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A sewage sludge utilizer may not:<section prefix="(1)">Refuse access to a sewage sludge utilization site to any representative of the Department, to a local health official, or to the local health official's designee, who requests access under this section; or</section><section prefix="(2)">Interfere with any inspection under this subtitle.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A local health official or the local health official's designee may inspect, monitor, and investigate any sewage sludge utilization site in the county where the official is employed.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">With the concurrence of the Department, a local health official may:<section prefix="(i)">Issue a stop work order to stop utilizing sewage sludge at a site; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Suspend a sewage sludge utilization permit.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If a local health official recommends issuance of a stop work order and the Department does not concur, the Department shall inspect the sewage sludge utilization site within 24 hours after it receives the recommendation.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">After inspecting the site and if necessary, the Department shall issue a stop work or other order to obtain compliance with State law, departmental regulations, or the sewage sludge utilization permit.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">A county may seek injunctive relief or other appropriate remedies in circuit court if:<section prefix="(i)">A local health official is not satisfied that the enforcement measures of the Department are adequate to protect public health and safety in the county; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">The Department does not make the inspection required by paragraph (2) of this subsection.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(5)">A local health official shall:<section prefix="(i)">Give the Department prompt notice of any inspection made by the local health official; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Report promptly in writing to the Department:</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Department:<section prefix="(i)">May delegate to the local health official any inspection, monitoring, or enforcement authority of the Department under this Part III of this subtitle; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Shall adopt regulations that establish standards for delegating authority under this subsection.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The regulations adopted under this subsection shall include:<section prefix="(i)">Procedures for submission, review, and approval or disapproval of any application for delegation of authority;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Provisions requiring that any application for delegation of authority be approved by the county;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Provisions for oversight by the Department, including program evaluations and financial audits; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">Provisions for revocation of a delegation, if the local health official fails to comply with the terms of a delegation agreement.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">If the Department finds that an application for delegation of authority meets all applicable requirements of this section and the regulations adopted under this section, the Department shall enter into a written delegation agreement.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The Department shall establish performance standards for grants to provide reasonable reimbursement to counties, to the extent funds are available, for costs local health officials incur when they undertake authority delegated under this subsection.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">A local health official may act through a designee under this subsection in accordance with an approved delegation agreement.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
