<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gen" order_by="" level="1">Environment</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gen-9-515</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>515</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">This section applies only in Montgomery County and Prince George's County.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The county council of each county shall at least once every 3 years:<section prefix="(1)">Prepare a county plan;</section><section prefix="(2)">Prepare, review, and revise, as the county council considers necessary, a separate statement of objectives and policies to be achieved and implemented by the county plan in the county; and</section><section prefix="(3)">Consider the following in the statements of objectives and policies of the county plans:<section prefix="(i)">Planning;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Zoning;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Population estimates;</section><section prefix="(iv)">Engineering;</section><section prefix="(v)">Economics; and</section><section prefix="(vi)">State, regional, municipal, local, and area plans.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">To achieve the objectives and policies set by the county council, the county executive of each county shall:<section prefix="(1)">Prepare a preliminary draft of the county plan;</section><section prefix="(2)">From time to time review and, as the county executive or county council considers necessary, prepare amendments to the county plan including revisions to service area category designations; and</section><section prefix="(3)">Submit to the county council for the county council's consideration, revision, modification, comment, and approval:<section prefix="(i)">The draft; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Any revision or amendment to the draft.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The county executive of each county shall prepare and submit to the county council:<section prefix="(1)">A final draft of the county plan to conform to the action of the county council in approving the draft; and</section><section prefix="(2)">A final revision or amendment to the county plan that takes into consideration any significant change in the intervening planning or development in the county.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">At least 30 days before the date set for a public hearing under subsection (f) of this section, the county council of each county shall submit its final draft or the final draft of any revision or amendment of the county plan for recommendation to:<section prefix="(1)">The Washington Suburban Sanitary Commission; and</section><section prefix="(2)">The Maryland-National Capital Park and Planning Commission.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The county council of each county shall:<section prefix="(1)">Hold a public hearing on:<section prefix="(i)">Its final draft of the county plan; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">The final draft of any revision or amendment to the county plan; and</section></section><section prefix="(2)">Publish a notice of the time and place of the public hearing at least 10 days before the hearing in a newspaper of general circulation in the county.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">After the public hearing in each county, the county council shall review, may amend as the county council considers necessary, and shall adopt the county plan or the revision or amendment to the county plan.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The adoption of the county plan or a revision or amendment of the county plan by the county council of the county is not final until 10 days after the action adopting it.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">During the 10-day period provided by paragraph (2) of this subsection, the county executive may:<section prefix="(i)">Review the county plan or any revision or amendment to the county plan; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Recommend for the consideration of the county council whatever change to the county plan or any revision or amendment to the county plan that the county executive considers necessary or desirable.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(h)">After the time periods required for adoption under this section, the county council of each county shall submit to the Department, as required by &#xA7; 9-506(b) and (c) of this subtitle:<section prefix="(1)">The county plan; or</section><section prefix="(2)">Any revision or amendment to the county plan.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
