<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gen" order_by="" level="1">Environment</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gen-5-303</section_number>
  <catch_line>WHEREAS, It is recognized that abatement of existing pollution and the control of future pollution o...</catch_line>
  <order_by>303</order_by>
  <text>WHEREAS, It is recognized that abatement of existing pollution and the control of future pollution of interstate streams can best be promoted through a joint agency representing the several states located wholly or in part within the area drained by any such interstate stream; and<section prefix="(a)">There is a commission consisting of 3 members to act jointly with commissions appointed for like purposes by the state of West Virginia, the commonwealths of Pennsylvania and Virginia, the District of Columbia, and an additional 3 members to be appointed by the President of the United States and which, together with the other commissions appointed as mentioned, shall constitute and be known as the Interstate Commission on the Potomac River Basin. The Commission for the State of Maryland shall consist of the Governor of the State and 2 members to be named by the Governor, who shall be actual residents in the Potomac River Drainage Basin. The terms of the members appointed by the Governor shall be 2 years, the first of the appointments of 2 members to be made on June 1, 1939, and they shall serve without compensation, but shall be paid their actual expenses incurred in and incident to the performance of their duties as set forth. This State shall contribute to the Interstate Commission on the Potomac River Basin its pro rata share of the expenses of the Commission, which shall be the sums as may be appropriate for the purpose in the State budget.</section><section prefix="(b)">The Governor of the State is authorized and directed to execute a compact on behalf of the State of Maryland with the other states and the District referred to, who may by their legislative bodies so authorize a compact in form substantially as follows:</section><section prefix="(a)">The Commission shall meet and organize within thirty days after the effective date of this compact, shall elect from its number a chairman and vice-chairman, shall adopt suitable bylaws, shall make, adopt and promulgate such rules and regulations as are necessary for its management and control, and shall adopt a seal.</section><section prefix="(b)">The Commission shall appoint and, at its pleasure, remove or discharge such officers and legal, engineering, clerical, expert and other assistants as may be required to carry the provisions of this compact into effect, and shall determine their qualifications and fix their duties and compensation. Such personnel as may be employed shall be employed without regard to any civil service or other similar requirements for employees of any of the signatory bodies. The Commission may maintain one or more offices for the transaction of its business and may meet at any time or place within the area of the signatory bodies.</section><section prefix="(c)">The Commission shall keep accurate accounts of all receipts and disbursements and shall make an annual report thereof and shall in such report set forth in detail the operations and transactions conducted by it pursuant to this compact. The Commission, however, shall not incur any obligations for administrative or other expenses prior to the making of appropriations adequate to meet the same nor shall it in any way pledge the credit of any of the signatory bodies. Each of the signatory bodies reserves the right to make at any time an examination and audit of the accounts of the Commission.</section><section prefix="(d)">A quorum of the Commission shall, for the transaction of business, the exercise of any powers, or the performance of any duties, consist of at least six members of the Commission who shall represent at least a majority of the signatory bodies; provided, however, that no action of the Commission relating to policy or stream classification or standards shall be binding on any one of the signatory bodies unless at least two of the Commissioners from such signatory body shall vote in favor thereof.</section><section prefix="(a)">To collect, analyze, interpret, co-ordinate, tabulate, summarize and distribute, technical and other data relative to, and to conduct studies, sponsor research and prepare reports on, pollution and other water problems of the Conservancy District.</section><section prefix="(b)">To co-operate with the legislative and administrative agencies of the signatory bodies, or the equivalent thereof, and with other commissions and federal, local governmental and nongovernmental agencies, organizations, groups and persons for the purpose of promoting uniform laws, rules or regulations for the abatement and control of pollution of streams and the utilization, conservation and development of the water and associated land resources in the said Conservancy District.</section><section prefix="(c)">To disseminate to the public information in relation to stream pollution problems and the utilization, conservation and development of the water and associated land resources of the Conservancy District and on the aims, views, purposes, and recommendations of the Commission in relation thereto.</section><section prefix="(d)">To co-operate with, assist, and provide liaison for and among, public and nonpublic agencies and organizations concerned with pollution and other water problems in the formulation and co-ordination of plans, programs and other activities relating to stream pollution or to the utilization, conservation or development of water or associated land resources, and to sponsor co-operative action in connection with the foregoing.</section><section prefix="(e)">In its discretion and at any time during or after the formulation thereof, to review and to comment upon any plan or program of any public or private agency or organization relating to stream pollution or the utilization, conservation or development of water or associated land resources.</section><section prefix="(f)"><section prefix="(1)">To make and, if needful from time to time, revise and to recommend to the signatory bodies, reasonable minimum standards for the treatment of sewage and industrial or other wastes now discharged or to be discharged in the future to the streams of the Conservancy District, and also for cleanliness of the various streams in the Conservancy District.</section><section prefix="(2)">To establish reasonable physical, chemical and bacteriological standards of water quality satisfactory for various classifications of use. It is agreed that each of the signatory bodies through appropriate agencies will prepare a classification of its interstate waters in the District in entirety or by portions according to present and proposed highest use, and for this purpose technical experts employed by appropriate state water-pollution control agencies are authorized to confer on questions relating to classification of interstate waters affecting two or more states. Each signatory body agrees to submit its classification of its interstate waters to the Commission with its recommendations thereon.</section></section><section prefix="1.">Faithful co-operation in the abatement of existing pollution and the prevention of future pollution in the streams of the Conservancy District and in the planning for the utilization, conservation and development of the water and associated land resources thereof.</section><section prefix="2.">The enactment of adequate and, insofar as is practicable, uniform legislation for the abatement and control of pollution and control and use of such streams.</section><section prefix="3.">The appropriation of biennial sums on the proportionate basis as set forth in Article IV.</section></text>
</law>
