<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gen" order_by="gen" level="1">Environment</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gen-9-228</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this section, "approved facility" means a facility located in or outside of the State for collect...</catch_line>
  <order_by>228</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, "approved facility" means a facility located in or outside of the State for collecting, recycling, or otherwise processing scrap tires that is approved or licensed by the Department in accordance with regulations adopted by the Department.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A person may not store scrap tires in the State unless the person demonstrates to the satisfaction of the Department that, within 90 days of the time that the person stores the scrap tires, the scrap tires will be:<section prefix="(1)">Returned to the marketplace;</section><section prefix="(2)">Used as fuel in an approved resource recovery incinerator;</section><section prefix="(3)">Used as a tire derived fuel in an approved facility; or</section><section prefix="(4)">Transferred, by means of a scrap tire hauler, to any facility within the scrap tire recycling system established under subsection (c) of this section.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The service shall establish a scrap tire recycling system that includes scrap tire collection facilities, scrap tire haulers, and in the following order of priority:<section prefix="(i)">Scrap tire recyclers; and</section><section prefix="(ii)"><section prefix="1.">An approved resource recovery facility that uses tires as a fuel substitute; or</section><section prefix="2.">An approved facility that uses tires as a tire derived fuel.</section></section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A person may not incinerate tires except in:<section prefix="(i)">An approved resource recovery facility that uses tires as a fuel substitute; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">An approved facility that uses tires as a tire derived fuel.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A facility that processes scrap tires for use as a fuel in an incinerator, boiler, or resource recovery facility or a facility that burns or incinerates scrap tires may not be approved or licensed under this subtitle, unless:<section prefix="(i)">There is no reasonable and economically available opportunity to process the tires and return them to the marketplace for reuse; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">The burning or incineration meets all federal and State air quality standards.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Scrap tire collection facilities, haulers, or recyclers may be publicly or privately owned and operated.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">After consultation with other State agencies, representatives of the tire industry, and representatives of local government, the service shall place in operation a scrap tire recycling system:<section prefix="(i)">By January 1, 1993 for any county with a population of 150,000 or more according to the most recent projections by the Department of Planning; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">By January 1, 1994 for any county with a population of less than 150,000 according to the most recent projections by the Department of Planning.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The service may establish a scrap tire recycling system required under paragraph (1) of this subsection on a regional basis.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">In establishing the scrap tire recycling system, the service:<section prefix="(i)">Shall give preference to existing private or public scrap tire collection, processing, or recycling programs or facilities that meet the requirements of this subtitle; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">May include in-State facilities licensed by the Department as well as out-of-state facilities approved by the Department.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">Each scrap tire recycling system established under this subsection shall:<section prefix="(i)">Meet all zoning and land use requirements of the county or municipal corporation in which the system is to be located; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Be provided for in the county plan required under &#xA7; 9-503 of this title.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Except as provided in subparagraph (ii) of this paragraph, after January 1, 1994 scrap tires may not be disposed of in a landfill.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The Secretary may waive the requirements of subparagraph (i) of this paragraph under such terms and conditions and for such periods as the Department considers appropriate if the Department determines that a scrap tire recycling system:<section prefix="1.">Does not exist; or</section><section prefix="2.">Has insufficient capacity to accommodate the amount of scrap tires generated in the State.</section></section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A person may not dispose of scrap tires except through a licensed scrap tire hauler or by delivering the tires to an approved facility.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Beginning on February 1, 1992, a tire recycling fee shall be imposed on the first sale of a new tire in the State by a tire dealer, including new tires sold as part of a new or used vehicle, trailer, farm implement, or other similar machinery.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">A county, municipal corporation, or any agency of a county or municipal corporation may not impose any tax, fee, or other charge on the first sale of a new tire by a tire dealer.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The tire recycling fee:<section prefix="(i)">May not exceed $1.00 per tire; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Shall be established by the Board of Public Works.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">For a sale made by a tire dealer to a person who resells tires, the tire dealer shall separately state its recycling fees paid by the tire dealer on the invoice or other document of sale.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">Each tire dealer shall:<section prefix="(i)">Pay the tire recycling fee; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Complete and submit, under oath, a return and remit the fees to the Comptroller of the Treasury on or before the 21st day of the month that follows the month in which the sale was made, and for other periods and on other dates that the Comptroller specifies by regulation, including periods for which no fees were due.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(5)">A tire dealer who timely files a tire recycling fee return and pays the tire recycling fees due is allowed, for the expense of administering and paying the fee, a credit equal to 0.6% of the gross amount of tire recycling fees that the tire dealer is to pay to the Comptroller.</section>
      <section prefix="(6)">If the amount of the tire recycling fee is separately stated in a retail sale, the tire recycling fee is not subject to any tax under Title 11 of the Tax - General Article or Title 13 of the Transportation Article.</section>
      <section prefix="(7)">At the end of each quarter, the Comptroller shall forward all tire recycling fees to the Used Tire Cleanup and Recycling Fund, less the costs of administration.</section>
      <section prefix="(8)">Except to the extent they are inconsistent with this subsection, the provisions of Title 13 of the Tax - General Article applicable to the sales and use tax shall govern the administration, collection, and enforcement of the tire recycling fee under this subsection.</section>
      <section prefix="(9)">The Comptroller:<section prefix="(i)">Shall administer the tire recycling fee; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">May adopt any regulations that are necessary or appropriate to administer, collect, and enforce the tire recycling fee.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(h)">Beginning on July 1, 1992, each scrap tire hauler shall:<section prefix="(1)">Be licensed by the Department to transport scrap tires from scrap tire collection facilities to scrap tire recyclers;</section><section prefix="(2)">Apply for a scrap tire hauler's license on a form provided by the Department; and</section><section prefix="(3)">Transport each load of scrap tires to the scrap tire recyclers in accordance with regulations adopted by the Department.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(i)">Beginning on July 1, 1992, each scrap tire collection facility shall:<section prefix="(1)">If located in the State, be licensed by the Department to receive tires from a consumer or a scrap tire hauler;</section><section prefix="(2)">Apply for a license on a form provided by the Department;</section><section prefix="(3)">Meet all zoning and land use requirements of the county or municipal corporation in which the tire collection facility is to be located;</section><section prefix="(4)">Manage scrap tires in accordance with regulations adopted by the Department;</section><section prefix="(5)">By means of a scrap tire hauler, transfer scrap tires to:<section prefix="(i)">A scrap tire recycler; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">Another scrap tire collection facility; and</section></section><section prefix="(6)">In accordance with regulations adopted by the Department and on forms provided by the Department, provide:<section prefix="(i)">The Department with:<section prefix="1.">A record of the destination;</section><section prefix="2.">The name of the hauler that is registered with the Department; and</section><section prefix="3.">The quantity of each shipment of scrap tires; and</section></section><section prefix="(ii)">Each hauler with:<section prefix="1.">A record of the destination; and</section><section prefix="2.">The quantity of each shipment of scrap tires.</section></section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(j)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Beginning on July 1, 1992, a person may not operate as a scrap tire recycler in the State unless the person is licensed by the Department.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">To apply for a license an applicant shall submit:<section prefix="(i)">An application to the Department on the form that the Department requires; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Any document or other information required in regulations adopted by the Department.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(k)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Department shall adopt regulations necessary to administer the provisions of this section, including:<section prefix="(i)">Minimum standards for the operation, maintenance, monitoring, reporting, and suspension of each scrap tire recycling system;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Requisite evidence of financial ability to properly establish, operate, and maintain a scrap tire recycling system, including the posting of bonds and other securities; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">The forfeiture of bonds and other securities for noncompliance with the requirements of this section or any applicable regulation.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Department may require the delivery of scrap tires in this State to 1 or more facilities, in the State or outside of the State, designated by the service as part of the tire recycling system.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A scrap tire hauler or scrap tire collection facility may not transport or transfer scrap tires to any place other than a facility designated under paragraph (2) of this subsection.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
