<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gen" order_by="" level="1">Environment</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gen-9-945</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>945</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">An authority may enter into any contract that the authority determines is necessary or incidental to the exercise of its powers or the performance of its duties under this subtitle, including a contract with:<section prefix="(1)">Any federal agency, this State, any agency of this State, any political subdivision, or any person:<section prefix="(i)">Providing for or relating to furnishing the services and facilities of a project of the authority; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">In connection with the services and facilities of a water system or sewerage system that is owned or controlled by the federal agency, this State, the agency of this State, the political subdivision, or the person;</section></section><section prefix="(2)">Any person, political subdivision, or public authority of this or any adjoining state for the construction and operation of a project that is located partly in this State and partly in the adjoining state; and</section><section prefix="(3)">Any federal agency or political subdivision relating to:<section prefix="(i)">The use by the authority of the services or facilities of any water system or sewerage system that is not owned or operated by the authority; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">The use by the federal agency, political subdivision, or residents of the political subdivision of:<section prefix="1.">Any project acquired or constructed by the authority under this subtitle; or</section><section prefix="2.">The services or facilities of the project.</section></section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A contract under this section:<section prefix="(1)">Is subject to any provision, limitation, or condition that is contained in:<section prefix="(i)">A resolution of the authority that authorizes the authority to issue bonds; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">A trust agreement that secures bonds of the authority;</section></section><section prefix="(2)">May provide for the collection of fees, rates, or charges for the services and facilities furnished to a political subdivision or any of its residents, and may provide that the collection be done:<section prefix="(i)">By a political subdivision or any agent of a political subdivision; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">By any agent of an authority; and</section></section><section prefix="(3)">May provide for the enforcement of any delinquent charge.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Any law that is enacted by a political subdivision under a contract under this section:<section prefix="(1)">Is not repealable if any bond to which the contract relates is outstanding and unpaid; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Is for the benefit of the bondholders.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A contract under this section and any law of a political subdivision that is enacted under the contract shall provide that the total of any rates, fees, and charges is sufficient to pay all of the obligations that are assumed by the other party to the contract.</section>
  </text>
</law>
