<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gen" order_by="" level="1">Environment</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gen-1-301</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>301</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Secretary shall carry out and enforce the provisions of this article and the rules and regulations adopted under this article.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Secretary may delegate duties, powers, and functions as provided in this article to a health officer for a county or to another county official authorized to administer and enforce environmental laws.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">In those counties where a county official other than the health officer is authorized to administer and enforce State environmental laws under this section, the county shall establish minimum qualifications for that county official that include standards of education and experience related to environmental issues.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">On or before October 1 of each year, the Secretary, in consultation with the Attorney General, shall submit to the Legislative Policy Committee, in accordance with &#xA7; 2-1246 of the State Government Article, a report on enforcement activities conducted by the Department during the previous fiscal year.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The report shall:<section prefix="1.">Include the information required under this subsection and any additional information concerning environmental enforcement that the Secretary decides to provide;</section><section prefix="2.">Be available to the public as soon as it is forwarded to the Legislative Policy Committee;</section><section prefix="3.">Include information on the total number of permits and licenses issued by or filed with the Department at any time and still in effect as of the last date of the fiscal year immediately preceding the date on which the report is filed;</section><section prefix="4.">Include information concerning specific enforcement actions taken with respect to the permits and licenses during the immediately preceding fiscal year; and</section><section prefix="5.">Include information on the type and number of contacts or consultations with businesses concerning compliance with State environmental laws.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">The information required in the report under paragraph (3) of this subsection shall be organized according to each program specified.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The report shall state the total amount of money as a result of enforcement actions, as of the end of the immediately preceding fiscal year:<section prefix="(i)">Deposited in the Maryland Clean Air Fund;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Deposited in the Maryland Oil Disaster Containment, Clean-Up and Contingency Fund;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Deposited in the Nontidal Wetland Compensation Fund;</section><section prefix="(iv)">Deposited in the Maryland Hazardous Substance Control Fund;</section><section prefix="(v)">Recovered by the Department from responsible parties in accordance with &#xA7; 7-221 of this article; and</section><section prefix="(vi)">Deposited in the Maryland Clean Water Fund.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The report shall include the information specified in subparagraphs (ii), (iii), (iv), and (v) of this paragraph for each of the following programs in the Department:<section prefix="1.">Ambient air quality control under Title 2, Subtitle 4 of this article;</section><section prefix="2.">Oil pollution under Title 4, Subtitle 4 of this article;</section><section prefix="3.">Nontidal wetlands under Title 5, Subtitle 9 of this article;</section><section prefix="4.">Asbestos under Title 6, Subtitle 4 of this article;</section><section prefix="5.">Lead paint under Title 6, Subtitle 8 of this article;</section><section prefix="6.">Controlled hazardous substances under Title 7, Subtitle 2 of this article;</section><section prefix="7.">Water supply, sewerage systems, and refuse disposal systems under Title 9, Subtitle 2 of this article;</section><section prefix="8.">Water discharges under Title 9, Subtitle 3 of this article;</section><section prefix="9.">Drinking water under Title 9, Subtitle 4 of this article; and</section><section prefix="10.">Wetlands under Title 16, Subtitle 2 of this article.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">For each of the programs set forth in subparagraph (i) of this paragraph, the Department shall provide the total number or amount of:<section prefix="1.">Final permits or licenses issued to a person or facility, as appropriate, and not surrendered, suspended, or revoked;</section><section prefix="2.">Inspections, audits, or spot checks performed at facilities permitted;</section><section prefix="3.">Injunctions obtained;</section><section prefix="4.">Show cause, remedial, and corrective action orders issued;</section><section prefix="5.">Stop work orders;</section><section prefix="6.">Administrative or civil penalties obtained;</section><section prefix="7.">Criminal actions charged, convictions obtained, imprisonment time ordered, and criminal fines received; and</section><section prefix="8.">Any other actions taken by the Department to enforce the requirements of the applicable environmental program, including:</section></section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">In addition to the information required in subparagraph (ii) of this paragraph, for the Lead Paint Program under Title 6, Subtitle 8 of this article, the report shall include the total number or amount of:<section prefix="1.">Affected properties registered; and</section><section prefix="2.">Inspectors or other persons accredited by the Department, for whom accreditation has not been surrendered, suspended, or revoked.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(iv)">In addition to the information required in subparagraph (ii) of this paragraph, for the Controlled Hazardous Substances Program under Title 7, Subtitle 2 of this article, the report shall include the following lists, updated to reflect the most recent information available for the immediately preceding fiscal year:<section prefix="1.">Possible controlled hazardous substance sites compiled in accordance with &#xA7; 7-223(a) of this article;</section><section prefix="2.">Proposed sites listed in accordance with &#xA7; 7-223(c) of this article at which the Department intends to conduct preliminary site assessments; and</section><section prefix="3.">Hazardous waste sites in the disposal site registry compiled in accordance with &#xA7; 7-223(f) of this article.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(v)">In addition to the information required in subparagraph (ii) of this paragraph, for the Drinking Water Program, the report shall include the total number of:<section prefix="1.">Actions to prevent public water system contamination or to respond to a Safe Drinking Water Act emergency under &#xA7;&#xA7; 9-405 and 9-406 of this article; and</section><section prefix="2.">Notices given to the public by public water systems under &#xA7; 9-410 of this article.</section></section>
      </section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
