<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gen" order_by="gen" level="1">Environment</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gen-7-301</section_number>
  <catch_line>As used in the compact, unless the context clearly indicates otherwise:...</catch_line>
  <order_by>301</order_by>
  <text>As used in the compact, unless the context clearly indicates otherwise:<section prefix="a.">"Broker" means any intermediate person who handles, treats, processes, stores, packages, ships or otherwise has responsibility for or possesses low-level waste obtained from a generator.</section><section prefix="b.">"Carrier" means a person who transports low-level waste to a regional facility.</section><section prefix="c.">"Commission" means the Appalachian States Low-Level Radioactive Waste Commission.</section><section prefix="d.">"Disposal" means the isolation of low-level waste from the biosphere.</section><section prefix="e.">"Facility" means any real or personal property, within the region, and improvements thereof or thereon, and any and all plant, structures, machinery and equipment, acquired, constructed, operated or maintained for the management or disposal of low-level waste.</section><section prefix="f.">"Generate" means to produce low-level waste requiring disposal.</section><section prefix="g.">"Generator" means a person whose activity results in the production of low-level waste requiring disposal.</section><section prefix="h.">"Hazardous life" means the time required for radioactive materials to decay to safe levels, as defined by the time period for the concentration of radioactive materials within a given container or package to decay to maximum permissible concentrations as defined by federal law or by standards to be set by a host state, whichever is more restrictive.</section><section prefix="i.">"Host state" means Pennsylvania or other party state so designated by the Commission in accordance with Article III of this compact.</section><section prefix="j.">"Institutional control period" means the time of the continued observation, monitoring and care of the regional facility following transfer of control from the operator to the custodial agency.</section><section prefix="k.">"Low-level waste" means radioactive waste that:<section prefix="1.">Is neither high-level waste or transuranic waste, nor spent nuclear fuel, nor by-product material as defined in Section 11(e)(2) of the Atomic Energy Act of 1954 as amended; and</section><section prefix="2.">Is classified by the federal government as low-level waste, consistent with existing law; but does not include waste generated as a result of atomic energy defense activities of the federal government, as defined in Public Law 96-573, or federal research and development activities.</section></section><section prefix="l.">"Management" means the reduction, collection, consolidation, storage, packaging or treatment of low-level waste.</section><section prefix="m.">"Operator" means a person who operates a regional facility.</section><section prefix="n.">"Party state" means any state that has become a party in accordance with Article V of this compact.</section><section prefix="o.">"Person" means an individual, corporation, partnership or other legal entity, whether public or private.</section><section prefix="p.">"Region" means the combined geographical area within the boundaries of the party states.</section><section prefix="q.">"Regional facility" means a facility within any party state which has been approved by the Commission for the disposal of low-level waste.</section><section prefix="r.">"Shallow land burial" means the disposal of low-level radioactive waste directly in subsurface trenches without additional confinement in engineered structures or by proper packaging in containers as determined by the law of the host state.</section><section prefix="s.">"Transuranic waste" means low-level waste containing radionuclides with an atomic number greater than 92 which are excluded from shallow land burial by the federal government.</section></text>
</law>
