<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gen" order_by="" level="1">Environment</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gen-6-815</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>815</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">No later than the first change in occupancy in an affected property that occurs on or after February 24, 1996, before the next tenant occupies the property, an owner of an affected property shall initially satisfy the risk reduction standard established under this subtitle by passing the test for lead-contaminated dust under &#xA7; 6-816 of this subtitle provided that any chipping, peeling, or flaking paint has been removed or repainted on:<section prefix="(1)">The exterior painted surfaces of the residential building in which the rental dwelling unit is located; and</section><section prefix="(2)">The interior painted surfaces of the rental dwelling unit.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">At each change in occupancy thereafter, before the next tenant occupies the property, the owner of an affected property shall satisfy the risk reduction standard established under this subtitle by passing the test for lead-contaminated dust under &#xA7; 6-816 of this subtitle in accordance with subsection (a) of this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">At each change in occupancy, an owner of an affected property shall have the property inspected to verify that the risk reduction standard specified in this section has been satisfied.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Exterior work required to satisfy the risk reduction standard may be delayed, pursuant to a waiver approved by the appropriate person under paragraph (2) of this subsection, during any time period in which exterior work is not required to be performed under an applicable local housing code or, if no such time period is specified, during the period from November 1 through April 1, inclusive.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A waiver under paragraph (1) of this subsection may be approved by the code official for enforcement of the housing code or minimum livability code of the local jurisdiction, or, if there is no such official, the Department of Housing and Community Development.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Notwithstanding the terms of the waiver, all work delayed in accordance with paragraph (1) of this subsection shall be completed within 30 days after the end of the applicable time period.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">Any delay allowed under paragraph (1) of this subsection may not affect the obligation of the owner to complete all other components of the risk reduction standard and to have those components inspected and verified.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">If the owner has complied with the requirements of paragraph (4) of this subsection, the owner may rent the affected property during any period of delay allowed under paragraph (1) of this subsection.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">On request of a local jurisdiction, the Secretary may designate the code official for enforcement of the housing code or minimum livability code for the local jurisdiction, or an appropriate employee of the local jurisdiction, to conduct inspections under this subtitle.</section>
  </text>
</law>
