<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gen" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="9-349" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gen-9-349</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Loans or loan guarantees may be awarded to industrial users for projects that provide for pretreatment of pollutants that are discharged directly or indirectly into publicly owned treatment works or into any conveyance leading to a publicly owned treatment plant.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Secretary and the Secretary of Business and Economic Development shall jointly administer the program established under this section with the Secretary of Business and Economic Development being primarily responsible for the assessment of the financial capability of an applicant and appropriateness of the terms and conditions of any loan assistance.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Loan assistance may be awarded to a person under this section if:<section prefix="(1)">An agreement is executed by the person that:<section prefix="(i)">Specifies the purpose, amount, manner of repayment, and any other condition required by the Board of Public Works;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Obligates the person to construct, install, and operate the pretreatment project in a manner which insures compliance with all pretreatment requirements and technical specifications, to maintain the project for its expected life span, and to bind any successor in title; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Shall be signed by the Secretary and the Secretary of Business and Economic Development or their designees;</section></section><section prefix="(2)">The applicant certifies that it is otherwise unable to obtain on reasonable terms sufficient credit to finance the pretreatment project and the Secretary of Business and Economic Development determines that there is a reasonable assurance of repayment of the loan;</section><section prefix="(3)">The Secretary of the Environment determines that the project meets all applicable technical standards and that all cost estimates are reasonable and represent eligible costs; and</section><section prefix="(4)">When an applicant leases the property where the pretreatment project will be constructed, that the landowner consents to the terms and conditions of the agreement.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">For any loan assistance exceeding $2,500, the Secretary of Business and Economic Development shall require the granting to the State of an appropriate security interest in any equipment, structures, or similar items purchased with State moneys.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">In accordance with &#xA7; 9-345 of this subtitle, the Secretary and the Secretary of Business and Economic Development jointly shall adopt rules and regulations to implement this section.</section>
  </text>
</law>
