<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gen" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="9-337" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gen-9-337</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Department shall give notice and hold any hearing under this subtitle in accordance with the Administrative Procedure Act.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Within 10 days after being served with an order under &#xA7; 9-335(a)(1) of this subtitle, the person served may request in writing a hearing before the Department.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If a request for a hearing is made under this subsection, the Department shall:<section prefix="(i)">Hold the hearing within 10 days after receiving the request; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Render a decision within 10 days after the hearing.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Within 10 days after being served with a notice under &#xA7; 9-335(a)(2) of this subtitle, the person served may request in writing a hearing before the Department.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Department may make a verbatim record of the proceedings of any hearing held under this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In connection with any hearing under this subtitle, the Department may:<section prefix="(i)">Subpoena any person or evidence; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Order a witness to give evidence.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A subpoenaed witness shall receive the same fees and mileage reimbursement as if the hearing were part of a civil action.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">If a person fails to comply with a subpoena or order issued under this subsection, on petition of the Department, a circuit court, by order, may:<section prefix="(i)">Compel obedience to the Department's order or subpoena; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">Compel testimony or the production of evidence.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The court may punish as a contempt any failure to obey its order issued under this section.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
