<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gen" order_by="" level="1">Environment</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gen-9-941</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>941</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">An authority shall pay the principal of and interest on its bonds only from the funds from which this subtitle authorizes payment.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">For any bond that an authority issues, the authority:<section prefix="(1)">Shall place the date of issue on the bond;</section><section prefix="(2)">Shall set the maturity date for the bond, which shall be any time up to 40 years from the date of issue; and</section><section prefix="(3)">May provide for the redemption of the bond before maturity:<section prefix="(i)">At the option of the authority; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">At a price and on terms and conditions that the authority fixes before it issues the bond.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A bond or certificate that otherwise conforms to this section is valid and sufficient for all purposes whether or not the officer whose signature or a facsimile of whose signature is on the bond or certificate is still an officer when the bond or certificate is delivered.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">An authority:<section prefix="(1)">Shall determine the form of its bonds; and</section><section prefix="(2)">May issue its bonds in coupon or registered form or both.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">An authority shall determine:<section prefix="(1)">The manner of execution of its bonds;</section><section prefix="(2)">The denominations of its bonds; and</section><section prefix="(3)">The places for payment of the principal of and interest on its bonds, which may be any bank or trust company.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">A bond issued under this subtitle is fully negotiable as provided in Title 8 of the Commercial Law Article.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">An authority may provide for:<section prefix="(1)">The registration of any coupon bond as to:<section prefix="(i)">Principal only; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">Both principal and interest; and</section></section><section prefix="(2)">The reconversion into a coupon bond of any bond that is registered as to both principal and interest.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
