<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gen" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="4-313.1" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gen-4-313.1</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Department shall impose an administrative civil penalty on a person who owns or operates a sewage treatment plant that is in violation of &#xA7; 4-302.1(b)(1), (c), or (d) of this subtitle.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The person accused of the violation shall have the right to a hearing but may waive that right in writing.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The penalty imposed under this subsection shall be:<section prefix="(i)">$5 for each pound of phosphorus discharged monthly in violation of &#xA7; 4-302.1(b)(1) of this subtitle; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">$2 for each pound of nitrogen discharged monthly in violation of &#xA7; 4-302.1(c) or (d) of this subtitle.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, a penalty imposed under this section may not be:<section prefix="(i)">Waived;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Reduced; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">Used to assist the penalized person in upgrading a sewage treatment plant.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A penalty imposed under this section may be waived if the phosphorus or nitrogen discharged in violation of &#xA7; 4-302.1 of this subtitle is due to an act of God or, if it could not reasonably have been anticipated by the owner or operator of the sewage treatment plant, a power outage or a massive leakage of any pollutant that contaminates the wastewater being treated.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Department shall deposit the penalties collected under this section in the Maryland Clean Water Fund created under &#xA7; 9-320 of this article.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Department shall collect the penalties required to be imposed under subsection (a) of this section on a monthly basis beginning on:<section prefix="(1)">February 15, 1989 for violations of &#xA7; 4-302.1(b)(1) of this subtitle; and</section><section prefix="(2)">November 15, 1991 for violations of &#xA7; 4-302.1(c) or (d) of this subtitle.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The penalties required to be imposed under this section are in addition to any other penalties provided by law.</section>
  </text>
</law>
