<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gen" order_by="" level="1">Environment</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gen-9-1601</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>1601</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Unless the context clearly requires otherwise, in this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Administration" means the Maryland Water Quality Financing Administration.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Bay Restoration Fund" means the Bay Restoration Fund established under &#xA7; 9-1605.2 of this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">"Biological nutrient removal" means a biological nutrient removal technology capable of reducing the nitrogen in wastewater effluent to not more than 8 milligrams per liter, as calculated on an annually averaged basis.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"Board" means the Board of Public Works.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">"Bond" means a bond, note, or other evidence of obligation of the Administration issued under this subtitle, including a bond or revenue anticipation note, notes in the nature of commercial paper, and refunding bonds.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">"Bond resolution" means the resolution or resolutions of the Director, including the trust agreement, if any, authorizing the issuance of and providing for the terms and conditions applicable to bonds.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">"Borrower" means a local government or a person as defined in &#xA7; 1-101(h) of this article who has received a loan.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">"Chesapeake and Atlantic Coastal Bays Nonpoint Source Fund" means the Chesapeake and Atlantic Coastal Bays Nonpoint Source Fund established under &#xA7; 9-1605.3 of this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(j)">"Community sewerage system" means a publicly or privately owned sewerage system that serves at least two lots.</section>
    <section prefix="(k)">"Director" means the Director of the Administration.</section>
    <section prefix="(l)">"Drinking Water Loan Fund" means the Maryland Drinking Water Revolving Loan Fund.</section>
    <section prefix="(m)">"Eligible costs" means the costs identified under &#xA7; 9-1605.2(i) of this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(n)">"Enhanced nutrient removal" means:<section prefix="(1)">An enhanced nutrient removal technology that is capable of reducing the nitrogen and phosphorus concentrations in wastewater effluent to concentrations of not more than 3 milligrams per liter total nitrogen and not more than 0.3 milligrams per liter total phosphorus, as calculated on an annually averaged basis; or</section><section prefix="(2)">If the Department has determined that the concentrations under item (1) of this subsection are not practicable for a wastewater facility, the lowest average annual wastewater effluent nitrogen and phosphorus concentrations that the Department determines are practicable for that facility.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(o)">"Equivalent dwelling unit" means a measure of wastewater effluent where one unit is equivalent to:<section prefix="(1)">If a local government or billing authority for a wastewater facility has established a definition for "equivalent dwelling unit" on or before January 1, 2004, the average daily flow of wastewater effluent that the local government or billing authority has established to be equivalent to the average daily flow of wastewater effluent discharged by a residential dwelling, which may not exceed 250 gallons; or</section><section prefix="(2)">If a local government or billing authority has not established a definition for "equivalent dwelling unit" on or before January 1, 2004, or if a local government or billing authority has established a definition that exceeds 250 gallons of wastewater effluent per day, an average daily flow of 250 gallons of wastewater effluent.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(p)">"Facility" means a wastewater facility or all or a portion of a water supply system as defined in &#xA7; 9-201(u) of this title.</section>
    <section prefix="(q)">"Federal Safe Drinking Water Act" means Title XIV of the Public Health Service Act, P.L. 93-523, as amended, 42 U.S.C. &#xA7; 300f, et seq., and the rules and regulations promulgated thereunder.</section>
    <section prefix="(r)">"Federal Water Pollution Control Act" means the Water Pollution Control Act of 1972, P.L. 92-500, as amended, 33 U.S.C. &#xA7; 1251, et seq., and rules and regulations promulgated thereunder.</section>
    <section prefix="(s)">"Fund" means a fund established by this subtitle, including the Water Quality Fund, the Drinking Water Loan Fund, and the Bay Restoration Fund and the Chesapeake and Atlantic Coastal Bays Nonpoint Source Fund.</section>
    <section prefix="(t)">"Grant" means a grant from the Administration to a grantee.</section>
    <section prefix="(u)">"Grant agreement" means a written agreement between the Administration and a grantee with respect to a grant.</section>
    <section prefix="(v)">"Grantee" means the grant recipient.</section>
    <section prefix="(w)">"Lender" has the meaning stated in &#xA7; 9-1606.1 of this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(x)">"Linked deposit" has the meaning stated in &#xA7; 9-1606.1 of this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(y)">"Linked deposit loan" has the meaning stated in &#xA7; 9-1606.1 of this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(z)">"Linked deposit program" has the meaning stated in &#xA7; 9-1606.1 of this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(aa)">"Loan" means a loan from the Administration to a borrower for the purpose of financing all or a portion of the cost of a wastewater facility, if the loan is from the Water Quality Fund, or water supply system, if the loan is from the Drinking Water Loan Fund.</section>
    <section prefix="(bb)">"Loan agreement" means a written agreement between the Administration and a borrower with respect to a loan.</section>
    <section prefix="(cc)">"Loan obligation" means a bond, note, or other evidence of obligation, including a mortgage, deed of trust, lien, or other security instrument, issued or executed by a borrower to evidence its indebtedness under a loan agreement with respect to a loan.</section>
    <section prefix="(dd)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Local government" means a county, municipal corporation, sanitary district, or other State or local public entity which has authority to own or operate a facility.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Local government" includes any combination of two or more of the public entities under paragraph (1) of this subsection when acting jointly to construct or operate a facility.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(ee)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Person" means an individual, corporation, partnership, association, the State, any unit of the State, commission, special taxing district, or the federal government.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Person" does not include a county, municipal corporation, bi-county or multicounty agency under Division II of the Land Use Article or Division II of the Public Utilities Article, housing authority under Division II of the Housing and Community Development Article, school board, community college, or any other unit of a county or municipal corporation, or a local fire department, as defined in &#xA7; 9-401 of the Public Safety Article.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(ff)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Residential dwelling" means a room or group of rooms occupied as living quarters by an individual, a single family, or other discrete group of persons with facilities that are used or intended to be used for living, sleeping, cooking, sanitation, and eating, including an apartment unit, condominium unit, cooperative unit, town house unit, mobile home, or house.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Residential dwelling" does not include a hospital, hotel, motel, inn, boarding house, club, dormitory, school, college, or similar seasonal, institutional, or transient facility.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(gg)">"Single site" means a discrete grouping of buildings or structures that are located on contiguous or adjacent property and owned by the same user.</section>
    <section prefix="(hh)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"User" means any person discharging wastewater to:<section prefix="(i)">A wastewater facility that has a State discharge permit or national pollutant discharge elimination system discharge permit;</section><section prefix="(ii)">An onsite sewage disposal system; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">A sewage holding tank.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"User" does not include a person whose sole discharge is stormwater under a stormwater permit.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(ii)">"Wastewater facility" means any equipment, plant, treatment works, structure, machinery, apparatus, interest in land, or any combination of these, which is acquired, used, constructed, or operated for the storage, collection, treatment, neutralization, stabilization, reduction, recycling, reclamation, separation, or disposal of wastewater, or for the final disposal of residues resulting from the treatment of wastewater, including: treatment or disposal plants; outfall sewers, interceptor sewers, and collector sewers; pumping and ventilating stations, facilities, and works; programs and projects for controlling nonpoint sources of water pollution and for estuarine conservation and management; and other real or personal property and appurtenances incident to their development, use, or operation.</section>
    <section prefix="(jj)">"Water Quality Fund" means the Maryland Water Quality Revolving Loan Fund.</section>
    <section prefix="(kk)">"Water supply system" has the meaning stated in &#xA7; 9-201(u) of this title.</section>
  </text>
</law>
