<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gen" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="9-314" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gen-9-314</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Department may adopt rules and regulations that set, for the waters of this State, water quality standards and effluent standards. These standards shall be designed to protect:<section prefix="(1)">The public health, safety, and welfare;</section><section prefix="(2)">Present and future use of the waters of this State for public water supply;</section><section prefix="(3)">The propagation of aquatic life and wildlife;</section><section prefix="(4)">Recreational use of the waters of this State; and</section><section prefix="(5)">Agricultural, industrial, and other legitimate uses of the waters of this State.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The rules and regulations adopted under this section shall include at least the following:<section prefix="(1)">Water quality standards that specify the maximum permissible short term and long term concentrations of pollutants in the water, the minimum permissible concentrations of dissolved oxygen and other desirable matter in the water, and the temperature range for the water.</section><section prefix="(2)">Effluent standards that specify the maximum loading or concentrations and the physical, thermal, chemical, biological, and radioactive properties of wastes that may be discharged into the waters of this State.</section><section prefix="(3)">Definition of technique for filling and sealing abandoned water wells and holes, for disposal wells, for deep mines and surface mines, and for landfills to prevent groundwater contamination, seepage, and drainage into the waters of this State.</section><section prefix="(4)">Requirements for the sale, offer, use, or storage of pesticides and other substances that the Department finds to constitute water pollution hazards.</section><section prefix="(5)">Procedures for water pollution incidents or emergencies that constitute an acute danger to health or the environment.</section><section prefix="(6)">Provisions for equipment and procedures for monitoring pollutants, collecting samples, and logging and reporting of monitoring.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Effluent standards set under this section shall be at least as stringent as those specified by the National Pollutant Discharge Elimination System.</section>
  </text>
</law>
