<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gen" order_by="gen" level="1">Environment</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gen-9-345</section_number>
  <catch_line>There is a Water Pollution Control Fund consisting of moneys made available under water quality loan...</catch_line>
  <order_by>345</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">There is a Water Pollution Control Fund consisting of moneys made available under water quality loan authorizations or by funds appropriated in the State budget.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Board of Public Works, upon the recommendation of the Secretary, may award financial assistance for the following types of projects:<section prefix="(1)">Construction of sewerage systems under &#xA7;&#xA7; 9-347 and 9-348 of this subtitle;</section><section prefix="(2)">Industrial user pretreatment projects under &#xA7; 9-349 of this subtitle;</section><section prefix="(3)">Best management practices to control or prevent agriculturally related nonpoint source pollution under &#xA7; 9-350 of this subtitle and Title 8, Subtitle 7 of the Agriculture Article; and</section><section prefix="(4)">Practices to reduce pollution from stormwater runoff in existing urbanized areas under &#xA7; 9-350 of this subtitle.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Secretary, with the approval of the Board of Public Works, shall adopt rules and regulations that establish application procedures and criteria for the award of financial assistance under this subtitle. The criteria shall provide the basis for project priority rankings and shall include, as appropriate:<section prefix="(i)">The water quality or public health impacts caused by existing circumstances;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Previous efforts expended to correct any existing problem;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Financial capacity of the applicant;</section><section prefix="(iv)">The problem prevention aspects of a proposed project;</section><section prefix="(v)">Cost effectiveness of a proposed project;</section><section prefix="(vi)">Planning requirements;</section><section prefix="(vii)">Provisions for monitoring and review; and</section><section prefix="(viii)">Measures to assure accountability for all funds awarded under this subtitle.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Project priority systems shall be established. Prior to adopting rules and regulations and establishing project priority rankings under this section, the Secretary shall consult with the Secretaries of Natural Resources, Agriculture, and Business and Economic Development and the Secretary of the Department of Planning.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">For financial assistance over $500,000 awarded under the Fund, the applicant shall demonstrate, to the satisfaction of the Department, that steps were taken to include small business enterprises, minority business enterprises, and women's business enterprises by:<section prefix="(1)">Placing qualified small business enterprises, minority business enterprises, and women's business enterprises on solicitation lists;</section><section prefix="(2)">Assuring that small business enterprises, minority business enterprises, and women's business enterprises are solicited whenever they are potential sources;</section><section prefix="(3)">Dividing total requirements, when economically feasible, into small tasks or quantities to permit maximum participation of small business enterprises, minority business enterprises, and women's business enterprises;</section><section prefix="(4)">Establishing delivery schedules, where the requirement permits, that encourage participation by small business enterprises, minority business enterprises, and women's business enterprises; and</section><section prefix="(5)">Using the services and assistance of the Maryland Department of Transportation and the Governor's Office of Minority Affairs in identifying and soliciting small business enterprises, minority business enterprises, and women's business enterprises.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">If the steps required under subsection (d) of this section are not demonstrated to the satisfaction of the Department, the Department may withhold financial assistance for the project.</section>
  </text>
</law>
