<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gen" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="15-1201" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gen-15-1201</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Mineral" includes:<section prefix="(1)">Gas;</section><section prefix="(2)">Oil and oil shale;</section><section prefix="(3)">Coal;</section><section prefix="(4)">Gaseous, liquid, and solid hydrocarbons;</section><section prefix="(5)">Cement materials, sand and gravel, road materials, and building stone;</section><section prefix="(6)">Chemical substances;</section><section prefix="(7)">Gemstone, metallic, fissionable, and nonfissionable ores; and</section><section prefix="(8)">Colloidal and other clay, steam, and geothermal resources.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Mineral interest" means an interest in a mineral estate, however created and regardless of form, whether absolute or fractional, divided or undivided, corporeal or incorporeal, including a fee simple or any lesser interest or any kind of royalty, production payment, executive right, nonexecutive right, leasehold, or lien in minerals, regardless of character.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">"Severed mineral interest" means a mineral interest that is severed from the interest in the surface estate overlying the mineral interest.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"Surface estate" means an interest in the estate overlying a mineral interest.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Surface owner" means any person vested with a whole or undivided fee simple interest or other freehold interest in the surface estate.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Surface owner" does not include the owner of a right-of-way, easement, or leasehold on the surface estate.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Unknown or missing owner" means any person vested with a severed mineral interest whose present identity or location cannot be determined:<section prefix="(i)">From the records of the county where the severed mineral interest is located; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">By diligent inquiry in the vicinity of the owner's last known place of residence.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Unknown or missing owner" includes the heirs, successors, or assignees of an unknown or missing owner.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
