<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gen" order_by="gen" level="1">Environment</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gen-17-303</section_number>
  <catch_line>To apply for a license, an applicant shall:...</catch_line>
  <order_by>303</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">To apply for a license, an applicant shall:<section prefix="(i)">Submit to the Board an application on the form that the Board provides;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Submit the documents required under this section; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Pay to the Board the required application fee set by the Board.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If the applicant is an entity, the representative member shall complete the application form and otherwise be responsible for the entity's compliance with this section.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If the applicant is an individual, the application form provided by the Board shall require:<section prefix="(i)">The name of the applicant;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The address of the applicant; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">The current and previous employment of the applicant relevant to the field of marine contracting.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If the applicant is an entity, the application form provided by the Board shall require:<section prefix="(i)">A list of the entity's owners; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">For each entity owner, the same information required regarding an individual applicant under paragraph (1) of this subsection.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">For all applicants, the application form shall require:<section prefix="(i)">The address of the applicant's proposed principal place of business and of each proposed branch office;</section><section prefix="(ii)">All trade or fictitious names that the applicant intends to use while performing marine contractor services; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">As the Board considers appropriate, any other information to assist in the evaluation of:<section prefix="1.">An individual applicant; or</section><section prefix="2.">If the applicant is an entity, any entity member.</section></section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The application form provided by the Board shall contain a statement advising the applicant of the penalties for violation of this title provided under &#xA7; 17-403 of this title.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If the applicant is an individual, the individual shall sign the application form under oath.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If the applicant is an entity, the representative member of the entity shall sign the application form under oath, and shall provide proof to the Board that the representative member is a member of the entity.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">An applicant for a license shall submit with the application proof of the insurance required under &#xA7; 17-302(c)(4) of this subtitle.</section>
  </text>
</law>
