<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gen" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="9-908" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gen-9-908</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section, "articles of amendment" means a document that proposes or adopts an amendment to the articles of incorporation of an authority.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Articles of amendment" includes a document that restates the articles of incorporation.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">An authority may amend its articles of incorporation in accordance with this section:<section prefix="(1)">To adopt a new name; or</section><section prefix="(2)">To change, enlarge, or diminish its powers, duties, and purposes.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">To amend its articles of incorporation, the board of directors of an authority shall adopt a resolution that proposes the amendments.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If the articles of incorporation are to be replaced, the resolution shall contain the language of the new articles of incorporation.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">If any provision in the articles of incorporation is to be added, deleted, or amended, the resolution shall contain the language of the entire amended provision.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The resolution shall direct submission of the amendment to the governing body of each member political subdivision.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">After the board of directors submits the amendment to the governing body of each member political subdivision, the governing body shall adopt or reject the amendment by law.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Articles of amendment under this section shall include:<section prefix="(1)">The name and location of the principal office of the authority;</section><section prefix="(2)">The complete amendment; and</section><section prefix="(3)">A statement that the amendment:<section prefix="(i)">Was proposed by the board of directors of the authority; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Was adopted by the governing body of each member political subdivision.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">If the governing body of each member political subdivision adopts the amendment:<section prefix="(1)">Two authorized officers of the authority shall:<section prefix="(i)">Sign and acknowledge articles of amendment under the seal of the authority; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Verify under oath the matters and facts set forth in the articles of amendment; and</section></section><section prefix="(2)">The authority shall file the articles of amendment for record with the State Department of Assessments and Taxation.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The State Department of Assessments and Taxation shall:<section prefix="(i)">Receive the articles of amendment;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Mark the date and time of receipt to the articles of amendment; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Issue a certificate of approval for any articles of amendment that comply with this subtitle.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">When the State Department of Assessments and Taxation issues a certificate of approval, the articles of amendment:<section prefix="(i)">Are in full force and effect; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Are conclusively deemed to be lawfully and properly adopted.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
