<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gen" order_by="gen" level="1">Environment</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gen-9-635</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this section the following words have the meanings indicated....</catch_line>
  <order_by>635</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">"Contracting party" means the other party to a contract made by a district under this section.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">"Contracting party" includes:<section prefix="1.">A person;</section><section prefix="2.">A county of this State or any other state;</section><section prefix="3.">A municipal corporation of this State or any other state;</section><section prefix="4.">This State or any other state;</section><section prefix="5.">The United States;</section><section prefix="6.">Any instrumentality of this State, any other state, or the United States; and</section><section prefix="7.">Another district of this State or any other state.</section></section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Contracting party's system" means any of the following systems owned or operated by a contracting party:<section prefix="(i)">A sewerage system.</section><section prefix="(ii)">A solid waste acceptance facility.</section><section prefix="(iii)">A solid waste disposal system.</section><section prefix="(iv)">A water system.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">If its sanitary commission approves, a district may make a contract with a contracting party:<section prefix="(1)">To buy services from the contracting party's system;</section><section prefix="(2)">To use the facilities of the contracting party's system; or</section><section prefix="(3)">To allow a contracting party or its customers to use the services or facilities of the district.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Any contract made under this section:<section prefix="(1)">Shall require that the fees, rates, or charges collected under the contract be sufficient to pay the obligations of the contracting party; and</section><section prefix="(2)">May allow a contracting party to collect from its customers the fees, rates, or charges due under the contract.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A contract made under this section is for the benefit of holders of the district's bonds.</section>
  </text>
</law>
