<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gen" order_by="gen" level="1">Environment</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gen-9-934</section_number>
  <catch_line>This section applies only in Allegany County, Dorchester County, and the town of Middletown in Frede...</catch_line>
  <order_by>934</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">This section applies only in Allegany County, Dorchester County, and the town of Middletown in Frederick County.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">An authority may not issue bonds unless the question of issuance of the bonds is submitted to the registered voters who reside within the geographical area served by the authority.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The governing body and the board of election supervisors in each political subdivision shall do whatever is necessary and proper to submit the question to a referendum of the qualified voters of the political subdivision.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A qualified voter at a referendum under this section is an individual who:<section prefix="(1)">Lives within the geographic area served by the authority; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Is qualified and registered to vote in State and county elections in the area.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The board of directors of the authority shall set the date for the referendum.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Except as otherwise provided in this subtitle, the Election Law Article governs the conduct of the referendum.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The appropriate board of election supervisors shall print the words "For the bond issue" and "Against the bond issue" on each ballot at a referendum under this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If a majority of the qualified voters who vote on the question vote "For the bond issue", the authority may issue the bonds.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If a majority of the qualified voters who vote on the question vote "Against the bond issue", the authority may not issue the bonds.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">A referendum under this section does not prevent an authority from submitting the same or a similar question at another referendum that is held at a later time.</section>
  </text>
</law>
