<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gen" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="15-401" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gen-15-401</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Each operator shall notify the Bureau immediately in the manner the Bureau prescribes if:<section prefix="(1)">Any change occurs in the name of the operator of a mine, an executive official concerned with its operation, or in the designation of the mine;</section><section prefix="(2)">A mine has been abandoned or work discontinued;</section><section prefix="(3)">Work has commenced for the purpose of opening a new mine. The notice shall include sketch maps outlining the plans intended to be pursued in the opening;</section><section prefix="(4)">The working of a mine is resumed after an abandonment or discontinuance for a period exceeding two months; or</section><section prefix="(5)">A squeeze, crush, or fire occurs, or a dangerous body of water, explosive, or noxious gas is found.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Each operator shall obtain from the Bureau and keep accessible at the mine a supply of the printed laws, rules, regulations, notices, forms, and record books required by law. He shall see that this material is delivered to every worker.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">At least once a week, each operator shall require the superintendent or managing official in charge of the mine to examine, read, and countersign in ink any report the mine foreman enters in the mine record book. If the person finds on examination or otherwise that the law is being violated, he shall stop any violation immediately. Each operator shall require the superintendent or other managing official in charge of the mine, and any other official in whatever capacity, to comply with the provisions of this subtitle, and especially not to obstruct the mine foreman or any other official in the execution of his duties. The operator, or a representative other than the mine foreman, shall visit every working place in each mine once every 60 days in order to note the condition of each place.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Each operator shall assist the Bureau and its officers in making any proper inspection. He shall execute promptly every proper order made under the provisions of this subtitle. An operator may not willfully neglect or refuse to obey any order, or interfere with the Bureau or any agent in the proper discharge of its or his duties.</section>
  </text>
</law>
