<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gen" order_by="gen" level="1">Environment</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gen-9-614</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this section, "amendment" means an amendment to the articles of incorporation of a district....</catch_line>
  <order_by>614</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, "amendment" means an amendment to the articles of incorporation of a district.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">In accordance with this section, a district may adopt amendments that:<section prefix="(1)">Can be included lawfully in original articles of incorporation; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Change the district's:<section prefix="(i)">Name;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Powers; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">Purposes.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">To adopt amendments, the sanitary commission shall adopt a resolution that:<section prefix="(1)">Directs that the proposed amendment be submitted to each member county; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Discloses the text of the proposed amendment by printing:<section prefix="(i)">The text of the entire articles of organization as the articles of organization would read after adoption of the proposed amendment;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The text of a provision in the articles of incorporation as that provision would read after adoption of the proposed amendment; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">The material whose addition to or removal from the articles of incorporation is proposed.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">By ordinance or resolution, the governing body of each member county shall adopt or reject the proposed amendment.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If the governing body of each member county adopts the proposed articles of amendment, two authorized officers of the district shall:<section prefix="(i)">Verify the facts set forth in the articles of amendment;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Put the district's seal on the articles of amendment; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Sign the articles of amendment.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The articles of amendment shall include:<section prefix="(i)">The name and address of the principal office of the district;</section><section prefix="(ii)">A statement that the amendment was proposed by the sanitary commissioners;</section><section prefix="(iii)">A statement that each member county adopted the amendment; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">The text of the amendment.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The district shall file the articles of amendment with the State Department of Assessments and Taxation.</section>
  </text>
</law>
