<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gen" order_by="gen" level="1">Environment</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gen-4-101.1</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this title the following words have the meanings indicated....</catch_line>
  <order_by>101.1</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this title the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Person" includes the federal government, the State, any county, municipal corporation, or other political subdivision of the State, or any of their units.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Pollution" means any contamination or other alteration of the physical, chemical, or biological properties of any waters of this State, including a change in temperature, taste, color, turbidity, or odor of the waters or the discharge or deposit of any organic matter, harmful organism, or liquid, gaseous, solid, radioactive, or other substances into any waters of this State, that will render the waters harmful or detrimental to:<section prefix="(1)">Public health, safety, or welfare;</section><section prefix="(2)">Domestic, commercial, industrial, agricultural, recreational, or other legitimate beneficial uses;</section><section prefix="(3)">Livestock, wild animals, or birds; or</section><section prefix="(4)">Fish or other aquatic life.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">"Waters of this State" includes:<section prefix="(1)">Both surface and underground waters within the boundaries of this State subject to its jurisdiction, including that part of the Atlantic Ocean within the boundaries of this State, the Chesapeake Bay and its tributaries, and all ponds, lakes, rivers, streams, storm drain systems, public ditches, tax ditches, and public drainage systems within this State, other than those designed and used to collect, convey, or dispose of sanitary sewage; and</section><section prefix="(2)">The flood plain of free-flowing waters determined by the Department of Natural Resources on the basis of the 100-year flood frequency.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
