<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gen" order_by="" level="1">Environment</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gen-6-839</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>839</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Whenever a qualified offer is made under this part, the qualified offer shall include payment for reasonable expenses and costs up to the amount specified in &#xA7; 6-840 of this subtitle for:<section prefix="(1)">The relocation of the household of the person at risk to lead-safe housing of comparable size and quality that may provide:<section prefix="(i)">The permanent relocation of the household of the affected person at risk to lead-safe housing, including relocation expenses, a rent subsidy, and incidental expenses; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">The temporary relocation of the household of the affected person at risk to lead-safe housing while necessary lead hazard reduction treatments are being performed in the affected property to make that affected property lead-safe; and</section></section><section prefix="(2)">Medically necessary treatment for the affected person at risk as determined by the treating physician or other health care provider or case manager of the person at risk that is necessary to mitigate the effects of lead poisoning, as defined by the Department by regulation, and, in the case of a child, until the child reaches the age of 18 years.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">An offeror is required to pay reasonable expenses for the medically necessary treatments under subsection (a)(2) of this section if coverage for these treatments is not otherwise provided by the Maryland Medical Assistance Program under Title 15, Subtitle 1 of the Health - General Article or by a third-party health insurance plan under which the person at risk has coverage or in which the person at risk is enrolled.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A qualified offer shall include a certification by the owner of the affected property, under the penalties of perjury, that the owner has complied with the applicable provisions of Parts III and IV of this subtitle in a manner that qualifies the owner to make a qualified offer under this part.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Department may adopt regulations that are necessary to carry out the provisions of this section.</section>
  </text>
</law>
