<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gen" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="15-404" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gen-15-404</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">A person may not work in any mine until he has satisfied the operator that he can do the work allotted to him without endangering the lives of his fellow workers, unless the person works with an experienced miner or other qualified person who instructs the person how to perform his duties safely and properly.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Each miner shall examine his working place before commencing work. After any stoppage of work during the shift he shall repeat this examination. If any part of the roof needs propping, he shall prop it and may not commence or resume work until it is made safe. Each miner shall be very careful to keep his working place in a safe condition at all times.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Each miner immediately shall cease work if he finds his place has become dangerous from any cause or condition beyond his power to remedy. Upon leaving the place, he shall install a plain danger signal at the entrance to warn other persons from entering. He shall immediately notify the mine foreman, and may not return until notified by the mine foreman that the danger has been removed.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Each worker at any mine shall notify the mine foreman or other official of any unsafe condition, including unsafe conditions of any working place, haulage road, or traveling way, or of damage to doors, brattices, or of obstructions to any air passage or failure in the ventilation which may become known to him.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">A person intentionally or carelessly may not damage any safety lamp, instrument, air course, or brattice, or without authority handle, remove, or damage any fencing, means of signalling, apparatus, or machinery, or obstruct or throw open airways, or enter a place in or about any mine against caution, or carry fire, open lights, matches, pipes, or other smokers' articles in a gassy mine, or open any door the opening of which is forbidden, or disobey any order given in carrying out the provisions of this subtitle or rule or regulation pursuant to it, or do any other act whereby the lives or health of persons employed or the security of the mine property is endangered.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">Each employee shall observe in and about the mine any special duty relating to the security of life or property as the Bureau, by classes of employment, defines and requires by rule or regulation.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">The mine operator shall direct the attention of each worker to the general and special rules and regulations and to any exit and escapeway of the mine in which he works.</section>
  </text>
</law>
