<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gen" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="14-109" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gen-14-109</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Explosives" means normal commercial explosives, blasting agents, and detonators.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Seismic operations" means the controlled application of vibratory energy from any source to determine if favorable conditions exist for the subsurface entrapment of oil or gas.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">"Seismic section" means a graphic, near-vertical display of waveform data that is usually processed by a computer program to facilitate the interpretation of subsurface conditions.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Unless a person obtains a permit from the Department, a person may not conduct seismic operations in the State.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">An applicant for a permit to conduct seismic operations shall submit an application that includes the information required by the Department.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">In addition to any other information required by the Department, an applicant for a permit to conduct seismic operations on the waters of the Chesapeake Bay and its navigable tributaries shall provide to the Department a written agreement to submit to the Department processed seismic sections for any operation conducted on the waters of the Chesapeake Bay and its navigable tributaries.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The Department shall hold processed seismic sections submitted under this subsection confidential.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The Department shall determine the terms and conditions for the issuance of a permit to conduct seismic operations.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">An applicant for a permit to conduct seismic operations shall demonstrate evidence of sufficient liability insurance coverage, in an amount determined by the Department, for any personal injury or property damage resulting from a seismic operation.</section>
      <section prefix="(6)">The Department may deny an application for a permit if:<section prefix="(i)">The applicant does not submit the information required by the Department;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The proposed activity poses a substantial risk of causing environmental damage that cannot be mitigated by the applicant, particularly to:</section><section prefix="(iii)">The proposed operation will violate regulations adopted by the Department in accordance with this section.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(7)">If the Department decides to deny the permit, the notification of denial shall state the reason, any modification necessary for approval of the application, and the rights of the applicant to appeal the decision as provided in Title 10, Subtitle 2 of the State Government Article.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A person may not use explosives in seismic operations conducted on the waters of the Chesapeake Bay and its tributaries.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A person may use explosives in seismic operations conducted on land if the person complies with the requirements for the use of explosives established by the Department.</section>
  </text>
</law>
