<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gen" order_by="gen" level="1">Environment</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gen-9-421</section_number>
  <catch_line>Grants and loans may be awarded to any State or local governmental entity responsible by law for the...</catch_line>
  <order_by>421</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Grants and loans may be awarded to any State or local governmental entity responsible by law for the provision of water supply systems in order to finance eligible costs of those systems that are necessary to satisfy State drinking water standards and policies or to protect the public health and comfort.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">State assistance under this Part II of this subtitle, may not exceed 87.5 percent of eligible costs for each project or part of a project.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">In the case of a project to be operated by a State-owned institution or facility, State financial assistance shall equal the total cost of the project less the amount of any federal grant made therefor.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">For financial assistance over $500,000 awarded under the Fund, the applicant shall demonstrate, to the satisfaction of the Department, that steps were taken to include small business enterprises, minority business enterprises, and women's business enterprises by:<section prefix="(1)">Placing qualified small business enterprises, minority business enterprises, and women's business enterprises on solicitation lists;</section><section prefix="(2)">Assuring that small business enterprises, minority business enterprises, and women's business enterprises are solicited whenever they are potential sources;</section><section prefix="(3)">Dividing total requirements, when economically feasible, into small tasks or quantities to permit maximum participation of small business enterprises, minority business enterprises, and women's business enterprises;</section><section prefix="(4)">Establishing delivery schedules, where the requirement permits, that encourage participation by small business enterprises, minority business enterprises, and women's business enterprises; and</section><section prefix="(5)">Using the services and assistance of the Maryland Department of Transportation and the Governor's Office of Minority Affairs in identifying and soliciting small business enterprises, minority business enterprises, and women's business enterprises.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">If the steps required under subsection (d) of this section are not demonstrated to the satisfaction of the Department, the Department may withhold financial assistance for the project.</section>
  </text>
</law>
