<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gen" order_by="" level="1">Environment</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gen-4-204</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>204</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">After July 1, 1984, unless exempted, a person may not develop any land for residential, commercial, industrial, or institutional use without submitting a stormwater management plan to the county or municipality that has jurisdiction, and obtaining approval of the plan from the county or municipality. A grading or building permit may not be issued for a property unless a stormwater management plan has been approved that is consistent with this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The developer shall certify that all land clearing, construction, development, and drainage will be done according to the plan.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Each county or municipality may provide by ordinance for the review and approval of stormwater management plans by the local soil conservation district.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Each governing body of a county or municipality may adopt a system of charges to fund the implementation of stormwater management programs, including the following:<section prefix="(i)">Reviewing stormwater management plans;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Inspection and enforcement activities;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Watershed planning;</section><section prefix="(iv)">Planning, design, land acquisition, and construction of stormwater management systems and structures;</section><section prefix="(v)">Retrofitting developed areas for pollution control;</section><section prefix="(vi)">Water quality monitoring and water quality programs;</section><section prefix="(vii)">Operation and maintenance of facilities; and</section><section prefix="(viii)">Program development of these activities.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The charges shall take effect upon enactment by the local governing body.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The charges may be collected in the same manner as county and municipal property taxes, have the same priority, and bear the same interest and penalties.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
