<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gen" order_by="gen" level="1">Environment</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gen-9-1607</section_number>
  <catch_line>The Administration may, subject to the prior approval of the Board and the Secretary, issue bonds fo...</catch_line>
  <order_by>1607</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Administration may, subject to the prior approval of the Board and the Secretary, issue bonds for the purpose of providing moneys for deposit to a fund.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">With respect to each issue of bonds, the Director shall adopt a bond resolution determining:<section prefix="(1)">The date or dates of issue;</section><section prefix="(2)">The date or dates of maturity and the amount or amounts maturing on such date or dates;</section><section prefix="(3)">The fixed or variable rate or rates of interest payable on the bonds, or manner of determining the same, and the date or dates of such payment;</section><section prefix="(4)">The form or forms and denomination or denominations, manner of execution and the place or places of payment of the bonds and of the interest thereon, which may be at any bank or trust company within or without this State;</section><section prefix="(5)">Whether the bonds or any part thereof shall be made redeemable before maturity and, if so, upon what terms, conditions, and prices; and</section><section prefix="(6)">Any other matter relating to the forms, terms, conditions, issuance, and sale of the bonds.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">No person executing the bonds or approving the issuance of the bonds shall be liable personally on the bonds or subject to any personal liability by reason of the issuance of the bonds.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Administration may enter into agreements with agents, banks, insurers, or others for the purpose of enhancing the marketability of or as security for the bonds.</section>
  </text>
</law>
