<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gen" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="9-802" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gen-9-802</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The powers granted by this subtitle are:<section prefix="(1)">Supplemental to the powers granted by any general, special, or local law; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Not restricted by any debt or tax rate limitation in any general law, local law, or municipal charter.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Any municipality may engage in the development of any sewerage facility under this subtitle regardless of any general, special, or local law that:<section prefix="(1)">Provides for the development of similar facilities;</section><section prefix="(2)">Requires approval by the voters of any municipality for the development of the sewerage facility; or</section><section prefix="(3)">Contains any other requirements, restrictions, limitations, or provisions regarding the development of the sewerage facility.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Any municipality may issue bonds under this subtitle to finance the development of any sewerage facility regardless of:<section prefix="(1)">Any general, special, or local law that provides for the issuance of bonds for similar purposes;</section><section prefix="(2)">Any general, special, or local law that requires approval by the voters of the municipality for the issuance of bonds;</section><section prefix="(3)">An unfavorable vote by the voters of the municipality if the Department or a court of competent jurisdiction has ordered the development of the sanitary facility; or</section><section prefix="(4)">Any other requirements, restrictions, limitations, or other provisions contained in any general, special, or local law.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">If any provision of this subtitle is inconsistent with any general, special, or local law, the provision of this subtitle controls.</section>
  </text>
</law>
