<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gen" order_by="" level="1">Environment</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gen-9-622</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>622</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The sanitary commission of each single county district consists of the following numbers of sanitary commissioners, each appointed by the governing body of the member county:<section prefix="(i)">Allegany County - 7;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Dorchester County - 6;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Somerset County, except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection - 5;</section><section prefix="(iv)">Worcester County - 5; and</section><section prefix="(v)">Other counties - 3.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">In a single county district in Somerset County, if there are more than 5 service areas in the single county district, the sanitary commission consists of:<section prefix="(i)">One sanitary commissioner from each service area; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">If there is an even number of service areas, one additional sanitary commissioner.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In a single county district in Somerset County, the sanitary commission consists of:<section prefix="(i)">A sanitary commissioner from each service area who is a resident of that service area; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">If there is an even number of service areas, one additional sanitary commissioner who is a resident of the county at large.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">In other counties, each sanitary commissioner shall be a resident of the county.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The term of a sanitary commissioner in a single county district is as follows:<section prefix="(i)">In Dorchester County, 6 years expiring on July 1 of the appropriate year.</section><section prefix="(ii)">In Allegany County, 6 years expiring on June 1 of the appropriate year.</section><section prefix="(iii)">In Somerset County, 6 years expiring, as required by the terms of the sanitary commissioners on July 1, 1982, on June 1 or January 1 of the appropriate year.</section><section prefix="(iv)">In any other county, 6 years expiring on January 1 of the appropriate year.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The terms of sanitary commissioners in a single county district are staggered as required by the terms provided for sanitary commissioners on July 1, 1989.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The terms of the first sanitary commissioners appointed in a single county district created after June 30, 1982 are as follows:<section prefix="(i)">For one sanitary commissioner, 2 years expiring on the second January 1 after the single county district is created.</section><section prefix="(ii)">For one sanitary commissioner, 4 years expiring on the fourth January 1 after the single county district is created.</section><section prefix="(iii)">For one sanitary commissioner, 6 years expiring on the sixth January 1 after the single county district is created.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">At the end of a term, a sanitary commissioner in a single county district continues to serve until a successor is appointed and qualifies.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A sanitary commissioner in a single county district who is appointed after a term has begun serves only for the rest of the term and until a successor is appointed and qualifies.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">At least 1 month before the term of a sanitary commissioner in a single county district expires, the governing body of the member county shall appoint a successor.</section>
  </text>
</law>
