<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gen" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="9-512" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gen-9-512</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, "building permit" means any permit that allows any building construction and is issued by any State or local authority.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A State or local authority may not issue a building permit unless:<section prefix="(i)">The water supply system, sewerage system, or solid waste acceptance facility is adequate to serve the proposed construction, taking into account all existing and approved developments in the service area;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Any water supply system, sewerage system, or solid waste acceptance facility described in the application will not overload any present facility for conveying, pumping, storing, or treating water, sewage, or solid waste;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Except for essential public services, after January 1, 1992, the county in which the proposed construction is located has an approved recycling plan under &#xA7; 9-505 of this subtitle and &#xA7; 9-1703 of this title; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">Except for essential public services, after January 1, 1994, the county in which the proposed construction is located has met the recycling reductions submitted in an approved recycling plan under &#xA7; 9-505 of this subtitle and &#xA7; 9-1703 of this title.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A water supply system, sewerage system, or solid waste acceptance facility referenced in a subdivision plat shall conform to the applicable county plan.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">If an allocation of water or wastewater is needed, and before a State or local authority may issue a building permit, the State shall:<section prefix="(i)">Have an allocation of water and wastewater from the county whose facilities are affected by the proposed building construction; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">Show evidence of being able to provide an acceptable on-site sewage disposal system or well system until an allocation becomes available, or on a permanent basis if the State elects.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The county shall timely review any State request for an allocation of water or wastewater, and report its findings to the State within 45 days from the date of such request.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">The Department may grant a waiver from the sanctions of subsection (b)(1)(iii) and (iv) of this section if the county demonstrates to the satisfaction of the Secretary that it cannot achieve the recycling goal due to unforseen or emergency circumstances beyond the county's control.</section>
      <section prefix="(6)">
        <section prefix="(i)">In the event that sanctions are imposed under this subsection, and the county submits an application for removing the sanctions, the Secretary shall promptly approve or deny the application.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">In the event that the Secretary has neither approved nor denied the application within 30 days of its submission, the application shall be deemed approved and the sanctions shall be removed.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">To apply for a building permit, an applicant shall:<section prefix="(1)">Submit an application to a State or local authority on the form that the authority requires; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Provide any information that the authority reasonably requires to comply with subsection (b) of this section.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A State or local authority may not record or approve a subdivision plat unless any approved facility for conveying, pumping, storing, or treating water, sewage, or solid waste to serve the proposed development would be:<section prefix="(i)">Completed in time to serve the proposed development; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Adequate to serve the proposed development, once completed, without overloading any water supply system, sewerage system, or solid waste acceptance facility.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Each water supply system, sewerage system, and solid waste acceptance facility in a subdivision shall:<section prefix="(i)">Conform to the applicable county plan; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Take into consideration all present and approved subdivision plats and building permits in the service area.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">If an allocation of water or wastewater is needed, and before a State or local authority may record or approve a subdivision plat, the State shall:<section prefix="(i)">Have an allocation of water and wastewater from the county whose facilities are affected by the proposed development; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">Show evidence of being able to provide an acceptable on-site sewage disposal system or well system until an allocation becomes available, or on a permanent basis if the State elects.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The county shall timely review any State request for an allocation of water or wastewater, and report its findings to the State within 45 days from the date of such request.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">To apply for approval of a subdivision plat, an applicant shall:<section prefix="(1)">Submit an application to the appropriate State or local authority on the form that the authority requires; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Provide any information that the authority reasonably requires to comply with subsection (d) of this section.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
