<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gen" order_by="" level="1">Environment</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gen-1-302</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>302</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">A person who knowingly falsifies, alters, or causes another to falsify or alter any permit, license, or certificate issued or required pursuant to this article to demonstrate compliance with any environmental regulation, permit condition, or other regulatory requirement under this article is guilty of a misdemeanor and on conviction is subject to a fine not exceeding $50,000 for each violation or imprisonment not exceeding 2 years or both.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A person who knowingly possesses, displays, or submits to the Department or any other person any falsified or altered permit, license, or certificate issued or required pursuant to this article to demonstrate compliance with any environmental regulation, permit condition, or other regulatory requirement under this article is guilty of a misdemeanor and on conviction is subject to a fine not exceeding $50,000 for each violation or imprisonment not exceeding 2 years or both.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Any fine imposed in accordance with this section shall be ordered paid into any applicable special fund authorized to receive fines for violations of any section of this article that requires or authorizes the document that is the subject of this violation.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Attorney General shall take charge of, investigate, prosecute, and defend on behalf of the State every case arising under the provisions of this section, including the recovery of any fines.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The provisions of this section may not limit or affect the power or authority of State's Attorneys under &#xA7; 15-102 of the Criminal Procedure Article.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
