<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gen" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="15-1103" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gen-15-1103</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Except for funds deposited in the Acid Mine Drainage Abatement and Treatment Fund under subsection (b) of this section, any funds the Department receives pursuant to Title IV of the federal Surface Mining Control and Reclamation Act of 1977 shall be deposited, together with any other funds appropriated for the purposes of this subtitle, in a special fund on the books of the Comptroller of the Treasury in an account known as the "Federal-State Reclamation Fund". The Department shall use the funds to accomplish the purposes of this subtitle in accordance with the provisions of this subtitle. The provisions of this subtitle shall apply only to the "Federal-State Reclamation Fund".</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">There is an Acid Mine Drainage Abatement and Treatment Fund in the Department.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Funds granted to the Department for acid mine drainage abatement and treatment under Title IV of the federal Surface Mining Control and Reclamation Act of 1977, as amended, may be deposited by the Department into the Acid Mine Drainage Abatement and Treatment Fund.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Funds deposited into the Acid Mine Drainage Abatement and Treatment Fund, together with all interest earned on those funds, shall remain available until expended and may not revert to the General Fund.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The Department may expend funds deposited into the Acid Mine Drainage Abatement and Treatment Fund and any interest accrued only to abate and treat acid mine drainage in accordance with the provisions of Title IV of the federal Surface Mining Control and Reclamation Act.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
