<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gen" order_by="" level="1">Environment</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gen-9-230</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>230</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Department of the Environment shall adopt regulations to carry out this Part III of this subtitle.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Department of the Environment may not adopt a regulation or part of a regulation that deals with the land application of sewage sludge without the approval of the Department of Agriculture.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">In adopting regulations under this Part III and &#xA7;&#xA7; 9-269 and 9-270 of this subtitle, the Department of the Environment shall consider:<section prefix="(1)">Alternative utilization methods;</section><section prefix="(2)">Pathogen control;</section><section prefix="(3)">Advertising requirements for public hearings and public information meetings;</section><section prefix="(4)">Performance bonds, liability insurance, or other forms of security;</section><section prefix="(5)">Procedures for notifying units of local government and other interested parties; and</section><section prefix="(6)">Adequate standards for transporting sewage sludge, including requirements for enclosing or covering sewage sludge during transportation.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">In addition to the considerations under subsection (b) of this section, in adopting regulations for the land application of sewage sludge, the Department of the Environment shall consider:<section prefix="(1)">Methods for calculating loading rates that:<section prefix="(i)">Will assure nondegradation of the groundwater supply; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">For agricultural land, shall be limited by the nutrient requirements of crop or cover vegetation, as recommended by the Department of Agriculture;</section></section><section prefix="(2)">The crops that are to be grown on land on which sewage sludge may be applied;</section><section prefix="(3)">The nature of any nearby surface water or groundwater;</section><section prefix="(4)">The character of any affected area;</section><section prefix="(5)">The character of nearby existing or planned land uses and transport routes;</section><section prefix="(6)">The nearness of the land on which sewage sludge may be applied to sensitive areas, including flood plains, wetlands, and areas of critical concern;</section><section prefix="(7)">The definitions of:<section prefix="(i)">Sewage sludge that is unsuitable for application to agricultural land;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Agricultural land;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Marginal land; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">Compost;</section></section><section prefix="(8)">Acceptable cumulative loading rates, including rates for nitrogen and heavy metals;</section><section prefix="(9)">Special requirements of land used for producing tobacco; and</section><section prefix="(10)">Reasonable buffer areas to separate any home or other property from land on which sewage sludge may be applied.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Department shall adopt regulations to establish a mechanism for determining annual generator's fees.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The regulations shall provide for public input into the development of fee schedules.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The fee schedules shall take into account:<section prefix="(i)">The volume of sewage sludge generated by a sewage sludge generator;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The method by which the sewage sludge is utilized;</section><section prefix="(iii)">The anticipated costs of monitoring and regulating sewage sludge utilization sites;</section><section prefix="(iv)">The anticipated needs of the State's sewage sludge regulation program; and</section><section prefix="(v)">The potential hazard of the sewage sludge generator's activities to public health, safety, or welfare or to the environment.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
