<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gen" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="9-915" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gen-9-915</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">This section applies to an authority that has two or more member political subdivisions.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Except as provided in subsection (g) of this section, the number of directors of the authority is the greater of:<section prefix="(1)">Five; or</section><section prefix="(2)">The number of member political subdivisions.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Except as provided in subsection (g) of this section, the articles of incorporation for the authority shall provide for:<section prefix="(1)">The appointment of directors;</section><section prefix="(2)">The staggering of their terms; and</section><section prefix="(3)">Where the number of member political subdivisions is less than five, the apportioning of the directors between or among the member political subdivisions.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The term of a director may not be more than 5 years.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If a vacancy occurs during the term of a director, the governing body of the political subdivision that is represented by the director shall fill the vacancy.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">If a political subdivision joins the authority, the governing body of the joining political subdivision immediately shall appoint one director for a term that is the same as the terms of the other directors.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">If a political subdivision withdraws from the authority, any director who was appointed to represent the withdrawing political subdivision immediately ceases to be a director.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">In Harford County:<section prefix="(1)">The number of directors of the authority is the greater of:<section prefix="(i)">Seven; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">The number of member political subdivisions.</section></section><section prefix="(2)">The articles of incorporation for the authority shall provide for the apportioning of the directors between or among the member subdivisions if the number of political subdivisions is less than seven.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
