<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gen" order_by="" level="1">Environment</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gen-2-202</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>202</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Council consists of not more than 15 members appointed by the Secretary.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Of the Council members:<section prefix="(i)">1 shall be appointed from a list of 3 qualified individuals who are professional engineers licensed in this State, submitted to the Secretary by the Baltimore section of the American Society of Mechanical Engineers;</section><section prefix="(ii)">1 shall be appointed from a list of 3 qualified individuals submitted to the Secretary by the Maryland section of the American Institute of Chemical Engineers;</section><section prefix="(iii)">2 shall be individuals who are employed in a manufacturing or public utility business in this State, each appointed from a separate list of 3 qualified individuals submitted to the Secretary by the Maryland Chamber of Commerce;</section><section prefix="(iv)">1 shall be a physician;</section><section prefix="(v)">1 shall be a member of the Regional Planning Council who is recommended to the Secretary by the Regional Planning Council;</section><section prefix="(vi)">1 shall be appointed from a list of 3 qualified individuals submitted to the Secretary by the Maryland Association of Counties;</section><section prefix="(vii)">4 shall be appointed 1 each from lists of 3 qualified individuals submitted to the Secretary by:<section prefix="1.">The Chairman of the Board of Directors of the Council of Governments of Metropolitan Washington;</section><section prefix="2.">The President of the Johns Hopkins University;</section><section prefix="3.">The President of the Maryland State-D.C. AFL-CIO; and</section><section prefix="4.">The Chancellor of the University System of Maryland;</section></section><section prefix="(viii)">2 shall be public members who represent the community at large; and</section><section prefix="(ix)">1 shall be a member of the Children's Environmental Health and Protection Advisory Council who has expertise in pediatric environmental health.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">In making appointments to the Council, the Secretary shall:<section prefix="(i)">Consider giving appropriate representation to the various geographical areas of this State; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Appoint at least 1 member who is engaged actively in farming and knowledgeable in farm and rural pollutant problems.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The term of a member is 5 years.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The terms of the members are staggered as required by the terms provided for members of the Council on July 1, 1986.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The member who represents the Regional Planning Council serves only so long as the member remains on the Regional Planning Council.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">At the end of a term, a member continues to serve until a successor is appointed and qualifies.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">A member who is appointed after a term has begun serves only for the rest of the term and until a successor is appointed and qualifies.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
