<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gen" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="9-210" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gen-9-210</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Subject to the provisions of subsection (b) of this section, the Secretary may not issue a permit to install, materially alter, or materially extend a refuse disposal system regulated under &#xA7; 9-204(a) of this subtitle until the requirements set forth in this subsection are met in the following sequence:<section prefix="(1)">Except for the opportunity for a public informational meeting, the Department has completed its preliminary phase 1 technical review of the proposed refuse disposal system;</section><section prefix="(2)">The Department has reported the findings of its preliminary phase 1 technical review, in writing, to the county's chief elected official and planning commission of the county where the proposed refuse disposal system is to be located; and</section><section prefix="(3)">The county has completed its review of the proposed refuse disposal system, and has provided to the Department a written statement that the refuse disposal system:<section prefix="(i)">Meets all applicable county zoning and land use requirements; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Is in conformity with the county solid waste plan.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Upon completion of the requirements of subsection (a)(1) and (2) of this section, the Department shall cease processing the permit application until the requirements of subsection (a)(3) of this section are met.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Secretary may not issue a permit for a rubble landfill under &#xA7; 9-204(a) of this subtitle unless the county in which the rubble landfill is located has specified the types of waste that may be disposed of in that rubble landfill in its county solid waste management plan under Subtitle 5 of this title.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The types of waste that a county may allow to be disposed of in a rubble landfill under this section include:<section prefix="(i)">Trees;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Land clearing debris that is not a controlled hazardous substance as defined in Title 7, Subtitle 2 of this article;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Demolition debris that is not a controlled hazardous substance as defined in Title 7, Subtitle 2 of this article; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">Construction debris that is not a controlled hazardous substance as defined in Title 7, Subtitle 2 of this article.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The following types of waste may be disposed of in a rubble landfill subject to the regulations adopted under this subtitle if the disposal of these wastes is expressly approved by the county in its county solid waste management plan:<section prefix="(i)">Asbestos, if:</section><section prefix="(ii)">White goods; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Subject to &#xA7; 9-228(f) of this subtitle, scrap tires.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
