<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gen" order_by="" level="1">Environment</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gen-9-652</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>652</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">After a service area has been created under &#xA7; 9-648 or &#xA7; 9-649 of this subtitle, the sanitary commission may obtain further surveys, plans, specifications, and estimates that relate to possible projects in a service area.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The sanitary commission may create, within a service area:<section prefix="(1)">Water service subareas;</section><section prefix="(2)">Sewerage service subareas; and</section><section prefix="(3)">Solid waste disposal subareas.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">In creating a service subarea under this subsection, the sanitary commission shall consider whether that creation:<section prefix="(1)">Best serves the needs of the communities in the whole service area; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Promotes convenience and economy of installation and operation of projects in the whole service area.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">When a plan for a proposed project is complete or when the sanitary commission proposes to create service subareas, the sanitary commission shall give notice and hold a public hearing at which time any individual will be given an opportunity to be heard in accordance with this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The hearing shall be held within 5 days of the last date that notice of the hearing is published under subsection (f) of this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">For 3 consecutive weeks before the hearing, the sanitary commission shall publish notice of the hearing in at least 1 newspaper of general circulation in each member county in which the proposed project or service subarea is to be located.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">The notice shall include:<section prefix="(1)">The probable cost, based on the latest available estimates, of the proposed project or subarea;</section><section prefix="(2)">A statement that the plans for the proposed project or subarea may be inspected at the office of the sanitary commission; and</section><section prefix="(3)">A statement that any individual interested in the proposed project or subarea will be heard at the hearing.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(h)">A statement of probable cost included in a notice under this section does not require that the actual cost be the same.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">After the hearing, the sanitary commission shall issue a decision on the proposal.</section>
    <section prefix="(j)">On receipt of a proper petition that protests the proposal, the sanitary commission shall hold a second hearing and give notice of that hearing.</section>
    <section prefix="(k)">A petition for a second hearing by the sanitary commission shall:<section prefix="(1)">Be signed by at least 25 resident landowners who would be served by the proposed project or who reside in the proposed service subarea;</section><section prefix="(2)">Be filed with the sanitary commission within 10 days after the sanitary commission issues a decision under subsection (i) of this section; and</section><section prefix="(3)">State the objections of the petitioners.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(l)">If a proper petition for a second hearing is filed with the sanitary commission, the sanitary commission shall hold a second hearing, if any, within 15 days after the petition is filed.</section>
    <section prefix="(m)">The sanitary commission shall give notice of the second hearing, if any, by:<section prefix="(1)">Mailing the notice to at least 1 petitioner; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Publishing a notice of the time and place of the hearing, at least 5 days before the second hearing, in at least 1 newspaper of general circulation in each county where the proposed project or service subarea is to be located.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(n)">After the second hearing, if any, the sanitary commission shall:<section prefix="(1)">By majority vote of the sanitary commissioners, determine whether the petitioner's objections are reasonable; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Issue a written order that decides the issue.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(o)">The sanitary commission shall give notice of its order after any second hearing under this section by:<section prefix="(1)">Mailing the order to at least 1 petitioner; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Publishing the order in at least 1 newspaper of general circulation in each member county where the proposed project or service subarea is to be located.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(p)">Persons aggrieved by the decision of the sanitary commission following a second hearing under this section may appeal to the member counties in accordance with this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(q)">An appeal to the member counties may be made under this section if:<section prefix="(1)">The appeal is signed by at least 20 of the petitioners for a second hearing before the sanitary commission; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Within 10 days after notice of the sanitary commission's decision after the second hearing is published under this section, the appeal is filed with the governing body of each member county where the proposed project or service subarea is to be located.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(r)">The governing body of each member county of the proposed project or service subarea shall hear the appeal from the second hearing.</section>
    <section prefix="(s)">After an appeal under this section, the proposed project or service subarea may not be established unless the governing body of each member county affirms the proposed project or service subarea.</section>
    <section prefix="(t)">The decision of the governing bodies of the member counties is final.</section>
  </text>
</law>
