<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gen" order_by="" level="1">Environment</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gen-9-946</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>946</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">An authority may set, charge, and collect rates, fees, and charges in connection with each of its projects to provide funds that, with any other available funds, are sufficient at all times:<section prefix="(1)">To pay:<section prefix="(i)">The expenses of the authority;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The cost of construction, extension, repair, improvement, maintenance, and operation of each facility and property of the authority;</section><section prefix="(iii)">The cost of maintenance, repair, and operation of each project for which the authority issued bonds under this subtitle, including the creation of reserves for the maintenance, repair, operation, replacement, depreciation, and necessary extensions of the project; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">The principal of and interest on all bonds of the authority whenever due and payable, including the creation of reserves to provide a margin of safety; and</section></section><section prefix="(2)">To fulfill the terms of any agreement that is made with:<section prefix="(i)">A purchaser or holder of any bond of the authority;</section><section prefix="(ii)">A political subdivision that is incorporated or is a member of the authority; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">A political subdivision that is or will be served by the authority.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">An authority may:<section prefix="(1)">Set rates, fees, and charges for the services and facilities of its water system that are sufficient to pay:<section prefix="(i)">The cost of maintenance, repair, and operation of its sewerage system; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">The principal of and interest on bonds that the authority issues for its sewerage system; and</section></section><section prefix="(2)">Subject to prior pledges of surplus revenue, pledge any surplus revenue of its water system for the purposes stated in item (1) of this subsection.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">An authority may base rates, fees, and charges for the services and facilities of its sewerage system on:<section prefix="(i)">The quantity of water used;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The amount of the water bill;</section><section prefix="(iii)">The number and size of sewer connections;</section><section prefix="(iv)">The number and kind of plumbing fixtures in use in the premises that are connected with the sewerage system;</section><section prefix="(v)">The number or average number of individuals who reside in, work in, or are otherwise connected with the premises that are connected with the sewerage system;</section><section prefix="(vi)">The type or character of the premises that are connected with the sewerage system;</section><section prefix="(vii)">Any other factor that affects the use of the facilities furnished; or</section><section prefix="(viii)">Any combination of these factors.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If any premises obtain all or part of their water from a source other than a public water system, an authority may charge the premises for sewerage services:<section prefix="(i)">By gauging or metering; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">In any other manner that the authority approves.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">An authority may base rates, fees, and charges for any of its other services and facilities on any factor that the authority determines to be reasonable and proper.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The rates, fees, and charges of an authority shall be:<section prefix="(1)">Reasonable;</section><section prefix="(2)">Uniform by class; and</section><section prefix="(3)">Determined solely by the authority.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Any person who questions whether the rates, fees, or charges of an authority are reasonable or uniform may sue the authority:<section prefix="(i)">In the circuit court for the county in which the project is located; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">If the project is located in 2 or more counties, in the circuit court for the county in which the principal office of the project is located.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The circuit court has exclusive jurisdiction to determine the reasonableness and uniformity of the rates, fees, and other charges of an authority.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
