<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gen" order_by="gen" level="1">Environment</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gen-5-1104.2</section_number>
  <catch_line>There is an Executive Committee created to provide oversight in the development of the State of Mary...</catch_line>
  <order_by>1104.2</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">There is an Executive Committee created to provide oversight in the development of the State of Maryland's plans for dredged material management.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Executive Committee shall consist of:<section prefix="(i)">The Secretary of Transportation, or the Secretary's designee;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The Secretary of Natural Resources, or the Secretary's designee;</section><section prefix="(iii)">The Secretary of the Environment, or the Secretary's designee;</section><section prefix="(iv)">A representative of the Chesapeake Bay Foundation, designated by the Chesapeake Bay Foundation;</section><section prefix="(v)">A representative of the Management Committee of the Dredged Material Placement Program; and</section><section prefix="(vi)">A citizen representative, appointed by the Governor.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Governor shall invite the following people to serve as members of the Executive Committee:<section prefix="(i)">A representative of the Army Corps of Engineers, Philadelphia District; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">A representative of the Army Corps of Engineers, Baltimore District.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Executive Committee shall meet as needed, but not less than semiannually.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Executive Committee shall:<section prefix="(1)">Review and recommend to the Governor dredged material placement options, including, but not limited to, the placement sites identified in the October 1, 2000 Report to the Maryland General Assembly regarding the Governor's Strategic Plan for Dredged Material Management, to fill short-term capacity needs as specified in &#xA7; 5-1102(d)(2)(ii) of this subtitle;</section><section prefix="(2)">Review and recommend to the Governor elements, as part of a continuous and long-term strategic plan for dredged material management, including changes to the plan; and</section><section prefix="(3)">Review and recommend to the Governor dredged material disposal sites for long-term dredged material placement capacity based on the following hierarchy:<section prefix="(i)">Beneficial use and innovative reuse of dredged material;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Upland sites and other environmentally sound confined capacity;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Expansion of existing dredged material disposal capacity other than the Hart-Miller Island Dredged Material Containment Facility and areas collectively known as Pooles Island, including G-West and Site 92; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">Other dredged material placement options to meet long-term placement needs, except for redepositing dredged material in an unconfined manner.</section></section></section>
  </text>
</law>
