<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gen" order_by="gen" level="1">Environment</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gen-9-698</section_number>
  <catch_line>Before a person may dig in or do any other construction on any way in a service area, the person sha...</catch_line>
  <order_by>698</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Before a person may dig in or do any other construction on any way in a service area, the person shall obtain from the sanitary commission approval of the digging or construction.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">To obtain approval, the person shall file with the sanitary commission a plan for the digging or construction that shows the depth and location of each:<section prefix="(1)">Conduit;</section><section prefix="(2)">Main;</section><section prefix="(3)">Pipe;</section><section prefix="(4)">Pole; and</section><section prefix="(5)">Other structure.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">If approval of the plans has been obtained from the sanitary commission, before a person may do any digging or construction different from the approved plans, the person shall:<section prefix="(1)">Submit a new plan that shows the changes in the information required for the original plan; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Obtain approval from the sanitary commission to do the digging or construction according to the new plan.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">If any obstruction has been constructed in, on, or under a way in violation of this section and if the sanitary commission is required to move that obstruction to build or operate a project:<section prefix="(1)">The district may move the obstruction and charge the cost of moving the obstruction to:<section prefix="(i)">The person who constructed or installed the obstruction; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">Any successor in interest to that person;</section></section><section prefix="(2)">The owner of the obstruction is not entitled to compensation under this subtitle for moving the obstruction; and</section><section prefix="(3)">The district is not liable for damage done to the obstruction.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">Before beginning work on the plumbing system on any property in a service area, a person shall:<section prefix="(1)">Obtain from the district a permit to do the plumbing work;</section><section prefix="(2)">Pay to the district the permit fee that the sanitary commission requires; and</section><section prefix="(3)">Allow the sanitary commission to inspect the plumbing work.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">Before connecting the plumbing system of any property to a water pipe or sewer pipe operated by the district, a person shall:<section prefix="(1)">Obtain from the district a permit to make the connection; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Comply with any additional conditions that the sanitary commission requires.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
