<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gen" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="7-409" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gen-7-409</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Board shall be a unit of the Department for purposes of executive organization.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Board has all powers necessary for carrying out the purposes of this subtitle, including but not limited to the powers set forth in this section, and may:<section prefix="(1)">Make any contract or agreement the Board determines to be necessary or incidental to the performance of its duties and to the execution of the purpose of and the powers granted by this subtitle;</section><section prefix="(2)">Make directly, or through the hiring of staff or consultants, any plans, surveys, investigations, or studies bearing on the characteristics of any site or on the need for and employment of sites and facilities throughout the State; and</section><section prefix="(3)">Prepare information to further public understanding of matters that the Board is required to consider, such as site suitability, management alternatives and the treatment and disposal needs of the State, and to disseminate such information to environmental and community organizations, schools, libraries, local, State, and federal government agencies, and other members of the general public.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The determination by the Board of statewide need and the plans and surveys prepared by the Board as authorized by this subtitle shall be prepared in form and substance suitable for inclusion in any statewide solid waste management plan.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">To assist the Board in carrying out the provisions of this subtitle, the Department shall routinely furnish the Board with copies of relevant information and data filed with the Department under the provisions of this article that are applicable to the generation, transport, and disposal of hazardous waste.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">In the event that the statewide plan is no longer required under the Resource Conservation and Recovery Act, as amended, the Board within 1 year after the Act is not in effect shall prepare a 10-year hazardous waste management plan and shall propose procedures for its adoption.</section>
  </text>
</law>
