<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gen" order_by="" level="1">Environment</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gen-9-209</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>209</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The applicant shall give notice of the application, the informational meeting, and hearings:<section prefix="(1)">To the public in compliance with Title 1, Subtitle 6 of this article;</section><section prefix="(2)">To the board of county commissioners or the county council of any county and the chief executive of any county or municipal corporation that the Department determines may be affected by the incinerator for public use or landfill system, by certified mail;</section><section prefix="(3)">To the Department of Natural Resources, by certified mail;</section><section prefix="(4)">To each member of the General Assembly representing any part of a county in which the landfill system or incinerator is located, by certified mail;</section><section prefix="(5)">To record owners of real property within 1,000 feet of the property line of the proposed incinerator for public use or landfill system, by certified mail to the addresses of record owners as indicated in the records of the State Department of Assessments and Taxation; and</section><section prefix="(6)">By posting a notice of the application, the informational meeting, and hearings in a conspicuous space on the site of the proposed incinerator for public use or landfill system.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The local officials notified under subsection (a)(2) of this section shall give notice of the application, the informational meeting, and hearings to all interested agencies of their respective jurisdictions.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">To the extent practicable, the Department and other units of the State government shall consolidate the informational meeting and hearings concerning permits for the same landfill system or incinerator for public use.</section>
  </text>
</law>
