<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gen" order_by="" level="1">Environment</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gen-7-509</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>509</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Upon submission of a proposed response action plan, the participant:<section prefix="(1)">Shall publish a notice of a proposed response action plan once a week for 2 consecutive weeks in a daily or weekly newspaper of general circulation in the geographical area in which the eligible property is located that shall include:<section prefix="(i)">A summary of the proposed response action plan;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The name and address of the participant and eligible property;</section><section prefix="(iii)">The name, address, and telephone number of the office within the Department from which information about the proposed response action plan may be obtained;</section><section prefix="(iv)">An address to which persons may submit written comments about the proposed response action plan;</section><section prefix="(v)">A deadline for the close of the public comment period by which written comments must be received by the Department; and</section><section prefix="(vi)">The date and location of the public informational meeting; and</section></section><section prefix="(2)">Shall post at the eligible property a notice of intent to conduct a response action plan at that property.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Department shall receive written comments from the public for 30 days after publication and posting required under this section or 5 days after the public informational meeting required under this section, whichever is later.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Department shall hold a public informational meeting on the proposed response action plan at the participant's expense within 40 days after the publication of the notice in accordance with subsection (a)(1) of this section.</section>
  </text>
</law>
