<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gen" order_by="" level="1">Environment</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gen-9-911</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>911</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">An authority may terminate its existence after the authority:<section prefix="(1)">Pays or provides for payment of the principal of and interest on each bond that the authority issued;</section><section prefix="(2)">Settles any other claim against the authority; and</section><section prefix="(3)">Has the approval by law of the governing body of each member political subdivision.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">To terminate its existence, an authority shall:<section prefix="(1)">Comply with the provisions of this section; and</section><section prefix="(2)">File articles of dissolution for record with the State Department of Assessments and Taxation.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The articles of dissolution shall include:<section prefix="(1)">A statement that requests the termination of the existence of the authority;</section><section prefix="(2)">A statement that the authority has:<section prefix="(i)">Paid or provided for payment of the principal of and interest on each bond that the authority issued; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Settled each other claim against the authority; and</section></section><section prefix="(3)">The signatures of the authorized officers of the authority.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If the articles of dissolution comply with this subtitle, the State Department of Assessments and Taxation shall:<section prefix="(i)">Note the termination of existence of the authority on the records of the Department; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Issue a certificate of approval to the board of directors of the authority.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">On approval of the articles of dissolution by the State Department of Assessments and Taxation, the existence of the authority ends.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
