<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gen" order_by="" level="1">Environment</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gen-5-903</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>903</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">There is a statewide program within the Department for the conservation, regulation, enhancement, creation, monitoring, and wise use of nontidal wetlands.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Department shall:<section prefix="(1)">Coordinate with other State agencies, federal agencies, other states, local governments, and interested persons in the regulation of nontidal wetlands;</section><section prefix="(2)">Assist local governments in undertaking nontidal wetland management planning, including mapping, technical assistance, and expediting the permit process;</section><section prefix="(3)">Develop certification programs to ensure uniform and professional standards for the identification, delineation, functional assessment, and mitigation of nontidal wetlands;</section><section prefix="(4)">Evaluate proposed activities on nontidal wetlands and grant or deny permits or other approvals of proposed activities;</section><section prefix="(5)">Conduct watershed studies and educational programs and disseminate information concerning the nontidal wetlands program;</section><section prefix="(6)">Prepare, adopt, and periodically revise guidance maps of nontidal wetlands;</section><section prefix="(7)">Adopt standards for planning, regulating, restoring, creating, and enhancing nontidal wetlands;</section><section prefix="(8)">Purchase, restore, and create nontidal wetlands; and</section><section prefix="(9)">Conduct periodic monitoring, cumulative impact assessment, and evaluation of activities authorized under this subtitle.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">By December 31, 1989 the Department shall adopt final regulations necessary to administer this subtitle, in accordance with &#xA7; 10-111(a) of the State Government Article.</section>
  </text>
</law>
