<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gen" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="1-606" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gen-1-606</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Board" means the Board of Public Works.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"License" means a license under &#xA7; 16-202 of this article.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">This section applies to:<section prefix="(1)">A permit listed under &#xA7; 1-601(a) of this subtitle;</section><section prefix="(2)">A permit listed under &#xA7; 5-204(f) of this article; or</section><section prefix="(3)">A license issued under &#xA7; 16-202 of this article.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Any judicial review of a determination provided for in accordance with &#xA7; 1-601 of this subtitle or &#xA7; 5-204 or &#xA7; 16-204 of this article shall be limited to a record compiled by the Department or Board, consisting of:<section prefix="(1)">Any permit or license application and any data submitted to the Department or Board in support of the application;</section><section prefix="(2)">Any draft permit or license issued by the Department or Board;</section><section prefix="(3)">Any notice of intent from the Department or Board to deny the application or to terminate the permit or license;</section><section prefix="(4)">A statement or fact sheet explaining the basis for the determination by the Department or Board;</section><section prefix="(5)">All documents referenced in the statement or fact sheet explaining the basis for the determination by the Department or Board;</section><section prefix="(6)">All documents, except documents for which disclosure is precluded by law or that are subject to privilege, contained in the supporting file for any draft permit or license;</section><section prefix="(7)">All comments submitted to the Department or Board during the public comment period, including comments made on the draft application;</section><section prefix="(8)">Any tape or transcript of any public hearings held on the application; and</section><section prefix="(9)">Any response to any comments submitted to the Department or Board.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">When a draft permit or license or tentative determination is issued, the Department or Board shall:<section prefix="(i)">Make available for inspection and copying no later than the date the permit, draft license, or tentative determination is issued:</section><section prefix="(ii)">Extend the public comment period by 60 days on request by a person.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A request submitted to the Department or Board under paragraph (1)(ii) of this subsection shall be:<section prefix="(i)">Submitted in writing; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Made before the expiration of the original comment period.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A public comment period may not be extended more than once under paragraph (1)(ii) of this subsection.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
