<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gen" order_by="" level="1">Environment</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gen-15-528</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>528</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Except as provided in subsection (b) of this section, any person, as defined in this subtitle, who has an interest that is or may be adversely affected may commence a civil action on his own behalf to compel compliance with this subtitle:<section prefix="(1)">Against the Department if there is alleged a failure of the Department to perform any act or duty under this subtitle that is not discretionary; or</section><section prefix="(2)">Against any other person who is alleged to be in violation of any rule, regulation, order, or permit issued under this subtitle.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">An action may not be commenced under subsection (a) of this section:<section prefix="(1)">Prior to 60 days after the plaintiff has given notice in writing of the alleged violation to the Department, the Attorney General, and to any alleged violator; provided that, the action may be brought immediately if the alleged violation constitutes an imminent threat to the health or safety of the plaintiff, or would immediately affect a legal interest of the plaintiff; or</section><section prefix="(2)">If the Department or the State has commenced and is diligently prosecuting a civil action to require compliance under this subtitle, but any person may intervene in the action as a matter of right.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Secretary of the United States Department of Interior may intervene as a matter of right in any action brought under this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">This section is intended to be read in conjunction with and to supplement the provisions of Subtitle 5 of Title 1 of the Natural Resources Article (Environmental Standing Act), but in the event of any conflict, the requirements of this section shall prevail.</section>
  </text>
</law>
