<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gen" order_by="" level="1">Environment</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gen-2-503</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>503</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">If a petition for a temporary fuel variance is filed in accordance with &#xA7; 2-502 of this subtitle, the Department shall schedule a public hearing on the petition to be held as soon as possible but no earlier than 10 days after publication of the notice required by this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The petitioner shall publish a prominent notice of the hearing in a newspaper of general circulation in the county where the source for which the temporary fuel variance is sought is located.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Except as otherwise provided by the Department, the notice shall contain:<section prefix="(1)">The name and address of the petitioner;</section><section prefix="(2)">The location and a description of the operations for which the temporary fuel variance is sought;</section><section prefix="(3)">A reference to the specific rule, regulation, or order from which the temporary fuel variance is sought;</section><section prefix="(4)">A brief statement explaining why the temporary fuel variance is sought;</section><section prefix="(5)">A statement that any person may oppose the petition at a public hearing on a specific date and at a specific time and location; and</section><section prefix="(6)">Any additional information that the Department requires.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Department may grant an emergency temporary fuel variance before the public hearing if:<section prefix="(i)">The petitioner shows to the Department an immediate need for the temporary fuel variance; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">The Air Management Administration recommends that the Department grant the temporary fuel variance before the hearing.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If the Department grants an emergency temporary fuel variance before the public hearing:<section prefix="(i)">The notice of the hearing shall state that an emergency temporary fuel variance has been granted and will be reviewed at the hearing; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">The hearing shall be held by the Department within 30 days after the petition is filed.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">After the hearing and if the Air Management Administration so recommends, the Department may:<section prefix="(1)">If a temporary fuel variance has not been previously granted:<section prefix="(i)">Grant a temporary fuel variance, subject to federal requirements, for a period of not more than 120 days; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">Refuse to grant a temporary fuel variance; and</section></section><section prefix="(2)">If an emergency temporary fuel variance has been granted previously:<section prefix="(i)">Terminate the emergency temporary fuel variance; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">Extend the emergency temporary fuel variance, subject to federal regulations, for a period of not more than 120 days from the date the variance was first granted.</section></section></section>
  </text>
</law>
