<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gen" order_by="gen" level="1">Environment</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gen-10-202</section_number>
  <catch_line>On the written complaint of 2 physicians or of at least 3 persons who claim to be affected by the co...</catch_line>
  <order_by>202</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">On the written complaint of 2 physicians or of at least 3 persons who claim to be affected by the condition, the Secretary shall investigate any complaint that any of the following is in a condition that injures any adjacent property or that is dangerous to human health:<section prefix="(1)">Any watercourse, well, spring, open ditch, gutter, cesspool, drain, outhouse, pigpen, or other place.</section><section prefix="(2)">Any accumulation or deposit of offensive or noxious matter.</section><section prefix="(3)">Any house, building, trades establishment, or manufacturing place.</section><section prefix="(4)">Any water in which mosquito larvae breed.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If the Secretary finds that the condition of the place or thing investigated may injure any adjacent property or may injure the life or health of any individual, the place or thing is in a state of nuisance and the Secretary shall serve a written notice to the person who is causing the nuisance, ordering the person to abate the nuisance within a time specified in the notice.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The notice shall be served:<section prefix="(i)">On the person who is causing the nuisance; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">If the person who is causing the nuisance cannot be found, on the owner or occupant of the property where the nuisance exists.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Secretary may file a complaint in the circuit court for the county where the nuisance exists if:<section prefix="(i)">The person served with the notice fails to comply with the requirements of the notice; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">Although the person served complies with the requirements of the notice, the nuisance is likely to recur on the same property.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A complaint filed under this subsection may seek a court order requiring the person served with the notice to do any or all of the following:<section prefix="(i)">To comply with the requirements of the Secretary's abatement notice.</section><section prefix="(ii)">To abate the nuisance within a time specified in the order.</section><section prefix="(iii)">To prevent the nuisance from recurring.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
