<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gen" order_by="gen" level="1">Environment</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gen-9-708</section_number>
  <catch_line>A municipal authority shall:...</catch_line>
  <order_by>708</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">A municipal authority shall:<section prefix="(1)">Construct and provide at its own expense for any water main or sanitary sewer constructed or established under Part II of this subtitle, a water service pipe or sewer connection that extends from the water main or sewer to the property line of each lot that abuts on a street or right-of-way in which the water main or sewer is laid; and</section><section prefix="(2)">When the municipal authority declares that a water main or sewer is complete and ready for use, notify each owner of abutting property that the owner shall:<section prefix="(i)">Connect all spigots or hydrants, toilets, and waste drains with the water main or sewer, within a reasonable time as determined by the municipal authority; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Install adequate spigots or hydrants, toilets and waste drains if:<section prefix="1.">There are no fixtures or drains; or</section><section prefix="2.">The municipal authority believes that the existing fixtures or drains are improper or inadequate.</section></section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">To prevent any use of or any injury to the public health, each owner of property that is connected with a sewer shall abandon, close, and leave, in the manner that the municipal authority directs, any:<section prefix="(1)">Cesspool;</section><section prefix="(2)">Drain;</section><section prefix="(3)">Privy; or</section><section prefix="(4)">Well that is determined by the municipal authority to be polluted or a menace to health.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">After notice from the municipal authority, if a property owner in Frederick County fails to comply with the provisions of this section, the municipal authority may:<section prefix="(i)">Have any necessary connections made;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Cause any cesspool, drains, or privy to be closed and abandoned; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Charge the property owner with the cost of the connection or closing or both.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">For purposes of this subsection, the costs:<section prefix="(i)">Are a lien against the affected property until paid; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">May be collected in the same manner as county or municipal taxes.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
