<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gen" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="9-668" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gen-9-668</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">For the construction, maintenance, or operation of any part of a project, the district may acquire any interest in real property by:<section prefix="(1)">Purchase; or</section><section prefix="(2)">Exercise of the power of eminent domain as provided in Title 12 of the Real Property Article.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as otherwise provided in this subsection, the district may condemn a property right in a cemetery only to install a sewer line or a water line.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The district may not condemn any property rights in and may not disturb:<section prefix="(i)">Any existing grave;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Any grave marker or monument;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Any grave site whose title has been transferred through a sale or exchange made in good faith; or</section><section prefix="(iv)">Any grave site as to which burial rights have vested or been transferred through a sale or agreement made in good faith.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Before the district condemns a property right in a cemetery, the sanitary commission shall adopt a resolution that:<section prefix="(1)">Is approved by a majority of the sanitary commissioners appointed from the member county in which the cemetery is located;</section><section prefix="(2)">Includes a declaration that the condemnation is necessary for the public health and safety; and</section><section prefix="(3)">Includes a declaration that immediate acquisition of the property right in the cemetery is necessary.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The sanitary commission shall bury every water line and sewer line that it builds in cemetery land.</section>
  </text>
</law>
