<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gen" order_by="" level="1">Environment</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gen-2-612</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>612</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Secretary may adopt rules and regulations that:<section prefix="(1)">Are patterned after &#xA7; 120 of the federal Clean Air Act and the federal regulations adopted under &#xA7; 120 of the federal Clean Air Act; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Specify:<section prefix="(i)">The circumstances under which a person who violates this title is subject to a noncompliance penalty equal to the economic benefit that accrues to the person because of noncompliance;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The method of calculating the noncompliance penalty;</section><section prefix="(iii)">The manner of payment of the noncompliance penalty; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">The circumstances under which a noncompliance penalty collected under this section is subject to rebate.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If a person fails to pay a noncompliance penalty in a timely manner, the Secretary may require the person to pay an additional nonpayment penalty for each quarter that the noncompliance penalty remains unpaid.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The nonpayment penalty shall equal 20 percent of the total of the person's noncompliance penalties and nonpayment penalties that remain unpaid at the beginning of the quarter.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">If a person fails to pay a noncompliance penalty or nonpayment penalty imposed under this section, the Department may bring an action to collect the penalty in the same manner as a civil penalty is collected under &#xA7; 2-610 of this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">An action under this section to collect a noncompliance penalty is in addition to and not instead of:<section prefix="(1)">An action under &#xA7; 2-609 of this subtitle; or</section><section prefix="(2)">Any other relief under this subtitle.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
