<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gen" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="7-513" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gen-7-513</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Upon completion of the requirements of the response action plan, the participant shall notify the Department in writing that the response action plan has been completed.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Within 30 days after receipt of the notice of completion under paragraph (1) of this subsection:<section prefix="(i)">The Department shall review the implementation and completion of the response action plan at the eligible property; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">If the Department determines that the requirements of the response action plan have been completed to the satisfaction of the Department and the response action plan has achieved the cleanup criteria, the Department shall issue a certificate of completion.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The certificate of completion shall state that, subject to the requirements of &#xA7; 7-514(b) of this subtitle:<section prefix="(1)">The requirements of the response action plan have been completed;</section><section prefix="(2)">The participant has demonstrated that the implementation of the response action plan at the eligible property has achieved the applicable cleanup criteria under &#xA7; 7-508 (b) of this subtitle;</section><section prefix="(3)">The Department may not bring an enforcement action against the participant at the eligible property; and</section><section prefix="(4)">The participant:<section prefix="(i)">Is released from further liability for the remediation of the eligible property under this title for any contamination identified in the environmental site assessment; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">May not be subject to a contribution action instituted by a responsible person.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Within 10 days after the issuance of a certificate of completion, the Department shall send a copy of the certificate of completion to the Director of the Department of Assessments and Taxation.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A requirement for long-term monitoring and maintenance in the approved response action plan may not delay the issuance of the certificate of completion under subsection (a) of this section.</section>
  </text>
</law>
