<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gen" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="9-1605.2" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gen-9-1605.2</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">There is a Bay Restoration Fund.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">It is the intent of the General Assembly that the Bay Restoration Fund be:<section prefix="(i)">Used, in part, to provide the funding necessary to upgrade any of the wastewater treatment facilities that are located in the State or used by citizens of the State in order to achieve enhanced nutrient removal where it is cost-effective to do so; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Available for treatment facilities discharging into the Atlantic Coastal Bays or other waters of the State, but that priority be given to treatment facilities discharging into the Chesapeake Bay.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Bay Restoration Fund shall be maintained and administered by the Administration in accordance with the provisions of this section and any rules or program directives as the Secretary or the Board may prescribe.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">There is established a Bay Restoration Fee to be paid by any user of a wastewater facility, an onsite sewage disposal system, or a holding tank that:<section prefix="(i)">Is located in the State; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">Serves a Maryland user and is eligible for funding under this subtitle.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Beginning on July 1, 2030, the Bay Restoration Fee is:</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">For a nonresidential user, the Bay Restoration Fee may be calculated based on an estimate of equivalent dwelling units of wastewater effluent generated, if the nonresidential user's wastewater bill is based on wastewater generated and not on water usage.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">For a residential dwelling that receives an individual sewer bill, a user of an onsite sewage disposal system or a holding tank that receives a water bill, a building or group of buildings under single ownership or management that receives a water and sewer bill and that contains multiple residential dwellings that do not receive an individual sewer bill, and a nonresidential user, the restoration fee shall be:</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)"/>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The total fee imposed under paragraph (1) of this subsection may not exceed $120,000 annually for a single site.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">
        <section prefix="(i)">For purposes of measuring average daily wastewater flow, the local government or billing authority for a wastewater facility shall use existing methods of measurement, which may include water usage or other estimation methods.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The averaging period is:</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(5)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The Bay Restoration Fee under this subsection may not be reduced as long as bonds are outstanding.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">Any change in the manner of determining the Bay Restoration Fee may not reduce the amount of funds available for the payment of outstanding bonds.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A user of a wastewater facility is exempt from paying the restoration fee if:<section prefix="(1)"><section prefix="(i)"/><section prefix="(ii)">The user's wastewater facility has not received a State or federal grant for that facility;</section></section><section prefix="(2)"><section prefix="(i)">The user's wastewater facility discharges to groundwater and the annual average nutrient concentrations in the wastewater prior to discharge to groundwater have not exceeded 3 milligrams per liter total nitrogen and 0.3 milligrams per liter total phosphorus, as demonstrated by analysis of the groundwater from monitoring wells located on the property and as reported in discharge monitoring reports for the previous calendar year; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">The user's wastewater facility has not received a federal or State grant for that facility; or</section></section><section prefix="(3)">The Department determines that:<section prefix="(i)">The user's wastewater facility discharges noncontact cooling water, water from dewatering operations, or reclaimed wastewater from a facility whose users pay in to the Fund; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">The discharge does not result in a net increase in loading of nutrients compared to the intake water.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Subject to the approval of the Administration, a local government or a billing authority for a water or wastewater facility shall establish a program to exempt from the requirements of this section a residential dwelling able to demonstrate substantial financial hardship as a result of the restoration fee.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Except as provided in subparagraph (ii) of this paragraph, the Bay Restoration Fee shall be collected by the local government or the billing authority for the water or wastewater facility, as appropriate, on behalf of the State.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">For a wastewater facility without a billing authority, the Comptroller may collect the restoration fee from the facility owner.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A local government, billing authority for a water or wastewater facility, or any other authorized collecting agency:<section prefix="(i)">May use all of its existing procedures and authority for collecting a water or sewer bill, an onsite sewage disposal system bill, or a holding tank bill in order to enforce the collection of the Bay Restoration Fee; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Shall establish a segregated account for the deposit of funds collected under this section.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">
        <section prefix="(i)">This paragraph applies only in Dorchester County.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">An unpaid Bay Restoration Fee shall be a lien against the property served by a wastewater facility, onsite sewage disposal system, or holding tank.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">A notice of lien shall be recorded in the land records of Dorchester County.</section>
        <section prefix="(iv)">The County Council may collect the Bay Restoration Fee on behalf of the Dorchester County Sanitary District.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(5)">
        <section prefix="(i)">In Caroline County, an unpaid Bay Restoration Fee shall be a lien against the property served by a wastewater facility, onsite sewage disposal system, or holding tank.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">A notice of lien shall be recorded in the land records of Caroline County.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A local government, the billing authority for a water or wastewater facility, or any other authorized collecting agency shall complete and submit, under oath, a return and remit the restoration fees collected to the Comptroller:<section prefix="(i)">On or before the 20th day of the month that follows the calendar quarter in which the restoration fee was collected; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">For other periods and on other dates that the Comptroller may specify by regulation, including periods in which no restoration fee has been collected.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Except to the extent of any inconsistency with this subsection, the provisions of Title 13 of the Tax - General Article that are applicable to the sales and use tax shall govern the administration, collection, and enforcement of the restoration fee under this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Comptroller may adopt regulations necessary to administer, collect, and enforce the restoration fee.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">
        <section prefix="(i)">From the restoration fee revenue, the Comptroller shall distribute to an administrative cost account the amount that is necessary to administer the fee, which may not exceed 0.5% of the fees collected by the Comptroller.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">After making the distribution required under subparagraph (i) of this paragraph, the Comptroller shall deposit the restoration fee in the Bay Restoration Fund.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(5)">The State Central Collection Unit may collect delinquent accounts under this section in accordance with &#xA7; 3-302 of the State Finance and Procurement Article.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The Bay Restoration Fund is a special, continuing, nonlapsing fund that is not subject to &#xA7; 7-302 of the State Finance and Procurement Article and shall be available in perpetuity for the purpose of providing financial assistance in accordance with the provisions of this section.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">Money in the Fund may not revert or be transferred to the General Fund or a special fund of the State.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Bay Restoration Fund shall be available for the purpose of providing financial assistance in accordance with the provisions of this section for:<section prefix="(i)">Eligible costs of projects relating to planning, design, construction, and upgrades of wastewater facilities to achieve enhanced nutrient removal as required by the conditions of a grant agreement and a discharge permit; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">All projects identified in subsections (h) and (i) of this section.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Subject to the provisions of any applicable bond resolution regarding the holding or application of amounts in the Bay Restoration Fund, the Treasurer shall separately hold, and the Comptroller shall account for, the Bay Restoration Fund.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">Subject to the provisions of any applicable bond resolution governing the investment of amounts in the Bay Restoration Fund, the Bay Restoration Fund shall be invested and reinvested in the same manner as other State funds.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">Any investment earnings shall be retained to the credit of the Bay Restoration Fund.</section>
      <section prefix="(6)">The Bay Restoration Fund shall be subject to audit by the Office of Legislative Audits as provided under &#xA7; 2-1220 of the State Government Article.</section>
      <section prefix="(7)">The Administration shall operate the Bay Restoration Fund in accordance with &#xA7;&#xA7; 9-1616 through 9-1621 of this subtitle.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">There shall be deposited in the Bay Restoration Fund:<section prefix="(1)">Funds received from the restoration fee;</section><section prefix="(2)">Net proceeds of bonds issued by the Administration;</section><section prefix="(3)">Interest or other income earned on the investment of money in the Bay Restoration Fund; and</section><section prefix="(4)">Any additional money made available from any sources, public or private, for the purposes for which the Bay Restoration Fund has been established.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(h)">
      <section prefix="(1)">With regard to the funds collected under subsection (b)(1)(i)1, from users of an onsite sewage disposal system or holding tank that receive a water bill, (i)2, and (i)3 of this section, beginning in fiscal year 2006, the Comptroller shall:<section prefix="(i)">Establish a separate account within the Bay Restoration Fund; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Disburse the funds as provided under paragraph (2) of this subsection.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Comptroller shall:<section prefix="(i)">Deposit 60% of the funds in the separate account to be used for:</section><section prefix="(ii)">Transfer 40% of the funds to the Maryland Agriculture Water Quality Cost Share Program in the Department of Agriculture in order to fund cover crop activities.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Funding for the costs identified in paragraph (2)(i)1 of this subsection shall be provided in the following order of priority:</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">Funding for the costs identified in paragraph (2)(i)1D of this subsection may be provided if:</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">Funding for the costs identified in paragraph (2)(i)1E of this subsection may be provided only if all of the following conditions are met:</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The Comptroller, in consultation with the Administration, may establish any other accounts and subaccounts within the Bay Restoration Fund as necessary to:<section prefix="(i)">Effectuate the purposes of this subtitle;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Comply with the provisions of any bond resolution;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Meet the requirements of any federal or State law or of any grant or award to the Bay Restoration Fund; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">Meet any rules or program directives established by the Secretary or the Board.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(i)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this subsection, "eligible costs" means the additional costs that would be attributable to upgrading a wastewater facility from biological nutrient removal to enhanced nutrient removal, as determined by the Department.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Funds in the Bay Restoration Fund shall be used only:<section prefix="(i)">To award grants for up to 100% of eligible costs of projects relating to planning, design, construction, and upgrade of a wastewater facility for flows up to the design capacity of the wastewater facility, as approved by the Department, to achieve enhanced nutrient removal in accordance with paragraph (3) of this subsection;</section><section prefix="(ii)"/><section prefix="(iii)">As a source of revenue or security for the payment of principal and interest on bonds issued by the Administration if the proceeds of the sale of the bonds will be deposited in the Bay Restoration Fund;</section><section prefix="(iv)">To earn interest on Bay Restoration Fund accounts;</section><section prefix="(v)">For the reasonable costs of administering the Bay Restoration Fund, which may not exceed 1.5% of the total restoration fees imposed on users of wastewater facilities that are collected by the Comptroller annually;</section><section prefix="(vi)">For the reasonable administrative costs incurred by a local government or a billing authority for a water or wastewater facility collecting the restoration fees, in an amount not to exceed 5% of the total restoration fees collected by that local government or billing authority;</section><section prefix="(vii)">For future upgrades of wastewater facilities to achieve additional nutrient removal or water quality improvement, in accordance with paragraphs (6) and (7) of this subsection;</section><section prefix="(viii)">For costs associated with the issuance of bonds; and</section><section prefix="(ix)">Subject to the allocation of funds and the conditions under subsection (h) of this section, for projects related to the removal of nitrogen from onsite sewage disposal systems and cover crop activities.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The grant agreement and State discharge permit, if applicable, shall require an owner of a wastewater facility to operate the enhanced nutrient removal facility in a manner that optimizes the nutrient removal capability of the facility in order to achieve enhanced nutrient removal performance levels.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The grant agreement shall require a grantee to demonstrate, to the satisfaction of the Department, that steps were taken to include small business enterprises, minority business enterprises, and women's business enterprises by:<section prefix="(i)">Placing qualified small business enterprises, minority business enterprises, and women's business enterprises on solicitation lists;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Assuring that small business enterprises, minority business enterprises, and women's business enterprises are solicited whenever they are potential sources;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Dividing total requirements, when economically feasible, into small tasks or quantities to permit maximum participation of small business enterprises, minority business enterprises, and women's business enterprises;</section><section prefix="(iv)">Establishing delivery schedules, where the requirement permits, that encourage participation by small business enterprises, minority business enterprises, and women's business enterprises; and</section><section prefix="(v)">Using the services and assistance of the Maryland Department of Transportation and the Governor's Office of Minority Affairs in identifying and soliciting small business enterprises, minority business enterprises, and women's business enterprises.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(5)">If the steps required under paragraph (4) of this subsection are not demonstrated to the satisfaction of the Department, the Department may withhold financial assistance for the project.</section>
      <section prefix="(6)">
        <section prefix="(i)">All wastewater facilities serving Maryland users that have contributed to the Bay Restoration Fund are eligible for grants under this section, including the Blue Plains Wastewater Treatment Plant in the District of Columbia.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">Grants issued under paragraph (2)(i) of this subsection for upgrades to the Blue Plains Wastewater Treatment Plant may be awarded only if each party to the Blue Plains Intermunicipal Agreement of 1985 contributes a proportional share of the upgrade costs in accordance with the Blue Plains Intermunicipal Agreement of 1985, as revised and updated.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(7)">Priority for funding an upgrade of a wastewater facility shall be given to enhanced nutrient removal upgrades at wastewater facilities with a design capacity of 500,000 gallons or more per day.</section>
      <section prefix="(8)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The eligibility and priority ranking of a project shall be determined by the Department based on criteria established in regulations adopted by the Department, in accordance with subsection (k) of this section.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The criteria adopted by the Department shall include, as appropriate, consideration of:</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(9)">A wastewater facility that has not been offered or has not received funds from the Department under this section or from any other fund in the Department may not be required to upgrade to enhanced nutrient removal levels, except as otherwise required under federal or State law.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(j)">
      <section prefix="(1)">There is a Bay Restoration Fund Advisory Committee.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Committee consists of the following members:<section prefix="(i)">The Secretaries of the Environment, Agriculture, Planning, Natural Resources, and Budget and Management, or their designees;</section><section prefix="(ii)">One member of the Senate, appointed by the President of the Senate;</section><section prefix="(iii)">One member of the House of Delegates, appointed by the Speaker of the House of Delegates;</section><section prefix="(iv)">Two individuals representing publicly owned wastewater facilities, appointed by the Governor;</section><section prefix="(v)">Two individuals representing environmental organizations, appointed by the Governor;</section><section prefix="(vi)">One individual each from the Maryland Association of Counties and the Maryland Municipal League, appointed by the Governor;</section><section prefix="(vii)">Two individuals representing the business community, appointed by the Governor;</section><section prefix="(viii)">Two individuals representing local health departments who have expertise in onsite sewage disposal systems, appointed by the Governor; and</section><section prefix="(ix)">One individual representing a university or research institute who has expertise in nutrient pollution, appointed by the Governor.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Governor shall appoint the chairman of the Committee from the designated members of the Committee.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The Committee may consult with any stakeholder group as it deems necessary.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The term of a member is 4 years.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">A member continues to serve until a successor is appointed.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">The terms of the members appointed by the Governor are staggered as required by the terms provided for members of the Committee on October 1, 2004.</section>
        <section prefix="(iv)">At the end of a term, a member continues to serve until a successor is appointed and qualifies.</section>
        <section prefix="(v)">A member who is appointed after a term has begun serves only for the rest of the term and until a successor is appointed and qualifies.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(6)">The Committee shall:<section prefix="(i)">Perform an analysis of the cost of nutrient removal from wastewater facilities;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Identify additional sources for funding the Bay Restoration Fund;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Make recommendations to improve the effectiveness of the Bay Restoration Fund in reducing nutrient loadings to the waters of the State;</section><section prefix="(iv)">Make recommendations regarding the appropriate increase in the restoration fee to be assessed in fiscal year 2008 and subsequent years as necessary to meet the financing needs of the Bay Restoration Fund;</section><section prefix="(v)">In consultation with the governing body of each county:</section><section prefix="(vi)">Advise the Department on the components of an education, outreach, and upgrade program established within the Department under subsection (h)(2)(i)2 of this section;</section><section prefix="(vii)">Study the availability of money from the Fund for the supplemental assistance program within the Department to provide grants to smaller, economically disadvantaged communities in the State to upgrade their wastewater collection and treatment facilities;</section><section prefix="(viii)">Advise the Secretary concerning the adoption of regulations as described in subsection (k) of this section; and</section><section prefix="(ix)">Beginning January 1, 2006, and every year thereafter, report to the Governor and, subject to &#xA7; 2-1246 of the State Government Article, the General Assembly on its findings and recommendations.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(7)">Members of the Committee:<section prefix="(i)">May not receive compensation; but</section><section prefix="(ii)">Are entitled to reimbursement for expenses under the Standard State Travel Regulations, as provided in the State budget.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(8)">The Department of the Environment, Department of Agriculture, Department of Planning, Department of Natural Resources, and Department of Budget and Management shall provide staff support for the Committee.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(k)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Beginning January 1, 2009, and every year thereafter, the Department and the Department of Planning shall jointly report on the impact that a wastewater treatment facility that was upgraded to enhanced nutrient removal during the calendar year before the previous calendar year with funds from the Bay Restoration Fund had on growth within the municipality or county in which the wastewater treatment facility is located.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">In preparing the report required under paragraph (1) of this subsection, the Department of the Environment and the Department of Planning shall:</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">In determining the information that should be included in the report under subparagraph (i) of this paragraph, the Department of the Environment and the Department of Planning shall act:</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Department and the Department of Planning shall submit the report required under paragraph (1) of this subsection to the President of the Senate, the Speaker of the House, the Senate Budget and Taxation Committee, the Senate Education, Health, and Environmental Affairs Committee, the House Appropriations Committee, the House Environmental Matters Committee, and the Governor, in accordance with &#xA7; 2-1246 of the State Government Article.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(l)">The Department shall adopt regulations that are necessary or appropriate to carry out the provisions of this section.</section>
  </text>
</law>
