<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gen" order_by="" level="1">Environment</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gen-15-313</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>313</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Director may enter into an agreement with an agency responsible for the regulation of coal mining in another state to provide for the recognition in Maryland of mine foreman and fire-boss certificates or other certifications issued by that state if:<section prefix="(1)">The Director determines that the certification requirements of that state are substantially equivalent to the corresponding Maryland requirements; and</section><section prefix="(2)">The other state provides reciprocal recognition of certificates issued by the Bureau.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">An individual who holds a mine foreman certificate, fire-boss certificate, or other certification issued by an agency of another state that has entered into an agreement under subsection (a) of this section may apply to the Bureau for reciprocal certification.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">An applicant for reciprocal certification shall submit to the Bureau:<section prefix="(i)">An application on the form provided by the Bureau;</section><section prefix="(ii)">A copy of the applicant's mine foreman certificate, fire-boss certificate, or other certification issued by the other state; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Any other information that the Bureau requires.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The examining authority:<section prefix="(1)">Shall review an application submitted under subsection (b) of this section;</section><section prefix="(2)">In accordance with the agreement entered into under subsection (a) of this section, may require that the applicant satisfy any additional requirements that the Bureau establishes for reciprocal certification; and</section><section prefix="(3)">If the applicant qualifies for reciprocal certification, may require the applicant to pay a fee to the State comparable to the fee for a certificate issued under other provisions of this subtitle.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">An individual to whom a reciprocal certificate is issued under this section shall promptly notify the Bureau if the state which issued the original mine foreman certificate, fire-boss certificate, or other certification that was a basis for the reciprocal certification suspends, revokes, or takes other disciplinary action against the original certificate.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The holder of a reciprocal certificate is subject to the jurisdiction of the Bureau in the same manner as the holder of:<section prefix="(1)">A mine foreman certificate or fire-boss certificate issued under this subtitle; or</section><section prefix="(2)">Any other certification recognized under this subtitle.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
