<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gen" order_by="gen" level="1">Environment</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gen-7-265</section_number>
  <catch_line>A person who commits any of the following offenses is guilty of a felony and on conviction is subjec...</catch_line>
  <order_by>265</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">A person who commits any of the following offenses is guilty of a felony and on conviction is subject to a fine not exceeding $100,000 or imprisonment not exceeding 5 years, or both:<section prefix="(1)">Storing, treating, dumping, discharging, abandoning, or otherwise disposing of a controlled hazardous substance in any place other than a controlled hazardous substance facility for which a current facility permit is in effect;</section><section prefix="(2)">Transporting for treatment, storage, or disposal a controlled hazardous substance to any place other than a controlled hazardous substance facility for which a current facility permit is in effect;</section><section prefix="(3)">Falsifying any information required by the Department under this subtitle or any rule, regulation, order, hauler certificate, vehicle certificate, or facility permit issued under this subtitle; or</section><section prefix="(4)">Authorizing, directing, or permitting any offense listed in this section.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A person who is convicted of violating the following sections of this subtitle or any regulation adopted under the following sections of this subtitle is guilty of a misdemeanor and on conviction is subject to a fine not exceeding $50,000 or imprisonment for not more than 3 years, or both:<section prefix="(1)">&#xA7; 7-209 of this subtitle;</section><section prefix="(2)">&#xA7; 7-249 of this subtitle; or</section><section prefix="(3)">&#xA7; 7-252 of this subtitle.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Each day on which a violation occurs constitutes a separate offense under this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Any person who knowingly transports, treats, stores, exports, or otherwise disposes of a controlled hazardous substance in a manner that would constitute a violation under subsection (a) of this section and who knows at that time the violation places another person in imminent danger of death or serious bodily injury is guilty of a felony and on conviction is subject to a fine not exceeding $250,000 or imprisonment not exceeding 15 years or both.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">For the purposes of this subsection, in determining whether a person's state of mind is knowing and whether a person knew that the violation or conduct placed another person in imminent danger of death or serious bodily injury, the criteria provided under &#xA7; 3008(f) of the Resource Conservation and Recovery Act (42 U.S.C. &#xA7; 6928(f)) shall apply.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
