<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gen" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="9-234" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gen-9-234</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">When the Department receives an application for a permit to utilize sewage sludge at a site, the Department immediately shall mail a copy of the permit application:<section prefix="(1)">To the legislative body and any elected executive of a county and to the elected executive of any municipal corporation where the sewage sludge utilization site is to be located; and</section><section prefix="(2)">To the legislative body and any elected executive of any other county within 1 mile of the sewage sludge utilization site.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">For a permit to apply sewage sludge on marginal land or to construct a permanent facility that is designed primarily to utilize sewage sludge, the Department shall:<section prefix="(1)">Publish notice of the application in a local newspaper having a substantial circulation in the county where the sewage sludge is to be applied or the facility is to be constructed;</section><section prefix="(2)">Mail a copy of the notice to:<section prefix="(i)">The local health official;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The chairman of the legislative body and any elected executive of the county where the sewage sludge is to be applied or the facility is to be constructed;</section><section prefix="(iii)">The elected executive of any municipal corporation where the sewage sludge is to be applied or the facility is to be constructed; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">Any other county within 1 mile of where the sewage sludge is to be applied or the facility is to be constructed.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as otherwise provided in &#xA7; 9-234.1 of this subtitle, within 15 days after receiving a copy of the permit application, the executive or the legislative body of the county, or the executive or the legislative body of the municipal corporation, where the sewage sludge is to be applied or the facility is to be constructed may request that the Department hold a public hearing.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If the Department receives a request under paragraph (1) of this subsection, the Department shall hold a public hearing in the affected subdivision in accordance with the Administrative Procedure Act.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">If the executives or legislative bodies of more than 1 county or municipal corporation request a hearing under this subsection, the Department may hold a consolidated hearing in 1 county.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">For a permit to apply sewage sludge on land other than marginal land, the Department shall mail a copy of the permit application to:<section prefix="(1)">The local health official;</section><section prefix="(2)">The chairman of the legislative body and any elected executive of the county where the sewage sludge is to be applied; and</section><section prefix="(3)">The elected executive of any municipal corporation where the sewage sludge is to be applied.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Within 10 days after receiving a copy of the permit application, the executive or the legislative body of the county, or the executive or the legislative body of the municipal corporation, where the sewage sludge is to be applied may request that the Department conduct a public information meeting.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If the Department receives a request under paragraph (1) of this subsection, the Department:<section prefix="(i)">Shall conduct a public information meeting in the affected subdivision;</section><section prefix="(ii)">May consolidate the public information meeting with 1 or more public information meetings for other applications in the same county; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Shall notify the applicant for a permit and give the applicant the opportunity to present information at the public information meeting.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">If the executives or legislative bodies of more than 1 county or municipal corporation request a public information meeting under this subsection, the Department may hold a consolidated public information meeting in 1 county.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The Department shall provide each county and municipal corporation that receives a copy of any application under this section with an opportunity to consult with the Department about the decision to issue, deny, or place restrictions on a sewage sludge utilization permit.</section>
  </text>
</law>
