<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gen" order_by="gen" level="1">Environment</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gen-6-811</section_number>
  <catch_line>On or before December 31, 1995, the owner of an affected property shall register the affected proper...</catch_line>
  <order_by>811</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">On or before December 31, 1995, the owner of an affected property shall register the affected property with the Department.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Notwithstanding paragraph (1) of this subsection, an owner of affected property for which an election is made under &#xA7; 6-803(a)(2) of this subtitle shall register at the time of the election.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The owner shall register each affected property using forms prepared by the Department, including the following information:<section prefix="(1)">The name and address of the owner;</section><section prefix="(2)">The address of the affected property;</section><section prefix="(3)">If applicable, the name and address of each property manager employed by the owner to manage the affected property;</section><section prefix="(4)">The name and address of each insurance company providing property insurance or lead hazard coverage for the affected property, together with the policy numbers of that insurance or coverage;</section><section prefix="(5)">The name and address of a resident agent, other agent of the owner, or contact person in the State with respect to the affected property;</section><section prefix="(6)">Whether the affected property was built before 1950 or after 1949;</section><section prefix="(7)">The date of the latest change in occupancy of the affected property;</section><section prefix="(8)">The dates and nature of treatments performed to attain or maintain a risk reduction standard under &#xA7; 6-815 or &#xA7; 6-819 of this subtitle; and</section><section prefix="(9)">The latest date, if any, on which the affected property has been certified to be in compliance with the provisions of &#xA7; 6-815 of this subtitle.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Subject to the provisions of paragraph (2) of this subsection, the information provided by an owner under subsection (b) of this section shall be open to the public.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Except as provided in subparagraph (ii) of this paragraph, the Department may not disclose an inventory or list of properties owned by an owner.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The Department shall, upon request, disclose whether the owner has met the percentage of inventory requirements under &#xA7; 6-817 of this subtitle.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
