<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gen" order_by="" level="1">Environment</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gen-9-101</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>101</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this title the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Discharge" means:<section prefix="(1)">The addition, introduction, leaking, spilling, or emitting of a pollutant into the waters of this State; or</section><section prefix="(2)">The placing of a pollutant in a location where the pollutant is likely to pollute.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Disposal system" means a system for disposing of wastes by surface, above surface, or underground methods.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Disposal system" includes a treatment works and a disposal well.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Effluent limitation" means a restriction or prohibition that:<section prefix="(i)">Is established under federal law or a law of this State; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Specifies quantities, rates, or concentrations of chemical, physical, biological, or other constituents that are discharged into the waters of this State.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Effluent limitation" includes:<section prefix="(i)">Parameters for toxic and nontoxic discharges;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Standards of performance for new sources; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Ocean discharge standards.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"Industrial user" means:<section prefix="(1)">A person who is engaged in manufacturing, fabricating, or assembling goods; or</section><section prefix="(2)">A member of any class of significant producers of pollutants identified under rules or regulations adopted by:<section prefix="(i)">The Secretary; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">The administrator of the United States Environmental Protection Agency.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">"National pollutant discharge elimination system" means the national system for issuing permits as designated by the Federal Water Pollution Control Act.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">"Pollutant" means:<section prefix="(1)">Any waste or wastewater that is discharged from:<section prefix="(i)">A publicly owned treatment works; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">An industrial source; or</section></section><section prefix="(2)">Any other liquid, gaseous, solid, or other substance that will pollute any waters of this State.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(h)">"Pollution" means any contamination or other alteration of the physical, chemical, or biological properties of any waters of this State, including a change in temperature, taste, color, turbidity, or odor of the waters or the discharge or deposit of any organic matter, harmful organism, or liquid, gaseous, solid, radioactive, or other substance into any waters of this State, that will render the waters harmful or detrimental to:<section prefix="(1)">Public health, safety, or welfare;</section><section prefix="(2)">Domestic, commercial, industrial, agricultural, recreational, or other legitimate beneficial uses;</section><section prefix="(3)">Livestock, wild animals, or birds; or</section><section prefix="(4)">Fish or other aquatic life.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(i)">"Publicly owned treatment works" means a facility that is:<section prefix="(1)">Owned by this State or a political subdivision, municipal corporation, or other public entity; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Used for the treatment of pollutants.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(j)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Solid waste" means any garbage, refuse, sludge, or liquid from industrial, commercial, mining, or agricultural operations or from community activities.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Solid waste" includes:<section prefix="(i)">Scrap tires as defined in &#xA7; 9-201 of this title; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Organic material capable of being composted in accordance with Subtitle 17, Part III of this title.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Solid waste" does not include:<section prefix="(i)">Solid or dissolved material in domestic sewage or in irrigation return flows; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">Compost as defined in &#xA7; 9-1701 of this title.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(k)">"Water quality standard" means a water quality standard that is adopted and effective under federal law or a law of this State.</section>
    <section prefix="(l)">"Waters of this State" includes:<section prefix="(1)">Both surface and underground waters within the boundaries of this State subject to its jurisdiction, including that part of the Atlantic Ocean within the boundaries of this State, the Chesapeake Bay and its tributaries, and all ponds, lakes, rivers, streams, public ditches, tax ditches, and public drainage systems within this State, other than those designed and used to collect, convey, or dispose of sanitary sewage; and</section><section prefix="(2)">The flood plain of free-flowing waters determined by the Department of Natural Resources on the basis of the 100-year flood frequency.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
