<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gen" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="9-205" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gen-9-205</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, "authority" means a water, sewerage, or sanitary district authority.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">This section applies only to any water supply system, sewerage system, or refuse disposal system that is for public use in this State.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Any authority or person who owns a water supply system, sewerage system, or refuse disposal system or who supplies or is authorized to supply water, sewerage, or refuse disposal service to the public shall submit to the Secretary:<section prefix="(1)">A certified copy of the complete plans for the water supply system, sewerage system, or refuse disposal system that:<section prefix="(i)">Is correct on the date of submission; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Is of the scope and detail that the Secretary requires; and</section></section><section prefix="(2)">Any existing specifications of or reports on the water supply system, sewerage system, or refuse disposal system.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">If plans do not exist or are of insufficient scope or detail, the authority or person who is required to submit the plans shall:<section prefix="(1)">Prepare and submit to the Secretary new or supplemented plans; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Make any investigation that is necessary to ensure that the new or supplemented plans are correct.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Secretary may request any other information about the water supply system, sewerage system, or refuse disposal system, including information or records on maintenance and operation, that the Secretary considers appropriate.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Any authority or person to whom a request is made under paragraph (1) of this subsection shall submit the information or records to the Secretary.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
