<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gen" order_by="gen" level="1">Environment</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gen-9-206</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this section the following words have the meanings indicated....</catch_line>
  <order_by>206</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Community sewerage system" means a publicly or privately owned sewerage system that serves at least two lots.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Growth tiers" means the tiers adopted by a local jurisdiction in accordance with Title 1, Subtitle 5 of the Land Use Article.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">"Lot" includes a part of a subdivision that:<section prefix="(i)">Is used or is intended to be used as a building site; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Is not intended to be further subdivided.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(5)">"Major subdivision" means:<section prefix="(i)">The subdivision of land:<section prefix="1.">Into new lots, plats, building sites, or other divisions of land defined or described as a major subdivision in a local ordinance or regulation:</section><section prefix="2.">If a local jurisdiction has not adopted a definition or description of a major subdivision on or before December 31, 2012, under item 1 of this item, into five or more new lots, plats, building sites, or other divisions of land; and</section></section><section prefix="(ii)">If the local ordinance or regulation has multiple definitions or descriptions of a major subdivision under item (i) of this paragraph, the definition or description of a major subdivision that is determined by the local jurisdiction to apply for the purposes of this section.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(6)">"Minor subdivision" means:<section prefix="(i)">The subdivision of land:<section prefix="1.">Into new lots, plats, building sites, or other divisions of land defined or described as a minor subdivision in a local ordinance or regulation:</section><section prefix="2.">If a local jurisdiction has not adopted a definition or description of a minor subdivision on or before December 31, 2012, under item 1 of this item, into fewer than five new lots, plats, building sites, or other divisions of land; and</section></section><section prefix="(ii)">If the local ordinance or regulation has multiple definitions or descriptions of a minor subdivision under item (i) of this paragraph, the definition or description of a minor subdivision that is determined by the local jurisdiction to apply for the purposes of this section.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(7)">"On-site sewage disposal" means the disposal of sewage beneath the soil surface.</section>
      <section prefix="(8)">
        <section prefix="(i)">"On-site sewage disposal system" means a sewage treatment unit, collection system, disposal area, and related appurtenances.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">"On-site sewage disposal system" includes a shared facility or community sewerage system that disposes of sewage effluent beneath the soil surface.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(9)">"Public sewer" means a community, shared, or multiuse sewerage system.</section>
      <section prefix="(10)">"Shared facility" means a sewerage system that:<section prefix="(i)">Serves more than one:<section prefix="1.">Lot and is owned in common by the users;</section><section prefix="2.">Condominium unit and is owned in common by the users or by a condominium association;</section><section prefix="3.">User and is located on individual lots owned by the users; or</section><section prefix="4.">User on one lot and is owned in common by the users; or</section></section><section prefix="(ii)">Is located wholly or partly on any of the common elements of a condominium; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">Serves a housing or another multiple ownership cooperative.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(11)">"State agency" means:<section prefix="(i)">The Maryland Agricultural Land Preservation Foundation;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The Maryland Environmental Trust;</section><section prefix="(iii)">The Department of Natural Resources; or</section><section prefix="(iv)">The Maryland-National Capital Park and Planning Commission.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(12)">"Subdivision" means a division of a tract or parcel of land into at least two lots for the immediate or future purpose of sale or building development.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Subsections (f) through (i) and subsection (l) of this section apply to residential subdivisions.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Subsections (f) through (i) do not apply to an application for approval of a residential subdivision under &#xA7; 9-512(e) of this title if:<section prefix="(i)"><section prefix="1.">By October 1, 2012, a submission for preliminary plan approval is made to a local jurisdiction that includes, at a minimum, the preliminary engineering, density, road network, lot layout, and existing features of the proposed site development;</section><section prefix="2.">By July 1, 2012, in a local jurisdiction that requires a soil percolation test before a submission for preliminary approval:</section><section prefix="3.">By July 1, 2012, in a local jurisdiction that requires a soil percolation test before a submission for preliminary approval and the local jurisdiction does not accept applications for soil percolation tests year round:</section></section><section prefix="(ii)">By October 1, 2016, the preliminary plan is approved.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Subsections (f) through (i) and subsection (l) of this section do not apply to covenants, restrictions, conditions, or conservation easements that were created or entered into at any time under &#xA7; 2-118 of the Real Property Article for the benefit of, or held by, a State agency or a local jurisdiction for the purpose of conserving natural resources or agricultural land.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Subsections (f) through (i) of this section may not be construed as granting any additional rights in covenants, restrictions, conditions, or conservation easements that were created or entered into at any time under &#xA7; 2-118 of the Real Property Article for the benefit of, or held by, a State agency or a local jurisdiction for the purpose of conserving natural resources or agricultural land.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Subsections (f) through (i) and subsection (l) of this section do not:<section prefix="(1)">Affect a local transfer of development rights program authorized under Article 25A, &#xA7; 5(x) of the Code or Title 7, Subtitle 2 or &#xA7; 22-105 of the Land Use Article; or</section><section prefix="(2)">Diminish the local development rights transferred in these transfer of development rights programs.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">Subsections (f) through (i) and subsection (l) of this section may not be construed as prohibiting a local jurisdiction from altering the definition or description of a major or minor subdivision in a local ordinance or regulation for local zoning or development purposes.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">On or after December 31, 2012, a local jurisdiction:<section prefix="(1)">May not authorize a residential major subdivision served by on-site sewage disposal systems, community sewerage systems, or shared systems until the local jurisdiction adopts the growth tiers in accordance with &#xA7; 5-104 of the Land Use Article; or</section><section prefix="(2)">If the local jurisdiction has not adopted the growth tiers in accordance with &#xA7; 5-104 of the Land Use Article, may authorize:<section prefix="(i)">A residential minor subdivision served by on-site sewage disposal systems if the residential subdivision otherwise meets the requirements of this title; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">A major or minor subdivision served by public sewer in a Tier I area.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in subsection (f)(2) of this section and subject to subsection (i) of this section, a local jurisdiction may authorize a residential subdivision plat only if:<section prefix="(i)">All lots proposed in an area designated for Tier I growth will be served by public sewer;</section><section prefix="(ii)">All lots proposed in an area designated for Tier II growth:<section prefix="1.">Will be served by public sewer; or</section><section prefix="2.">If the subdivision is a minor subdivision, may be served by on-site sewage disposal systems;</section></section><section prefix="(iii)">Except as provided in subsection (h) of this section, the subdivision is a minor subdivision served by individual on-site sewage disposal systems in a Tier III or Tier IV area; or</section><section prefix="(iv)">The subdivision is a major subdivision served by on-site sewage disposal systems, a community system, or a shared facility located in a Tier III area and has been recommended by the local planning board in accordance with &#xA7; 5-104 of the Land Use Article.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Any delay in the approval of a residential subdivision plat under this subsection may not be construed as applying to any deadline for approving or disapproving a subdivision plat under Division II or &#xA7; 5-201 of the Land Use Article or a local ordinance.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(h)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The limitation of minor subdivisions in subsection (g)(1)(iii) of this section does not apply to a local jurisdiction, if the subdivision and zoning requirements in their cumulative Tier IV areas result in an actual overall yield of not more than one dwelling unit per 20 acres that has been verified by the Department of Planning.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A local jurisdiction may request, in writing, a verification of the actual overall yield from the Department of Planning.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Department of Planning shall verify the actual overall yield after consultation with the Maryland Sustainable Growth Commission, established in &#xA7; 5-702 of the State Finance and Procurement Article.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(i)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If two or more local jurisdictions adopt conflicting growth tier designations for the same area, the Department and the Department of Planning shall confer with the local jurisdictions to seek resolution of the conflicting designations.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If a conflict in growth tier designations is not resolved, the Department of Planning shall recommend to the Department and the Department may approve the preferred local jurisdiction designations as recommended by the Department of Planning based on the following best planning practices or factors:<section prefix="(i)">The comprehensive plan, including the municipal growth element, the water resources element, the land use element, and, if applicable, the priority preservation element;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Growth projections and development capacity; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Availability of infrastructure.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(j)">With respect to land that is platted for subdivision, a person may not offer any of the land for sale or development or erect a permanent building on the land, unless there have been submitted to the Department:<section prefix="(1)">A plat of the subdivision;</section><section prefix="(2)">A statement of the methods, consistent with Subtitle 5 of this title, by which the subdivision is to be supplied with water and sewerage service;</section><section prefix="(3)">Documentation by the local jurisdiction that a major subdivision on-site sewage disposal system, a community sewerage system, or a shared facility is in a:<section prefix="(i)">Tier III area as adopted by the local jurisdiction; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">Tier IV area in a local jurisdiction that is exempt from the limitation of minor subdivisions as provided in subsection (h) of this section; and</section></section><section prefix="(4)">Any other information that the Department requires.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(k)">On the basis of information provided under subsection (j) of this section, the Department may order:<section prefix="(1)">Preparation and submission, within any time the Department sets, of any plans and specifications that the Department considers necessary to provide for adequate water supply and sewerage service to the subdivision; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Installation, within any time the Department sets, of the whole or any part of a water supply system or sewerage system for the subdivision that:<section prefix="(i)">Conforms to the plans submitted to the Department and to any revision of the plans that the Department approves; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">In the judgment of the Department, is needed for the public health.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(l)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This subsection applies to a residential minor subdivision in a Tier II, Tier III, or Tier IV area.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Except as provided in paragraphs (4) and (5) of this subsection, on or after December 31, 2012, if a tract or parcel of land is subdivided into a residential minor subdivision leaving any remainder parcel or tract of land:<section prefix="(i)">The residential minor subdivision may not be resubdivided or further subdivided; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">The remainder parcel or tract of land may not be subdivided.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Except as provided in paragraphs (4) and (5) of this subsection, on or after December 31, 2012, the subdivision plat of the residential minor subdivision shall state that:<section prefix="(i)">The residential minor subdivision may not be resubdivided or further subdivided;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The remainder parcel or tract of land may not be subdivided; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">The subdivision plat is subject to State law and local ordinances and regulations.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">On or after December 31, 2012, if a tract or parcel of land is subdivided into a residential minor subdivision, the residential minor subdivision or the remainder parcel or tract of land may be resubdivided or further subdivided if the subdivision or the remainder parcel or tract of land is:<section prefix="(i)">Within a priority funding area as defined in Title 5, Subtitle 7B of the State Finance and Procurement Article; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Designated for public sewerage service within 10 years in the approved water and sewer plan.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(5)">
        <section prefix="(i)">A tract or parcel of land may be subdivided into a residential minor subdivision in Tier II, Tier III, or Tier IV areas over time if each time a new lot or parcel is created, the subdivision plat states the number of new lots, plats, building sites, or other divisions of land that are left with the number of lots, plats, building sites, or other divisions of land allowed as a subdivision.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">Except as provided in paragraph (iii) of this paragraph, when the tract or parcel of land that is subdivided over time reaches the total number of lots, plats, building sites, or other divisions of land that are allowed as a residential minor subdivision, the subdivision plat shall state that:<section prefix="1.">The residential minor subdivision may not be resubdivided or further subdivided;</section><section prefix="2.">The remainder parcel or tract of land may not be subdivided; and</section><section prefix="3.">The subdivision plat is subject to State law and local ordinances and regulations.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">A remainder parcel or tract of land may be subdivided for nonresidential agricultural purposes, including a farm market, agricultural processing facility, or creamery, and the owner may apply for approval of an on-site sewage disposal system to serve the nonresidential agricultural purposes.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(m)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this subsection, "agricultural activities" includes:<section prefix="(i)">Plowing, tillage, cropping, seeding, cultivating, and harvesting for the production of food and fiber products; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">The grazing of livestock.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A local jurisdiction may enact a local law or ordinance for the transfer of the right to subdivide, up to 7 lots, by an owner of property used for agricultural activities to the owner of another property used for agricultural activities in accordance with this subsection.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The local law or ordinance shall provide for the recordation of any rights to subdivide that are transferred under this subsection.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">A property used for agricultural activities the owner of which receives rights to subdivide under this subsection:<section prefix="(i)">Is limited to a total of 15 lots; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Shall cluster the lots on the property.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(5)">Rights to subdivide may not be transferred from the owner of property used for agricultural activities in a Tier III area to the owner of property used for agricultural activities in a Tier IV area.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
