<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gen" order_by="" level="1">Environment</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gen-6-820</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>820</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Except as provided in subsection (b) of this section, an owner of an affected property shall give to the tenant of the affected property a notice, prepared by the Department, of the tenant's rights under &#xA7;&#xA7; 6-817 and 6-819 of this subtitle, according to the following schedule:<section prefix="(1)">At least 25% of the owner's affected properties by May 25, 1996;</section><section prefix="(2)">At least 50% of the owner's affected properties by August 25, 1996;</section><section prefix="(3)">At least 75% of the owner's affected properties by November 25, 1996; and</section><section prefix="(4)">100% of the owner's affected properties by February 25, 1997.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">On or after February 24, 1996, an owner of an affected property shall give to the tenant of the affected property a notice, prepared by the Department, of the tenant's rights under &#xA7;&#xA7; 6-817 and 6-819 of this subtitle upon the execution of a lease or the inception of a tenancy.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">An owner of an affected property shall give to the tenant of the affected property a notice, prepared by the Department, of the tenant's rights under &#xA7;&#xA7; 6-817 and 6-819 of this subtitle at least every 2 years after last giving the notice to the tenant.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The owner shall include, with the notice of the tenant's rights that is provided to a tenant under this section upon the execution of a lease or the inception of a tenancy, a copy of the current verified inspection certificate for the affected property prepared under &#xA7; 6-818 of this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Notice given under this section shall be written, and shall be sent by:<section prefix="(i)">Certified mail, return receipt requested; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">A verifiable method approved by the Department.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">When giving notice to a tenant under this section, the owner shall provide documentation of the notice to the Department in a manner acceptable to the Department.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A notice required to be given to a tenant under this section shall be sent to a party or parties identified as the lessee in a written lease in effect for an affected property or, if there is no written lease, the party or parties to whom the property was rented.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">A person who has acquired, or will acquire, an affected property shall give the notice required under this section to the tenant of the affected property:<section prefix="(1)">Before transfer of legal title; or</section><section prefix="(2)">Within 15 days following transfer of legal title.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
