<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gen" order_by="gen" level="1">Environment</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gen-9-1110</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this section the following words have the meanings indicated....</catch_line>
  <order_by>1110</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Community sewerage system" means a publicly or privately owned sewerage system that serves at least two lots.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Controlling authority" means a unit of government, a body public and corporate, or an intercounty agency authorized by the State, a county, or a municipal corporation to provide for the management, operation, and maintenance of a community sewerage system, shared facility, or multiuse sewerage system.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">"Shared facility" means a sewerage system that:<section prefix="(i)">Serves more than one:<section prefix="1.">Lot and is owned in common by the users;</section><section prefix="2.">Condominium unit and is owned in common by the users or by a condominium association;</section><section prefix="3.">User and is located on individual lots owned by the users; or</section><section prefix="4.">User on one lot and is owned in common by the users;</section></section><section prefix="(ii)">Is located wholly or partly on any of the common elements of a condominium; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">Serves a housing cooperative or other multiple ownership cooperative.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">This section may not be construed as requiring a local jurisdiction to:<section prefix="(1)">Be a controlling authority; or</section><section prefix="(2)">Authorize or allow the use of a shared facility or a community sewerage system within the local jurisdiction.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A shared facility or community sewerage system may be approved only if the system:<section prefix="(1)">Is managed, operated, and maintained by:<section prefix="(i)">A controlling authority; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">A third party under contract with the controlling authority; and</section></section><section prefix="(2)">Discharges:<section prefix="(i)">To the surface waters of the State in accordance with a permit issued under &#xA7; 9-323 of this title;</section><section prefix="(ii)">By way of land application under a nutrient management plan required under &#xA7; 8-803.1 of the Agriculture Article that assures 100% of the nitrogen and phosphorus in the applied effluent will be taken up by vegetation; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">By way of an on-site sewerage system.</section></section></section>
  </text>
</law>
