<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gen" order_by="" level="1">Environment</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gen-2-609.1</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>609.1</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, "approval" means approval for prevention of significant deterioration or approval of new sources in nonattainment areas.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">A person may not knowingly act or fail to act in violation of a condition or requirement imposed on the person by a permit or approval issued under this title.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">A person may not knowingly fail to obtain a permit or approval that the person knows or should have known is required under this title.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">A person may not violate a duty imposed on the person by a rule, regulation, order, or approved plan for compliance adopted or issued under this title with knowledge that the person's conduct constitutes a violation of the duty.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A person who violates a provision of this subsection is guilty of a misdemeanor and on conviction is subject to:<section prefix="(i)">For a first offense, a fine not exceeding $25,000 or imprisonment not exceeding 1 year or both; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">For a violation committed after a first conviction under this section, a fine not exceeding $50,000 or imprisonment not exceeding 2 years or both.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Each day on which violations occur is a separate violation under this subsection.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">This subsection does not apply to violations enumerated in subsection (c) of this section.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A person is guilty of a misdemeanor and on conviction is subject to a fine not exceeding $10,000 for each day of violation or imprisonment not exceeding 6 months or both if the person:<section prefix="(1)">Knowingly makes any false statement, representation, or certification in any application, record, report, plan, or other document filed or required to be maintained under this title or any rule, regulation, order, approved plan for compliance, approval, or permit adopted or issued under this title; or</section><section prefix="(2)">Knowingly falsifies, tampers with, or renders inaccurate any monitoring device or methods required to be maintained under this title or any rule, regulation, order, approved plan for compliance, approval, or permit adopted or issued under this title.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
