<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gen" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="14-111" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gen-14-111</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Every holder of a permit to drill for gas or oil shall:<section prefix="(1)">Submit a completion report on forms to be supplied by the Department within 30 days after the drilling of a well has been completed;</section><section prefix="(2)">Submit cutting samples at the request of the Department;</section><section prefix="(3)">Notify the Department when a well is about to be abandoned;</section><section prefix="(4)">Seal and plug the well in a manner approved by the Department;</section><section prefix="(5)">Post a performance bond to the State in the amount not to exceed $100,000 for each oil or gas well, and not to exceed $500,000 as a blanket bond for all of the permit holder's oil or gas wells, with good and sufficient surety, as provided in subsection (d)(1) of this section, conditioned upon compliance with the provisions of this subtitle;</section><section prefix="(6)">Obtain and keep in effect liability insurance coverage in an amount not less than $300,000 for each person and $500,000 for each occurrence or accident to pay damages for injury to persons or damage to property caused by the drilling, production operations, or plugging of all of the permit holder's gas or oil wells in the State; and</section><section prefix="(7)">Notify the Department of the location of the equipment required by regulation for the prevention and containment of gas leaks and oil spills.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Department may adopt regulations to increase the minimum amounts of liability insurance coverage under subsection (a)(6) of this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Department shall adopt regulations requiring each holder of a permit to drill for gas or oil to have equipment available for the prevention and containment of gas leaks and oil spills.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A holder of a permit to drill for gas or oil may:<section prefix="(1)">Post the performance bond under subsection (a)(5) of this section in:<section prefix="(i)">Cash;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Certificates of deposit;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Letters of credit from any bank or other savings institution; or</section><section prefix="(iv)">Any other good and sufficient security; and</section></section><section prefix="(2)">Provide for the holder's own liability insurance under subsection (a)(6) of this section.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
