<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gen" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="1-607" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gen-1-607</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This subsection applies to applications for all licenses and permits issued, or required to be reissued, by the Department.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">On or before January 1, 1998, and each year thereafter, in consultation with interested parties, the Department shall publish expected review times for each licensing and permitting program.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">On or before January 1, 1998, for each licensing and permitting program, the Department shall offer assistance and information to persons which may include:<section prefix="(i)">Written lists of information and materials required with applications;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Written lists of common application questions and mistakes;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Preapplication meetings with prospective applicants to address technical issues;</section><section prefix="(iv)">Written receipts to the applicant upon submission of an application; and</section><section prefix="(v)">The status of active applications.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This subsection applies to permits which are:<section prefix="(i)">Identified in &#xA7; 1-601(a) of this subtitle; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">Issued under Title 5, Subtitle 9 of this article.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Department shall provide to the applicant:<section prefix="(i)">A notice of completed application; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">If the Department determines that the application is incomplete, the reasons, in writing, that the application was determined to be incomplete.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">For permits identified in &#xA7; 1-601(a) of this subtitle, the notice of completed application shall include an estimated time for issuance of the tentative determination if requested by the applicant.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">For permits issued under Title 5, Subtitle 9 of this article, the notice of completed application shall include an estimate of the date by which the Department will grant, deny, or condition the permit.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(4)">A permit applicant may apply to the Department for a refund of all or a portion of the application fee if:<section prefix="(i)"/><section prefix="(ii)">The applicant demonstrates that the delay was caused solely by the Department and was not the result of procedures or requirements outside the control of the Department, including:</section><section prefix="(iii)"/></section>
      <section prefix="(5)">The Secretary, or the Secretary's designee, shall review the refund request and determine if a refund of any amount is appropriate.</section>
      <section prefix="(6)">If the Secretary denies the refund request, the Department shall provide the applicant a written explanation of the denial and of the procedures and requirements outside the control of the Department on which the denial was based within 60 days.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
