<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gen" order_by="" level="1">Environment</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gen-9-201</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>201</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"First sale" means a sale of a new tire that is not a sale to a wholesaler or out-of-state retailer.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Local health official" means:<section prefix="(1)">A health officer or a designee of the health officer; or</section><section prefix="(2)">The Director of the Department of Environmental Protection of Montgomery County or a designee of the Director.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">"Person" includes the federal government, a state, county, municipal corporation, or other political subdivision.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"Refuse disposal system" includes:<section prefix="(1)">An incinerator;</section><section prefix="(2)">A transfer station;</section><section prefix="(3)">A landfill system;</section><section prefix="(4)">A landfill;</section><section prefix="(5)">A solid waste processing facility; and</section><section prefix="(6)">Any other solid waste acceptance facility.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">"Scrap tire" means any tire that no longer is suitable for its original intended purpose by virtue of wear, damage, or defect.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">"Scrap tire collection facility" means a place where scrap tires are:<section prefix="(1)">Deposited by a consumer or a scrap tire hauler; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Transferred to another scrap tire collection facility or scrap tire recycler.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(h)">"Scrap tire hauler" means a person who as part of a commercial business:<section prefix="(1)">Transports scrap tires; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Is approved and licensed by the Department to transport scrap tires to a scrap tire recycler or a scrap tire collection facility.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(i)">"Scrap tire recycler" means a person who is approved and licensed by the Department to process scrap tires to a form of raw materials or products that may be returned to the marketplace.</section>
    <section prefix="(j)">"Service" means the Maryland Environmental Service.</section>
    <section prefix="(k)">"Sewage" means:<section prefix="(1)">Any human or animal excretion or water-carried domestic waste; or</section><section prefix="(2)">A mixture of industrial waste and any of the things in item (1) of this subsection.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(l)">"Sewage sludge" means any thickened liquid, suspension, settled solid, or dried residue that a sewage treatment plant extracts from sewage.</section>
    <section prefix="(m)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Sewage sludge generator" means a person who owns or operates a facility that receives and processes sewage in this State or produces sewage sludge to be utilized in this State.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Sewage sludge generator" includes:<section prefix="(i)">The Washington Suburban Sanitary Commission; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">The Maryland Environmental Service.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Sewage sludge generator" does not include the owner or operator of a septic system.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(n)">"Sewage sludge utilization permit" means a permit, issued by the Department, to utilize sewage sludge.</section>
    <section prefix="(o)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Sewage sludge utilizer" means a person who utilizes sewage sludge in this State.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Sewage sludge utilizer" includes:<section prefix="(i)">The Washington Suburban Sanitary Commission; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">The Maryland Environmental Service.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(p)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Sewerage system" means:<section prefix="(i)">The channels used or intended to be used to collect and dispose of sewage; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Any structure or appurtenance used or intended to be used to collect or prepare sewage for discharge into the waters of this State.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Sewerage system" includes any sewer of any size.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Sewerage system" does not include the plumbing system inside any building served by the sewerage system.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(q)">"Store scrap tires" means the accumulation of scrap tires in any form or configuration in excess of 15,000 cubic feet.</section>
    <section prefix="(r)">"Tire dealer" means a person who sells new tires to:<section prefix="(1)">A seller of tires in the State that is not a tire wholesaler; or</section><section prefix="(2)">A consumer of a tire on which a recycling fee has not been paid.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(s)">"Tire wholesaler" means a person who transfers tires to a person who is not a consumer.</section>
    <section prefix="(t)">"Utilize sewage sludge" means to collect, handle, burn, store, treat, or transport sewage sludge to or from a sewage sludge generator or utilizer in this State, to apply it to land, or to dispose of it.</section>
    <section prefix="(u)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Water supply system" means:<section prefix="(i)">A source and the surrounding area from which water is supplied for drinking or domestic purposes; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Any structure, channel, or appurtenance used to prepare water for use or to deliver water to a consumer.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Water supply system" does not include the plumbing system inside any building that is served by the water supply system.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
