<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gen" order_by="gen" level="1">Environment</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gen-2-404.1</section_number>
  <catch_line>Except for an applicant who elects to proceed under subsection (d) of this section, a final decision...</catch_line>
  <order_by>404.1</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Except for an applicant who elects to proceed under subsection (d) of this section, a final decision by the Department on the issuance, renewal, or revision of an operating permit issued pursuant to Title V of the federal Clean Air Act Amendments of 1990 is subject to judicial review by any person who:<section prefix="(1)">Meets the threshold standing requirements under federal constitutional law; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Participated in a public participation process through the submission of written or oral comments, unless an opportunity for public participation was not required by statute or regulation.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Judicial review shall be on the administrative record before the Department and limited to objections raised during the public comment period, unless the petitioner demonstrates:<section prefix="(1)">That the objections were not reasonably ascertainable during the comment period; or</section><section prefix="(2)">That grounds for the objections arose after the comment period.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Unless otherwise required by statute, a petition for judicial review by a person who meets the requirements of subsection (a) of this section shall be filed with the circuit court for the county in which any party resides or has a principal place of business.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">An applicant for an air quality operating permit may seek judicial review in accordance with Title 10, Subtitle 2 of the State Government Article.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Except for an applicant as described in paragraph (1) of this subsection, a person is not entitled to a contested case hearing regarding Title V operating permits.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
