<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gen" order_by="gen" level="1">Environment</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gen-9-949</section_number>
  <catch_line>An authority has a lien on real estate:...</catch_line>
  <order_by>949</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">An authority has a lien on real estate:<section prefix="(1)">For:<section prefix="(i)">The amount of any fee, rent, or charge, including a tapping fee, imposed on an owner, tenant, or occupant of the real estate for the use and services of a project of the authority; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Any accrued interest on the fee, rent, or charge; and</section></section><section prefix="(2)">From the time when the fee, rent, or charge is due and payable.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A lien under this section is superior to any interest of an owner, tenant, or occupant of the affected real estate.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A lien under this section binds or affects a subsequent bona fide purchaser of the real estate who purchases for valuable consideration and without actual notice of the lien only after the amount of the lien is entered in a lien register that is:<section prefix="(1)">Furnished for this purpose by and at the expense of the authority; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Kept among the land records of the county where the real estate is located.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The clerk of the circuit court in the county where the real estate is located:<section prefix="(i)">Shall keep and make available for public inspection any lien register that an authority provides to the clerk under this section;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Shall record and index in the lien register any entry that the authority certifies; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Is entitled to a fee of 5 cents for each entry that the clerk makes under this section.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">To record a lien under this section, an authority shall pay to the clerk of the circuit court a fee of 5 cents for each entry.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The amount of the fee paid for recording a lien shall be added to the amount of the lien.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">To discharge a lien under this section, a person shall pay to the authority:<section prefix="(i)">The total amount of the lien; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Any interest that has accrued on the lien to the date of payment.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">When a person discharges a lien under this subsection, the authority shall deliver to the person a certificate of payment.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">When a person presents a certificate of payment to the clerk of the circuit court in the county where the real estate is located, the clerk, without any fee, shall record the discharge of the lien in the lien register.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
