<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gen" order_by="" level="1">Environment</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gen-7-406</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>406</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Each application for a certificate submitted to the Board shall contain a report with information of the type, quality, and detail that will permit adequate consideration of the environmental, social, technical, and economic factors involved in the establishment and operation of the proposed facilities. The applicant shall make the report available to affected subdivisions and to the public.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">On receipt of the application for a certificate the Board shall forward a copy of that application to the Department. The Department shall consider the application for a certificate as an application for the facility permit that is required under this article.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">On receipt of any application for a facility permit that is required under this article, the Department shall forward a copy of the facility permit application to the Board.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The portion of the applicant's report dealing with environmental and social assessments shall contain, but not be limited to:<section prefix="(i)">The potential impact of the method and route of transportation of hazardous or low-level nuclear waste to the site and the potential impact of the establishment and operation of the proposed facility on air and water quality, existing land use, transportation, and natural resources in the area affected by proposed facilities;</section><section prefix="(ii)">A description of the expected effect of the facility; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Recommendations for minimizing any adverse impact.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The portion of the applicant's report dealing with technical and economic assessments shall contain, but not be limited to:<section prefix="(i)">Detailed descriptions of the proposed site and facility, including site location and boundaries and facility purpose, type, size, capacity, and location on the site and estimates of the cost and charges to be made for material accepted; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Provisions for managing the site following cessation of operation of the facility.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Acceptance by the Board of any application for processing does not preclude the Board from requiring further information from the applicant if the Board considers the additional information necessary for adequate consideration of the application.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Board shall adopt regulations describing and governing the procedure for obtaining a certificate, including procedures under paragraph (2) of this subsection. The provisions of this section do not exempt the Board from the requirements of Title 10, Subtitles 1 and 2 of the State Government Article.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Procedural regulations adopted under this subsection shall:<section prefix="(i)">Provide for notice to interested persons of any decision to issue or deny a certificate;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Permit a person to request a hearing under Title 10, Subtitle 2 of the State Government Article (Administrative Procedure Act - Contested Cases), if the person makes factual allegations with sufficient particularity to demonstrate that:<section prefix="1.">The person is aggrieved by the decision; and</section><section prefix="2.">The decision is:</section></section><section prefix="(iii)">Provide the Board with discretionary authority to stay the effectiveness of its decision pending the outcome of the hearing; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">Provide that, if a request for a hearing is granted, the Board's final decision on the application shall be based on the record made in the hearing, including the proposed findings of fact and conclusions of law recommended to the Board by the presiding officer.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">At least 90 days prior to issuance of a certificate, the Board shall seek the advice and comment of the following:<section prefix="(i)">The Secretaries of Natural Resources, the Environment, Business and Economic Development, and Agriculture;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The Director of Planning;</section><section prefix="(iii)">The Controlled Hazardous Substances Advisory Council; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">The governing body of any subdivision of the State within which all or part of the proposed site is to be located and the governing bodies of adjoining subdivisions.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">At least 90 days prior to the issuance of a certificate, the Board shall seek the comments of:<section prefix="(i)">Each landowner of record whose property is within 1,000 feet of the proposed site; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Residents who live within 1 mile of the proposed site.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Within 30 days after the Board seeks the advice of a party listed under paragraph (1) of this subsection, the party shall respond to the Board in writing by either:<section prefix="(i)">Setting forth the advice and comments of the party as to the proposed certification; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">Stating that the party has no comments as to the proposed certification.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Before it may issue a certificate, the Board shall hold an informational meeting in the subdivision in which the proposed site is to be located for the purpose of receiving advice and comments from the public.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The informational meeting shall be held at least 60 days prior to the issuance of a certificate.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">If a site is located in more than one subdivision, the informational meeting shall be held at a location reasonably convenient and accessible to the affected jurisdictions.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The informational meeting may not be held until the application is complete.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(h)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Board shall make a decision to issue or deny a certificate within 6 months of receipt of an application and any additional information required under this section, and shall advise the governing body of a subdivision in writing of any rejection of a site that it recommended and of the reasons for the rejection.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">With the concurrence of the applicant, the Board may extend this period for no more than an additional 6 months.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(i)">The Board shall set by rule and regulation a reasonable schedule of fees necessary to recover the costs of processing applications and issuing certificates under this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(j)">On issuance of a certificate the Board shall file a copy of that certificate with the Secretary to the Board and the Secretary of State. Copies of the certificate shall be sent by the Secretary to the Board to:<section prefix="(1)">The governing body of any political subdivision of the State within which all or part of the proposed site is to be located and the governing bodies of adjoining subdivisions;</section><section prefix="(2)">The record owner(s) of the site and the record owners of adjoining property;</section><section prefix="(3)">The applicant, if different from the record owner;</section><section prefix="(4)">The Department;</section><section prefix="(5)">The Department of Natural Resources;</section><section prefix="(6)">The Department of Agriculture;</section><section prefix="(7)">The Department of Labor, Licensing, and Regulation; and</section><section prefix="(8)">The Department of Planning.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(k)">The Board shall maintain records of its transactions including the applications and supporting data submitted by those seeking certificates from the Board and any other technical data considered in issuing or denying a certificate. These records are public records for the purposes of Part III of Title 10, Subtitle 6 of the State Government Article.</section>
    <section prefix="(l)">The Board shall consider, review, and approve or deny hazardous or low-level nuclear waste sites applied for by the Maryland Environmental Service in the same manner in which it acts upon applications for issuance of certificates from other parties.</section>
  </text>
</law>
