<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gen" order_by="" level="1">Environment</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gen-9-661</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>661</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">During construction of a water line or a sewer line, the sanitary commission, at its own expense, shall construct a connector to the property line of each parcel that abuts the way in which the water line or sewer line is laid.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">However, the Sanitary Commission of Worcester County may determine not to construct a connector to any parcel that lacks a plumbing system at the time of construction of the line. At a time and in a manner that it determines to be appropriate, the Sanitary Commission of Worcester County shall construct or permit the construction of a connector to any parcel:<section prefix="(i)">Whose owner requests the connection subsequent to the construction of the water line or sewer line; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">That abuts the way in which the line is laid.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">When construction on the water line or sewer line is complete, the sanitary commission shall notify each abutting property owner of the completion.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">On receipt of the notice of completion, and by a time set by the sanitary commission, each owner of abutting property shall:<section prefix="(1)">Pay the connection charge determined under this section; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Make appropriate connections of the plumbing system on the property to the connector constructed by the sanitary commission.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Any plumbing system of each parcel of abutting property that is to be served shall include at least:<section prefix="(1)">1 toilet that the sanitary commission approves; and</section><section prefix="(2)">1 washbasin that the sanitary commission approves.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">When the plumbing system of the property has been connected to the connector constructed by the sanitary commission, the owner of the property shall disconnect, as appropriate, each cesspool, sink drain, and privy on the property so that the disconnected component is:<section prefix="(1)">Closed;</section><section prefix="(2)">Abandoned; and</section><section prefix="(3)">In a sanitary condition so that no odor or nuisance can arise from it.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except for the Sanitary Commission of Worcester County, a sanitary commission shall determine a connection charge that is:<section prefix="(i)">At least equal to the actual cost to the district of constructing the connector;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Based on the length of the connector and width of the way in which the water pipe or sewer pipe is laid; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">The same on each side of the way.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Sanitary Commission of Worcester County shall determine connection charges as provided under &#xA7; 9-656(b)(2)(ii) of this subtitle.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except for the Sanitary Commission of Worcester County, if the connection charges collected under this section are more than the cost of the connections made, a sanitary commission shall:<section prefix="(i)">Keep the excess revenues in a special fund; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Use the fund only for repairs, replacement, and extraordinary expenses of the water system or sewer system.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">In Worcester County, if the connection charges are more than the cost of the connections made, the Sanitary Commission shall:<section prefix="(i)">Keep the excess revenues in a special fund;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Use the fund for repairs, replacement, and extraordinary expenses of the water system or sewer system; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">Use the fund for any other purpose relating to the operation of the service area to which the fund relates.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
