<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gen" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="1-604" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gen-1-604</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">After the Department receives the permit application, the Department shall prepare a tentative determination, which shall include the following information:<section prefix="(i)">A proposal to issue or to not issue a permit;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Any proposed permit limitations and conditions;</section><section prefix="(iii)">A brief explanation of the Department's tentative determination; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">Any proposed schedule of compliance.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If the tentative determination is to issue a permit, the tentative determination shall include a draft permit, which shall be available to the public for inspection and copying.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Department shall publish a notice of the tentative determination. This publication shall allow 30 calendar days for public comment before the issuance of the final determination.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The Department shall schedule a public hearing on the tentative determination when a written request for a public hearing is made within 20 days of publication of a notice of the tentative determination.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The public hearing may be canceled if all persons who made timely written requests withdraw the requests prior to the meeting. In addition, the Department may schedule a public hearing on a tentative determination at its discretion.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Department shall prepare a final determination if:<section prefix="(i)">Written comments adverse to the tentative determination were received by the Department within 30 days after the publication of the notice of tentative determination pursuant to this section;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Comments adverse to the tentative determination were received in writing at, or within 5 days after, the public hearing conducted pursuant to this section;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Comments adverse to the tentative determination were received orally at the public hearing conducted pursuant to this section and the Department prepared a transcript of the comments made at the hearing; or</section><section prefix="(iv)">The final determination is substantively different from the tentative determination and all persons aggrieved by the final determination have not waived, in writing, their right to request a contested case hearing.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If the Department is required to prepare a final determination under this section, the Department shall publish a notice of the final determination.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">If the Department is not required to prepare a final determination under this section, the tentative determination is a final decision by the Department when the permit is issued or denied.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
