<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gen" order_by="gen" level="1">Environment</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gen-9-270</section_number>
  <catch_line>If, by violating any applicable statute, regulation, or permit condition, a sewage treatment plant t...</catch_line>
  <order_by>270</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">If, by violating any applicable statute, regulation, or permit condition, a sewage treatment plant that has a design capacity of 1,000,000 gallons or more per day creates a nuisance or otherwise may affect adversely public health or the environment, the person who owns or operates the sewage treatment plant is liable to the State for an administrative civil penalty not exceeding $10,000 a day.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The penalty imposed under this section shall be assessed with consideration given to:<section prefix="(1)">The extent to which the existence of the violation was known to the violator but uncorrected by the violator and the extent to which the violator exercised reasonable care;</section><section prefix="(2)">Any actual or potential harm to human health or to the environment, including injury to or impairment of the natural resources of the State;</section><section prefix="(3)">The degree of interference with general welfare, health, or property rights of the public;</section><section prefix="(4)">The extent to which the location of the violation creates the potential for harm to the environment or to human health or safety;</section><section prefix="(5)">The available technology for controlling, reducing, or eliminating the emissions that caused the violation; and</section><section prefix="(6)">The extent to which the current violation is part of a recurrent pattern of the same or similar type of violation committed by the violator.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Each day a violation continues is a separate violation under this section.</section>
  </text>
</law>
