<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gen" order_by="" level="1">Environment</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gen-9-1901</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>1901</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Distributor" means any person that:<section prefix="(1)">Sells a packaged product to a retailer; or</section><section prefix="(2)">Receives a shipment or consignment of, or in any other manner acquires, packaged products for distribution to a retailer for:<section prefix="(i)">Sale to a consumer; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">Promotional purposes.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Manufacturer" means any person that manufactures a package or packaging component.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Manufacturer" includes any person that sells a package or packaging component to a distributor.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Package" means a container used to market, protect, or handle a product.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Package" includes:<section prefix="(i)">A unit package, an intermediate package, and a shipping container as defined by the American Society for Testing and Materials; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">An unsealed receptacle such as a carrying case, crate, cup, pail, rigid foil or other tray, wrap, wrapping film, bag, and tub.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Packaging component" means any individual assembled part of a package.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Packaging component" includes any interior or exterior blocking, bracing, cushioning, weatherproofing, coating, closure, label, ink, dye, pigment, adhesive, or any other additive.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Packaging component" does not include any package or packaging component that contains cadmium and is intended for reuse more than 5 times.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
