<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gen" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="9-283" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gen-9-283</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Except as provided in subsection (c) of this section, by regulation, the Department shall establish and collect a fee to be paid by a generator of coal combustion by-products, based on a per ton rate of coal combustion by-products generated by the generator annually.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Department shall base the fees on the following factors:<section prefix="(1)">The total annual tonnage of coal combustion by-products that the generator generates;</section><section prefix="(2)">The type and volume of coal combustion by-products generated by the generator;</section><section prefix="(3)">Whether the generator uses or disposes of the coal combustion by-products;</section><section prefix="(4)">To the extent that the coal combustion by-products are used rather than disposed of, the types of the uses;</section><section prefix="(5)">Whether the coal combustion by-products are transported for use or disposal out-of-state; and</section><section prefix="(6)">Other factors the Department considers appropriate.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Department may not establish or impose a fee on coal combustion by-products that are:<section prefix="(1)">Beneficially used, as the Department determines; or</section><section prefix="(2)">Used for coal mine reclamation in accordance with regulations the Department adopts or with regulations of the receiving state.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Fees imposed on coal combustion by-products that are transported for use or disposal out-of-state may not exceed 50% of the fees established for disposal in-State.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The fees collected by the Department under this section shall be deposited into the Fund and used in accordance with &#xA7; 9-284 of this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The fees imposed shall be set at the rate necessary to implement the purposes set forth in &#xA7; 9-284 of this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">In any fiscal year, if the fee schedule established by the Department generates revenue that exceeds the amount necessary to operate a regulatory program to control the management of coal combustion by-products, the Department shall reduce the fees in the following fiscal year.</section>
  </text>
</law>
