<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gen" order_by="" level="1">Environment</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gen-13-101</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>101</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this title the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Board" means the State Board of Well Drillers.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Geotechnical" refers to that category of well driller license which authorizes the practice of well drilling limited to wells constructed for the purpose of sampling, measuring, or test pumping for scientific, engineering, or regulatory purposes, including wells constructed specifically for the removal of contaminants from an aquifer, but not including water supply test wells.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"License" means, unless the context requires otherwise, any license issued by the Board under this title to practice well drilling.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"License" includes, unless otherwise indicated:<section prefix="(i)">A well driller license; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">A restricted license.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"Person" means:<section prefix="(1)">The federal government, this State, any county, municipal corporation, or other political subdivision of this State, or any of their units;</section><section prefix="(2)">Any individual, receiver, trustee, guardian, personal representative, fiduciary, or representative of any kind; and</section><section prefix="(3)">Any partnership, firm, association, corporation, or other entity.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">"Practice well drilling" includes engaging in any of the following activities for profit:<section prefix="(1)">Making, altering, repairing, or sealing a well; or</section><section prefix="(2)">Installing, altering, repairing, or disconnecting well system equipment.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(g)">"Restricted license" means any license issued by the Board that authorizes its holder to engage in some, but not all, of the activities which constitute the practice of well drilling.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">"Water supply" refers to that category of well driller license which authorizes the practice of well drilling limited to wells constructed for the purpose of obtaining a water supply, including wells constructed for the purpose of installing a heat pump.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">"Well" means any hole made in the ground:<section prefix="(1)">To explore for groundwater;</section><section prefix="(2)">To obtain or monitor groundwater;</section><section prefix="(3)">To inject water into any underground formation from which groundwater may be produced; or</section><section prefix="(4)">To transfer heat to or from the ground or groundwater, if the hole:<section prefix="(i)">Extends more than 20 feet below the surface of the ground; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Is not a well for obtaining geothermal resources under &#xA7; 5-601 of this article.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(j)">"Well driller license" means any license issued by the Board to engage in all activities that constitute the practice of well drilling, including all activities permitted under any restricted license.</section>
    <section prefix="(k)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Well system equipment" means any equipment that is necessary to draw or purify water from a well.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Well system equipment" includes any casing, grout, screen, water tank, water pump, or water conditioning equipment.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
