<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gen" order_by="gen" level="1">Environment</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gen-6-1202.1</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this section, "transportation equipment", "military equipment", and "components of transportation...</catch_line>
  <order_by>1202.1</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section, "transportation equipment", "military equipment", and "components of transportation or military equipment" do not include shipping pallets used to transport unpackaged fruits and vegetables.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">This section does not apply to:<section prefix="(i)">Original equipment manufacturer replacement service parts or other products manufactured before January 1, 2011, if the part or products were manufactured in compliance with applicable federal, State, and local laws; and</section><section prefix="(ii)"><section prefix="1.">A vehicle, as defined in &#xA7; 11-176 of the Transportation Article;</section><section prefix="2.">An aircraft, as defined in &#xA7; 5-101 of the Transportation Article; or</section><section prefix="3.">A product, part, or replacement part for use in a vehicle or aircraft.</section></section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Beginning on December 31, 2010, a person may not manufacture, lease, sell, or distribute for sale or lease in the State any of the following products that contain more than one-tenth of 1% of decaBDE by mass:<section prefix="(i)">Mattresses;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Upholstered furniture designed for residential use; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Electrical or electronic equipment.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Except as provided in paragraph (3) of this subsection, beginning on December 31, 2012, a person may not manufacture, lease, sell, or distribute for sale or lease in the State any product that contains more than one-tenth of 1% of decaBDE by mass.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Paragraph (2) of this subsection does not apply to:<section prefix="(i)">Transportation equipment;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Military equipment; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">Components of transportation or military equipment.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">On or after December 31, 2013, a person may not manufacture, lease, sell, or distribute for sale or lease in the State the following products that contain more than one-tenth of 1% of decaBDE by mass:<section prefix="(1)">Transportation equipment;</section><section prefix="(2)">Military equipment; or</section><section prefix="(3)">Components of transportation or military equipment.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">This section does not prohibit:<section prefix="(1)">A retailer that is in possession of a product prohibited for manufacture, lease, sale, or distribution for sale or lease under subsections (b) and (c) of this section from selling, recycling, or otherwise disposing of a product that is in the retailer's or lessor's inventory on or after the date that the prohibition takes effect;</section><section prefix="(2)">A person from recycling a product that contains decaBDE;</section><section prefix="(3)">A person from selling, leasing, recycling, or otherwise disposing of a product that contains recycled decaBDE;</section><section prefix="(4)">Any activity involving a product that contains decaBDE that occurs subsequent to first sale at retail; or</section><section prefix="(5)">A person from transporting or storing a product prohibited under subsections (b) and (c) of this section for later distribution outside the State.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
