<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gen" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="5-401" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gen-5-401</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Authority" means Maryland Potomac Water Authority.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Federal government" means:<section prefix="(1)">The United States of America; or</section><section prefix="(2)">Any governmental agency of the United States of America.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">"Initial cost" means the portion of water supply costs of the project which nonfederal entities must contract to repay prior to construction of the project. Actual payment of initial cost may be extended over a 50-year period beginning when augmented flow first is available from the project.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"Non-Maryland user" means a user not assessable by a represented county.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">"Potomac River" means the main stem and North Branch of the Potomac River and its tributaries in those reaches below the augmented average flow surface level of the main stem and North Branch.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">"Project" means a federally constructed dam, reservoir, and appurtenances on the North Branch of the Potomac River, commonly referred to as the Bloomington Dam project.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">"Represented county" means any county enumerated in this subtitle as being within the district.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">"The district", unless otherwise indicated in the text to mean the District of Columbia, means the area of jurisdiction of the Authority, which includes the following counties: Allegany, Frederick, Garrett, Montgomery, Prince George's, and Washington.</section>
    <section prefix="(j)">"User" means any person who uses water from the Potomac River for any purpose without regard to whether or not the water is consumed, altered, or replaced.</section>
  </text>
</law>
