<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gen" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="9-907" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gen-9-907</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Each incorporating political subdivision shall include in the law that creates an authority the articles of incorporation for the authority.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The articles of incorporation shall include:<section prefix="(1)">An appropriate name for the authority, which includes the word "authority";</section><section prefix="(2)">A statement that the authority is formed under this subtitle;</section><section prefix="(3)">The name of each incorporating political subdivision;</section><section prefix="(4)">The name, address, and term of office for each member of the 1st board of directors of the authority;</section><section prefix="(5)">If the governing body of any incorporating political subdivision determines that its members are the board of directors of the authority, a statement to this effect; and</section><section prefix="(6)">The purpose of the authority.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The officers of each incorporating political subdivision shall sign, acknowledge, and file the articles of incorporation for record with the State Department of Assessments and Taxation.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The State Department of Assessments and Taxation shall:<section prefix="(i)">Receive the articles of incorporation;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Mark the date and time of receipt to the articles; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Issue a certificate of approval for any articles that comply with this subtitle.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">When the State Department of Assessments and Taxation issues a certificate of approval, the authority:<section prefix="(i)">Begins to exist as a public body politic and corporate;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Is conclusively considered to be lawfully and properly created;</section><section prefix="(iii)">May exercise its powers under this subtitle; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">Has the right to exist as a corporation for a term of 50 years.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
