<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gen" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="2-404" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gen-2-404</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">This section applies to the following activities:<section prefix="(1)">Construction of a new source;</section><section prefix="(2)">Replacement of components of an existing permitted source, if the fixed capital cost of the replacement components exceeds one-half of the fixed capital cost that would be required to construct a new source comparable in process to the existing source; and</section><section prefix="(3)">Modification of an existing permitted source by making a physical or operational change to the source that will result in a significant net increase in emissions of any pollutant from that source.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Before accepting an application for a permit subject to subsection (c) of this section, the Department shall require the applicant to submit documentation:<section prefix="(i)">That demonstrates that the proposal has been approved by the local jurisdiction for all zoning and land use requirements; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">That the source meets all applicable zoning and land use requirements.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Paragraph (1) of this subsection does not apply to any application for a permit to construct at an existing source unless the existing source is a nonconforming use.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Department shall comply with the provisions in subsection (d) of this section before issuing a permit for the activities listed in subsection (a) of this section at:<section prefix="(1)">Any source which is required to obtain a permit to operate under regulations adopted under this subtitle;</section><section prefix="(2)">Any source which is subject to federal standards under 40 C.F.R. Part 60 (New Source Performance Standards), 40 C.F.R. Part 61 (National Emission Standards for Hazardous Air Pollutants), or 40 C.F.R. 52.21 (Prevention of Significant Deterioration); or</section><section prefix="(3)">Any source that will, after control, discharge 25 tons or more per year of a pollutant regulated under this title in the areas of Baltimore City designated by the United States Post Office as zip code numbers 21225, 21226, and 21230.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Before issuing a permit subject to subsection (c) of this section, the Department shall:<section prefix="(i)">Comply with the provisions of Title 1, Subtitle 6 of this article; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Conduct any public hearing required by Title 1, Subtitle 6 of this article in the county in which the proposed source is located.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">In addition to the requirements under paragraph (1) of this subsection, before issuing a permit to construct a source described in subsection (c)(3) of this section, the Department shall require at the expense of the applicant the preparation of an ambient air quality impact analysis regarding the proposed construction.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The provisions of this section do not apply to any permit to construct control equipment on an existing source or to any permit to operate.</section>
  </text>
</law>
