<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gen" order_by="gen" level="1">Environment</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gen-15-517</section_number>
  <catch_line>The Secretary shall establish within the Bituminous Coal Open-Pit Mining Reclamation Fund a bond sup...</catch_line>
  <order_by>517</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Secretary shall establish within the Bituminous Coal Open-Pit Mining Reclamation Fund a bond supplement reserve to be used if funds received from the forfeiture of bonds under &#xA7; 15-514 of this subtitle are not sufficient:<section prefix="(1)">To reclaim the land affected by the operation on which the liability was charged on the bond; and</section><section prefix="(2)">To perform:<section prefix="(i)">The requirements of this subtitle;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The requirements of regulations adopted under this subtitle; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Any permit condition that the operator has failed to perform.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Secretary shall deposit to the credit of the bond supplement reserve the following funds:<section prefix="(1)">A portion of the assessment under &#xA7; 15-509(b)(1) of this subtitle equal to 2 cents for each ton of coal produced for the month;</section><section prefix="(2)">The amount of the assessment under &#xA7; 15-509(b)(2) of this subtitle; and</section><section prefix="(3)">The amount of the assessment under &#xA7; 15-509(d) of this subtitle.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">When the amount of money in the bond supplement reserve equals or exceeds $750,000 at the end of the month, deposits into the reserve of the amounts provided in subsection (b)(1) and (2) of this section shall end temporarily.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The assessment under &#xA7; 15-509(d) of this subtitle shall end temporarily for any month when:<section prefix="(1)">The amount of money in the bond supplement reserve equals or exceeds $750,000 at the end of the month;</section><section prefix="(2)">An amount equal to the amount paid to the bond supplement reserve under subsection (b)(1) of this section from the assessment under &#xA7; 15-509(d) of this subtitle has been credited to the Bituminous Coal Open-Pit Mining Reclamation Fund; and</section><section prefix="(3)">An amount equal to the amount paid to the bond supplement reserve under subsection (b)(2) of this section from the assessment under &#xA7; 15-509(d) of this subtitle has been remitted to the fiscal authority of the county in which the coal was removed.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">At the end of any month when the amount of money in the bond supplement reserve is reduced below $500,000:<section prefix="(1)">The assessment under &#xA7; 15-509(d) of this subtitle shall resume; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Deposits into the bond supplement reserve of the amounts in subsection (b)(1), (2), and (3) of this section shall resume.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The Secretary shall notify each county when remitting or suspending the remittance of the amount under &#xA7; 15-509(b)(2) of this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">The Secretary shall meet and confer with the Land Reclamation Committee at least 30 days before procuring any services for which funds from the bond supplement reserve will be used, and shall provide the Committee an opportunity to submit comments and recommendations about the proposed expenditure.</section>
  </text>
</law>
