<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gen" order_by="" level="1">Environment</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gen-5-904</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>904</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Department may delegate all or part of its authority under this subtitle to any county that enacts a nontidal wetland protection program by December 31, 1994 that meets at least the minimum standards adopted by the Department.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">After December 31, 1994, the Department may delegate all or part of its authority under this subtitle to a county that applies to the Department to initiate a nontidal wetland protection program and meets at least the minimum standards adopted by the Department.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The Department shall establish a schedule for acceptance of applications from counties to initiate programs under this paragraph that provides a limited period of time once every 2 years for counties to submit their applications to the Department.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A delegation in accordance with this subsection:<section prefix="(i)">May not be effective for more than 2 years; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">May be renewed by the Department for additional 2-year periods.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">After an opportunity for a hearing and upon a finding that the county program is not being administered in a manner consistent with the standards adopted by the Department, the Department may withdraw program delegation.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Any regulated activity undertaken by a unit of State government shall comply with the provisions of this subtitle, including the provisions of this subtitle requiring the issuance of a nontidal wetland permit by the Department. The unit is not required to have local government approval.</section>
  </text>
</law>
