<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gen" order_by="gen" level="1">Environment</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gen-9-649</section_number>
  <catch_line>This section does not authorize the creation of a service area that includes territory in another se...</catch_line>
  <order_by>649</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">This section does not authorize the creation of a service area that includes territory in another service area.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">If the required number of property owners sign a petition that requests the creation of a service area in a district, the sanitary commission shall review the petition.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The required number of petitioning property owners is:<section prefix="(1)">In Dorchester County, the lesser of:<section prefix="(i)">25 percent of the property owners in the proposed service area; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">25 property owners in the proposed service area; and</section></section><section prefix="(2)">In any other member county, 25 property owners in the proposed service area.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The petition:<section prefix="(1)">Shall include a definite statement of the boundaries of the proposed service area;</section><section prefix="(2)">May request that the proposed service area be designated as a new service area; and</section><section prefix="(3)">If the proposed service area is contiguous to an existing service area, may request that the existing service area be extended to include the proposed service area.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">If the sanitary commission approves the petition, the sanitary commission may:<section prefix="(1)">Obtain a preliminary engineering survey that describes the feasibility and probable costs of providing to the service area the services that a district can provide under this subtitle; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Submit the approved petition to the governing body of each member county of the proposed service area for consideration by that governing body.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">If the sanitary commission disapproves the petition or does not obtain an engineering survey, the sanitary commission shall:<section prefix="(1)">Notify each petitioner by mail of the sanitary commission's action; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Include in the notice an estimate of the cost of obtaining the engineering survey.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(g)">If the sanitary commission does not get an engineering survey, the sanitary commission may not take further action on the petition unless the petitioners pay to the district the estimated cost of the engineering survey.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">If the petitioners pay the estimated cost of the engineering survey, the sanitary commission shall obtain the engineering survey in accordance with this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">If the petitioners pay the cost of a survey under this section and if a service area later is created or changed under this section, the sanitary commission shall repay to the petitioners the survey costs incurred by the petitioners.</section>
    <section prefix="(j)">When the preliminary engineering survey is complete and after giving notice in accordance with this section, the sanitary commission shall hold a public hearing to consider the petition.</section>
    <section prefix="(k)">
      <section prefix="(1)">For at least 3 weeks before the hearing, notice of the hearing shall be published in each member county once a week in at least 1 newspaper of general circulation in the county.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The notice shall include:<section prefix="(i)">A description of the proposed service area; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">The time and place of the hearing.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(l)">At the hearing, the sanitary commission shall provide a report of:<section prefix="(1)">The latest estimate of the cost of creating the proposed service area;</section><section prefix="(2)">The latest estimate of the cost of providing facilities in the proposed service area; and</section><section prefix="(3)">How much of the cost will be funded by issuing bonds under this subtitle.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(m)">In deciding on a petition presented under this section, the sanitary commission shall consider:<section prefix="(1)">The standards required under &#xA7; 9-647 of this subtitle; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Whether granting the petition would require a bond issuance that is excessive under subsection (n) of this section.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(n)">A bond issuance is excessive if:<section prefix="(1)">The bond issuance is for funding a proposed service area; and</section><section prefix="(2)">After the bond issuance, the unamortized balance of bonds issued for the proposed service area would exceed 25 percent of the total value of property in the service area, as assessed for county taxation.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(o)">The sanitary commission shall deny the petition if:<section prefix="(1)">Granting the petition would violate the standards of &#xA7; 9-647 of this subtitle; or</section><section prefix="(2)">Granting the petition would require a bond issuance that is excessive under subsection (n) of this section.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(p)">The sanitary commission shall:<section prefix="(1)">Issue an order that denies, grants, or modifies the petition; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Publish its order in each member county where the proposed service area is located in at least 1 newspaper of general circulation in the county.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(q)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The governing bodies of the member counties in the proposed service area shall review the order of the sanitary commission, if at least 10 individuals who own property in and reside in the proposed service area request a review of the order within 10 days after notice of the sanitary commission's order is published.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">After due notice, the governing bodies of the member counties at a hearing shall consider de novo the factors that the sanitary commission was required to consider.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">After the hearing, the governing bodies of the member counties may affirm or reverse the order of the sanitary commission.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(r)">
      <section prefix="(1)">When a proposed service area is approved finally under this section, the sanitary commission shall file plats of the service area:<section prefix="(i)">In the office of the sanitary commission;</section><section prefix="(ii)">With the governing body of each county in which any part of the service area lies; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">With the clerk of the circuit court for each county in which any part of the service area lies for filing in a plat book among the land records.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The plats required under this subsection shall:<section prefix="(i)">Be made under the supervision of the sanitary commission's engineers;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Show the boundaries of the service area; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">In the case of the plat filed among the land records, be indexed in the records in the names of the district and the service area.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(s)">If a service area created under this section is a new service area, the sanitary commission shall give the service area a distinctive name.</section>
    <section prefix="(t)">A service area is created when the requirements of this section have been met.</section>
    <section prefix="(u)">Each service area created under this section is a separate taxing district.</section>
  </text>
</law>
