<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gen" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="5-901" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gen-5-901</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Agricultural activity" means aquaculture and farming activities.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Agricultural activity" includes:<section prefix="(i)">Plowing, tillage, cropping, seeding, cultivating, and harvesting for the production of food and fiber products; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">The grazing of livestock.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Best management practices" means conservation practices or systems of practices and management measures that:<section prefix="(1)">Control soil loss and reduce water quality degradation caused by nutrients, animal waste, toxics, and sediment; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Minimize adverse impacts to the surface water and groundwater flow and circulation patterns, and to the chemical, physical, and biological characteristics of a nontidal wetland.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">"Compensation ratio" means the ratio of the area of wetland restored, created, or enhanced to the area of wetland for which mitigation is required.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"Department" means the Department of the Environment.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">"Forestry activity" means planting, cultivating, thinning, harvesting, or any other activity undertaken to use forest resources or to improve their quality or productivity.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">"Isolated nontidal wetland" means a nontidal wetland that is not hydrologically connected, through surface or subsurface flow, to streams, tidal or nontidal wetlands, or tidal waters.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">"Mitigation banking" means wetland restoration, creation, or enhancement undertaken expressly for the purpose of providing compensation credits for wetland losses from future activities.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Nontidal wetland" means an area that is inundated or saturated by surface water or groundwater at a frequency and duration sufficient to support, and that under normal circumstances does support, a prevalence of vegetation typically adapted for life in saturated soil conditions, commonly known as hydrophytic vegetation.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The determination of whether an area is a nontidal wetland shall be made in accordance with the publication known as the "Federal Manual for Identifying and Delineating Jurisdictional Wetlands", published in 1989 and as may be amended.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Nontidal wetlands" do not include tidal wetlands regulated under Title 16 of this article.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(j)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Regulated activity" means any of the following activities in a nontidal wetland or within a 25 foot buffer of the nontidal wetland:<section prefix="(i)">The removal, excavation, or dredging of soil, sand, gravel, minerals, organic matter, or materials of any kind;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The changing of existing drainage characteristics, sedimentation patterns, flow patterns, or flood retention characteristics;</section><section prefix="(iii)">The disturbance of the water level or water table by drainage, impoundment, or other means;</section><section prefix="(iv)">The dumping, discharging of material, or filling with material, including the driving of piles and placing of obstructions;</section><section prefix="(v)">The grading or removal of material that would alter existing topography; and</section><section prefix="(vi)">The destruction or removal of plant life that would alter the character of a nontidal wetland.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Regulated activity" does not include an agricultural activity or forestry activity as defined in this section.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(k)">"Soil conservation and water quality plan" means a land use plan for a farm that shows a farmer how to make best possible use of soil and water resources while protecting and conserving those resources for the future.</section>
  </text>
</law>
