<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gen" order_by="gen" level="1">Environment</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gen-1-101</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this article the following words have the meanings indicated....</catch_line>
  <order_by>101</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this article the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Contested case hearing" means an adjudicatory hearing in accordance with the contested case procedures of Subtitle 2 of the Maryland Administrative Procedure Act.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"County" means a county of this State and, unless expressly provided otherwise, Baltimore City.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">"Department" means the Department of the Environment.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"Health officer" means the Baltimore City Commissioner of Health or the health officer of a county.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">"Includes" or "including" means includes or including by way of illustration and not by way of limitation.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">"Informational meeting" means a meeting, open to the public, at which the applicant or the Department presents information concerning a permit application. An informational meeting is not a contested case hearing nor an agency hearing under &#xA7; 10-202(d) of the State Government Article.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">"Person" means an individual, receiver, trustee, guardian, personal representative, fiduciary, or representative of any kind and any partnership, firm, association, corporation, or other entity.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">"Physician" means an individual who is authorized under the Maryland Medical Practice Act to practice medicine in this State.</section>
    <section prefix="(j)">"Public hearing" means a meeting, open to the public, at which the Department receives oral and written comments concerning a tentative determination. A public hearing is not a contested case hearing nor an agency hearing under &#xA7; 10-202(d) of the State Government Article.</section>
    <section prefix="(k)">"Secretary" means the Secretary of the Environment.</section>
    <section prefix="(l)">"State" means:<section prefix="(1)">A state, possession, or territory of the United States;</section><section prefix="(2)">The District of Columbia; or</section><section prefix="(3)">The Commonwealth of Puerto Rico.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(m)">"Substantively" means in a manner substantially affecting the rights, duties, or obligations of a member of the public.</section>
  </text>
</law>
