<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gen" order_by="gen" level="1">Environment</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gen-9-601</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated....</catch_line>
  <order_by>601</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Bond" means any bond, note, or other evidence of indebtedness or obligation that a district is authorized to issue under this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Cost", as applied to any project, includes the cost of and all expenses incident to the construction, acquisition, improvement, or placement in operation of a project, including the cost and expenses of:<section prefix="(i)">The purchase price of a project;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The cost of acquiring all the capital stock of a corporation that owned a project;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Amounts paid to discharge obligations of the owner of a project, if paid to vest title to a project in the district;</section><section prefix="(iv)">Any interest in real or personal property acquired in connection with it;</section><section prefix="(v)">Financial, technical, professional, engineering, and legal services;</section><section prefix="(vi)">Plans, specifications, surveys, estimates of costs and revenues, feasibility or practicability reports, machinery, equipment, administrative expenses, and other expenses that are necessary and incident to the financing authorized for the construction, acquisition, improvement, or placement in operation of a project; and</section><section prefix="(vii)">Financing the project, including finance charges and interest before, during, and for 1 year after completion of construction.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Cost", as to any obligation or expense that is incurred before the bonds are issued, also includes the cost and expense of engineering services, estimates of costs and revenues, and any other technical or professional services that may be used in the construction, acquisition, or improvement of a project.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"District" means an entity that is created under this subtitle.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"District" includes a board, body, or commission that assumes the principal functions of a district that is created under this subtitle and later abolished.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"Governing body" means the body or board that is authorized to enact ordinances or resolutions for a county.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">"Improvement" means any construction, repair, replacement, extension, or betterment of a project.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">"Independent system" means a water system, sewerage system, or solid waste disposal system that:<section prefix="(1)">Is not operated by a sanitary commission or a municipality; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Serves territory not served by a project.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(h)">"Member county" means a county that:<section prefix="(1)">Has formed or joined a district under this subtitle; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Has not withdrawn from the district.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(i)">"Municipal system" means a water system, sewerage system, or solid waste disposal system that:<section prefix="(1)">Is operated by a municipality; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Serves territory not served by a project.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(j)">"Project" means a water system, sewerage system, solid waste disposal system, or solid waste acceptance facility or any part of these that a district owns, constructs, or operates.</section>
    <section prefix="(k)">"Sanitary commission" means a sanitary commission created under this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(l)">"Service area" means a defined geographical area that is established as a service area by a sanitary commission under this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(m)">"Sewage" means any water-carried waste created in and carried or to be carried away from a residence, hotel, school, hospital, industrial establishment, commercial establishment, or any other building, including any household and industrial wastes that are present.</section>
    <section prefix="(n)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Sewerage system" means a plant, system, facility, or property that can:<section prefix="(i)">Carry sewage away;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Collect sewage;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Neutralize sewage;</section><section prefix="(iv)">Stabilize sewage; or</section><section prefix="(v)">Treat sewage.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Sewerage system" includes the following parts of a sewerage system:<section prefix="(i)">A disposal field.</section><section prefix="(ii)">A drainage ditch.</section><section prefix="(iii)">A force main.</section><section prefix="(iv)">An intercepting ditch.</section><section prefix="(v)">An intercepting sewer.</section><section prefix="(vi)">A lateral sewer.</section><section prefix="(vii)">An outfall sewer.</section><section prefix="(viii)">A pumping station.</section><section prefix="(ix)">A sewage conduit.</section><section prefix="(x)">Sewage equipment.</section><section prefix="(xi)">A sewage lagoon.</section><section prefix="(xii)">A sewage pipe.</section><section prefix="(xiii)">A sewage pipe line.</section><section prefix="(xiv)">A sewage treatment plant.</section><section prefix="(xv)">A trunk sewer.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Sewerage system" includes any property or property right used in the operation of the sewerage system.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(o)">"Solid waste acceptance facility" means a facility whose primary purpose is:<section prefix="(1)">Disposing of solid waste;</section><section prefix="(2)">Processing solid waste; or</section><section prefix="(3)">Treating solid waste.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(p)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Solid waste disposal system" means a system that systematically or on a schedule collects solid waste and transports it to a solid waste acceptance facility for treatment or disposal.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Solid waste disposal system" includes a solid waste acceptance facility that is used with the system.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(q)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Water system" means a plant, system, facility, or property that can supply water or distribute water.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Water system" includes the following parts of a water system:<section prefix="(i)">A dam.</section><section prefix="(ii)">A filtration plant.</section><section prefix="(iii)">A hydrant.</section><section prefix="(iv)">A lateral.</section><section prefix="(v)">A reservoir.</section><section prefix="(vi)">A standpipe.</section><section prefix="(vii)">A valve.</section><section prefix="(viii)">A water distribution system.</section><section prefix="(ix)">Water equipment.</section><section prefix="(x)">A water intake.</section><section prefix="(xi)">A water main.</section><section prefix="(xii)">A water meter.</section><section prefix="(xiii)">A water pumping station.</section><section prefix="(xiv)">A water purification plant.</section><section prefix="(xv)">A water supply system.</section><section prefix="(xvi)">A well.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Water system" includes any property or property right used in the operation of the water system.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
