<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gen" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="15-511" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gen-15-511</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">After completion of all coal removal, backfilling, regrading, and planting on the permit, the operator shall file with the Department a completion report on a form furnished by the Department no later than the time the next mining and reclamation progress report required by &#xA7; 15-508(b) of this subtitle is to be submitted.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The report shall identify the operation, the area of land affected by the strip mining operation, and identify any area proposed to be reserved for deep mining or any other lawful purpose in accordance with subsection (b) of this section.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The completion report shall be accompanied by a completion map. The map shall be prepared and certified by a registered professional engineer or registered land surveyor and contain the following information:<section prefix="(i)">The information required by the map under &#xA7; 15-505(c)(2) of this subtitle;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The surveyed boundaries of the areas affected on the permit;</section><section prefix="(iii)">The surveyed boundaries of all areas which have been backfilled and planted on the permit and indicate the month and year each area was planted;</section><section prefix="(iv)">The surveyed boundaries of any areas proposed to be reserved for deep mining or other purposes under subsection (b) of this section; and</section><section prefix="(v)">A legend which indicates the total acres of the permit, acres affected on the permit, the acres remaining open on the permit, and the acres reserved for deep mining or other purposes.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The Department shall review the completion report.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">If the Department determines the report is correct, the report shall be approved.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">If the report is not approved, the Department shall notify the operator, in writing, setting forth the reasons for disapproval and identify the action necessary to secure approval.</section>
        <section prefix="(iv)">The operator shall take the action necessary to secure approval of the report.</section>
        <section prefix="(v)">Approval of the completion report by the Department exempts the operator from the filing of further mining and reclamation progress reports on the permit pursuant to &#xA7; 15-508(b) of this subtitle.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">If the operator or any other person desires to conduct deep mining on the premises or use a portion of the permit area for haulageways or any other lawful purpose, the operator may designate a location, subject to the Department's approval, to be used for one or more of these purposes. At a designated and approved location it is not necessary to backfill as required by this subtitle until the deep mining or other use is completed. During this time the bond on file for that portion of the operation may not be released unless a bond as required by Subtitle 6 of this title is filed with the Department. The area of each reserved opening and its location shall be described in the completion report and designated on the attached map. Before commencing operation of a deep mine, a permit must be obtained and a bond filed as required by Subtitle 6 of this title.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">If within two years after the completion of the strip mining operation deep mining has not been initiated at the proposed location, reclamation shall be completed in accordance with this subtitle.</section>
  </text>
</law>
