<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gen" order_by="" level="1">Environment</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gen-9-1708</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>1708</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A person may operate a natural wood waste recycling facility in this State only in accordance with the provisions of this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">In addition to the other provisions of this section, after July 1, 1992, a person may not operate a natural wood waste recycling facility in the State without a permit issued by the Department under this section.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A natural wood waste recycling facility may accept only natural wood waste.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A natural wood waste recycling facility shall be operated in a manner that prevents health hazards and minimizes nuisances. Discharges to air or waters of the State shall be limited to discharges allowable under permits governing solid waste disposal, water pollution control, or air pollution control. Dust resulting from the operations shall be controlled at all times.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Adequate personnel and equipment shall be maintained at all times to ensure proper operation and prompt attention to correct problems associated with the construction and maintenance of a natural wood waste recycling facility.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The disposal site shall be under the supervision of a responsible individual present at the disposal site at all times during the operation of a natural wood waste recycling facility.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">Access to a natural wood waste recycling facility shall be controlled at all times, and entrances shall be adequately closed when the site is not in operation.</section>
      <section prefix="(6)">Suitable measures to prevent and to control fires at a natural wood waste recycling facility shall be provided.</section>
      <section prefix="(7)">A person may not burn wood waste at a natural wood waste recycling facility except as permitted by the Department or, when applicable, by the local governmental authority.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Secretary may by regulation establish additional conditions under which a person may operate a natural wood waste recycling facility.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">On or before July 1, 1992, the Department shall adopt regulations to establish a permit system for natural wood waste recycling facilities.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The provisions of &#xA7;&#xA7; 9-334 through 9-342 of this title and &#xA7; 10-104 of this article shall be used and shall apply to enforce violations of this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">A facility required to obtain a permit by the Department under Subtitle 2, Title 9 of this article is not required to obtain a permit under this section.</section>
  </text>
</law>
