<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gen" order_by="" level="1">Environment</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gen-15-603</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>603</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Secretary shall adopt rules and regulations for prevention of water pollution or damage to the land surface resulting from deep mining operations. The rules and regulations shall include standards and procedures for insuring reclamation or sealing of mined areas after operations cease.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Secretary may study and recommend and shall approve all procedures for reclamation, conservation, and revegetation of affected areas, including mine opening sealing, prevention or reclamation of subsidence damage, underground fires, disposition of spoil, restoration of plant cover, prevention of erosion, prevention of the creation of acid water, and any other actions that will ensure conservation and beneficial utilization of the natural resources of the State.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Secretary shall review all mining and reclamation plans, progress reports, inspection reports, and completion reports.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Secretary may enter to inspect any deep mine operation to determine reclamation progress, conservation, and water quality conditions and investigate for violations of this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">In order to protect the stability of land, the Secretary shall suspend deep mining under urbanized areas, cities, towns and communities and adjacent to industrial or commercial buildings, major impoundments or permanent streams if the Secretary finds imminent danger to inhabitants of the urbanized areas, cities, towns and communities.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The surface effects of deep mining shall be subject to the applicable provisions of Subtitle 5 of this title and any rules or regulations adopted pursuant thereto.</section>
  </text>
</law>
