<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gen" order_by="" level="1">Environment</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gen-9-1710</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>1710</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Container" means any rigid plastic container or plastic bottle.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Label" means a molded, imprinted, or raised symbol located on or near the bottom of a container.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">"Plastic bottle" means a plastic container intended for single use that:<section prefix="(i)">Has a neck that is smaller than the container;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Accepts a screw-type, snap cap, or other similar closure; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Has a capacity of at least 16 fluid ounces but less than 5 gallons.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(5)">"Rigid plastic container" means any formed or molded container, other than a bottle that:<section prefix="(i)">Is intended for single use;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Is predominantly composed of plastic resin;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Has a relatively inflexible finite shape or form; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">Has a capacity of at least 8 ounces but less than 5 gallons.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A person may not distribute for sale in the State any container unless the container is labeled indicating the plastic resin used to produce the container.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The label required under subsection (b) of this section shall:<section prefix="(i)">Appear on or near the bottom of the container;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Be clearly visible; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Consist of:<section prefix="1.">A number placed within 3 arrows forming a triangle as described in paragraph (2) of this subsection; and</section><section prefix="2.">Letters placed below the triangle of arrows.</section></section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The 3 arrows shall form an equilateral triangle with the apex of each point of the triangle at the midpoint of each arrow, rounded with a short radius.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The arrowhead of each arrow shall be at the midpoint of each side of the triangle with a short gap separating the pointer from the base of the adjacent arrow.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">The triangle formed by the 3 arrows curved at their midpoints shall depict a clockwise path around the code number.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The numbering and lettering shall be as follows:<section prefix="(i)">For polyethylene terepthalate, the letters "PETE" and the number 1;</section><section prefix="(ii)">For high density polyethylene, the letters "HDPE" and the number 2;</section><section prefix="(iii)">For vinyl, the letter "V" and the number 3;</section><section prefix="(iv)">For low density polyethylene, the letters "LDPE" and the number 4;</section><section prefix="(v)">For polypropylene, the letters "PP" and the number 5;</section><section prefix="(vi)">For polystyrene, the letters "PS" and the number 6; and</section><section prefix="(vii)">For any other plastic resin, the word "Other" and the number 7.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Any person who knowingly and willfully distributes for sale a container in violation of this section is guilty of a misdemeanor and on conviction is subject to a fine not exceeding $50 per violation.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The Department shall adopt regulations to administer and enforce the provisions of this section.</section>
  </text>
</law>
