<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gen" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="14-504" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gen-14-504</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Any person proposing to construct a facility in the coastal area shall file an application with the Department in the form the Secretary prescribes. The application shall be accompanied by the information the Secretary requires and shall include the following information:<section prefix="(1)">A project description specifying:<section prefix="(i)">What is planned to be constructed, its purpose, use, location, cost, and size; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">The methods of construction, construction schedule, and operation procedure.</section></section><section prefix="(2)">A list of all licenses, permits or other approvals required by any government unit.</section><section prefix="(3)">All information necessary or required for any application to the State or any of its units or departments, for any other permit, license or approval required for or in connection with the facility.</section><section prefix="(4)">Detailed information as to the need for the facility and facts concerning alternate site locations as may be requested by the Secretary.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Department shall establish a reasonable fee schedule to reimburse the Department for the costs of filing and processing of an application required by this subtitle. The fee shall include at least the cost of the statement required by &#xA7; 14-506 of this subtitle, payable in advance of any required State expenditure.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">All units and departments of the State shall, to the fullest extent possible, cooperate with any person proposing to construct a facility in the coastal area by supplying the person with information and assistance as he may request.</section>
  </text>
</law>
