<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gen" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="9-320" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gen-9-320</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">There is a Maryland Clean Water Fund.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The following payments shall be made into the Maryland Clean Water Fund:<section prefix="(1)">All application fees, permit fees, renewal fees, and funds collected by the Department under this subtitle, including any civil or administrative penalty or any fine imposed by a court under the provisions of this subtitle;</section><section prefix="(2)">Any civil penalty or any fine imposed by a court under the provisions of Title 5, Subtitle 5 of this article relating to water appropriation and use;</section><section prefix="(3)">Any civil or administrative penalty or any fine imposed by a court under the provisions of Title 4, Subtitle 1 of this article; and</section><section prefix="(4)">Any fees or funds that the Department collects under Subtitle 2, Part III of this title and &#xA7;&#xA7; 9-269 and 9-270 of this title and any civil or administrative penalty or fine imposed by a court under the provisions of Subtitle 2 of this title.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Department shall use the Maryland Clean Water Fund for activities that are related to:<section prefix="(1)">The identification, monitoring, and regulation of the proper discharge of effluent into the waters of the State including program development of these activities as provided by the State budget;</section><section prefix="(2)">The management, conservation, protection, and preservation of the State's groundwater and surface water including program development of these activities as provided by the State budget;</section><section prefix="(3)">Correcting to the extent possible the failure to implement or maintain erosion and sediment controls;</section><section prefix="(4)">Administration of the sediment control program;</section><section prefix="(5)">Emergency removal of sewage sludge or mitigation of the effect of any utilization of sewage sludge that the Department finds:<section prefix="(i)">Endangers public health, safety, or welfare; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">Endangers or damages natural resources;</section></section><section prefix="(6)">Activities that are:<section prefix="(i)">Conducted by the Department, by a local health official, or by the local health official's designee under &#xA7; 9-243(e) of this title; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Related to identifying, monitoring, or regulating the utilization of sewage sludge, including program development; and</section></section><section prefix="(7)">Providing supplemental inspections and monitoring of sewage sludge utilization sites by:<section prefix="(i)">Contracting with a county on request of that county to provide supplemental inspections and monitoring; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Limiting the value of services provided under the contract to no more than 45% of the generator fees for sludge utilized in that county that is generated outside of that county or service area.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">An expenditure that the Department makes under subsection (c)(5) of this section shall be reimbursed to the Department by the sewage sludge utilizer whose sewage sludge utilization brought about the expenditure by:<section prefix="(1)">Endangering public health, safety, or welfare; or</section><section prefix="(2)">Endangering or damaging natural resources.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">In addition to any other legal action authorized by this subtitle, the Attorney General may bring an action against any person who fails to reimburse the Department under subsection (d) of this section to recover any expenditure that the Department makes under subsection (c)(5) of this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">In determining the use of the Maryland Clean Water Fund, priority shall be given to activities relating to the water quality of the Chesapeake Bay and its tributaries.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">Notwithstanding any law to the contrary, funds credited and any interest accrued to the Fund:<section prefix="(1)">Shall remain available until expended; and</section><section prefix="(2)">May not be reverted to the General Fund under any other provision of law.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
