<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gen" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="9-1707" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gen-9-1707</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">"Newsprint" means paper of the type generally used in the publication of newspapers or commercial advertising inserts printed by the publisher that are made primarily from mechanical woodpulps combined with some chemical woodpulp.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">"Newsprint" includes paper made from old newspapers that have been deinked, using the recycled pulp in lieu of virgin pulp.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Reporting period" means:<section prefix="(i)">The calendar year for 2005 and earlier; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">The calendar year and the immediately preceding two calendar years for 2006 and all subsequent years.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in subsection (h) of this section, the recycled content percentage requirements for newspapers distributed in the State shall, on a statewide basis, be in accordance with the recycled content percentage requirements specified in subsection (c) of this section for the reporting period.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">In the year following any reporting period in which the Secretary determines, based on the reports submitted under subsection (e) of this section, that the recycled content percentage requirements specified in subsection (c) of this section have not been met on a statewide basis, each newspaper shall:<section prefix="(i)">For newspapers distributed in the State, satisfy the recycled content percentage requirement under subsection (c) of this section for the reporting period; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">Pay the newsprint recycling incentive fee required under subsection (d) of this section for that reporting period.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">To satisfy the recycled content percentage requirement of this section for a reporting period, at least the percentage specified in paragraph (2) of this subsection, by weight, of the total newsprint used by the publisher during that reporting period for newspapers distributed in the State shall be recycled materials.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The recycled content percentage requirement is:<section prefix="(i)">12% for 1992;</section><section prefix="(ii)">12% for 1993;</section><section prefix="(iii)">20% for 1994, 1995, 1996, 1997, 1998, and 1999;</section><section prefix="(iv)">25% for 2000;</section><section prefix="(v)">30% for 2001 and 2002;</section><section prefix="(vi)">35% for 2003 and 2004; and</section><section prefix="(vii)">40% for 2005 and all subsequent reporting periods.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The newsprint recycling incentive fee for any reporting period is $10 for each ton of a publisher's recycled content deficiency for the reporting period, as determined under paragraph (2) of this subsection.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A publisher's recycled content deficiency for a reporting period is the difference between:<section prefix="(i)">The product of multiplying the total tons of newsprint used by the publisher for the reporting period times the required percentage for that reporting period; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">The actual tonnage of recycled material contained in the newsprint used by the publisher for the reporting period.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A publisher of a newspaper distributed in the State shall complete and file with the Secretary:<section prefix="(i)">A quarterly report, on or before the last day of the month that follows each calendar quarter; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">An annual report, on or before January 31 following each calendar year.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Except as provided in paragraph (3) of this subsection, a report required under this subsection shall:<section prefix="(i)">Be in the form and manner and contain any information that the Secretary requires by regulation; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">State, for the period covered by the report:</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Secretary may not require the disclosure of the price per ton of newsprint paid by any publisher in any report required under this subsection.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">A publisher shall pay any newsprint recycling incentive fee required for a calendar year with the annual report that covers that year.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">There is a State Recycling Trust Fund.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Fund shall consist of:<section prefix="(i)">The newsprint recycling incentive fee;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The telephone directory recycling incentive fee collected under &#xA7; 9-1709 of this subtitle;</section><section prefix="(iii)">The covered electronic device manufacturer registration fee collected under &#xA7; 9-1728 of this subtitle;</section><section prefix="(iv)">All fines and penalties collected under this subtitle;</section><section prefix="(v)">Money appropriated in the State budget to the Fund; and</section><section prefix="(vi)">Any other money from any other source accepted for the benefit of the Fund.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Secretary shall administer the Fund.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The Treasurer shall hold the Fund separately and the Comptroller shall account for the Fund.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">At the end of each fiscal year, any unspent or unencumbered balance in the Fund that exceeds $2,000,000 shall revert to the General Fund of the State in accordance with &#xA7; 7-302 of the State Finance and Procurement Article.</section>
      <section prefix="(6)">In accordance with the State budget, the Fund shall be used only:<section prefix="(i)">To provide grants to the counties to be used by the counties to develop and implement local recycling plans;</section><section prefix="(ii)">To provide grants to counties that have addressed methods for the separate collection and recycling of covered electronic devices in accordance with &#xA7; 9-1703(c)(1) of this subtitle;</section><section prefix="(iii)">To provide grants to municipalities to be used by the municipalities to implement local covered electronic device recycling programs; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">To carry out the purposes of the land management administration.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(7)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The Treasurer shall invest the money in the Fund in the same manner as other State money may be invested.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">Any investment earnings of the Fund shall be credited to the General Fund of the State.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">Repealed.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">There is a Newsprint Recycling Board in the Department.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The Newsprint Recycling Board shall meet only at the request of the Secretary.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Newsprint Recycling Board is composed of 9 members appointed by the Governor as follows:<section prefix="(i)">2 shall be representatives of newspaper publishers appointed from a list of at least 5 names submitted by the Maryland Delaware District of Columbia Press Association;</section><section prefix="(ii)">1 shall be a representative of the Northeast Waste Disposal Authority;</section><section prefix="(iii)">1 shall be a representative of the Maryland Environmental Service;</section><section prefix="(iv)">1 shall be a representative of local governments;</section><section prefix="(v)">1 shall be a representative of the newspaper recycling manufacturing industry;</section><section prefix="(vi)">1 shall be a representative of an industry, other than an industry that uses old newspapers; and</section><section prefix="(vii)">2 shall be representatives of environmental groups with some expertise in recycling.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Governor shall appoint the Chairman of the Newsprint Recycling Board from among the members.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The term of a member of the Newsprint Recycling Board is 3 years.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The terms of the members of the Newsprint Recycling Board are staggered as required by the terms of the members of the Board serving on December 31, 1991.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">At the end of a term, a member continues to serve until a successor is appointed and qualifies.</section>
        <section prefix="(iv)">A member of the Newsprint Recycling Board may not serve more than two 3-year terms.</section>
        <section prefix="(v)">The members of the Newsprint Recycling Board shall serve without compensation, but shall be reimbursed for all reasonable expenses incurred in the performance of their duties.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(5)">Upon the application of a newspaper publisher, the Newsprint Recycling Board shall, on the affirmative vote of a majority of the members eligible to vote, excuse the publisher of all or part of the recycled content percentage requirements of this section for the newspaper publisher under such terms and conditions and for such periods as the Board considers appropriate if the Board determines, after taking into consideration the publisher's supply contracts which existed as of March 15, 1990, that:<section prefix="(i)">The publisher could not obtain from manufacturers serving the mid-Atlantic region an adequate supply of recycled newsprint comparable in quality to virgin newsprint; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">The publisher has made a good faith effort to meet the recycled content percentage requirements.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(6)">If the Newsprint Recycling Board fails to act on an application for an excuse of all or part of the recycled content percentage requirements made under paragraph (5) of this subsection within 45 days of the filing of the application with the Board, the application shall be deemed approved.</section>
      <section prefix="(7)">The Newsprint Recycling Board shall:<section prefix="(i)">Review the reports filed under subsection (e) of this section;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Analyze the availability and utilization of newsprint containing recycled material;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Comment on the appropriateness of the recycled content percentage requirements, including whether the requirements encourage manufacturers of virgin newsprint to convert to recycling;</section><section prefix="(iv)">Comment on the need for continuation of the provisions of this section and the impact the provisions of this section have on users of old newspapers for purposes other than producing newsprint;</section><section prefix="(v)">Work with municipalities and other collectors of old newspapers to develop a reliable system to provide a stable and quality supply of old newspapers for recycling;</section><section prefix="(vi)">Work to encourage the location of production facilities in the region to ensure an increase in the supply of recycled newsprint; and</section><section prefix="(vii)">Work to encourage the reuse of old newspapers.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(i)">A county, municipality, or any agency of a county or municipality may not:<section prefix="(1)">Impose on a publisher or distributor of newspapers by law, ordinance, or regulation any recycling content percentage requirements or taxes or charges based on the percent of recycled or virgin fiber contained in a newspaper; or</section><section prefix="(2)">Require the publisher or distributor of newspapers to collect or dispose of old newspapers in any way not imposed on the nonpublisher businesses in the county or municipality.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
