<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gen" order_by="" level="1">Environment</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gen-9-343</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>343</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A person who violates any provision of or fails to perform any duty imposed by this subtitle, or who violates any provision of or fails to perform any duty imposed by a rule, regulation, order, or permit adopted or issued under this subtitle, is guilty of a misdemeanor and on conviction is subject to:<section prefix="(i)">For a first offense, a fine not exceeding $25,000 or imprisonment not exceeding 1 year or both; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">If the conviction is for a violation committed after a first conviction of the person under this subsection, a fine not exceeding $50,000 for each day of violation or imprisonment not exceeding 2 years or both.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">In addition to any criminal penalties imposed on a person convicted under this subsection, the person may be enjoined from continuing the violation.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Each day on which a violation occurs is a separate violation under this subsection.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A person is guilty of a misdemeanor and on conviction is subject to a fine not exceeding $50,000 or imprisonment not exceeding 2 years or both if the person:<section prefix="(1)">Knowingly makes any false statement, representation, or certification in any application, record, report, plan, or other document filed or required to be maintained under this subtitle or any rule, regulation, order, or permit adopted or issued under this subtitle; or</section><section prefix="(2)">Falsifies, tampers with, or knowingly renders inaccurate any monitoring device or method required to be maintained under this subtitle or any rule, regulation, order, or permit adopted or issued under this subtitle.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
