<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gen" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="9-269" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gen-9-269</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A person who violates any provision of Part III of this subtitle or any rule, regulation, order, or permit adopted or issued under Part III of this subtitle is liable to the State for civil penalties.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">These civil penalties are:<section prefix="(i)">A basic civil penalty not exceeding $10,000; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">An additional penalty not exceeding $10,000 a day for each day that the violation continues, up to a maximum of $50,000.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The State shall recover the civil penalties under this section in a civil action.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In addition to any other remedies available at law or in equity and after an opportunity for a hearing which may be waived in writing by the person accused of a violation, the Department may impose a penalty for violation of any provision of Part III of this subtitle or any regulation, order, or permit adopted or issued under Part III of this subtitle.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The penalty imposed on a person under this subsection shall be:<section prefix="(i)">Up to $1,000 for each violation, but not exceeding $50,000 total; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Assessed with consideration given to:</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Each day a violation occurs is a separate violation under this subsection.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">Any penalty imposed under this subsection is payable to the State and collectible in any manner provided by law for the collection of debts.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">If any person who is liable to pay a penalty imposed under this subsection fails to pay it after demand, the amount, together with interest and any costs that may accrue, shall be:<section prefix="(i)">A lien in favor of the State on any property, real or personal, of the person; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Recorded in the office of the clerk of court for the county in which the property is located.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(6)">Any penalty collected under this subsection shall be placed in the Maryland Clean Water Fund under &#xA7; 9-320 of this title.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in paragraph (3) of this subsection, in addition to any other penalties set forth in this section, if any sewage sludge utilizer violates the terms of the permit by any action or inaction of the utilizer that results in the return of the sewage sludge to the generator, the utilizer is liable to the State for civil penalties.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The civil penalty imposed under this subsection may not exceed $100 for each wet ton of sewage sludge returned to the generator.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The provisions of this subsection do not apply if the violation is not caused by any action or inaction of the utilizer.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
