<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gen" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="9-699" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gen-9-699</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">A person may not:<section prefix="(1)">Interfere with an inspection made under authority of &#xA7; 9-606 of this subtitle;</section><section prefix="(2)">Violate &#xA7; 9-661 of this subtitle by failing:<section prefix="(i)">To maintain at least 1 sanitary toilet and wash basin as a part of any plumbing system that is used on any parcel after it is connected to a connector; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">To disconnect and close each cesspool, sink, drain, and privy on a parcel after it is connected to a connector;</section></section><section prefix="(3)">Violate a water conservation order;</section><section prefix="(4)">Construct or operate an independent system in violation of &#xA7; 9-664 of this subtitle;</section><section prefix="(5)">Fail to move an obstruction in violation of &#xA7; 9-669 of this subtitle;</section><section prefix="(6)">Fail, in violation of &#xA7; 9-697(a) of this subtitle, to perform any act required of that person in paying principal or interest on bonds issued under this subtitle;</section><section prefix="(7)">Use, for any purpose other than repaying in accordance with this subtitle, any funds that, under this subtitle, are required to be used to pay principal and interest on bonds;</section><section prefix="(8)">Violate &#xA7; 9-698 of this subtitle;</section><section prefix="(9)">Operate, or make any connection to a fire hydrant, unless the act is done:<section prefix="(i)">With written permission of the sanitary commission; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">By a fire department in discharge of its duties; or</section></section><section prefix="(10)">Deface, damage, or obstruct a fire hydrant.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A person who violates this section is guilty of a misdemeanor and on conviction is subject to a fine not exceeding $100 or imprisonment in jail not exceeding 30 days or both.</section>
  </text>
</law>
