<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gen" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="7-208" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gen-7-208</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">With the advice of the Council, the Department shall adopt rules and regulations to carry out the provisions of this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Before adopting any rule or regulation that relates to substances governed by the Federal Insecticide, Fungicide, and Rodenticide Act, the Department shall submit the rule or regulation to the State Secretary of Agriculture for review and approval.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">In adopting any rule or regulation, the Department shall consider among other things:<section prefix="(1)">Existing physical conditions;</section><section prefix="(2)">The character of an affected specific area;</section><section prefix="(3)">Zoning;</section><section prefix="(4)">The nature of any existing receiving body of water; and</section><section prefix="(5)">The technical feasibility and economic reasonableness of measuring or reducing a particular type of water pollution.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A rule or regulation under this subtitle may:<section prefix="(1)">Apply to pollutant and hazardous substance sources located outside this State that cause, contribute to, or threaten environmental damage in this State;</section><section prefix="(2)">Make special provisions for alert and abatement standards and procedures for occurrences or emergencies of pollution or on other short term conditions that are an acute danger to public health or to the environment;</section><section prefix="(3)">Specify different provisions as circumstances require for different:<section prefix="(i)">Pollutant, solid waste, and hazardous substance sources; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Geographical areas; or</section></section><section prefix="(4)">If an exemption is consistent with federal law or federal regulation, exempt persons from any requirements of this subtitle.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The Department by rule or regulation, shall:<section prefix="(1)">Identify all hazardous substances that are controlled hazardous substances governed by this subtitle;</section><section prefix="(2)">Set standards and describe tests to identify lethal, toxic, and other injurious effects of controlled hazardous substances;</section><section prefix="(3)">Set minimum design standards for controlled hazardous substance facilities;</section><section prefix="(4)">Establish types and quantities of controlled hazardous substances that may be disposed of;</section><section prefix="(5)">Establish procedures for monitoring the generation, transportation, treatment, storage, or disposal of controlled hazardous substances;</section><section prefix="(6)">Set minimum requirements for the operation, maintenance, monitoring, reporting, and supervision of any controlled hazardous substance facility;</section><section prefix="(7)">Set requirements for receiving and applying for facility permits;</section><section prefix="(8)">Set standards for determining bond values and fees under this subtitle;</section><section prefix="(9)">Set health and safety standards that relate specifically to the site of a controlled hazardous substance facility after consideration of, among other things, the following:<section prefix="(i)">Geology;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Seismology;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Hydrology;</section><section prefix="(iv)">Demography; and</section><section prefix="(v)">Climatology; and</section></section><section prefix="(10)">By June 30, 1991, adopt by regulation a revised State Hazardous Substance Response Plan that establishes standards and procedures for actions taken under &#xA7;&#xA7; 7-220 and 7-222 of this subtitle.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The revised State Hazardous Substance Response Plan shall at a minimum include:<section prefix="(1)">Methods for discovering and investigating sites at which hazardous substances have been disposed of or otherwise come to be located;</section><section prefix="(2)">Methods for evaluating any releases or threats of releases which pose substantial danger to the public health or the environment;</section><section prefix="(3)">Factors to be considered in determining the type of response action which will be implemented, including the cost of implementing, maintaining, and operating the remedy; and</section><section prefix="(4)">Methods and criteria for determining the appropriate extent of removal, remedy, and other measures authorized by this title.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(g)">In addition to the other provisions of this section, in its rules and regulations that govern low-level nuclear waste, the Department shall:<section prefix="(1)">Provide for the classification of low-level nuclear wastes by radionuclide content and level of radioactivity for different storage or disposal procedures;</section><section prefix="(2)">Provide for consultation with any affected political subdivision; and</section><section prefix="(3)">Set standards and procedures, including notice and hearing requirements, for revocation or suspension of a facility permit, a hauler certificate, or a vehicle certificate.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
