<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gen" order_by="gen" level="1">Environment</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gen-9-406</section_number>
  <catch_line>The Secretary shall adopt an adequate plan for providing safe drinking water under emergency circums...</catch_line>
  <order_by>406</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Secretary shall adopt an adequate plan for providing safe drinking water under emergency circumstances.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">If, in the judgment of the Secretary, emergency circumstances exist with respect to a need for safe drinking water, the Secretary may take any action necessary to provide safe drinking water where it otherwise would not be available.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Notwithstanding &#xA7; 9-407(b) of this subtitle, the Secretary may adopt and enforce regulations for a contaminant if the Secretary determines that the contaminant poses a significant risk to public health and for which complete interim or revised national primary drinking water regulations are not in effect.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">As part of the Secretary's determination under paragraph (1) of this subsection, the Secretary shall prepare a report that includes:<section prefix="(i)">1 year of statewide monitoring data for the contaminant, which identifies locations in the State where the contaminant level may pose a significant risk to public health;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Peer reviewed assessments, methodologies, and data concerning the particular contaminant; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">A cost/benefit analysis of implementing the proposed standard for the contaminant conducted by the Department that includes:<section prefix="1.">Review and comment by the Department of Business and Economic Development; and</section><section prefix="2.">After the Department provides notice of the analysis and a reasonable opportunity to comment to the affected public water systems, any submitted written statements from public water systems affected by the proposed standard.</section></section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Nothing in this subsection affects the Department's authority to adopt and enforce complete interim or revised national primary drinking water regulations.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
