<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gen" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="9-1728" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gen-9-1728</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">A covered electronic device manufacturer's registration shall include:<section prefix="(1)">The brand names under which the manufacturer sells or offers for sale covered electronic devices in the State;</section><section prefix="(2)">Whether the manufacturer has implemented a covered electronic device takeback program;</section><section prefix="(3)">If the manufacturer has implemented a covered electronic device takeback program:<section prefix="(i)">A toll-free number or website address that provides information about the takeback program, including a detailed description of how a person may return a covered electronic device for recycling, refurbishing, or reuse; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">One year after the implementation of the program and each year thereafter, a report on the implementation of the program during the prior year, including:</section></section><section prefix="(4)">The total number of covered electronic devices sold in the State in the prior year, including:<section prefix="(i)">The types of covered electronic devices sold; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">The brand names under which the covered electronic devices were sold; and</section></section><section prefix="(5)">Any additional information required by the Department in regulation.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The registration shall:<section prefix="(1)">Be submitted to the Department by March 1 of each year; and</section><section prefix="(2)">If the manufacturer has implemented a covered electronic device takeback program, be updated prior to any significant change in the program.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The covered electronic device manufacturer registration fee shall be paid by a manufacturer in accordance with this subsection.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">For the initial registration by a manufacturer, the registration fee is:<section prefix="(i)">$10,000 for a manufacturer that sold at least 1,000 covered electronic devices in the State in the prior year; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">$5,000 for a manufacturer that sold at least 100 but not more than 999 covered electronic devices in the State in the prior year.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">For each subsequent annual registration by a manufacturer that did not have an implemented covered electronic device takeback program in the prior year, the registration fee is:<section prefix="(i)"/><section prefix="(ii)">$5,000 for a manufacturer that sold at least 100 but not more than 999 covered electronic devices in the State in the prior year.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">For each subsequent annual registration by a manufacturer that had an implemented covered electronic device takeback program in the prior year, the registration fee is $500.	</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">There is no registration fee for a manufacturer that sold less than 100 covered electronic devices in the State in the prior year.</section>
      <section prefix="(6)">The registration fee required under this subsection shall:<section prefix="(i)">Be submitted to the Department by March 1 of each year; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Be paid into the State Recycling Trust Fund.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Department shall:<section prefix="(i)">Review the registration submitted under this section; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">If the registration does not meet the requirements of this section and the regulations adopted by the Department under this subtitle, notify the manufacturer of the insufficiency.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Within 60 days after receipt of a notice of insufficiency, the manufacturer shall submit a revised registration that addresses the insufficiencies noted by the Department.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The Department shall maintain a list of registered covered electronic device manufacturers on its Web site.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The sales data submitted in accordance with subsection (a)(4) of this section shall be treated as confidential and proprietary, and may not be disclosed except as otherwise required by law.</section>
  </text>
</law>
