<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gen" order_by="gen" level="1">Environment</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gen-6-1001</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated....</catch_line>
  <order_by>1001</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Abatement" means a set of measures that eliminate or reduce lead-based paint hazards in residential, public, or commercial buildings, bridges, or other structures or superstructures in accordance with standards established by the Department which may include:<section prefix="(1)">The removal of lead-based paint and lead-contaminated dust, the containment or encapsulation of lead-based paint, the replacement or demolition of lead-painted surfaces or fixtures, and the removal or covering of lead-contaminated soil;</section><section prefix="(2)">All preparation, cleanup, disposal, and postabatement clearance testing activities associated with these measures; and</section><section prefix="(3)">The renovation, repair, and painting of a lead-containing substance in a residential, public, or commercial building built before 1978.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Lead containing substance" means:<section prefix="(1)">Any paint, plaster, or surface encapsulation material containing more than 0.50 percent lead by weight calculated as lead metal in the dried solid or more than 0.7 milligrams lead per square centimeter as measured by an X-ray fluorescence analyzer; or</section><section prefix="(2)">Such other standards consistent with an applicable federal definition as the Department may set by regulation.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">"Person" includes any public or municipal corporation, or any agency, bureau, department, or instrumentality of federal, State, or local government.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"Provide lead paint abatement services" means to engage in the risk assessment, inspection, or abatement of lead-containing substances.</section>
  </text>
</law>
