<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gen" order_by="gen" level="1">Environment</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gen-15-830</section_number>
  <catch_line>On completion of reclamation of an area of affected land, the permittee immediately shall notify the...</catch_line>
  <order_by>830</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">On completion of reclamation of an area of affected land, the permittee immediately shall notify the Department. The Department shall make an inspection of the area, and if it finds that the permittee has not completed to the Department's reasonable satisfaction all the reclamation required by the permit, the Department shall order the permittee to do so at once and shall reinspect the area following completion of the work. If the Department finds that reclamation has been completed properly and if the Department has received the final reclamation report required under subsection (b) of this section, it shall notify the permittee in writing and release the permittee from further obligations regarding the affected land. At the same time it shall release all or the appropriate portion of any performance bond or cash deposit which the permittee has posted under &#xA7; 15-823 of this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The permittee shall furnish a final reclamation report which includes the following:<section prefix="(1)">The terms of the original surface mining permit and all subsequent modifications;</section><section prefix="(2)">A summary of the original mining and reclamation plan and all subsequent modifications;</section><section prefix="(3)">A statement summarizing any departures from the mining and reclamation plan and the reasons for them;</section><section prefix="(4)">A statement summarizing any problems encountered during the progress of mining work or reclamation work, and the measures taken to correct these problems;</section><section prefix="(5)">The total acreage of land disturbed and reclaimed;</section><section prefix="(6)">The status or condition of areas progressively reclaimed since the initiation of mining work in the area; and</section><section prefix="(7)">A final map that is consistent with the original mining and reclamation map required by &#xA7; 15-822(b) of this subtitle.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
