<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gen" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="9-1111" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gen-9-1111</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, "rural zone" means an area of Montgomery County designated as a Rural Zone, Rural Cluster Zone, Rural Density Transfer Zone, Rural Neighborhood Cluster Zone, or Rural Service Zone as described in the Montgomery County Code Zoning Ordinance.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in subsection (c) of this section, in Montgomery County, an on-site sewage disposal system or well located in a rural zone may only serve one additional lot or parcel that has been subdivided from a single property on which the on-site sewage disposal system or well is located under an on-site sewage disposal system easement or well easement, respectively, provided that:<section prefix="(i)">The property on which the on-site sewage disposal system or well is located does not have an existing on-site sewage disposal system easement or well easement;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The subdivision of the property was made in accordance with a State or county agricultural land conservation program if the property is subject to an agricultural land conservation easement; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Only one on-site sewage disposal system easement may serve only one subdivided lot or parcel.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">An easement for an on-site sewage disposal system or well under paragraph (1) of this subsection may be granted from the original parcel to a new lot or parcel being created and the easement must not be granted to any lot or parcel that did not originate from the same original parcel.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">An on-site sewage disposal system or well under subsection (b)(1) of this section may not:<section prefix="(1)">Serve land that is designated by the State or the governing body of Montgomery County as a special protection area; or</section><section prefix="(2)">Decrease the land available for agricultural production by more than 4,000 square feet.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
