<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gen" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="9-1108.1" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gen-9-1108.1</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Nitrogen removal technology" has the meaning stated in &#xA7; 9-1108 of this subtitle.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"On-site sewage disposal system" has the meaning stated in &#xA7; 9-1108 of this subtitle.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">"Vendor" means a person that sells, offers for sale, or distributes on-site sewage disposal systems that utilize nitrogen removal technology.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In accordance with subsection (c) of this section, the Department shall evaluate and rank all best available nitrogen removal technologies for on-site sewage disposal systems to advise local governments and residents of the State of approved technologies that qualify for funding under &#xA7; 9-1605.2(h)(2) of this title.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Department shall:<section prefix="(i)">Make available the evaluation and ranking of all best available nitrogen removal technologies required under this section on the Department's Web site; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Provide the evaluation and ranking of all best available nitrogen removal technologies to a county, municipality, or resident of the State in any correspondence relating to approved technologies that qualify for funding under &#xA7; 9-1605.2(h)(2) of this title.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Department shall evaluate and rank all best available nitrogen removal technologies for on-site sewage disposal systems based on:<section prefix="(1)">The total amount of nitrogen reduction the technology can achieve;</section><section prefix="(2)">The total cost of the technology, including the estimated annual cost of operation and maintenance, including electricity costs;</section><section prefix="(3)">The cost per pound of the nitrogen reduction; and</section><section prefix="(4)">Any other information the Department determines is necessary.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Beginning June 1, 2011, and every 2 years thereafter, the Department shall request information from vendors necessary to carry out the requirements of this section.</section>
  </text>
</law>
