<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gen" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="4-704" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gen-4-704</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">There is an Oil Contaminated Site Environmental Cleanup Fund.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Subject to subsection (c) of this section, the Fund shall be used to:<section prefix="(1)">Reimburse an owner or operator of:<section prefix="(i)">An underground oil storage tank subject to the requirements of &#xA7; 4-409(b)(3) of this title for site rehabilitation costs incurred on or after October 1, 1993 resulting from contamination caused by releases from an underground oil storage tank;</section><section prefix="(ii)">An underground oil storage tank not subject to the requirements of &#xA7; 4-409(b)(3) of this title for site rehabilitation costs incurred on or after October 1, 2000 resulting from contamination caused by releases from an underground oil storage tank; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">A heating oil tank for site rehabilitation costs incurred on or after October 1, 2000 resulting from contamination caused by releases from a heating oil tank including piping connected to the tank;</section></section><section prefix="(2)">Provide funds for site rehabilitation activities carried out by the Department or under the Department's direction and control; and</section><section prefix="(3)">To the extent provided in the State budget and in an amount not to exceed 8% of the revenues in the Fund during the fiscal year, provide funds for the Department's administration of this subtitle.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Twenty-five percent of the revenues credited to the Fund shall be used for reimbursement of heating oil tank site rehabilitation costs as provided in this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The provisions of this subtitle do not apply to:<section prefix="(1)">An underground storage tank that is:<section prefix="(i)">Owned by a State, county, or municipal corporation; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">Owned by a local education agency.</section></section><section prefix="(2)">An underground storage tank installed pursuant to Subtitle I of the federal Resource Conservation and Recovery Act; or</section><section prefix="(3)">Owners or operators of underground storage tanks that were not in compliance with the requirements of Subtitle I of the federal Resource Conservation and Recovery Act on December 22, 1998.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Money in the Fund not required to meet the Department's obligations in the exercise of the Department's responsibility under this section:<section prefix="(i)">Shall be deposited with the State Treasurer to the credit of the Fund; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">May be invested as provided by law.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Interest received on the investment of the excess funds shall be credited to the Fund for use for the purposes described in this subtitle.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
