<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gen" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="9-711" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gen-9-711</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">A municipal authority may issue bonds when and in the amounts needed to provide funds for all or part of a system's:<section prefix="(1)">Design;</section><section prefix="(2)">Construction;</section><section prefix="(3)">Extension;</section><section prefix="(4)">Alteration;</section><section prefix="(5)">Purchase; or</section><section prefix="(6)">Condemnation.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The bonds issued under this subtitle:<section prefix="(1)">May be issued without previous legislative authority;</section><section prefix="(2)">May be outstanding in addition to the total indebtedness otherwise permitted by law;</section><section prefix="(3)">May be of any type and denomination determined by the municipal authority, so long as no bonds mature later than 50 years from the date of issue;</section><section prefix="(4)">Shall be exempt forever from any State, county, or municipal taxation; and</section><section prefix="(5)">Shall be a lien on all property within the municipality that issues them.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Before issuing bonds under Part II of this subtitle, a municipal authority shall submit to a referendum of the voters of the municipality the question of whether to issue the bonds.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The referendum shall be held at:<section prefix="(i)">Any regular municipal election; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">A special municipal election, provided that the voters are given at least 20 days' notice of the election.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The referendum ballot shall include the words "for ... bonds" and "against ... bonds".</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">If a majority of the votes cast are "for ... bonds", the municipal authority may issue the bonds.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">If a majority of the votes cast are "against ... bonds", the municipal authority:<section prefix="(i)">May not issue the bonds; but</section><section prefix="(ii)">May submit the question at any later regular or special municipal election as provided under this section, until a majority of the votes cast is "for ... bonds".</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
