<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gen" order_by="" level="1">Environment</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gen-6-905.6</section_number>
  <catch_line>// EFFECTIVE UNTIL DECEMBER 31, 2017 PER CHAPTER 713 OF 2009 //...</catch_line>
  <order_by>905.6</order_by>
  <text>// EFFECTIVE UNTIL DECEMBER 31, 2017 PER CHAPTER 713 OF 2009 //<section prefix="(a)">A person that violates any provision of &#xA7; 6-905.4 or &#xA7;  6-905.5 of this subtitle, or any regulation adopted to implement the provisions of &#xA7; 6-905.4 or &#xA7; 6-905.5 of this subtitle, is guilty of a misdemeanor and on conviction is subject to:<section prefix="(1)">For a first offense, a fine not exceeding $1,000;</section><section prefix="(2)">For a second offense, a fine not exceeding $2,500; and</section><section prefix="(3)">For a third or subsequent offense, a fine not exceeding $5,000.</section></section><section prefix="(b)">A person that violates any provision of &#xA7; 6-905.4 or &#xA7;  6-905.5 of this subtitle, or any regulation adopted to implement the provisions of &#xA7; 6-905.4 or &#xA7; 6-905.5 of this subtitle, is liable for a civil penalty to be collected in a civil action in the circuit court for any county in the State not exceeding:<section prefix="(1)">$1,000 for a first offense;</section><section prefix="(2)">$2,500 for a second offense; or</section><section prefix="(3)">$5,000 for a third or subsequent offense.</section></section><section prefix="(c)"><section prefix="(1)">In addition to any other remedies available at law or in equity, after an opportunity for a hearing, the Department may impose a fine for each violation of &#xA7; 6-905.4 or &#xA7; 6-905.5 of this subtitle, or of any regulation adopted under &#xA7; 6-905.4 or &#xA7; 6-905.5 of this subtitle, not exceeding:<section prefix="(i)">$1,000 for a first offense;</section><section prefix="(ii)">$2,500 for a second offense; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">$5,000 for a third or subsequent offense.</section></section><section prefix="(2)">The Department shall consider the following in assessing the fine in paragraph (1) of this subsection:<section prefix="(i)">The willfulness of the violation;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The extent to which the violation was known, but uncorrected, by the violator;</section><section prefix="(iii)">The extent to which the violation resulted in actual harm to human health or the environment;</section><section prefix="(iv)">The nature and degree of injury to, or interference with, general welfare and health; and</section><section prefix="(v)">The extent to which the current violation is part of a pattern of the same or similar type of violation by the violator.</section></section></section><section prefix="(d)">Each day a violation continues is a separate offense under this section.</section><section prefix="(e)">Fines and penalties collected under this section shall be deposited in the State Recycling Trust Fund.</section></text>
</law>
