<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gen" order_by="" level="1">Environment</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gen-3-105</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>105</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in this section, this title does not limit the power of a political subdivision to adopt noise control ordinances, rules, or regulations.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A political subdivision may not adopt any noise control ordinance, rule, or regulation that is less stringent than the environmental noise standards, sound level limits, and noise control rules and regulations adopted under this title.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">A political subdivision may not adopt any noise control ordinance, rule, or regulation, including the environmental noise standards, sound level limits, and noise control rules and regulations adopted under this title, that prohibits trapshooting, skeetshooting, or other target shooting between the hours of 9 a.m. and 10 p.m. by a shooting sports club that is chartered and in operation as of January 1, 2001.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">This paragraph does not apply in Baltimore City or Allegany, Anne Arundel, Calvert, Charles, Garrett, Howard, Montgomery, St. Mary's, and Washington counties.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(4)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Except as provided in subparagraph (ii) of this paragraph, Allegany County, Anne Arundel County, Garrett County, Washington County, or a political subdivision of Allegany County, Anne Arundel County, Garrett County, or Washington County may not adopt any noise control ordinance, rule, or regulation, including the environmental noise standards, sound level limits, and noise control rules and regulations adopted under this title, that prohibits trapshooting, skeetshooting, or other target shooting between the hours of 9 a.m. and 10 p.m. by a shooting sports club that is chartered and in operation as of January 1, 2005.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">
          <section prefix="1.">Subject to the provisions of subsubparagraph 2 of this subparagraph, Allegany County, Anne Arundel County, Garrett County, Washington County, or a political subdivision of Allegany County, Anne Arundel County, Garrett County, or Washington County may adopt any noise control ordinance, rule, or regulation, including the environmental noise standards, sound level limits, and noise control rules and regulations adopted under this title, that prohibits trapshooting, skeetshooting, or other target shooting between the hours of 9 a.m. and 10 p.m. by a shooting sports club that the responsible political subdivision determines is not in compliance as of January 1, 2005 with environmental noise standards, sound level limits, or noise control rules or regulations adopted under this title.</section>
          <section prefix="2.">A noise control ordinance, rule, or regulation adopted under subsubparagraph 1 of this subparagraph shall allow trapshooting, skeetshooting, and other target shooting between the hours of 9 a.m. and 10 p.m. by a shooting sports club that the responsible political subdivision determines has become compliant with environmental noise standards, sound level limits, and noise control rules and regulations adopted under this title.</section>
        </section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(5)">Carroll County or a political subdivision of Carroll County may not enforce any noise control ordinance, rule, or regulation, including the environmental noise standards, sound level limits, and noise control rules and regulations adopted under this title, against a public school in Carroll County that violates the ordinance, rule, or regulation between the hours of 8 a.m. and 9:30 p.m.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Each political subdivision is encouraged to consider:<section prefix="(1)">Compliance with State or local noise standards before acting on any proposed variance requests or changes in zoning classifications; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Whether the permit or activity will be in compliance with local and State noise control standards, prior to the issuance of a building, activity permit, or similar authorizing document.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
