<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gen" order_by="" level="1">Environment</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gen-9-656</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>656</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">To pay the principal and interest on bonds issued under this subtitle, a sanitary commission may set reasonable benefit assessments and reasonable connection charges.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">In Allegany County, a sanitary commission may also set reasonable benefit assessments to pay the cost of capital improvements to a water or sewerage system.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Sanitary Commission of Worcester County may also set reasonable benefit assessments and reasonable connection charges to pay other costs on bonds issued under this subtitle.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">In Dorchester County, a sanitary commission may also set reasonable benefit assessments to pay the cost of capital improvements and repairs to a water or sewerage system.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except for Worcester County, a connection charge made under this section shall be equal at least to the cost of making the connection between a water system or sewerage system and the property served by that system.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">In Worcester County, a connection charge shall be equal at least to:<section prefix="(i)">The actual cost of making the connection between a water system or sewerage system and the property served by the system; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">The average cost of making a connection based on:<section prefix="1.">The diameter and the length of the connector; or</section><section prefix="2.">The diameter of the connector and the width of the way in which the water pipe or sewer pipe is laid.</section></section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">In the case of connectors constructed under &#xA7; 9-661 of this subtitle during construction of the water line or sewer line, the Sanitary Commission of Worcester County shall determine a connection charge under paragraph (2)(ii) of this subsection that is the same on each side of the way in which the line is laid.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Sanitary Commission may set benefit assessments on all property, improved or unimproved, that abuts a way in which a water main or sewer has been built.</section>
  </text>
</law>
