<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gen" order_by="gen" level="1">Environment</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gen-9-663</section_number>
  <catch_line>A sanitary commission:...</catch_line>
  <order_by>663</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">A sanitary commission:<section prefix="(1)">Shall control the use of water in its district; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Has jurisdiction over each fire hydrant connected to a system operated by the district.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">If a sanitary commission determines that there is a shortage of water or that the supply of water should be conserved, the sanitary commission may:<section prefix="(1)">Issue an order that requires the conservation of water; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Include in the order specific requirements for conserving water use.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The sanitary commission shall publish the order in a newspaper published in each member county covered by the order.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Each water user shall obey the order of the sanitary commission, effective with the earlier of:<section prefix="(1)">The first publication of the order; or</section><section prefix="(2)">Receipt of the order from the sanitary commission.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">Without notice, the sanitary commission may disconnect the water supply of any person who violates the order.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">To prevent waste of water, a representative of a sanitary commission at any reasonable time may enter any property connected to a system operated by the district and inspect the plumbing system on the property.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">On entering any property, the representative of the sanitary commission shall present appropriate credentials to the owner, operator, or agent in charge.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">After the inspection, the representative of the sanitary commission may order necessary changes to the plumbing system:<section prefix="(i)">To eliminate leaks;</section><section prefix="(ii)">To prevent water loss; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">To prevent unnecessary or improper use of sewers.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
