<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gen" order_by="" level="1">Environment</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gen-16-205</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>205</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Board may require as a condition to issuance of a wetlands license that compensation be made to the State, of a kind and in an amount deemed appropriate by the Board.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Board shall establish a compensation rate for cables, pipelines, or similar structures in accordance with this subsection.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The minimum compensation rate:<section prefix="(i)">Is $2.50 per linear foot per year for cables, pipelines, or similar structures;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Applies to each individual cable, pipeline, or similar structure; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Applies to all new and existing authorizations beginning July 2, 2012.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Board may:<section prefix="(i)">Increase the compensation rate as considered appropriate; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Adjust the compensation rate to reflect changes in the Consumer Price Index as published by the Bureau of Labor Statistics of the U.S. Department of Labor or by an appropriate method selected by the Board.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Monetary compensation received by the State in conjunction with a wetlands license may not be applied to the State Annuity Bond Fund Account.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">There is created a special fund, known as the Tidal Wetlands Compensation Fund.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The following money shall be deposited in the Tidal Wetlands Compensation Fund:<section prefix="(i)">Any monetary payment by a licensee in lieu of creating, restoring, or enhancing tidal wetlands that is required by the Department or the Board as a condition of a permit or license;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Any penalty imposed by a court in accordance with this title; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Any penalty imposed by the Department under this title.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">Funds in the Tidal Wetlands Compensation Fund may be appropriated only for the creation, restoration, or enhancement of tidal wetlands, including:<section prefix="(1)">Acquisition of land or easements;</section><section prefix="(2)">Maintenance of mitigation sites;</section><section prefix="(3)">Purchase of credits in mitigation banks;</section><section prefix="(4)">Management of invasive or nuisance species identified by the Department;</section><section prefix="(5)">Cost sharing assistance to landowners in the management and control of phragmites under Title 8, Subtitle 21 of the Natural Resources Article; and</section><section prefix="(6)">Contractual services necessary to accomplish the intent of this subsection.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">Funds credited and any interest accrued to the Fund:<section prefix="(1)">Shall remain available until expended; and</section><section prefix="(2)">May not revert to the General Fund under any other provision of law.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(g)">All monetary compensation paid to the State in conjunction with a wetlands license other than that specified under subsection (d)(2) of this section shall be deposited in the Wetlands and Waterways Program Fund established under &#xA7; 5-203.1 of this article.</section>
  </text>
</law>
