<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gen" order_by="" level="1">Environment</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gen-4-202.1</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>202.1</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, this section applies to a county or municipality that is subject to a national pollutant discharge elimination system Phase I municipal separate storm sewer system permit.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">This section does not apply to a county or municipality that, on or before July 1, 2012, has enacted and implemented a system of charges under &#xA7; 4-204 of this subtitle for the purpose of funding a watershed protection and restoration program, or similar program, in a manner consistent with the requirements of this section.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">On or before July 1, 2013, a county or municipality shall adopt and implement local laws or ordinances necessary to establish a watershed protection and restoration program.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A watershed protection and restoration program established under this section shall include:<section prefix="(1)">A stormwater remediation fee; and</section><section prefix="(2)">A local watershed protection and restoration fund.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A county or municipality shall maintain or administer a local watershed protection and restoration fund in accordance with this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The purpose of a local watershed protection and restoration fund is to provide financial assistance for the implementation of local stormwater management plans through stormwater management practices and stream and wetland restoration activities.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection and subsection (f) of this section, a county or municipality shall establish and annually collect a stormwater remediation fee from owners of property located within the county or municipality in accordance with this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Property owned by the State, a unit of State government, a county, a municipality, or a regularly organized volunteer fire department that is used for public purposes may not be charged a stormwater remediation fee under this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">A county or municipality shall set a stormwater remediation fee for property in an amount that is based on the share of stormwater management services related to the property and provided by the county or municipality.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">A county or municipality may set a stormwater remediation fee under this paragraph based on:<section prefix="1.">A flat rate;</section><section prefix="2.">An amount that is graduated, based on the amount of impervious surface on each property; or</section><section prefix="3.">Another method of calculation selected by the county or municipality.</section></section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(4)">A stormwater remediation fee established under this section is separate from any charges that a county or municipality establishes related to stormwater management for new developments under &#xA7; 4-204 of this subtitle, including fees for permitting, review of stormwater management plans, inspections, or monitoring.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A county or municipality shall establish policies and procedures, approved by the Department, to reduce any portion of a stormwater remediation fee established under subsection (e) of this section to account for on-site and off-site systems, facilities, services, or activities that reduce the quantity or improve the quality of stormwater discharged from the property.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The policies and procedures established by a county or municipality under paragraph (1) of this subsection shall include:<section prefix="(i)">Guidelines for determining which on-site systems, facilities, services, or activities may be the basis for a fee reduction, including guidelines:<section prefix="1.">Relating to properties with existing advanced stormwater best management practices;</section><section prefix="2.">Relating to agricultural activities or facilities that are otherwise exempted from stormwater management requirements by the county or municipality; and</section><section prefix="3.">That account for the costs of, and the level of treatment provided by, stormwater management facilities that are funded and maintained by a property owner;</section></section><section prefix="(ii)">The method for calculating the amount of a fee reduction; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Procedures for monitoring and verifying the effectiveness of the on-site systems, facilities, services, or activities in reducing the quantity or improving the quality of stormwater discharged from the property.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">For the purpose of monitoring and verifying the effectiveness of on-site systems, facilities, services, or activities under paragraph (2)(iii) of this subsection, a county or municipality may:<section prefix="(i)">Conduct on-site inspections;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Authorize a third party, certified by the Department, to conduct on-site inspections on behalf of the county or municipality; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">Require a property owner to hire a third party, certified by the Department, to conduct an on-site inspection and provide to the county or municipality the results of the inspection and any other information required by the county or municipality.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A property may not be assessed a stormwater remediation fee by both a county and a municipality.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Before a county may impose a stormwater remediation fee on a property located within a municipality, the county shall:<section prefix="1.">Notify the municipality of the county's intent to impose a stormwater remediation fee on property located within the municipality; and</section><section prefix="2.">Provide the municipality reasonable time to pass an ordinance authorizing the imposition of a municipal stormwater remediation fee instead of a county stormwater remediation fee.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">If a county currently imposes a stormwater remediation fee on property located within a municipality and the municipality decides to implement its own stormwater remediation fee under this section or &#xA7; 4-204 of this subtitle, the municipality shall:<section prefix="1.">Notify the county of the municipality's intent to impose its own stormwater remediation fee; and</section><section prefix="2.">Provide the county reasonable time to discontinue the collection of the county stormwater remediation fee within the municipality before the municipality's stormwater remediation fee becomes effective.</section></section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A county or municipality shall establish a procedure for a property owner to appeal a stormwater remediation fee imposed under this section.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(h)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A county or municipality shall determine the method, frequency, and enforcement of the collection of the stormwater remediation fee.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A county or municipality shall deposit the stormwater remediation fees it collects into its local watershed protection and restoration fund.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">There shall be deposited in a local watershed protection and restoration fund:<section prefix="(i)">Funds received from the stormwater remediation fee;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Interest or other income earned on the investment of money in the local watershed protection and restoration fund; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Any additional money made available from any sources for the purposes for which the local watershed protection and restoration fund has been established.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">Subject to paragraph (5) of this subsection, a county or municipality shall use the money in its local watershed protection and restoration fund for the following purposes only:<section prefix="(i)">Capital improvements for stormwater management, including stream and wetland restoration projects;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Operation and maintenance of stormwater management systems and facilities;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Public education and outreach relating to stormwater management or stream and wetland restoration;</section><section prefix="(iv)">Stormwater management planning, including:<section prefix="1.">Mapping and assessment of impervious surfaces; and</section><section prefix="2.">Monitoring, inspection, and enforcement activities to carry out the purposes of the watershed protection and restoration fund;</section></section><section prefix="(v)">To the extent that fees imposed under &#xA7; 4-204 of this subtitle are deposited into the local watershed protection and restoration fund, review of stormwater management plans and permit applications for new development;</section><section prefix="(vi)">Grants to nonprofit organizations for up to 100% of a project's costs for watershed restoration and rehabilitation projects relating to:<section prefix="1.">Planning, design, and construction of stormwater management practices;</section><section prefix="2.">Stream and wetland restoration; and</section><section prefix="3.">Public education and outreach related to stormwater management or stream and wetland restoration; and</section></section><section prefix="(vii)">Reasonable costs necessary to administer the local watershed protection and restoration fund.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(5)">A county or municipality may use its local watershed protection and restoration fund as an environmental fund, and may deposit to and expend from the fund additional money made available from other sources and dedicated to environmental uses, provided that the funds received from the stormwater remediation fee are expended only for the purposes authorized under paragraph (4) of this subsection.</section>
      <section prefix="(6)">The funds disbursed under this subsection are intended to be in addition to any existing State or local expenditures for stormwater management.</section>
      <section prefix="(7)">Money in a local watershed protection and restoration fund may not revert or be transferred to the general fund of any county or municipality.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(i)">Beginning July 1, 2014, and every 2 years thereafter, a county or municipality shall make publicly available a report on:<section prefix="(1)">The number of properties subject to a stormwater remediation fee;</section><section prefix="(2)">The amount of money deposited into the watershed protection and restoration fund over the previous 2 fiscal years; and</section><section prefix="(3)">The percentage of funds in the local watershed protection and restoration fund spent on each of the purposes provided in subsection (h)(4) of this section.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(j)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A county or municipality shall establish a program to exempt from the requirements of this section a property able to demonstrate substantial financial hardship as a result of the stormwater remediation fee.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A county or municipality may establish a separate hardship exemption program or include a hardship exemption as part of a system of offsets established under subsection (f)(1) of this section.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(k)">The Department may adopt regulations to implement and enforce this section.</section>
  </text>
</law>
