<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gen" order_by="gen" level="1">Environment</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gen-9-950</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this section, "abutting lot" means a parcel of land:...</catch_line>
  <order_by>950</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, "abutting lot" means a parcel of land:<section prefix="(1)">That abuts on a street or other public way that contains a sanitary sewer that is part of, is served by, or may be served by the sewerage system of an authority; and</section><section prefix="(2)">On which a building has been constructed for residential, commercial, or industrial use.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Except as provided in subsection (c) of this section, when an authority acquires or constructs a sewerage system under this subtitle, the authority, by rule, regulation, or resolution, may require each owner of an abutting lot to:<section prefix="(1)">Connect with the sewerage system of the authority each building that is constructed for residential, commercial, or industrial use on the abutting lot; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Stop using any other method for the disposal of sewage or other polluting matter.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The authority may not require the owner of an abutting lot to connect any building on the abutting lot if the abutting lot is served by a facility for the disposal of sewage or other polluting matter that was constructed and is operated in accordance with standards set or approved by the Secretary.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Whenever this section requires a person to connect a building to the sewerage system of an authority, the person shall make the connection in accordance with the rules and regulations of the authority.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The rules and regulations of an authority may set a reasonable charge for making a connection under this section.</section>
  </text>
</law>
