<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gen" order_by="gen" level="1">Environment</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gen-8-101</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this title the following words have the meanings indicated....</catch_line>
  <order_by>101</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this title the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Board" means the Radiation Control Advisory Board.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Emergency" means a sudden and unforeseen condition of such public gravity and urgency that it requires immediate response to protect the public health and welfare.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">"General license" means a license that, under the rules and regulations adopted by the Department under this title, is effective without the filing of an application by the licensee.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"Person" includes any public or municipal corporation and any agency, bureau, department, or instrumentality of State or local government and, to the extent authorized by federal law, federal government.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">"Radiation" means:<section prefix="(1)">Ionizing radiation, including gamma rays, X-rays, alpha particles, beta particles, neutrons, high speed electrons, high speed protons, and any other atomic or nuclear particles or rays;</section><section prefix="(2)">Any electromagnetic radiation that can be generated during the operation of a manufactured device that has an electronic circuit; or</section><section prefix="(3)">Any sonic, ultrasonic, or infrasonic waves that are emitted as a result of the operation, in a manufactured device, of an electronic circuit that can generate a physical field of radiation.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(g)">"Specific license" means a license that, under the rules and regulations adopted by the Department under this title, is effective only after the applicant files an application and the Department approves the application.</section>
  </text>
</law>
