<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gen" order_by="gen" level="1">Environment</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gen-2-605</section_number>
  <catch_line>The Department shall give notice of and hold any hearing held under &#xA7; 2-603 or &#xA7; 2-604 of this sub...</catch_line>
  <order_by>605</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Department shall give notice of and hold any hearing held under &#xA7; 2-603 or &#xA7; 2-604 of this subtitle in accordance with the Administrative Procedure Act and the requirements of this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Before the hearing, the person charged, on request, shall be given an opportunity to examine all information and reports that relate to the alleged offense.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The person charged may be represented at the hearing by counsel.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A person may withhold information about secret processes or methods of manufacture or production from any public hearing under this subtitle, and the Department and its personnel shall keep confidential any such information that it requires, ascertains, or discovers.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">Testimony taken at the hearing shall be under oath and recorded.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">Copies of the transcript and of any other record of the hearing shall be provided to the person charged at that person's request and expense.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Secretary or a designee of the Secretary may issue subpoenas for any person or evidence and administer oaths in connection with any proceeding under this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">At the request and the expense of the person charged, the Secretary or a designee of the Secretary shall subpoena any person or evidence on behalf of the person charged.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">If a person fails to comply with a notice of hearing or a subpoena issued under this section, the circuit court for the county where the person charged resides, on petition of the Secretary, may:<section prefix="(i)">Compel obedience to the notice or subpoena; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">Compel testimony or the production of evidence.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
