<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gen" order_by="gen" level="1">Environment</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gen-13-306</section_number>
  <catch_line>The Board shall issue an appropriate license to any applicant who:...</catch_line>
  <order_by>306</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Board shall issue an appropriate license to any applicant who:<section prefix="(1)">Meets the requirements of this title;</section><section prefix="(2)">Pays the required fee; and</section><section prefix="(3)">Provides evidence of any performance bond and contractor's liability insurance that the Board may require.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In accordance with its rules and regulations, the Board shall issue well driller licenses and restricted licenses.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">There are 3 categories of well driller licenses:<section prefix="1.">Well driller general;</section><section prefix="2.">Well driller-geotechnical; and</section><section prefix="3.">Well driller-water supply.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">A well driller license may be limited to the drilling of wells for particular purposes.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">There are 3 categories of restricted licenses:<section prefix="(i)">Water conditioner installer;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Water pump installer; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Well rig operator.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">There is a master class license and a journeyman class license in each category of well driller license.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">There is an apprentice class well driller license which shall serve as:<section prefix="(i)">The apprentice license for all categories of well driller licenses; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">The apprentice license for the well rig operator category of restricted license.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">There is an apprentice class license in the following restricted license categories:<section prefix="(i)">Water conditioner installer; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Water pump installer.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The Board shall designate on each license issued the category and, where applicable, the class of the license.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Until July 1, 1993, this title does not prohibit any master well driller licensed by the Board on July 1, 1990 from practicing well drilling while obtaining the education and experience required to be licensed under any one of the 3 categories of well driller licenses in this title.<section prefix="(1)">The Board may waive the examination requirement of this title for any master well driller licensed by the Board on July 1, 1990 who provides to the Board satisfactory evidence that the licensee has:<section prefix="(i)">Well driller-geotechnical - installed geotechnical wells during the past 7 years and obtained national certification as a monitoring well driller or completed a 40-hour training program dealing with hazardous waste or monitoring site operations required by the Occupational Safety and Health Administration;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Well driller-water supply - installed 20 water supply wells during the past 7 years and acquired 10 of the 20 hours of continuing education required by &#xA7; 13-308 of this subtitle in water conditioning and water pump technology; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">Well driller-general - fulfilled the requirements of subparagraphs (i) and (ii) of this paragraph.</section></section><section prefix="(2)">The Board shall adopt regulations to implement the provisions of this section.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
