<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gen" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="4-401" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gen-4-401</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Cleanup" means abatement, containment, removal, and disposal of oil and the restoration of the environment to its existing state prior to a discharge.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Damages" means any damages for which liability exists under the laws of this State resulting from, arising out of, or related to the discharge or threatened discharge of oil.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">In addition, "damages" includes:<section prefix="(i)">The cost of assessing the damages;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Damages for injury to, destruction of, loss of, or loss of use of natural resources, including the reasonable costs of assessing the damage;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Damages for injury to or economic losses resulting from the destruction of real or personal property that shall be recoverable by a claimant who owns or leases that property;</section><section prefix="(iv)">Damages for loss of subsistence use of natural resources, that shall be recoverable by any claimant who so uses natural resources that have been injured, destroyed, or lost, without regard to the ownership or management of the resources;</section><section prefix="(v)">Damages equal to the net loss of taxes, royalties, rents, fees, or net profit shares due to the injury, destruction, or loss of real property, personal property, or natural resources, that shall be recoverable by the State or a political subdivision of the State;</section><section prefix="(vi)">Damages equal to the loss of profits or impairment of earning capacity due to the injury, destruction, or loss of real property, personal property, or natural resources, that shall be recoverable by any claimant; and</section><section prefix="(vii)">Damages for net costs of providing increased or additional public services during or after removal activities, including protection from fire, safety, or health hazards caused by a discharge of oil, that shall be recoverable by the State or a political subdivision of the State.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">"Discharge" means the addition, introduction, leaking, spilling, or emitting any oil to State waters or the placing of any oil in a location where it is likely to reach State waters.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"Heating oil tank" means an aboveground or underground tank for the storage of heating oil for use as a fuel in heating a residential property.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">"Lender" means a person who is:<section prefix="(1)">A holder of a mortgage or deed of trust on a site or a security interest in property located on a site; or</section><section prefix="(2)">A holder of a mortgage or deed of trust who acquires title through foreclosure or deed in lieu of foreclosure.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Management" means directing or controlling operations at a site or facility related to the storage or discharge of oil.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Management" does not include rendering advice on financial matters, rendering financial assistance, or actions taken to protect or secure a site or facility or property located on the site or at the facility, if the advice, assistance, or actions do not involve the storage, disposal, or remediation of discharged oil.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(h)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Oil" means oil of any kind and in any liquid form including:<section prefix="(i)">Petroleum;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Petroleum by-products;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Fuel oil;</section><section prefix="(iv)">Sludge containing oil or oil residues;</section><section prefix="(v)">Oil refuse;</section><section prefix="(vi)">Oil mixed with or added to or otherwise contaminating soil, waste, or any other liquid or solid media;</section><section prefix="(vii)">Crude oils;</section><section prefix="(viii)">Aviation fuel;</section><section prefix="(ix)">Gasoline;</section><section prefix="(x)">Kerosene;</section><section prefix="(xi)">Light and heavy fuel oils;</section><section prefix="(xii)">Diesel motor fuel, including biodiesel fuel, regardless of whether the fuel is petroleum based;</section><section prefix="(xiii)">Asphalt;</section><section prefix="(xiv)">Ethanol that is intended to be used as a motor fuel or fuel source; and</section><section prefix="(xv)">Regardless of specific gravity, every other nonedible, nonsubstituted liquid petroleum fraction unless that fraction is specifically identified as a hazardous substance under the Comprehensive Environmental Response, Compensation, and Liability Act of 1980, 42 U.S.C. &#xA7; 9601 et seq.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Oil" does not include:<section prefix="(i)">Liquefied propane;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Liquefied natural gas; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">Any edible oils.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(i)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Oil storage facility" means any installation, structure or premises, aboveground or underground, in which oil is stored.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Oil storage facility" does not include any tank on a farm or private residence with a capacity to store 1,100 gallons or less of motor fuel or heating oil for noncommercial or personal use or any vessel.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(j)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Person responsible for the discharge" includes:<section prefix="(i)">The owner of the discharged oil;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The owner, operator, or person in charge of the oil storage facility, vessel, barge, or vehicle involved in the discharge at the time of or immediately before the discharge; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Any other person who through act or omission causes the discharge.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Person responsible for the discharge" does not include:<section prefix="(i)">A person who, without participating in the management of an underground oil storage tank, and who otherwise is not engaged in petroleum production, refining, or marketing, holds indicia of ownership in an underground oil storage tank primarily to protect its security interest in that underground oil storage tank if that person:</section><section prefix="(ii)">A holder of a mortgage or deed of trust who acquires title to a property that is subject to a corrective action plan approved by the Department under this subtitle provided that the holder complies with the requirements, prohibitions, and conditions of the plan;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Subject to paragraph (3) of this subsection, a lender who extends credit for the performance of removal or remedial actions conducted in accordance with requirements imposed under this title who:</section><section prefix="(iv)">Subject to paragraph (3) of this subsection, a lender who takes action to protect or preserve a mortgage or deed of trust on a site or a security interest in property located on a site at which a discharge of oil has occurred, by stabilizing, containing, removing, or preventing the discharge of oil in a manner that does not cause or contribute to a discharge of oil if:</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A lender taking action to protect or preserve a mortgage or deed of trust or security interest in property located on a site, who causes or contributes to a discharge of oil shall be liable solely for costs incurred in response to the discharge which the lender caused or to which the lender contributed unless the lender was a person responsible for the discharge before acquiring a mortgage, deed of trust, or security interest in the site or property located on the site.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(k)">"Removal costs" means the costs of removal that are incurred after a discharge of oil has occurred or, in any case where there is a substantial threat of a discharge of oil, the costs to prevent, minimize, or mitigate oil pollution from such an incident.</section>
    <section prefix="(l)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Underground oil storage tank" means one or more tanks including underground pipes connected to tanks, with a volume of 10 percent or more beneath the surface of the ground.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Underground oil storage tank" does not include a:<section prefix="(i)">Tank on a farm or private residence with a capacity to store 1,100 gallons or less of motor fuel or heating oil for noncommercial or personal use;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Septic tank;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Pipeline facility, including gathering lines, regulated under 49 U.S.C. 60101, et seq.;</section><section prefix="(iv)">Intrastate pipeline facility regulated under State laws comparable to the provisions of the law referred to in subparagraph (iii) of this paragraph;</section><section prefix="(v)">Surface impoundment, pit, pond, or lagoon;</section><section prefix="(vi)">Stormwater or wastewater collection system;</section><section prefix="(vii)">Flow-through process tank;</section><section prefix="(viii)">Storage tank situated in an underground area, such as a basement, cellar, mineworking, drift, shaft, or tunnel if the storage tank is situated upon or above the surface of the floor; or</section><section prefix="(ix)">Pipe connected to any tank described in subparagraphs (i) through (viii) of this paragraph.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
