<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gen" order_by="" level="1">Environment</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gen-15-204</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>204</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">There is a Land Reclamation Committee. It consists of the following 13 members:<section prefix="(i)">Two members of the Department, including a chairman of the Committee appointed by the Secretary;</section><section prefix="(ii)">A representative of the soil conservation district of Allegany County;</section><section prefix="(iii)">A representative of the soil conservation district of Garrett County;</section><section prefix="(iv)">Two members appointed by the Governor with the advice and consent of the Senate for 3-year terms to represent the mining industry;</section><section prefix="(v)">One member who is a representative of Allegany County to be appointed by the Governor, on the recommendation of the Allegany County Commissioners, with the advice and consent of the Senate to represent the local government for a 3-year term;</section><section prefix="(vi)">One member who is a representative of Garrett County to be appointed by the Governor, on the recommendation of the Garrett County Commissioners, with the advice and consent of the House of Delegates to represent local government for a 3-year term;</section><section prefix="(vii)">Two members from the community who do not have any interests in any mining operation, one to be a resident of Garrett County and one to be a resident of Allegany County, appointed by the Secretary for 3-year terms; and</section><section prefix="(viii)">Three members of the Department of Natural Resources appointed by the Secretary of Natural Resources.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Committee members representing the community or local government shall receive the per diem set by the Secretary for each day they meet with the Committee or are called on by the chairman to transact other business of the Committee. Funds for the per diem allowances shall be provided for in the budget of the Department.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Committee shall meet at the chairman's request and at least twice a year. A quorum consists of at least 9 members. No action may be approved by the Committee unless a quorum is present and a majority of those present approves the action.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">Members of the Land Reclamation Committee shall file a United States Department of the Interior State Employee Statement of Employment and Financial Interests.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">Committee members shall recuse themselves from proceedings that may affect their direct or indirect financial interests.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Committee may:<section prefix="(1)">Study and recommend surface coal mine reclamation policies, practices, and standards;</section><section prefix="(2)">From time to time, review the surface coal mining laws, regulations, and policies for the purpose of recommending changes to improve the efficiency and effectiveness of the program;</section><section prefix="(3)">Review proposed changes to the surface coal mining laws and regulations to provide comments to the General Assembly and the Department;</section><section prefix="(4)">Review the Department's administration of the surface coal mining regulatory program and the abandoned coal mine reclamation program to determine compliance with the purpose of the subtitles;</section><section prefix="(5)">Enter on any surface coal mining operation to determine mining and reclamation conditions; and</section><section prefix="(6)">Recommend research, demonstration, and cost-sharing projects to promote optimum revegetation of surface coal mined lands.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
