<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gen" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="6-810" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gen-6-810</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Commission shall study and collect information on the:<section prefix="(1)">Effectiveness of this subtitle in:<section prefix="(i)">Protecting children from lead poisoning; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Lessening risks to responsible owners;</section></section><section prefix="(2)">Effectiveness of the treatments specified in &#xA7;&#xA7; 6-815 and 6-819 of this subtitle, including recommendations for changes to those treatments;</section><section prefix="(3)">Availability of third-party bodily injury liability insurance and premises liability insurance for affected property, including waivers of lead hazard exclusion and coverage for qualified offers made under Part V of this subtitle;</section><section prefix="(4)">Ability of State and local officials to respond to lead poisoning cases;</section><section prefix="(5)">Availability of affordable housing;</section><section prefix="(6)">Adequacy of the qualified offer caps; and</section><section prefix="(7)">Need to expand the scope of this subtitle to other property serving persons at risk, including child care centers, family child care homes, and preschool facilities.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Commission may appoint a subcommittee or subcommittees to study the following subjects relating to lead and lead poisoning:<section prefix="(1)">Medical referral;</section><section prefix="(2)">Regulation and compliance;</section><section prefix="(3)">Worker education;</section><section prefix="(4)">Social services;</section><section prefix="(5)">Educational services;</section><section prefix="(6)">Legal aspects;</section><section prefix="(7)">Employer services;</section><section prefix="(8)">Abatement of lead sources;</section><section prefix="(9)">Financial subsidies and other encouragement and support for the abatement of the causes of lead poisoning;</section><section prefix="(10)">Laboratory services; and</section><section prefix="(11)">Other subjects that the Commission considers necessary.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Commission shall review the implementation and operation of this subtitle and, on or before January 1 of each year, starting in 1996, submit a report to the Governor and, subject to the provisions of &#xA7; 2-1246 of the State Government Article, the General Assembly on the results of the review, and the Commission's recommendations concerning this subtitle, other lead poisoning issues, and the need for further action that the Commission determines to be necessary.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Department shall consult with the Commission on establishing the optional lead-contaminated dust testing standards under &#xA7; 6-816 of this subtitle and in developing regulations to implement this subtitle.</section>
  </text>
</law>
