<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gen" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="9-655" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gen-9-655</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">After the hearing processes required in &#xA7; 9-648 or &#xA7; 9-649 of this subtitle are complete, a sanitary district may begin construction on a project that has been approved under either of those sections.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The sanitary commission shall follow the bid solicitation procedure of this section for any construction work on the project, unless the cost will be $5,000 or less.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The sanitary commission may solicit bids for all or part of the project for which bids are sought.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Whenever the sanitary commission solicits bids under this section for construction contracts, the sanitary commission shall advertise the solicitation in each member county in at least 1 newspaper of general circulation in the county.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">In addition to the advertising required by subsection (d) of this section, the sanitary commission may advertise the solicitation in other newspapers or technical journals.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">If the sanitary commission awards a contract in response to bids received under this section, the sanitary commission shall award the contract to the lowest responsible bidder.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">If the sanitary commission determines that the prices quoted in any bid are unreasonable or unbalanced, it may reject the bid.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">If the sanitary commission rejects all the bids, the sanitary commission may:<section prefix="(1)">Readvertise; or</section><section prefix="(2)">Do the project or any part of it with its own temporary or permanent employees.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(i)">The sanitary commission may include in the contract additional conditions and requirements for:<section prefix="(1)">Performance bonds;</section><section prefix="(2)">Penalties; and</section><section prefix="(3)">Liquidated damages.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
