<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gen" order_by="gen" level="1">Environment</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gen-9-1701</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated....</catch_line>
  <order_by>1701</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Compost" means the product of composting in accordance with the standards established by the Secretary of Agriculture under &#xA7; 6-221 of the Agriculture Article.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Composting" means the controlled biological decomposition of organic waste material in accordance with the standards established by the Secretary under this title.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Computer" means a desktop personal computer or laptop computer, including the computer monitor.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Computer" does not include:<section prefix="(i)">A personal digital assistant device;</section><section prefix="(ii)">A computer peripheral device, including:<section prefix="1.">A mouse or other similar pointing device;</section><section prefix="2.">A printer; or</section><section prefix="3.">A detachable keyboard.</section></section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Covered electronic device" means a computer or video display device with a screen that is greater than 4 inches measured diagonally.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Covered electronic device" does not include a video display device that is part of a motor vehicle or that is contained within a household appliance or commercial, industrial, or medical equipment.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">"Covered electronic device takeback program" means a program, established by a covered electronic device manufacturer or a group of covered electronic device manufacturers, for the collection and recycling, refurbishing, or reuse of a covered electronic device labeled with the name of the manufacturer or the manufacturer's brand label, including:<section prefix="(1)">Providing, at no cost to the returner, a method of returning a covered electronic device to the manufacturer, including postage paid mailing packages or designated collection points throughout the State;</section><section prefix="(2)">Contracting with a recycler, local government, other manufacturer, or any other person; or</section><section prefix="(3)">Any other program approved by the Department.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(g)">"Director" means the Director of the Office of Recycling.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">"Manufacturer" means a person that is the brand owner of a covered electronic device sold or offered for sale in the State, by any means, including transactions conducted through sales outlets, catalogs, or the Internet.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Natural wood waste" means tree and other natural vegetative refuse.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Natural wood waste" includes tree stumps, brush and limbs, root mats, logs, and other natural vegetative material.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(j)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Natural wood waste recycling facility" means a facility where recycling services for natural wood waste are provided.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Natural wood waste recycling facility" does not include a collection or processing facility operated by:<section prefix="(i)">A nonprofit or governmental organization located in the State; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">A single individual or business that provides recycling services for its own employees or for its own recyclable materials generated on its own premises.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(k)">"Office" means the Office of Recycling within the Department.</section>
    <section prefix="(l)">"Recyclable materials" means those materials that:<section prefix="(1)">Would otherwise become solid waste for disposal in a refuse disposal system; and</section><section prefix="(2)">May be collected, separated, or processed and returned to the marketplace in the form of raw materials or products.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(m)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Recycling" means any process in which materials that would otherwise become solid waste are collected, separated, or processed and returned to the marketplace in the form of raw materials or products.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Recycling" includes composting.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(n)">"Recycling services" means the services provided by persons engaged in the business of recycling, including the collection, processing, storage, purchase, sale, or disposition of recyclable materials.</section>
    <section prefix="(o)">"Resource recovery facility" means a facility in existence as of January 1, 1988 that:<section prefix="(1)">Processes solid waste to produce valuable resources, including steam, electricity, metals, or refuse-derived fuel; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Achieves a volume reduction of at least 50 percent of its solid waste stream.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(p)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Solid waste stream" means garbage or refuse that would, unless recycled, be disposed of in a refuse disposal system located in this State.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Solid waste stream" does not include:<section prefix="(i)">Hospital waste;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Rubble;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Scrap material;</section><section prefix="(iv)">Land clearing debris;</section><section prefix="(v)">Sewage sludge; or</section><section prefix="(vi)">Waste generated by a single individual or business and disposed of in a facility dedicated solely for that entity's waste.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(q)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Video display device" means an electronic device with an output surface that displays or is capable of displaying moving graphical images or visual representations of image sequences or pictures that show a number of quickly changing images on a screen to create the illusion of motion.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Video display device" includes a device that is an integral part of the display and cannot easily be removed from the display by the consumer and that produces the moving image on the screen.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A video display device may use a cathode-ray tube (CRT), liquid crystal display (LCD), gas plasma, digital light processing, or other image-projection technology.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(r)">"White goods" includes:<section prefix="(1)">Refrigerators;</section><section prefix="(2)">Stoves;</section><section prefix="(3)">Washing machines;</section><section prefix="(4)">Dryers;</section><section prefix="(5)">Water heaters; and</section><section prefix="(6)">Air conditioners.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(s)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Yard waste" means organic plant waste derived from gardening, landscaping, and tree trimming activities.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Yard waste" includes leaves, garden waste, lawn cuttings, weeds, and prunings.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
