<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gen" order_by="" level="1">Environment</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gen-6-1304</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>1304</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">A United States manufacturer, or if the manufacturer is not a United States manufacturer, the importer of record, of a children's product for which a children's product certification is required under federal law shall:<section prefix="(1)">Test whether the children's product is a lead-containing product by using a testing entity qualified or certified under federal law; and</section><section prefix="(2)">If the children's product tested under item (1) of this subsection is not a lead-containing product, issue a certificate that certifies that the children's product is not a lead-containing product.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A person shall ensure that the certificate issued in accordance with subsection (a) of this section is transmitted with the children's product to any distributor or retailer who receives the children's product.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A manufacturer shall:<section prefix="(1)">Maintain a copy of any documents related to lead testing and any certificate issued in accordance with subsection (a) of this section; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Provide a copy to the Department or any person on request.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A retailer shall:<section prefix="(1)">Maintain a copy of any certificate issued in accordance with subsection (a) of this section; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Provide a copy to the Department or any person on request.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, a person may not sell or offer for sale in the State, by any means, including transactions conducted through a sales outlet, a catalog, or the Internet, a children's product for which there is no certificate issued in accordance with subsection (a) of this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Notwithstanding any other provision of this subtitle, a certificate is not required for the sale of a used children's product at a thrift store, consignment store, yard sale, or any other secondhand point of sale.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">A certificate issued in accordance with subsection (a) of this section shall be:<section prefix="(1)">Based on a test of each children's product or on a testing protocol that is established or recognized by the Department; and</section><section prefix="(2)">On a form created or approved by the Department.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
