<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gen" order_by="gen" level="1">Environment</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gen-9-679</section_number>
  <catch_line>In accordance with the rules and regulations that the Dorchester County Commissioners approve:...</catch_line>
  <order_by>679</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In accordance with the rules and regulations that the Dorchester County Commissioners approve:<section prefix="(1)">The Sanitary Commission shall make benefit assessments on the property in a shared facility area in an amount that is enough to:<section prefix="(i)">Pay the principal and interest on each bond issued and any other obligation incurred by the Sanitary Commission in constructing the shared facility; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Pay any other costs incurred in building the shared facility; and</section></section><section prefix="(2)">The Sanitary Commission may establish reasonable charges on each parcel in the shared facility area.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Sanitary Commission shall give to the owner of each parcel in the shared facility area written notice of:<section prefix="(i)">The class and subclass of the parcel;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The benefit assessment for the parcel; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">The time and place of the hearing to which the owner is entitled under this section.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Sanitary Commission shall mail the notice to the owner at the last known address of the owner on the Dorchester County tax assessment records.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Sanitary Commission shall give each property owner an opportunity for a hearing before the Sanitary Commission.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">After the hearing, the Sanitary Commission may adjust the classification or benefit assessment as appropriate.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The Sanitary Commission shall make the levy of each benefit assessment the Sanitary Commission determines under this section so that the levy is effective for the July 1 that follows the first March 31 that occurs on or after the date:<section prefix="(1)">Construction is completed on the shared facility; or</section><section prefix="(2)">The shared facility is acquired.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">While unpaid, benefit assessments and other charges are a lien on the parcel for which made.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">The lien granted by this subsection is subordinate only to State taxes and municipal taxes.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">
      <section prefix="(1)">As to each lien that arises against a parcel in the shared facility area, the Sanitary Commission shall keep a public record that:<section prefix="(i)">Identifies the owners of the parcel;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Describes the parcel and gives any lot number of record that applies to the parcel; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Shows the amount of the lien.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Sanitary Commission shall file the record of liens with the Clerk of the Circuit Court for Dorchester County, for filing among the land records for Dorchester County.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The record of liens shall be legal notice of all existing liens in the shared facility area.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(i)">
      <section prefix="(1)">To enforce the collection of unpaid benefit assessments or other charges that are at least 60 days overdue, the Sanitary Commission, at any time, may:<section prefix="(i)">Sue any person who was an owner of record of the parcel at any time since the benefit assessment was last paid; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">File a bill in equity to enforce a lien through a decree of sale of property against any person who was an owner of record of the parcel at any time since the benefit assessment was last paid.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">When recorded, the lien shall be legal notice to any person who has any interest in a parcel.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
