<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gen" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="12-101" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gen-12-101</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this title the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Board" means the State Board of Waterworks and Waste Systems Operators.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Certificate" means, unless the context requires otherwise, a certificate of certification as an operator, industrial operator, or superintendent, issued by the Board.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Certificate" includes:<section prefix="(i)">A certificate; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">A temporary certificate, as limited by &#xA7; 12-305 of this title.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">"Certified industrial operator" means, unless the context requires otherwise, an industrial operator who is certified by the Board.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"Certified operator" means, unless the context requires otherwise, an operator who is certified by the Board.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">"Certified superintendent" means, unless the context requires otherwise, a superintendent who is certified by the Board.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Industrial operator" means an individual who operates the controls or maintains the logs of an industrial wastewater works.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Industrial operator" does not include a superintendent.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(h)">"Industrial wastewater works" means a facility used to collect, store, pump, treat, or discharge any waste substance that results from:<section prefix="(1)">A manufacturing process;</section><section prefix="(2)">A business process; or</section><section prefix="(3)">The development of a natural resource.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(i)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Operator" means an individual who participates in the operation of:<section prefix="(i)">A waterworks, including the control of the flow, processing, and distribution of water; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">A wastewater works, including the collection, control of flow, processing, and discharge of wastewater and effluent.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Operator" does not include a superintendent.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(j)">"Responsible charge" means responsibility for the operation and performance of all or any part of a waterworks, wastewater works, or industrial wastewater works.</section>
    <section prefix="(k)">"Superintendent" means an individual who is designated by any employing or appointing person, county, municipality, sanitary district, or this State as the individual in responsible charge of a waterworks, wastewater works, or industrial wastewater works.</section>
    <section prefix="(l)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Wastewater works" means a facility used to collect, store, pump, treat, or discharge any liquid or waterborne waste.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Wastewater works" does not include:<section prefix="(i)">A facility that is used only by a private residence;</section><section prefix="(ii)">A facility that uses a septic tank or subsoil absorption; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">An industrial wastewater works.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(m)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Waterworks" means a facility used to collect, store, pump, treat, or distribute water for human consumption.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Waterworks" does not include a facility that is used only by a private residence.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
