<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gen" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="1-701" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gen-1-701</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, "environmental justice" means equal protection from environmental and public health hazards for all people regardless of race, income, culture, and social status.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">There is a Commission on Environmental Justice and Sustainable Communities.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Commission consists of the following 20 members:<section prefix="(i)">One member of the Senate of Maryland, appointed by the President of the Senate;</section><section prefix="(ii)">One member of the House of Delegates, appointed by the Speaker of the House;</section><section prefix="(iii)">The Secretary, or the Secretary's designee;</section><section prefix="(iv)">The Secretary of Health and Mental Hygiene, or the Secretary's designee;</section><section prefix="(v)">The Secretary of Planning, or the Secretary's designee;</section><section prefix="(vi)">The Secretary of Business and Economic Development, or the Secretary's designee;</section><section prefix="(vii)">The Secretary of Housing and Community Development, or the Secretary's designee;</section><section prefix="(viii)">The Secretary of Transportation, or the Secretary's designee; and</section><section prefix="(ix)">Twelve members appointed by the Governor who represent the following interests:</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Of the twelve members appointed by the Governor under paragraph (1)(ix) of this subsection, at least two members shall represent affected communities concerned with environmental justice.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The term of a member appointed by the Governor is 3 years.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">At the end of a term, a member continues to serve until a successor is appointed and qualifies.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A member who is appointed after a term has begun serves only for the rest of the term and until a successor is appointed and qualifies.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">A member may not be appointed to more than two consecutive terms.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The Governor shall designate the chairman of the Commission.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The Department shall provide staff for the Commission.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Commission shall meet at the times and places that the chairman determines.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A majority of members of the Commission shall constitute a quorum for the transaction of business.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A member of the Commission:<section prefix="(i)">May not receive compensation as a member of the Commission; but</section><section prefix="(ii)">Is entitled to reimbursement for expenses under the Standard State Travel Regulations, as provided in the State budget.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(h)">The Commission shall:<section prefix="(1)">Advise State government agencies on environmental justice and related community issues;</section><section prefix="(2)">Review and analyze the impact of current State laws and policies on the issue of environmental justice and sustainable communities;</section><section prefix="(3)">Assess the adequacy of State and local government laws to address the issue of environmental justice and sustainable communities;</section><section prefix="(4)">Coordinate with the Children's Environmental Health and Protection Advisory Council on recommendations related to environmental justice and sustainable communities;</section><section prefix="(5)">Develop criteria to assess whether communities in the State may be experiencing environmental justice issues; and</section><section prefix="(6)">Recommend options to the Governor for addressing issues, concerns, or problems related to environmental justice that surface after reviewing State laws and policies, including prioritizing areas of the State that need immediate attention.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(i)">On or before October 1 of each year, the Commission shall report its findings and recommendations to the Governor and, subject to &#xA7; 2-1246 of the State Government Article, the General Assembly.</section>
  </text>
</law>
