<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gen" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="15-810" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gen-15-810</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Department shall approve and grant or deny the permit requested as expeditiously as possible, but not later than 30 days after the application forms or any supplemental information required are filed with the Department. The Department shall process the permit application concurrently with any local or county land use and zoning reviews.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Department may deny the permit on finding that:<section prefix="(1)">Any requirement of this subtitle or any rule or regulation adopted under it will be violated by the proposed operation;</section><section prefix="(2)">The operation will have an unduly adverse effect on wildlife or fresh water, estuarine, or marine fisheries;</section><section prefix="(3)">The applicant has failed to provide applicable permits or approvals covering the operation from all State and local regulatory agencies responsible for air and water pollution and sediment control;</section><section prefix="(4)">The operation will constitute a substantial physical hazard to a neighboring dwelling house, school, church, hospital, commercial or industrial building, public road, or other public or private property in existence at the time of application for the permit;</section><section prefix="(5)">The operation will have a significantly adverse effect on the uses of a publicly owned park, forest, or recreation area in existence at the time of application for the permit;</section><section prefix="(6)">The applicant does not possess a valid surface mining license from the State;</section><section prefix="(7)">The applicant has not corrected all violations which he may have committed under any prior permit and which resulted in:<section prefix="(i)">Revocation of his permit;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Termination of the operation by order of the Department;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Forfeiture of part or all of his bond or other security;</section><section prefix="(iv)">Conviction of a misdemeanor under &#xA7;&#xA7; 15-807(f) and 15-808(k) of this subtitle; or</section><section prefix="(v)">Any other court order issued against the applicant as a result of departmental action; or</section></section><section prefix="(8)">Previous experience with similar operations indicates a substantial probability that the operation will result in substantial deposits of sediment in stream beds or lakes, landslides, or other water pollution.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Department may not issue the permit until the appropriate county has:<section prefix="(1)">Completed its review of the proposed land use; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Provided the Department with a written statement that states that the proposed land use conforms with all applicable county zoning and land use requirements.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">In the absence of any of these findings, a permit shall be granted. However, no permit becomes effective until the applicant has deposited with the Department an acceptable performance bond or other security pursuant to &#xA7; 15-823 of this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">Public notice, informational hearings, and judicial review shall be conducted in accordance with the provisions of &#xA7; 5-204 of this article.</section>
  </text>
</law>
