<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gen" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="2-901" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gen-2-901</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Business entity" means:<section prefix="(i)">A person conducting or operating a trade or business in Maryland; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">An organization operating in Maryland that is exempt from taxation under &#xA7; 501(c)(3) or (4) of the Internal Revenue Code.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Cash in lieu of parking program" means an employer-funded program under which an employer offers to provide a cash allowance to an employee in an amount equal to the parking subsidy that the employer would otherwise pay or incur to provide the employee a parking space.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">"Guaranteed ride home" means immediate transportation provided by a business entity for an employee who:<section prefix="(i)">Receives any of the commuter benefits described in subsection (b)(1) or (2) of this section or commutes by way of a nonmotorized method of transportation; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Is required to leave work early for illness or other verifiable reason.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(5)">"Instrument" means a pass, token, fare card, voucher, or similar item.</section>
      <section prefix="(6)">"Parking subsidy" means:<section prefix="(i)">The difference between the out-of-pocket amount paid by an employer on a regular basis to secure the availability of an employee parking space not owned by the employer and the price charged to the employee for use of that space; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">For parking owned or leased by the employer as an integral part of a larger facility, the fair market value of a parking space provided by the employer for parking commuter vehicles, as determined:</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A business entity may claim a tax credit in an amount equal to 50% of the cost of providing the following commuter benefits to the business entity's employees:<section prefix="(1)">If provided for the purpose of travel between the employee's residence and place of employment, any portion of the cost of transportation to or from a location in the State in a vehicle or an instrument that is used to offset any portion of the cost of transportation to or from a location in the State in a vehicle:<section prefix="(i)">With a seating capacity of at least eight adult individuals; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">At least 80% of the annual mileage of which is incurred:</section></section><section prefix="(2)">An instrument that:<section prefix="(i)">Entitles an individual, at no additional cost or at a reduced fare, to transportation to or from a location in the State on a publicly or privately owned mass transit system other than a taxi service; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">Is redeemable at a transit pass sales outlet for the purpose stated in item (i) of this item; or</section></section><section prefix="(3)">For an employee who resides or works in the State:<section prefix="(i)">A cash in lieu of parking program; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">A guaranteed ride home.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The credit allowed under this section may not exceed $50 per individual employee per month.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The credit allowed under this section may not exceed the total tax otherwise payable by the business entity for that taxable year, determined before the application of the credit under this section but after the application of any other credit.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The unused amount of the credit under this section for any taxable year may not be carried over to any other taxable year.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
