<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gen" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="9-664" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gen-9-664</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">An independent system may be constructed in accordance with this section:<section prefix="(1)">By a member county at its own expense; or</section><section prefix="(2)">By and at the expense of the owners of property that will be served by the independent system.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A person or member county may construct an independent system only if:<section prefix="(1)">The independent system will serve an area that is not served by a project or a municipal system; and</section><section prefix="(2)">The sanitary commission approves.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The person or member county that proposes to construct the independent system shall:<section prefix="(1)">Submit to the sanitary commission plans and specifications for construction of the independent system; and</section><section prefix="(2)">If the sanitary commission approves the plans and specifications, construct the independent system in accordance with the approved plans and specifications.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Each independent system shall be operated:<section prefix="(1)">At the expense of the person or county that constructs it; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Under the general supervision of the sanitary commission.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The person or county that constructs an independent system shall:<section prefix="(1)">Keep accurate records of:<section prefix="(i)">The construction of the independent system;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The operation of the independent system; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">The cost of building and operating the independent system; and</section></section><section prefix="(2)">File copies of the records with the sanitary commission.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
