<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gen" order_by="gen" level="1">Environment</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gen-7-403</section_number>
  <catch_line>There is a Hazardous Waste Facilities Siting Board....</catch_line>
  <order_by>403</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">There is a Hazardous Waste Facilities Siting Board.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Board consists of 8 members appointed by the Governor who shall represent the various geographical areas of the State. No more than one member of the Board shall be a resident of the same county or of Baltimore City.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Of the 8 members:<section prefix="(i)">Two shall be members of the scientific community in the State, one of whom shall be a geologist;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Three shall be members of the general public who have no financial interest in the waste disposal industry, at least one of whom has had a demonstrated involvement in environmental matters;</section><section prefix="(iii)">One shall be appointed from a list of three or more persons nominated by the Maryland Association of Counties;</section><section prefix="(iv)">One shall be appointed from a list of three or more persons nominated by the Maryland Chamber of Commerce; and</section><section prefix="(v)">One shall be appointed from a list of three or more persons nominated by the Maryland Municipal League.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Before taking office, each appointee to the Board shall take the oath required by Article I, &#xA7; 9 of the Maryland Constitution.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The term of a member is 4 years.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The terms of the initial appointees expire as follows: one member representing the general public and one member representing the scientific community on January 1, 1984, one member representing the general public and one member representing the scientific community on January 1, 1985 and the remaining members on January 1, 1983.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The Governor shall appoint a chairman from among the 8 members.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">At the end of a term, a member continues to serve until a successor is appointed and qualifies.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">A member who is appointed after a term has begun serves only the remainder of that term and until a successor is appointed and qualifies.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">A member may be removed by the appointing authority for incompetency or misconduct.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">Each member of the Board is entitled to:<section prefix="(1)">Compensation in accordance with the State budget; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Reimbursement for expenses under the Standard State Travel Regulations, as provided in the State budget.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(j)">The affirmative vote of a majority of the members of the Board then serving is necessary for any decision of the Board.</section>
  </text>
</law>
