<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gen" order_by="" level="1">Environment</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gen-17-308</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>308</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Secretary shall adopt regulations to stagger the terms of the licenses.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A license expires on the date the Secretary sets, in accordance with subsection (a) of this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">At least 2 months before a license expires, the Board shall send to the licensee, by first-class mail or electronically, to the last known address of the licensee:<section prefix="(1)">A renewal application form; and</section><section prefix="(2)">A notice that states:<section prefix="(i)">The date on which the current license expires;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The date by which the Board must receive the renewal application for the renewal to be issued and mailed before the license expires; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">The amount of the renewal fee.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Before a license expires, the licensee may renew the license for an additional 2-year term if the licensee:<section prefix="(1)">Is otherwise entitled to be licensed;</section><section prefix="(2)">Pays to the Board:<section prefix="(i)">The required renewal fee set by the Board; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Any outstanding fees; and</section></section><section prefix="(3)">Submits to the Board:<section prefix="(i)">Satisfactory evidence of compliance with the continuing education requirements established under subsection (e) of this section;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Satisfactory evidence of compliance with the insurance requirements established under &#xA7; 17-302 of this subtitle;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Satisfactory evidence of the resolution of any license violations, suspensions, denials, revocations, or other Board actions taken under this title; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">A renewal application on the form that the Board provides.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A licensee shall complete 12 hours of continuing education instruction covering marine contractor subject matter approved by the Board.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The Board shall approve the substance and form of a continuing education course if the course is:<section prefix="1.">Offered by a qualified instructor; or</section><section prefix="2.">Conducted by an educational institution approved by the Board.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The licensee is responsible for the cost of any continuing education course.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The Board shall renew the license of each licensee who meets the requirements of this section.</section>
  </text>
</law>
