<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gen" order_by="gen" level="1">Environment</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gen-3-401</section_number>
  <catch_line>Except as otherwise provided by law, the Department shall adopt environmental noise standards, sound...</catch_line>
  <order_by>401</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Except as otherwise provided by law, the Department shall adopt environmental noise standards, sound level limits, and noise control rules and regulations as necessary to protect the public health, the general welfare, and property.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">In adopting environmental noise standards, the Department or a political subdivision that chooses to adopt environmental noise standards shall consider:<section prefix="(1)">Information published by the Administrator of the United States Environmental Protection Agency on the levels of environmental noise that must be attained and maintained in defined areas under various conditions to protect public health and welfare with an adequate margin of safety; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Scientific information about the volume, frequency, duration, and other characteristics of noise that may harm public health, safety, or general welfare, including:<section prefix="(i)">Temporary or permanent hearing loss;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Interference with sleep, speech communication, work, or other human activities;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Adverse physiological responses;</section><section prefix="(iv)">Psychological distress;</section><section prefix="(v)">Harm to animal life;</section><section prefix="(vi)">Devaluation of or damage to property; and</section><section prefix="(vii)">Unreasonable interference with the enjoyment of life or property.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In adopting sound level limits and noise control rules and regulations, the Department or the political subdivision shall consider, among other things:<section prefix="(i)">The residential, commercial, or industrial nature of the area affected;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Zoning;</section><section prefix="(iii)">The nature and source of various kinds of noise;</section><section prefix="(iv)">The degree of noise reduction that may be attained and maintained using the best available technology;</section><section prefix="(v)">Accepted scientific and professional methods for measurement of sound levels; and</section><section prefix="(vi)">The cost of compliance with the sound level limits.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The sound level limits adopted under this subsection shall be consistent with the environmental noise standards adopted by the Department.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The sound level limits and noise control rules and regulations adopted under this subsection may not prohibit trapshooting or other target shooting on any range or other property in Frederick County that the Frederick County Department of Planning and Zoning has approved as a place for those sporting events.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The sound level limits and noise control rules and regulations adopted under this subsection shall be as follows for residential heat pumps and air conditioning units:<section prefix="(i)">Residential heat pumps 75dba.</section><section prefix="(ii)">Residential air conditioning units 70dba.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(5)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The sound level limits and noise control rules and regulations adopted under this subsection may not prohibit trapshooting, skeetshooting, or other target shooting between the hours of 9 a.m. and 10 p.m. on any range or other property of a shooting sports club that is chartered and in operation as of January 1, 2001.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">This paragraph does not apply in Allegany, Anne Arundel, Baltimore City, Calvert, Charles, Garrett, Howard, Montgomery, St. Mary's, and Washington counties.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(6)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Except as provided in subparagraph (ii) of this paragraph, the Department may not adopt sound level limits and noise control rules and regulations under this subsection that prohibit trapshooting, skeetshooting, or other target shooting between the hours of 9 a.m. and 10 p.m. in Allegany County, Anne Arundel County, Garrett County, or Washington County on any range or other property of a shooting sports club that is chartered and in operation as of January 1, 2005.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">
          <section prefix="1.">Subject to the provisions of subsubparagraph 2 of this subparagraph, the Department may adopt sound level limits and noise control rules and regulations under this subsection that prohibit trapshooting, skeetshooting, or other target shooting between the hours of 9 a.m. and 10 p.m. in Allegany County, Anne Arundel County, Garrett County, or Washington County on any range or other property of a shooting club that the Department determines is not in compliance as of January 1, 2005 with environmental noise standards, sound level limits, or noise control rules and regulations adopted under this title.</section>
          <section prefix="2.">A sound level limit or noise control rule or regulation adopted under this subsection shall allow trapshooting, skeetshooting, and other target shooting between the hours of 9 a.m. and 10 p.m. by a shooting sports club that the Department determines has become compliant with sound level limits and noise control rules and regulations adopted under this title.</section>
        </section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This section does not authorize the Department to adopt environmental noise standards, sound level limits, or noise control rules and regulations that apply to noise from:<section prefix="(i)">Construction or repair work on public property;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Fire or rescue station alerting devices; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">In Frederick County or Frederick City:<section prefix="1.">A fair listed in the Maryland Agricultural Fairs and Shows Schedule that is maintained by the Maryland Agricultural Fair Board; or</section><section prefix="2.">Any other event held on the same grounds as a fair under item 1 of this item.</section></section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Noise control rules and regulations that apply to Department of Transportation facilities shall be adopted by the Department of Transportation.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
