<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gen" order_by="" level="1">Environment</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gen-5-910</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>910</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The General Assembly declares that:<section prefix="(1)">In the application review process, one of the primary mitigation issues is locating the most beneficial area to conduct wetland restoration, creation, or enhancement;</section><section prefix="(2)">Where unavoidable losses or degradations occur as a result of permitted human activity, there exists a sequential process for mitigation site location which includes consideration of on-site alternatives;</section><section prefix="(3)">Mitigation banking, which allows a person to restore, enhance, or create a functional wetland ecosystem, may offer a sound mitigation alternative and may provide an opportunity to contribute to the goal of no net loss in wetlands acreage and function; and</section><section prefix="(4)">Mitigation banking may not alter the regulatory requirements of &#xA7; 5-907 of this subtitle.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Department shall develop standards and adopt regulations for the creation of wetland mitigation banks, including:<section prefix="(1)">The types and locations of wetlands to be restored, created, or enhanced and the types and locations of wetlands to be filled for which a person may obtain credit through a mitigation bank;</section><section prefix="(2)">The types and number of credits available through the bank to offset losses by acreage and by function of a wetland to be filled;</section><section prefix="(3)">The method of wetland construction, supervision, and maintenance to be required of a bank owner seeking to obtain credit for use of the bank;</section><section prefix="(4)">Maintenance requirements;</section><section prefix="(5)">Monitoring requirements;</section><section prefix="(6)">Bonding requirements, to include assurance of wetland function;</section><section prefix="(7)">Reporting requirements to the Department;</section><section prefix="(8)">Consistency with developed watershed plans, forest conservation, local growth management policies, and local comprehensive plans;</section><section prefix="(9)">Requirements for the protection in perpetuity of mitigation banks, through methods that include easements, covenants, or similar mechanisms, that shall be in place at the time credits are withdrawn;</section><section prefix="(10)">Compensation ratios for mitigation through mitigation banks that shall equal or exceed 1.5 to 1; and</section><section prefix="(11)">Public notice and comment requirements, including opportunity for public review and comment on any specific wetland bank that is greater than 5 acres in size.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The standards and regulations adopted by the Department under this section shall ensure that:<section prefix="(1)">The provisions of &#xA7; 5-907 of this subtitle, including the avoidance, alternative analysis, and minimization of disturbance of nontidal wetlands, are fully adhered to;</section><section prefix="(2)">The goals of &#xA7; 5-902 of this subtitle to attain no net overall loss in nontidal wetland acreage and function and to strive for a net resource gain are achieved;</section><section prefix="(3)">On-site mitigation is examined before conducting mitigation off site; and</section><section prefix="(4)">Mitigation through wetland banking should be accomplished in and with preference to the same watershed and county as the wetland for which mitigation is required.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This section may not be construed to require the Department to:<section prefix="(i)">Establish or fund State mitigation banks;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Fund the establishment of mitigation banking by the private sector; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">Use State lands for mitigation banking.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Department may establish mitigation banking through and with the cooperation of the private sector and may use State lands for mitigation banking sites.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
