<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gen" order_by="" level="1">Environment</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gen-7-266</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>266</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In addition to being subject to an injunctive action under this subtitle, a person who violates any provision of this subtitle or of any rule, regulation, order, hauler certificate, vehicle certificate, or facility permit adopted or issued under this subtitle is liable to a civil penalty not exceeding $25,000, to be collected in a civil action. Each day a violation occurs is a separate violation under this subsection.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In addition to any other remedies available at law or in equity and after an opportunity for a hearing which may be waived in writing by the person accused of a violation, the Department may impose a penalty for violation of any provision of this subtitle or any rule, regulation, order, hauler certificate, vehicle certificate, driver certificate, or facility permit adopted or issued under this subtitle.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The penalty imposed on a person under this subsection shall be:<section prefix="(i)">Up to $25,000 for each violation, but not exceeding $100,000 total; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Assessed with consideration given to:<section prefix="1.">The willfulness of the violation, the extent to which the existence of the violation was known to but uncorrected by the violator, and the extent to which the violator exercised reasonable care;</section><section prefix="2.">Any actual harm to the environment or to human health, including injury to or impairment of the use of the waters of this State or the natural resources of this State;</section><section prefix="3.">The cost of cleanup and the cost of restoration of natural resources;</section><section prefix="4.">The nature and degree of injury to or interference with general welfare, health, and property;</section><section prefix="5.">The extent to which the location of the violation, including location near waters of this State or areas of human population, creates the potential for harm to the environment or to human health or safety;</section><section prefix="6.">The available technology and economic reasonableness of controlling, reducing, or eliminating the violation;</section><section prefix="7.">The degree of hazard posed by the particular waste material or materials involved; and</section><section prefix="8.">The extent to which the current violation is part of a recurrent pattern of the same or similar type of violation committed by the violator.</section></section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Each day a violation occurs is a separate violation under this subsection.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">Any penalty imposed under this subsection is payable to this State and collectible in any manner provided at law for the collection of debts.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">If any person who is liable to pay a penalty imposed under this subsection fails to pay it after demand, the amount, together with interest and any costs that may accrue, shall be:<section prefix="(i)">A lien in favor of this State on any property, real or personal, of the person; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Recorded in the office of the clerk of court for the county in which the property is located.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(6)">Any penalty collected under this subsection shall be placed in a special fund to be used for monitoring and surveillance by the Department to assure and maintain an adequate record of any violations, including discharge of waste material and other pollutants into the waters of this State or into the environment.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
