<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gen" order_by="" level="1">Environment</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gen-15-827</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>827</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The permittee shall file an operations and progress report with the Department by March 31 of each year, on a form prescribed and furnished by the Department, which shall cover the preceding calendar year and shall:<section prefix="(1)">Identify the mine, the permittee, and the permit number;</section><section prefix="(2)">Identify the location of the operation as to county, district, nearest municipality, and nearest public road;</section><section prefix="(3)">Report the type of mineral produced, the volume produced, and the value of production of each for the previous year. Individual company data is confidential and may be released only with the permittee's written consent;</section><section prefix="(4)">State the acreage disturbed by surface mining during the previous year;</section><section prefix="(5)">State and describe the amount and type of reclamation carried out during the previous year;</section><section prefix="(6)">Estimate the acreage to be newly disturbed by mining in the next year; and</section><section prefix="(7)">Provide any additional information or maps which the Department reasonably requires.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">In addition, at the end of each calendar year the permittee shall furnish to the Department a new surveyed map, showing the status of the operation and indicating the area affected and reclaimed during the preceding year, particularly with relation to the property lines and boundaries shown on the map and survey furnished with the original application. A registered professional engineer or professional surveyor is not required to prepare this progress report map. However, if prepared by the permittee, the map shall be of reasonable quality, accuracy, and legibility, and acceptable to the Department.</section>
  </text>
</law>
