<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gen" order_by="" level="1">Environment</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gen-6-401</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>401</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Asbestos material" means any material or product which contains more than 1 percent asbestos.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Asbestos occupation" means any job as an inspector, project designer, management planner, asbestos abatement contractor, asbestos supervisor, or asbestos abatement worker involving:<section prefix="(i)">A project in a public and commercial building or in a school building that involves the location, identification, physical and hazard assessment, enclosure, removal, repair, renovation, or demolition of asbestos material in a public and commercial building or in a school building;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The inspection, planning, or design of any project in a school building as enumerated in subparagraph (i) of this paragraph; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">The inspection or design of any project in a public and commercial building as enumerated in subparagraph (i) of this paragraph.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Asbestos occupation" does not include work on any small-scale, short-duration operations, maintenance, and repair activities as defined in 40 C.F.R. 763, Appendix C to Subpart E, Asbestos Model Accreditation Plan.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">"Business entity" means a partnership, firm, association, corporation, sole proprietorship, or other business concern.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"Interior space" includes:<section prefix="(1)">Exterior hallways connecting buildings;</section><section prefix="(2)">Porticoes; and</section><section prefix="(3)">Mechanical systems used to condition interior space.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">"License" means a license issued by the Department under this subtitle to remove and encapsulate asbestos.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Public and commercial building" means the interior space of any building that is not a school building.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Public and commercial building" includes:<section prefix="(i)">Industrial and office buildings;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Residential apartment buildings of 10 or more dwelling units;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Condominiums of 10 or more dwelling units;</section><section prefix="(iv)">Government-owned buildings;</section><section prefix="(v)">Colleges;</section><section prefix="(vi)">Museums;</section><section prefix="(vii)">Airports;</section><section prefix="(viii)">Hospitals;</section><section prefix="(ix)">Churches;</section><section prefix="(x)">Stores;</section><section prefix="(xi)">Warehouses; and</section><section prefix="(xii)">Factories.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Public and commercial building" does not include any residential apartment building of fewer than 10 dwelling units, any condominium of fewer than 10 dwelling units, or any detached single-family home.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(h)">"Public unit" includes:<section prefix="(1)">Any agency, bureau, department, or instrumentality of State government that is not subject to Executive Order 01.01.1987.22;</section><section prefix="(2)">Any agency, bureau, department, or instrumentality of federal or local government;</section><section prefix="(3)">Educational institutions that are not subject to Executive Order 01.01.1987.22; and</section><section prefix="(4)">Any public, quasi-public, or municipal corporation.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(i)">"School" means any elementary or secondary school as defined in the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965, at 20 U.S.C. 8801.</section>
  </text>
</law>
