<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gen" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="15-1204" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gen-15-1204</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">An owner of a mineral interest may record, at any time, a notice of intent to preserve the mineral interest or a part of a mineral interest.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A mineral interest is preserved in the county in which the notice is recorded.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The following individuals may record a notice in accordance with subsection (a) of this section:<section prefix="(i)">An owner of the mineral interest;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Another person legally authorized to act on behalf of the owner; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">A co-owner, for the benefit of any or all co-owners.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A notice recorded under subsection (a) of this section shall contain:<section prefix="(i)"/><section prefix="(ii)">An identification of the mineral interest or part of the mineral interest to be preserved, in accordance with subsection (c) of this section.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A mineral interest shall be identified by:<section prefix="(1)">A reference to the location in the records of the instrument that creates, reserves, or otherwise evidences the interest;</section><section prefix="(2)">The judgment or decree that confirms the mineral interest;</section><section prefix="(3)">A legal description of the mineral interest, if accompanied by a reference to the name of the record owner under whom the owner of the mineral interest claims; or</section><section prefix="(4)">A general reference to any or all mineral interests of the owner in any real property situated in the county, if:<section prefix="(i)">A previously recorded instrument created, reserved, or otherwise evidenced the mineral interest; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">A judgment or decree confirms the mineral interest.</section></section></section>
  </text>
</law>
