<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gen" order_by="gen" level="1">Environment</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gen-9-350</section_number>
  <catch_line>Grants may be awarded to counties and municipalities for projects to reduce pollution from stormwate...</catch_line>
  <order_by>350</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Grants may be awarded to counties and municipalities for projects to reduce pollution from stormwater runoff in existing urbanized areas.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Grants may be used for construction on privately owned property if:<section prefix="(i)">Necessary for the purpose of the project; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">An agreement has been made with the property owner.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A grant awarded under this subsection:<section prefix="(i)">Shall not exceed 75 percent of all eligible costs; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Shall not exceed $500,000.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In addition to cost sharing funds provided under Title 8, Subtitle 7 of the Agriculture Article, grants may be awarded for projects to implement best management practices to prevent or control agriculturally related nonpoint sources of water pollution on State land or to governmental entities in other areas in which the potential for water pollution from agriculture is substantial. When cost sharing funds are provided under Title 8, Subtitle 7 of the Agriculture Article, the procedures and requirements of that law rather than &#xA7; 9-345 of this subtitle apply.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Grants awarded under this subsection to governmental entities or for use on State land may be awarded for up to 100 percent of the total cost of a project. However, in awarding such grants, the applicant's financial capability to cost share and any resultant economic benefit shall be considered in determining the extent of any required matching dollar amount.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">All grants awarded under this subsection shall be made after prior consultation with the Secretary of Agriculture.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
