<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gen" order_by="" level="1">Environment</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gen-4-705</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>705</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The owner or operator of an underground oil storage tank eligible under &#xA7; 4-704(b)(1)(ii) of this subtitle may apply to the Fund for reimbursement, until December 31, 2007, for usual, customary, and reasonable costs incurred on or after October 1, 2000 in performing site rehabilitation.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The owner of a heating oil tank eligible under &#xA7; 4-704(b)(1)(iii) of this subtitle may apply to the Fund no later than 6 months after rehabilitation completion for reimbursement, until June 30, 2013, for usual, customary, and reasonable costs incurred on or after October 1, 2000 in performing site rehabilitation.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Any reimbursement from the Fund for applications approved on or after July 1, 1996 is subject to:<section prefix="(i)">For owners or operators of six tanks or fewer, a deductible of $7,500;</section><section prefix="(ii)">For owners or operators of more than 6 but not more than 15 tanks, a deductible of $10,000;</section><section prefix="(iii)">For owners or operators of more than 15 but not more than 30 tanks, a deductible of $15,000;</section><section prefix="(iv)">For owners or operators of more than 30 tanks, a deductible of $20,000; and</section><section prefix="(v)">For residential owners of heating oil tanks, a deductible of $500; and</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The maximum amount to be reimbursed from the Fund shall be:<section prefix="(i)">$125,000 for underground oil storage tanks per occurrence; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">$20,000 for heating oil tanks per occurrence.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">To be eligible for reimbursement from the Fund, an owner or operator shall:<section prefix="(1)">Certify that the discharge is not the result of a willful or deliberate act;</section><section prefix="(2)">Submit a corrective action plan, schedule, and cost estimate to the Department that shall include provisions for the environmentally sound treatment or disposal of contaminated soils that meet all federal and State requirements and standards; and</section><section prefix="(3)">Except for heating oil tanks, certify that the discharge is from a tank registered under &#xA7; 4-411.1 of this title.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">If the owner or operator knowingly submits a false certification under subsection (e) of this section, that owner or operator is not eligible for reimbursement under this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">Only expenses that are cost-effective, reasonable, and consistent with a corrective action plan approved by the Department may be eligible for reimbursement from the Fund.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">The cost for replacement or retrofitting of underground oil storage tanks or heating oil tanks and associated piping is not eligible for reimbursement, and the Department may not incur these costs or expend moneys from the Fund for these purposes.</section>
  </text>
</law>
