<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gen" order_by="gen" level="1">Environment</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gen-9-659</section_number>
  <catch_line>The sanitary commission shall connect the water system or sewerage system to any parcel:...</catch_line>
  <order_by>659</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The sanitary commission shall connect the water system or sewerage system to any parcel:<section prefix="(i)">Whose owner requests the connection;</section><section prefix="(ii)">That does not abut a way in which a water pipe or sewer pipe is laid; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">That is not the subject of a benefit assessment levied under &#xA7; 9-657 or &#xA7; 9-658 of this subtitle.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">However, the Sanitary Commission of Worcester County may also construct or permit the construction of a connector to any parcel described under paragraph (1) at a time and in a manner that it determines to be appropriate.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The sanitary commission shall classify the parcel and determine a front-foot charge on the parcel as if the parcel abutted on a way in which a water pipe or sewer pipe is laid.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">When a connection is made under this section, the owner of the parcel has the same rights and duties and the district has the same remedies as to the benefit assessment that apply to benefit assessments under &#xA7;&#xA7; 9-657 and 9-658 of this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Payment of a benefit assessment made under this section:<section prefix="(1)">Is due when levied by the sanitary commission;</section><section prefix="(2)">Is in default 60 days after the payment is due; and</section><section prefix="(3)">When in default, bears interest from the date of default:<section prefix="(i)">In Allegany and Somerset counties, at the rate set by the respective Sanitary Commission; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">In all other counties, at the rate of 0.5 percent a month.</section></section></section>
  </text>
</law>
