<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gen" order_by="gen" level="1">Environment</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gen-7-501</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated....</catch_line>
  <order_by>501</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Active enforcement" means after the Department has issued a notice of violation, order, consent order, or other enforcement action of the Department and until completion of activities required by that action.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">For purposes of paragraph (1) of this subsection, "other enforcement action" does not include a site complaint.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Applicant" means a person who applies to participate in the Voluntary Cleanup Program.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">"Background level" means the level of a substance occurring naturally at the site prior to any manmade spill or release.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"Contamination" means a release, discharge, or threatened release of:<section prefix="(1)">A controlled hazardous substance, as defined in &#xA7; 7-201 of this title; or</section><section prefix="(2)">Oil, as defined in &#xA7; 4-401 of this article.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">"Eligible applicant" means:<section prefix="(1)">A responsible person who has not knowingly or willfully violated any law or regulation concerning controlled hazardous substances; or</section><section prefix="(2)">An inculpable person.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Eligible property" means property that is contaminated or perceived to be contaminated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Eligible property" does not include property that is:<section prefix="(i)">On the national priorities list under &#xA7; 105 of the federal act;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Except as provided in paragraph (3)(i) of this subsection, under active enforcement; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">Subject to a controlled hazardous substances permit issued in accordance with this title.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">"Eligible property" includes a site under active enforcement if:<section prefix="1.">All applications filed in connection with the property are filed by inculpable persons; and</section><section prefix="2.">Any response action plan and cleanup criteria approved by the Department under this subtitle is at least as protective of public health and the environment as the requirements of any outstanding active enforcement action.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">"Eligible property" includes sites listed on the Comprehensive Environmental Response, Compensation, and Liability Information System.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(h)">"Federal act" has the meaning stated in &#xA7; 7-201(j) of this title.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">"Imminent and substantial endangerment" means a release or threatened release of a hazardous substance that may pose a risk of significant harm to the public health or the environment at some foreseeable time in the future and is not limited to an emergency situation.</section>
    <section prefix="(j)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Inculpable person" means a person who:<section prefix="(i)">Has no prior or current ownership interest in an eligible property at the time of application to participate in the Voluntary Cleanup Program; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Has not caused or contributed to contamination at the eligible property at the time of application to participate in the Voluntary Cleanup Program.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Inculpable person" includes:<section prefix="(i)">A successor in interest in an eligible property acquired from an inculpable person, as defined in paragraph (1) of this subsection, if the successor in interest does not have a prior ownership interest in the eligible property and, other than by virtue of ownership of the eligible property, is not otherwise a responsible person at the eligible property; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Notwithstanding paragraph (1)(i) of this subsection, a person who is not considered a responsible person under &#xA7; 7-201(t)(2) of this title.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(k)">"Participant" means an applicant accepted into the Voluntary Cleanup Program.</section>
    <section prefix="(l)">"Previously undiscovered contamination" means contamination at an eligible property which was not identified or addressed in a notice of no further requirements or response action plan.</section>
    <section prefix="(m)">"Program" means the Voluntary Cleanup Program established under this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(n)">"Responsible person" has the meaning stated in &#xA7; 7-201(t) of this title.</section>
  </text>
</law>
