<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gen" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="9-413" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gen-9-413</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">A person who willfully violates &#xA7; 9-412(a)(4) or (5) of this subtitle is subject to a civil penalty of up to $5,000 for each day on which the violation exists.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A person who violates &#xA7; 9-412(a)(1), (2), or (3) of this subtitle is guilty of a misdemeanor and on conviction is subject to a fine not exceeding $5,000 for each day on which the violation occurs or failure to comply continues.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">In an action brought in the appropriate court to enforce the order, a person who willfully violates or fails or refuses to comply with any order issued by the Secretary under this subtitle may be fined not more than $5,000 for each day on which the violation occurs or failure to comply continues.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In addition to any other remedies available at law and after an opportunity for a hearing, which may be waived in writing by the person accused of a violation, the Department may impose a penalty for violation of any provision of this subtitle or any order, regulation, or plan adopted or issued under this subtitle.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The penalty imposed on a supplier of water serving a population of more than 10,000 under this subsection shall be:<section prefix="(i)">Up to $1,000 per day for each violation, but not exceeding $25,000 total for each violation; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Assessed with consideration given to:</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The penalty imposed on a supplier of water serving a population of 3,301 to 10,000 under this subsection shall be:<section prefix="(i)">Up to $500 per day for each violation, but not exceeding $12,500 total for each violation; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Assessed with consideration given to the factors set forth in paragraph (2)(ii) of this subsection.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The penalty imposed on a supplier of water serving a population of 501 to 3,300 under this subsection shall be:<section prefix="(i)">Up to $250 per day for each violation, but not exceeding $6,250 total for each violation; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Assessed with consideration given to the factors set forth in paragraph (2)(ii) of this subsection.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(5)">The penalty imposed on a supplier of water serving a population of 500 or less under this subsection shall be:<section prefix="(i)">Up to $100 per day for each violation, but not exceeding $5,000 total for each violation; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Assessed with consideration given to the factors set forth in paragraph (2)(ii) of this subsection.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(6)">Each day a violation occurs is a separate violation under this subsection.</section>
      <section prefix="(7)">Any penalty imposed under this subsection is payable to the State and collectible in any manner provided at law for the collection of penalties.</section>
      <section prefix="(8)">All penalties collected under this subtitle shall be paid into the Maryland Clean Water Fund created under &#xA7; 9-320 of this title.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
