<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gen" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="9-501" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gen-9-501</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Community sewerage system" means a publicly or privately owned sewerage system that serves at least 2 lots.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Community water supply system" means a water supply system that serves at least 2 lots.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"County plan" means a comprehensive plan for adequately providing throughout the county, including all towns, municipal corporations, and sanitary districts in the county, the following facilities and services by public or private ownership:<section prefix="(i)">Water supply systems;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Sewerage systems;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Solid waste disposal systems;</section><section prefix="(iv)">Solid waste acceptance facilities; and</section><section prefix="(v)">Systematic collection and disposal of solid waste, including litter.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"County plan" includes a revised or amended county plan.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"Individual sewerage system" means a sewerage system that serves only 1 lot.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">"Individual water supply system" means a water supply system that supplies water to only 1 lot.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">"Litter" means any:<section prefix="(1)">Waste material;</section><section prefix="(2)">Refuse;</section><section prefix="(3)">Garbage;</section><section prefix="(4)">Trash;</section><section prefix="(5)">Debris;</section><section prefix="(6)">Dead animal; or</section><section prefix="(7)">Other discarded material.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(h)">"Lot" means a parcel of land, including a part of a subdivision, that:<section prefix="(1)">Is used or is intended to be used as a building site; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Is not intended to be further subdivided.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(i)">"Multiuse sewerage system" means a sewerage system that:<section prefix="(1)">Serves only 1 lot;</section><section prefix="(2)">Serves a number of individuals;</section><section prefix="(3)">Has a treatment capacity of more than 5,000 gallons a day; and</section><section prefix="(4)">Is not publicly owned or operated.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(j)">"Multiuse water supply system" means an individual water supply system that:<section prefix="(1)">Has the capacity to supply more than 5,000 gallons of water a day; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Serves a number of individuals.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(k)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Proposed county plan" means a county plan that:<section prefix="(i)">Has been adopted by the county governing body; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Has not been approved by the Department.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Proposed county plan" includes any proposed amendment or revision of the county plan.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(l)">"Sewage" means any human or animal excretion, street wash, domestic waste, or industrial waste.</section>
    <section prefix="(m)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Sewerage system" means:<section prefix="(i)">The channels used or intended to be used to collect and dispose of sewage; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Any structure and appurtenance used or intended to be used to collect or prepare sewage for discharge into the waters of this State.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Sewerage system" includes any sewer of any size.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Sewerage system" does not include the plumbing system inside any building served by the sewerage system.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(n)">"Solid waste acceptance facility" means any sanitary landfill, incinerator, transfer station, or plant whose primary purpose is to dispose of, treat, or process solid waste.</section>
    <section prefix="(o)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Solid waste disposal system" means any publicly or privately owned system that:<section prefix="(i)">Provides a scheduled or systematic collection of solid waste;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Transports the solid waste to a solid waste acceptance facility; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Treats or otherwise disposes of the solid waste at the solid waste acceptance facility.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Solid waste disposal system" includes each solid waste acceptance facility that is used in connection with the solid waste disposal system.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(p)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Subdivision" means any division of a tract or parcel of land into at least 2 lots, for the purpose of sale or building development.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Subdivision" includes any change in street lines or lot lines.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Except as provided in paragraph (4) of this subsection, "subdivision" does not include any division of land into parcels of more than 3 acres, if the division:<section prefix="(i)">Is for agricultural purposes; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Does not involve any new street or easement of access.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">In Carroll County, "subdivision" does not include:<section prefix="(i)">Any division of land into parcels of more than 3 acres, if the division:</section><section prefix="(ii)">A remainder parcel of land of 25 acres or more that exists as a result of the division of a large parcel into at least 2 smaller parcels, provided that any occupied dwelling on the remainder parcel is serviced by a properly functioning sewerage disposal system and potable water supply.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(q)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Water supply system" means a publicly or privately owned or operated:<section prefix="(i)">Source and the surrounding area from which water is supplied for drinking or domestic purposes; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Structure, channel, or appurtenance used or intended to be used to prepare water for use or to deliver water to a consumer.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Water supply system" does not include the plumbing system inside any building that is served by the water supply system.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
