<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gen" order_by="gen" level="1">Environment</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gen-4-212</section_number>
  <catch_line>Unless the person served with an order under &#xA7; 4-209(a)(1) of this subtitle makes a request for a h...</catch_line>
  <order_by>212</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Unless the person served with an order under &#xA7; 4-209(a)(1) of this subtitle makes a request for a hearing in accordance with &#xA7; 4-211(b) of this subtitle, the order is a final order.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If the person served with an order under &#xA7; 4-209(a)(1) of this subtitle makes a request for a hearing in accordance with &#xA7; 4-211(b) of this subtitle, the order becomes a final corrective order in accordance with the Department's decision following the hearing.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If the Department issues a notice under &#xA7; 4-209(a)(2) or (3) of this subtitle, the Department may not issue an order that requires corrective action by the person to whom the notice is directed until after the later of:<section prefix="(i)">The conclusion of the hearing, if any; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">The review of the report, if any.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">After the time within which the Department may not issue a corrective order has passed, if the Department finds that a violation of this subtitle has occurred, the Department shall issue an order that requires correction of the violation within a time set in the order.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Any order issued under this subsection is a final corrective order and the person to whom the order is directed is not entitled to a hearing before the Department as a result of the order.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Department shall:<section prefix="(1)">Take action to secure compliance with any final corrective order; and</section><section prefix="(2)">If the terms of the final corrective order are violated or if a violation is not corrected within the time set in the order, sue to require correction of the violation.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">This section does not prevent the Department or the Attorney General from taking action against a violator before the expiration of the time limitation or schedules in the order.</section>
  </text>
</law>
