<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gen" order_by="" level="1">Environment</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gen-6-905.3</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>905.3</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">This section does not apply to:<section prefix="(1)">Prescription drugs;</section><section prefix="(2)">Any substance regulated by the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act;</section><section prefix="(3)">Biological products regulated by the federal Food and Drug Administration under the federal Public Health Service Act;</section><section prefix="(4)">Medical equipment not intended for use by nonmedical personnel; or</section><section prefix="(5)">Products that contain mercury-added products that are labeled in accordance with this section.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">On or after April 1, 2006, unless the product is labeled in accordance with subsection (c) of this section and the regulations adopted by the Department under this section, a manufacturer or wholesaler may not sell a mercury-added product:<section prefix="(i)">At retail in the State; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">To a retailer in the State.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">On or after April 1, 2006, unless the product is labeled in accordance with subsection (c) of this section and the regulations adopted by the Department under this section, a retailer may not knowingly sell a new mercury-added product in the State.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, the label of a mercury-added product shall clearly inform the purchaser or consumer that:<section prefix="(i)">Mercury is present in the product; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">The product shall be managed in accordance with federal and State environmental laws to minimize the release of mercury into the environment.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A label that conforms to another state's label requirements for mercury-added products satisfies the requirements of this subsection.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The manufacturer of a mercury-added product is responsible for affixing the label required by this section on mercury-added products manufactured on or after January 1, 2006.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">
          <section prefix="1.">A manufacturer of a motor vehicle may meet the labeling requirements of this section by placing the label on the doorpost of a new vehicle.</section>
          <section prefix="2.">If the servicing of a vehicle includes the addition of a mercury-added product, the label on the doorpost of the vehicle shall be appropriately updated.</section>
        </section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">A manufacturer that labels a mercury-added product in compliance with another state's labeling requirements for the same or a similar mercury-added product satisfies the requirements of this subsection.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this subsection, "mercury-added fluorescent lamp" means a fluorescent lamp that exhibits the toxicity characteristic for mercury under Title 26, Subtitle 13, Chapter 2 of the Code of Maryland Regulations.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Except as provided in paragraph (3) of this subsection, on or after October 1, 2006, a person who, during a calendar year, discards at least the minimum weight or minimum number of mercury-added fluorescent lamps, as established in regulations adopted under subsection (f) of this section, shall arrange for the final reclamation or destination of the lamps at a:<section prefix="(i)">Reclamation facility; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">Destination facility, as defined by the Department in regulation.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Department may delay the requirements of paragraph (2) of this subsection if it determines that it will not be feasible for a person to arrange for the final reclamation or destination of lamps at reclamation facilities on the date provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">Unless otherwise provided under federal or State law:<section prefix="(i)">An owner or operator of an industrial or commercial property may assign the responsibility for ensuring compliance with this subsection to a tenant who is otherwise responsible for maintaining the property; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">If a tenant is responsible for ensuring compliance and fails to comply with this subsection, the owner or operator of the property is not liable for the failure to comply.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">By October 1, 2005, the Department shall adopt regulations necessary for the implementation of this section, including the establishment of:<section prefix="(1)">Standards for the size, location, and typeface of the label required by this section;</section><section prefix="(2)">Criteria under which a person subject to this section may be exempted from the labeling and reclamation or destination requirements and limitations of this section; and</section><section prefix="(3)">During the course of a calendar year, the minimum weight and the minimum number, as applicable, of mercury-added fluorescent lamps that shall be required for a person to deliver the lamps or arrange for their delivery to a:<section prefix="(i)">Reclamation facility; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">Destination facility, as defined by the Department in regulation.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(g)">Before adopting a regulation under this section, the Department shall consult with persons that have an interest in or are directly impacted by the proposed regulation.</section>
  </text>
</law>
