<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gen" order_by="" level="1">Environment</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gen-5-1104</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>1104</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">With the advice and consent of the Senate, the Governor shall appoint a Hart-Miller-Pleasure Island Citizens Oversight Committee.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The terms and qualifications of members of the Oversight Committee shall be determined by the Governor.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Oversight Committee shall be composed of the following members:<section prefix="(1)">2 trustees from the grantee in interest, as defined in &#xA7; 5-1202.2(a)(1) of the Natural Resources Article;</section><section prefix="(2)">1 individual from the North Point Peninsula Community Coordinating Council;</section><section prefix="(3)">1 individual from the Essex Middle River Civic Council, Inc.;</section><section prefix="(4)">2 interested citizens, 1 of whom shall reside in the sixth legislative district, and 1 of whom shall reside in the seventh legislative district;</section><section prefix="(5)">1 individual from the Baltimore County Waterman's Association;</section><section prefix="(6)">1 individual who represents the pleasure boating industry in Baltimore County;</section><section prefix="(7)">1 individual who represents the sport fishing or crabbing industry in Baltimore County;</section><section prefix="(8)">1 individual from the Greater Dundalk Community Council; and</section><section prefix="(9)">1 individual from the Hart and Miller Island Area Environmental Group, Inc.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Oversight Committee shall:<section prefix="(1)">Monitor and provide oversight regarding:<section prefix="(i)">The future development, use, and maintenance of the Hart-Miller-Pleasure Island chain; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">The water quality immediately surrounding the islands; and</section></section><section prefix="(2)">Hear and dispose of complaints lodged by individuals affected by the future development and the water quality immediately surrounding the Hart-Miller-Pleasure Island chain.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
