<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gen" order_by="gen" level="1">Environment</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gen-15-1206</section_number>
  <catch_line>If the title to a severed mineral interest is vested in an unknown or missing owner, the circuit cou...</catch_line>
  <order_by>1206</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">If the title to a severed mineral interest is vested in an unknown or missing owner, the circuit court of the county where the severed mineral interest is located may on petition, and after notice and a hearing:<section prefix="(1)">Place the severed mineral interest in trust by order;</section><section prefix="(2)">Appoint a trustee for the unknown or missing owner;</section><section prefix="(3)">Order the trustee to create a separate trust bank account to manage all trust assets;</section><section prefix="(4)">Authorize the trustee to sell, execute, and deliver a valid lease on the minerals to the owner of the surface estate; and</section><section prefix="(5)">Place conditions on the authorization in item (4) of this subsection.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A petition to create a trust for a severed mineral interest and to appoint a trustee under subsection (a) of this section may be filed by a person vested in fee simple with the whole or undivided interest in the surface estate or estates.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If the unknown or missing owner of a vested severed mineral interest does not contest a trust created under subsection (a)(1) of this section on or before 5 years after the date that the court issued the order creating the trust, the trustee shall file a petition to terminate the trust and to convey title to the severed mineral interest to the surface owners.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The petition in paragraph (1) of this subsection shall:<section prefix="(i)">Name as defendants:<section prefix="1.">The surface owners; and</section><section prefix="2.">Any other person with a legal interest in the severed mineral interest, including any unknown or missing owners; and</section></section><section prefix="(ii)">Include:<section prefix="1.">A legal description of the severed mineral interest;</section><section prefix="2.">A description of the putative property interests of each of the parties;</section><section prefix="3.">The last known address of each of the parties;</section><section prefix="4.">An affidavit signed by the surface owners, affirming fee simple ownership of the surface estate or estates, and requesting the court to convey title to the severed mineral interest at issue; and</section><section prefix="5.">An affidavit signed by the trustee, affirming that after conducting a diligent inquiry, including a search in the county where the severed mineral interest is located, performed in accordance with generally accepted standards of title examination of the land records of the county, records of register of wills of the county, and records of the circuit court for the county, the trustee cannot locate the unknown or missing owner.</section></section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Following a petition by the trustee made under subsection (c) of this section, the court shall, after notice, hold a hearing on the motion and enter an order requiring the trustee to convey the unknown or missing owner's mineral interest to the named surface owners if:<section prefix="(1)">The unknown or missing owner does not appear to contest the petition; and</section><section prefix="(2)">The court finds that the individuals named in the petition as the surface owners are in fact the fee simple owners of the surface estate or estates.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">If the court orders the conveyance in accordance with subsection (d) of this section, the trustee shall:<section prefix="(1)">Convey by recordable instrument the unknown or missing owner's severed mineral interest to the named surface owners;</section><section prefix="(2)">Pay from any trust account all required taxes, court costs, expenses, and fees, including any fee for services to the trustee authorized by the court;</section><section prefix="(3)">Pay any balance remaining in any trust account after the payments set forth in item (2) of this subsection to the named surface owners;</section><section prefix="(4)">Close any trust account; and</section><section prefix="(5)">Make a final report to the court accounting for the financial transactions of the trust.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">After the conveyance to the surface owners in accordance with subsection (e) of this section, the surface owners shall be entitled to receive all proceeds from the lease of the mineral interest conveyed.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">After receiving the final report of the trustee in accordance with subsection (e)(5) of this section, the court shall order the trust terminated and the trustee discharged.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A trust created under this section shall be administered by the court as provided by the Maryland Rules.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Under this section, procedures for notice to interested persons, the forms of petitions, and the conduct and requirements at a hearing shall be as provided by the Maryland Rules.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
