<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gen" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="9-726.1" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gen-9-726.1</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">If a bill for sewerage service is unpaid for 45 days after being sent, a political subdivision may disconnect water service to the property.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Before disconnecting water service under this section, the political subdivision shall provide notice:<section prefix="(1)">By mail sent to the last known address of the owner of the property; or</section><section prefix="(2)">By posting the notice on the premises of the property served.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This subsection applies if a political subdivision:<section prefix="(i)">Provides sewerage service to a property; but</section><section prefix="(ii)">Does not provide water service to the property and water service is provided to the property by another political subdivision or by a private water company.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If a political subdivision advises another political subdivision or a private water company that a bill for sewerage service is unpaid for 45 days after being sent, subject to the notice provisions under subsection (b) of this section, the political subdivision or private water company informed of the unpaid bill may disconnect water service to the property.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Before reconnecting water service, a political subdivision may require full payment of the sewerage bill plus a reconnection charge reasonably related to the cost of reconnection, as established by regulation of the political subdivision.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A private water company may apply a reasonable reconnection charge, in accordance with the ratemaking requirements of Title 4 of the Public Utilities Article, when it reconnects water service.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">This subsection does not preclude the use of any other procedure available to a political subdivision to collect unpaid sewerage charges.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This subsection applies only to property subject to a condominium regime established under Title 11 of the Real Property Article.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Notwithstanding any other law, if the political subdivision directly bills the governing body of a condominium or a person designated by the governing body of a condominium for water or sewer usage charges for all or a portion of the units in a condominium property, and a charge is in default for at least 60 days, the political subdivision or private water company informed of the unpaid bill shall post notice conspicuously at or near the entry to the common area of the condominium.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The political subdivision may enter onto the common area of a condominium property at a reasonable time to post the notice required under this subsection.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
