<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="get" order_by="" level="1">Estates and Trusts</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>get-1-101</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>101</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In the estates of decedents law the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Administrative probate" is defined in &#xA7; 5-301 of this article.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Book" includes a form of electronic recordation.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">"Child" is defined in &#xA7;&#xA7; 1-205 through 1-208 of this title.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"County" includes Baltimore City.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">"Court" is defined in &#xA7; 2-101 of this article.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Environmental law" means a federal, State, or local law, rule, regulation, or ordinance that relates to the protection of the environment.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Environmental law" includes Title 16 of the Environment Article.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(h)">"Heir" is a person entitled to property of an intestate decedent pursuant to &#xA7;&#xA7; 3-101 through 3-110 of this article.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">"Interested person" is:<section prefix="(1)">A person named as executor in a will;</section><section prefix="(2)">A person serving as personal representative after judicial or administrative probate;</section><section prefix="(3)">A legatee in being, not fully paid, whether his interest is vested or contingent;</section><section prefix="(4)">An heir even if the decedent dies testate, except that an heir of a testate decedent ceases to be an "interested person" when the register has given notice pursuant to &#xA7; 2-210 or &#xA7; 5-403(a) of this article.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(j)">"Issue" is defined in &#xA7; 1-209 of this title.</section>
    <section prefix="(k)">"Judicial probate" is defined in &#xA7; 5-401 of this article.</section>
    <section prefix="(l)">"Legacy" means any property disposed of by will, including property disposed of in a residuary clause and assets passing by the exercise by the decedent of a testamentary power of appointment.</section>
    <section prefix="(m)">"Legatee" means a person who under the terms of a will would receive a legacy. It includes a trustee but not a beneficiary of an interest under the trust.</section>
    <section prefix="(n)">"Letters" include letters testamentary and letters of administration.</section>
    <section prefix="(o)">"Maryland Rules" means the rules promulgated by the Court of Appeals of Maryland under the authority of the Constitution and laws of Maryland.</section>
    <section prefix="(p)">"Net estate" means the property of the decedent exclusive of the family allowance and enforceable claims against the estate, except as used in &#xA7;&#xA7; 3-102 and 3-203 of this article.</section>
    <section prefix="(q)">"Personal representative" includes an executor or administrator but not a special administrator.</section>
    <section prefix="(r)">"Property" includes both real and personal property, and any right or interest therein. "Property" refers to (1) all real and personal property of a decedent and (2) any right or interest therein which does not pass, at the time of the decedent's death, to another person by the terms of the instrument under which it is held, or by operation of law.</section>
    <section prefix="(s)">"Register" is defined in &#xA7; 2-201 of this article.</section>
    <section prefix="(t)">"Representation" is defined in &#xA7; 1-210 of this title.</section>
    <section prefix="(u)">"Special administrator" means an administrator appointed as provided in &#xA7; 6-401 of this article.</section>
    <section prefix="(v)">"Trust company" means an institution that is authorized to exercise trust or fiduciary powers and that:<section prefix="(1)">Is organized under the laws of this State as a State bank, trust company, or savings bank; or</section><section prefix="(2)">Is organized under the laws of the United States and:<section prefix="(i)">Has its principal office in this State; or</section><section prefix="(ii)"><section prefix="1.">Has an office in this State that is not its principal office; and</section><section prefix="2.">Meets the definition of a trust institution under 12 U.S.C. &#xA7; 1841(c)(2)(D); or</section></section><section prefix="(iii)"><section prefix="1.">Has an office in this State that is not its principal office; and</section><section prefix="2.">Accepts deposits at its office in this State; or</section></section></section><section prefix="(3)">Is organized under the laws of another state as a bank, trust company, or savings bank and:<section prefix="(i)"><section prefix="1.">Has an office in this State that is not its principal office;</section><section prefix="2.">Meets the definition of a trust institution under 12 U.S.C. &#xA7; 1841(c)(2)(D); and</section><section prefix="3.">Is a direct or indirect subsidiary of a bank holding company that has a direct or indirect bank, trust company, or savings bank subsidiary that has an office in this State at which deposits are accepted; or</section></section><section prefix="(ii)"><section prefix="1.">Has an office in this State that is not its principal office; and</section><section prefix="2.">Accepts deposits at its office in this State.</section></section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(w)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Will" means a written instrument which is executed in the form prescribed by &#xA7;&#xA7; 4-102 through 4-104 of this article, and has not been revoked in a manner provided by &#xA7; 4-105 of this article.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Will" includes a codicil.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
