<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="get" order_by="" level="1">Estates and Trusts</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>get-14-401</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>401</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Adult" means an individual who is at least 18 years of age.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Beneficiary" means an individual for whose present benefit property is held by a trustee in accordance with this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">"Conservator" means a person appointed or qualified by a court to act as general, limited, or temporary guardian of an individual's property or a person legally authorized to perform substantially the same functions.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"Court" means the circuit courts of the State of Maryland.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">"Declarant" means a transferor who creates a trust under this subtitle and serves as the trustee.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">"Guardian" means a person appointed or qualified by a court as a guardian of the person of an individual, including a limited guardian, but not a person who is only a guardian ad litem.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">"Legal representative" means a personal representative, conservator, or an attorney in fact under a durable power of attorney.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">"Member of the beneficiary's family" means a beneficiary's spouse, descendant, stepchild, parent, stepparent, grandparent, brother, sister, uncle, or aunt, whether of the whole or half blood or by adoption.</section>
    <section prefix="(j)">"Person" means an adult, corporation, organization, or any other legal entity.</section>
    <section prefix="(k)">"Personal representative" means an executor, administrator, or special administrator of a decedent's estate, a person legally authorized to perform substantially the same functions, or a successor to any of them.</section>
    <section prefix="(l)">"State" means the United States of America, a state or subdivision thereof, a territory or possession of the United States, the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, and any territory or possession subject to the legislative authority of the United States.</section>
    <section prefix="(m)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Transferor" means a person who creates a trust by transfer or declaration under this subtitle.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Transferor" does not include a person, other than the person who created the trust, who augments an existing trust.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(n)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Trust" means a trust created under this subtitle.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Trust" does not include a trust created by the transferor for the benefit of the transferor.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(o)">"Trust property" means any property, income, or proceeds resulting from the investment of property held in trust under this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(p)">"Trustee" means a person authorized by law to act as trustee who is designated as trustee of a trust under this subtitle or successor to the person designated.</section>
  </text>
</law>
