<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="get" order_by="get" level="1">Estates and Trusts</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>get-15-516</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this section the following words have the meanings indicated....</catch_line>
  <order_by>516</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">"Payment" means a payment that a trustee may receive over a fixed number of years or during the life of one or more individuals because of services rendered or property transferred to the payer in exchange for future payments.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">"Payment" includes:<section prefix="1.">A payment made in money or property from the payer's general assets or from a separate fund created by the payer; or</section><section prefix="2.">For the purposes of subsection (d), (e), (f), or (g) of this section, any payment from a separate fund, regardless of the reason for the payment.</section></section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Separate fund" includes a private or commercial annuity, an individual retirement account, and a pension, profit-sharing, stock-bonus, or stock-ownership plan.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">To the extent that a payment is characterized as interest, a dividend, or a payment made in lieu of interest or a dividend, a trustee shall allocate the payment to income. The trustee shall allocate to principal the balance of the payment and any other payment received in the same accounting period that is not characterized as interest, a dividend, or an equivalent payment.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">If no part of a payment is characterized as interest, a dividend, or an equivalent payment, and all or part of the payment is required to be made, a trustee shall allocate to income 10 percent of the part that is required to be made during the accounting period and the balance to principal. If no part of a payment is required to be made or the payment received is the entire amount to which the trustee is entitled, the trustee shall allocate the entire payment to principal. For purposes of this subsection, a payment is not "required to be made" to the extent that it is made because the trustee exercises a right of withdrawal.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Except as otherwise provided in subsection (e) of this section, subsections (f) and (g) of this section apply, and subsections (b) and (c) of this section do not apply, in determining the allocation of a payment made from a separate fund to:<section prefix="(1)">A trust to which an election to qualify for a marital deduction under &#xA7; 2056(b)(7) of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 has been made; or</section><section prefix="(2)">A trust that qualifies for the marital deduction under &#xA7; 2056(b)(5) of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">Subsections (d), (f), and (g) of this section do not apply if, and to the extent that, the series of payments would, without the application of subsection (d) of this section, qualify for the marital deduction under &#xA7; 2056(b)(7)(C) of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A trustee shall determine the internal income of each separate fund for the accounting period as if the separate fund were a trust subject to this subtitle.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">On request of the surviving spouse, the trustee shall demand that the person administering the separate fund distribute the internal income to the trust.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The trustee shall allocate:<section prefix="(i)">A payment from the separate fund to income to the extent of the amount of the internal income of the separate fund and distribute that amount to the surviving spouse; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">The balance of the payment to principal.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">On request of the surviving spouse, the trustee shall allocate principal to income to the extent the internal income of the separate fund exceeds payments made from the separate fund to the trust during the accounting period.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If a trustee cannot determine the internal income of a separate fund but can determine the value of the separate fund, the internal income of the separate fund is deemed to equal 4% of the fund's value, according to the most recent statement of value before the beginning of the accounting period.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If the trustee cannot determine both the internal income of the separate fund and the fund's value, the internal income of the fund is deemed to equal the product of the interest rate and the present value of the expected future payments, as determined under &#xA7; 7520 of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 for the month preceding the accounting period for which the computation is made.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(h)">This section does not apply to payments to which &#xA7; 15-517 of this subtitle applies.</section>
  </text>
</law>
