<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="get" order_by="" level="1">Estates and Trusts</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>get-17-108</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>108</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">A power of attorney executed in this State is valid and enforceable as to persons dealing with the agent.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A power of attorney executed other than in this State is valid and enforceable in this State as to persons dealing with the agent if, when the power of attorney was executed, the execution complied with:<section prefix="(1)">The law of the jurisdiction that determines the meaning and effect of the power of attorney; or</section><section prefix="(2)">The requirements for a military power of attorney in accordance with 10 U.S.C. &#xA7; 1044b.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as otherwise provided by law other than this title and subject to paragraph (2) of this subsection, a photocopy or electronically transmitted copy of an original power of attorney is as valid and binding as the original power of attorney.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A clerk of court may refuse to record a photocopy or electronically transmitted copy of an original power of attorney.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A principal may delegate to one or more agents the authority to do any act specified in the statutory forms in Subtitle 2 of this title.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Notwithstanding paragraph (1) of this subsection, if a principal designates one or more coagents, all coagents shall act together unanimously unless the power of attorney otherwise provides.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The acts specified in the statutory forms may not, notwithstanding paragraph (1) of this subsection, be deemed to invalidate or limit the validity of other authorized acts that a principal may delegate to an agent.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
