<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="get" order_by="get" level="1">Estates and Trusts</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>get-9-209</section_number>
  <catch_line>Subject to subsections (b) through (k) of this section, delivery of a disclaimer may be effected by ...</catch_line>
  <order_by>209</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Subject to subsections (b) through (k) of this section, delivery of a disclaimer may be effected by personal delivery, first-class mail, or any other method likely to result in its receipt.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">In the case of an interest created under the law of intestate succession or an interest created by will, other than an interest in a testamentary trust:<section prefix="(1)">A disclaimer shall be delivered to the personal representative for the decedent's estate; or</section><section prefix="(2)">If there is no personal representative, it shall be filed with a court having jurisdiction to appoint the personal representative.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">In the case of an interest in a testamentary trust:<section prefix="(1)">A disclaimer shall be delivered to the trustee, or if no trustee is then serving, to the personal representative of the decedent's estate; or</section><section prefix="(2)">If there is no personal representative, it shall be filed with a court having jurisdiction to enforce the trust.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In the case of an interest in an inter vivos trust, a disclaimer shall be delivered to the trustee.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If there is no trustee, it shall be filed with a court having jurisdiction to enforce the trust.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">If the disclaimer is made before the time the instrument creating the trust becomes irrevocable, it shall be delivered to the settlor of a revocable trust or the transferor of the interest.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">In the case of an interest created by a beneficiary designation made before the time the designation becomes irrevocable, a disclaimer shall be delivered to the person making the beneficiary designation.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">In the case of an interest created by a beneficiary designation made after the time the designation becomes irrevocable, a disclaimer shall be delivered to the person obligated to distribute the interest.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">In the case of a disclaimer by a surviving holder of jointly held property, the disclaimer shall be delivered to the person to whom the disclaimed interest passes.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">In the case of a disclaimer by an object or taker in default of exercise of a power of appointment at any time after the power was created:<section prefix="(1)">The disclaimer shall be delivered to the holder of the power or to the fiduciary acting under the instrument that created the power; or</section><section prefix="(2)">If there is no fiduciary, it shall be filed with a court having authority to appoint the fiduciary.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(i)">In the case of a disclaimer by an appointee of a nonfiduciary power of appointment:<section prefix="(1)">The disclaimer shall be delivered to the holder, the personal representative of the holder's estate, or to the fiduciary under the instrument that created the power; or</section><section prefix="(2)">If there is no fiduciary, it shall be filed with a court having authority to appoint the fiduciary.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(j)">In the case of a disclaimer by a fiduciary of a power over a trust or estate, the disclaimer shall be delivered as provided in subsection (b), (c), or (d) of this section as if the power disclaimed were an interest in property.</section>
    <section prefix="(k)">In the case of a disclaimer of a power by an agent, the disclaimer shall be delivered to the principal or the principal's representative.</section>
  </text>
</law>
