<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="get" order_by="" level="1">Estates and Trusts</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>get-5-201</section_number>
  <catch_line>The petition for probate shall contain all knowledge or information of the petitioner with respect t...</catch_line>
  <order_by>201</order_by>
  <text>The petition for probate shall contain all knowledge or information of the petitioner with respect to the items listed in this section.<section prefix="(a)">It shall state the name, domicile, place, and date of death of the decedent.</section><section prefix="(b)">It shall state the interest of the person filing the petition.</section><section prefix="(c)">It shall state the county in which the decedent was domiciled at the time of his death and, if not domiciled in Maryland, the county in this State which the petitioner believes was the situs of the largest part in value of the property of the decedent at the time of his death.</section><section prefix="(d)">It shall list all other proceedings filed in Maryland and elsewhere regarding the same estate.</section><section prefix="(e)">It shall state whether the decedent died testate or intestate, and<section prefix="(1)">If testate, there shall be exhibited with the petition the will or a copy of the will. If this exhibit cannot be produced, a statement of the reasons for the inability, the name, and the address of the person in whose custody the documents may be, a statement of the provisions of the will as far as known to the petitioner, and a statement of the manner in which the exhibit came into the hands of the petitioner as well as a statement that he knows of no later will; or</section><section prefix="(2)">If intestate, a statement of the extent of a search for a will.</section></section><section prefix="(f)">It shall state the names and addresses of all persons who are witnesses to the will referred to in subsection (e)(1) of this section.</section></text>
</law>
