<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="get" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="4-506" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>get-4-506</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Except as otherwise provided in subsection (g) of this section and subject to subsection (f) of this section, in the absence of an express, contrary indication by the donor, a person other than the donor is barred from making, amending, or revoking an anatomical gift of a donor's body or part if the donor made:<section prefix="(1)">An anatomical gift of the donor's body or part under &#xA7; 4-503 of this subtitle; or</section><section prefix="(2)">An amendment to an anatomical gift of the donor's body or part under &#xA7; 4-504 of this subtitle.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A donor's revocation of an anatomical gift of the donor's body or part under &#xA7; 4-504 of this subtitle is not a refusal and does not bar another person specified in &#xA7; 4-501 or &#xA7; 4-507 of this subtitle from making an anatomical gift of the donor's body or part under &#xA7; 4-503 or &#xA7; 4-508 of this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">If a person other than a donor makes an unrevoked anatomical gift of the donor's body or part under &#xA7; 4-503 of this subtitle, or an amendment to an anatomical gift of the donor's body or part under &#xA7; 4-504 of this subtitle, another person may not make, amend, or revoke the gift of the donor's body or part under &#xA7; 4-508 of this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A revocation of an anatomical gift of a donor's body or part under &#xA7; 4-504 of this subtitle by a person other than the donor does not bar another person from making an anatomical gift of the body or part under &#xA7; 4-503 or &#xA7; 4-508 of this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">In the absence of an express, contrary indication by the donor or other person authorized to make an anatomical gift under &#xA7; 4-503 of this subtitle, an anatomical gift of a part is not a refusal to give another part or a limitation on the making of an anatomical gift of another part at a later time by the donor or another person.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">In the absence of an express, contrary indication by the donor or other person authorized to make an anatomical gift under &#xA7; 4-503 of this subtitle, an anatomical gift of a part for one or more of the purposes set forth in &#xA7; 4-503 of this subtitle is not a limitation on the making of an anatomical gift of the part for any other purpose by the donor or other person under &#xA7; 4-503 or &#xA7; 4-508 of this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">If a donor who is an unemancipated minor dies, a reasonably available parent or guardian of the donor may revoke or amend an anatomical gift of the donor's body or part.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">If an unemancipated minor who signed a refusal dies, a reasonably available parent or guardian of the minor may revoke the minor's refusal.</section>
  </text>
</law>
