<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="get" order_by="" level="1">Estates and Trusts</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>get-2-206</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>206</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The registers of wills are entitled to charge and collect for the performance of their duties the fees in this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">For taking probate of wills and furnishing 2 certified copies of the will and codicils, granting letters of administration and furnishing 12 certificates of letters, issuing warrants to appraise, entering on estate docket, filing elections of surviving spouses to take intestate shares, filing renunciations and disclaimers, filing and recording wills, bonds, inventories, accounts of sale, releases, administration accounts, petitions and orders, and other papers filed in the administration of decedents' estates not otherwise specified in subsections (c) through (l) of this section, the probate fees under paragraph (2) of this subsection.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Probate fees shall be assessed on the value of the probate estate at the following rates:</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Except as provided in paragraph (4) of this subsection, for purposes of determinations under paragraph (2) of this subsection, the value of a probate estate is the amount, as reflected in the administration accounts filed in the proceedings, that equals:<section prefix="(i)">The sum of:<section prefix="1.">The value of all inventories filed in the proceedings;</section><section prefix="2.">All principal and income receipts; and</section><section prefix="3.">All increases realized on a disposition, other than a distribution to beneficiaries, of any probate asset; less</section></section><section prefix="(ii)">All decreases realized on a disposition, other than a distribution to beneficiaries, of any probate asset.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">If an estate proceeds through modified administration, for the purpose of determining the appropriate fee under paragraph (2) of this subsection, the value of an estate is the gross value of the probate assets reported on the final report under modified administration.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Except as provided in subparagraphs (ii) and (iii) of this paragraph, the register shall assess and collect the probate fee when the first administration account is filed.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">If there are any additions to the value of a probate estate, as reflected in any subsequent administration account, the register shall:<section prefix="1.">Assess an additional fee in an amount equal to the excess of:</section><section prefix="2.">Collect the additional fee when the subsequent administration account is filed.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">If an estate proceeds through modified administration, the register shall assess and collect the probate fee when the personal representative files the final report under modified administration.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">For furnishing additional certificates of letters, with seal $1</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">For affixing seal of office to a transcript or other paper, if expressly required by law or a person  $1</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">For affixing seal of office to a certificate, transcript, or other paper exemplified under the act of Congress $2</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">For passing and entering every claim or voucher against an estate of a deceased person, and endorsing certificate on each claim or voucher when passed by the court or register, for each $3</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">For  entering papers  in caveat or other controversial  matter, for each side$10</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">For transcribing papers filed in caveat or other controversial proceedings when taken to higher court, per page or part of a page $2</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">For recording papers filed in caveat or other controversial proceedings, when mandate of higher court is filed, per page or part of a page $2</section>
    <section prefix="(j)">For copies of a paper or record, including plain certification and seal, per page or part of a page  $2</section>
    <section prefix="(k)">For photostatic or other artificially reproduced copies of a paper or record, per page or part of a page  50 cents</section>
    <section prefix="(l)">For receiving a will for deposit during the lifetime of the testator $5</section>
    <section prefix="(m)">For  all  filing  and  entries  regarding  a  guardianship proceeding, a single fee of $20</section>
    <section prefix="(n)">For receiving and paying over an inheritance tax due the State, the register is allowed a commission of 25% of the inheritance tax.</section>
    <section prefix="(o)">For providing a probate information booklet and materials  $2</section>
    <section prefix="(p)">For all proceedings involving a foreign personal representative, a single fee of 1% of the gross value of the estate, not to exceed $100.</section>
  </text>
</law>
