<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="get" order_by="get" level="1">Estates and Trusts</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>get-13-301</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated....</catch_line>
  <order_by>301</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Adult" means an individual who has attained the age of 21 years.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Broker" means a person lawfully engaged in the business of effecting transactions in securities or commodities for the person's own account or for the account of others.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">"Conservator" means a person appointed or qualified by a court to act as general, limited, or temporary guardian of a minor's property or a person legally authorized to perform substantially the same functions.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"Court" means a circuit court, an orphans' court, or a court exercising the jurisdiction of an orphans' court.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">"Custodial property" means:<section prefix="(1)">Any interest in property transferred to a custodian under this subtitle; and</section><section prefix="(2)">The income from and proceeds of that interest in property.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(g)">"Custodian" means a person so designated under &#xA7; 13-309 of this subtitle or a successor or substitute custodian designated under &#xA7; 13-318 of this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">"Financial institution" means a bank, trust company, savings institution, or credit union chartered and supervised under State or federal law.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">"Legal representative" means an individual's personal representative or conservator.</section>
    <section prefix="(j)">"Member of the minor's family" means the minor's parent, stepparent, spouse, grandparent, brother, sister, uncle, or aunt, whether of the whole or half blood or by adoption.</section>
    <section prefix="(k)">"Minor" means an individual who has not attained the age of 21 years.</section>
    <section prefix="(l)">"Person" means an individual, corporation, organization, or other legal entity.</section>
    <section prefix="(m)">"Personal representative" means an executor, administrator, successor personal representative, or special administrator of a decedent's estate or a person legally authorized to perform substantially the same functions.</section>
    <section prefix="(n)">"Qualified minor's trust" means a trust, including a trust created by a custodian for the use and benefit of a minor:<section prefix="(1)">Of which a minor is the sole beneficiary during the minor's lifetime; and</section><section prefix="(2)">That meets the requirements of &#xA7; 2503(c) of the Internal Revenue Code and the regulations implementing that section.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(o)">"State" includes any state of the United States, the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, and any territory or possession subject to the legislative authority of the United States.</section>
    <section prefix="(p)">"Transfer" means a transaction that creates custodial property under &#xA7; 13-309 of this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(q)">"Transferor" means a person who makes a transfer under this subtitle.</section>
  </text>
</law>
