<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="get" order_by="get" level="1">Estates and Trusts</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>get-3-203</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this section, "net estate" means the property of the decedent passing by testate succession, with...</catch_line>
  <order_by>203</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, "net estate" means the property of the decedent passing by testate succession, without a deduction for State or federal estate or inheritance taxes, and reduced by:<section prefix="(1)">Funeral and administration expenses;</section><section prefix="(2)">Family allowances; and</section><section prefix="(3)">Enforceable claims and debts against the estate.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Instead of property left to the surviving spouse by will, the surviving spouse may elect to take a one-third share of the net estate if there is also a surviving issue, or a one-half share of the net estate if there is no surviving issue.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The surviving spouse who makes this election may not take more than a one-half share of the net estate.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">For the purposes of this section, the net estate and the property allocable to a share of a surviving spouse shall be valued as of the date or dates of distribution.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">For the purposes of this section, a surviving spouse who has elected to take against a will shall be entitled to the surviving spouse's portion of the income earned on the net estate during the period of administration based on a one-third or one-half share, whichever is applicable.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If one or more distributions have been made to a surviving spouse or another person that require an adjustment in the relative interests of the beneficiaries, the applicable share shall be adjusted.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
