<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="get" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="14-106" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>get-14-106</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, "beneficiary" means a person in being who has a vested interest, whether:<section prefix="(1)">Possessory or not; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Subject to divestment or not.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Subject to the provisions of paragraph (2) of this subsection, on petition by a trustee, personal representative, beneficiary, or a party in interest, after notice as the court may direct to the trustees, personal representatives, beneficiaries, and parties in interest, and for good cause shown, a court may:<section prefix="(i)">Divide a trust into 2 or more separate trusts; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">Consolidate 2 or more trusts into a single trust.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A court may divide a trust or consolidate trusts:<section prefix="(i)">On terms and conditions as the court considers appropriate; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">If the court is satisfied that a division of a trust or consolidation of trusts will not defeat or materially impair:</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A court may pass orders that the court considers proper or necessary to protect the interests of a:<section prefix="(i)">Trustee;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Personal representative;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Beneficiary; or</section><section prefix="(iv)">Party in interest.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">This section applies to trusts:<section prefix="(1)">Whenever created;</section><section prefix="(2)">Whether inter vivos or testamentary;</section><section prefix="(3)">Created by the same or different instruments;</section><section prefix="(4)">Created by the same or different persons; and</section><section prefix="(5)">Regardless of where created or administered.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">This section may not be construed to limit the right of a trustee or personal representative to divide a trust or consolidate trusts, without an order of a court, in accordance with the applicable provisions of the governing instrument.</section>
  </text>
</law>
