<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="get" order_by="get" level="1">Estates and Trusts</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>get-2-211</section_number>
  <catch_line>The register shall maintain in the register's office, for the purpose of recording the proceedings i...</catch_line>
  <order_by>211</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The register shall maintain in the register's office, for the purpose of recording the proceedings in connection with the administration of estates, a wills record book, an administration proceedings record book, a release record book, and a claims docket in addition to the claims against the nonresident decedents book described in &#xA7; 5-503 of this article.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Immediately upon the administrative or judicial probate of a will the register shall record it, with every paper incidental to probate, in the wills record book, and the register shall index it under the name of the decedent.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Upon the final approval of the final administration account, all inventories, accounts, petitions, notices to creditors, and orders of court shall be recorded by the register in the administration proceedings record book, and indexed under the name of the decedent.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Every release shall be promptly recorded by the register in the release record book, in the order of their filing, and shall be indexed under the name of the releasor.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Every claim filed with the register under the provisions of &#xA7; 8-104(c) of this article shall be entered by the register in the claims docket promptly upon receipt so that the record shall show the name of the claimant, the nature of the claim, and the amount of the claim.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Every entry relating to an estate or a decedent shall be indexed under the name of the decedent.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
