<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="get" order_by="get" level="1">Estates and Trusts</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>get-4-501</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated....</catch_line>
  <order_by>501</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Agent" means an individual:<section prefix="(1)">Authorized to make health care decisions on behalf of a principal by a power of attorney for health care; or</section><section prefix="(2)">Expressly authorized to make an anatomical gift on behalf of a principal by a record signed by the principal.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Anatomical gift" means a donation of all or part of a human body to take effect after the donor's death for the purpose of transplantation, therapy, research, or education.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Decedent" means a deceased individual whose body or part is or may be the source of an anatomical gift.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Decedent" includes:<section prefix="(i)">A stillborn infant; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Subject to restrictions imposed by law other than this subtitle, a fetus.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Decedent" does not include a blastocyst, embryo, or fetus that is the subject of an induced abortion.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Disinterested witness" means a witness other than:<section prefix="(i)">A spouse, child, parent, sibling, grandchild, grandparent, or guardian of an individual who makes, amends, revokes, or refuses to make an anatomical gift; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">Another adult who exhibits special care and concern for an individual who makes, amends, revokes, or refuses to make an anatomical gift.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Disinterested witness" does not include a person to which an anatomical gift may pass under &#xA7; 4-509 of this subtitle.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Document of gift" means a donor card or any other record used to make an anatomical gift.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Document of gift" includes a statement or symbol on a driver's license, an identification card, or a donor registry.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">"Donor" means an individual whose body or part is the subject of an anatomical gift.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">"Donor registry" means a database that contains records of anatomical gifts and amendments to or revocations of anatomical gifts as provided in &#xA7; 4-516 of this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Driver's license" means a license or permit issued by the Motor Vehicle Administration to operate a vehicle, whether or not conditions are attached to the license or permit.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Driver's license" includes a learner's permit.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(j)">"Emancipated minor" means a person under the age of 18 years who is:<section prefix="(1)">Married;</section><section prefix="(2)">A parent;</section><section prefix="(3)">Serving in the military;</section><section prefix="(4)">Emancipated by court order;</section><section prefix="(5)">Living separately from the parents of the person and is self-supporting; or</section><section prefix="(6)">Emancipated for another purpose recognized by law.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(k)">"Eye bank" means a person that:<section prefix="(1)">Is licensed, accredited, or regulated under federal or state law to engage in the recovery, screening, testing, processing, storage, or distribution of human eyes or portions of human eyes;</section><section prefix="(2)">Is accredited by the Eye Bank Association of America or the American Association of Tissue Banks; and</section><section prefix="(3)">Has a permit issued in accordance with Title 17, Subtitle 3 of the Health - General Article.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(l)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Guardian" means a person appointed by a court to make decisions regarding the support, care, education, health, or welfare of an individual.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Guardian" does not include a guardian ad litem, unless the guardian ad litem is authorized by a court to consent to donation.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(m)">"Hospital" means a facility licensed as a hospital under the law of any state or a facility operated as a hospital by the United States, a state, or a subdivision of a state.</section>
    <section prefix="(n)">"Identification card" means an identification card issued by the Motor Vehicle Administration.</section>
    <section prefix="(o)">"Know" means to have actual knowledge.</section>
    <section prefix="(p)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Nontransplant tissue bank" means a person that recovers, screens, procures, transports, stores, or arranges for the storage and distribution of a body or part solely for the purpose of research, training, or education.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Nontransplant tissue bank" includes:<section prefix="(i)">The State Anatomy Board;</section><section prefix="(ii)">A program for a purpose described in paragraph (1) of this subsection operated by officers or employees of the United States; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">A nonprofit organization described in paragraph (1) of this subsection permitted to operate under &#xA7; 5-409 of the Health - General Article.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Nontransplant tissue bank" does not include:<section prefix="(i)">An eye bank;</section><section prefix="(ii)">An organ procurement organization; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">A transplant tissue bank.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(q)">"OCME" means the Office of the Chief Medical Examiner.</section>
    <section prefix="(r)">"Organ procurement organization" means a person designated by the Secretary of the United States Department of Health and Human Services as an organ procurement organization.</section>
    <section prefix="(s)">"Parent" means a parent whose parental rights have not been terminated.</section>
    <section prefix="(t)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Part" means an organ, an eye, or tissue of a human being.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Part" does not include the whole body.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(u)">"Physician" means an individual authorized to practice medicine or osteopathy under the law of any state.</section>
    <section prefix="(v)">"Procurement organization" means an eye bank, an organ procurement organization, or a tissue bank.</section>
    <section prefix="(w)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Prospective donor" means an individual who is dead or whose death is imminent and has been determined by a procurement organization to have a part that could be medically suitable for transplantation, therapy, research, or education.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Prospective donor" does not include an individual who has made a refusal.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(x)">"Reasonably available" means able to be contacted by a procurement organization without undue effort and willing and able to act in a timely manner consistent with existing medical criteria necessary for the making of an anatomical gift.</section>
    <section prefix="(y)">"Recipient" means an individual into whose body a decedent's part has been or is intended to be transplanted.</section>
    <section prefix="(z)">"Record" means information that is inscribed on a tangible medium or is stored in an electronic or any other medium and is retrievable in perceivable form.</section>
    <section prefix="(aa)">"Refusal" means a record created under &#xA7; 4-505 of this subtitle that expressly states an intent to bar other persons from making an anatomical gift of an individual's body or part.</section>
    <section prefix="(bb)">"Sign" means to:<section prefix="(1)">Have present intent to authenticate or adopt a record; and</section><section prefix="(2)"><section prefix="(i)">Execute or adopt a tangible symbol; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">Attach to or logically associate with the record an electronic symbol, sound, or process.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(cc)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Technician" means an individual determined to be qualified to remove or process parts by an appropriate organization that is licensed, accredited, or regulated under federal or state law.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Technician" includes an enucleator.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(dd)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Tissue" means a portion of the human body other than an organ or eye.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Tissue" does not include:<section prefix="(i)">Blood unless the blood is donated for the purpose of research or education; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">An ovum or sperm for the purpose of creating an embryo to use in therapy, research, or education, unless the anatomical gift is made by the donor to the spouse of the donor.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(ee)">"Tissue bank" means a transplant tissue bank or nontransplant tissue bank.</section>
    <section prefix="(ff)">"Transplant hospital" means a hospital that furnishes organ transplants and other medical and surgical specialty services required for the care of transplant patients.</section>
    <section prefix="(gg)">"Transplant tissue bank" means a person that is licensed, accredited, or regulated under federal or State law to engage in the recovery, screening, testing, processing, storage, or distribution of tissue in accordance with Title 17, Subtitle 3 of the Health - General Article.</section>
  </text>
</law>
