<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="get" order_by="get" level="1">Estates and Trusts</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>get-4-603</section_number>
  <catch_line>An international will:...</catch_line>
  <order_by>603</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">An international will:<section prefix="(1)">Shall be made in writing;</section><section prefix="(2)">Does not need to be written by the testator;</section><section prefix="(3)">May be written in any language; and</section><section prefix="(4)">May be written by hand or by any other means.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The testator shall declare in the presence of at least two witnesses and a person authorized to act in connection with international wills that the document is the testator's will and that the testator knows the contents of the document.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The testator need not inform the witnesses or the authorized person of the contents of the will.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">In the presence of the witnesses and of the authorized person, a testator shall:<section prefix="(1)">Sign the will; or</section><section prefix="(2)">If the testator has previously signed the will, acknowledge the testator's signature.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If a testator is unable to sign, the absence of the testator's signature does not affect the validity of the will if:<section prefix="(i)">The testator indicates the reason for the testator's inability to sign; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">The authorized person makes note on the will of the reason for the testator's inability to sign.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If a testator is unable to sign, another person present, including the authorized person or one of the witnesses, may sign the testator's name for the testator if:<section prefix="(i)">The other person signs at the direction of the testator; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">The authorized person makes note on the will of the other person signing the testator's name at the direction of the testator.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Notwithstanding paragraph (2) of this subsection, a person is not required to sign the testator's name at the testator's direction.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The witnesses and the authorized person shall there and then attest the will by signing their names in the presence of the testator.</section>
  </text>
</law>
