<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="get" order_by="" level="1">Estates and Trusts</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>get-13.5-204</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>204</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">A court of this State having jurisdiction under &#xA7; 13.5-201 of this subtitle to appoint a guardian or issue a protective order may decline to exercise jurisdiction if the court determines at any time that a court of another state is a more appropriate forum.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If a court of this State declines jurisdiction over a guardianship proceeding or protective proceeding under subsection (a) of this section, the court shall either dismiss the proceeding or stay the proceeding.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A court under paragraph (1) of this subsection may impose any other condition the court considers just and proper, including the condition that a petition for the appointment of a guardian or protective order be promptly filed in another state.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">In determining whether the court is an appropriate forum, a court shall consider all relevant factors, including:<section prefix="(1)">An expressed preference of the respondent;</section><section prefix="(2)">Whether abuse, neglect, or exploitation of the respondent has occurred or is likely to occur and which state could best protect the respondent from the abuse, neglect, or exploitation;</section><section prefix="(3)">The length of time the respondent was physically located in or was a legal resident of this State or another state;</section><section prefix="(4)">The distance of the respondent from the court in each state;</section><section prefix="(5)">The financial circumstances of the estate of the respondent;</section><section prefix="(6)">The nature and location of the evidence;</section><section prefix="(7)">The ability of the court in each state to decide the issue expeditiously and the procedures necessary to present evidence;</section><section prefix="(8)">The familiarity of the court of each state with the facts and issues in the proceeding; and</section><section prefix="(9)">If an appointment were made, the ability of the court to monitor the conduct of the guardian or conservator.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
