<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="get" order_by="get" level="1">Estates and Trusts</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>get-15-1A-01</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated....</catch_line>
  <order_by>01</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Bank" has the meaning stated in 12 U.S.C. &#xA7; 1841(c).</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Bank holding company" has the meaning stated in 12 U.S.C. &#xA7; 1841(a).</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Beneficiary" means a person who receives or is entitled as a matter of right to receive a current distribution of principal or income from a trust, estate, or fund with respect to which a substitution of a corporate fiduciary is made under this subtitle.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Beneficiary" includes:<section prefix="(i)">If the beneficiary is a minor, the beneficiary's natural or legal guardian; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">If the beneficiary is a disabled person, as defined in &#xA7; 13-101 of this article, any person acting on behalf of the beneficiary under a guardianship, conservatorship, or committee.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"Capital requirement" means a provision in any court order, statute, regulation, or writing, including a will, trust, or similar document or instrument, that requires a fiduciary to have a specified minimum amount of capital or capital and surplus.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">"Corporate fiduciary" means:<section prefix="(1)">A bank;</section><section prefix="(2)">A trust company; or</section><section prefix="(3)">Any other corporate entity that is authorized to act as a fiduciary under the laws of this State.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(g)">"Fiduciary" includes:<section prefix="(1)">A trustee;</section><section prefix="(2)">An executor or executrix;</section><section prefix="(3)">A personal representative;</section><section prefix="(4)">A receiver;</section><section prefix="(5)">A special administrator;</section><section prefix="(6)">A guardian;</section><section prefix="(7)">A conservator;</section><section prefix="(8)">A committee;</section><section prefix="(9)">A custodian under the Maryland Uniform Transfers to Minors Act; and</section><section prefix="(10)">Any other person who has a fiduciary relationship the responsibilities of which are customarily performed by a corporate fiduciary.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(h)">"Successor fiduciary" means a corporate fiduciary that is substituted for another corporate fiduciary under the provisions of &#xA7; 15-1A-02 of this subtitle, by reason of:<section prefix="(1)">A merger or consolidation of corporate fiduciaries;</section><section prefix="(2)">The acquisition of the stock or assets of a corporate fiduciary by another corporate fiduciary;</section><section prefix="(3)">The transfer by a corporate fiduciary of its trust and fiduciary business to another corporate fiduciary; or</section><section prefix="(4)">The acquisition or formation by a corporate fiduciary of a subsidiary, which is itself a corporate fiduciary, in order to undertake the trust and fiduciary business of the subsidiary's parent entity.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(i)">"Trust company" has the meaning stated in &#xA7; 1-101 of this article.</section>
  </text>
</law>
