<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="get" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="5-105" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>get-5-105</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Subject to &#xA7; 5-104 of this subtitle, the register or court may grant letters to:<section prefix="(1)">A trust company;</section><section prefix="(2)">Any other corporation authorized by law to be a personal representative; or</section><section prefix="(3)">Subject to subsection (b) of this section, any individual.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Letters may not be granted to a person who, at the time a determination of priority is made, has filed with the register a declaration in writing that the person renounces the right to administer or is:<section prefix="(1)">Under the age of 18 years;</section><section prefix="(2)">Mentally incompetent;</section><section prefix="(3)">Convicted of a serious crime;</section><section prefix="(4)">Not a citizen of the United States unless the person is a permanent resident of the United States and is:<section prefix="(i)">The spouse of the decedent;</section><section prefix="(ii)">An ancestor of the decedent;</section><section prefix="(iii)">A descendant of the decedent; or</section><section prefix="(iv)">A sibling of the decedent;</section></section><section prefix="(5)">A full-time judge of a court established under the laws of Maryland or the United States including, a judge of an orphans' or probate court, or a clerk of court, or a register, unless the person is the surviving spouse or is related to the decedent within the third degree; or</section><section prefix="(6)">A nonresident of the State, unless there shall be on file with the register an irrevocable designation by the nonresident of an appropriate person who resides in the State on whom service of process may be made in the same manner and with the effect as if it were served personally in the State on the nonresident.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
