<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="get" order_by="" level="1">Estates and Trusts</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>get-13-904</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>904</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A parent may designate a standby guardian by means of a written designation:<section prefix="(i)">Signed in the presence of two witnesses, at least 18 years old, neither of whom is the standby guardian; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Signed by the standby guardian.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">If a parent is physically unable to sign a written designation, another person may sign the designation on the parent's behalf and at the parent's direction.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">
          <section prefix="1.">A designation under this paragraph shall be signed in the presence of the parent and two witnesses at least 18 years of age, neither of whom may be the standby guardian.</section>
          <section prefix="2.">The standby guardian also shall sign a designation under this paragraph.</section>
        </section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A designation of a standby guardian shall identify the parent, the minor, and the person designated to be the standby guardian, state the duties of the standby guardian, and indicate that the parent intends for the standby guardian to become the minor's guardian in the event the parent either:<section prefix="(i)">Becomes incapacitated; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">Becomes debilitated and consents to the beginning of the standby guardian's authority.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A parent may designate an alternate standby guardian in the same writing and by the same manner as the designation of a standby guardian.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A designation may, but need not, be in the following form:</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">A consent by another person with parental rights to a designation of a standby guardian by a parent may, but need not be, in the following form:</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The authority of the standby guardian under a designation shall begin on:<section prefix="(1)">The standby guardian's receipt of a copy of a determination of incapacity under &#xA7; 13-906 of this subtitle; or</section><section prefix="(2)">The standby guardian's receipt of:<section prefix="(i)">A copy of a determination of debilitation under &#xA7; 13-906 of this subtitle;</section><section prefix="(ii)">A copy of the parent's written consent to the beginning of the standby guardianship, signed by the parent in the presence of two witnesses at least 18 years of age, neither of whom is the standby guardian, and signed by the standby guardian; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">A copy of the birth certificate for each child for whom the standby guardian is designated.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If a parent is physically unable to sign a written consent to the beginning of the standby guardianship, another person may sign the written consent to the beginning of the standby guardianship on the parent's behalf and at the parent's direction.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A consent under this subsection to the beginning of the standby guardianship shall be signed in the presence of the parent and two witnesses at least 18 years of age, neither of whom may be the standby guardian.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The standby guardian also shall sign a consent to the beginning of the standby guardianship under this subsection.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A standby guardian shall file a petition for judicial appointment within 180 days of the date of the beginning of the standby guardianship under this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If the standby guardian fails to file the petition within the time specified in this subsection, the standby guardian's authority shall terminate 180 days from the date of the beginning of the standby guardianship.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The standby guardian's authority shall begin again on the filing of the petition.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A standby guardian shall file a petition for appointment as guardian after receipt of:<section prefix="(i)">A copy of a determination of incapacity made under &#xA7; 13-906 of this subtitle; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">Copies of:<section prefix="1.">A determination of debilitation made under &#xA7; 13-906 of this subtitle; and</section><section prefix="2.">The parent's written consent to the beginning of the standby guardianship under this section.</section></section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Subject to the provisions of paragraphs (3) and (4) of this subsection, the petition shall be accompanied by:<section prefix="(i)">The written designation of the standby guardian signed, or consented to, by each person having parental rights over the child;</section><section prefix="(ii)">A copy of:<section prefix="1.">The determination of incapacity of the parent; or</section><section prefix="2.">The determination of debilitation and the parental consent to the beginning of the standby guardianship; and</section></section><section prefix="(iii)">If the petition is filed by a person designated as alternate standby guardian, a statement that the person designated as standby guardian is unwilling or unable to act as standby guardian, and the basis for the statement.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">If a person who has parental rights cannot be located after reasonable efforts have been made to locate the person, the standby guardian may file a petition under this section without the consent of the person to the designation of the standby guardian.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">If the standby guardian submits documentation, satisfactory to the court, of the reasonable efforts to locate the person who has parental rights, the court may appoint a standby guardian under this section.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">The court shall appoint a person to be a standby guardian under this section if the court finds that:<section prefix="(1)">The person was duly designated as standby guardian;</section><section prefix="(2)">A determination of incapacity, or a determination of debilitation and parental consent to the beginning of the standby guardianship, has been made under this section;</section><section prefix="(3)">The interests of the minor will be promoted by the appointment of a standby guardian of the person or property of the minor; and</section><section prefix="(4)">If the petition is by a person designated as alternate standby guardian, the person designated as standby guardian is unwilling or unable to act as standby guardian.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(h)">A parent may revoke a standby guardianship created under this section:<section prefix="(1)">Before the filing of a petition, by notifying the standby guardian verbally or in writing or by any other act that is evidence of a specific intent to revoke the standby guardianship; and</section><section prefix="(2)">If a petition has been filed by:<section prefix="(i)">Executing a written revocation;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Filing the revocation with the court in which the petition was filed; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Promptly notifying the standby guardian of the revocation.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(i)">A person who is judicially appointed as a standby guardian under this section may at any time before the beginning of the person's authority renounce the appointment by:<section prefix="(1)">Executing a written renunciation;</section><section prefix="(2)">Filing the renunciation with the court that issued the decree; and</section><section prefix="(3)">Promptly notifying in writing the parent of the revocation.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
