<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="get" order_by="" level="1">Estates and Trusts</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>get-9-112</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>112</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">If the personal representative cannot obtain agreement from all interested persons entitled to share in the distribution of the property, he may apply to the court to make distribution. The court shall designate a day and direct the giving of notice to all interested persons concerned. The court may appoint two disinterested individuals, not related to the interested persons to make an appropriate division for distribution, or recommend to the court a sale of part or all of the property, and the court shall direct the distribution it considers appropriate.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">If a majority in relation to value fails to appear on the appointed day, or appear and object to the distribution suggested, or if the court considers a sale of part or all of the property more appropriate and advantageous, the personal representative shall make the sale or sales and divide the proceeds, together with unsold property, as the court directs.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">In the event the personal representative has reason to believe that there may be one or more interested persons whose names or addresses are not known to him, or if it is not known to him if an interested person is still surviving, he may appoint a meeting of all interested persons to be held on a day the court designates.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The personal representative shall give notice to all interested persons known to him, and shall publish a notice of the meeting once a week in three successive weeks, in a newspaper of general circulation in the county of his appointment, stating the time, date, place, and purpose of the meeting which shall be held no sooner than 20 days after the first publication. The personal representative shall also take other steps and make other efforts to learn the names and addresses of additional interested persons as the court considers appropriate under the circumstances.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">On the date of the meeting, distribution of the net estate shall be made under the direction and control of the court. Distribution by the personal representative in accordance with the direction of the court at the meeting protects and indemnifies the personal representative acting in obedience to it.</section>
  </text>
</law>
