<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="get" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="4-503" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>get-4-503</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Subject to &#xA7; 4-506 of this subtitle, an anatomical gift may be made during the life of a donor for the purpose of transplantation, therapy, research, or education by:<section prefix="(1)"><section prefix="(i)">A donor who is an adult; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">A donor who is a minor, if the minor is:</section></section><section prefix="(2)">An agent of a donor, unless a power of attorney for health care or other record prohibits the agent from making an anatomical gift;</section><section prefix="(3)">A parent of a donor, if the donor is an unemancipated minor; or</section><section prefix="(4)">A guardian of a donor.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A donor may make an anatomical gift:<section prefix="(1)">By authorizing a statement or symbol indicating that the donor has made an anatomical gift to be imprinted on the donor's driver's license or identification card;</section><section prefix="(2)">By will;</section><section prefix="(3)">During a terminal illness or an injury of the donor, by any form of communication addressed to at least two adults, at least one of whom is a disinterested witness; or</section><section prefix="(4)">As provided in subsection (c) of this section.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A donor or other person authorized to make an anatomical gift under this section may make a gift by:<section prefix="(i)">A donor card or other record signed by the donor or other person making the gift; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">Authorizing that a statement or symbol indicating that the donor has made an anatomical gift be included on a donor registry.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If a donor or other person authorized to make an anatomical gift under this section is physically unable to sign a record, the record may be signed by another individual at the direction of the donor or other person and shall:<section prefix="(i)">Be witnessed by at least two adults, at least one of whom is a disinterested witness, who have signed at the request of the donor or other person; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">State that the record has been signed and witnessed as provided in item (i) of this paragraph.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Revocation, suspension, expiration, or cancellation of a driver's license or an identification card that indicates an anatomical gift does not invalidate the gift.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">An anatomical gift made by will takes effect on the donor's death whether or not the will is probated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If a will that makes an anatomical gift is invalidated after the donor's death, the anatomical gift does not become invalid.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
