<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="get" order_by="get" level="1">Estates and Trusts</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>get-15-502.3</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this section, "qualified beneficiary" means:...</catch_line>
  <order_by>502.3</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, "qualified beneficiary" means:<section prefix="(1)">A person who, on the date that notice is given by the trustee in accordance with subsection (b) of this section:<section prefix="(i)">Is a distributee or permissible distributee of the income or principal of the trust estate;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Would be a distributee or permissible distributee of the income or principal of the trust estate if the interests of the distributees described in item (i) of this paragraph terminated on the date that notice is given by the trustee; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">Would be a distributee or permissible distributee of the income or principal of the trust estate if the trust were to terminate on the date that notice is given by the trustee and no powers of appointment were exercised;</section></section><section prefix="(2)">If an individual described in paragraph (1) of this subsection is a minor, the individual's natural or legal guardian; or</section><section prefix="(3)">If an individual described in paragraph (1) of this subsection is a disabled person, as defined in &#xA7; 13-101 of this article, any person acting on behalf of the individual under a guardianship, conservatorship, or committee.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A trustee shall give notice of a proposed decision regarding the exercise or nonexercise of the discretionary power conferred under:<section prefix="(1)">Section 15-502.1(a) of this subtitle to convert a trust to a unitrust;</section><section prefix="(2)">Section 15-502.1(i) of this subtitle to reconvert from a unitrust; or</section><section prefix="(3)">Section 15-502.2(a) of this subtitle to adjust between principal and income.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The trustee shall mail the notice required under subsection (b) of this section to:<section prefix="(1)">All qualified beneficiaries, except that notice of the proposed decision need not be given to any qualified beneficiary who consents in writing to the proposed decision at any time before the notice is mailed; and</section><section prefix="(2)">The creator of the trust, if living.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The notice of proposed decision shall state that it is given in accordance with this section and shall state the following:<section prefix="(1)">The name and mailing address of the trustee, together with the name and telephone number of a person who may be contacted for additional information;</section><section prefix="(2)">A description of the decision proposed to be taken and, if the proposed decision also includes an action that requires an order of a court in accordance with &#xA7; 15-502.1 or &#xA7; 15-502.2 of this subtitle, a description of that action;</section><section prefix="(3)">The time within which written consents to the proposed decision may be given to the trustee, which shall be at least 30 days after the mailing of the notice of proposed decision; and</section><section prefix="(4)">The date on or after which the proposed decision may be taken or is effective, which shall be after the end of the time within which consents to the proposed decision may be given to the trustee.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">If the trustee receives the written consent of all qualified beneficiaries, then the trustee shall undertake the proposed decision unless the proposed decision also includes an action that requires an order of a court in accordance with &#xA7; 15-502.1 or &#xA7; 15-502.2 of this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">If any qualified beneficiary does not consent to the proposed decision, or if the proposed decision includes an action that requires an order of a court under &#xA7; 15-502.1 or &#xA7; 15-502.2 of this subtitle, then the trustee or any qualified beneficiary may file a petition to review the proposed decision in the circuit court for the county in which the trustee resides in this State, if the trustee is an individual, or in which the principal place of business of the trustee is located in this State.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In a proceeding under subsection (f) of this section:<section prefix="(i)">With respect to the power to convert to a unitrust under &#xA7; 15-502.1(a) of this subtitle or to reconvert from a unitrust under &#xA7; 15-502.1(i) of this subtitle, the sole remedy in the proceeding is to direct, deny, or revise the conversion to a unitrust or reconversion from a unitrust; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">With respect to the power to adjust between principal and income under &#xA7; 15-502.2(a) of this subtitle, the sole remedy in the proceeding is to direct, deny, or revise the adjustment between principal and income.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Notice of the proceeding shall be given by the petitioner to the trustee and to all qualified beneficiaries.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(h)">Any action taken or not taken in accordance with the provisions of this section shall be binding on the trustee, all qualified beneficiaries, and any other person who has a present or future interest in the trust, vested or contingent, including any unborn or unascertained beneficiary, and the trustee is not liable to any person for that action taken or not taken.</section>
  </text>
</law>
