<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="get" order_by="" level="1">Estates and Trusts</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>get-2-205</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>205</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">It is the intent of this section that each register shall receive a fair and adequate compensation for the effort and duties required of the register by the register's office.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The volume and character of work done by the register shall be in comparison to the salary fixed by the Board of Public Works for each of the other registers.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Each register is entitled to receive an annual salary of not more than $98,500, to be determined in each instance by the Board of Public Works.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">In determining the annual salary of the register, the Board of Public Works shall be guided in the exercise of its discretion by:<section prefix="(i)">The population of the county determined by the last official United States census;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The dollar volume of total fees and taxes collected and excess fees turned over to the State for each of the preceding 5 years by the office of the register for which the salary is being fixed; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Other pertinent data which have relation to the reasonableness of the salary in relation to the work done and volume handled by the office.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The minimum annual salary for the register in Baltimore City is $12,000.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The salaries of the registers shall be paid semimonthly from the fees and receipts of the office, after deducting the expenses of the office.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Expenses include salaries of deputies and clerks, books, stationery, office supplies, and other necessary and customary expenses of doing business.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If the fees and receipts of the office are insufficient in any fiscal year to pay all or a part of the expenses of the office and authorized salary of a register, the deficiency shall be funded from the taxes remitted to the Comptroller of the treasury by the register during that fiscal year. Written authority for the transfer of funds shall be first obtained from the State Comptroller.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">In the event that tax collections for the fiscal year are insufficient, the Comptroller shall make up the deficit from excess fees remitted from all other registers.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
