<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="get" order_by="" level="1">Estates and Trusts</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>get-15-104</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>104</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Regardless of any other provision of law, any fiduciary holding securities in its fiduciary capacity, any bank or trust company holding securities as a custodian or agent, and any bank or trust company holding securities as custodian for a fiduciary, is authorized to deposit or arrange for the deposit of the securities in a securities clearing corporation, regardless of whether or not the depositor owns capital stock of the clearing corporation. When securities are so deposited, certificates representing securities of the same class of the same issuer may be merged and held in bulk in the name of the nominee of the clearing corporation with any other securities deposited in the clearing corporation by any person regardless of the ownership of the securities, and certificates of small denomination may be merged into one or more certificates of larger denomination. The records of the fiduciary and the records of the bank or trust company acting as custodian, as agent or as custodian for a fiduciary shall show at all times the name of the party for whose account the securities are so deposited. Title to the securities may be transferred by bookkeeping entry on the books of the clearing corporation without physical delivery of certificates representing the securities.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A bank or trust company depositing securities pursuant to this section is subject to the rules and regulations as, in the case of State chartered institutions, the Commissioner of Financial Regulation and, in the case of national banking associations, the comptroller of the currency may issue from time to time. A bank or trust company acting as custodian for a fiduciary, on demand by the fiduciary, shall certify in writing to the fiduciary the securities so deposited by the bank or trust company in the clearing corporation for the account of the fiduciary.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A fiduciary, on demand by any party to a judicial proceeding for the settlement of the account of the fiduciary or on demand by the attorney for the party, shall certify in writing to the party the securities deposited by the fiduciary in the clearing corporation for its account as fiduciary.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">This section applies whether the trust be created or the appointment made prior or subsequent to July 1, 1973.</section>
  </text>
</law>
