<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="get" order_by="" level="1">Estates and Trusts</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>get-8-104</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>104</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Claims against an estate of a decedent may be presented as provided in this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The claimant may deliver or mail to the personal representative a verified written statement of the claim indicating its basis, the name and address of the claimant, and the amount claimed. If the claim is not yet due, the date when it will become due shall be stated. If the claim is contingent, the nature of the contingency shall be stated. If the claim is secured, the security shall be described. The failure of the claimant to comply with the provisions of this section or with the reasonable requests of the personal representative for additional information may be a basis for disallowance of a claim in the discretion of the court.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The claimant may file a verified written statement of the claim, substantially in the form contained in this subsection. If the claim is filed prior to the appointment of the personal representative, the claimant may file his claim with the register in the county in which the decedent was domiciled or in any county in which he resided on the date of his death or in which real property or a leasehold interest in real property of the decedent is located. If the claim is filed after the appointment of the personal representative, the claimant shall file his claim with the register of the county in which probate proceedings are being conducted and shall deliver or mail a copy of the statement to the personal representative.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">When a cause survives death, the claimant is not required to file a claim under subsection (b) or (c) of this section. He may commence an action against the estate or against a person to whom property has been distributed, but the commencement of the action must occur within the time limited for the filing of claims.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If the decedent was covered by a liability insurance policy which at the time the action is instituted provides insurance coverage for the occurrence, then, notwithstanding the other provisions of this section, an action against the estate may be instituted after the expiration of the time designated in this section, but within the period of limitations generally applicable to such actions.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The existence of insurance coverage is not admissible at the trial of the case and if a verdict is rendered against the estate:<section prefix="(i)">The judgment is not limited to the amount of insurance coverage for the occurrence; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">The amount of the judgment that is recoverable from the estate is limited to the amount of the decedent's liability insurance policy.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">These provisions permit claims against the Maryland Automobile Insurance Fund, if otherwise proper.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The provisions of this subsection may not be construed to limit the rights of a plaintiff to:<section prefix="(i)">Proceed against the plaintiff's insurance carrier; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">Otherwise make a claim under any applicable first party insurance policy.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
