<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="get" order_by="" level="1">Estates and Trusts</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>get-9-104</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>104</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Subject to the terms of the will and the needs of administration, the assets of the estate of a decedent shall be distributed in kind to the extent possible through application of the provisions of this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A specific legatee shall receive distribution of the legacy given to him.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A family allowance or that portion of an intestate share, statutory share, or legacy that is otherwise payable in cash may be satisfied by value in kind provided:<section prefix="(1)">The person entitled to the payment has not demanded payment in cash;</section><section prefix="(2)">The property distributed in kind is valued at fair market value as of the date of its distribution; and</section><section prefix="(3)">A residuary legatee has not requested that the asset in question remain a part of the residue of the estate.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">When there is no objection to the proposed distribution, or when it is practicable to distribute undivided interests, the residuary estate shall be distributed in kind.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">In other cases, residuary property may be converted into cash for distribution.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">After the probable charges against the estate are known, the personal representative may mail or deliver a proposal for distribution to all persons who have a right to object to the proposed distribution.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If not waived in writing, the right of a distributee to object to the proposed distribution terminates if the distributee fails to object in writing received by the personal representative within 30 days after mailing or delivery of the proposal.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
