<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="get" order_by="" level="1">Estates and Trusts</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>get-14-405</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>405</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The trustee's obligations begin when the trustee accepts the trust property by writing words substantially similar to those specified in &#xA7; 14-404(e) of this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A trustee shall:<section prefix="(1)">Take control of trust property;</section><section prefix="(2)">Register or record title to trust property if appropriate; and</section><section prefix="(3)">Collect, hold, manage, invest, and reinvest trust property.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">In administering trust property, a trustee shall observe the standard of care that would be observed by a prudent person dealing with property of another and is not limited by any other statute restricting investments by fiduciaries.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">If a trustee has a special skill or expertise, or is named trustee on the basis of representations of a special skill or expertise, the trustee shall utilize that skill or expertise.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A trustee shall at all times keep trust property separate and distinct from all other property in a manner sufficient to identify it clearly as trust property.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Trust property consisting of an undivided interest is so identified if the trustee's interest is held as a tenant in common.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Trust property subject to recordation is so identified if it is recorded, registered, or held in an account designated in the name of the trustee, followed by the words, "As trustee for ___________________ (name of beneficiary) under the Maryland Discretionary Trust Act", or similar words.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">A trustee, acting in a fiduciary capacity, has all the rights and powers over trust property that an unmarried adult owner has over individually owned property, but a trustee may exercise those rights and powers in a fiduciary capacity only.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">A claim based on a contract entered into by a trustee acting in a fiduciary capacity, an obligation arising from the trustee's ownership or control of trust property, or a tort committed in the course of administering the trust, may be asserted by a third person against the trust property by proceeding against the trustee in a fiduciary capacity, whether or not the trustee is personally liable.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">At any time, the transferor may require the trustee to furnish bond.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">The trustee shall maintain complete records of all trust property and all trust transactions.</section>
    <section prefix="(j)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The following persons in the order listed may request an accounting of trust property and transactions:<section prefix="(i)">The transferor or the transferor's legal representative;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The beneficiary or the beneficiary's legal representative;</section><section prefix="(iii)">The guardian of the person of the beneficiary;</section><section prefix="(iv)">An adult member of the beneficiary's family or that family member's legal representative; or</section><section prefix="(v)">A person interested in the trust property or a person interested in the welfare of the beneficiary, either of whom the court determines to have a legitimate interest.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The trustee shall provide a written accounting of all trust property and trust transactions for the previous year, or for a longer period if needed for tax purposes, upon request by and at reasonable times to a person authorized in paragraph (1) of this subsection.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The trustee shall give the transferor, successor trustee, or court a complete accounting, including a written accounting of all trust property, a description and records of all trust transactions, and any other relevant documents and information concerning the trust upon the resignation or removal of the trustee, the termination of the trust, or the demand of the court.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The trustee may petition the court for approval of final accounts.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">Upon removal of a trustee by a court, the court shall require:<section prefix="(i)">An accounting of trust property;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The delivery of the trust property and records to the successor trustee; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">The execution of all instruments required for transfer of the trust property.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(k)">Upon petition of the trustee or any person who may petition for an accounting as specified in subsection (j) of this section, the court, after notice to those persons as directed by the court, may:<section prefix="(1)">Issue instructions to the trustee;</section><section prefix="(2)">Review the propriety of the acts of a trustee; and</section><section prefix="(3)">Review the reasonableness of the trustee's compensation or the compensation of other persons.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(l)">A successor trustee may not be held liable for the acts or omissions of any predecessor trustee.</section>
    <section prefix="(m)">Except as otherwise provided in the registration, declaration, or other instrument of transfer creating the trust, or by court order, a trustee:<section prefix="(1)">Is entitled to reimbursement from trust property for reasonable expenses incurred in the performance of fiduciary services; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Has a noncumulative election, to be made no later than 6 months after the end of each calendar year, to charge reasonable compensation, not to exceed the maximum commissions for trustee services provided for at the time by Maryland law, for fiduciary services performed during that calendar year.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
