<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="get" order_by="get" level="1">Estates and Trusts</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>get-14-112</section_number>
  <catch_line>A trust may be created to provide for the care of an animal alive during the lifetime of the settlor...</catch_line>
  <order_by>112</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">A trust may be created to provide for the care of an animal alive during the lifetime of the settlor.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A trust authorized by this section terminates:<section prefix="(1)">If created to provide for the care of one animal alive during the lifetime of the settlor, on the death of the animal; or</section><section prefix="(2)">If created to provide for the care of more than one animal alive during the lifetime of the settlor, on the death of the last surviving animal.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A trust authorized by this section may be enforced by a person appointed under the terms of the trust or, if no person is appointed, by a person appointed by the court.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A person having an interest in the welfare of an animal the care for which a trust is established may request the court to appoint a person to enforce the trust or to remove a person appointed.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except to the extent that the court may determine that the value of a trust authorized by this section exceeds the amount required for the use intended by the trust, the property of the trust may be applied only to the intended use of the trust.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Except as otherwise provided under the terms of the trust, property not required for the intended use of the trust shall be distributed:<section prefix="(i)">To the settlor, if living; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">If the settlor is deceased, to the successors in interest of the settlor.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
