<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="get" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="2-108" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>get-2-108</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Except in Montgomery County and Harford County, the judges of the courts shall receive compensation and allowances as prescribed by law. Unless otherwise provided, the compensation shall be paid in monthly installments. Mileage or travel expenses may not be allowed to a judge for attending sessions of his court except as specifically provided.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Each of the judges of the Court for Allegany County shall receive an annual salary set by the County Commissioners in accordance with Article 24, Title 12, Subtitle 1 of the Code. Each judge shall also receive an expense allowance in the amount of $600 annually, to be paid at the rate of $50 monthly.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Each of the judges of the Court for Anne Arundel County shall receive an annual compensation of:<section prefix="(i)">$27,000 for calendar year 2007; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">$29,000 for calendar year 2008 and each subsequent calendar year.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Chief Judge shall receive an additional $500 annually.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Each judge shall also receive an expense allowance up to $150 per month for personal expenses incidental to his duties, to be paid by the Comptroller of Anne Arundel County each month upon presentation of an itemized voucher in accordance with rules and regulations prescribed by the Comptroller.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Each associate judge of the Court of Baltimore City shall receive an annual compensation of $62,500, and the Chief Judge shall receive an annual compensation of $72,500.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">Each associate judge who was in active service on or after January 1, 1984 shall be paid after the termination of active service, if he is then at least 60 years of age or when he shall attain 60 years of age, a pension or salary calculated at the rate of $3,125 annually for each year, or a part of a year, of active service; but the maximum pension or salary for the service by an associate judge may not exceed $31,250 annually.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">Each Chief Judge who was in active service on or after January 1, 1984, shall be paid, after the termination of active service, if he is then at least 60 years of age or when he shall attain 60 years of age, a pension or salary calculated at the rate of $3,625 annually for each year, or a part of a year of active service; but the maximum pension or salary for the service by a Chief Judge may not exceed $36,250 annually. The pension or salary shall be paid by the City of Baltimore in the same manner as the salaries of the judges of the Court for the City are paid.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The surviving spouse of every elected judge of the Court of Baltimore City shall be paid one half of the pension to which his spouse was entitled at the time of his death, or would have become entitled to by reason of attaining 60 years of age. In each instance, the pension shall be paid to the spouse until remarriage or death. The provisions of this subsection shall not apply in the case of a spouse who was married to a sitting judge for a period of less than three years prior to his death, and to a retired judge for a period less than three years before his retirement.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">Each of the judges of the Court for Baltimore County shall receive an annual compensation of $39,000 beginning July 1, 2003. The Chief Judge shall receive an additional $500 annually.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Each of the judges of the Court for Calvert County shall receive as annual compensation the sum of:<section prefix="(i)">$8,000 for calendar year 2006;</section><section prefix="(ii)">$8,250 for calendar year 2007;</section><section prefix="(iii)">$8,500 for calendar year 2008; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">$8,750 for calendar year 2009 and each subsequent calendar year.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The salary of the Chief Judge is:<section prefix="(i)">$8,200 for calendar year 2006;</section><section prefix="(ii)">$8,450 for calendar year 2007;</section><section prefix="(iii)">$8,700 for calendar year 2008; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">$8,950 for calendar year 2009 and each subsequent calendar year.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The County Commissioners may provide additional funds for expenses for the judges.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">Each of the judges of the Court for Caroline County shall receive an annual salary as determined by the County Commissioners, but not less than $5,000.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">Each of the judges of the Court for Carroll County shall receive an annual compensation of $10,000 to be paid monthly. Each judge shall also be allowed $200 annually for traveling expenses, payable quarterly.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">Each of the judges of the Court for Cecil County shall receive an annual compensation of $5,500. Each judge shall also receive an allowance for traveling expenses of $780 annually, to be paid quarterly by the County Commissioners.</section>
    <section prefix="(j)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The annual salary for each judge of the Court for Charles County is $10,000.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Each judge is entitled to $500 each year for travel expenses, payable quarterly.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(k)">Each of the judges of the Court for Dorchester County shall receive an annual salary as determined by the County Council, but not less than $4,700. Each judge shall also receive an expense allowance as determined by the County Council, but not less than $800 annually.</section>
    <section prefix="(l)">The Chief Judge of the Court for Frederick County shall receive an annual compensation of $6,500. Each of the associate judges of the Court for Frederick County shall receive an annual compensation of $6,000. Each judge also shall receive reimbursement for expenses actually incurred in the performance of duties, up to $700 per year, to be paid by the Board of County Commissioners each month upon presentation of an itemized voucher.</section>
    <section prefix="(m)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Each of the judges of the Court for Garrett County shall receive an annual salary set by the Board of County Commissioners in accordance with &#xA7;&#xA7; 32.43 and 32.44 of the Public Local Laws of Garrett County.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Each judge shall be reimbursed for traveling to and from the sessions of the Court at the rate Garrett County pays for mileage. Each judge shall also receive an amount for expenses for every day's attendance on the sessions of the Court set by the Board of County Commissioners in accordance with &#xA7;&#xA7; 32.43 and 32.44 of the Public Local Laws of Garrett County.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(n)">Repealed.</section>
    <section prefix="(o)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Each judge of the Court for Howard County shall receive annual compensation of $8,000, to be paid monthly.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The annual salary of the Chief Judge is $9,500, to be paid monthly.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Each judge shall also receive an expense allowance, in addition, up to $50 per month, for personal expenses incidental to the judge's duties, to be paid by the Treasurer of Howard County each month on presentation of an itemized voucher.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(p)">Each of the judges of the Court for Kent County shall receive an annual compensation of $4,000. Each judge shall also receive an allowance for traveling expenses of $520 annually, to be paid quarterly by the County Commissioners.</section>
    <section prefix="(q)">The salary of each associate judge of the Court for Prince George's County shall be $42,000 per annum, and the salary of the Chief Judge shall be $42,500 per annum.</section>
    <section prefix="(r)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Each of the judges of the Court for Queen Anne's County shall receive a salary as set by the County Commissioners.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Each judge shall receive an allowance for travel expenses in accordance with the County budget.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The County Commissioners shall pay quarterly to each judge the travel allowance provided in subparagraph (i) of this paragraph.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(s)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Each of the judges of the Court for St. Mary's County shall receive an annual salary of:<section prefix="(i)">$6,000 for the calendar year 2007;</section><section prefix="(ii)">$6,500 for the calendar year 2008;</section><section prefix="(iii)">$7,000 for the calendar year 2009; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">$7,500 for the calendar year 2010.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Each judge shall also be allowed $1,000 annually for traveling expenses, payable quarterly.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(t)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Chief Judge of the Court for Somerset County shall receive an annual salary of $3,800 to be paid quarterly.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Each of the associate judges of the Court for Somerset County shall receive an annual salary of $3,400 to be paid quarterly.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Each judge shall also receive a daily allowance for traveling expenses of $34.50 for every day's attendance upon the sessions of the Court.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(u)">Each of the judges of the Court for Talbot County shall receive a salary as set by the County Council.</section>
    <section prefix="(v)">
      <section prefix="(1)">As compensation each of the judges of the Court for Washington County shall receive an annual compensation of not more than $7,000 per year.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Each judge shall also receive an expense allowance, not to exceed $1,000 per year, to be paid by the Board of County Commissioners upon presentation of an itemized voucher of legitimate expenses.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">For purposes of subparagraph (i) of this paragraph, legitimate expenses include:</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(w)">Each judge of the Court for Wicomico County shall receive an annual salary of $6,400 to be paid quarterly. Each judge shall also receive an annual allowance for traveling expenses of $1,560 to be paid quarterly.</section>
    <section prefix="(x)">The Board of County Commissioners of Worcester County shall determine the compensation for judges of the Court for Worcester County but the compensation may not be less than the sum of $30 for every day's attendance upon the sessions of the Court. The judges shall also receive an allowance for traveling expenses of $1,600 annually.</section>
    <section prefix="(y)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except in Montgomery, Frederick, Carroll, Talbot, Cecil, Kent, Queen Anne's, Baltimore, Garrett, and Harford counties and Baltimore City, and except as provided in paragraphs (3) and (4) of this subsection, a county shall pay a pension, in the same manner as salaries are paid during active service, to each judge of the Orphans' Court who:<section prefix="(i)">Has terminated active service;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Has reached 60 years of age; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Has completed at least two terms of office.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Except as provided in this section, the salary or pension shall be the greater of:<section prefix="(i)">$1,200 annually; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">An annual amount calculated at the rate of 4 percent of the last annual amount of compensation multiplied by the number of years or partial years of service, not exceeding 12 years.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">An Orphans' Court judge in Somerset County and Worcester County is eligible for a pension under this subsection only if he is in office on or before July 1, 1979.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">In Wicomico County, an Orphans' Court judge who has completed at least 12 years in office is eligible for a pension under this subsection.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">In Prince George's County, the salary or pension to each Orphans' Court judge shall be the greater of:<section prefix="(i)">$1,200 annually; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">An annual amount calculated at the rate of 4 percent of the last annual amount of compensation multiplied by the number of years or partial years of service, not exceeding 20 years.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(6)">In Allegany County, the pension for an Orphans' Court judge shall be the greater of:<section prefix="(i)">$1,200 annually; or</section><section prefix="(ii)"/></section>
      <section prefix="(7)">The pension or salary may be suspended during any month the judge is a full-time employee of any county or of this State.</section>
      <section prefix="(8)">Notwithstanding any provision of this section an Orphans' Court judge may not receive a pension under this section if he is receiving any other State pension based on service as an Orphans' Court judge.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
