<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="get" order_by="get" level="1">Estates and Trusts</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>get-9-202</section_number>
  <catch_line>A person may disclaim in whole or in part any interest in or power over property, including a power ...</catch_line>
  <order_by>202</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A person may disclaim in whole or in part any interest in or power over property, including a power of appointment.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A person may disclaim the interest or power even if the creator imposed a spendthrift provision or similar restriction upon transfer or a restriction or limitation on the right to disclaim.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except to the extent that a fiduciary's right to disclaim is expressly restricted or limited by another statute of the State or by the instrument creating the fiduciary relationship, a fiduciary may disclaim in whole or in part any interest in or power over property, including a power of appointment, whether acting in a personal or representative capacity.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A fiduciary may disclaim the interest or power even if the creator imposed a spendthrift provision or similar restriction upon transfer or a restriction or limitation on the right to disclaim, or an instrument other than the instrument that created the fiduciary relationship imposed a restriction or limitation on the right to disclaim.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">To be effective, a disclaimer must:<section prefix="(1)">Be in writing or other record;</section><section prefix="(2)">Declare the disclaimer;</section><section prefix="(3)">Describe the interest or power disclaimed;</section><section prefix="(4)">Be signed by the person making the disclaimer; and</section><section prefix="(5)">Be delivered or filed in the manner provided in &#xA7; 9-209 of this subtitle.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A partial disclaimer may be expressed as a fraction, percentage, monetary amount, term of years, limitation of a power, or any other interest or estate in the property.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">A disclaimer becomes irrevocable when it is delivered or filed pursuant to &#xA7; 9-209 of this subtitle or when it becomes effective as provided in &#xA7;&#xA7; 9-203 through 9-208 of this subtitle, whichever occurs later.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A disclaimer made under this subtitle is not a transfer, assignment, or release.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Creditors of the disclaimant have no interest in the property disclaimed.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
