<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="get" order_by="get" level="1">Estates and Trusts</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>get-17-202</section_number>
  <catch_line>You should be very careful in deciding whether or not to sign this document. The powers granted by y...</catch_line>
  <order_by>202</order_by>
  <text>You should be very careful in deciding whether or not to sign this document. The powers granted by you (the principal) in this document are broad and sweeping. This power of attorney authorizes another person (your agent) to make decisions concerning your property for you (the principal). Your agent will be able to make decisions and act with respect to your property (including your money) whether or not you are able to act for yourself.<section prefix=""><section prefix="(1)">Contract with another person, on terms agreeable to the agent, to accomplish a purpose of a transaction and perform, rescind, cancel, terminate, reform, restate, release, or modify the contract or another contract made by or on behalf of the principal;</section><section prefix="(2)">Execute, acknowledge, seal, deliver, file, or record any instrument or communication the agent considers desirable to accomplish a purpose of a transaction;</section><section prefix="(3)">Seek on the principal's behalf the assistance of a court or other governmental agency to carry out an act authorized in this power of attorney;</section><section prefix="(4)">Initiate, participate in, submit to alternative dispute resolution, settle, oppose, or propose or accept a compromise with respect to a claim existing in favor of or against the principal or intervene in litigation relating to the claim;</section><section prefix="(5)">Engage, compensate, and discharge an attorney, accountant, discretionary investment manager, expert witness, or other advisor;</section><section prefix="(6)">Prepare, execute, and file a record, report, or other document to safeguard or promote the principal's interest under a statute or regulation and communicate with representatives or employees of a government or governmental subdivision, agency, or instrumentality, on behalf of the principal; and</section><section prefix="(7)">Do lawful acts with respect to the subject and all property related to the subject.</section></section></text>
</law>
