<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="get" order_by="" level="1">Estates and Trusts</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>get-13-207</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>207</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Persons are entitled to appointment as guardian for a minor or disabled person according to the following priorities:<section prefix="(1)">A conservator, committee, guardian of property, or other like fiduciary appointed by any appropriate court of any foreign jurisdiction in which the minor or disabled person resides;</section><section prefix="(2)">A person or corporation nominated by the minor or disabled person if the designation was signed by the minor or disabled person after his 16th birthday, and, in the opinion of the court, he had sufficient mental capacity to make an intelligent choice at the time he executed the designation;</section><section prefix="(3)">His spouse;</section><section prefix="(4)">His parents;</section><section prefix="(5)">A person or corporation nominated by the will of a deceased parent;</section><section prefix="(6)">His children;</section><section prefix="(7)">The persons who would be his heirs if he were dead;</section><section prefix="(8)">A person or corporation nominated by a person who, or institution, organization, or public agency which, is caring for him;</section><section prefix="(9)">A person or corporation nominated by a governmental agency which is paying benefits to him; and</section><section prefix="(10)">Any other person considered appropriate by the court.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A person specified in a priority in subsection (a)(1), (3), (4), (6) or (7) may waive and nominate in writing a person or corporation to serve in his stead. A nominee of a person holding a priority has the same priority as the person making the nomination.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Among persons with equal priority, the court shall select the one best qualified of those willing to serve. For good cause the court may pass over a person with priority and appoint a person with less priority or no priority.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Nonresidence does not disqualify any person from serving as guardian. Any nonresident who is appointed cannot qualify until he has on file with the register or clerk an irrevocable designation by him of an appropriate person who resides in the State on whom service of process may be made in the same manner and with the effect as if it were served personally in the State on the nonresident.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The court may not name an official or employee of a local department of social services, the State Department of Human Resources, a local area agency on aging as defined in &#xA7; 10-101 of the Human Services Article, or the Department of Aging as guardian of the estate.</section>
  </text>
</law>
