<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="get" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="13.5-101" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>get-13.5-101</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this title the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Conservator" means a person appointed by a court to administer the property of an adult, including a person appointed as guardian under Title 13, Subtitle 2 of this article to manage the property of a disabled person.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Emergency" means a circumstance that likely will result in a substantial harm to the health, safety, or welfare of a respondent, and for which the appointment of a guardian is necessary because no other person has authority and is willing to act on behalf of the respondent.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">"Guardian" means a person appointed by a court to make decisions regarding the person of an adult, including a person appointed under Title 13, Subtitle 7 of this article.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"Guardianship order" means an order appointing a guardian.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">"Guardianship proceeding" means a proceeding in which an order for the appointment of a guardian is sought or has been issued.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">"Home state" means the state in which the respondent was physically present for at least 6 consecutive months, including a period of temporary absence, immediately before the filing of a petition for the appointment of a guardian or protective order.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">"Incapacitated person" means an adult for whom a guardian has been appointed, including a "disabled person" as defined in &#xA7; 13-101 of this article.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">"Party" means the respondent, petitioner, guardian, conservator, or any other person allowed by the court to participate in a guardianship or protective proceeding.</section>
    <section prefix="(j)">"Protected person" means an adult for whom a protective order has been made.</section>
    <section prefix="(k)">"Protective order" means an order appointing a conservator or a guardian of the property in accordance with Title 13, Subtitle 2 of this article, or another court order related to management of an adult's property.</section>
    <section prefix="(l)">"Protective proceeding" means a judicial proceeding in which a protective order is sought or has been issued.</section>
    <section prefix="(m)">"Record" means information that is inscribed on a tangible medium or that is stored in an electronic or other medium and is retrievable in perceivable form.</section>
    <section prefix="(n)">"Respondent" means an adult for whom a protective order or the appointment of a guardian is sought.</section>
    <section prefix="(o)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Significant-connection state" means a state, other than the home state, with which a respondent has a significant connection other than mere physical presence and in which substantial evidence concerning the respondent is available.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Determination of whether a respondent has a significant connection with a particular state shall include consideration of the following factors:<section prefix="(i)">The location of the family of the respondent and others required to be notified of the guardianship or protective proceeding;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The length of time the respondent at any time was physically present in the state and the duration of any absences;</section><section prefix="(iii)">The location of the respondent's property; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">The extent to which the respondent has other ties to the state such as voting registration, filing of state or local tax returns, vehicle registration, driver's license, social relationships, and receipt of services. </section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(p)">"State" means a state of the United States, the District of Columbia, Puerto Rico, the United States Virgin Islands, a federally recognized Indian tribe, or any territory or insular possession subject to the jurisdiction of the United States.</section>
  </text>
</law>
