<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="get" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="4-505" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>get-4-505</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">An individual may refuse to make an anatomical gift of the individual's body or part by:<section prefix="(1)">A record signed by:<section prefix="(i)">The individual; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">Subject to subsection (b) of this section, if the individual is physically unable to sign, another individual acting at the direction of the individual;</section></section><section prefix="(2)">The individual's will, whether or not the will is admitted to probate or invalidated after the individual's death; or</section><section prefix="(3)">During a terminal illness of the individual or while the individual is injured, any form of communication addressed to at least two adults, at least one of whom is a disinterested witness.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A record signed in accordance with subsection (a)(1)(ii) of this section shall:<section prefix="(1)">Be witnessed by at least two adults, at least one of whom is a disinterested witness, who have signed at the request of the individual; and</section><section prefix="(2)">State that the record has been signed and witnessed as provided in item (1) of this subsection.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">An individual who has made a refusal may amend or revoke the refusal:<section prefix="(1)">In a manner for making a refusal provided in subsection (a) of this section;</section><section prefix="(2)">By subsequently making an anatomical gift in accordance with &#xA7; 4-503 of this subtitle that is inconsistent with the refusal; or</section><section prefix="(3)">By destroying or canceling the record evidencing the refusal, or the portion of the record used to make the refusal, with the intent to revoke the refusal.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Except as otherwise provided in &#xA7; 4-506(h) of this subtitle, in the absence of an express, contrary indication by the individual set forth in the refusal, an individual's unrevoked refusal to make an anatomical gift of the individual's body or part bars all other persons from making an anatomical gift of the individual's body or part.</section>
  </text>
</law>
