<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="get" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="13-220" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>get-13-220</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The appointment of a guardian terminates when the guardianship terminates under &#xA7; 13-221 of this subtitle and may be terminated sooner by his death, disability, resignation, or removal.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Termination of appointment of a guardian has the effects provided in this section.<section prefix="(1)">Termination ends the right and power pertaining to the office of guardian. Unless otherwise ordered by the court, a guardian whose appointment has been terminated shall perform acts necessary to protect the estate and deliver the property to the successor guardian.</section><section prefix="(2)">Subject to the provisions of the Maryland Rules, termination does not discharge a guardian from liability for transactions or omissions occurring before termination, or relieve him of the duty to preserve, account for, and deliver to his successor property subject to his control.</section><section prefix="(3)">All lawful acts of a guardian before the termination of his appointment shall remain valid and effective.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The death of a guardian or the decree of a court of competent jurisdiction that he is under legal disability shall terminate his appointment. The personal representative of a deceased guardian or the person appointed to protect the estate of a guardian under legal disability shall have the duty to protect property belonging to the estate being administered by the deceased or disabled guardian.<section prefix="(1)">He shall have the power to perform acts necessary for the protection of property.</section><section prefix="(2)">He shall immediately account for and deliver the property to a successor guardian.</section><section prefix="(3)">He shall apply immediately to the court for the appointment of a successor guardian to carry on the administration of the estate which was being administered by the deceased or disabled guardian in accordance with the Maryland Rules.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A guardian who desires to resign his office may do so in accordance with the provisions of the same Maryland Rules by which a fiduciary may resign his office.</section>
  </text>
</law>
