<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="get" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="7-202" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>get-7-202</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Subject to the provisions of this section, the value of each item listed in the inventory shall be fairly appraised as of the date of death and stated in the inventory.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The personal representative may appraise the corporate stocks listed on a national or regional exchange or over the counter securities and items in &#xA7; 7-201(4) and (5) of this subtitle.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The personal representative shall secure an independent appraisal of the items in all of the other categories.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The personal representative may select one of the methods specified in this section.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The personal representative may apply for appraisal by appraisers designated by the register under &#xA7; 2-301(a) or &#xA7; 2-302 of this article.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, instead of an appraisal of the fair market value, real and leasehold property may be valued at:<section prefix="(i)">The full cash value for property tax assessment purposes as of the most recent date of finality; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">The contract sales price for the property if:</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Paragraph (1) of this subsection does not apply to property assessed for property tax purposes on the basis of its use value.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Instead of an appraisal of the fair market value, a motor vehicle may be valued by a personal representative on the basis of the average value of the motor vehicle set forth in:<section prefix="(1)">The National Automobile Dealers' Association official used car guide; or</section><section prefix="(2)">Any substantially similar price guide designated by the register.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The personal representative may employ a qualified and disinterested appraiser to assist the personal representative in ascertaining the fair market value, as of the date of the death of the decedent, of an asset the value of which may be fairly debatable.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Different persons may be employed to appraise different kinds of assets included in the estate.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The name and address of each appraiser shall be indicated on the inventory with the item or items the appraiser appraised.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">Reasonable appraisal fees shall be allowed as an administration expense.</section>
  </text>
</law>
