<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="get" order_by="" level="1">Estates and Trusts</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>get-14-403</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>403</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Any person having the right to transfer property to another person may create a trust as a transferor under this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The transferor may:<section prefix="(1)">As declarant serve as trustee;</section><section prefix="(2)">Designate a trustee;</section><section prefix="(3)">Designate how the trustee will be chosen;</section><section prefix="(4)">Designate successor trustees in the order in which they will serve; and</section><section prefix="(5)">Designate how successor trustees will be chosen.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The trustee shall hold, manage, expend, and transfer trust property as provided in this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The successor trustee shall assume the responsibilities of the trustee when the trustee is no longer willing or able to serve.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">A trust may have only one beneficiary but more than one trustee.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">A trustee:<section prefix="(1)">Is not personally liable to a third person:<section prefix="(i)">On a contract properly entered into in a fiduciary capacity unless the trustee fails to reveal that capacity or to identify the trust in the contract; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">For an obligation arising from control of trust property or for a tort committed in the course of the administration of the trust, unless the trustee is personally at fault;</section></section><section prefix="(2)">May decline to serve as trustee before accepting trust property by notifying in writing the person who designated the trustee, or that person's legal representative; and</section><section prefix="(3)">May resign as trustee by notifying the successor trustee in writing, transferring all trust property to the successor trustee, providing the successor trustee with a complete accounting of trust property, and confirming that the successor trustee has accepted the trust property.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(g)">The next willing successor trustee in line shall accept the records and trust property and become trustee as soon as practicable after:<section prefix="(1)">The resignation of the trustee;</section><section prefix="(2)">The declination of the trustee;</section><section prefix="(3)">The death of the trustee; or</section><section prefix="(4)">The removal of the trustee.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(h)">If the trustee is unable or unwilling to serve and no successor trustee will serve, the following persons in the order listed may petition the court to designate a successor trustee:<section prefix="(1)">The transferor or the legal representative of the transferor;</section><section prefix="(2)">The trustee;</section><section prefix="(3)">The beneficiary or the beneficiary's legal representative;</section><section prefix="(4)">The guardian of the person of the beneficiary;</section><section prefix="(5)">An adult member of the beneficiary's family or that family member's legal representative; or</section><section prefix="(6)">A person interested in the trust property or a person interested in the welfare of the beneficiary, either of whom the court determines to have a legitimate interest.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(i)">Unless renounced by the transferor, the transferor may at any time remove or change the designation of the trustee and successor trustees.</section>
  </text>
</law>
