<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="get" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="2-106" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>get-2-106</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Except as provided in this section and unless a different time is prescribed by local law, the court shall be held in each county at the usual place of holding court in the county, on the second Tuesday of February, April, June, August, October, and December, and more often if need be, according to its own adjournment. One of the judges of the court, in the absence of the others, shall have power to hold court at a stated time of adjournment only for the purpose of adjourning. Two judges shall have full power to do an act which the court is or may be authorized by law to perform, and two of them shall have power to hold court on a day not named in an adjournment, on the application of a person having pressing business in the court, if notice be given to any interested person, and the register records that notice has been given. One of the judges, in the absence of the others on account of prolonged illness, or in case of vacancy, shall have full power to do an act which the court is authorized by law to do, provided there is attached to the proceedings or papers in each case a certificate signed by the register, certifying to the vacancy or prolonged illness of the judge or judges not attending court on that day. If the court does not meet on a day fixed for its meeting and is not adjourned as provided, the register shall adjourn the court from day to day until a meeting is had according to law.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The sessions of the Court in Baltimore City shall continue from 10 a.m. to 4 p.m., if necessary for the transaction of the business of the Court.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">In Baltimore City, a judge of the Orphans' Court who is also an attorney-at-law has full power to do any act which the Court is or may be authorized by law to perform, including the power to hold court on a day not named in an adjournment.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">On request of any interested party filed within the time determined by the Court, two judges shall be required to act for the Court.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">In Montgomery County, a judge of the Circuit Court for Montgomery County at the time sitting as the Orphans' Court for the County shall have full power to do an act which the Orphans' Court of the County is or shall be authorized to perform, including the power to hold court on a day not named in an adjournment as provided.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Each judge of the Court for Prince George's County shall spend at least three days each week in the conduct of the business of the Court. In Prince George's County, a judge of the Orphans' Court who is also an attorney-at-law has full power to do any act which the Court is or may be authorized to perform, including the power to hold court on a day not named in an adjournment. However, upon request of any interested party, two judges shall be required to act for the Court. If necessary to transact business before the Court, court may be convened 5 days each week.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">In Harford County, the provisions of subsection (a) of this section do not apply. A judge of the Circuit Court for Harford County shall sit as the Orphans' Court for the County at the time or times established by the judges of the County Circuit Court and shall have full power to do any act which the Orphans' Court of the County is or shall be authorized to perform, including the power to hold court on a day not named in an adjournment.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The sessions of the Court in Baltimore County shall continue from 10 a.m. to 4 p.m., if necessary for the transaction of the business of the Court.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A judge of the Orphans' Court in Baltimore County who is also an attorney-at-law has full power to do any act that the Court is authorized by law to perform, including the power to hold court on a day not named in an adjournment.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In Charles County,  the sessions of the Court shall be held on at least one day each week, as determined by the Court, for the transaction of business.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">In Howard County, the sessions of the Court shall be held as determined by the Court for the transaction of business.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(h)">In Anne Arundel County, the sessions of the Court shall be held at least 2 full business days each week, and more often if necessary, for the transaction of business.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">If an orphans' court judge of a county is unable to serve for any reason, the Chief Judge of the Court of Appeals may assign, on a temporary basis, an orphans' court judge of another county to sit for the judge who is unable to serve.</section>
  </text>
</law>
