<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="get" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="14-110" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>get-14-110</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The following persons may exercise trust or fiduciary powers in this State:<section prefix="(1)">An individual;</section><section prefix="(2)">A trust company as defined in &#xA7; 1-101 of this article;</section><section prefix="(3)">An organization exempt from taxation under &#xA7; 501(c) of the Internal Revenue Code; and</section><section prefix="(4)">Subject to subsection (b) of this section, a bank, trust company, or savings bank, other than one described in paragraph (2) of this subsection, that is:<section prefix="(i)">Organized under the laws of another state and authorized to exercise trust or fiduciary powers in the state where its principal place of business is located; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">Organized under the laws of the United States and authorized to exercise trust or fiduciary powers under federal law.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A bank, trust company, or savings bank described in subsection (a)(4) of this section may exercise trust or fiduciary powers in this State only if the laws of the state where its principal place of business is located authorize a bank, trust company, or savings bank from this State to exercise trust or fiduciary powers in that state.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A bank, trust company, or savings bank authorized to exercise trust powers under subsection (a)(4) of this section shall file with the Commissioner of Financial Regulation, prior to exercising trust powers in this State, information sufficient to identify:<section prefix="(i)">The correct corporate name of the bank, trust company, or savings bank;</section><section prefix="(ii)">An address and telephone number of a contact person for the bank, trust company, or savings bank;</section><section prefix="(iii)">A resident agent; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">Any additional information considered necessary by the Commissioner for protection of the public.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
