<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="get" order_by="get" level="1">Estates and Trusts</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>get-12-102</section_number>
  <catch_line>Unless otherwise specifically provided in another section of the estates of decedents law, the provi...</catch_line>
  <order_by>102</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Unless otherwise specifically provided in another section of the estates of decedents law, the provisions of the estates of decedents law apply as provided in this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Titles 1, 3, 5, 6, 7, 8, 9, and 10 apply to the estate of any decedent dying on or after January 1, 1970, except the last sentence of &#xA7; 7-502(a) shall apply only if the personal representative gives the notice after July 1, 1974.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Title 2 applies, in every instance, on and after January 1, 1970.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Title 4 applies to any will executed on or after 12:01 a.m. on January 1, 1970, except that &#xA7; 4-105 applies to any act or acts of revocation occurring on or after January 1, 1970. As to the rules relating to any will executed before January 1, 1970, the law before January 1, 1970 shall be applicable, except that &#xA7; 4-403 applies to the legacy of any testator who dies on or after July 1, 1983. The provisions of &#xA7; 4-411 apply to a legacy made by a testator living on June 1, 1959, or born after that date without regard to the date of the execution of the will, the trust instrument, or an amendment to it. Section 4-411 shall not be construed as casting doubt upon the validity of (1) a legacy made by a testator who died prior to June 1, 1959, or (2) a legacy which does not come within the provisions of the section.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">Section 11-101 applies to a will or inter vivos transfer executed on or after July 1, 1929.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">Section 11-102(b)(2) applies to a will or inter vivos instrument executed on or after January 1, 1970.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">Section 11-103 applies to (1) an inter vivos instrument which took effect on or after June 1, 1960; (2) a will where the testator died after that date; or (3) any appointment made after that date, including an appointment by inter vivos instrument or will under powers created before that date.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">Section 11-104 applies to a will or inter vivos conveyance executed after May 31, 1912.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">Section 11-106 applies to the estate of any decedent dying on or after June 1, 1967.</section>
    <section prefix="(j)">Section 11-107 applies to the estate of any decedent dying on or after January 1, 1970. As to the estate of a decedent dying between October 1, 1964 and December 31, 1969, the provisions of Chapter 918 of the Acts of 1965 apply.</section>
    <section prefix="(k)">Section 11-108 applies to any releases executed on or after January 1, 1970.</section>
    <section prefix="(l)">Section 7-308 of the Tax - General Article applies to the estate of any decedent dying on or after June 1, 1965.</section>
    <section prefix="(m)">Every provision of Title 11 not specifically mentioned in this section became applicable on January 1, 1970.</section>
  </text>
</law>
