<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gfi" order_by="gfi" level="1">Financial Institutions</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gfi-11-413</section_number>
  <catch_line>The Commissioner may not examine or audit any licensee or other person except as expressly provided ...</catch_line>
  <order_by>413</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Commissioner may not examine or audit any licensee or other person except as expressly provided in this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If a buyer has reason to believe that any person has violated any provision of this subtitle or of any other law that regulates agreements, the buyer may file with the Commissioner a written complaint that states the details of the alleged violation.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">On receipt of the written complaint, the Commissioner may inspect any books, records, letters, and contracts of any licensee, seller, or other person that relate to the complaint.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">In investigating a written complaint made under this section, the Commissioner may:<section prefix="(1)">Hold a hearing on the complaint at a time and place in this State that are reasonably convenient to the parties involved;</section><section prefix="(2)">Subpoena witnesses;</section><section prefix="(3)">Take depositions of witnesses who reside outside of this State in the same manner as provided for depositions to be taken in civil actions in courts of record;</section><section prefix="(4)">Pay witnesses the same fees and mileage for their attendance as provided for witnesses in civil actions in courts of record; and</section><section prefix="(5)">Administer oaths.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If any person fails to comply with an order or subpoena of the Commissioner under this subtitle or to appear as a witness and testify concerning any matter about which the person may be interrogated under this subtitle, the Commissioner may file a petition for enforcement with the circuit court for any county.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">On petition by the Commissioner, the court, if it finds it appropriate to do so, shall order the person to:<section prefix="(i)">Obey the order or subpoena; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Produce any necessary records, documents, or other evidence.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The Commissioner shall make findings on any written complaint made under this section and send a copy of the findings to each person involved in the complaint.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">A person may not knowingly refuse to permit the Commissioner to conduct any investigation or examination authorized by this section.</section>
  </text>
</law>
