<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gfi" order_by="" level="1">Financial Institutions</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gfi-6-905</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>905</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Commissioner may order a credit union, or enter into an agreement with a credit union, to take corrective action if the Commissioner finds that the credit union:<section prefix="(1)">Has failed to file a report when due;</section><section prefix="(2)">Is insolvent;</section><section prefix="(3)">Has violated any provision of this title; or</section><section prefix="(4)">Is engaged in an unsafe or unauthorized practice.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Before the order becomes effective, the Commissioner shall give the credit union an opportunity for a hearing.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Notice of the hearing shall be given and the hearing shall be held in accordance with Title 10 of the State Government Article.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">If the Commissioner determines that the violation or practice under subsection (a) of this section requires immediate action to protect depositors or members, the Commissioner:<section prefix="(1)">May issue a cease and desist order that is effective on service; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Shall give the credit union an opportunity for a hearing to rescind the order.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">If the credit union fails to comply with the order within 60 days after it becomes effective, the Commissioner may:<section prefix="(1)">Take possession of the business and assets of the credit union and operate it until the Commissioner permits it to resume business or until the Commissioner orders its liquidation under item (3) of this subsection;</section><section prefix="(2)">Order the credit union share guaranty corporation that insures the credit union to take possession of the business and assets of the credit union and operate it in accordance with the Commissioner's instructions until the Commissioner permits it to resume business or until the Commissioner orders its liquidation under item (3) of this subsection; or</section><section prefix="(3)">Place the credit union in receivership for liquidation in the same manner as provided for a banking institution under Title 5, Subtitle 6 of this article.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
