<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gfi" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="12-922" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gfi-12-922</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">To enable the Commissioner to determine compliance with this subtitle, a licensee shall make and preserve the following books, accounts, and records for a period of at least 7 years:<section prefix="(1)">A general ledger containing all assets, liability, capital, income, and expense accounts;</section><section prefix="(2)">Each debt management services agreement between the licensee and a consumer;</section><section prefix="(3)">Books and records for each consumer with whom the licensee has a debt management services agreement;</section><section prefix="(4)">Bank statements and bank reconciliation records;</section><section prefix="(5)">A copy of each written summary required under &#xA7; 12-916(a)(1)(i)2 of this subtitle; and</section><section prefix="(6)">A copy of each signed acknowledgment required under &#xA7; 12-916(a)(1)(i)3 of this subtitle.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A licensee may retain the books, accounts, and records required under this section at any location, provided that the licensee:<section prefix="(1)">Notifies the Commissioner in writing of the location of the books, accounts, and records; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Makes the books, accounts, and records available at a location in the State, as agreed by the Commissioner and the licensee, within 7 days after a written request for examination by the Commissioner.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A licensee shall retain the books, accounts, and records required under this section in:<section prefix="(1)">Original form; or</section><section prefix="(2)">Photographic, electronic, or other similar form approved by the Commissioner.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">If the Commissioner finds that the books, accounts, and records of the licensee are insufficient to determine compliance with this subtitle, the Commissioner may require the licensee to have a certified public accountant audit the licensee, at the licensee's expense, for any period of time that the Commissioner considers necessary.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A licensee shall keep all books, accounts, and records relating to a consumer confidential, and may not disclose any information about a consumer except to a duly authorized government official, the consumer, or the consumer's representative.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A duly authorized government official may disclose information obtained under paragraph (1) of this subsection only in accordance with Title 10, Subtitle 6 of the State Government Article.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The requirements of this section also apply to books, accounts, and records in the possession of a subsidiary, affiliate, or other person that relate to the operation of and services provided by the licensee's debt management services business.</section>
  </text>
</law>
