<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gfi" order_by="" level="1">Financial Institutions</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gfi-12-921</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>921</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">On or before April 30 of each year, a licensee shall report to the Commissioner on the debt management services business of the licensee conducted during the preceding calendar year.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The annual report shall be on the form that the Commissioner requires.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The report shall include:<section prefix="(i)">An audited financial statement that is prepared in accordance with generally accepted accounting principles and includes a balance sheet, income statement, statement of changes in fund balances, and statement of cash flow;</section><section prefix="(ii)">An alphabetical list of all debt management counselors who provided services for the licensee during the previous calendar year;</section><section prefix="(iii)">The number of consumers for whom the licensee provided debt management services under a debt management services agreement during the preceding calendar year;</section><section prefix="(iv)">The number of consumers who signed new debt management services agreements with the licensee during the preceding calendar year;</section><section prefix="(v)">The highest number of consumers for whom the licensee provided debt management services under a debt management services agreement during any month in the preceding calendar year;</section><section prefix="(vi)">The amounts paid by consumers to the licensee, both in total and for each month, during the preceding calendar year, broken down by:<section prefix="1.">Payments to be disbursed to creditors; and</section><section prefix="2.">Payments for the licensee's services;</section></section><section prefix="(vii)">The percentage of all consumers who received a consumer education program and subsequently executed a debt management services agreement during the preceding calendar year;</section><section prefix="(viii)">The number of consumers who successfully completed a debt management plan during the preceding calendar year;</section><section prefix="(ix)">The number of consumers who ceased participating in a debt management plan without successfully completing the plan during the preceding calendar year; and</section><section prefix="(x)">A representative sample of the written summary required under &#xA7; 12-916(a)(1)(i)2 of this subtitle.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Within 15 days after the occurrence of any of the following events, a licensee shall file a written report with the Commissioner describing the event and its expected impact on the licensee's activities in the State:<section prefix="(i)">The filing for bankruptcy or reorganization by the licensee;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The institution of a revocation or suspension proceeding against the licensee by a governmental authority that is related to the licensee's debt management services business in any state;</section><section prefix="(iii)">A felony indictment or conviction of the licensee, or any of its officers, directors, or debt management counselors, that is related to the licensee's debt management services business;</section><section prefix="(iv)">The commencement of a civil action by a consumer against the licensee, or its owners, officers, directors, principals, or debt management counselors, that is related to the licensee's debt management services business;</section><section prefix="(v)">The filing of any material litigation against the licensee, or its owners, officers, directors, principals, or debt management counselors, that is related to the licensee's debt management services business; and</section><section prefix="(vi)">A list of all third-party vendors and other service providers that the licensee used in providing debt management services at any time in the preceding calendar year.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The written report required under paragraph (1) of this subsection shall be sent to the Commissioner by certified mail, return receipt requested, and include details sufficient to identify the event.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Commissioner may require any other reports from a licensee that the Commissioner considers necessary.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">If a licensee fails to make any report required by this subtitle, the Commissioner may require the licensee to pay a surcharge not exceeding $50 for each day that the report is overdue.</section>
  </text>
</law>
