<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gfi" order_by="gfi" level="1">Financial Institutions</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gfi-11-501</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated....</catch_line>
  <order_by>501</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Borrower" means a person who makes a loan application for or receives a loan or other extension of credit that is or is intended to be secured in whole or in part by any interest in a dwelling or residential real estate located in Maryland.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Dwelling" has the meaning stated in 15 U.S.C. &#xA7; 1602(w).</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Dwelling" does not include a residential structure or mobile home unless the residential structure or mobile home, or at least one unit contained in the residential structure or mobile home, is owner-occupied.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Independent evidence of commercial purpose" means, where a mortgage loan is made for a commercial purpose to an individual, any and all documentation by which the mortgage lender, prior to the making or procurement of the loan, establishes that the borrower is seeking funds for a legitimate commercial enterprise.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Independent evidence of commercial purpose" does not include an affidavit of the borrower without supporting evidence, except where:<section prefix="(i)">The borrower is seeking funds to start a business and has not yet incorporated or prepared documentation or proof of ownership of a commercial enterprise; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">The affidavit states the purpose for which the proceeds of the mortgage loan are to be used and the nature of the business conducted or to be conducted by the borrower.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"Interest in real estate" includes:<section prefix="(1)">A confessed judgment note or consent judgment required or obtained by any person acting as a mortgage lender for the purpose of acquiring a lien on a dwelling or residential real estate;</section><section prefix="(2)">A sale and leaseback required or obtained by any person acting as a mortgage lender for the purpose of creating a lien on a dwelling or residential real estate;</section><section prefix="(3)">A mortgage, deed of trust or lien other than a judgment lien, on a dwelling or residential real estate; and</section><section prefix="(4)">Any other security interest that has the effect of creating a lien on a dwelling or residential real estate in Maryland.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">"License" means a license issued by the Commissioner under this subtitle to authorize a person to engage in business as a mortgage lender.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">"Licensee" means a person who is licensed under the Maryland Mortgage Lender Law.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Loan application" means any oral or written request for an extension of credit that is made in accordance with procedures established by a mortgage lender for the purpose of inducing the lender to seek to procure or make a mortgage loan.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Loan application" does not include the use of an account or line of credit to obtain a loan within a previously established credit limit.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(i)">"Mortgage broker" means a person who:<section prefix="(1)">For a fee or other valuable consideration, whether received directly or indirectly, aids or assists a borrower in obtaining a mortgage loan; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Is not named as a lender in the agreement, note, deed of trust, or other evidence of the indebtedness.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(j)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Mortgage lender" means any person who:<section prefix="(i)">Is a mortgage broker;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Makes a mortgage loan to any person; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">Is a mortgage servicer.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Mortgage lender" does not include:<section prefix="(i)">A financial institution that accepts deposits and is regulated under Title 3, Title 4, Title 5, or Title 6 of this article;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The Federal Home Loan Mortgage Corporation;</section><section prefix="(iii)">The Federal National Mortgage Association;</section><section prefix="(iv)">The Government National Mortgage Association;</section><section prefix="(v)">Any person engaged exclusively in the acquisition of all or any portion of a mortgage loan under any federal, State, or local governmental program of mortgage loan purchases; or</section><section prefix="(vi)">An affiliated insurance producer-mortgage loan originator licensed under &#xA7; 11-603.1 of this subtitle.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(k)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Mortgage lending business" means the activities set forth in the definition of "mortgage lender" in subsection (j) of this section which require that person to be licensed under this subtitle.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Mortgage lending business" includes the making or procuring of mortgage loans secured by a dwelling or residential real estate located outside Maryland.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(l)">"Mortgage loan" means any loan primarily for personal, family, or household use that is secured by a mortgage, deed of trust, or other equivalent consensual security interest on a dwelling or residential real estate on which a dwelling is constructed or intended to be constructed.</section>
    <section prefix="(m)">"Mortgage loan originator" has the meaning stated in &#xA7; 11-601 of this title.</section>
    <section prefix="(n)">"Mortgage servicer" means a person who:<section prefix="(1)">Engages in whole or in part in the business of servicing mortgage loans for others; or</section><section prefix="(2)">Collects or otherwise receives payments on mortgage loans directly from borrowers for distribution to any other person.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(o)">''Nationwide Mortgage Licensing System and Registry'' means a mortgage licensing system developed and maintained by the Conference of State Bank Supervisors and the American Association of Residential Mortgage Regulators for the licensing and registration of licensed mortgage loan originators and mortgage lenders.</section>
    <section prefix="(p)">"Person" means a natural person, corporation, limited liability company, partnership, business trust, statutory trust, or association.</section>
    <section prefix="(q)">"Residential real estate" means any owner-occupied real property located in Maryland on which a dwelling is constructed or intended to be constructed.</section>
    <section prefix="(r)">"State" means the State of Maryland.</section>
  </text>
</law>
