<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gfi" order_by="gfi" level="1">Financial Institutions</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gfi-12-404</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this section, "Fund" means the Money Transmission Fund established under this section....</catch_line>
  <order_by>404</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, "Fund" means the Money Transmission Fund established under this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">There is a Money Transmission Fund that consists of:<section prefix="(1)">All revenue received for the licensing of persons who engage in the business of money transmission under this subtitle;</section><section prefix="(2)">Income from the investments that the State Treasurer makes for the Fund; and</section><section prefix="(3)">Any other fee, examination assessment, or revenue received by the Commissioner under this subtitle.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Notwithstanding subsection (b) of this section, the Commissioner shall pay all fines and penalties collected by the Commissioner under this subtitle into the General Fund of the State.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The purpose of the Fund is to pay all the costs and expenses incurred by the Commissioner that are related to the regulation of the business of money transmission under this subtitle, including:<section prefix="(1)">Expenditures authorized under this subtitle; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Any other expense authorized in the State budget.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">All the costs and expenses of the Commissioner relating to the regulation of the business of money transmission under this subtitle shall be included in the State budget.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Any expenditures from the Fund to cover costs and expenses of the Commissioner may be made only:<section prefix="(i)">With an appropriation from the Fund approved by the General Assembly in the annual State budget; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">By the budget amendment procedure provided for in &#xA7; 7-209 of the State Finance and Procurement Article.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">If, in any given fiscal year, the amount of the revenue collected by the Commissioner and deposited into the Fund exceeds the actual appropriation for the Commissioner to regulate the business of money transmission under this subtitle, the excess amount shall be carried forward within the Fund.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The State Treasurer is the custodian of the Fund.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The State Treasurer shall deposit payments received from the Commissioner into the Fund.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Fund is a continuing, nonlapsing fund and is not subject to &#xA7; 7-302 of the State Finance and Procurement Article, and may not be deemed a part of the General Fund of the State.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Unless otherwise provided by law, no part of the Fund may revert or be credited to:<section prefix="(i)">The General Fund of the State; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">A special fund of the State.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
