<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gfi" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="12-905" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gfi-12-905</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">There is a Debt Management Services Fund that consists of:<section prefix="(1)">All revenue received for the licensing of persons that provide debt management services under this subtitle;</section><section prefix="(2)">Income from investments that the Treasurer makes for the Fund; and</section><section prefix="(3)">Except as provided in subsection (b) of this section, any other fee or revenue received by the Commissioner under this subtitle.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Commissioner shall pay all fines and penalties collected by the Commissioner under this subtitle into the General Fund of the State.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The purpose of the Fund is to pay all the costs and expenses incurred by the Commissioner that are related to the regulation of the debt management services business under this subtitle, including:<section prefix="(1)">Expenditures authorized under this subtitle; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Any other expense authorized in the State budget.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Treasurer is the custodian of the Fund.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Treasurer shall deposit payments received from the Commissioner into the Fund.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Fund is a continuing, nonlapsing fund that is not subject to &#xA7; 7-302 of the State Finance and Procurement Article, and may not be deemed a part of the General Fund of the State.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Unless otherwise provided by law, no part of the Fund may revert or be credited to:<section prefix="(i)">The General Fund of the State; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">A special fund of the State.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">All the costs and expenses of the Commissioner relating to the regulation of the debt management services business under this subtitle shall be included in the State budget.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Any expenditures from the Fund to cover costs and expenses of the Commissioner may be made only:<section prefix="(i)">By an appropriation from the Fund approved by the General Assembly in the annual State budget; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">By the budget amendment procedure provided for in &#xA7; 7-209 of the State Finance and Procurement Article.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">If, in any fiscal year, the amount of the revenue collected by the Commissioner and deposited into the Fund exceeds the actual appropriation for the Commissioner to regulate the debt management services business under this subtitle, the excess amount shall be carried forward within the Fund.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">The Office of Legislative Audits shall audit the accounts and transactions of the Fund under &#xA7; 2-1220 of the State Government Article.</section>
  </text>
</law>
