<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gfi" order_by="" level="1">Financial Institutions</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gfi-3-211.1</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>211.1</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, "receivership" means a proceeding in which:<section prefix="(1)">The Commissioner takes possession of a nondepository trust company in accordance with &#xA7; 5-601, &#xA7; 5-602, or &#xA7; 5-602.1 of this article; and</section><section prefix="(2)">A receiver is appointed in accordance with &#xA7; 5-605 of this article.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A nondepository trust company shall pledge securities or deliver a surety bond to the Commissioner, for the benefit of the Commissioner, to defray the costs of a receivership.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The amount of the securities or surety bond shall be determined by the Commissioner in an amount that the Commissioner deems appropriate to defray such costs, but in no event shall the amount exceed:<section prefix="(i)">$1,000,000 for a nondepository trust company with a composite rating, using the Uniform Interagency Trust Rating System, of 1 or 2; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">$3,000,000 for a nondepository trust company with a composite rating, using the Uniform Interagency Trust Rating System, of 3, 4, or 5.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Subject to the provisions of Title 5, Subtitle 6 of this article, in the event of a receivership, the Commissioner or a receiver appointed under &#xA7; 5-605 of this article may, without regard to any priorities, preferences, or adverse claims, reduce the pledged securities or the surety bond to cash and use the cash to defray the costs associated with the receivership.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If a nondepository trust company chooses to pledge securities to satisfy the requirement of subsection (b) of this section, the securities shall be held at a depository institution or a federal reserve bank approved by the Commissioner.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Commissioner may specify the types of securities that may be pledged.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Any fees associated with holding pledged securities shall be the responsibility of the nondepository trust company.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">Securities pledged by a nondepository trust company may not be assets relied on by the nondepository trust company to meet the minimum capital requirements of &#xA7; 3-209 of this subtitle.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">Any income earned on securities pledged by a nondepository trust company:<section prefix="(i)">Shall be paid to the nondepository trust company; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">May not be held by the Commissioner.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If a nondepository trust company chooses to purchase a surety bond to satisfy the requirement of subsection (b) of this section, the surety bond shall be issued by a bonding company that:<section prefix="(i)">Is authorized to do business in this State; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Has a rating in one of the three highest grades as determined by a national rating service.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The surety bond shall be in a form approved by the Commissioner.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A nondepository trust company may not obtain a surety bond from any affiliate, as defined in &#xA7; 5-401 of this article.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
