<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gfi" order_by="" level="1">Financial Institutions</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gfi-1-202</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>202</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">A requirement in this article that a document be acknowledged means that the document shall be acknowledged by an individual:<section prefix="(1)">As the act of that individual; or</section><section prefix="(2)">If the document is that of a corporate or other entity, as the act of that entity.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A requirement in this article that a document be verified means that the document shall be verified by a declaration made under the penalties for perjury that the matters and facts contained in the document are true to the best of the knowledge, information, and belief of the individual making the declaration.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The acknowledgment or verification shall be made:<section prefix="(1)">Before an individual authorized to take acknowledgments or administer oaths; or</section><section prefix="(2)">By a signed statement of acknowledgment or verification that:<section prefix="(i)">Is in the document or attached to and made part of the document; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">As to a verification, states that the statement is made under the penalties for perjury.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">If the procedures provided in subsection (c)(2) of this section are used:<section prefix="(1)">A statement of acknowledgment has the same legal effect as an acknowledgment made before an individual authorized to take acknowledgments; and</section><section prefix="(2)">A statement of verification subjects the individual making the statement to the penalties for perjury to the same extent as if the statement had been verified under oath before an individual authorized to administer oaths.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
