<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gfi" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="5-401" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gfi-5-401</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Affiliate" means any association, corporation, business trust, statutory trust, or other similar organization that:<section prefix="(1)">Is not a bank service corporation and is controlled by a banking institution through:<section prefix="(i)">Direct or indirect ownership or control of more than 50 percent of the voting rights;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Control of the election of a majority of the management;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Direct or indirect ownership or control of more than 50 percent of the voting rights exercised at the last election of the management;</section><section prefix="(iv)">Directors of the banking institution constituting a majority of the management of the organization; or</section><section prefix="(v)">Any direct or indirect control by stockholders of the banking institution, if the stockholders own or control:</section></section><section prefix="(2)">Controls a banking institution through:<section prefix="(i)">Direct or indirect ownership or control of more than 50 percent of the voting rights;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Control of the election of a majority of the directors of the banking institution;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Direct or indirect ownership or control of more than 50 percent of the voting rights exercised at the last election of the directors; or</section><section prefix="(iv)">The holding of substantially all of the capital stock of the banking institution by trustees for stockholders of the organization.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Bank service corporation" means a corporation:<section prefix="(1)">At least some of the stock of which is owned by a banking institution; and</section><section prefix="(2)">That is organized to perform bank service corporation activities of the type permitted under applicable provisions of Title 12 of the United States Code to a bank service corporation owned exclusively by national banking associations.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">"Management" means the directors, trustees, or other persons exercising similar functions of an association, corporation, business trust, statutory trust, or other similar organization.</section>
  </text>
</law>
