<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gfi" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="5-302" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gfi-5-302</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">As to the interest bearing account of each depositor in a banking institution, the banking institution shall generally make available to any customer with an existing account, in addition to actually giving to the customer, on the opening of the interest bearing account and, later, on demand of the customer:<section prefix="(i)">Written notice of:</section><section prefix="(ii)">The following written notice:</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Not less than 30 days before a banking institution adopts any change regarding any information required under paragraph (1)(i) of this subsection, the banking institution shall inform each customer of the change in the banking institution's periodic statement or by written notice.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A banking institution shall pay interest on each interest bearing account that is instituted for a specific purpose, including "Christmas" or "vacation" accounts, for a period of 1 year or less at an annual rate not less than the 6-month average dealer bid rate on nationally traded certificates of deposit, as published by the Federal Reserve in "Selected Interest Rates (Daily) - H.15", as of the first business day of the calendar year.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A banking institution that fails to comply with subsection (a) or (b) of this section shall be liable to any customer of the banking institution who sustains any injury or loss as the result of the failure to comply for:<section prefix="(1)">All foreseeable losses incurred by the customer; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Reasonable attorney's fees.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Subject to paragraph (2) of this subsection, on or after October 1, 1992, a banking institution shall comply with the requirements in:<section prefix="(i)">Subsection (a) of this section; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">Final regulations adopted by the Federal Reserve Board pursuant to &#xA7; 269 of Public Law 102-242.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">On or after the date when compliance with the final regulations adopted by the Federal Reserve Board pursuant to &#xA7; 269 of Public Law 102-242 is mandatory, a banking institution shall comply with the requirements in those final regulations and subsection (a) of this section shall be null and void.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
