<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gfi" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="5-512" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gfi-5-512</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Commercial loan" means a loan that is made:<section prefix="(i)">Solely to acquire or carry on a business or commercial enterprise; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">To any business or commercial organization.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Consumer loan" means a loan that is made primarily for personal, family, or household purposes.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">"Executive officer" has the meaning stated in Title 12 of the Code of Federal Regulations, &#xA7; 215.2.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Unless the loan is approved or exempted from approval as provided in this section, the following persons may not borrow, directly or indirectly, any money from a banking institution:<section prefix="(1)">Any director, officer, or employee of the banking institution;</section><section prefix="(2)">Any partnership of which the director, officer, or employee is a member; or</section><section prefix="(3)">Any corporation in which the director, officer, or employee is an officer or owns the majority interest.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">This section does not require approval of:<section prefix="(1)">A commercial loan that is made to:<section prefix="(i)">A director of the banking institution, unless the director also is an officer or employee of the banking institution;</section><section prefix="(ii)">A partnership of which the director is a member, unless an officer or employee of the banking institution also is a member of that partnership; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">A corporation in which the director holds any interest, unless an officer or employee of the banking institution is an officer or owns the majority interest in that corporation; or</section></section><section prefix="(2)">A loan that is:<section prefix="(i)">A consumer loan; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Is made to an employee of a banking institution who is not an executive officer or director of the banking institution.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A loan to a director, officer, or employee of a banking institution may be made only if the loan has been approved by a resolution adopted at and recorded in the minutes of a meeting of:<section prefix="(i)">The board of directors of the banking institution; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">The executive committee of the banking institution, if that committee is authorized to make loans.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If a loan is approved by an executive committee, the loan approval shall be reported to the board of directors at its next meeting.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A loan made under this section shall be reviewed every 6 months by the board of directors.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The loan may not be renewed or extended unless the renewal or extension has been approved by a resolution adopted at a meeting of the board of directors and recorded in the minutes of the meeting.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">All loans to a director, officer, or employee of a banking institution are subject to the limitations imposed by &#xA7; 3-601 of this article.</section>
  </text>
</law>
