<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gfi" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="11-609" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gfi-11-609</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Subject to any regulations the Commissioner adopts in connection with the transition to the Nationwide Mortgage Licensing System and Registry, an initial license term shall:<section prefix="(1)">Be for a maximum period of 1 year;</section><section prefix="(2)">Begin on the first day the license is issued; and</section><section prefix="(3)">Expire on December 31 of the year the license is issued.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">On or before November 1 of the year of expiration, a license may be renewed if the licensee:<section prefix="(1)">Subject to subsections (e) and (f) of this section, meets the minimum standards for the issuance of a license and otherwise is entitled to be licensed;</section><section prefix="(2)">Pays to the Commissioner a renewal fee set by the Commissioner; and</section><section prefix="(3)">Submits to the Commissioner:<section prefix="(i)">A renewal application on the form that the Commissioner requires; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Satisfactory evidence of compliance with any continuing education requirements under this subtitle or set by regulations adopted by the Commissioner.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Subject to any regulations the Commissioner adopts in connection with the transition to the Nationwide Mortgage Licensing System and Registry, a renewal term shall:<section prefix="(1)">Be for a maximum period of 1 year;</section><section prefix="(2)">Begin on January 1 of each year after the initial term; and</section><section prefix="(3)">Expire on December 31 of the year the renewal term begins.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">In addition to the license renewal fee required under subsection (b)(2) of this section, an applicant for a license renewal shall pay to the Nationwide Mortgage Licensing System and Registry any fees that the Nationwide Mortgage Licensing System and Registry imposes in connection with the renewal application.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">Notwithstanding anything to the contrary in this section or &#xA7; 11-605 of this subtitle, an applicant for renewal of a license who is duly licensed under this subtitle on July 1, 2009:<section prefix="(1)">May comply with the following requirements for renewal of the license on or before December 31, 2010:<section prefix="(i)">The fingerprinting and criminal history report requirement under &#xA7; 11-604 of this subtitle;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The surety bond coverage requirement under &#xA7; 11-619 of this subtitle; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">The prelicensing testing requirement under &#xA7; 11-606.1 of this subtitle; and</section></section><section prefix="(2)">Is deemed to have satisfied the prelicensing educational course requirement under &#xA7; 11-606 of this subtitle if the applicant completed 20 hours of continuing education courses approved by the Commissioner within 5 years prior to the expiration date of the applicant's current license.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">If a license is surrendered voluntarily or is suspended or revoked, the Commissioner may not refund any part of the license fee regardless of the time remaining in the license term.</section>
  </text>
</law>
