<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gfi" order_by="" level="1">Financial Institutions</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gfi-6-304</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>304</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">A credit union may convert to another field of membership type, as described in &#xA7; 6-301 of this subtitle, if:<section prefix="(1)">The credit union:<section prefix="(i)">Meets the common bond requirements of the proposed field of membership type; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Files with the Commissioner an application and any other documents that the Commissioner deems necessary to make a determination on the application; and</section></section><section prefix="(2)">The Commissioner determines that approval:<section prefix="(i)">Is in the best interest of the existing and proposed memberships;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Provides a means for better service to the existing membership;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Is in accordance with sound credit union practices; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">Does not expose the funds of the existing members to unnecessary risk.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Unless the Commissioner notifies the credit union that a different time period is necessary, within 120 days after the application is filed, the Commissioner shall notify the credit union of the determination on the application.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">No less than 30 days before the effective date of the conversion, the credit union shall give notice of the conversion to all groups of potential members of the credit union that will be removed from the field of membership as a result of the conversion.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">On and after the effective date of the conversion, the credit union:<section prefix="(i)">May not continue to serve groups within the field of membership of the credit union that no longer qualify for membership in the credit union as a result of the conversion; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">May continue to serve members of a group identified under item (i) of this paragraph who are members before the effective date of the conversion.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
