<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gfi" order_by="" level="1">Financial Institutions</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gfi-3-601</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>601</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">This section does not apply to:<section prefix="(1)">Any readily marketable bond or like obligation that is held by a commercial bank as an investment;</section><section prefix="(2)">Any loan that is made to this State or to a political subdivision and that matures in less than 1 year;</section><section prefix="(3)">Any loan of $3,500 or less, unless that loan exceeds 20 percent of the unimpaired capital and surplus of the commercial bank; or</section><section prefix="(4)">Any liability lawfully incurred before June 1, 1937.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The total of all liabilities of any one person to a commercial bank, including all liabilities referred to in this section, may not exceed at any time 30 percent of the unimpaired capital and surplus of the commercial bank.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this subsection, "loan":<section prefix="(i)">Includes an obligation under a standby letter of credit; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Does not include any discount or obligation that is subject to subsection (d) or (e) of this section.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The total liability of any one person to a commercial bank for loans may not exceed at any time:<section prefix="(i)">10 percent of the unimpaired capital and surplus of the commercial bank; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">30 percent of the unimpaired capital and surplus of the commercial bank if the excess over 10 percent is approved by a two-thirds vote of the board of directors and is secured by currency or obligations of the United States or obligations of this State or any political subdivision.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this subsection, "commercial paper" means any commercial paper issued in connection with a commercial transaction or any chattel paper, if the person negotiating the commercial paper or chattel paper owns it.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The total liability of any one person to a commercial bank for discounts of commercial paper may not exceed at any time 25 percent of the unimpaired capital and surplus of the commercial bank.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this subsection, "obligations secured by goods" means obligations that are drawn in good faith against actual existing values and are:<section prefix="(i)">Secured by goods in the process of shipment; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">When accepted, accompanied by documents of title for these goods.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The total liability of any one person to a commercial bank for obligations secured by goods may not exceed at any time 25 percent of the unimpaired capital and surplus of the commercial bank.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">For purposes of this section, the rules set forth in subsections (g) through (j) of this section apply in computing the total liabilities of any one person to a commercial bank.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, the total liabilities of any individual to a commercial bank include:<section prefix="(i)">All liabilities to the commercial bank of any partnership or unincorporated association of which the individual is a member; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">All loans that the commercial bank makes for the benefit of the individual or for the benefit of any partnership or unincorporated association of which the individual is a member.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If the individual holds only a limited interest in a limited partnership, the liabilities of the limited partnership and the loans made for its benefit that are included in the individual's total liabilities may not exceed the value of the individual's interest in the limited partnership.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(h)">The total liabilities of any partnership or unincorporated association to a commercial bank include:<section prefix="(1)">All liabilities of its individual members to the commercial bank; and</section><section prefix="(2)">All loans that the commercial bank makes for the benefit of the partnership or association or for the benefit of any member of the partnership or association.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(i)">The total liabilities of any corporation to a commercial bank include all loans that the commercial bank makes for the benefit of the corporation.</section>
    <section prefix="(j)">For purposes of this section, a loan is considered to be made for the benefit of a corporation, partnership, or unincorporated association to the extent that the proceeds of the loan are transferred to the corporation, partnership, or association.</section>
    <section prefix="(k)">For purposes of this section, "unimpaired surplus" of a commercial bank includes surplus, retained earnings, and 100 percent of the reserve for possible loan losses.</section>
  </text>
</law>
