<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gfi" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="3-703" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gfi-3-703</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">An agreement of consolidation, merger, or transfer of assets shall be approved by the affirmative vote of a majority of the full authorized membership of the board of directors of each constituent commercial bank.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The agreement shall include:<section prefix="(1)">The name of each constituent bank and the address of its principal banking office;</section><section prefix="(2)">The terms of the proposed transaction;</section><section prefix="(3)">A statement that the agreement is subject to approval by the Commissioner and by the stockholders of each constituent bank;</section><section prefix="(4)">Provisions for disposing of any stock of the successor that is not taken by objecting stockholders of the constituent banks;</section><section prefix="(5)">As to the successor:<section prefix="(i)">The address of the proposed principal banking office;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The authorized capital stock, including the number of shares and the par value of each share of stock;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Whether it will issue preferred stock in the proposed transaction and, if so, the amount, terms, and preferences; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">Any amendments to its charter and bylaws; and</section></section><section prefix="(6)">Any other provisions that the Commissioner requires to carry out the Commissioner's duties with respect to the proposed transaction.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">After the board of directors of each constituent bank has approved the agreement, the following shall be filed with the Commissioner for approval:<section prefix="(1)">The agreement;</section><section prefix="(2)">The name and address of each office of the constituent banks and of the successor;</section><section prefix="(3)">The name and residence address of each individual who will be a director when the proposed transaction becomes effective;</section><section prefix="(4)">The name and residence address of each individual who will be an officer when the proposed transaction becomes effective;</section><section prefix="(5)">A certified copy of the approving resolution of each board of directors, showing the required approval by the board; and</section><section prefix="(6)">Evidence of proper action by the board of directors of any constituent national banking association.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as otherwise provided by law, any person who knowingly submits false information to the Commissioner while complying with subsection (c) of this section is guilty of a misdemeanor.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A person who violates this section is subject to a fine of not more than $1,000, or imprisonment for not more than 5 years, or both.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
