<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gfi" order_by="gfi" level="1">Financial Institutions</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gfi-6-807</section_number>
  <catch_line>A credit union may establish a branch in the State in accordance with the provisions of this section...</catch_line>
  <order_by>807</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">A credit union may establish a branch in the State in accordance with the provisions of this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A credit union that proposes to establish a branch in the State shall:<section prefix="(i)">File with the Commissioner, at least 30 days before the intended opening date, a notice of intention to open a branch;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Submit to the Commissioner any information the Commissioner requires in order to evaluate the proposed branch; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Pay to the Commissioner a branch fee of $100.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The branch fee may not apply to a branch that is acquired by a credit union through a merger or consolidation with, or transfer to the credit union of all or substantially all of the assets of, a credit union.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">In deciding whether to approve the establishment of a branch, the Commissioner shall consider whether:<section prefix="(1)">The establishment of the branch will promote the convenience of the members of the credit union;</section><section prefix="(2)">The applicant has sufficient net worth to support the branch; and</section><section prefix="(3)">The applicant generally is operating in compliance with the provisions of this title.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Commissioner shall decide whether to approve the establishment of a branch within 30 days of receipt of the notice specified in subsection (b)(1) of this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The establishment of a branch shall be deemed approved if the Commissioner takes no action on the notice within the time limit specified in this subsection.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
