<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gfi" order_by="" level="1">Financial Institutions</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gfi-13-1110</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>1110</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Authority may consider proposals submitted by local jurisdictions to designate a heritage area as a recognized heritage area.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Authority shall adopt regulations that specify criteria and procedures for designating recognized heritage areas.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A proposal for the designation of a heritage area as a recognized heritage area shall:<section prefix="(1)">Be previously approved and submitted by the governing bodies of all of the local jurisdictions located within the specific boundaries proposed for the recognized heritage area;</section><section prefix="(2)">To the maximum extent practicable, be developed in consultation with affected State agencies;</section><section prefix="(3)">Specify the boundaries for the recognized heritage area;</section><section prefix="(4)">Identify the local entity responsible for coordinating development of the management plan required under &#xA7; 13-1111 of this subtitle;</section><section prefix="(5)">Describe the cultural, historic, and natural resources which contribute to the special character of the heritage area;</section><section prefix="(6)">Specify the general goals and objectives for the preservation, development, and management of the heritage area;</section><section prefix="(7)">Identify the types of public and private uses to be accommodated in the heritage area;</section><section prefix="(8)">Describe strategies for encouraging and accommodating visitation to and compatible economic development of the heritage area;</section><section prefix="(9)">Provide an economic overview of the long and short term costs and benefits related to the development of the heritage area; and</section><section prefix="(10)">Describe the techniques and means to be instituted by the local jurisdictions to assure the long term preservation and protection of the cultural, historic, and natural resources within the heritage area, including zoning, subdivision controls, and other growth management techniques.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Authority may not designate a heritage area as a recognized heritage area unless the Authority finds that:<section prefix="(1)">The heritage area contains resources of statewide significance that have retained integrity of setting and a cohesive character;</section><section prefix="(2)">The heritage area contains at least one or more:<section prefix="(i)">Historic districts either listed in, or determined to be eligible for listing in, the Maryland Register of Historic Properties in accordance with &#xA7; 5A-323 of the State Finance and Procurement Article; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">Natural or recreational resources determined by the Secretary of Natural Resources to be of statewide significance; and</section></section><section prefix="(3)">Public assistance for the heritage area is reasonably expected to produce additional private investments, job creation, and tourism revenues.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The boundaries for each recognized heritage area are the boundaries depicted on the map accompanying each proposal as approved by the Authority.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">After initial approval by the Authority of the boundaries of a recognized heritage area, the Authority may amend or revise the boundaries:<section prefix="(i)">With the approval of all of the local jurisdictions where the property to be added or removed is located; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">On publication of a revised drawing or boundary description in the Maryland Register.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Boundary maps for each recognized heritage area shall be kept on file at the Authority and at the office of the county clerk where the recognized heritage area is located.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">Designation of a heritage area by the Authority as a recognized heritage area establishes eligibility for matching grant assistance for the development of management plans.</section>
  </text>
</law>
