<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gfi" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="5-806" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gfi-5-806</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Except for a bank, trust company, savings bank, or savings and loan association that is authorized to do business in this State, a person may not use any name, title, or other words that represent that the person is authorized to do the business of banking in this State.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">In this subsection the following terms have the meanings indicated.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)"/>
        <section prefix="(iii)">"Name" means the name, trade name, trademark,  service mark, logo, or tagline used by a bank to identify itself.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Except with the consent of the bank, a person may not use the name of a bank or any term or design that is similar to the name of a bank in any marketing material provided to another person or in any solicitation of another person in a manner  that may cause a reasonable person to be confused, mistaken, or deceived that the marketing material or solicitation:<section prefix="(i)">Originated from the bank;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Originated from someone affiliated, connected, or associated with the bank;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Is approved or sponsored by the bank; or</section><section prefix="(iv)">Is the responsibility of the bank.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">In addition to any other remedies a bank may have under any other provision of law, a bank that is affected by a violation of subsection (b) of this section may bring an action against the person that committed the violation to recover:<section prefix="(1)">Actual damages sustained as a result of the violation;</section><section prefix="(2)">Either:<section prefix="(i)">All profits attributable to the violation; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">$1,000 for each violation; and</section></section><section prefix="(3)">Court costs and reasonable attorney's fees.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Any person who violates subsection (a) of this section is guilty of a misdemeanor and on conviction is subject to a fine not exceeding $3,000 or imprisonment not exceeding 5 years or both.</section>
  </text>
</law>
