<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gfi" order_by="" level="1">Financial Institutions</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gfi-12-412</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>412</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, "trust company" has the meaning stated in &#xA7; 1-101 of the Estates and Trusts Article.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">With the application for a new or renewal license, the applicant shall file evidence of a surety device with the Commissioner as provided in this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A surety bond purchased to satisfy the provisions of subsection (b) of this section shall run to this State for the benefit of any individual who has been damaged by a violation of State law or regulation governing the business of money transmission committed by a licensee or an authorized delegate of a licensee.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The surety bond shall be:<section prefix="(i)">In the amount required under subsection (e) of this section; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Issued by a bonding, surety, or insurance company that is authorized to do business in this State.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The surety bond shall be conditioned so that the licensee and any authorized delegate of the licensee shall comply with all State and federal laws and regulations governing the business of money transmission and shall fulfill all obligations to all parties to a money transmission.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The liability of a surety:<section prefix="(i)">Is not affected by the insolvency or bankruptcy of the licensee or by any misrepresentation, breach of warranty, failure to pay a premium, or other act or omission of the licensee; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Continues as to all transactions of the licensee or an authorized delegate, for no longer than 5 years after the licensee ceases, for any reason, to be licensed. However, the Commissioner may permit the surety bond to be reduced or eliminated prior to that time if the amount of the licensee's payment instruments outstanding in this State are reduced.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(5)">A licensee or surety may cancel a surety bond by giving the Commissioner notice of the cancellation by certified mail, return receipt requested, bearing a postmark from the United States Postal Service. However, the cancellation is not effective until 90 days after the Commissioner receives the notice.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A deposit in lieu of a surety bond made to satisfy the provisions of subsection (b) of this section shall:<section prefix="(i)">Have a market value equal to the amount required under subsection (e) of this section; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Be held by the Commissioner to secure the same obligations as are required to be secured by a surety bond under subsection (c) of this section.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">At any time, a licensee may exchange investments for other investments that meet the requirements of this subsection.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Commissioner may sell or transfer investments and distribute the proceeds on the same basis as provided for claims against a surety bond under paragraph (c)(1) of this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">As long as a licensee is solvent, the licensee is entitled to receive any interest or dividends earned by the investments.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The Commissioner may place the investments in the custody of any qualified trust company in this State.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The licensee shall pay the compensation of this custodian.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The amount of the surety device shall be in an amount of not less than $150,000 and not more than $1,000,000, as determined by the Commissioner.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">In setting the amount of the surety device, the Commissioner shall consider:<section prefix="(i)">The financial condition of the licensee or applicant;</section><section prefix="(ii)">For a licensee, the average monthly outstanding payment instruments or outstanding money transmission liability for the previous 12 months;</section><section prefix="(iii)">For an applicant, the projected monthly payment instrument sales and money transmission volume in the State, the business experience, and any other factor deemed appropriate; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">The potential loss of buyers and holders of payment instruments or persons for whom or to whom money is transmitted if the applicant or licensee becomes financially impaired.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If the principal amount of a surety device is reduced by a payment of a claim or judgment, the licensee shall file with the Commissioner evidence of any new or additional surety device in the amount that the Commissioner sets.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If the Commissioner at any time believes that the surety device is insufficient, exhausted, or otherwise unsatisfactory, the Commissioner may require evidence of an additional surety device to be filed by the licensee. Within 30 days after the Commissioner makes a written demand for the new surety device, the licensee shall file the evidence of the new surety device.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">A penalty imposed under &#xA7; 12-426(e)(2) of this subtitle may be paid and collected from the proceeds of a surety device.</section>
  </text>
</law>
