<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gfi" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="9-1005" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gfi-9-1005</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Except as expressly permitted by federal law or Title 5, Subtitle 11 of this article, a savings and loan association or savings and loan holding company that is not a Maryland association, an interstate association, an out-of-state association, a Maryland savings and loan holding company, or an out-of-state savings and loan holding company may not acquire a Maryland association, a Maryland savings and loan holding company, an interstate association, or an out-of-state savings and loan holding company having a Maryland association subsidiary.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, if a Maryland association, interstate association, Maryland savings and loan holding company, or out-of-state savings and loan holding company ceases to be a Maryland association, interstate association, Maryland savings and loan holding company, or out-of-state savings and loan holding company, as defined in this subtitle, the association or savings and loan holding company shall, within 2 years, divest itself of all deposit-taking offices in Maryland, Maryland associations, and Maryland savings and loan holding companies.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A Maryland association, an interstate association, a Maryland savings and loan holding company, or an out-of-state savings and loan holding company may not be required to divest its deposit-taking offices in Maryland, Maryland associations, or Maryland savings and loan holding companies if:<section prefix="(i)">An institution in another jurisdiction not within the region is acquired under &#xA7; 116 or &#xA7; 123 of the Garn-St. Germain Depository Institutions Act of 1982, as amended or 12 U.S.C. &#xA7; 1823(f);</section><section prefix="(ii)">A savings and loan association or savings and loan holding company having deposit-taking offices in a jurisdiction other than within the region is acquired in the regular course of securing or collecting a debt previously contracted in good faith, and the savings and loan association or savings and loan holding company divests the securities or assets acquired within 2 years of the date of acquisition; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">An increase in deposits in deposit-taking offices or in savings and loan association subsidiaries not within the region is not the result of an acquisition of a savings and loan association or savings and loan holding company.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Any acquisition which would result in an association chartered under this title, or under the laws of any other state, having a deposit-taking office in Maryland is prohibited.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Division Director may enforce the provisions of this section through the imposition of penalties up to $500 per day each day the violation continues to exist, the issuance of cease and desist orders under &#xA7; 8-401 of this article, and any other remedies as are provided by law.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">In determining the amount of financial penalty to be imposed, the Division Director shall consider the following:<section prefix="(i)">The seriousness of the violation;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The good faith of the violator;</section><section prefix="(iii)">The violator's history of previous violations;</section><section prefix="(iv)">The deleterious effect of the violation on the public and the savings and loan industry; and</section><section prefix="(v)">The assets of the violator.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
