<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gfi" order_by="gfi" level="1">Financial Institutions</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gfi-9-708</section_number>
  <catch_line>With the prior written approval of the Secretary, the Division Director may institute proceedings in...</catch_line>
  <order_by>708</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">With the prior written approval of the Secretary, the Division Director may institute proceedings in the circuit court of the county where the principal office of a savings and loan association is located for the appointment of a receiver if:<section prefix="(1)"><section prefix="(i)">The savings and loan association or related entity fails to comply with a final order of the Division Director;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The irregularities giving rise to a conservatorship are not corrected;</section><section prefix="(iii)">An emergency exists; or</section><section prefix="(iv)">The savings and loan association or related entity is conducting an unsafe and unsound operation; and</section></section><section prefix="(2)">The Division Director considers the appointment of a receiver to be in the public interest.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Subject to the provisions of &#xA7; 9-709 of this subtitle, a court may appoint a receiver if it finds that a savings and loan association or related entity is:<section prefix="(1)">In an impaired or insolvent condition;</section><section prefix="(2)">In substantial violation of any law or regulation;</section><section prefix="(3)">Concealing any of its assets or records or refusing to submit its records or affairs for inspection to an examiner or lawful agent;</section><section prefix="(4)">Conducting an unsafe and unsound operation;</section><section prefix="(5)">In violation of any final order; or</section><section prefix="(6)">Eligible for receivership under the provisions of Title 10 of this article.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A receiver has:<section prefix="(1)">All the powers and authority of the conservator;</section><section prefix="(2)">The power to liquidate; and</section><section prefix="(3)">Any other powers and authority as may be expressed in the order of any court of competent jurisdiction.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">In addition to the specific powers set forth in this title and any powers granted by order of the court, a receiver appointed under this section has and may exercise all powers necessary or appropriate to liquidate the business and affairs of the savings and loan association, including all of the powers granted by law to the conservator of a savings and loan association and all of the powers granted by law to the receiver of a Maryland corporation that is in the process of voluntary or involuntary dissolution.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except to the extent otherwise provided in this subsection, Title 13 of the Maryland Rules applies to the estate of a savings and loan association for which a receiver is appointed under this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">On motion of the receiver any other interested party, or on the court's own initiative, the court may, after notice and a hearing, waive compliance with or modify one or more of the requirements of Subtitle BP relating to the timing of, method of, or procedures for providing notices, providing claims, or administering distributions from the receivership estate, if the waiver or modification relates to the preservation of the confidentiality of savings account holders, or a reduction in the cost of administration of the receivership estate.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Any waiver or modification made under paragraph (2) of this subsection only shall apply prospectively to actions taken by the receiver or any other person after adoption by the court.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
