<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gfi" order_by="" level="1">Financial Institutions</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gfi-12-915</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>915</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A licensee shall give the Commissioner written notice of any change in the information required to be included in the licensee's application under &#xA7; 12-908(b)(1) and (2) of this subtitle at least 30 days before the change is effective.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The licensee shall provide with the notice evidence that, after the change described in the notice, the licensee will continue to satisfy the surety bond requirement under &#xA7; 12-914 of this subtitle.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Unless approved by the Commissioner, a licensee may not change an owner, officer, director, or principal of the licensee, or an agent who is acting on behalf of the licensee to manage a trust account, listed on the licensee's application under &#xA7; 12-908(b)(3) and (6) of this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">To request approval of a proposed change described in subsection (b) of this section, the licensee shall notify the Commissioner in writing of the proposed change and submit any information that the Commissioner requires.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">For a proposed change in owner or agent acting on behalf of the licensee to manage a trust account, the Commissioner may determine that the filing of a new application for the issuance of a license is warranted.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Unless the Commissioner notifies the licensee that a different time period is necessary, the Commissioner shall approve or deny a request for a change described in subsection (b) of this section within 60 days after the date the Commissioner receives all information required under paragraph (1) of this subsection.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
