<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gfi" order_by="gfi" level="1">Financial Institutions</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gfi-11-206</section_number>
  <catch_line>To apply for a license, an applicant shall sign and submit to the Commissioner a verified applicatio...</catch_line>
  <order_by>206</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">To apply for a license, an applicant shall sign and submit to the Commissioner a verified application on the form that the Commissioner requires.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The application shall include:<section prefix="(i)">The applicant's name and address and, if the applicant is not an individual, the names and addresses of each of its principal owners and each of its officers, directors, or members;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The address at which the business is to be conducted; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Any other pertinent information that the Commissioner requires for an investigation and findings under &#xA7; 11-207 of this subtitle.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">With the application, the applicant shall pay to the Commissioner:<section prefix="(1)">An investigation fee of $100; and</section><section prefix="(2)">A license fee of:<section prefix="(i)">$1,700 if the applicant applies for a license to be issued on or after January 1 and on or before December 31 of an even-numbered year;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Effective January 1, 1999, $850 if the applicant applies for a license to be issued on or after January 1 and on or before December 31 of an odd-numbered year; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">$1,700 if the applicant applies for a license to be issued on or after October 1, 1997 and on or before December 31, 1997.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">With the application, the applicant shall file with the Commissioner a surety bond.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The surety bond filed under this subsection shall run to this State for the benefit of this State and of any person who has a cause of action against the applicant under the Maryland Consumer Loan Law.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The surety bond shall be:<section prefix="(i)">In an amount equal to twice the amount of the largest loan that may be made under the Maryland Consumer Loan Law;</section><section prefix="(ii)">With sureties that the Commissioner approves; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Conditioned that the applicant will comply with the Maryland Consumer Loan Law and will pay to this State or to any person any money that the applicant may owe to this State or to that person under the Maryland Consumer Loan Law.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">For each license for which an applicant applies, the applicant shall:<section prefix="(1)">Submit a separate application;</section><section prefix="(2)">Pay a separate investigation fee and license fee; and</section><section prefix="(3)">File a separate bond.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
