<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gfi" order_by="" level="1">Financial Institutions</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gfi-3-712</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>712</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Consummation of a consolidation or merger has the effects provided in this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The separate existence of each constituent bank, except the successor, ceases.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The successor shall be considered the same business and corporate entity as each of the constituent banks and has all of the rights, powers, and duties of each constituent bank, except:<section prefix="(i)">As limited by the successor's charter or bylaws; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">As limited by the Commissioner or the bank supervisory agency of the state by which an other-state bank is chartered under subsection (e) of this section.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Each constituent bank's rights, franchises, and interests in any property become the property of the successor without any deed, transfer, or other action.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The successor has the same powers that each constituent bank had as to any property held in any fiduciary capacity, without any deed, transfer, or other action. The successor may be removed or replaced as fiduciary in the same manner and to the same extent as the constituent bank.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Unless this construction would be unreasonable, any reference to any constituent bank in any writing, whether executed or taking effect before or after the consolidation or merger, shall be interpreted as a reference to the successor.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The successor may use the name of any constituent bank if it can do any act more conveniently under that name.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">If a constituent bank has assets or engages in business activities that do not conform to the law governing the successor, the Commissioner or the bank supervisory agency of the state by which an other-state bank is chartered may allow a reasonable time for the successor to conform to that law.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">Unless the Commissioner approves, the successor may not carry on its books an asset received from a constituent bank at a higher value than that on the books of the constituent bank at the time of the last examination by a State or federal bank examiner before the effective date of the consolidation or merger.</section>
  </text>
</law>
