<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gfi" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="9-913" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gfi-9-913</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Except as otherwise provided in this section and in this title, any violation of any provision of this title or any regulation adopted in accordance with this title by a director, officer, controlling person, or employee of an association is punishable by a fine not to exceed $10,000, or imprisonment in the penitentiary for not more than 18 months, or both.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In addition to any of the remedies provided by this title or Title 8 of this article, the willful omission, making, or concurrence in making or publishing a written report, exhibit, or entry in a financial statement on the books of the association, which contains a material statement known to be false, upon conviction, is punishable by a fine not more than $100,000, or imprisonment in the penitentiary for not more than 10 years, or both.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">For purposes of this subsection, "material" means "substantial and important as to influence a reasonable and prudent businessman or investor".</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">In addition to any other remedies provided by this title or Title 8 of this article, the knowing declaration of a dividend in violation of &#xA7; 9-324 of this title, upon conviction, is punishable by a fine not more than $100,000, or imprisonment in the penitentiary for not more than 10 years, or both.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Any officer, director, controlling person, agent, or employee of an association who makes a loan for his own use and benefit with an attempt to conceal that from the Division of Savings and Loan Associations, upon conviction, shall be fined not more than $100,000, or imprisoned in the penitentiary for not more than 10 years, or both.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">Any officer, director, controlling person, agent, or employee connected in any capacity with an association who makes a false statement to an employee or agent of the Division of Savings and Loan Associations with the intent to deceive, upon conviction, shall be fined not more than $100,000, or imprisoned in the penitentiary for not more than 10 years, or both.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">Any person who aids or abets any other person in the violation of the provisions of this title or Title 8 of this article as described in subsections (b), (c), (d), and (e) of this section, upon conviction, shall be fined not more than $10,000, or imprisoned in the penitentiary for not more than 1 year, or both.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">The Division Director shall furnish to the Attorney General, or the proper prosecuting attorney, information obtained by the Division Director evidencing a violation of the laws relating to savings and loan associations and related entities.</section>
  </text>
</law>
