<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gfi" order_by="gfi" level="1">Financial Institutions</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gfi-10-101</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this title the following words have the meanings indicated....</catch_line>
  <order_by>101</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this title the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Association" means a corporation or mutual association that is chartered under the laws of this State as a savings and loan association.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Board" means the Board of Directors of the State of Maryland Deposit Insurance Fund Corporation.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">"Division Director" means the Director of the Division of Savings and Loan Associations.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"Federal insurance" means insurance provided by the Federal Savings and Loan Insurance Corporation.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">"Fund" means the State of Maryland Deposit Insurance Fund Corporation.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">"Fund Director" means the Director of the State of Maryland Deposit Insurance Fund Corporation.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">"Insured institution" means:<section prefix="(1)">A national banking association, a federal savings bank, or a banking institution incorporated as a State bank, trust company, savings bank, or other similar institution, whether under the laws of this or any other state, the deposits of which are insured by the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation; or</section><section prefix="(2)">A federal savings and loan association, a federal savings bank, a savings and loan association, a building and loan association, or a similar institution incorporated under the laws of this or any other state, the deposits of which are insured by the Federal Savings and Loan Insurance Corporation.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(i)">"Major association" means an association with total assets of $40,000,000 or more.</section>
    <section prefix="(j)">"Member association" means an association that is a member of the State of Maryland Deposit Insurance Fund Corporation.</section>
    <section prefix="(k)">"Savings account" means a savings share account, a savings deposit account, or any other deposit in an association.</section>
  </text>
</law>
