<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gfi" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="2-114" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gfi-2-114</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Commissioner may:<section prefix="(1)">Make public or private investigations as the Commissioner considers necessary to:<section prefix="(i)">Determine whether a person has violated a provision of law, regulation, rule, or order over which the Commissioner has jurisdiction; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">Aid in the enforcement of a law or in the prescribing of regulations, rules, and orders over which the Commissioner has jurisdiction;</section></section><section prefix="(2)">Require or permit a person to file a statement in writing, under oath or otherwise as the Commissioner determines, as to all the facts and circumstances concerning the matter to be investigated; and</section><section prefix="(3)">Subject to the provisions of Title 10, Subtitle 6 of the State Government Article, publish information concerning a violation of a law, regulation, rule, or order over which the Commissioner has jurisdiction.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">For the purpose of an investigation or proceeding, the Commissioner or an officer designated by the Commissioner may administer oaths and affirmations, subpoena witnesses, compel witness attendance, take evidence, and require the production of books, papers, correspondence, memoranda, agreements, or other documents or records that the Commissioner considers relevant or material to the inquiry.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In case of contumacy by or refusal to obey a subpoena issued to a person, the circuit court of the county in which the person resides or transacts business, on application by the Commissioner, may issue to the person an order requiring the person to appear before the Commissioner or the officer designated by the Commissioner to produce documentary evidence if so ordered or to give evidence touching the matter under investigation or in question.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Failure to obey the order of the court may be punished by the court as a contempt of court.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
