<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gfi" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="13-1001" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gfi-13-1001</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Authority" means the Canal Place Preservation and Development Authority.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Bonds" means taxable or tax-exempt bonds, including refunding bonds, bond anticipation notes, notes in the nature of commercial paper, certificates, or any other evidence of obligation issued by the Authority.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">"Fund" means the Canal Place Preservation and Development Authority Financing Fund established under &#xA7; 13-1017 of this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"Heritage Area" means the Canal Place Heritage Area, initially known as the Canal Place Historic Preservation District, the boundaries of which are described:<section prefix="(1)">In the addendum of January 1993, entitled "The Canal Place Historic Preservation District", to the report of May 1992 of the Maryland State Highway Administration entitled "The Canal Parkway Development - Station Square Project"; and</section><section prefix="(2)">In any revisions that are:<section prefix="(i)">Made by the Authority under &#xA7; 13-1008(8) or (10) of this subtitle; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Approved by the Maryland Heritage Areas Authority in accordance with &#xA7; 13-1111 of this title.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">"Local jurisdiction" means:<section prefix="(1)">Any of the 23 counties of the State;</section><section prefix="(2)">The City of Baltimore; or</section><section prefix="(3)">Any municipal corporation subject to the provisions of Article XI-E of the Maryland Constitution.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(g)">"Maryland Heritage Areas Authority" means the Maryland Heritage Areas Authority created under Subtitle 11 of this title.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">"Park corridor" means the land area within the Heritage Area the boundaries of which are described:<section prefix="(1)">In the report of May 1992 of the Maryland State Highway Administration entitled "The Canal Parkway Development - Station Square Project"; and</section><section prefix="(2)">In any revision that the Authority makes under &#xA7; 13-1008(8) of this subtitle to the report of May 1992 of the Maryland State Highway Administration entitled "The Canal Parkway Development - Station Square Project".</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
