<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gfi" order_by="gfi" level="1">Financial Institutions</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gfi-5-808</section_number>
  <catch_line>The Commissioner may order any banking institution to cease and desist from:...</catch_line>
  <order_by>808</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Commissioner may order any banking institution to cease and desist from:<section prefix="(1)">An unsafe or unsound banking practice;</section><section prefix="(2)">A practice that is injurious to the public interest; or</section><section prefix="(3)">A violation of a law, rule, or regulation that relates to the Commissioner's supervision of the institution.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">To protect depositors, stockholders, or the public, the Commissioner may include in a cease and desist order a restriction on the withdrawal of money from any banking institution.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Commissioner may include in a cease and desist order a requirement that the officers or directors of a banking institution act affirmatively to correct any violation or practice.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Before a cease and desist order takes effect, the Commissioner shall give the banking institution an opportunity for a hearing.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Notice of the hearing shall be given and the hearing shall be held in accordance with the Administrative Procedure Act.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">If the Commissioner determines that the violation or practice under subsection (a) of this section requires immediate action to protect depositors, stockholders, or the public, the Commissioner:<section prefix="(1)">May issue a cease and desist order that is effective on service; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Shall give the banking institution an opportunity for a hearing to rescind the order.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
