<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gfi" order_by="gfi" level="1">Financial Institutions</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gfi-6-302</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this section, "immediate family relative" means:...</catch_line>
  <order_by>302</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, "immediate family relative" means:<section prefix="(1)">A spouse;</section><section prefix="(2)">A child;</section><section prefix="(3)">A sibling;</section><section prefix="(4)">A parent;</section><section prefix="(5)">A grandparent;</section><section prefix="(6)">A grandchild;</section><section prefix="(7)">A stepparent;</section><section prefix="(8)">A stepchild;</section><section prefix="(9)">A step-sibling; or</section><section prefix="(10)">Any adopted relative.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A member of a credit union may be:<section prefix="(1)">An individual who shares with other members of the credit union one of the common bonds within the field of membership types approved by the Commissioner;</section><section prefix="(2)">An employee of the credit union;</section><section prefix="(3)">An entity that is composed primarily of individuals who are eligible for membership;</section><section prefix="(4)">An individual living in the same residence and maintaining a single economic unit with an individual who is eligible for membership; and</section><section prefix="(5)">An immediate family relative of an individual who is eligible for membership.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A person that is eligible for membership under subsection (b) of this section becomes a member when the person:<section prefix="(1)">Subscribes to and pays for at least one share; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Meets all of the other requirements of the bylaws of the credit union.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Once an individual who is eligible for membership under subsection (b)(4) or (5) of this section becomes a member, then an immediate family relative of the member is eligible to become a member.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">A member remains a member of a credit union until the member:<section prefix="(1)">Chooses to withdraw from the membership of the credit union; or</section><section prefix="(2)">Is expelled by the board under &#xA7; 6-319 of this subtitle.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
