<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gfi" order_by="gfi" level="1">Financial Institutions</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gfi-9-1008</section_number>
  <catch_line>It is the purpose of this subtitle to permit orderly development of savings and loan association ope...</catch_line>
  <order_by>1008</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">It is the purpose of this subtitle to permit orderly development of savings and loan association operations on a regional reciprocal basis. It is not the purpose of this subtitle to authorize interstate savings and loan association operations on any basis other than as provided in this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Except as provided in subsection (c) of this section, if any of the provisions of this subtitle relating to the terms, conditions, and limitations under which interstate acquisitions of Maryland associations, interstate associations, Maryland savings and loan holding companies, and out-of-state savings and loan holding companies having Maryland association subsidiaries are permitted are declared invalid for any reason by any state or federal court of competent jurisdiction and if the action of the court would substantially impair the purpose of this subtitle, then on the entry of a final nonappealable order or the expiration of time for appeal, this subtitle shall be null and void in its entirety and shall cease to be of any force or effect from the effective date of the order or the expiration of the time for appeal.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Any transaction that has been lawfully approved under this subtitle prior to a determination of invalidity under subsection (b) of this section shall be unaffected by a determination of invalidity.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Division Director shall closely monitor the results of regional savings and loan operations and report to the General Assembly, as provided under &#xA7; 2-1246 of the State Government Article, and the Department of Legislative Services on October 1 of each year, on the effects of regional reciprocal savings and loan operations.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The report shall include at a minimum:<section prefix="(i)">Initial or proposed capital investments, loan policies, investment policies, dividend policies, and the general plan of business, including the cost of services that are offered by any interstate association or any savings and loan holding company operating in Maryland or are to be offered by any interstate association or out-of-state savings and loan holding company seeking to operate in Maryland;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Specific steps taken or proposed to be taken to meet the credit needs of individuals, including low and moderate income residents in the community to be served;</section><section prefix="(iii)">The financial and managerial resources of the interstate association or out-of-state savings and loan holding company;</section><section prefix="(iv)">The financial history and future prospects of the interstate association or out-of-state savings and loan holding company;</section><section prefix="(v)">The resultant concentration of resources and amount of total assets and total deposits to be held by the interstate association or out-of-state savings and loan holding company after a merger or acquisition;</section><section prefix="(vi)">The impact of regional reciprocal savings and loan association operations on competition;</section><section prefix="(vii)">The availability of home financing for all groups, including low and moderate income groups;</section><section prefix="(viii)">The availability of credit for loans;</section><section prefix="(ix)">Rates charged for credit;</section><section prefix="(x)">Any fees charged for credit;</section><section prefix="(xi)">Any other information the Division Director may consider relevant or that the General Assembly may request;</section><section prefix="(xii)">Number of applications submitted, approved and denied; and</section><section prefix="(xiii)">The impact of regional savings and loan operations on existing savings and loan associations.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
