<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gfi" order_by="" level="1">Financial Institutions</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gfi-11-515</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>515</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Commissioner shall examine the business of each licensee:<section prefix="(i)">In accordance with a schedule established by the Commissioner; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">At any other time that the Commissioner reasonably considers necessary.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The schedule established by the Commissioner under paragraph (1)(i) of this subsection shall:<section prefix="(i)">Take into account:<section prefix="1.">The length of time the licensee has been engaged in business as a mortgage lender;</section><section prefix="2.">Any prior violations by the licensee of the mortgage lending law or regulations;</section><section prefix="3.">The nature and number of any complaints made against the licensee; and</section><section prefix="4.">The result of findings from any prior examination of the licensee; and</section></section><section prefix="(ii)">Provide that:<section prefix="1.">New licensees shall be examined within 18 months of the date the license is issued; and</section><section prefix="2.">Each licensee shall be examined at least once during any 36-month period.</section></section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Any person aggrieved by the conduct of a licensee under this subtitle in connection with a mortgage loan may file a written complaint with the Commissioner who shall investigate the complaint.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Commissioner may make any other investigation of any person if the Commissioner has reasonable cause to believe that the person has violated any provision of this subtitle, of any regulation adopted under this subtitle, or of any other law regulating mortgage loan lending in the State.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A licensee shall pay to the Commissioner a per-day fee set by the Commissioner for each of the Commissioner's employees engaged in:<section prefix="(1)">An examination required under subsection (a)(1) of this section; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Any other examination or investigation conducted under this section that the Commissioner reasonably considers necessary.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">In connection with an examination or investigation made under this section, the Commissioner may:<section prefix="(1)">Examine the books and records of any licensee or of any other person who the Commissioner believes has violated any provision of this subtitle, or any rule or regulation adopted under this subtitle, or of any other law regulating mortgage loan lending in the State;</section><section prefix="(2)">Subpoena documents or other evidence; and</section><section prefix="(3)">Summon and examine under oath any person whose testimony the Commissioner requires.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If any person fails to comply with a subpoena or summons of the Commissioner under this subtitle or to testify concerning any matter about which the person may be interrogated under this subtitle, the Commissioner may file a petition for enforcement with the circuit court for any county.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">On petition by the Commissioner, the court may order the person to attend and testify or produce evidence.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
