<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gfi" order_by="" level="1">Financial Institutions</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gfi-1-210</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>210</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Account agreement" means one or more written instruments that establish when a certificate of deposit is payable.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Certificate of deposit" means a deposit or share account at a depository institution that:<section prefix="(i)">Is payable by the depository institution at the expiration of a specified time; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">May be transferable or nontransferable, negotiable or nonnegotiable, and renewable or nonrenewable.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">"Depository institution" means a State-chartered or federally chartered financial institution located in the State that is authorized to maintain certificates of deposit.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">"Maturity date" means the time specified in an account agreement when a certificate of deposit is first payable, without taking into account any agreement regarding renewals.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Subject to subsection (c) of this section, an action to enforce the obligation of a depository institution to pay all or part of the balance of a certificate of deposit must be commenced by the earlier of:<section prefix="(1)">The time that an action to enforce an obligation under &#xA7; 3-118(e) of the Commercial Law Article must be commenced, if the certificate of deposit is subject to that section; or</section><section prefix="(2)">6 years after the later of:<section prefix="(i)">The maturity date of the certificate of deposit;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The due date of the certificate of deposit indicated in the depository institution's last written notice of renewal of the certificate of deposit, if any;</section><section prefix="(iii)">The date of the last written communication from the depository institution recognizing the depository institution's obligation to pay the certificate of deposit; or</section><section prefix="(iv)">The last day of the taxable year for which a person identified in the certificate of deposit last reported interest income earned on the certificate of deposit on a federal or State income tax return.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Notwithstanding subsection (b) of this section, an action to enforce the obligation of a depository institution to pay all or part of the balance of an automatically renewing certificate of deposit in existence on June 1, 2006, must be commenced by the later of:<section prefix="(1)">6 years after the later of the events described in subsection (b)(2)(i) through (iv) of this section; or</section><section prefix="(2)">1 year after June 1, 2006.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
