<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gfi" order_by="gfi" level="1">Financial Institutions</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gfi-6-309</section_number>
  <catch_line>When filing the articles of incorporation and bylaws with the Commissioner under &#xA7; 6-307 of this su...</catch_line>
  <order_by>309</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">When filing the articles of incorporation and bylaws with the Commissioner under &#xA7; 6-307 of this subtitle, the incorporators shall file with the Commissioner an initial application on a form that the Commissioner requires.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The initial application shall include:<section prefix="(1)">The field of membership type requested;</section><section prefix="(2)">A detailed description of the field of membership;</section><section prefix="(3)">A mission statement;</section><section prefix="(4)">A detailed business plan that includes the items that the Commissioner reasonably requires; and</section><section prefix="(5)">Any other information that the Commissioner reasonably requires.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In connection with an initial application and at any other time the Commissioner requests, each incorporator and director shall provide fingerprints for use by the Federal Bureau of Investigation and the Criminal Justice Information System Central Repository of the Department of Public Safety and Correctional Services to conduct criminal history records checks.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Any incorporator or director required by this subsection to provide fingerprints shall pay any processing or other fee required by the Federal Bureau of Investigation or the Criminal Justice Information System Central Repository of the Department of Public Safety and Correctional Services.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The fingerprinting and criminal history records check requirements shall apply to any other official or officer of the credit union as requested by the Commissioner.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
