<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gfi" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="11-603.1" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gfi-11-603.1</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, "affiliated insurance producer-mortgage loan originator" means an individual who:<section prefix="(1)">Originates mortgage loans only on behalf of a single financial institution that is:<section prefix="(i)">Described in &#xA7; 11-502(b)(1) of this title; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Approved by the Commissioner under subsection (b) of this section;</section></section><section prefix="(2)">Is a licensed insurance producer in good standing under &#xA7; 10-103 of the Insurance Article; and</section><section prefix="(3)">Holds an appointment as an insurance producer for an insurer that controls, is controlled by, or is under common control with:<section prefix="(i)">The financial institution described in item (1) of this subsection; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">A mortgage lender licensee that:</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Commissioner shall approve a financial institution described in subsection (a)(1) of this section based on the following criteria:<section prefix="(1)">The financial institution is in good standing with its primary state or federal regulator; and</section><section prefix="(2)">The financial institution is in material compliance with applicable state and federal law.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Commissioner shall approve a mortgage lender licensee described in subsection (a)(3)(ii) of this section based on the following criteria:<section prefix="(1)">The mortgage lender licensee is in good standing with the Commissioner and any other regulator to which it is subject; and</section><section prefix="(2)">The mortgage lender licensee is in material compliance with applicable state and federal law.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Approval by the Commissioner of a financial institution under subsection (b) of this section and a mortgage lender licensee under subsection (c) of this section shall be in writing.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">An application for a license under this section shall be in the form approved by the Commissioner.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The application shall require the identification of:<section prefix="(i)">The financial institution described in subsection (a)(1) of this section;</section><section prefix="(ii)">If applicable, the mortgage lender licensee described in subsection (a)(3)(ii) of this section; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">The insurer with which the applicant holds an appointment.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">An application for a license under this section shall be signed by an authorized representative of:<section prefix="(i)">The financial institution identified in the application; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">If a mortgage lender licensee is identified in the application, the mortgage lender licensee.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">Notwithstanding &#xA7;&#xA7; 11-602(a) and 11-603 of this subtitle, and subject to the provisions of this section, a license issued under this section authorizes the licensee to act as a mortgage loan originator.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">An applicant for a license under this section and a licensee under this section shall comply with all other requirements for licensure as a mortgage loan originator under this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">A licensee under this section shall limit the licensee's activities to originating mortgage loans only on behalf of a single financial institution approved by the Commissioner under subsection (b) of this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">The financial institution identified in a licensee's license application or, if a mortgage lender licensee is identified in a licensee's license application, the mortgage lender licensee shall:<section prefix="(1)">Supervise the licensee, including providing direction through written instructions or electronic means and by periodically examining the licensee's books, records, and other aspects of the licensee's business;</section><section prefix="(2)">Be held jointly and severally liable with the licensee for claims arising out of the licensee's mortgage loan origination activities; and</section><section prefix="(3)">Meet, or cause the licensee to meet, the surety bond requirements under &#xA7; 11-619(c) of this subtitle.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(j)">Except as provided in subsection (k) of this section, a licensee under this section may not:<section prefix="(1)">Aid or assist a borrower to obtain a mortgage loan from a financial institution other than the financial institution identified in the licensee's license application;</section><section prefix="(2)">Except for compensation based on the principal balance of a mortgage loan, be compensated by any person for mortgage loan origination activities on a basis that depends on the terms of the mortgage loan, including interest rate or fees;</section><section prefix="(3)">Receive a finder's fee, as defined in &#xA7; 12-801 of the Commercial Law Article;</section><section prefix="(4)">Handle borrower or other third party funds in connection with the origination or closing of a mortgage loan;</section><section prefix="(5)">Refer a borrower to any other licensee under Subtitle 5 of this title; or</section><section prefix="(6)">Make or service a mortgage loan.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(k)">A licensee under this section may forward a check to the financial institution identified in the licensee's license application if the check is:<section prefix="(1)">Made payable to the financial institution;</section><section prefix="(2)">From an applicant for a mortgage loan; and</section><section prefix="(3)">In connection with an application for a mortgage loan to cover costs for:<section prefix="(i)">An appraisal;</section><section prefix="(ii)">A credit report; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">Processing the application.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(l)">
      <section prefix="(1)">An individual may not act as an affiliated insurance producer-mortgage loan originator under a name or for an employer that is different from the name and employer that appear on the license unless the licensee:<section prefix="(i)">Notifies the Commissioner in writing in advance of a change in the licensee's name or the licensee's employer;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Pays to the Commissioner a license amendment fee set by the Commissioner for each notice provided under item (i) of this paragraph; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">In the case of a new employer, amends the sponsorship information on the Nationwide Mortgage Licensing System and Registry by submitting the amendment in the form required by the Commissioner to indicate that the licensee is an employee of the new employer.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If a licensee ceases to be employed by a financial institution approved by the Commissioner under subsection (b) of this section, the licensee shall notify the Commissioner within 10 business days, and the license shall be placed into nonactive status.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">During the time that a license is in nonactive status, it is a violation of this subtitle for the licensee to engage in any activity for which a license is required under this subtitle.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The license shall remain in nonactive status until the licensee:<section prefix="(i)">Notifies the Commissioner in writing that the licensee has obtained employment with a financial institution that is approved by the Commissioner under subsection (b) of this section; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Has complied with the requirements set forth in paragraph (1) of this subsection.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(m)">The Commissioner may issue a license under this subtitle to an individual who is not employed by a financial institution approved by the Commissioner under subsection (b) of this section, provided that the license is placed into and remains in nonactive status until the licensee:<section prefix="(1)">Notifies the Commissioner in writing that the licensee has obtained employment with a financial institution approved by the Commissioner under subsection (b) of this section; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Has complied with the requirements set forth in subsection (l)(1) of this section.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
