<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gfi" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="9-412.1" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gfi-9-412.1</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Any checks or drafts provided directly or indirectly by a savings and loan association for use in connection with a personal checking or draft account shall have the numerical month and year in which the account was opened printed on the face of the checks or drafts, except as provided in subsection (b) of this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The provisions of subsection (a) of this section shall not apply under certain conditions:<section prefix="(1)">If an individual personal checking account is closed at a particular savings and loan and a joint personal account is opened at the same savings and loan that includes one of the customers who previously had the individual personal account, then the numerical month and year printed on the face of the checks or drafts shall be the numerical month and year in which the individual personal account was established.</section><section prefix="(2)">If a joint personal account is closed at a particular savings and loan and an individual personal account is opened at the same savings and loan by one of the customers who previously was included under the joint account, then the numerical month and year printed on the face of the checks or drafts shall be the numerical month and year in which the joint account was established.</section><section prefix="(3)">If a customer with an individual personal account or with a joint personal account opens an additional account at the same savings and loan, then the numerical month and year printed on the face of the checks or drafts shall be the numerical month and year in which the initial account was established.</section><section prefix="(4)">In the case of a personal checking or draft account that is closed and a new personal checking or draft account opened simultaneously on the advice of the savings and loan association, the checks or drafts for the new account shall have the numerical month and year in which the closed account was originally opened printed on the face of the checks or drafts.</section><section prefix="(5)">If the closed account was opened prior to July 1, 1987, a date is not required to be printed on the checks or drafts.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A check, draft, or order provided on the opening of a personal checking or draft account for use by the customer until printed checks or drafts have been prepared is not required to have the numerical month and year in which the account was opened printed on the face of the check, draft, or order.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The savings and loan association and the check printer may not be held liable for unintentional errors in the month and year printed on the face of the check.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The customer may not be charged for the reprinting of the checks when the checks are reprinted due to error in the month and year printed on the face of the check.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
