<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gfi" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="12-114" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gfi-12-114</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">A licensee shall keep the books and records that the Commissioner requires to determine compliance with this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Unless a longer period is expressly required by State or federal law, a licensee shall retain the records required under this subtitle for a period of at least 2 years.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A licensee may retain the records required under this subtitle at any location, provided that the licensee:<section prefix="(1)">Notifies the Commissioner in writing of the location of the records; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Makes the records available at a place of business for which a license has been issued or at the licensee's principal place of business, as agreed by the Commissioner and the licensee, within 7 days of a written request for examination by the Commissioner.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">In addition to any other books and records that the Commissioner may require, a licensee shall retain:<section prefix="(1)">A chronological register of all payment instruments cashed by the licensee showing:<section prefix="(i)">The name of the customer;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The transaction date;</section><section prefix="(iii)">The type and amount of payment instrument;</section><section prefix="(iv)">The amount of fee charged; and</section><section prefix="(v)">A complete description of the identification presented by the customer; and</section></section><section prefix="(2)">The licensee's bank statements and canceled checks.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">A licensee shall retain the records required under this section in one of the following ways:<section prefix="(1)">Original form;</section><section prefix="(2)">An electronic equivalent approved by the Commissioner; or</section><section prefix="(3)">A microphotographic copy approved by the Commissioner.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
