<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gfi" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="9-101" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gfi-9-101</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this title the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Capital stock" means capital stock issued by a capital stock association.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Capital stock association" means a savings and loan association that has authority under this title to issue capital stock.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">"Claim" means:<section prefix="(1)">A right to payment, whether or not the right is reduced to judgment, liquidated, unliquidated, fixed, contingent, matured, unmatured, disputed, undisputed, legal, equitable, secured, or unsecured; or</section><section prefix="(2)">A right to an equitable remedy for breach of performance if the breach gives rise to a right to payment, whether or not the right to an equitable remedy is reduced to judgment, fixed, contingent, matured, unmatured, disputed, undisputed, secured, or unsecured.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"Deposit association" means a savings and loan association that has savings deposit accounts.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">"Division Director" means the Commissioner.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">"Employee" does not include a controlling person, director, or officer of an association.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">"Federal association" means:<section prefix="(1)">A savings and loan association that is incorporated under the laws of the United States; or</section><section prefix="(2)">A federal savings bank that operates under the jurisdiction of the Federal Home Loan Bank Board and whose accounts are insured by the Federal Savings and Loan Insurance Corporation.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(i)">"Fund Director" means the Director of the State of Maryland Deposit Insurance Fund Corporation.</section>
    <section prefix="(j)">"Mutual association" means a savings and loan association that does not have authority to issue capital stock.</section>
    <section prefix="(k)">"Net worth certificate" means a capital instrument issued by a savings and loan association for the purpose of increasing or maintaining the capital of the association.</section>
    <section prefix="(l)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Savings account" means that part of the savings liability of a savings and loan association that is credited to the account of the holder of the account.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Savings account" includes a savings certificate account or any other fixed term account.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(m)">"Savings and loan association" has the meaning stated in &#xA7; 8-101 of this article.</section>
    <section prefix="(n)">"Savings deposit account" means a savings account that:<section prefix="(1)">Is a liability of a deposit association to the extent of its withdrawal value; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Is not a share interest in a savings and loan association.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(o)">"Savings liability" means the aggregate amount of savings accounts of savings account holders, including earnings credited to the accounts.</section>
    <section prefix="(p)">"Savings share account" means a savings account that is a share interest in a savings and loan association.</section>
    <section prefix="(q)">"Secretary" has the meaning stated in &#xA7; 8-101 of this article.</section>
    <section prefix="(r)">"Statutory merger" means the transfer of all or substantially all of the assets of a corporation which transfer is:<section prefix="(1)">Subject to all or substantially all of the liabilities of the transferor; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Followed by the dissolution of the transferor corporation.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(s)">"Unsecured days funds" has the meaning stated in the rules and regulations of the Federal Home Loan Bank Board that apply to savings associations insured by the Federal Savings and Loan Insurance Corporation.</section>
  </text>
</law>
