<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gfi" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="3-314" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gfi-3-314</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Bank holding company" has the meaning stated in the Federal Bank Holding Company Act of 1956.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Stock acquisition" means:<section prefix="(i)">An acquisition of the outstanding voting stock of a commercial bank or bank holding company in this State, if the acquisition will affect the power to direct or to cause the direction of the management or policy of any banking institution or bank holding company; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">An acquisition of any voting stock of a commercial bank, if the acquisition will give any one person control of 25 percent or more of the voting stock of the commercial bank.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Except as provided in this section, a person may not make a stock acquisition.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A person who intends to make a stock acquisition shall apply to the Commissioner for approval, at least 60 days before the acquisition becomes effective.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The application shall include:<section prefix="(i)">A description of the proposed stock acquisition; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">All other information that is available to inform the Commissioner of the effect of the acquisition on the power to direct or to cause direction of the management or policy of a banking institution or bank holding company.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">If there is any doubt as to whether the stock acquisition will affect the power to direct or cause direction of the management or policy of a commercial bank or bank holding company, the doubt shall be resolved in favor of reporting to the Commissioner.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Commissioner may deny approval for a stock acquisition that the Commissioner determines to be anticompetitive or to threaten the safety or soundness of a banking institution.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">Voting stock that is acquired in violation of this section may not be voted for 5 years.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The provisions of this section do not apply to an acquisition for which an application is required under &#xA7; 5-904 of this article.</section>
  </text>
</law>
