<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gfi" order_by="gfi" level="1">Financial Institutions</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gfi-3-202</section_number>
  <catch_line>The incorporators shall sign and acknowledge two copies of articles of incorporation....</catch_line>
  <order_by>202</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The incorporators shall sign and acknowledge two copies of articles of incorporation.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The articles of incorporation shall include:<section prefix="(1)">The name and address of each incorporator;</section><section prefix="(2)">A statement that each incorporator is 18 years old or older and a citizen of this State and the United States;</section><section prefix="(3)">A statement that the incorporators are associating to form a State bank or a trust company under this subtitle;</section><section prefix="(4)">The name of the State bank or trust company, which may not be similar in any material respect to the name of any other bank or trust company in this State;</section><section prefix="(5)">The municipal area and county where the principal banking office of the State bank or trust company is to be located;</section><section prefix="(6)">The number of directors and the names and residence addresses of those who will serve as directors until their successors are elected and qualify; and</section><section prefix="(7)">As to its capital stock:<section prefix="(i)">The total number of shares that the State bank or trust company has authority to issue;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The par value of the shares, which may not be less than $10 a share; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">The total par value of all shares.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The articles of incorporation may include:<section prefix="(1)">Any provision that requires for any purpose the concurrence of a greater proportion of the votes of all classes or of any class of capital stock than the proportion required by this article for that purpose; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Any provision that defines, limits, or denies the preemptive rights of stockholders to acquire additional stock of the State bank or trust company.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
