<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gfi" order_by="gfi" level="1">Financial Institutions</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gfi-11-606.1</section_number>
  <catch_line>To qualify for an initial license, an applicant shall pass a qualified written test developed by the...</catch_line>
  <order_by>606.1</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">To qualify for an initial license, an applicant shall pass a qualified written test developed by the Nationwide Mortgage Licensing System and Registry and administered by a test provider approved by the Nationwide Mortgage Licensing System and Registry.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A written test shall not be treated as a qualified written test for purposes of subsection (a) of this section unless the test adequately measures the applicant's knowledge and comprehension in appropriate subject areas, including:<section prefix="(1)">Ethics;</section><section prefix="(2)">Federal law and regulations relating to mortgage origination;</section><section prefix="(3)">State law and regulations relating to mortgage origination; and</section><section prefix="(4)">Federal and State law and regulations relating to fraud, consumer protection, the nontraditional mortgage product marketplace, and fair lending issues.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">To pass a qualified written test, an applicant must receive a test score of at least 75 percent.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">An applicant may take a test three times, provided that each subsequent test occurs at least 30 days after the preceding test.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">After failing three tests, an applicant shall wait at least 6 months before taking the test again.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A licensee who fails to renew and maintain a valid license for a period of 5 years or longer shall retake the test and achieve a passing grade as set forth in subsection (c) of this section before obtaining a new license.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Calculation of the time period during which an individual is unlicensed under paragraph (1) of this subsection shall exclude any time during which the individual is a registered mortgage loan originator.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">This section does not prohibit a test provider approved by the Nationwide Mortgage Licensing System and Registry from providing a test at the location of the employer of the applicant or any subsidiary or affiliate of the employer of the applicant, or any entity with which the applicant holds an exclusive arrangement to conduct the business of a mortgage loan originator.</section>
  </text>
</law>
