<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gfi" order_by="" level="1">Financial Institutions</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gfi-12-103</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>103</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">This subtitle does not apply to:<section prefix="(1)">Any bank, trust company, savings bank, savings and loan association, or credit union incorporated or chartered under the laws of this State or the United States that maintains its principal office in this State;</section><section prefix="(2)">Any out-of-state bank, as defined in &#xA7; 5-1001 of this article, having a branch that accepts deposits in this State; and</section><section prefix="(3)">Any institution incorporated under federal law as a savings association or savings bank that does not maintain its principal office in this State but has a branch that accepts deposits in this State.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A subsidiary or affiliate of an institution described in subsection (a) of this section is exempt from all requirements of licensing under this subtitle provided the subsidiary or affiliate:<section prefix="(1)">Is subject to audit or examination by a regulatory body or agency of this State, the United States, or the state where the subsidiary or affiliate maintains its principal office; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Submits to the Commissioner in writing and prior to providing check cashing services the following information:<section prefix="(i)">The subsidiary's or affiliate's name and address, and the names and addresses of each:<section prefix="1.">Owner who owns 5% or more of the subsidiary or affiliate; and</section><section prefix="2.">Officer, director, or principal of the subsidiary or affiliate;</section></section><section prefix="(ii)"><section prefix="1.">Each address at which check cashing services will be provided; and</section><section prefix="2.">If a mobile unit will be used to provide check cashing services, the vehicle identification number of the mobile unit and the geographic area in which the mobile unit will be operating; and</section></section><section prefix="(iii)">Any other information that the Commissioner requests.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">An exempt entity is not subject to the provisions of &#xA7;&#xA7; 12-106 through 12-112, inclusive, and &#xA7; 12-122 of this subtitle.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">An exempt entity is subject to:<section prefix="(i)">The provisions of &#xA7;&#xA7; 12-113 through 12-121, inclusive, and &#xA7;&#xA7; 12-123 through 12-127, inclusive, of this subtitle; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Any regulation, except to the extent the regulation concerns licensing, adopted under this subtitle.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
