<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gfi" order_by="" level="1">Financial Institutions</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gfi-6-804</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>804</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Any credit union may dissolve voluntarily, if the board, the members of the credit union, and the Commissioner approve the dissolution as provided in this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A majority of the board of a credit union proposing to dissolve shall adopt a resolution that:<section prefix="(1)">Recommends that the credit union be dissolved voluntarily; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Directs that a proposal of dissolution be submitted to the members.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A proposed dissolution shall be approved at an annual or special meeting of the members or by mail ballot by the affirmative vote of two-thirds of the entire membership of the credit union.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Commissioner may substitute any reasonable method of determining the vote of the members.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">After a proposed dissolution is approved by the members, the credit union shall file with the Commissioner:<section prefix="(1)">A copy of the resolution of the board recommending voluntary dissolution, attested to by:<section prefix="(i)">The chairman or vice chairman of the board; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">The secretary or treasurer of the credit union;</section></section><section prefix="(2)">A verified statement of the names and addresses of the officers and directors of the credit union; and</section><section prefix="(3)">The vote by which the voluntary dissolution was approved by the members.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If the Commissioner finds that the credit union is solvent, the Commissioner shall issue to the credit union duplicate certificates stating that the credit union appears to have complied with this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The credit union shall file one of the certificates with the State Department of Assessments and Taxation.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">When the certificate is filed with the State Department of Assessments and Taxation, the credit union is dissolved.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">On dissolution, a credit union may operate only to wind up its business and affairs.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Under the direction of the Commissioner, the liquidating agent of the dissolved credit union, appointed by the board, shall:<section prefix="(i)">Discharge its debts and obligations;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Collect and distribute its assets; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Do anything else necessary to wind up its business and affairs.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">For 3 years after the dissolution becomes effective, the credit union, acting by its board and liquidating agent:<section prefix="(i)">Shall continue in existence for the purpose of winding up its business and affairs; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">May sue and be sued in its name.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
