<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gfi" order_by="gfi" level="1">Financial Institutions</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gfi-7-104</section_number>
  <catch_line>The Corporation exercises its powers and performs its duties subject to the authority of the Commiss...</catch_line>
  <order_by>104</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Corporation exercises its powers and performs its duties subject to the authority of the Commissioner.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Except as otherwise provided in this subtitle, the Corporation has all of the powers, privileges, and immunities granted to Maryland corporations under the Maryland General Corporation Law.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Subject to the provisions of Part III of this subtitle, the Corporation has perpetual existence.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Corporation may:<section prefix="(1)">Lend money to any credit union;</section><section prefix="(2)">Guarantee, endorse, or act as surety on the obligations of or otherwise assist financially any credit union; and</section><section prefix="(3)">Establish and regulate the terms and conditions of and charges for any loans or financial assistance to credit unions.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Corporation may buy, lease, or otherwise acquire and sell, mortgage, lease, or otherwise dispose of real or personal property on the terms that its Board of Directors considers advisable.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Corporation may acquire any real or personal property in satisfaction of debts or enforcement of obligations and may dispose of that property.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The Corporation may:<section prefix="(1)">Assist in the merger, stabilization, consolidation, or liquidation of credit unions; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Take possession of and operate the business and assets of any credit union if ordered to do so by the Commissioner under &#xA7; 6-905 of this article.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(g)">The Corporation may become a member of the National Association of Share Insurance Corporations or any comparable organization.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">The Corporation may invest any of its funds in:<section prefix="(1)">Cash or deposits in checking or savings accounts with or certificates of deposit of:<section prefix="(i)">Any bank that is a member of the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Any savings and loan association whose deposits are insured by the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation;</section></section><section prefix="(2)">Cash or deposits in share or deposit accounts with or certificates of deposit or notes of any credit union that is a member of the Corporation, the National Credit Union Administration Share Insurance Program, or a similar insurance program;</section><section prefix="(3)">Obligations of:<section prefix="(i)">The United States or any state or any political subdivision of any state;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Any commission, instrumentality, agency, or authority of the United States or any state; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Any corporation that is incorporated under the laws of the United States or of any state;</section></section><section prefix="(4)">Readily marketable, dividend-paying shares of any corporation that is incorporated under the laws of the United States or of any state, except that it may not invest more than 10 percent of its total assets in these shares nor more than 3 percent of its total assets in the shares of any one corporation; and</section><section prefix="(5)">Any other investments, including common trust investments, that are permitted by law or authorized by the Commissioner for credit unions.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(i)">The Corporation may:<section prefix="(1)">Borrow money and otherwise incur obligations for any of its purposes;</section><section prefix="(2)">Issue its secured or unsecured bonds, debentures, notes, or other evidences of obligation; and</section><section prefix="(3)">Secure these obligations by mortgage, pledge, or other lien on all or any part of its property, rights, and privileges.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
