<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gfi" order_by="" level="1">Financial Institutions</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gfi-1-101</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>101</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this article, unless the context clearly requires otherwise, the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Address" means post office address, including, if applicable, street and number, municipal area or county, state, and, if outside of the United States, country.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Any state" means:<section prefix="(1)">Any state, possession, or territory of the United States;</section><section prefix="(2)">The District of Columbia; or</section><section prefix="(3)">The Commonwealth of Puerto Rico.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">"Banking institution" means an institution that is incorporated under the laws of this State as a State bank, trust company, or savings bank.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"Charter" has the meaning stated in &#xA7; 1-101 of the Corporations and Associations Article.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">"Commercial bank" means an institution that is incorporated under the laws of this State as a State bank or trust company.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">"Commissioner" means the Commissioner of Financial Regulation in the Department of Labor, Licensing, and Regulation.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">"County" means a county of this State and, unless otherwise indicated, Baltimore City.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">"Financial institution" means any financial institution of the type supervised under this article, whether or not State-chartered.</section>
    <section prefix="(j)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Foreign bank" means any financial institution or other institution that engages in banking activities that are usual in connection with the business of banking in the nations in which the institution is organized or operates.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Foreign bank" does not include a bank organized under the laws of any state or a national banking association that has its headquarters in any state.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(k)">"Includes" or "including" means includes or including by way of illustration and not by way of limitation.</section>
    <section prefix="(l)">"Mail" means to deposit in the United States mail, postage prepaid.</section>
    <section prefix="(m)">"Mortgage" includes a deed of trust that secures a debt or the performance of an obligation.</section>
    <section prefix="(n)">"Municipal area" means a municipal corporation or an unincorporated city, town, or village.</section>
    <section prefix="(o)">"National banking association" means an institution that is incorporated under federal law as a bank.</section>
    <section prefix="(p)">"Other-state bank" means a bank chartered and primarily regulated by another state.</section>
    <section prefix="(q)">"Person" means an individual, receiver, trustee, guardian, personal representative, fiduciary, or representative of any kind and any partnership, firm, association, corporation, or other entity.</section>
    <section prefix="(r)">"Political subdivision" means:<section prefix="(1)">A county or municipal corporation of this State; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Unless the context requires otherwise, a special taxing district of this State.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(s)">"Real property" includes any interest in real property.</section>
  </text>
</law>
