<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gfi" order_by="" level="1">Financial Institutions</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gfi-13-801</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>801</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated, unless otherwise required by the context.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Bonds" means any bonds, notes, or other obligations of an issuer, the interest on which is exempt from federal taxation under the Code and the tax-exempt status of which is subject to the volume limitation established under &#xA7; 146 of the Code.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Code" means the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, as amended, and the applicable regulations thereunder.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">"Community Development Administration" means that division of the Department of Housing and Community Development established under Title 4, Subtitle 2 of the Housing and Community Development Article.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"County" means any county in the State of Maryland and the City of Baltimore.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">"Housing bonds" means any "qualified mortgage bonds" and bonds for any "qualified residential rental project" as those terms are defined in the Code.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">"Issuer" means any State issuer or local issuer.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">"Local issuer" means any county, municipality, or industrial development authority established under Title 12, Subtitle 1 of the Economic Development Article, or other agency with authority to issue bonds, other than a State issuer.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">"Maryland State ceiling" means the volume limitation established pursuant to &#xA7; 146 of the Code on the aggregate dollar amount of bonds that may be issued by State and local issuers in any calendar year.</section>
    <section prefix="(j)">"Minority business enterprise" means the minority business enterprises as defined in &#xA7; 14-301 of the State Finance and Procurement Article.</section>
    <section prefix="(k)">"Municipality" means any municipal corporation subject to the provisions of Article XI-E of the Maryland Constitution.</section>
    <section prefix="(l)">"Secretary" means the Secretary of Business and Economic Development.</section>
    <section prefix="(m)">"Secretary's reserve" means the allocation of the Maryland State ceiling initially made under &#xA7; 13-802(4) of this subtitle and augmented under &#xA7; 13-805 of this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(n)">"State issuer" means the State of Maryland or any agency of the State of Maryland with authority to issue bonds.</section>
  </text>
</law>
