<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gfi" order_by="gfi" level="1">Financial Institutions</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gfi-12-102</section_number>
  <catch_line>This subtitle does not apply to check cashing services:...</catch_line>
  <order_by>102</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">This subtitle does not apply to check cashing services:<section prefix="(1)"><section prefix="(i)">For which a fee of up to 1.5% of the face amount of the payment instrument is charged per payment instrument; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">That are incidental to the retail sale of goods or services by the person that is providing the check cashing services;</section></section><section prefix="(2)">In which a customer presents a payment instrument for the exact amount of a purchase; or</section><section prefix="(3)">Involving foreign currency exchange services or the cashing of a payment instrument drawn on a financial institution other than a federal, State, or other state financial institution.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This subtitle does not apply to a transaction that is subject to the Maryland Consumer Loan Law (Title 12, Subtitle 3 of the Commercial Law Article and Title 11, Subtitle 2 of this article), including a transaction in which an additional fee is charged to defer the presentment or deposit of a payment instrument until a subsequent date.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A check cashing service is not subject to the Maryland Consumer Loan Law if:<section prefix="(i)">The fee charged for the check cashing service does not exceed the fee permitted under this subtitle;</section><section prefix="(ii)">No additional fee is charged to defer the presentment or deposit of the payment instrument; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">The check cashing service is not subject to renewal or extension by any means.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
