<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gfi" order_by="" level="1">Financial Institutions</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gfi-3-720</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>720</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The fair value of the shares of stock shall be determined as of the date of the stockholders' meeting approving the consolidation, merger, or transfer of assets.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The determination of fair value shall be made by three appraisers as follows:<section prefix="(i)">One chosen by the owners of two thirds of the shares involved;</section><section prefix="(ii)">One chosen by the board of directors of the successor; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">The third chosen by the other two appraisers.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The fair value to which any two appraisers agree shall govern.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The appraisers shall give notice of the fair value determination to the successor and to each stockholder who has made demand for the determination under &#xA7; 3-719 of this subtitle.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Within 5 days after the appraisers give the notice of the fair value determination, a stockholder who is dissatisfied with that value may notify the Commissioner.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Commissioner shall have the shares reappraised.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">This reappraisal is final and binding as to the value of the shares of stock of that stockholder.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If the appraisal to be made under subsection (b) of this section is not completed within 90 days after the consolidation, merger, or transfer of assets becomes effective, the Commissioner shall have an appraisal made.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">This appraisal is final and binding as to the value of the shares of stock of all objecting stockholders.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The successor shall pay the expenses of each appraisal made under this section.</section>
  </text>
</law>
