<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gfi" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="4-203" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gfi-4-203</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The incorporators shall:<section prefix="(1)">File with the Commissioner for examination the two copies of the articles of incorporation; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Pay to the Commissioner an examination fee of $1,500.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Commissioner shall investigate and determine if:<section prefix="(1)">The articles are framed in accordance with law;</section><section prefix="(2)">The character, responsibility, and general fitness of the incorporators and directors named in the articles command confidence and warrant belief that the business of the proposed savings bank will be conducted honestly and efficiently, in accordance with the intent of this article; and</section><section prefix="(3)">Allowing the proposed savings bank to engage in business:<section prefix="(i)">Will promote public convenience and advantage; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Is expedient and desirable.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">After the investigation, the Commissioner may require any change in the articles of incorporation that the Commissioner considers necessary.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Within 6 months after the articles are filed for examination, the Commissioner shall sign, date, and endorse each copy as "approved" or "refused".</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If formation of the savings bank is refused, the Commissioner shall return one of the endorsed copies of the articles to the incorporators.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">If formation of the savings bank is approved, the Commissioner shall:<section prefix="(i)">Return one of the endorsed copies of the articles to the incorporators; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Keep and record one of the endorsed copies.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
