<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gfi" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="6-329" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gfi-6-329</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Subject to the provisions of this section, the directors may be elected exclusively by mail ballot or electronically in accordance with regulations adopted by the Commissioner, if:<section prefix="(1)">The board of the credit union, by resolution posted conspicuously at the principal office of the credit union at least 90 days before the annual meeting of the members of the credit union, authorizes the election of directors exclusively by mail ballot or electronically; or</section><section prefix="(2)"><section prefix="(i)">The bylaws provide for the election of directors exclusively by mail ballot or electronically; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Notice of the election and the annual meeting is posted conspicuously at the principal office of the credit union at least 90 days before the date of the annual meeting.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">At least 75 days before the annual meeting, the board of the credit union shall appoint a nominating committee of at least three members.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The nominating committee shall nominate at least one member for each vacancy on the board, after determining that a proposed nominee agrees to permit the nomination and, if elected, to accept the office.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The nominating committee shall file its nominations with the secretary of the credit union at least 60 days before the annual meeting.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The secretary shall post these nominations conspicuously at the principal office of the credit union at least 55 days before the annual meeting.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The lesser of 1 percent or 500 of the members in good standing, but in any case no less than 20, may nominate candidates for directorships by signing a petition.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">Each page of the petition shall include:</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">Each petition shall contain:</section>
        <section prefix="(iv)">The nominating committee shall determine the validity of any petition.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Petitioners shall file their nomination with the secretary of the credit union at least 55 days before the annual meeting.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The secretary shall post these nominations conspicuously at the principal office of the credit union at least 20 days before the annual meeting.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">When only one member is nominated for a position to be filled, the chairman may:<section prefix="(i)">Take a voice vote; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">Declare the nominee elected by general consent or acclamation at the annual meeting.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If the nominations of the nominating committee and any petitioners provide more than one nominee for each directorship to be filled, the secretary:<section prefix="(i)">For an election of directors conducted by mail ballot, shall mail to each member in good standing, at least 20 days before the annual meeting:</section><section prefix="(ii)">For an election of directors conducted electronically, shall provide the information and identification form required under item (i) of this paragraph as provided in regulations adopted by the Commissioner.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">One form may be printed or provided electronically that represents a combined ballot and identification form.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The board shall appoint the tellers of the election.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The tellers of an election may not count a ballot unless it is:<section prefix="(1)">Mailed or electronically submitted to the tellers; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Received by the tellers not later than midnight of the 7th day before the date of the annual meeting.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(g)">The tellers of the election shall:<section prefix="(1)">Verify or cause to be verified the name of each voter and the credit union account number of the voter as it appears on the identification form;</section><section prefix="(2)">Authenticate any questionable or challenged identification form;</section><section prefix="(3)">Keep the verified identification form and ballot for safekeeping pending the count of the vote;</section><section prefix="(4)">Keep separate any questionable or challenged identification form and ballot until the authentication, verification, or challenge is resolved;</section><section prefix="(5)">Determine that each eligible voter does not vote more than once and is a member in good standing; and</section><section prefix="(6)">After the time set in subsection (f)(2) of this section, tally the votes and report the results to the board.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(h)">The board shall report the results of the election at the annual meeting of the members.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">The Commissioner shall establish by regulation procedures for conducting an election of directors electronically, including procedures for:<section prefix="(1)">Providing notice of the election to each member in good standing;</section><section prefix="(2)">Providing the information and identification form specified in subsection (d)(2)(i)1 of this section;</section><section prefix="(3)">Providing instructions on how to access and use the electronic election system; and</section><section prefix="(4)">Allowing a member to opt out of using the electronic election system and vote by mail ballot.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
