<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gfi" order_by="" level="1">Financial Institutions</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gfi-11-507</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>507</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">To apply for a license, an applicant shall:<section prefix="(i)">Complete, sign, and submit to the Commissioner an application made under oath in the form, and in accordance with the process, that the Commissioner requires; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Provide all information that the Commissioner requests.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The applicant shall comply with all conditions and provisions of the application for licensure and be issued a license before acting as a mortgage lender at a particular location.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">With each application, the applicant shall pay to the Commissioner the following fees:<section prefix="(1)">A nonrefundable investigation fee set by the Commissioner; and</section><section prefix="(2)">A nonrefundable license fee set by the Commissioner.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">In addition to the license fee required under subsection (b)(2) of this section, an applicant for an initial license shall pay to the Nationwide Mortgage Licensing System and Registry any fees that the Nationwide Mortgage Licensing System and Registry imposes in connection with the application.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">For each license for which an applicant applies, the applicant shall:<section prefix="(1)">Submit a separate application;</section><section prefix="(2)">Pay a separate nonrefundable license fee;</section><section prefix="(3)">Pay any application processing fee or other fees that the Nationwide Mortgage Licensing System and Registry imposes in connection with the application;</section><section prefix="(4)">If applicable, pay the surcharge; and</section><section prefix="(5)">File a separate surety bond or other financial guaranty under &#xA7; 11-508 of this subtitle.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">In addition to any sanctions that may be imposed under this subtitle by the Commissioner, a nonrefundable surcharge of $500 shall be paid with an application if the applicant has begun acting as a mortgage lender without a license at the location for which an application is filed.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">A person who knowingly makes a false statement under oath on an application filed with the Commissioner under this section is guilty of perjury and on conviction is subject to the penalties of &#xA7; 9-101 of the Criminal Law Article.</section>
  </text>
</law>
