<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gfi" order_by="gfi" level="1">Financial Institutions</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gfi-6-603</section_number>
  <catch_line>Except as provided in subsection (b) of this section, and in &#xA7; 6-328 (7) and (8) of this title, a l...</catch_line>
  <order_by>603</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in subsection (b) of this section, and in &#xA7; 6-328 (7) and (8) of this title, a loan may not be made to any member of a credit union unless it is approved unanimously by those members of the credit committee who are present at a meeting that is attended by a majority of the members of the credit committee.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If the bylaws of the credit union so provide, an applicant for a loan that is not approved by the credit committee may appeal to the board of directors.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The credit committee or the president may appoint loan officers.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The appointment of loan officers by the president shall be subject to confirmation by the credit committee.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">The credit committee shall supervise loan officers and delegate to them the power to approve or disapprove loans in accordance with written instructions or policies adopted by the board.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Not more than one loan officer may be a member of the credit committee.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A loan made by a loan officer in accordance with the written instructions or policies of the board does not have to be approved by the credit committee.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Each loan officer shall give the credit committee the record of each loan that the officer approves or disapproves within 7 days after a loan application is made.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The credit committee shall act on each loan application where the decision of the loan officer has been appealed by the credit union member.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(5)">A loan officer may not disburse credit union funds for any loan that the loan officer approved.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The credit committee shall meet as often as necessary.</section>
  </text>
</law>
