<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gfi" order_by="" level="1">Financial Institutions</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gfi-11-505</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>505</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">A license issued under this subtitle authorizes the licensee to act as a mortgage lender under the license at the licensed place of business.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Only 1 place of business may be maintained under any 1 license.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A mortgage lender may maintain more than 1 license under this subtitle provided that a separate application for each license is made pursuant to &#xA7; 11-507 of this subtitle and the Commissioner approves such application.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Commissioner shall include on each license:<section prefix="(i)">The name of the licensee; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">The address at which the business is to be conducted.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A person may not conduct any mortgage loan business at any location or under any name different from the address and name that appears on the person's license.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A licensee may not allow any note, or loan contract, mortgage, or evidence of indebtedness secured by a secondary mortgage or deed of trust on a dwelling or residential real estate to be signed or executed at any place for which the person does not have a license, except at the office of:<section prefix="(i)">The attorney for the borrower or for the licensee; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">A title insurance company, a title company, or an attorney for a title insurance company or a title company.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Notwithstanding paragraph (1) of this subsection, a licensee may conduct the loan closing at another location at the written request of the borrower or the borrower's designee to accommodate the borrower because of the borrower's sickness.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Commissioner shall adopt regulations to ensure that the loan application process is conducted fairly and in a manner consistent with the best interests of both the borrower and mortgage lender.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">A license may be issued under this subtitle to a business entity whose principal office is located outside this State provided that the business entity maintains a resident agent within the State at all times during the term of the license, regardless of whether:<section prefix="(1)">The business entity maintains any office within the State; or</section><section prefix="(2)">The activities of the business entity constitute doing business or having a tax situs in this State under the applicable provisions of the Corporations and Associations Article.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(g)">A person exempt from licensing under this subtitle who employs a mortgage loan originator licensed under Subtitle 6 of this title shall be registered with the Nationwide Mortgage Licensing System and Registry.</section>
  </text>
</law>
