<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gfi" order_by="gfi" level="1">Financial Institutions</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gfi-13-804</section_number>
  <catch_line>On September 15 of each calendar year, each issuer shall submit a report, approved in writing by its...</catch_line>
  <order_by>804</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">On September 15 of each calendar year, each issuer shall submit a report, approved in writing by its bond counsel, to the Secretary containing the following information:<section prefix="(1)">The amount of the total allocation of the Maryland State ceiling allocated in that year to the issuer prior to September 15;</section><section prefix="(2)">The amount and type of bonds issued in that year pursuant to the total allocation to the issuer in that year;</section><section prefix="(3)">The amount and type of bonds not issued, but anticipated to be issued on or before September 30 of that year, pursuant to the total allocation to the issuer in that year; and</section><section prefix="(4)">Any other information that the Secretary may request.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Each issuer shall file with the Secretary a copy of each executed information report required by &#xA7; 149(e)(2) of the Code to be filed with the federal Internal Revenue Service.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Each such information report shall be filed by the earlier of 10 business days following the date of the issuance of the bonds or December 30 of the calendar year in which the bonds are issued. The Secretary may grant an extension of time for the filing of any such information report.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Any bonds for which such executed information report is not filed with the Secretary in accordance with this subsection shall be deemed not to have received an allocation of the Maryland State ceiling.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Each issuer shall provide the Secretary with such additional reports and other information regarding its allocation of the Maryland State ceiling and the use thereof as the Secretary may request.</section>
  </text>
</law>
