<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gfi" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="3-209" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gfi-3-209</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Before the Commissioner issues a certificate to do business, the required capital stock and the required surplus shall be paid in full.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A commercial bank shall have required capital stock that equals at least:<section prefix="(i)">$750,000, if it is in a municipal area with not more than 50,000 inhabitants; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">$1.5 million, if it is in a municipal area with more than 50,000 inhabitants.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A commercial bank shall have a surplus in an amount that equals at least 20 percent of its required capital stock.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Before a commercial bank establishes a branch, the commercial bank shall have capital stock and surplus as provided in this subsection.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">For a branch that is to be located inside the municipal area of the principal banking office of the commercial bank, the commercial bank shall have capital stock and surplus that equal at least the sum of the amounts required by subsection (a) of this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">For a branch that is to be located outside the municipal area of the principal banking office of the commercial bank, the commercial bank shall have capital stock and surplus that equal at least the sum of:<section prefix="(i)">The amount required by subsection (a) of this section; and</section><section prefix="(ii)"/></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Unless otherwise provided by law, the unimpaired capital and surplus of a commercial bank include its debt instruments issued under &#xA7; 3-312 of this title.</section>
  </text>
</law>
