<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gfi" order_by="" level="1">Financial Institutions</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gfi-5-808.1</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>808.1</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">After notice and a hearing, the Commissioner may assess a civil penalty against a banking institution that the Commissioner determines has:<section prefix="(1)">Violated a cease and desist order issued by the Commissioner under &#xA7; 5-808 of this subtitle; or</section><section prefix="(2)">Engaged in:<section prefix="(i)">An unsafe or unsound banking practice; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">A practice that is injurious to the public interest.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The civil penalty may not exceed:<section prefix="(1)">$1,000 per violation; and</section><section prefix="(2)">$1,000 per violation for each day that the violation continues.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A civil penalty shall be assessed by written notice of assessment served on the person to be assessed.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The notice of assessment shall state the:<section prefix="(i)">Amount of the civil penalty;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Legal authority for the assessment; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Matters of fact or law constituting the grounds for the assessment.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The notice of assessment shall constitute a final order for purposes of judicial review pursuant to &#xA7; 10-221 of the State Government Article.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">In determining the amount of the civil penalty to be assessed, the Commissioner shall consider:<section prefix="(1)">The seriousness of the violation;</section><section prefix="(2)">The good faith of the violator;</section><section prefix="(3)">The violator's history of previous violations;</section><section prefix="(4)">The deleterious effect of the violation on the public and the banking industry;</section><section prefix="(5)">The assets of the violator; and</section><section prefix="(6)">Any other factors relevant to the determination of the civil penalty.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A civil penalty assessed under this section shall be due and payable within 30 days after the Commissioner issues the notice of assessment.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Commissioner may reduce or set aside a civil penalty.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The Commissioner shall pay all civil penalties collected under this section into the General Fund of the State.</section>
  </text>
</law>
