<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gfi" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="6-716" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gfi-6-716</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Eligible credit union member" means an individual member of a credit union who:<section prefix="(i)">Maintains a qualifying share certificate account at a credit union participating in a savings promotion raffle;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Is a member in good standing;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Is an adult; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">Is a resident of this State.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Qualifying share certificate account" means a savings account, savings program, or other time deposit offered to an eligible credit union member.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">"Savings promotion raffle" means a contest:<section prefix="(i)">Associated with one or more qualified share certificate accounts;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Conducted by a credit union, alone or together with other businesses; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">In which eligible credit union members are offered one or more chances to win specified prizes.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Subject to the approval of the Commissioner, a credit union may conduct a savings promotion raffle for the exclusive benefit of eligible credit union members if:<section prefix="(1)">A requirement for a chance to win a specified prize is:<section prefix="(i)">The deposit of a minimum specified amount of money in a qualifying share certificate account according to the terms and conditions developed for the savings promotion raffle; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">The submission of an entry according to the terms and conditions developed for the savings promotion raffle with no deposit or purchase necessary;</section></section><section prefix="(2)">Each entry in the savings promotion raffle has an equal chance of being drawn;</section><section prefix="(3)">The credit union maintains books and records relating to the savings promotion raffle; and</section><section prefix="(4)">The savings promotion raffle will not:<section prefix="(i)">Harm the credit union's ability to operate in a safe and sound manner; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">Mislead the credit union's members.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A credit union offering a savings promotion raffle under this section shall post in any location where entries may be submitted and disclose in any materials promoting the raffle a statement describing the terms and conditions of the raffle including that:<section prefix="(1)">No purchase is necessary;</section><section prefix="(2)">Making deposits or purchasing goods or services will not improve the odds of winning; and</section><section prefix="(3)">The odds of winning will be determined based on the number of entries received.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Commissioner may:<section prefix="(1)">Examine the conduct of a savings promotion raffle; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Issue a cease and desist order under &#xA7; 6-906 of this title for a violation of this section.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
