<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gfi" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="6-401" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gfi-6-401</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Each credit union shall have a supervisory committee.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The board shall appoint the members of the supervisory committee at:<section prefix="(1)">The first meeting of the board following the annual meeting of the members; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Any time there is a vacancy.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Subject to the provisions of paragraph (2) of this subsection, the board shall determine the number of members on the supervisory committee.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The supervisory committee shall have at least three and not more than seven members.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Each member of the supervisory committee shall be appointed from among the members of the credit union.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Not more than one member of the supervisory committee may be a director.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">An officer of the credit union, a member of the credit committee, or an employee of the credit union may not be a member of the supervisory committee.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">At least one member of the supervisory committee shall have experience in:<section prefix="(i)">Accounting;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Auditing; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">General business.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(5)">Each member of the supervisory committee:<section prefix="(i)">Shall be bonded;</section><section prefix="(ii)">May not have been convicted of any criminal offense involving dishonesty or breach of trust;</section><section prefix="(iii)">May not have habitually neglected to pay any debts;</section><section prefix="(iv)">May not become insolvent or bankrupt while serving on the supervisory committee; and</section><section prefix="(v)">May not have been removed by the Commissioner or any state or federal regulatory agency as an officer, official, or employee of a financial institution.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The members of the supervisory committee shall elect the chairman of the supervisory committee:<section prefix="(1)">At the beginning of each term of appointment to the committee; and</section><section prefix="(2)">At any time there is a vacancy and the board is notified.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">A member of the supervisory committee serves for 1 year and until a successor is appointed and qualifies.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">Each member of the supervisory committee shall take an oath to perform faithfully the duties of the office.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The board shall appropriate funds:<section prefix="(i)">For an audit conducted by an outside auditor; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">If required, for an internal auditing function.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The supervisory committee has the sole authority to engage or terminate outside and internal auditors.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
