<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gfi" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="6-331" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gfi-6-331</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, "compensation" means anything of value given to an official that is:<section prefix="(1)">In exchange for services performed as an official; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Reportable as income to the Internal Revenue Service or the Comptroller of the State.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Each official is entitled to the compensation that:<section prefix="(1)">Subject to the provisions of subsection (c) of this section, the members authorize; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Except as provided in subsection (d)(2) of this section, is approved by the Commissioner.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">All compensation to be paid under subsection (b) of this section shall be authorized by a vote of the members at the annual meeting of the membership in accordance with &#xA7; 6-317 of this subtitle.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Written disclosure of the proposed compensation and each official's expenses shall be made to all members in good standing not less than 30 days and not more than 90 days before the annual meeting of members.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The written disclosure required under paragraph (2) of this subsection shall contain at least the following information:<section prefix="(i)">The proposed dollar amount of compensation that will be paid to each official on a per meeting or other applicable basis;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The aggregate dollar amount of compensation paid to all officials for the 12 months immediately preceding the date of the notice of the annual meeting of members;</section><section prefix="(iii)"/><section prefix="(iv)">The aggregate dollar amount of all officials' expenses, excluding compensation, for the 12 months immediately preceding the date of the notice of the annual meeting of members.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The written disclosure shall be conspicuously set apart from other information provided to the members.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The written disclosure may be included in:</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">All requests for the Commissioner's approval under subsection (b) of this section shall:<section prefix="(i)">Be made in writing; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Contain a certification by the president of the credit union that the compensation has been authorized by the membership in accordance with subsection (c) of this section.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Commissioner's approval is not required if the credit union:<section prefix="(i)">Was rated "1" or "2" as of the last examination conducted by the Commissioner; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Has a positive net income as of the end of the previous calendar year.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
