<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gfi" order_by="gfi" level="1">Financial Institutions</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gfi-5-1102</section_number>
  <catch_line>This subtitle sets forth the conditions under which an out-of-state bank holding company may acquire...</catch_line>
  <order_by>1102</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">This subtitle sets forth the conditions under which an out-of-state bank holding company may acquire and hold:<section prefix="(1)">One or more savings and loan associations to be converted into one or more commercial banks; or</section><section prefix="(2)">One or more newly-formed commercial banks that have acquired or acquire one or more savings and loan associations.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The acquisition of a commercial bank by an out-of-state bank holding company under this subtitle is authorized for purposes of &#xA7; 3(d) of the Act.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, an out-of-state bank holding company that has made an acquisition under this subtitle subsequently shall be permitted, directly or indirectly, to acquire and hold Maryland bank holding companies or constituent banks, as defined in Title 3, Subtitle 7 of this article, in this State as if the out-of-state bank holding company were a bank holding company the operations of whose banking subsidiaries are principally conducted in this State for purposes of &#xA7; 3(d) of the Act. Any merger with or acquisition of a Maryland bank holding company by an out-of-state bank holding company, directly or indirectly, or any consolidation with, merger with or transfer of assets to a constituent bank by an out-of-state bank holding company, directly or indirectly, shall be governed by the procedural requirements of Subtitle 10 of this title.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Except for the procedural requirements of this section, an out-of-state bank holding company may acquire and hold Maryland bank holding companies or constituent banks in this State under subsection (c) of this section without regard to the restrictions found in Subtitle 10 of this title.</section>
  </text>
</law>
