<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gfi" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="2-115" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gfi-2-115</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">When the Commissioner determines that a person has engaged in an act or practice constituting a violation of a law, regulation, rule or order over which the Commissioner has jurisdiction, and that immediate action against the person is in the public interest, the Commissioner may in the Commissioner's discretion issue, without a prior hearing, a summary order directing the person to cease and desist from engaging in the activity, provided that the summary cease and desist order gives the person:<section prefix="(1)">Notice of the opportunity for a hearing before the Commissioner to determine whether the summary cease and desist order should be vacated, modified, or entered as final; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Notice that the summary cease and desist order will be entered as final if the person does not request a hearing within 15 days of receipt of the summary cease and desist order.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">When the Commissioner determines after notice and a hearing, unless the right to notice and a hearing is waived, that a person has engaged in an act or practice constituting a violation of a law, regulation, rule or order over which the Commissioner has jurisdiction, the Commissioner may in the Commissioner's discretion and in addition to taking any other action authorized by law:<section prefix="(1)">Issue a final cease and desist order against the person;</section><section prefix="(2)">Suspend or revoke the license of the person;</section><section prefix="(3)">Issue a penalty order against the person imposing a civil penalty up to the maximum amount of $1,000 for a first violation and a maximum amount of $5,000 for each subsequent violation; or</section><section prefix="(4)">Take any combination of the actions specified in this subsection.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">In determining the amount of financial penalty to be imposed under subsection (b) of this section, the Commissioner shall consider the following factors:<section prefix="(1)">The seriousness of the violation;</section><section prefix="(2)">The good faith of the violator;</section><section prefix="(3)">The violator's history of previous violations;</section><section prefix="(4)">The deleterious effect of the violation on the public and the industry involved;</section><section prefix="(5)">The assets of the violator; and</section><section prefix="(6)">Any other factors relevant to the determination of the financial penalty.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Notice of any hearing under this section shall be given and the hearing shall be held in accordance with the Administrative Procedure Act.</section>
  </text>
</law>
