<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gfi" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="7-120" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gfi-7-120</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section, "assets" means:<section prefix="(i)">All net earnings of the Corporation accumulated under &#xA7; 7-114 of this subtitle; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">All real or tangible or intangible personal property of the Corporation.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">In this section, "assets" does not include member deposits.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Within 2 years after the date that the Corporation no longer has any members, the Corporation shall complete the dissolution of the Corporation in accordance with the provisions of this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">When the Corporation no longer has any members, the Corporation shall file articles of dissolution with the Commissioner and the State Department of Assessments and Taxation.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Except as provided in subsection (d) of this section, the Corporation is dissolved when the Commissioner accepts the Corporation's articles of dissolution.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Corporation continues to exist for the purpose of collecting money owing to the Corporation, paying, satisfying, and discharging any existing debts or obligations, collecting and distributing the Corporation's assets, and doing all other acts required to liquidate and wind up the business and affairs of the Corporation.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">After paying, satisfying, and discharging any existing debts or obligations, the Corporation shall transfer its remaining assets to a corporation that satisfies the requirements of subsection (e) of this section.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The corporation receiving the assets under subsection (d)(2) of this section shall:<section prefix="(1)">Be a nonprofit corporation that is exempt from federal taxation under &#xA7; 501(c)(3) of the Internal Revenue Code;</section><section prefix="(2)">Have been organized:<section prefix="(i)">For educational and charitable purposes; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">To promote and publicize the interest and welfare of credit unions and their members in this State; and</section></section><section prefix="(3)">Have been in existence and operating under a charter that includes the following purposes for at least 10 years:<section prefix="(i)">Promoting the ideals of the credit union movement, including the cooperative nonprofit aspect, democratic aspect, the common bond, volunteerism, personalized service, cooperative spirit, and the encouragement of thrift and the creation of a source of credit at fair and reasonable rates;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Helping to strengthen and develop credit unions serving low-income individuals;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Improving and stimulating the ability of credit unions to provide low-cost consumer loans;</section><section prefix="(iv)">Promoting the elasticity and flexibility of the resources of credit unions;</section><section prefix="(v)">Conducting or funding research on all aspects of credit union operations and the credit union movement in general;</section><section prefix="(vi)">Cooperating and assisting credit unions and local and national organizations and credit unions to improve the general welfare of the people through credit unions;</section><section prefix="(vii)">Providing scholarships and awards to professionals and volunteers in the credit union movement; and</section><section prefix="(viii)">Furthering the credit union movement and performing all necessary and properly related services and activities.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The Corporation shall promptly notify the Commissioner following the completion of the liquidation and the winding up of the business and affairs of the Corporation.</section>
  </text>
</law>
