<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gfi" order_by="" level="1">Financial Institutions</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gfi-9-204</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>204</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The articles of incorporation of a savings and loan association shall set forth:<section prefix="(1)">The name of the association;</section><section prefix="(2)">The county in which the association's first principal place of business is to be located;</section><section prefix="(3)">A precise and accurate statement of the purpose or purposes for which the association is organized, as well as a statement that it is organized in compliance with State law;</section><section prefix="(4)">The term for which the association is to exist, which may be perpetual;</section><section prefix="(5)">The name, occupation, citizenship, place of residence, and post office address of each incorporator;</section><section prefix="(6)">The name, occupation, citizenship, place of residence, and post office address of each of the first directors; and</section><section prefix="(7)">If the association is a capital stock association, provisions for the issuance of capital stock.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The proposed bylaws of the association shall provide for:<section prefix="(1)"><section prefix="(i)">The dates of regular meetings of shareholders, if any;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The notice of the regular meetings to be given;</section><section prefix="(iii)">The qualification of voters and the manner of voting;</section><section prefix="(iv)">The manner of calling special meetings;</section><section prefix="(v)">The number of members that constitute a quorum; and</section><section prefix="(vi)">The date of the annual meeting;</section></section><section prefix="(2)"><section prefix="(i)">The number of directors and their qualifications, other than those specified in this title;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The terms of office of the directors which may not be less than 1 year or more than 3 years;</section><section prefix="(iii)">If the terms of office are more than 1 year, the method of division into classes for the purpose of electing, as nearly as may be, an equal number of directors each year; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">The removal or suspension of directors;</section></section><section prefix="(3)"><section prefix="(i)">The meetings of the board of directors; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">The powers and duties of the board of directors;</section></section><section prefix="(4)"><section prefix="(i)">The officers;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The manner of election of the officers;</section><section prefix="(iii)">The terms of office, duties, and compensation of the officers; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">The bonds required of officers;</section></section><section prefix="(5)"><section prefix="(i)">The classes of shares that may be issued;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The issuance of shares, whether issued in series or otherwise;</section><section prefix="(iii)">The times when shares may be issued; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">The matured value of shares;</section></section><section prefix="(6)">The manner in which evidence of share ownership shall be issued to members;</section><section prefix="(7)">The time and manner of apportioning, crediting, and paying dividends;</section><section prefix="(8)">The conditions upon which shares may be transferred, matured, withdrawn, retired, or suspended and forfeited; and</section><section prefix="(9)">The manner and conditions under which the bylaws may be altered or amended.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">By January 1, 1987, the Division Director shall adopt model articles of incorporation and bylaws of savings and loan associations that are not inconsistent with the provisions of subsections (a) and (b) of this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">An association may modify or alter its articles of incorporation or bylaws to be consistent with the model.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
