<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gfi" order_by="gfi" level="1">Financial Institutions</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gfi-4-701.1</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this section the following words have the meanings indicated....</catch_line>
  <order_by>701.1</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Converting institution" means a federal mutual savings bank.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Federal mutual savings bank" means an institution that:<section prefix="(i)">Is incorporated under federal law as a savings bank; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Is a mutual association.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A converting institution that is located in this State may convert into a savings bank as provided by federal law and this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The converting institution shall meet the requirements of this title for the incorporation of a savings bank.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The procedures for incorporation may be modified as required by the difference between incorporation and conversion.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">In accordance with regulations adopted by the Commissioner, any interested person may request that the Commissioner conduct a hearing regarding the conversion.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The board of directors of the converting institution shall sign, acknowledge, and file articles of incorporation.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The articles of incorporation shall state that the conversion has been approved by the members or board of directors in the manner required by subsection (e) of this section.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The conversion shall be approved at a meeting called for that purpose, by the affirmative vote of:<section prefix="(1)">Two-thirds of the members of the converting institution, voting in person or by proxy; or</section><section prefix="(2)">If there are no members, the board of directors of the converting institution.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The new savings bank resulting from the conversion:<section prefix="(1)">Shall be considered the same business and corporate entity as the converting institution; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Except as limited by this article or by its charter or bylaws, has all of the rights, powers, and duties of the converting institution.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(g)">The converting institution's rights, franchises, and interests in any property become the property of the new savings bank, subject to the liabilities of the converting institution that exist at the time of the conversion.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">Unless this construction would be unreasonable, any reference to the converting institution in any writing, whether executed or taking effect before or after the conversion, shall be interpreted as a reference to the new savings bank.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">If a converting institution has assets or engages in business activities that do not conform to the law governing savings banks, the Commissioner may allow a reasonable time for the new savings bank to conform to that law.</section>
  </text>
</law>
