<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gfi" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="13-1124" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gfi-13-1124</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, "aggrieved person" means:<section prefix="(1)">A person that:<section prefix="(i)">Is a party to a dispute that the Authority resolves under &#xA7; 13-1108(4)(ii) of this subtitle; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Is aggrieved by the Authority's final action in resolving the dispute under &#xA7; 13-1108(4)(ii) of this subtitle; or</section></section><section prefix="(2)">The local jurisdictions within a certified heritage area from which the Authority has withdrawn approval of a management plan under &#xA7; 13-1111(p) of this subtitle.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">This section does not apply to:<section prefix="(1)">The failure of the Authority to designate:<section prefix="(i)">A heritage area as a recognized heritage area; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">A recognized heritage area as a certified heritage area through the approval of a management plan;</section></section><section prefix="(2)">Actions taken by the Authority under its powers to issue bonds under Part IV of this subtitle; or</section><section prefix="(3)">The failure of the Authority to award or enforce the terms of grants, loans, or other financing.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">An aggrieved person may appeal to the Office of Administrative Hearings for a hearing in accordance with Title 10, Subtitle 2 of the State Government Article.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The decision of the Office of Administrative Hearings is the final administrative decision.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The Office of Administrative Hearings may not modify the Authority's resolution of a dispute unless the aggrieved person shows by a preponderance of the evidence that:<section prefix="(1)">The final action of the Authority was arbitrary or capricious; or</section><section prefix="(2)">The Authority failed to follow its own procedures or regulations for resolving a dispute under &#xA7; 13-1108(4)(ii) of this subtitle.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
