<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gfi" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="8-303" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gfi-8-303</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Division Director shall adopt regulations necessary to accomplish the policies set forth in &#xA7; 8-102 of this title.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Without limiting the authority conferred by subsection (a) of this section, the Division Director may adopt regulations consistent with the provisions of this title and Title 9 of this article with respect to:<section prefix="(1)">Any powers conferred on the Division Director in this title and Title 9 of this article;</section><section prefix="(2)">Reserve requirements;</section><section prefix="(3)">Stock ownership and dividends;</section><section prefix="(4)">Stock transfers (change of control);</section><section prefix="(5)">Incorporators, controlling persons, directors, officers, employees, and agents of a savings and loan association;</section><section prefix="(6)">Bylaws;</section><section prefix="(7)">Related entities;</section><section prefix="(8)">The structure of the office of the Division;</section><section prefix="(9)">The operation, conduct, and management of savings and loan associations;</section><section prefix="(10)">Withdrawable accounts, savings accounts and plans, and contracts for savings programs;</section><section prefix="(11)">Loans and loan expenses, including underwriting procedures;</section><section prefix="(12)">Investments;</section><section prefix="(13)">Forms and definitions;</section><section prefix="(14)">Types of financial records to be maintained by savings and loan associations;</section><section prefix="(15)">Retention periods of various financial records of savings and loan associations;</section><section prefix="(16)">Internal control procedures of savings and loan associations;</section><section prefix="(17)">Chartering and branching;</section><section prefix="(18)">Liquidations;</section><section prefix="(19)">Mergers;</section><section prefix="(20)">Conversions;</section><section prefix="(21)">Reports which may be required by the Division Director;</section><section prefix="(22)">Conflicts of interest;</section><section prefix="(23)">Accounting rules;</section><section prefix="(24)">Issuance of orders;</section><section prefix="(25)">Removal of directors, officers, and employees;</section><section prefix="(26)">Advertising; and</section><section prefix="(27)">Enforcement remedies relating to limitations on interest rates on deposits.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Without limiting the authority conferred by subsection (a) of this section, directors and officers of savings and loan associations shall develop and implement, by December 31, 1989, written:<section prefix="(1)">Real estate appraisal policies; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Procedures pertaining to the hiring and performance of real estate appraisers.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The procedures required under subsection (c)(2) of this section shall set forth specific factors to be considered by the savings and loan association's directors and officers, including but not limited to:<section prefix="(1)">Whether the appraiser is licensed or certified under the Business Occupations and Professions Article; and</section><section prefix="(2)">The real estate appraiser's:<section prefix="(i)">Professional education; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Experience in real estate appraising.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">Real estate appraisal policies and procedures shall be submitted by the savings and loan associations to the Division Director for review and approval.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The regulations adopted by the Division Director may include reasonable requirements and limitations on the types and amounts of investments, the manner of raising capital, and the nature and amounts of reserves, irrespective of their effects on free economic competition.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">If the Division Director believes that a savings and loan association or any of its controlling persons, directors, officers, agents, or employees has violated any provision of this title or Title 9 that relates to the association, the Division Director immediately shall report the violation to:<section prefix="(1)">The Secretary of Labor, Licensing, and Regulation;</section><section prefix="(2)">The Governor; and</section><section prefix="(3)">The Attorney General, who shall take the appropriate steps to institute an investigation or other appropriate action for the violation.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(h)">The Division Director may provide advisory opinions on conflicts of interest on request.</section>
  </text>
</law>
