<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gfi" order_by="" level="1">Financial Institutions</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gfi-5-209</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>209</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Except as otherwise provided in this article, the Commissioner and the employees of and the attorney for the Commissioner's office may not disclose:<section prefix="(1)">The name of any debtor of a banking institution;</section><section prefix="(2)">Any information about the private accounts with or transactions of a banking institution;</section><section prefix="(3)">Any information obtained in the course of examining a banking institution; or</section><section prefix="(4)">Any confidential information obtained from a federal banking authority.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">This section does not apply to any information that a person discloses:<section prefix="(1)">In performing a public duty to report on or take special action about the business of a banking institution;</section><section prefix="(2)">In testifying as a witness in a criminal proceeding; or</section><section prefix="(3)">In informing any director or authorized officer, employee, or agent of a banking institution under examination of the results of that examination.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">As provided in this subsection, the Commissioner may give a federal banking authority a copy of any examination of a banking institution, a copy of any report made by the banking institution, and any other information that the Commissioner has about the banking institution.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Commissioner may give the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation information about a banking institution if:<section prefix="(i)">The institution is insured by the Corporation; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">The institution:<section prefix="1.">Is applying for insurance from the Corporation; and</section><section prefix="2.">Asks the Commissioner to do so.</section></section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Commissioner may give the Federal Reserve Bank of Richmond information about a banking institution if:<section prefix="(i)">The institution is a member of the Federal Reserve System; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">The institution:<section prefix="1.">Is applying for membership in the System; and</section><section prefix="2.">Asks the Commissioner to do so.</section></section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Except as otherwise provided by law, all confidential information disclosed to any person as permitted under this section:<section prefix="(1)">Remains the property of the Commissioner; and</section><section prefix="(2)">May not be further disclosed by that person without the written permission of the Commissioner.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">Any person who violates any provision of this section is guilty of a misdemeanor and on conviction is subject to:<section prefix="(1)">Forfeiture of the office or employment; and</section><section prefix="(2)">A fine not exceeding $1,000 or imprisonment not exceeding 2 years or both.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
