<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gfi" order_by="gfi" level="1">Financial Institutions</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gfi-1-211</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this section the following words have the meanings indicated....</catch_line>
  <order_by>211</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Depository institution" means any State-chartered or federally chartered financial institution, other-state bank, or foreign bank that:<section prefix="(i)">Is located in this State or maintains a branch in this State; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Is authorized to maintain qualifying deposit accounts.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Eligible customer" means an individual who:<section prefix="(i)">Is an adult; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Is a resident of this State.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">"Qualifying deposit account" means a savings account, savings program, or other time deposit offered to an eligible customer.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">"Savings promotion raffle" means a contest:<section prefix="(i)">Associated with one or more qualified deposit accounts;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Conducted by a depository institution, alone or together with other businesses; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">In which eligible customers are offered one or more chances to win specified prizes.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A depository institution may conduct a savings promotion raffle if:<section prefix="(i)">A requirement for a chance to win a specified prize is:<section prefix="1.">The deposit of a minimum specified amount of money in a qualifying deposit account according to the terms and conditions developed for the savings promotion raffle; or</section><section prefix="2.">The submission of any entry according to the terms and conditions developed for the savings promotion raffle with no deposit or purchase necessary;</section></section><section prefix="(ii)">Each entry in the savings promotion raffle has an equal chance of being drawn;</section><section prefix="(iii)">The depository institution maintains books and records relating to the savings promotion raffle; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">The savings promotion raffle will not:<section prefix="1.">Harm the depository institution's ability to operate in a safe and sound manner; or</section><section prefix="2.">Mislead the depository institution's customers.</section></section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A depository institution offering a savings promotion raffle under this section shall post in any location where entries may be submitted and disclose in any materials promoting the raffle a statement describing the terms and conditions of the raffling including that:<section prefix="(i)">No purchase is necessary;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Making deposits or purchasing goods or services will not improve the odds of winning; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">The odds of winning will be determined based on the number of entries received.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">In addition to the requirements under paragraph (1) of this subsection, a savings promotion raffle conducted by a banking institution must be approved by the Commissioner.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Except as preempted by federal law, the Commissioner may:<section prefix="(1)">Examine the conduct of a savings promotion raffle; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Issue a cease and desist order under &#xA7; 5-808 of this article for a violation of this section.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
