<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gfi" order_by="" level="1">Financial Institutions</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gfi-7-206</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>206</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">To apply for a certificate of authority, an applicant shall sign and submit to the Commissioner an application made under oath on the form that the Commissioner requires.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The application shall include:<section prefix="(i)">The applicant's corporate name, business address, and any trade names under which the applicant conducts business;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The name and business address of each of the applicant's officers and directors;</section><section prefix="(iii)">The address at which the business is to be conducted;</section><section prefix="(iv)">The name and address of the applicant's proposed resident agent in the State; and</section><section prefix="(v)">Any other information that the Commissioner reasonably requires.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">With the application, the applicant shall submit:<section prefix="(1)">A certified copy of its articles of incorporation with all amendments;</section><section prefix="(2)">A certified copy of its bylaws with all amendments;</section><section prefix="(3)">A copy of the applicant's annual financial statements as of the immediately preceding December 31, prepared in accordance with generally accepted accounting principles and audited and certified by an independent certified public accountant;</section><section prefix="(4)">If domiciled outside the State, a copy of the applicant's most recent report of examination, if any, made by the responsible supervisory official in its state of domicile;</section><section prefix="(5)">If domiciled outside the State, certification by the responsible supervisory official in its state of domicile showing that the applicant is authorized to engage in the credit union share guaranty business in that state;</section><section prefix="(6)">A copy of the applicant's current standard written contract with participating credit unions containing the rights and obligations of the parties; and</section><section prefix="(7)">Any other information and documents that the Commissioner reasonably requires.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">With the application, the applicant shall pay to the Commissioner a nonrefundable application fee of $5,000.</section>
  </text>
</law>
