<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gfi" order_by="" level="1">Financial Institutions</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gfi-5-1101</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>1101</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Acquire" means to assume ownership or control, directly or indirectly, of any voting shares of, interest in, or all or a substantial portion of the assets and liabilities, including, unless otherwise determined in writing by the Director of the State of Maryland Deposit Insurance Fund Corporation to be in the best financial interest of the Fund, all savings accounts liabilities that are insured by the Fund, to the extent of the insurance, and liabilities to the State, of the following institutions:<section prefix="(1)">A savings and loan association;</section><section prefix="(2)">A newly-formed commercial bank chartered to consummate a transaction with a savings and loan association under this subtitle; or</section><section prefix="(3)">A commercial bank that results from the conversion of a savings and loan association.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Act" means the federal Bank Holding Company Act of 1956, as amended.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">"Maryland bank holding company" means a company that is defined as a bank holding company under the Act and that conducted its principal banking business in Maryland on July 1, 1966, or on the date on which the company became a bank holding company under the Act, whichever occurred later.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"Out-of-state bank holding company" means a company that is defined as a bank holding company under the Act and that conducted its principal banking business in a jurisdiction of the United States other than Maryland on July 1, 1966, or on the date on which the company became a bank holding company under the Act, whichever occurred later.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">"Savings accounts" has the meaning stated in &#xA7; 10-101(k) of this article.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">"Savings and loan association" means a corporation that is:<section prefix="(1)">Chartered under the laws of this State as a savings and loan association; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Insured by the State of Maryland Deposit Insurance Fund Corporation.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
