<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gfi" order_by="" level="1">Financial Institutions</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gfi-10-103</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>103</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Fund Director is appointed by the Governor.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Fund Director serves at the pleasure of the Secretary of Labor, Licensing, and Regulation.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">For a period of 2 years after termination of employment with the Fund, if the Fund Director is employed by a savings and loan association that is insured by the Fund, or becomes a director, officer, attorney, or agent of a savings and loan association that is insured by the Fund, that individual may not:<section prefix="(1)">Represent, formally or informally, the association in any judicial, administrative, or other proceeding in which:<section prefix="(i)">The Fund is a party; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">The former Fund Director substantially participated;</section></section><section prefix="(2)">Participate in any application submitted to the Fund for the Division's approval; or</section><section prefix="(3)">Attempt to influence, or make any oral or written communication, on behalf of the association in any matter before the Fund relating to the association in which the individual participated personally and substantially as Fund Director.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">All of the corporate powers of the Fund shall be exercised by the Fund Director.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Board consists of 11 members.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Of the Board members:<section prefix="(i)">3 shall be elected by the member associations, subject to the approval of the Secretary of Labor, Licensing, and Regulation; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">8 shall be appointed by the Governor.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">From among its members, the Board shall elect a chairman.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The Board may appoint officers as it considers advisable.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(4)">No officer or director of the Fund, whether appointed or elected, shall be personally liable on any contract legally entered into on behalf of the Fund unless the contract, by its terms, expressly obligates that officer or director.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
