<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gfi" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="13-1113" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gfi-13-1113</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">As provided in the State budget, the Authority may award:<section prefix="(1)">Grants and loans to local jurisdictions or other appropriate entities for planning, design, acquisition, development, preservation, restoration, interpretation, marketing, and programming of certified heritage areas; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Grants to local jurisdictions or other appropriate entities to develop management plans in recognized heritage areas.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A grant to develop a management plan may not exceed 50% of the cost of the management plan.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, the Authority may make acquisition and development grants only for projects in a target investment zone within a certified heritage area  for a period of up to 10 years after the day on which the Authority first approves funding for acquisition or development grants in:<section prefix="(i)">The target investment zone; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">That portion of the target investment zone added through a boundary amendment approved by the Authority.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Authority may make acquisition or development grants for a project in a target investment zone after the 10-year period described in paragraph (1) of this subsection, or outside a target investment zone, if the Authority determines that the project is essential for the success of the management plan for the certified heritage area.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">An acquisition or development grant:<section prefix="(i)">May not be used for any purpose other than implementation of the certified heritage area in conformity with the approved management plan; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">May not exceed 50% of the total project cost for which the grant is awarded.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Subject to paragraph (2) of this subsection, the Authority may make program grants to local jurisdictions and other appropriate entities:<section prefix="(i)">To develop and present interpretive exhibits, materials or other appropriate products to further the educational and recreational objectives of the certified heritage areas program; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">To encourage revitalization of, and reinvestment in, certified heritage area resources.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A program grant made by the Authority under paragraph (1) of this subsection may not exceed 50% of the estimated project cost.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">Through the resources of the members of the Authority and in cooperation with other State agencies, the Authority shall provide technical assistance to management entities implementing a management plan.</section>
  </text>
</law>
