<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gfi" order_by="gfi" level="1">Financial Institutions</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gfi-11-601</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated....</catch_line>
  <order_by>601</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Borrower" has the meaning stated in &#xA7; 11-501 of this title.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Clerical or support duties" includes the following activities relating to the processing or underwriting of a mortgage loan when performed subsequent to the receipt of a loan application:<section prefix="(1)">The receipt, collection, distribution, and analysis of information usual and customary for the processing or underwriting of a mortgage loan; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Communication with a consumer to obtain information necessary for the processing or underwriting of a mortgage loan, to the extent that the communication does not include offering or negotiating mortgage loan rates or terms, or counseling consumers about mortgage loan rates or terms.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Depository institution" has the meaning stated in the Federal Deposit Insurance Act, 12 U.S.C. &#xA7; 1813(c).</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Depository institution" includes credit unions.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"Federal banking agencies'' means the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System, the Comptroller of the Currency, the Director of the Office of Thrift Supervision, the National Credit Union Administration, and the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">"Fund" means the Mortgage Lender-Originator Fund established under &#xA7; 11-610 of this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">"Immediate family member" means a spouse, child, sibling, parent, grandparent, grandchild, stepparent, stepchild, and stepsibling.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">"Independent contractor" means a person whose compensation is paid without a deduction for federal or State income tax.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">"Individual" means a natural person.</section>
    <section prefix="(j)">"Individual loan servicer" means an individual who on behalf of a note holder or mortgage loan servicer:<section prefix="(1)">Collects or receives payments, including payments of principal, interest, escrow amounts, and other amounts due on existing mortgage loan obligations owed to the note holder or mortgage loan servicer, at a time when the borrower is in default, or in reasonably foreseeable likelihood of default; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Working with the borrower and the note holder or mortgage loan servicer, collects data and makes decisions to modify, either temporarily or permanently, the terms of the mortgage loan obligations described in item (1) of this subsection or to proceed with collection efforts through foreclosure or other processes.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(k)">"License" means a license issued by the Commissioner under this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(l)">"Licensee" means an individual who is licensed by the Commissioner under this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(m)">"Loan application" has the meaning stated in &#xA7; 11-501 of this title.</section>
    <section prefix="(n)">"Mortgage lender" means a person that is licensed as a mortgage lender under Subtitle 5 of this title.</section>
    <section prefix="(o)">"Mortgage lending business" has the meaning stated in &#xA7; 11-501 of this title.</section>
    <section prefix="(p)">"Mortgage loan" has the meaning stated in &#xA7; 11-501 of this title.</section>
    <section prefix="(q)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Mortgage loan originator" means an individual who for compensation or gain, or in the expectation of compensation or gain:<section prefix="(i)">Takes a loan application; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">Offers or negotiates terms of a mortgage loan.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Mortgage loan originator" does not include an individual who:<section prefix="(i)">Acts solely as a mortgage loan processor or underwriter;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Performs only real estate brokerage activities and is licensed in accordance with Title 17 of the Business Occupations and Professions Article, unless the individual is compensated by a mortgage lender, mortgage broker, or other mortgage loan originator or by any agent of a mortgage lender, mortgage broker, or other mortgage loan originator; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">Is involved solely in extensions of credit relating to timeshare plans, as that term is defined in 11 U.S.C. &#xA7; 101(53d).</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(r)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Mortgage loan processor or underwriter" means an individual who performs clerical or support duties as an employee of, at the direction of, and subject to the supervision and instruction of a person licensed, or exempt from licensing, under Title 5 of this article.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Mortgage loan processor or underwriter" does not include an individual who:<section prefix="(i)">Represents to the public, through advertising or other means of communication including the use of business cards, stationery, brochures, signs, rate lists, or other promotional items, that the individual can or will perform any of the activities of a mortgage loan originator; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">Performs mortgage loan processing or underwriting activities as an independent contractor.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(s)">''Nationwide Mortgage Licensing System and Registry'' has the meaning stated in &#xA7; 11-501 of this title.</section>
    <section prefix="(t)">"Nontraditional mortgage product" means any mortgage product other than a 30-year fixed rate mortgage loan.</section>
    <section prefix="(u)">"Person" has the meaning stated in &#xA7; 11-501 of this title.</section>
    <section prefix="(v)">''Real estate brokerage activity'' means any activity for which a license is required under Title 17 of the Business Occupations and Professions Article.</section>
    <section prefix="(w)">''Registered mortgage loan originator'' means any individual who:<section prefix="(1)">Is a mortgage loan originator;</section><section prefix="(2)">Is an employee of:<section prefix="(i)">A depository institution;</section><section prefix="(ii)">A subsidiary that is:<section prefix="1.">Owned and controlled by a depository institution; and</section><section prefix="2.">Regulated by a federal banking agency; or</section></section><section prefix="(iii)">An institution regulated by the Farm Credit Administration; and</section></section><section prefix="(3)">Is registered with, and maintains a unique identifier through, the Nationwide Mortgage Licensing System and Registry.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(x)">"Residential real estate" has the meaning stated in &#xA7; 11-501 of this title.</section>
    <section prefix="(y)">''Unique identifier'' means a number or other identifier assigned by the Nationwide Mortgage Licensing System and Registry.</section>
  </text>
</law>
