<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gfi" order_by="gfi" level="1">Financial Institutions</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gfi-3-403</section_number>
  <catch_line>After the initial issuance of capital stock by a commercial bank, each of its directors shall own in...</catch_line>
  <order_by>403</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">After the initial issuance of capital stock by a commercial bank, each of its directors shall own in good faith and of record unencumbered shares of the capital stock of:<section prefix="(i)">The commercial bank; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">A corporation that owns more than 80 percent of the capital stock of the commercial bank.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The unencumbered capital stock owned by the director shall be in the amount of at least:<section prefix="(i)">$500; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">$250, if the commercial bank is a State bank that has $50,000 or less in capital stock.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">To determine the amount of capital stock owned by a director:<section prefix="(i)">Based on the value of the stock on the date of purchase or on the date the director took office, whichever is greater, any 1 or more of the following may be considered:<section prefix="1.">Aggregate par value in the amount required under either paragraph (2)(i) or (ii) of this subsection;</section><section prefix="2.">Aggregate shareholder's equity in the amount required under either paragraph (2)(i) or (ii) of this subsection; or</section><section prefix="3.">Aggregate fair market value in the amount required under paragraph (2)(i) or (ii) of this subsection; and</section></section><section prefix="(ii)">Debt instruments of the commercial bank or corporation may not be considered.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A majority of the directors of a commercial bank shall be residents of this State.</section>
  </text>
</law>
