<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gfi" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="13-1101" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gfi-13-1101</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Authority" means the Maryland Heritage Areas Authority established under &#xA7; 13-1103 of this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Bonds" means revenue bonds, including refunding bonds or revenue anticipation notes, issued by the Authority.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">"Certified heritage area" means a heritage area designated in accordance with &#xA7; 13-1111 of this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"Fund" means the Maryland Heritage Areas Authority Financing Fund established under &#xA7; 13-1114 of this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">"Heritage area" means a developed area of public and private uses that:<section prefix="(1)">Ranges in size from a portion of a county or municipal corporation to a regional area with a special coherence;</section><section prefix="(2)">Is distinguished by physical and cultural resources which have played a vital role in the historic life and development of the community and contribute to the public through interpretive, educational, and recreational use;</section><section prefix="(3)">Is composed of contiguous or noncontiguous geographic areas; and</section><section prefix="(4)">May include traditional parks and historic places or property on the national or State register of historic properties.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Local plan" means the policies, statements, goals, and interrelated plans for private and public land use, transportation, and community facilities documented in texts and maps which constitute the guide for the area's future development.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Local plan" includes a general plan, master plan, comprehensive plan, community plan, and the like as adopted in accordance with Title 1, Subtitle 4 or Title 3 of the Land Use Article.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(h)">"Management plan" means a document prepared in accordance with &#xA7; 13-1111 of this subtitle that includes a comprehensive statement in words, maps, illustrations, or other media of communication of the objectives, policies, and standards to guide public and private action for the preservation, interpretation, development, and use of the cultural, historic, natural, and architectural resources of a certified heritage area.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">"Recognized heritage area" means a heritage area that:<section prefix="(1)">The local jurisdictions within the heritage area have nominated for designation as a recognized heritage area under &#xA7; 13-1110 of this subtitle; and</section><section prefix="(2)">The Heritage Areas Authority has designated as eligible to apply for designation as a certified heritage area under &#xA7; 13-1111 of this subtitle.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(j)">"Target investment zone" means a specific area:<section prefix="(1)">Located within a certified heritage area;</section><section prefix="(2)">Identified in a management plan approved by the Authority or through a process specified by the Authority; and</section><section prefix="(3)">Intended to attract significant private investment to the area in order to encourage demonstrable results and return on public investment within the area in a relatively short period of time.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
