<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gfi" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="11-603" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gfi-11-603</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">A license issued under this subtitle authorizes the licensee to act as a mortgage loan originator only when acting within the scope of employment with:<section prefix="(1)">A mortgage lender; or</section><section prefix="(2)">A person who is exempt from licensing as a mortgage lender.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A licensee may not:<section prefix="(1)">Maintain more than one license under this subtitle; or</section><section prefix="(2)">Be employed by more than one mortgage lender or person who is exempt from licensing as a mortgage lender.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Commissioner shall include on each license:<section prefix="(i)">The name of the licensee;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The name of the licensee's employer; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">The unique identifier of the licensee if the licensee has been issued a unique identifier.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">An individual may not act as a mortgage loan originator under a name or for an employer that is different from the name and employer that appear on the license unless the licensee:<section prefix="(i)">Notifies the Commissioner in writing in advance of a change in the licensee's name or the licensee's employer;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Pays to the Commissioner a license amendment fee set by the Commissioner for each notice provided under this paragraph; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">In the case of a new employer, amends the sponsorship information on the Nationwide Mortgage Licensing System and Registry by submitting the amendment, in the form required by the Commissioner, to indicate that the licensee is an employee of the new employer.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">If a licensee ceases to be employed by a licensed mortgage lender or by a person exempt from licensing as a mortgage lender, the licensee shall notify the Commissioner within 10 business days, and the license shall be placed into nonactive status.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">During the time that a license is in nonactive status, it is a violation of this subtitle for the licensee to engage in any activity for which a license is required under this subtitle.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">The license shall remain in nonactive status until the licensee:<section prefix="(i)">Notifies the Commissioner in writing that the licensee has obtained employment with a licensed mortgage lender or with a person exempt from licensing as a mortgage lender; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Has complied with the requirements set forth in paragraph (2) of this subsection.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A license may be issued under this subtitle to an individual who is not employed by a licensed mortgage lender or a person exempt from licensing as a mortgage lender provided the license is placed into and remains in nonactive status until the licensee:<section prefix="(1)">Notifies the Commissioner in writing that the licensee has obtained employment with a licensed mortgage lender or with a person exempt from licensing as a mortgage lender; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Has complied with the requirements set forth in subsection (c)(2) of this section.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">A license may be issued under this subtitle to an individual who is employed by a mortgage lender, or a person exempt from licensing as a mortgage lender, that has its principal office located outside the State if the mortgage lender or the person exempt from licensing as a mortgage lender maintains a resident agent within the State.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">This section does not apply to an affiliated insurance producer-mortgage loan originator licensed under &#xA7; 11-603.1 of this subtitle.</section>
  </text>
</law>
