<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gfi" order_by="gfi" level="1">Financial Institutions</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gfi-12-409</section_number>
  <catch_line>After the filing of a complete application, the Commissioner shall investigate the financial conditi...</catch_line>
  <order_by>409</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">After the filing of a complete application, the Commissioner shall investigate the financial condition and responsibility, financial and business experience, character, and general fitness of the applicant.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Unless the Commissioner notifies the applicant that a different time period is necessary, the Commissioner shall approve or deny each application for a license within 60 days after the date a complete application is filed.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The applicant may by written request to the Commissioner withdraw the application at any time before the issuance of the license.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Commissioner shall issue a license to any applicant who meets the requirements of this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If an applicant does not meet the requirements of this subtitle, the Commissioner shall:<section prefix="(i)">Notify the applicant immediately of this fact;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Subject to the hearing provisions of &#xA7; 12-428 of this subtitle, deny the application;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Return the surety device filed under &#xA7; 12-407 of this subtitle; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">Keep the license fee and the investigation fee.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Within 30 days after the Commissioner denies an application, the Commissioner shall state the reasons for the denial in writing and mail them to the address listed in the application.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
