<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gfi" order_by="" level="1">Financial Institutions</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gfi-11-506.1</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>506.1</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, "Central Repository" means the Criminal Justice Information System Central Repository of the Department of Public Safety and Correctional Services.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">This section does not apply to any corporation the securities of which are exempt from registration under &#xA7; 11-601(8) or (12) of the Corporations and Associations Article.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">In connection with an initial application and at any other time the Commissioner requests, each applicant or licensee shall provide fingerprints for:<section prefix="(1)">Use by the Central Repository to conduct State criminal history records checks; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Submission to the Federal Bureau of Investigation, and any other governmental agency or entity authorized to receive this information, for a state, national, or international criminal history background check.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">In addition to the requirement under subsection (c) of this section, if the Commissioner requires in connection with an initial application, and at any other time the Commissioner requests, an applicant or licensee shall provide to the Nationwide Mortgage Licensing System and Registry information concerning the applicant's identity, including:<section prefix="(1)">Fingerprints for submission to the Federal Bureau of Investigation, and any other governmental agency or entity authorized to receive this information, for a state, national, or international criminal history background check; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Personal history and experience in a form prescribed by the Nationwide Mortgage Licensing System and Registry, including the submission of authorization for the Nationwide Mortgage Licensing System and Registry and the Commissioner to obtain:<section prefix="(i)">An independent credit report from a consumer reporting agency described in the federal Fair Credit Reporting Act, 15 U.S.C. &#xA7; 1681a(p); and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Information related to any administrative, civil, or criminal findings by any governmental jurisdiction.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The Commissioner may request from the Central Repository, the Federal Bureau of Investigation, or the Nationwide Mortgage Licensing System and Registry, as applicable, for each applicant or licensee who is required to provide fingerprints under subsection (c) or (d) of this section:<section prefix="(1)"><section prefix="(i)">The state, national, or international criminal history records of the applicant or licensee; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">A printed statement listing any conviction or other disposition of, and any plea of guilty or nolo contendere to, any criminal charge;</section></section><section prefix="(2)"><section prefix="(i)">An update of the initial criminal history records check or criminal history background check of the applicant or licensee; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">A revised statement listing any conviction or other disposition of, and any plea of guilty or nolo contendere to, any criminal charge occurring after the date of the initial criminal history records check or criminal history background check; and</section></section><section prefix="(3)">An acknowledged receipt of the application for a criminal history records check or criminal history background check of the applicant or licensee.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">An applicant or licensee who is required to provide fingerprints under subsection (c) or (d) of this section shall pay any processing or other fees required by the Central Repository, the Federal Bureau of Investigation, and the Nationwide Mortgage Licensing System and Registry.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">To implement this subtitle, the Commissioner may use the Nationwide Mortgage Licensing System and Registry as a channeling agent to request information from and distribute information to the Department of Justice, any other governmental agency with subject matter jurisdiction, and any other state licensing entity that has loan originators registered with the Nationwide Mortgage Licensing System and Registry.</section>
  </text>
</law>
