<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gfi" order_by="" level="1">Financial Institutions</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gfi-4-803</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>803</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The savings bank shall:<section prefix="(1)">File with the Commissioner for examination the application for approval of reorganization; and</section><section prefix="(2)">At the time of filing of an application for approval of reorganization, pay to the Commissioner a fee of $1,500.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Commissioner shall investigate the proposed articles of incorporation of the subsidiary savings bank and determine if:<section prefix="(1)">The articles are framed in accordance with law;</section><section prefix="(2)">The character, responsibility, and general fitness of the incorporators and directors named in the articles command confidence and warrant belief that the business of the proposed subsidiary savings bank will be conducted honestly and efficiently in accordance with the intent of this article; and</section><section prefix="(3)">Allowing the proposed subsidiary savings bank to engage in business:<section prefix="(i)">Will promote public convenience and advantage; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Is expedient and desirable.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">After investigating the proposed articles of incorporation of the subsidiary savings bank, the Commissioner may require any change in the articles of incorporation that the Commissioner considers necessary.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">As to the proposed articles of incorporation of the subsidiary savings bank:<section prefix="(1)">Within 3 months after the application is filed for examination, the Commissioner shall sign, date, and endorse each copy of the articles of incorporation as "approved" or "refused".</section><section prefix="(2)">If formation of the subsidiary savings bank is refused, the Commissioner shall return one of the endorsed copies of the articles of incorporation to the incorporators.</section><section prefix="(3)">If formation of the subsidiary savings bank is approved, the Commissioner shall:<section prefix="(i)">Return one of the endorsed copies of the articles of incorporation to the incorporators; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Keep and record one of the endorsed copies.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">Within 3 months after the application for approval of reorganization is filed for examination, the Commissioner shall approve or reject the application. The Commissioner may not approve the application unless the Commissioner determines:<section prefix="(1)">That the plan of reorganization is:<section prefix="(i)">Reasonably required to protect the welfare of the general economy of this State;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Not detrimental to the public interest or the savings bank; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">In compliance with the regulations and conditions that the Commissioner adopts;</section></section><section prefix="(2)">That if the reorganization is pursuant to an acquisition by the mutual holding company of all the stock of a savings and loan association:<section prefix="(i)">Exigent circumstances exist that make the acquisition necessary to maintain the viability or prevent the probable failure of the savings and loan association acquired; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">The mutual holding company agrees to obtain federal insurance for the deposits of the acquired savings and loan association within the time limitation imposed by the Commissioner;</section></section><section prefix="(3)">That immediately before the reorganization, the depositors of the savings bank are entitled to deposits in the subsidiary savings bank of like amounts, interest rates, and other terms, without interruption of interest;</section><section prefix="(4)">That all deposits continue to be insured by the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation up to the maximum amount provided by law; and</section><section prefix="(5)">That the applicant has met all the requirements of this subtitle and Subtitle 9 of this title.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
