<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gfi" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="12-802" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gfi-12-802</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Currency" means currency and coin of the United States or any other country.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Department" means the Department of Labor, Licensing, and Regulation.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Financial institution" means:<section prefix="(i)">A national banking association;</section><section prefix="(ii)">A State banking institution;</section><section prefix="(iii)">A credit union that is organized under the laws of this State or of the United States;</section><section prefix="(iv)">Any other organization that is organized under the banking laws of the State and subject to the supervision of the Commissioner;</section><section prefix="(v)">A savings and loan association that is organized under the laws of the State or of the United States; or</section><section prefix="(vi)">Persons engaged in the business of cashing checks for a fee unless performed incidental to the sale of goods or services.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Financial institution" does not include any person licensed by the Commissioner under Title 11 of this article.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"Person" means an individual, partnership, firm, trust, estate, association, corporation, or other entity.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">"Secretary" means the Secretary of Labor, Licensing, and Regulation.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">"Transaction" includes the deposit, withdrawal, transfer, bailment, loan, pledge payment, or exchange of currency by, through, or to the financial institution.</section>
  </text>
</law>
