<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gfi" order_by="" level="1">Financial Institutions</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gfi-6-325</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>325</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Each credit union shall have at least five directors.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Each director:<section prefix="(1)">Shall be a member of the credit union;</section><section prefix="(2)">Shall be bonded;</section><section prefix="(3)">May not have:<section prefix="(i)">Defaulted on the payment of any monetary obligation to the credit union;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Been convicted of any criminal offense involving dishonesty or breach of trust;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Habitually neglected to pay debts;</section><section prefix="(iv)">Become insolvent or bankrupt; or</section><section prefix="(v)">Been removed by any state or federal regulatory agency from office as an officer, official, or employee of a financial institution; and</section></section><section prefix="(4)">Shall comply with any other qualifications set forth in the credit union bylaws.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A director holds office for the term that the bylaws provide, which may not exceed 3 years, and until a successor is elected and qualifies.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Each director shall take an oath that the director:<section prefix="(1)">Will diligently and honestly perform the duties as director in administering the credit union's affairs;</section><section prefix="(2)">Will remain responsible for the performance of the duties of the director even if the director delegates the performance of the duties; and</section><section prefix="(3)">Will not knowingly or willfully permit the violation of an applicable law or regulation.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The chairman and, if any, vice chairman of the board shall be elected by and from the directors.</section>
  </text>
</law>
