<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gfi" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="13-1008.1" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gfi-13-1008.1</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Authority may adopt and enforce regulations for the parking of motor vehicles in and on any facilities or property the Authority owns or controls.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The regulations shall:<section prefix="(1)">Be reasonably necessary for the efficient operation of facilities or property owned or controlled by the Authority;</section><section prefix="(2)">Provide for a uniform system for accessible parking for individuals with disabilities, to enhance the safety of individuals with disabilities in conformity with the federal Uniform System for Parking for Persons with Disabilities and the federal Americans with Disabilities Act accessibility guidelines for buildings and facilities; and</section><section prefix="(3)">Include procedures for the voluntary payment of fines directly to the Authority in uncontested parking cases.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Maryland State Police or the Police Department of the City of Cumberland may issue citations for violations of the regulations adopted under this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The issuance of citations under this section shall comply with the requirements of Title 26, Subtitle 3 of the Transportation Article.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A person who violates a parking regulation under this section is subject to a fine established by the Authority in accordance with paragraph (2) of this subsection.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Authority shall adopt regulations to establish fines that are equal to the fines that the City of Cumberland, by ordinance, may impose for similar parking violations.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">All regulations adopted under this section shall be posted conspicuously in a public place on facilities or property owned or controlled by the Authority.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">The Executive Director of the Authority may designate employees of the Authority or security personnel under contract with the Authority to issue citations, to the extent authorized by the Executive Director of the Authority, for violations of motor vehicle parking regulations adopted under this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">The Executive Director of the Authority, in consultation with the chief police officer of the Maryland State Police and the Maryland Police Training Commission, shall adopt regulations establishing:<section prefix="(1)">Qualifications for individuals appointed under subsection (g) of this section, which may include prerequisites of character, training, experience, and education; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Standards for the performance of the duties assigned to individuals appointed under subsection (g) of this section.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
