<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gfi" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="5-1001" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gfi-5-1001</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Affiliate" means any company that controls, is controlled by, or is under common control with another company.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Bank" has the meaning stated in the Federal Deposit Insurance Act, 12 U.S.C. &#xA7; 1813(a)(1).</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">"Bank supervisory agency" means:<section prefix="(1)">The Office of the Comptroller of the Currency, the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation, the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System, or any successor to these agencies; or</section><section prefix="(2)">An agency of another state with primary responsibility for chartering and supervising banks.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Branch" means a bank office open to the public at which deposits are received, checks are paid, or money is lent.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Branch" includes a mobile branch or other special-purpose facility that performs a function of a branch.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Branch" does not include an automated teller machine as defined in &#xA7; 1-401 of this article.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">"Commercial activities" means activities in which a bank holding company, a financial holding company, a national bank, or a national bank financial subsidiary may not engage under federal law.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">"De novo branch" means a branch of an out-of-state bank or banking institution that:<section prefix="(1)">Is originally established by the out-of-state bank or banking institution as a branch; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Does not become a branch of the out-of-state bank or banking institution as a result of:<section prefix="(i)">The acquisition by the out-of-state bank or banking institution of an insured depository institution or a branch of an insured depository institution; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">The conversion, merger, or consolidation of an insured depository institution or a branch of an insured depository institution.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(h)">"Home state" means:<section prefix="(1)">As to a national banking association, the state in which its main office is located; and</section><section prefix="(2)">As to a state-chartered bank, the state by which it is chartered.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(i)">"Home state regulator" means the agency in a bank's home state with primary responsibility for chartering and regulating banks.</section>
    <section prefix="(j)">"Host state" means a state, other than the home state of a bank, in which the bank maintains or seeks to establish a branch.</section>
    <section prefix="(k)">"Insured depository institution" means any financial institution the deposits of which are insured by the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation.</section>
    <section prefix="(l)">"National banking association" means a bank chartered under the National Bank Act.</section>
    <section prefix="(m)">"Other-state bank" means a bank chartered and primarily regulated by another state.</section>
    <section prefix="(n)">"Out-of-state bank" means:<section prefix="(1)">A national banking association with its main office in a state other than this State; or</section><section prefix="(2)">An other-state bank.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
