<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gfi" order_by="gfi" level="1">Financial Institutions</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gfi-11-619</section_number>
  <catch_line>Each mortgage loan originator shall be covered by a surety bond in accordance with this section....</catch_line>
  <order_by>619</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Each mortgage loan originator shall be covered by a surety bond in accordance with this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A mortgage loan originator who is an employee of a person subject to licensure under Subtitle 5 of this title may use the surety bond of that person to meet the mortgage loan originator's surety bond requirement.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A mortgage loan originator who is an employee of a person exempt from licensure under Subtitle 5 of this title may use a surety bond of the person to meet the mortgage loan originator's surety bond requirement, provided the surety bond meets the requirements, based on mortgage loan volume, under &#xA7; 11-508 of this title.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A licensee who is an affiliated insurance producer-mortgage loan originator shall be deemed in compliance with this section if the licensee:<section prefix="(1)">Holds a surety bond that would satisfy the surety bond requirements under &#xA7; 11-508 of this title if the affiliated insurance producer-mortgage loan originator were a licensee under Subtitle 5 of this title; or</section><section prefix="(2)">Is covered under a blanket surety bond held by the financial institution or mortgage lender licensee identified in &#xA7; 11-603.1(a)(3) of this subtitle if the blanket surety bond:<section prefix="(i)">Covers all affiliated insurance producer-mortgage loan originators; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Is in the amount of $1,000,000 or another amount as required by the Commissioner by regulation.</section></section></section>
  </text>
</law>
