<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gfi" order_by="" level="1">Financial Institutions</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gfi-3-312</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>312</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">If the Commissioner approves, a commercial bank may issue and sell debt instruments that are repayable on the terms and bear the rate of interest, if any, stated in the instruments.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The issuance of a debt instrument does not impair the capital stock of a commercial bank if the amount of the debt instrument is represented by cash or sound assets that exceed the impairment determined by the Commissioner.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The holder of a debt instrument is not subject to any liability imposed on stockholders under any law of this State.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">In the event of liquidation, a debt instrument is:<section prefix="(1)">Subordinate to the claims of any depositor or creditor; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Preferred to the claim of any stockholder.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Each holder of a debt instrument has the voting rights that the charter provides and the Commissioner approves.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A reference in this article to a required vote of the holders of the capital stock of a commercial bank includes holders of debt instruments to the extent that they are entitled to vote under this subsection.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">Before a commercial bank retires or pays any debt instrument:<section prefix="(1)">It shall obtain the approval of the Commissioner; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Any existing deficit in its capital, disregarding any debt instrument to be retired, shall be paid in cash so that the sound capital assets of the commercial bank are at least equal to its capital stock.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
