<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gfi" order_by="gfi" level="1">Financial Institutions</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gfi-9-612</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this section, "savings and loan association" means a savings and loan association organized under...</catch_line>
  <order_by>612</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, "savings and loan association" means a savings and loan association organized under this title as a mutual association.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Notwithstanding any other provision of this title, the Division Director may approve the voluntary conversion of a savings and loan association to a capital stock association and the sale of the association's newly issued capital stock to a third party or parties in a transaction in which the association members have no rights of approval or participation and no rights to the continuance of any legal or beneficial ownership interest in the converted association if the circumstances of the conversion and sale would, under federal law, permit the Federal Home Loan Bank Board to authorize a voluntary supervisory stock conversion.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Division Director may approve a voluntary supervisory stock conversion only if:<section prefix="(1)">The Division Director determines that:<section prefix="(i)">The Division Director would have grounds to seek the appointment of a conservator or receiver under this title;</section><section prefix="(ii)">No equity value would be realized by the savings and loan association's mutual account holders after liquidation of the association;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Severe financial conditions exist that threaten the financial stability of the savings and loan association;</section><section prefix="(iv)">The conversion to a capital stock form is likely to improve the financial condition of the savings and loan association;</section><section prefix="(v)">The association will be viable after the conversion; and</section><section prefix="(vi)">The approval of the conversion is not detrimental to the public interest; and</section></section><section prefix="(2)">The approval imposes the same conditions that federal law requires or permits.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Division Director may adopt rules and regulations for a voluntary supervisory stock conversion, including:<section prefix="(i)">Procedures for application and approval; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Conditions for approval of the Division Director in the final order.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Division Director may approve the chartering of a capital stock corporation to acquire the assets of, or merge with, a mutual association under this section.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">A conversion under this section is not subject to the requirements contained in the following sections of this title:<section prefix="(1)">&#xA7;&#xA7; 9-206 through 9-208, inclusive;</section><section prefix="(2)">&#xA7;&#xA7; 9-216 through 9-222, inclusive;</section><section prefix="(3)">&#xA7;&#xA7; 9-601 through 9-609, inclusive; and</section><section prefix="(4)">&#xA7;&#xA7; 9-627 through 9-630, inclusive.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
