<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gfi" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="6-307" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gfi-6-307</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The incorporators shall:<section prefix="(1)">File with the Commissioner for examination three copies of the articles of incorporation and two copies of the bylaws; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Pay to the Commissioner a fee of $500.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Commissioner shall investigate and determine if:<section prefix="(1)">The articles and bylaws are framed in accordance with law and are reasonable;</section><section prefix="(2)">The character, responsibility, and general fitness of the incorporators command confidence and warrant belief that the business of the proposed credit union will be conducted honestly and efficiently, in accordance with the intent of this title; and</section><section prefix="(3)">Allowing the proposed credit union to engage in business:<section prefix="(i)">Will promote public convenience and advantage; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Is expedient and desirable.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">After the investigation, the Commissioner may require any change in the articles of incorporation or bylaws that the Commissioner considers necessary.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Unless the Commissioner notifies the applicant that a different time period is necessary, within 120 days after the articles and bylaws are filed, the Commissioner shall sign, date, and endorse each copy of the articles and bylaws as "approved" or "refused".</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If formation of the credit union is refused, the Commissioner shall notify the incorporators in writing of the reason for the refusal.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">If formation of the credit union is approved, the Commissioner shall:<section prefix="(i)">Return to the incorporators two of the endorsed copies of the articles and one of the endorsed copies of the bylaws; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Keep one of the endorsed copies of the articles and the bylaws.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
