<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gfi" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="9-1105" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gfi-9-1105</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">To convert to a credit union, the mutual association shall deliver to the Commissioner:<section prefix="(1)">A written application for conversion in the form that the Department of Labor, Licensing, and Regulation requires;</section><section prefix="(2)">Any additional exhibits the Department may require;</section><section prefix="(3)">Any filing fee set by the Department by regulation; and</section><section prefix="(4)">Its proposed amended articles and bylaws.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Upon receipt of an application to convert, the Commissioner shall examine the mutual association.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The examination shall include, but not be limited to, the following:<section prefix="(1)">The financial history and condition of the mutual association including:<section prefix="(i)">The identification of overvalued assets, undisclosed nonperforming loans, and understated liabilities;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The identification of assets that may become nonperforming assets upon conversion;</section><section prefix="(iii)">The identification of loans in default and loans past due over 60 days;</section><section prefix="(iv)">Review of material litigation affecting the mutual association, and the identification of significant judgments, orders or decrees affecting its financial status; and</section><section prefix="(v)">Review of mortgage contracts, participating loans, and other commitments.</section></section><section prefix="(2)">The management of the association.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">As a condition of approval of an application of conversion, the Commissioner may require a mutual association to have its books and records audited and certified under &#xA7; 9-502 of this title.</section>
  </text>
</law>
