<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gfi" order_by="gfi" level="1">Financial Institutions</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gfi-8-307</section_number>
  <catch_line>The Division Director shall devote full time to the duties of the office....</catch_line>
  <order_by>307</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Division Director shall devote full time to the duties of the office.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Division Director and staff may not be officers, directors, employees, auditors, agents of, or attorneys for, nor retained in any manner by, nor have any ownership interest or deposit whatsoever in, any savings and loan association or related entity.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Division Director, Division staff, and members of the immediate families of the Division Director and Division staff, as defined in &#xA7; 15-102 of the State Government Article may not accept, directly or indirectly, any gift, gratuity, or remuneration of any type from any savings and loan association or related entity or from any director, officer, controlling person, employee, or agent of any savings and loan association or related entity.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Division Director, Division staff, and members of the immediate families of the Division Director and Division staff as defined in &#xA7; 15-102 of the State Government Article may not become indebted to any association or related entity that is subject to the jurisdiction of the Division Director.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Any person who violates any provision of this section is subject to forfeiture of that person's office or employment in addition to any other penalty prescribed by law.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Subject to paragraph (2) of this subsection, nothing in this section may be construed to affect any contractual obligation, including a savings account, in existence before January 15, 1986.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">All contractual obligations, including savings accounts, in existence before January 15, 1986, and the corresponding dollar amounts shall be fully disclosed to the Secretary of Labor, Licensing, and Regulation.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The Secretary of Labor, Licensing, and Regulation shall file each disclosure with the State Ethics Commission.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">For a period of 2 years after termination of employment with the Division of Savings and Loan Associations, if the Division Director or former deputy division director is employed by a Maryland savings and loan association or becomes a director, officer, attorney, or agent of a Maryland savings and loan association, that individual may not:<section prefix="(1)">Represent, formally or informally, the association in any judicial, administrative, or other proceeding in which:<section prefix="(i)">The Division of Savings and Loan Associations is a party; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">The former Division Director or former deputy division director substantially participated;</section></section><section prefix="(2)">Participate in any application submitted to the Division for the Division's approval; or</section><section prefix="(3)">Attempt to influence, or make any oral or written communication, on behalf of the association in any matter before the Division relating to the association in which the individual participated personally and substantially as Division Director or former deputy division director.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
