<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gfi" order_by="gfi" level="1">Financial Institutions</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gfi-9-309</section_number>
  <catch_line>A savings and loan association may not establish or relocate any branch office or relocate a princip...</catch_line>
  <order_by>309</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">A savings and loan association may not establish or relocate any branch office or relocate a principal office unless the Division Director approves its application to do so.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">An application for the establishment or relocation of a branch office or relocation of a principal office shall include:<section prefix="(1)">An application fee of $500 unless the application is for relocation within a one-half mile radius of the existing site; and</section><section prefix="(2)">A statement of:<section prefix="(i)">The need for the establishment or relocation;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The address of the proposed location;</section><section prefix="(iii)">The services to be provided;</section><section prefix="(iv)">The estimated annual expense; and</section><section prefix="(v)">The source of payment for the annual expense.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Division Director shall publish notice of the filing of an application under this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The notice shall state:<section prefix="(i)">The scheduled date, place, and time of a public hearing at least 30 days and not more than 90 days after the filing;</section><section prefix="(ii)">That written protests to the application may be made by any savings and loan association located in the area where a savings and loan office is proposed, and that protests shall be received by the Division Director no later than 10 days before the scheduled hearing; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">That the hearing may be canceled if no written protest is received within the time provided in the notice.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The notice shall be published:<section prefix="(i)">At least once each week for 2 successive weeks at the expense of the applicant in a newspaper of general circulation in the political subdivision where the proposed office is to be located;</section><section prefix="(ii)">In the Maryland Register, as provided in the State Documents Law; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">As the Division Director considers otherwise desirable.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">As provided in this section:<section prefix="(1)">Any savings and loan association located in the area where a proposed branch office of a savings and loan association is to be located or a principal office is proposed to be relocated may protest the requested approval of the Division Director; and</section><section prefix="(2)">The Division Director shall give any savings and loan association that protests under paragraph (1) of this subsection an opportunity to be heard.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">Not later than 30 days after the conclusion of the hearing or, if a hearing is not held, after the scheduled hearing date, the Division Director shall approve an application under this section if the Director finds that:<section prefix="(1)">The public interest will be promoted; and</section><section prefix="(2)">The office will be operated efficiently and in accordance with this title.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The Division Director may not approve a new office or location for any savings and loan association that is not in compliance with Title 8 of this article and this title or any other law or regulation of this State relating to savings and loan associations.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">Any applicant may appeal any action or nonaction of the Division Director to the Circuit Court for Baltimore City.</section>
  </text>
</law>
