<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gfi" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="1-205" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gfi-1-205</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Depository institution" means a State-chartered or federally chartered financial institution located in this State that is authorized to maintain deposit or share accounts.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Compliance review committee" means:<section prefix="(i)">An audit, loan review, or compliance committee appointed by the board of directors of a depository institution; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">Any other person to the extent the person acts in an investigatory capacity at the direction of a compliance review committee.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">"Compliance review documents" means documents prepared for or created by a compliance review committee.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">"Loan review committee" means a person or group of persons who, on behalf of a depository institution, reviews loans held by the institution for the purpose of assessing the credit quality of the loans, compliance with the institution's loan policies, and compliance with applicable laws and regulations.</section>
      <section prefix="(6)">"Person" means an individual, group of individuals, board, committee, partnership, firm, association, corporation, or other entity.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">This section applies to a compliance review committee whose functions are to evaluate and seek to improve:<section prefix="(1)">Loan underwriting standards;</section><section prefix="(2)">Asset quality;</section><section prefix="(3)">Financial reporting to federal or State regulatory agencies; or</section><section prefix="(4)">Compliance with federal or State statutory or regulatory requirements.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Except as provided in subsection (d) of this section:<section prefix="(1)">Compliance review documents are confidential and are not discoverable or admissible in evidence in any civil action arising out of matters evaluated by the compliance review committee; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Compliance review documents delivered to a federal or State governmental agency remain confidential and are not discoverable or admissible in evidence in any civil action arising out of matters evaluated by the compliance review committee.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Subsection (c) of this section does not apply to any information required by statute or regulation to be maintained by or provided to a governmental agency while the information is in the possession of the governmental agency to the extent applicable law expressly authorizes its disclosure.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">This section may not be construed to limit the discovery or admissibility in any civil action of any documents that are not compliance review documents.</section>
  </text>
</law>
