<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gfi" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="6-909" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gfi-6-909</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Except as otherwise provided in this article, the Commissioner and the employees of and the attorney for the Commissioner's office may not disclose:<section prefix="(1)">The name of any debtor of a credit union;</section><section prefix="(2)">Any information about the private accounts with or transactions of a credit union;</section><section prefix="(3)">Any information obtained in the course of examining a credit union; or</section><section prefix="(4)">Any confidential information obtained from a credit union authority.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">This section does not apply to any information that a person discloses:<section prefix="(1)">In performing a public duty to report on or take special action about the business of a credit union;</section><section prefix="(2)">In testifying as a witness in a criminal proceeding; or</section><section prefix="(3)">In informing any official, officer, employee, or agent of a credit union under examination of the results of that examination.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Commissioner may give a credit union share guaranty corporation information about a credit union if:<section prefix="(i)">The credit union is insured by the credit union share guaranty corporation; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">The credit union:</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Commissioner may give the National Credit Union Administration Share Insurance Program information about a credit union if:<section prefix="(i)">The credit union is insured by the National Credit Union Administration Share Insurance Program; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">The credit union:</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Except as otherwise provided by law, all confidential information disclosed to any person as permitted under this section:<section prefix="(1)">Remains the property of the Commissioner; and</section><section prefix="(2)">May not be further disclosed by that person without the written permission of the Commissioner.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">A person that violates any provision of this section is guilty of a misdemeanor and on conviction is subject to:<section prefix="(1)">Forfeiture of the person's office or employment; and</section><section prefix="(2)">A fine not exceeding $1,000 or imprisonment not exceeding 2 years or both.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
