<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gfi" order_by="gfi" level="1">Financial Institutions</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gfi-1-204</section_number>
  <catch_line>A provision in an account agreement for a transfer on death in compliance with this section is nonte...</catch_line>
  <order_by>204</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">A provision in an account agreement for a transfer on death in compliance with this section is nontestamentary and shall be effective according to the provisions of this section. Transfers pursuant to this section are effective in the form and manner prescribed by this section and are not to be considered testamentary.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">"Account" means any type of deposit or share account at a depository institution.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">"Account" includes:<section prefix="1.">Checking and other demand deposit accounts;</section><section prefix="2.">Negotiable order of withdrawal and other savings accounts;</section><section prefix="3.">Share draft accounts; and</section><section prefix="4.">Certificated and uncertificated time deposit accounts.</section></section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Account agreement" means a written agreement, whether in 1 or more instruments, that establishes the type of account, the terms of account, and the relationship between the depository institution and the party or parties to the account.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">"Beneficiary" means any person designated on a trust account as a person:<section prefix="(i)">To whom the account belongs after the death of all trustees for the account; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Who does not possess a present right to draw upon funds in the account during the lifetime of any trustee for the account.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(5)">"Convenience person" means any person who is authorized to draw upon funds in an account:<section prefix="(i)">Under a power of attorney given by 1 or more parties to the account; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">By virtue of a designation in the account agreement appointing that person as agent of a party or the parties to the account for the convenience of the party or parties.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(6)">"Depository institution" means any State-chartered or federally chartered financial institution, other-state bank, or foreign bank that:<section prefix="(i)">Is located in this State or maintains a branch in this State; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Is authorized to maintain accounts.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(7)">"Joint account" means any account other than a P.O.D. account or a trust account established in the name of 2 or more parties.</section>
      <section prefix="(8)">
        <section prefix="(i)">"Multiple-party account" means any of the following types of accounts at a depository institution:<section prefix="1.">Joint account;</section><section prefix="2.">P.O.D. account; or</section><section prefix="3.">Trust account.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">"Multiple-party account" does not include any:<section prefix="1.">Account established and designated for the deposit of funds of a corporation, partnership, joint venture, limited liability company, or other association of persons for business purposes;</section><section prefix="2.">Account established and designated for the deposit of funds of a charitable or civic organization;</section><section prefix="3.">Fiduciary account where the relationship is established other than by the account agreement;</section><section prefix="4.">Account established and designated as governed under the Maryland Uniform Transfers to Minors Act;</section><section prefix="5.">Account established and designated as governed under Title 13, Subtitle 4 of the Estates and Trusts Article; or</section><section prefix="6.">Account that would not be a multiple-party account except for the fact that 1 or more convenience persons are authorized to draw upon funds in the account.</section></section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(9)">
        <section prefix="(i)">"Party" means any person who, by the terms of the account agreement, possesses a present right to draw upon funds in a multiple-party account.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">"Party" includes a trustee of a trust account.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">"Party" does not include a:<section prefix="1.">Beneficiary of a trust account;</section><section prefix="2.">P.O.D. payee of a P.O.D. account; or</section><section prefix="3.">Convenience person.</section></section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(10)">"P.O.D. account" means any account established in the name of 1 or more parties where funds in the account may be drawn upon:<section prefix="(i)">By 1 party during the party's lifetime and by 1 or more P.O.D. payees on the party's death; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">By 1 or more parties during their respective lifetimes and, upon the death of all the parties, by 1 or more P.O.D. payees.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(11)">"P.O.D. payee" means any person designated on a P.O.D. account as a person:<section prefix="(i)">To whom the account belongs after the death of all parties to the account; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Who does not possess a present right to draw upon funds in the account during the lifetime of any party to the account.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(12)">
        <section prefix="(i)">"Power of attorney" means any writing signed by 1 or more parties to an account that authorizes 1 or more persons to draw upon funds in the account as agent or agents for the signing party or parties.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The designation of a person as a convenience person on an account shall be deemed to be a durable power of attorney appointing that person as agent for the party or parties to the account regardless of any disability of the party or parties subsequent to the designation.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(13)">
        <section prefix="(i)">"Trust account" means any account established in the name of 1 or more parties as trustees for 1 or more beneficiaries where:<section prefix="1.">None of the beneficiaries is also a trustee;</section><section prefix="2.">The trust relationship is established by the account agreement; and</section><section prefix="3.">There is no corpus of the trust other than the funds in the account.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">"Trust account" does not include a:<section prefix="1.">Trust account under a testamentary trust, declaration of trust, or a trust agreement that has significance apart from the account; or</section><section prefix="2.">Fiduciary account arising from a fiduciary relationship.</section></section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A depository institution is authorized to establish multiple-party accounts subject to the terms of this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Multiple-party accounts established on or after October 1, 1993, shall be subject to and comply with the terms of this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A multiple-party account established before October 1, 1993, shall be subject to and comply with the terms of this section if:<section prefix="(i)">The parties expressly state in an account agreement that complies with subsection (e) of this section that the account shall be subject to the terms of this section; or</section><section prefix="(ii)"><section prefix="1.">The depository institution gives a written notice that:</section><section prefix="2.">After that notice is given, any party to the account:</section></section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Upon the death of a party to a multiple-party account, the right to any funds in the account shall be determined in accordance with the express terms of the account agreement.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If the account agreement does not expressly establish the right to funds in the account upon the death of a party, or if there is no account agreement, any funds in the account upon the death of a party shall belong to the surviving party or parties.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Unless the account agreement expressly provides otherwise, upon the death of the last party to a multiple-party account, any funds remaining in the account shall belong to:<section prefix="(i)">The beneficiaries of a trust account who are then living;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The P.O.D. payees of a P.O.D. account who are then living; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">Subject to paragraph (4) of this subsection, the personal representative of:<section prefix="1.">The last surviving party of a trust account if no beneficiary is then living;</section><section prefix="2.">The last surviving party of a P.O.D. account if no P.O.D. payee is then living; or</section><section prefix="3.">The last surviving party of a joint account.</section></section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">No payment from a multiple-party account may be made to the personal representative of a deceased party unless:<section prefix="(i)">Proof is presented to the depository institution showing that the deceased party was the last surviving party; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">There is no right of survivorship under this section.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(5)">If there is no right of survivorship under this section, the depository institution may make payment from a multiple-party account to the personal representative of a deceased party without liability to:<section prefix="(i)">Any other party; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">Any party's heirs, personal representatives, or assigns.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(6)">No funds in an account shall belong to any convenience person by reason of that capacity.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Each account agreement for a multiple-party account opened on or after October 1, 1993, shall contain a clear and conspicuous written statement specifying that unless contrary direction is given in the account agreement, upon the death of a party, the funds in the multiple-party account shall belong to the surviving party or parties.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">For multiple-party accounts opened on or after October 1, 1993, the depository institution shall give to the account party or parties:<section prefix="(i)">A copy of the account agreement; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">A written notice identifying the type of account, the survivorship rights of the parties to the account, and the method by which the account party or parties can obtain a copy of the account agreement.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">Unless the account agreement expressly provides otherwise, the funds in a multiple-party account may be withdrawn by any party or by a convenience person for any party or parties, whether or not any other party to the account is incapacitated or deceased.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">A depository institution may presume that an account established by the parties as a trust account complies with the definitional requirements of a trust account as set forth in subsection (b) of this section unless, prior to the establishment of the account, the depository institution is provided with written notice to the contrary.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">Any written materials required by this section to be given to account parties:<section prefix="(1)">Shall be deemed given if:<section prefix="(i)">Delivered in person to any one of the account parties; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">Mailed to the account party or parties by first-class mail, postage prepaid, to the address for the account shown on the records of the depository institution; and</section></section><section prefix="(2)">May be provided along with or as part of other materials given to account parties.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(i)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A person who has an ownership interest in an account that is not a multiple-party account may designate another person as a convenience person on that account.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">No funds in the account shall belong to any convenience person by reason of that capacity.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
