<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gfi" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="6-705" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gfi-6-705</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The assets of a credit union that are not committed for loans may be invested in:<section prefix="(1)">General obligations of or obligations guaranteed by the United States;</section><section prefix="(2)">Deposits, loans, shares, or stock of any federal reserve bank, federal home loan bank, or any central liquidity facility established under state or federal law;</section><section prefix="(3)">Securities, obligations, or other instruments of or issued by or fully guaranteed as to principal and interest by the federal government or a unit of the federal government;</section><section prefix="(4)">General obligations of a state or a federal territory or political subdivision, provided that the general obligation is rated in one of the three highest rating categories of a nationally recognized statistical rating organization as determined by the Commissioner;</section><section prefix="(5)">Deposits or federal funds of any financial institution that has federal deposit insurance;</section><section prefix="(6)">Shares or deposits of other credit unions;</section><section prefix="(7)">Mutual funds that invest solely in investments permissible for direct investment by the credit union;</section><section prefix="(8)">Repurchase transactions secured by investments permissible for direct investment by the credit union; or</section><section prefix="(9)">Any other investment that the Commissioner approves.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Subject to the provisions of paragraph (2) of this subsection, in addition to the investments authorized under subsection (a) of this section, a credit union may request authority from the Commissioner to make other investments, including investments authorized under the federal Credit Union Act or regulations of the National Credit Union Administration, on an ongoing basis.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">To obtain the Commissioner's approval for additional investment authority under paragraph (1) of this subsection, a credit union shall submit to the Commissioner an investment policy.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Commissioner may review the investment policies of the credit union and order changes.</section>
  </text>
</law>
