<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gfi" order_by="gfi" level="1">Financial Institutions</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gfi-13-1104</section_number>
  <catch_line>The Authority consists of:...</catch_line>
  <order_by>1104</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Authority consists of:<section prefix="(1)">The Secretary of Housing and Community Development;</section><section prefix="(2)">The Secretary of Business and Economic Development;</section><section prefix="(3)">The Secretary of Higher Education;</section><section prefix="(4)">The Secretary of Transportation;</section><section prefix="(5)">The Secretary of Natural Resources;</section><section prefix="(6)">The Secretary of the Department of Planning;</section><section prefix="(7)">The State Historic Preservation Officer; and</section><section prefix="(8)">Ten members appointed by the Governor with the advice and consent of the Senate:<section prefix="(i)">Two of whom shall be elected officials or representatives of local jurisdictions;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Two of whom shall be appointed from names recommended by the President of the Maryland Senate;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Two of whom shall be appointed from names recommended by the Speaker of the House of Delegates;</section><section prefix="(iv)">One of whom is a public member of the Maryland Greenways Commission;</section><section prefix="(v)">One of whom is a public member of the Maryland Tourism Development Board;</section><section prefix="(vi)">One of whom is a member of the public who has significant education or experience in historic preservation; and</section><section prefix="(vii)">One of whom is a member of the public who has significant education or experience in heritage tourism.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Of the elected officials or representatives from local jurisdictions, the Governor shall appoint:<section prefix="(1)">One elected official or representative from a list submitted by the Maryland Association of Counties; and</section><section prefix="(2)">One elected official or representative from a list submitted by the Maryland Municipal League.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The members appointed to the Authority shall represent the gender, racial, and geographic makeup of the State.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A member of the Authority may not also be a member of the board of directors or any other type of governing or oversight body of an organization qualifying for State funds as a recognized or certified heritage area.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">A cabinet member of the Authority may designate a representative to act in the absence of the cabinet member.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except for State officials, the term of a member of the Authority is 4 years.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The terms of members appointed by the Governor are staggered as required by the terms provided for members on October 1, 1996.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">At the end of a term, a member continues to serve until a successor is appointed and qualifies.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">A member who is appointed after a term has begun serves only for the rest of the term and until a successor is appointed and qualifies.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">At the end of the term of a member or on the resignation or removal of a member, the Governor shall appoint a member to the Authority with the advice and consent of the Senate.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">The Secretary of Planning shall serve as chair of the Authority.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">The Governor may remove a member that a Governor appointed for incompetence, misconduct, or failure to perform the duties of the position.</section>
  </text>
</law>
