<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gfi" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="12-1010" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gfi-12-1010</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>// EFFECTIVE UNTIL JUNE 30, 2015 PER CHAPTERS 280 AND 281 OF 2011 //<section prefix="(a)">Except as allowed under this subtitle, a registrant may not offer, provide, or attempt to provide debt settlement services in the State.</section><section prefix="(b)"><section prefix="(1)">A registrant may charge a consumer a debt settlement services fee as provided under this section.</section><section prefix="(2)">A registrant may not:<section prefix="(i)">Charge a consumer a fee for consultation or for obtaining a consumer's credit report; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">Require a voluntary contribution from a consumer for any service provided by the registrant.</section></section></section><section prefix="(c)">Except as provided under subsection (d) of this section, a registrant may not charge a consumer a debt settlement services fee until after:<section prefix="(1)">A debt settlement services agreement has been executed between the registrant and the consumer;</section><section prefix="(2)">The registrant has renegotiated, settled, reduced, or otherwise altered the terms of at least one individual debt specified in the debt settlement services agreement; and</section><section prefix="(3)">The consumer has made at least one payment in accordance with the debt settlement services agreement.</section></section><section prefix="(d)">Subsection (c) of this section does not prohibit a registrant from requesting or requiring a consumer to deposit funds in an account to be used for debt settlement services fees and for payments to creditors or debt collectors in connection with a debt settlement services agreement, provided that:<section prefix="(1)">The funds are held in an account at an insured financial institution, as defined in &#xA7; 1-101 of this article;</section><section prefix="(2)">The consumer owns the funds held in the account, including any accrued interest;</section><section prefix="(3)">The financial institution or entity administering the account is not owned or controlled by, or in any way affiliated with, the registrant;</section><section prefix="(4)">The financial institution or entity administering the account does not pay or accept any money or other compensation in exchange for referrals of business involving the registrant, but may charge account related fees; and</section><section prefix="(5)">If the consumer requests to withdraw from the debt settlement services agreement, within 7 days after the consumer's request, all funds in the account, including accrued interest, less any debt settlement services fees earned by the registrant in compliance with this section, are paid to the consumer.</section></section><section prefix="(e)"><section prefix="(1)">Subject to paragraph (2) of this subsection, for each individual debt, a debt settlement services fee shall:<section prefix="(i)">Bear the same proportional relationship to the debt settlement services fee for settling the total debt as the individual debt amount bears to the total debt; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">Be calculated as a percentage of the amount by which the principal amount of the debt exceeds the amount paid to the creditor or debt collector to settle the debt.</section></section><section prefix="(2)">The percentage charged under paragraph (1)(ii) of this subsection shall be the same for each individual debt.</section></section><section prefix="(f)"><section prefix="(1)">A registrant shall allow a consumer to withdraw from a debt settlement services agreement at any time.</section><section prefix="(2)">If a consumer withdraws from the debt settlement services agreement, the registrant:<section prefix="(i)">May not charge the consumer a penalty; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">May collect debt settlement services fees earned by the registrant in compliance with this section.</section></section></section></text>
</law>
