<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gfi" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="12-1012" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gfi-12-1012</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>// EFFECTIVE UNTIL JUNE 30, 2015 PER CHAPTERS 280 AND 281 OF 2011 //<section prefix="(a)">A debt settlement services agreement shall:<section prefix="(1)">Be signed and dated by the registrant and the consumer; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Include, in at least 12 point type:<section prefix="(i)">The name, address, and telephone number of the consumer;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The name, address, and telephone number of the registrant;</section><section prefix="(iii)">A description of the debt settlement services to be provided to the consumer;</section><section prefix="(iv)"/><section prefix="(v)">The identity of each individual creditor or debt collector whose debts are included in the debt settlement services agreement and the principal amount of the debt owed to each individual creditor or debt collector;</section><section prefix="(vi)">The principal amount of the total debt included in the debt settlement services agreement;</section><section prefix="(vii)">A good faith estimate of the amount of time necessary to achieve the represented results;</section><section prefix="(viii)">To the extent that the debt settlement services may include a debt settlement offer to any of the consumer's creditors or debt collectors, a good faith estimate of:</section><section prefix="(ix)">A statement that:</section><section prefix="(x)">If the registrant requests or requires the consumer to deposit funds in a dedicated account, a statement that:</section><section prefix="(xi)">A statement that the consumer may be required to pay taxes on the amount by which the consumer's debt is reduced.</section></section></section><section prefix="(b)">The disclosures required under subsection (a)(2)(vii) through (xi) of this section shall be provided to the consumer in a clear and conspicuous manner in the debt settlement services agreement.</section></text>
</law>
