<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gfi" order_by="" level="1">Financial Institutions</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gfi-5-503</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>503</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">A banking institution may buy and hold real property only as provided in this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Subject to the limitations in paragraph (3) of this subsection, a banking institution may buy or hold any real property that is necessary for the convenient transaction of its business.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">In addition to its offices, this property may include:<section prefix="(i)">A parking lot that the banking institution provides, with or without charge, primarily for the use of its customers; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Any rental space that is located in the bank building or on adjoining land.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Except as provided in paragraph (4) of this subsection, a banking institution may not invest in its bank building and furnishings more than an amount that equals 50 percent of its unimpaired capital and surplus or guaranty fund.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">If a banking institution is rated CAMELS 1 or 2 and remains well capitalized in accordance with the requirements of the Federal Deposit Insurance Act, it may invest in its bank building and furnishings an amount equivalent to 75 percent of its:<section prefix="(i)">Unimpaired capital, surplus, and undivided profits; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">Guaranty fund and undivided profits.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Subject to the limitations in paragraphs (2) and (3) of this subsection, a banking institution may hold any real property that the banking institution acquires:<section prefix="(i)">In satisfaction of a debt contracted in the course of its business; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">At sale on a judgment, decree, or mortgage foreclosure under a security that it holds.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">At a sale, a banking institution may not bid more than the amount of money that is necessary to satisfy the secured debts and costs.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A banking institution:<section prefix="(i)">May not hold property acquired under this subsection for more than:<section prefix="1.">8 years; and</section><section prefix="2.">Under conditions that the Commissioner sets, 2 additional years; and</section></section><section prefix="(ii)">Within 1 year after that period, shall:<section prefix="1.">Sell the property; or</section><section prefix="2.">Reduce the value of the property on its books to a value that the Commissioner approves.</section></section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
