<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gfi" order_by="" level="1">Financial Institutions</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gfi-6-703</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>703</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, "risk assets" means a credit union's total loans outstanding to its members.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Each credit union shall have a reserve fund to meet losses on loans and to meet other contingencies that the Commissioner specifies.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The reserve fund may be distributed to the members of the credit union only on dissolution of the credit union.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">After paying organization expenses, each credit union shall credit to its reserve fund all entrance fees, transfer fees, and fines.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A credit union in operation for 4 years or more and having assets of $500,000 or more shall credit to the reserve fund, at the end of each accounting period:<section prefix="(i)">10 percent of its gross income until the reserve fund equals 4 percent of its risk assets; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Then, 5 percent of its gross income until the reserve fund equals 6 percent of its risk assets.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A credit union in operation for less than 4 years or having assets of less than $500,000 shall credit to the reserve fund, at the end of each accounting period:<section prefix="(i)">10 percent of its gross income until the reserve fund equals 7.5 percent of its risk assets; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Then, 5 percent of its gross income until the reserve fund equals 10 percent of its risk assets.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">On recommendation of the board, the amount credited to the reserve fund may be increased.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">If the reserve fund falls below the amounts required by subsection (c)(2) or (3) of this section, it shall be restored by regular contributions.</section>
  </text>
</law>
