<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gfi" order_by="gfi" level="1">Financial Institutions</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gfi-5-901</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated....</catch_line>
  <order_by>901</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Acquire" means:<section prefix="(1)">For one bank holding company to merge or consolidate with another bank holding company;</section><section prefix="(2)">For a bank holding company to assume direct or indirect ownership or control of:<section prefix="(i)">More than 5 percent of any class of voting shares of another bank holding company or a bank; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">All or substantially all of the assets of another bank holding company or a bank; or</section></section><section prefix="(3)">To take any other action that results in the direct or indirect control by a bank holding company of another bank holding company or a bank.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Affiliate" has the meaning stated in &#xA7; 5-401 of this title.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">"Bank" has the meaning stated in &#xA7; 2(c) of the Bank Holding Company Act.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"Bank holding company":<section prefix="(1)">Has the meaning stated in &#xA7; 2(a) of the Bank Holding Company Act; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Unless the context requires otherwise, includes:<section prefix="(i)">A Maryland bank holding company;</section><section prefix="(ii)">An out-of-state bank holding company;</section><section prefix="(iii)">A foreign bank holding company; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">A corporation or other entity that becomes a bank holding company by making an acquisition under this subtitle.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">"Bank Holding Company Act" means the federal Bank Holding Company Act of 1956.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">"Bank supervisory agency" means:<section prefix="(1)">The Office of the Comptroller of the Currency, the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation, the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System, and the Office of Foreign Assets Control, and any successor to these agencies;</section><section prefix="(2)">Any agency of another state with primary responsibility for chartering and supervising banks; and</section><section prefix="(3)">Any agency of a foreign country with primary responsibility for chartering and supervising banks.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(h)">"Control" has the meaning stated in &#xA7; 2(a) of the Bank Holding Company Act.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">"Deposit":<section prefix="(1)">With respect to any bank holding company other than a foreign bank holding company, has the meaning stated in 12 U.S.C. &#xA7; 1813(l); and</section><section prefix="(2)">With respect to a foreign bank holding company, has the meaning stated in the law of the country in which the holding company is organized or incorporated.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(j)">"Foreign bank holding company" means a bank holding company with its principal place of business outside the United States.</section>
    <section prefix="(k)">"Insured depository institution" means any financial institution the deposits of which are insured by the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation.</section>
    <section prefix="(l)">"Maryland bank" means a bank that is:<section prefix="(1)">Organized under Title 3 or Title 4 of this article; or</section><section prefix="(2)">Organized under federal law and having its main office in this State.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(m)">"Maryland bank holding company" means a bank holding company that:<section prefix="(1)">Had its principal place of business in this State on the later of July 1, 1966 or the date on which the company became a bank holding company; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Is not controlled by a bank holding company other than a Maryland bank holding company.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(n)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Out-of-state bank holding company" means a bank holding company that is not a Maryland bank holding company.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Out-of-state bank holding company" includes a foreign bank holding company.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(o)">"Principal place of business" means the jurisdiction in which the total deposits of a bank holding company's bank subsidiaries are the greatest.</section>
    <section prefix="(p)">"State" means any state, territory, or other possession of the United States, including the District of Columbia.</section>
    <section prefix="(q)">"Subsidiary" has the meaning stated in &#xA7; 2(d) of the Bank Holding Company Act.</section>
  </text>
</law>
