<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gfi" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="2-104" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gfi-2-104</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Applicant" means an applicant for employment with the Commissioner.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Central Repository" means the Criminal Justice Information System Central Repository of the Department of Public Safety and Correctional Services.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">"Employee" means a full-time or part-time employee of the Commissioner, including a temporary employee or a contractual employee.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Commissioner may employ a staff in accordance with the State budget.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Commissioner shall apply to the Central Repository for a State and national criminal history records check for each applicant prior to an offer of employment.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Commissioner may apply to the Central Repository for a State and national criminal history records check for an employee.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">As part of the application for a criminal history records check, the Commissioner shall submit to the Central Repository:<section prefix="(1)">Two complete sets of the  legible fingerprints taken on forms approved by the Director of the Central Repository and the Director of the Federal Bureau of Investigation;</section><section prefix="(2)">The fee authorized under &#xA7; 10-221(b)(7) of the Criminal Procedure Article for access to Maryland criminal history records; and</section><section prefix="(3)">The mandatory processing fee required by the Federal Bureau of Investigation for a national criminal history records check.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">In accordance with &#xA7;&#xA7; 10-201 through 10-234 of the Criminal Procedure Article, the Central Repository shall forward to the subject applicant or employee and the Commissioner the applicant's or employee's criminal history record information.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">Information obtained from the Central Repository under this section:<section prefix="(1)">Shall be confidential;</section><section prefix="(2)">May not be redisseminated; and</section><section prefix="(3)">Shall be used only for the employment purpose authorized by this section.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(h)">The subject of a criminal history records check under this section may contest the contents of the printed statement issued by the Central Repository as provided in &#xA7; 10-223 of the Criminal Procedure Article.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">In considering any felony or misdemeanor conviction of an individual as it relates to the individual's qualification for employment with the Commissioner, the Commissioner shall consider:<section prefix="(1)">The nature of the crime;</section><section prefix="(2)">The relevance of the crime to the duties and responsibilities related to employment;</section><section prefix="(3)">The length of time since the conviction; and</section><section prefix="(4)">The behavior and activities of the individual since the conviction.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
