<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gfi" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="11-511" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gfi-11-511</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Subject to any regulations the Commissioner adopts in connection with the transition to the Nationwide Mortgage Licensing System and Registry, an initial license term shall:<section prefix="(1)">Begin on the day the license is issued; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Expire on December 31 of the year:<section prefix="(i)">The license is issued, if the license is issued before November 1; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">Succeeding the year that the license is issued, if the license is issued on or after November 1.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">At least 60 days before its expiration, a license may be renewed if the licensee:<section prefix="(1)">Otherwise is entitled to be licensed;</section><section prefix="(2)">Pays to the Commissioner a nonrefundable renewal fee set by the Commissioner;</section><section prefix="(3)">Files a bond or bond continuation certificate for the amount required under &#xA7; 11-508 of this subtitle; and</section><section prefix="(4)">Submits to the Commissioner:<section prefix="(i)">A renewal application on the form that the Commissioner requires; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Satisfactory evidence of compliance with any continuing education requirements set by regulations adopted by the Commissioner.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Subject to any regulations the Commissioner adopts in connection with the transition to the Nationwide Mortgage Licensing System and Registry, a renewal term shall:<section prefix="(1)">Be for a period of 1 year;</section><section prefix="(2)">Begin on January 1 of each year after the initial term; and</section><section prefix="(3)">Expire on December 31 of the year the renewal term begins.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">In addition to the license renewal fee required under subsection (b)(2) of this section, an applicant for a license renewal shall pay to the Nationwide Mortgage Licensing System and Registry any fees that the Nationwide Mortgage Licensing System and Registry imposes in connection with the renewal application.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">If a license is surrendered voluntarily, or is suspended or revoked, the Commissioner may not refund any part of the license fee regardless of the time remaining in the license term.</section>
  </text>
</law>
