<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gfi" order_by="" level="1">Financial Institutions</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gfi-12-901</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>901</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Annual gross revenue" means income or revenue from all sources, before any expenses or taxes, computed according to generally accepted accounting principles for the preceding fiscal year.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Consultation fee" means a fee paid by a consumer to a debt management services provider in connection with the processing of any application that the consumer makes for debt management services.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">"Consumer" means an individual who:<section prefix="(1)">Resides in the State; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Is seeking debt management services or has entered into a debt management services agreement.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"Consumer education program" means a program or plan that:<section prefix="(1)">Seeks to improve the financial literacy of consumers regarding personal finance, budgeting, and credit and debt management; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Provides counseling tailored to the needs and circumstances of the consumer with regard to options and strategies for addressing the consumer's debt problems, including:<section prefix="(i)">Creating and maintaining a budget;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Establishing debt management payment plans with creditors;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Negotiating directly with creditors on payment or interest rate relief; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">Filing for bankruptcy.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">"Debt management counselor" means a permanent, temporary, or contractual employee of a debt management services provider or its agent who provides counseling to consumers on behalf of the debt management services provider.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">"Debt management services" means receiving funds periodically from a consumer under an agreement with the consumer for the purpose of distributing the funds among the consumer's creditors in full or partial payment of the consumer's debts.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">"Debt management services agreement" means a written contract, plan, or agreement between a debt management services provider and a consumer for the performance of debt management services.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">"Debt management services provider" means a person that provides or offers to provide debt management services to a consumer.</section>
    <section prefix="(j)">"Fund" means the Debt Management Services Fund established under &#xA7; 12-905 of this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(k)">"Licensee" means a person licensed under this subtitle to provide debt management services.</section>
    <section prefix="(l)">"Maintenance fee" means a fee paid by a consumer to a debt management services provider for the maintenance or servicing of the consumer's accounts with the consumer's creditors in accordance with a debt management services agreement.</section>
    <section prefix="(m)">"Relative" means any of the following who are related to an individual by blood, marriage, or adoption:<section prefix="(1)">A spouse;</section><section prefix="(2)">A child;</section><section prefix="(3)">A sibling;</section><section prefix="(4)">A parent;</section><section prefix="(5)">A grandparent;</section><section prefix="(6)">A grandchild;</section><section prefix="(7)">A stepparent;</section><section prefix="(8)">A stepchild;</section><section prefix="(9)">A stepsibling;</section><section prefix="(10)">An aunt; or</section><section prefix="(11)">An uncle.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(n)">"Resident agent" means an individual residing in the State or a Maryland corporation whose name, address, and designation as a resident agent are filed or recorded with the State Department of Assessments and Taxation in accordance with the provisions of the Corporations and Associations Article.</section>
    <section prefix="(o)">"Trust account" means an account that is:<section prefix="(1)">Established in a financial institution that is federally insured;</section><section prefix="(2)">Separate from the debt management services provider's operating account;</section><section prefix="(3)">Designated as a "trust account" or by another appropriate designation indicating that the funds in the account are not the funds of the licensee or its officers, employees, or agents;</section><section prefix="(4)">Unavailable to creditors of the debt management services provider; and</section><section prefix="(5)">Used to hold funds paid by consumers to a debt management services provider for disbursement to creditors of the consumers.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
