<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gfi" order_by="" level="1">Financial Institutions</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gfi-3-702</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>702</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Any bank may, as provided in this subtitle:<section prefix="(1)">Consolidate with one or more other banks to form a new consolidated bank;</section><section prefix="(2)">Merge into another bank or have one or more other banks merged into it; or</section><section prefix="(3)">Transfer its assets to another bank.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">If the successor will be a commercial bank:<section prefix="(1)">The consolidation, merger, or transfer of assets shall be made in accordance with the provisions of this subtitle; and</section><section prefix="(2)">If one of the constituent banks is a national banking association or a federally chartered savings bank or savings and loan association, federal law governs its actions and the rights of its stockholders.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">If the successor will be a national banking association or a federally chartered savings bank or savings and loan association:<section prefix="(1)">Federal law governs:<section prefix="(i)">The actions of a constituent bank;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The rights of its stockholders; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">The effect of the consolidation, merger, or transfer of assets on its rights, franchises, interests, and fiduciary duties; and</section></section><section prefix="(2)">Except for this section and &#xA7; 3-710 of this subtitle, the other provisions of this subtitle do not apply to the consolidation, merger, or transfer of assets.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">If one of the constituent banks is an other-state bank:<section prefix="(1)">Maryland law governs:<section prefix="(i)">The actions of the banking institution;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The rights of its stockholders; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">The effect of the consolidation, merger, or transfer of assets on its rights, franchises, interests, and fiduciary duties; and</section></section><section prefix="(2)">The law of the other state governs:<section prefix="(i)">The actions of the other-state bank;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The rights of its stockholders; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">The effect of the consolidation, merger, or transfer of assets on its rights, franchises, interests, and fiduciary duties.</section></section></section>
  </text>
</law>
