<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gfi" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="7-209" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gfi-7-209</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Commissioner may suspend or revoke the certificate of authority of a credit union share guaranty corporation if the credit union share guaranty corporation or a director or officer of the credit union share guaranty corporation:<section prefix="(1)">Makes a material misstatement in an application for a certificate of authority;</section><section prefix="(2)">Is convicted under the laws of the United States or any state of:<section prefix="(i)">A felony; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">A misdemeanor that is directly related to the activities authorized by the certificate of authority;</section></section><section prefix="(3)">In connection with any credit union share guaranty transaction:<section prefix="(i)">Commits a fraud;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Engages in an illegal or dishonest activity; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">Misrepresents or fails to disclose a material fact to a person entitled to that information;</section></section><section prefix="(4)">Violates any provision of this subtitle, any rule or regulation adopted under this subtitle, or any other law regulating credit union share guaranty business in the State, or fails to comply with an order of the Commissioner;</section><section prefix="(5)">Is found by the Commissioner to be in unsound condition or in a condition that renders further transaction of credit union share guaranty business hazardous to participating credit unions, the members of the participating credit unions, or the public;</section><section prefix="(6)">Refuses or delays payment of amounts due claimants without just cause;</section><section prefix="(7)">Refuses to be examined or to produce records or files for examination by the Commissioner when required;</section><section prefix="(8)">Refuses to provide additional information reasonably requested by the Commissioner; or</section><section prefix="(9)">Otherwise demonstrates unworthiness, bad faith, dishonesty, or any other quality that indicates that the business of the credit union share guaranty corporation has not been or will not be conducted honestly, fairly, and equitably.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">In determining whether the certificate of authority of a credit union share guaranty corporation should be suspended or revoked for a conviction listed in subsection (a)(2) of this section, the Commissioner shall consider:<section prefix="(1)">The nature of the crime;</section><section prefix="(2)">The relationship of the crime to the activities authorized by the certificate of authority;</section><section prefix="(3)">The relevance of the conviction to the fitness and qualification of the credit union share guaranty corporation to engage in the credit union share guaranty business;</section><section prefix="(4)">The length of time since the conviction; and</section><section prefix="(5)">The behavior and activities of the credit union share guaranty corporation since the conviction.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Commissioner may enforce the provisions of this subtitle and any rule or regulation adopted under this subtitle by:<section prefix="(i)">Issuing an order to the credit union share guaranty corporation or entering into an agreement under which the credit union share guaranty corporation agrees:</section><section prefix="(ii)">Imposing a civil penalty not exceeding $1,000 for each violation.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If a violator fails to comply with an order or agreement under this subsection, the Commissioner may impose a civil penalty not exceeding $1,000 for each violation from which the violator failed to cease and desist or for which the violator failed to take affirmative corrective action.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Commissioner may file a petition in the circuit court for a county seeking enforcement of an order issued under this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">In determining the amount of financial penalty to be imposed under subsection (c) of this section, the Commissioner shall consider:<section prefix="(1)">The seriousness of the violation;</section><section prefix="(2)">The good faith of the violator;</section><section prefix="(3)">The violator's history of previous violations;</section><section prefix="(4)">The deleterious effect of the violation on the public and holders of credit union share or deposit accounts;</section><section prefix="(5)">The assets of the violator; and</section><section prefix="(6)">Any other factors relevant to the determination of the financial penalty.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Before the Commissioner takes any action under subsection (a) or (c) of this section, the Commissioner shall give the credit union share guaranty corporation an opportunity for a hearing.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A hearing under this subtitle shall be held in accordance with the Administrative Procedure Act.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The hearing notice shall be sent by certified mail, return receipt requested, to the credit union share guaranty corporation to the principal place of business of the credit union share guaranty corporation at least 30 days before the hearing.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
