<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gfi" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="12-1001" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gfi-12-1001</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>// EFFECTIVE UNTIL JUNE 30, 2015 PER CHAPTERS 280 AND 281 OF 2011 //<section prefix="(a)">In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated.</section><section prefix="(b)">"Consumer" means an individual who:<section prefix="(1)">Resides in the State; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Is seeking debt settlement services or has entered into a debt settlement services agreement in connection with debts that are consumer debts, as defined in &#xA7; 13-101 of the Commercial Law Article.</section></section><section prefix="(c)">"Debt management services" has the meaning stated in &#xA7; 12-901 of this title.</section><section prefix="(d)"><section prefix="(1)">"Debt settlement services" means any service or program represented, directly or by implication, to renegotiate, settle, reduce, or in any way alter the terms of payment or other terms of a debt between a consumer and one or more unsecured creditors or debt collectors, including a reduction in the balance, interest rate, or fees owed by a consumer to an unsecured creditor or debt collector.</section><section prefix="(2)">"Debt settlement services" does not include debt management services.</section></section><section prefix="(e)">"Debt settlement services agreement" means a written contract, plan, or agreement between a debt settlement services provider and a consumer for the performance of debt settlement services.</section><section prefix="(f)">"Debt settlement services fee" means a fee charged to a consumer by a debt settlement services provider for providing debt settlement services for a consumer.</section><section prefix="(g)">"Debt settlement services provider" means a person that provides or offers to provide debt settlement services for a consumer regardless of whether the person provides the debt settlement services on a for-profit or not-for-profit basis.</section><section prefix="(h)">"Dedicated account" means an account described in &#xA7; 12-1010(d) of this subtitle.</section><section prefix="(i)">"Offer, provide, or attempt to provide debt settlement services" means providing debt settlement services:<section prefix="(1)">To consumers through any means, including telephone telemarketing, Internet solicitation, and face-to-face meetings; and</section><section prefix="(2)">On an intrastate or interstate basis.</section></section><section prefix="(j)">"Principal amount of the debt" means the amount of a debt at the time the debt is included in a debt settlement services agreement.</section><section prefix="(k)">"Registrant" means a person registered under this subtitle to provide debt settlement services.</section></text>
</law>
