<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gfi" order_by="gfi" level="1">Financial Institutions</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gfi-6-805</section_number>
  <catch_line>Any credit union voluntarily may place its business and assets in the hands of the Commissioner for ...</catch_line>
  <order_by>805</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Any credit union voluntarily may place its business and assets in the hands of the Commissioner for liquidation as provided in this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A majority of the board proposing a voluntary receivership shall:<section prefix="(1)">Adopt a resolution that declares that the voluntary receivership is advisable; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Set a date for a vote on the proposed voluntary receivership by the members of the credit union at an annual or special meeting of the members or by mail ballot to be filed on or before that date.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Commissioner, at the request of the board, may:<section prefix="(1)">Waive the vote of the members; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Substitute any reasonable method of determining the approval by the members.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Unless the Commissioner takes action under subsection (c) of this section, the proposed voluntary receivership shall be approved by the affirmative vote of a majority of the members of the credit union who vote on the proposal.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">After the action is approved by the members, the proper officers of the credit union shall certify the action of the members to the Commissioner, and the Commissioner shall post a notice at each office of the credit union that states: "This credit union is in the hands of the Maryland Commissioner of Financial Regulation for liquidation."</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">If a credit union is placed in the hands of the Commissioner under this section, the Commissioner shall place the credit union in receivership for liquidation in the same manner as provided for a banking institution under Title 5, Subtitle 6 of this article.</section>
  </text>
</law>
