<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gfi" order_by="" level="1">Financial Institutions</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gfi-11-605</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>605</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Commissioner may not issue a mortgage loan originator license unless the Commissioner makes, at a minimum, the following findings:<section prefix="(1)">The applicant has never had a mortgage loan originator license revoked in any governmental jurisdiction;</section><section prefix="(2)">The applicant has not been convicted of, or pled guilty or nolo contendere to, a felony in a domestic, foreign, or military court:<section prefix="(i)">During the 7-year period immediately preceding the date of the application for licensing; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">At any time preceding the date of application, if the felony involved an act of fraud, dishonesty, a breach of trust, or money laundering;</section></section><section prefix="(3)">The applicant has demonstrated financial responsibility, character, and general fitness sufficient to command the confidence of the community and to warrant a determination that the mortgage loan originator will operate honestly, fairly, and efficiently;</section><section prefix="(4)">The applicant has completed the prelicensing education requirement under &#xA7; 11-606 of this subtitle and any prelicensing education requirements established by the Commissioner by regulation;</section><section prefix="(5)">The applicant has passed a test that meets the requirements established under &#xA7; 11-606.1 of this subtitle and any prelicensing testing requirements established by the Commissioner by regulation; and</section><section prefix="(6)">The applicant has met the surety bond requirement under &#xA7; 11-619 of this subtitle.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A conviction for which a pardon has been granted is not a conviction for purposes of subsection (a)(2) of this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A determination that an individual does not meet the requirements for financial responsibility under subsection (a)(3) of this section may not be based solely on:<section prefix="(1)">Debts arising from medical expenses, including judgments;</section><section prefix="(2)">Except for delinquent child support payments, debts, including judgments, arising from divorce proceedings or divorce settlements;</section><section prefix="(3)">Foreclosures on the applicant's principal residence;</section><section prefix="(4)">The applicant's credit score as reported by any consumer reporting agency, as defined in 15 U.S.C. &#xA7; 1681a; or</section><section prefix="(5)">The applicant's involvement in a bankruptcy proceeding under Title 11 of the United States Code.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
