<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gfi" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="6-803" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gfi-6-803</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Merging credit union" means a credit union that is absorbed or acquired by another credit union in a merger and ceases to exist after the merger.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Surviving credit union" means a credit union that absorbs or acquires another credit union in a merger and continues to exist after the merger.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">"New credit union" means a credit union that is created when two or more credit unions consolidate to form a newly created credit union.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">With the approval of the Commissioner, any credit union may merge or consolidate as provided in this section.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">A merger or consolidation under this section may be with a credit union organized under the laws of the United States, this State, or any other state.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">A single common bond credit union may merge or consolidate with another single common bond credit union resulting in a surviving or new single common bond credit union provided that the credit unions party to the merger or consolidation share the same single common bond, as defined under &#xA7; 6-301(c)(2) of this title, prior and subsequent to the merger or consolidation.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">A single common bond credit union may merge or consolidate with another single common bond credit union resulting in a surviving or new multiple common bond credit union provided that:</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A single common bond credit union may merge or consolidate with a multiple common bond credit union resulting in a surviving or new multiple common bond credit union provided that:<section prefix="(i)">Prior to the merger or consolidation, the multiple common bond credit union includes or adds to its field of membership the group served by the single common bond credit union, as provided under &#xA7; 6-303 of this title; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">The surviving or new multiple common bond credit union satisfies the requirements for multiple common bonds under &#xA7; 6-301(c)(3) and (e) of this title.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">A multiple common bond credit union may merge or consolidate with another multiple common bond credit union resulting in a surviving or new multiple common bond credit union provided that:<section prefix="(i)"/><section prefix="(ii)">The surviving or new multiple common bond credit union satisfies the requirements for multiple common bonds under &#xA7; 6-301(c)(3) and (e) of this title.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(5)">A single or multiple common bond credit union may merge, as the merging credit union, with a community credit union, as the surviving credit union, provided that:<section prefix="(i)"/><section prefix="(ii)">No less than 30 days before the effective date of the merger, the merging credit union gives notice of the merger to all groups of potential members of the merging credit union that will be removed from the field of membership as a result of the merger; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">On and after the effective date of the merger, the surviving credit union:</section></section>
      <section prefix="(6)">A community credit union may merge or consolidate with another community credit union provided that:<section prefix="(i)">The members of the surviving or new credit union remain within a single well-defined local community, neighborhood, rural district, or county; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">The surviving or new credit union is within reasonable geographic proximity to the members of the credit union party to the merger or consolidation.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(7)">Except as provided in paragraphs (8) and (9) of this subsection, a community credit union may not merge, as a merging credit union, with a single or multiple common bond credit union.</section>
      <section prefix="(8)">Notwithstanding the provisions of paragraph (2), (3), (4), or (5) of this subsection or the numerical limitations prescribed in &#xA7; 6-301(e) of this title, the Commissioner may approve the merger or consolidation of any credit union with a multiple common bond credit union, as a new or surviving credit union, when safety and soundness concerns are present as determined by the Commissioner.</section>
      <section prefix="(9)">Notwithstanding the provisions of paragraphs (2) through (8) of this subsection, the Commissioner may approve the merger or consolidation of any credit union, whether or not the credit unions party to the merger or consolidation have the same field of membership type, if:<section prefix="(i)">Any of the credit unions party to the merger or consolidation is insolvent or likely to become insolvent;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The merger or consolidation is in the best interest of the membership of the credit unions party to the merger or consolidation; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">The merger or consolidation will not adversely affect the financial condition of the surviving or new credit union.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If the surviving or new credit union will be a State credit union:<section prefix="(i)">The merger or consolidation shall be made in accordance with the provisions of this subtitle; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">If one of the credit unions is a federal credit union, federal law governs its actions and the rights of its members.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If the surviving or new credit union will be a federal credit union:<section prefix="(i)">The merger or consolidation shall be made in accordance with federal law which governs its actions and the rights of its members; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">The merger or consolidation shall be made in accordance with the provisions of this subtitle for a State credit union and the rights of its members.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">If the surviving or new credit union will be another State credit union:<section prefix="(i)">The merger or consolidation shall be made in accordance with the provisions of this subtitle for the State credit union and the rights of its members; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">The merger or consolidation shall be made in accordance with the provisions of the other State laws for the other State credit union and the rights of its members.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A majority of the board of each credit union proposing a merger or consolidation shall:<section prefix="(1)">Adopt a resolution that declares that the merger or consolidation is advisable; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Set a date for a vote on the proposed merger or consolidation by the members of each credit union party to the merger or consolidation at any annual or special meeting of the membership or by mail ballot to be filed on or before that date.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The Commissioner, at the request of the board, may:<section prefix="(1)">Waive the vote of the members; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Substitute any reasonable method of determining the approval by the members.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The merger or consolidation shall be in accordance with a plan that:<section prefix="(1)">States the field of membership type that the surviving or new credit union will have;</section><section prefix="(2)">Is agreed to by a majority of the board of each credit union party to the merger or consolidation; and</section><section prefix="(3)">Unless provided otherwise by the Commissioner, is approved by the members of each credit union party to the merger or consolidation, by the affirmative vote of a majority of the members of each credit union party to the merger or consolidation who vote on the proposal.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">After agreement by the board and approval by the members of each credit union party to the merger or consolidation, two officers of each credit union party to the merger or consolidation shall execute a certificate of merger or consolidation.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The certificate of merger or consolidation shall include as to each credit union party to the merger or consolidation:<section prefix="(i)">The time and place of the meeting of the board at which the plan was agreed to;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The vote by which the plan was agreed to by the board;</section><section prefix="(iii)">A copy of the resolution or other action by which the plan was agreed to by the board;</section><section prefix="(iv)">The date on or by which the plan was approved by the members of each credit union; and</section><section prefix="(v)">Unless provided otherwise by the Commissioner, the vote by which the plan was approved by the members of each credit union.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(h)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A credit union may merge or consolidate if:<section prefix="(i)"/><section prefix="(ii)">The Commissioner determines that:</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Unless the Commissioner notifies the credit union that a different time period is necessary, within 60 days after the certificate of merger or consolidation is filed, the Commissioner shall:<section prefix="(i)">Notify each credit union party to the merger or consolidation of the determination on the application; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Certify the certificate of merger or consolidation and return the certificate to each credit union party to the merger or consolidation.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(i)">When the certificate is certified and sent back to the credit unions by the Commissioner:<section prefix="(1)">All of the property, property rights, and members' interest of the credit unions party to the merger or consolidation belong to the surviving or new credit union without deed, endorsement, or other instrument of transfer;</section><section prefix="(2)">All of the debts, obligations, and liabilities of the credit unions party to the merger or consolidation are assumed by the surviving or new credit union; and</section><section prefix="(3)">The rights and privileges of the members of the credit unions party to the merger or consolidation remain intact.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(j)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The surviving or new credit union shall act promptly to file and record the certified certificate and plan of merger or consolidation with the State Department of Assessments and Taxation.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">When the certificate and plan of merger or consolidation are filed with the State Department of Assessments and Taxation, the merger or consolidation takes effect.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
