<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gfi" order_by="" level="1">Financial Institutions</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gfi-1-301</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>301</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Fiduciary institution" means:<section prefix="(i)">A national banking association;</section><section prefix="(ii)">A State banking institution;</section><section prefix="(iii)">An other-state bank that maintains a branch in this State;</section><section prefix="(iv)">A credit union that is organized under the laws of this State or of the United States;</section><section prefix="(v)">Any other organization that is organized under the banking laws of this State and subject to the supervision of the Commissioner; or</section><section prefix="(vi)">A savings and loan association that is organized under the laws of this State or of the United States.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Fiduciary institution" does not include any person licensed by the Commissioner under Title 11 of this article.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Financial record" means the original or any copy or record of:<section prefix="(i)">A document that grants signature authority over a deposit or share account;</section><section prefix="(ii)">A statement, ledger card, or other record of a deposit or share account that shows transactions in or with respect to that deposit or account;</section><section prefix="(iii)">A check, clear draft, or money order that is drawn on a fiduciary institution or issued and payable by or through a fiduciary institution;</section><section prefix="(iv)">Any item, other than an institutional or periodic charge, that is made under an agreement between a fiduciary institution and another person and that constitutes a debit or a credit to that person's deposit or share account; or</section><section prefix="(v)">Any information that relates to a loan account or an application for a loan.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Financial record" includes any evidence of a transaction conducted by means of an electronic terminal.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">"Supervisory agency" means:<section prefix="(1)">The Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation;</section><section prefix="(2)">The Federal Savings and Loan Insurance Corporation;</section><section prefix="(3)">The Federal Home Loan Bank Board;</section><section prefix="(4)">The National Credit Union Administration;</section><section prefix="(5)">The Federal Reserve Board;</section><section prefix="(6)">The United States Comptroller of the Currency;</section><section prefix="(7)">The State of Maryland Deposit Insurance Fund Corporation;</section><section prefix="(8)">The Credit Union Insurance Corporation;</section><section prefix="(9)">The Commissioner;</section><section prefix="(10)">The Division of Savings and Loan Associations; or</section><section prefix="(11)">An agency of another state with primary responsibility for chartering and supervising banks.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
