<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gfi" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="5-1105" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gfi-5-1105</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Except as provided in subsections (b), (c), (d), and (e) of this section, a commercial bank acquired under this subtitle may exercise all the powers of, and shall be subject only to those restrictions imposed on a commercial bank owned by a Maryland bank holding company under applicable State law.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A commercial bank that results from a conversion of a savings and loan association or acquires a savings and loan association may hold assets or conduct business activities, other than insurance assets and insurance activities, that result from the acquisition of a savings and loan association and that do not conform with applicable law, unless a different period is authorized by federal regulatory agencies:<section prefix="(1)">For a period of 5 years after the acquisition; and</section><section prefix="(2)">If the Commissioner approves, for an additional period not exceeding 5 years.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A commercial bank that results from a conversion of a savings and loan association or acquires a savings and loan association may hold insurance assets or conduct insurance activities that result from the acquisition of a savings and loan association and that do not conform with applicable law, unless a different period is authorized by federal regulatory agencies, for a period of 2 years after the date of acquisition.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Except as provided in subsection (c) of this section, a commercial bank acquired under this subtitle may hold insurance assets or conduct insurance activities only to the extent permitted under applicable law to a Maryland commercial bank.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">A commercial bank that results from the conversion of a savings and loan association or acquires a savings and loan association that is subject to the provisions of this section may not exercise any rights afforded to a Maryland bank, a Maryland bank holding company, or an out-of-state bank holding company under any Maryland law authorizing reciprocal interstate banking acquisitions until such time as national reciprocal interstate banking is authorized under State law.</section>
  </text>
</law>
