<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gfi" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="12-410" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gfi-12-410</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Commissioner shall include on each license:<section prefix="(1)">The trade name of the licensee; and</section><section prefix="(2)">The address at which the business is to be conducted.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A license authorizes the licensee to do business under the license, at the licensed place of business.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A license does not authorize the licensee to accept deposits or engage otherwise in a banking business except as authorized in this subtitle.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Only one place of business may be maintained under any one license.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Commissioner may issue more than one license to an applicant who:<section prefix="(1)">Complies with &#xA7; 12-407 of this subtitle; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Otherwise meets the requirements of this subtitle.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A license may not be transferred or assigned.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">If the licensee has its principal executive office in the State, the licensee shall prominently display the license and unique identifier in the location that is open to the public and at which the licensee engages in the business of money transmission.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">If the licensee has its principal executive office outside the State, the licensee shall maintain the license in the principal executive office.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Each authorized delegate shall display prominently at each location open to the public a notice in at least 48-point type that states the following:</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A licensee that offers Internet money transmission services shall include the following notice on its website:</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
