<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gfi" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="6-609" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gfi-6-609</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Eligible obligation" means a loan or a group of loans made to a member of a credit union by a lender other than the credit union to which the member belongs.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Student loan" means a loan that is:<section prefix="(i)">Granted to finance the borrower's attendance at an institution of higher education or at a vocational school; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Secured by, and on which payment of the outstanding principal and interest has been deferred in accordance with, the insurance or guarantee of the federal government, a state government, or a unit of the federal government or of a state government.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Subject to the provisions of paragraph (2) of this subsection, a credit union may purchase, in whole or in part, in accordance with the board's purchase policies:<section prefix="(i)">Eligible obligations of its members;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Eligible obligations of the individual members of a liquidating credit union, from the liquidating credit union;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Student loans if the credit union is granting student loans on an ongoing basis and if the purchase will facilitate the credit union's packaging of a pool of the loans to be sold or pledged on the secondary market; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">Real estate loans if the credit union is granting real estate loans under this subtitle on an ongoing basis and if the purchase will facilitate the credit union's packaging of a pool of the loans to be sold or pledged on the secondary mortgage market.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A credit union may make a purchase under paragraph (1) of this subsection if:<section prefix="(i)">The board or investment committee approves the purchase;</section><section prefix="(ii)">A written agreement and a schedule of the eligible obligations covered by the agreement are retained by the credit union for inspection;</section><section prefix="(iii)">The aggregate of the unpaid balance of eligible obligations purchased under paragraph (1)(i) and (ii) of this subsection does not exceed 5% of the total assets of the credit union; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">For purchases of real estate loans under paragraph (1)(iv) of this subsection, the pool of loans to be sold or pledged on the secondary mortgage market:</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A credit union may sell or pledge, in whole or in part, the eligible obligations or loans purchased under subsection (b)(1) of this section if:<section prefix="(1)">The board or investment committee approves the sale or pledge; and</section><section prefix="(2)">The written agreement covering the sale or pledge and a schedule of the eligible obligations or loans covered by the agreement are retained by the credit union for inspection.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A credit union may agree to service any eligible obligation the credit union purchases or sells in whole or in part.</section>
  </text>
</law>
