<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gfi" order_by="" level="1">Financial Institutions</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gfi-5-606</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>606</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The receiver may appoint any clerks needed to carry out the receivership.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The salaries of these clerks shall be paid out of the funds of the banking institution.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Notwithstanding subsection (a) of this section, the receiver of a nondepository trust company may, as needed to carry out the receivership:<section prefix="(i)">Appoint any clerks, agents, counsel, employees, and assistants; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Retain officers and employees of the nondepository trust company.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The salaries and all other expenses of the individuals specified under paragraph (1) of this subsection that are court approved shall be paid from the assets of the nondepository trust company, the proceeds of the sale of securities pledged under &#xA7; 3-211.1 of this article, or recovery against a surety bond delivered under &#xA7; 3-211.1 of this article.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Any proceeds of a sale of pledged securities that remain after making the payments required under paragraph (2) of this subsection and &#xA7; 5-604.1(a) of this subtitle shall be an asset of the nondepository trust company.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The receiver may borrow money and, with the approval of the court, pledge, mortgage, or encumber any of the institution's assets to:<section prefix="(1)">Pay the obligations of the institution;</section><section prefix="(2)">Pay dividends to the depositors or creditors of the institution; or</section><section prefix="(3)">Enable the institution to reopen or reorganize.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The receiver shall file with the court, in the form that the court requires, an itemized account of:<section prefix="(i)">All receipts, disbursements, and expenses; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Any proposed distribution.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The court shall accept the account to the same extent as if an auditor of the court had prepared and filed the account.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, the receiver may not make any distribution until the court ratifies the receiver's account.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">With the approval of the court, the receiver may pay in full each creditor whose total claims do not exceed $5.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
