<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gfl" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="5-301" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gfl-5-301</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Caregiver" means a person with whom a child resides and who exercises responsibility for the welfare of the child.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Child" means an individual who is the subject of a guardianship or adoption petition under this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">"Guardianship" means an award, under this subtitle, of any power of a guardian.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"Identifying information" means information that reveals the identity or location of an individual.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Parent" means an individual who, at the time a petition for guardianship is filed under this subtitle or at any time before a court terminates the individual's parental rights:<section prefix="(i)">meets a criterion in &#xA7; 5-306(a) of this subtitle; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">is the mother.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Parent" does not include an individual whom a court has adjudicated not to be a father or mother of a child.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">"Party" means:<section prefix="(1)">in a guardianship case under this subtitle:<section prefix="(i)">the child;</section><section prefix="(ii)">except as provided in &#xA7; 5-326(a)(3)(iii) of this subtitle, the child's parent; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">the local department to which the child is committed;</section></section><section prefix="(2)">in an adoption case under Part III of this subtitle:<section prefix="(i)">the child;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the child's parent; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">the individual seeking adoption;</section></section><section prefix="(3)">in an adoption case under Part IV of this subtitle:<section prefix="(i)">the child; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">the individual seeking adoption; and</section></section><section prefix="(4)">if express reference is made to a CINA case, a governmental unit or person defined as a party in &#xA7; 3-801 of the Courts Article.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
