<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gfl" order_by="gfl" level="1">Family Law</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gfl-10-350</section_number>
  <catch_line>If &#xA7; 10-352 of this subtitle does not apply, except as otherwise provided in &#xA7; 10-353.1 of this su...</catch_line>
  <order_by>350</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">If &#xA7; 10-352 of this subtitle does not apply, except as otherwise provided in &#xA7; 10-353.1 of this subtitle, on the filing of a complaint, a tribunal of this State may modify a child support order issued in another state that is registered in this State if, after notice and hearing, the tribunal finds that:<section prefix="(1)">the following requirements are met:<section prefix="(i)">neither the child, nor the obligee who is an individual, nor the obligor resides in the issuing state;</section><section prefix="(ii)">a plaintiff who is a nonresident of this State seeks modification; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">the defendant is subject to the personal jurisdiction of the tribunal of this State; or</section></section><section prefix="(2)">this State is the state of residence of the child or a party who is an individual is subject to the personal jurisdiction of the tribunal of this State and all of the parties who are individuals have filed consents in a record in the issuing tribunal for a tribunal of this State to modify the support order and assume continuing, exclusive jurisdiction.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Modification of a registered child support order is subject to the same requirements, procedures, and defenses that apply to the modification of an order issued by a tribunal of this State, and the order may be enforced and satisfied in the same manner.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Except as otherwise provided in &#xA7; 10-353.1 of this subtitle, a tribunal of this State may not modify any provision of a child support order that may not be modified under the law of the issuing state, including the duration of the obligation of support. If two or more tribunals have issued child support orders for the same obligor and same child, the order that controls and must be so recognized under the provisions of &#xA7; 10-310 of this subtitle establishes the provisions of the support order which are nonmodifiable.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">In a proceeding to modify a child support order, the law of the state that is determined to have issued the initial controlling order governs the duration of the obligation of support.  The obligor's fulfillment of the duty of support established by that order precludes imposition of a further obligation of support by a tribunal of this State.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">On issuance of an order by a tribunal of this State modifying a child support order issued in another state, the tribunal of this State becomes the tribunal of continuing, exclusive jurisdiction.</section>
  </text>
</law>
