<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gfl" order_by="" level="1">Family Law</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gfl-5-1014</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>1014</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">When a complaint is filed under this subtitle, the court may issue, to assure the appearance of the defendant at trial:<section prefix="(1)">a summons for the appearance of the defendant; or</section><section prefix="(2)">a warrant for the arrest of the defendant.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The summons shall state the time and place for the defendant to appear at trial.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If the defendant fails to appear as directed in the summons, the court may issue, at any time, a warrant for the defendant's arrest.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The arrest warrant shall direct any officer of this State who is authorized to execute warrants to bring the defendant before the court to answer and have the matters in the complaint adjudicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If a defendant is arrested under a warrant, the defendant shall be taken before:<section prefix="(i)">the court that issued the warrant; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">a commissioner of the District Court.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The court or commissioner shall set bond for the defendant. The bond shall be conditioned on:<section prefix="(i)">the defendant's appearance in the issuing court on the date and at the time specified in the warrant; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">the defendant's obedience to any order of the court in the proceedings.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The court or commissioner may require on the bond the securities or sureties the court or the commissioner considers appropriate.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">If the defendant does not give bond, the court or commissioner shall order the defendant imprisoned in the city or county jail until bond is given or until the issuing court discharges the defendant.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
