<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gfl" order_by="" level="1">Family Law</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gfl-5-3B-06</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>06</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In a case under this subtitle, a court shall appoint an attorney to represent a parent who:<section prefix="(i)">has a disability that makes the parent incapable of effectively participating in the case; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">when the parent must decide whether to consent to adoption, is still a minor.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">To determine whether a disability makes a parent incapable of effectively participating in a case, a court, on its own motion or on motion of a party, may order examination of the parent.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In a case under this subtitle, a court shall appoint an attorney to represent a prospective adoptee who:<section prefix="(i)">has a disability that makes the prospective adoptee incapable of effectively participating in the case; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">when the prospective adoptee must decide whether to consent to adoption, is at least 10 years old.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">To determine whether a disability makes a prospective adoptee incapable of effectively participating in a case, a court, on its own motion or on motion of a party, may order examination of the prospective adoptee.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">An attorney or firm:<section prefix="(1)">may represent more than one party in a case under this subtitle only if the Maryland Lawyers' Rules of Professional Conduct allow; and</section><section prefix="(2)">may not represent a prospective adoptive parent and parent in the same adoption case.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Counsel appointed under this section may be compensated for reasonable fees, as approved by the court.</section>
  </text>
</law>
