<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gfl" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="5-4C-01" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gfl-5-4C-01</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Administration" means the Social Services Administration of the Department.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Adoptee" means an individual:<section prefix="(1)">who was adopted in this State; or</section><section prefix="(2)">who was placed for adoption by:<section prefix="(i)">a child placement agency licensed in this State; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">a local department.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">"Director" means the Director of the Administration.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"Identifying information" means information that reveals the identity or location of an adoptee, the natural parents of an adoptee, or a natural sibling.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">Repealed.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">"Natural father" means a man who:<section prefix="(1)">was married to the adoptee's natural mother at the time of conception;</section><section prefix="(2)">was married to the adoptee's natural mother at the time of the adoptee's birth;</section><section prefix="(3)">was named as the father on the adoptee's pre-adoption birth certificate, unless the man has signed a denial of paternity or his nonpaternity has been determined by a court;</section><section prefix="(4)">was identified by the natural mother as the father of the adoptee, unless the man has signed a denial of paternity or his nonpaternity has been determined by a court;</section><section prefix="(5)">has been adjudicated to be the father of the adoptee; or</section><section prefix="(6)">has acknowledged himself orally or in writing to be the father of the adoptee.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(h)">"Natural sibling" means an individual who is at least 21 years old and shares 1 or both natural parents with an adoptee.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">"Registry" means the Mutual Consent Voluntary Adoption Registry.</section>
  </text>
</law>
