<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gfl" order_by="gfl" level="1">Family Law</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gfl-14-303</section_number>
  <catch_line>To protect the welfare of the alleged vulnerable adult the local department shall begin a thorough i...</catch_line>
  <order_by>303</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">To protect the welfare of the alleged vulnerable adult the local department shall begin a thorough investigation:<section prefix="(1)">within 5 working days after the receipt of the report of suspected abuse, neglect, self-neglect, or exploitation; or</section><section prefix="(2)">within 24 hours after the receipt of the report of suspected abuse, neglect, self-neglect, or exploitation if the report indicates that an emergency exists.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The investigation shall include:<section prefix="(1)">a determination of whether:<section prefix="(i)">the individual is a vulnerable adult; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">there has been abuse, neglect, self-neglect, or exploitation; and</section></section><section prefix="(2)">if the individual is determined to be a vulnerable adult and to have suffered abuse, neglect, self-neglect, or exploitation:<section prefix="(i)">a determination of the nature, extent, and cause of the abuse, neglect, self-neglect, or exploitation;</section><section prefix="(ii)">a determination of the identity of the person or persons responsible for the abuse, neglect, self-neglect, or exploitation;</section><section prefix="(iii)">an evaluation of the home environment; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">a determination of any other pertinent facts.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">On request by the local department, the local State's Attorney or the appropriate law enforcement agency shall assist in the investigation.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">As appropriate, the local office on aging or the Department of Aging, local geriatric evaluation service, or any other public or private agency providing services or care to the alleged vulnerable adult or whose information or expertise may be of assistance in assessing risk or planning services may assist in the investigation on the request by the local department.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Any agencies set out in this subsection may jointly agree to cooperative arrangements for investigation.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">An investigation under this section shall be completed within:<section prefix="(1)">30 days; or</section><section prefix="(2)">10 days if the report indicates that an emergency exists.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">Parties participating in an investigation may share pertinent client information relevant to the investigation.</section>
  </text>
</law>
