<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gfl" order_by="gfl" level="1">Family Law</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gfl-7-103.2</section_number>
  <catch_line>This section applies to an action for divorce in which issues of child support, custody, or visitati...</catch_line>
  <order_by>103.2</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">This section applies to an action for divorce in which issues of child support, custody, or visitation are raised.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Prior to granting a decree of divorce, the court may require all parties to participate in an educational seminar that is designed to educate parents about the effects, and to minimize the disruption, of a divorce on the lives of children.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Court of Appeals shall adopt rules to implement this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Rules adopted in accordance with this subsection shall:<section prefix="(i)">provide for the content of the seminar required under this section;</section><section prefix="(ii)">require successful completion of the seminar by all parties to the action within a certain time after the service of the original complaint upon the defendant;</section><section prefix="(iii)">establish sanctions for failure to successfully complete the seminar required under this section;</section><section prefix="(iv)">for purposes of funding the cost of the seminar, establish a fee that:<section prefix="1.">shall be assessed as costs; and</section><section prefix="2.">may be waived under appropriate circumstances; and</section></section><section prefix="(v)">establish criteria for exemption from the requirement that the parties participate in an educational seminar, except that a court may not exempt the parties from attending the educational seminar if there is any evidence of domestic violence or child abuse or neglect.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The seminar required under this section may be provided under contract with a public or private agency.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">Unless the parties stipulate otherwise, any information about a party, including statements or reports, obtained from an educational seminar required by this section, is not admissible during the action for divorce of that party.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">This section may not be construed to require the parties to an action for divorce to attend the educational seminar together.</section>
  </text>
</law>
