<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gfl" order_by="gfl" level="1">Family Law</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gfl-5-358</section_number>
  <catch_line>If, after a hearing on a petition of an adoptee or former parent, a juvenile court is satisfied that...</catch_line>
  <order_by>358</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">If, after a hearing on a petition of an adoptee or former parent, a juvenile court is satisfied that the adoptee or blood relative of the adoptee or former parent urgently needs medical information not in local department and juvenile court records, the juvenile court may appoint an intermediary to try to contact the adoptee or a former parent of the adoptee for the information.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">An intermediary appointed under this section:<section prefix="(1)">may only advise an adoptee or former parent of the need for medical information; and</section><section prefix="(2)">may not:<section prefix="(i)">reveal any identifying information about an adoptee or former parent; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">try, in any manner, to encourage or discourage contact between an adoptee and former parent.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">An intermediary appointed under this section shall file with the appointing juvenile court a confidential written report on the intermediary's efforts to contact an adoptee or former parent.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">When a juvenile court receives a report from an intermediary, the juvenile court may disclose to the adoptee or former parent, without revealing identifying information about an adoptee or former parent:<section prefix="(1)">whether the intermediary advised an adoptee or former parent about the need for medical information; and</section><section prefix="(2)">medical information that the adoptee or a former parent provided.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, a juvenile court may order an adoptee or former parent to pay a reasonable fee for the services of an intermediary under this section.</section>
  </text>
</law>
