<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gfl" order_by="gfl" level="1">Family Law</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gfl-5-3B-15</section_number>
  <catch_line>Subsection (b) of this section does not apply to an adoption by a spouse of the prospective adoptee'...</catch_line>
  <order_by>15</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Subsection (b) of this section does not apply to an adoption by a spouse of the prospective adoptee's parent or a relative of the prospective adoptee.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A court shall issue a show-cause order that includes advice as to the parent's rights to:<section prefix="(1)">have independent counsel; and</section><section prefix="(2)">receive adoption counseling and guidance.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">On issuance of a show-cause order as to a prospective adoptee, a petitioner shall serve the order:<section prefix="(1)">on each of the prospective adoptee's living parents who has not consented to the adoption; and</section><section prefix="(2)">if the prospective adoptee is at least 10 years old and has not consented to the adoption, on the prospective adoptee.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Service under this section shall be by:<section prefix="(1)">personal service; or</section><section prefix="(2)">certified mail, restricted delivery, return receipt requested.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">Service under this section shall be attempted at the parent's last address known to the petitioner.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If a court is satisfied, by affidavit or testimony, that, after reasonable efforts in good faith, a petitioner could not identify a parent or could not effect service on a parent, the court shall order service through notice by publication as to that parent.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Notice under this subsection shall consist of substantially the following statement:</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Service under this subsection shall be by:<section prefix="(i)">publication at least once in one or more newspapers in general circulation in the county where the petition is filed or, if different, where the parent's last address known to the petitioner is located; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">posting for at least 30 days on a website of the Department.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The Department may charge a petitioner a reasonable fee to cover the cost of posting.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
