<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gfl" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="5-570" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gfl-5-570</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this Part VII of this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Child" means an individual under the age of 16 years.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Child care center" means an agency, institution, or establishment that, for part or all of a day, or on a 24-hour basis on a regular schedule, and at least twice a week, offers or provides child care to children who do not have the same parentage except as otherwise provided for in law or regulation.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Child care center" shall include a nonpublic nursery school in which an instructional program is offered or provided for children who are under the age of 5 years.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Child care center" does not include:<section prefix="(i)">a nonpublic kindergarten in which an instructional program is offered or provided for children who are at least 5 years old;</section><section prefix="(ii)">a nonpublic elementary school in which an instructional program is offered or provided for children who are in grades 1 through 8;</section><section prefix="(iii)">a child care home, a child care institution, or other child care facility that offers or provides a residential placement for a child and is established, licensed, or registered under this subtitle, Title 9 of the Human Services Article, or Title 10 of the Health - General Article; or</section><section prefix="(iv)">a family child care home or large family child care home that is required to be registered or is registered under this subtitle.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">"Department" means the State Department of Education.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"Letter of compliance" means a letter issued by the State Department of Education to a religious organization that meets the requirements under &#xA7; 5-573 of this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">"License" means a license issued by the State Department of Education to operate a child care center.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">"Person" includes a State, county, or municipal corporation.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">"State Superintendent" means the State Superintendent of Schools or the State Superintendent's designee.</section>
  </text>
</law>
