<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gfl" order_by="gfl" level="1">Family Law</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gfl-5-321</section_number>
  <catch_line>Consent of a parent to guardianship may include a waiver of the right to notice of:...</catch_line>
  <order_by>321</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Consent of a parent to guardianship may include a waiver of the right to notice of:<section prefix="(i)">the filing of a petition under this subtitle; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">a hearing under this subtitle.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Consent to guardianship entered into before a judge on the record shall include a waiver of a revocation period.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Consent of a party to guardianship is not valid unless:<section prefix="(i)">the consent is given in a language that the party understands;</section><section prefix="(ii)">if given in a language other than English, the consent:<section prefix="1.">is given before a judge on the record; or</section><section prefix="2.">is accompanied by the affidavit of a translator stating that the translation of the document of consent is accurate;</section></section><section prefix="(iii)">the party has received written notice or on the record notice before a judge of:<section prefix="1.">the revocation provisions in subsections (a)(2) and (c)(1) of this section;</section><section prefix="2.">the search rights of adoptees and parents under &#xA7; 5-359 of this subtitle and the search rights of adoptees, parents, and siblings under Subtitle 4B of this title; and</section><section prefix="3.">the right to file a disclosure veto under &#xA7; 5-359 of this subtitle;</section></section><section prefix="(iv)">if signed after counsel enters an appearance for a parent, the consent is accompanied by an affidavit of counsel stating that:<section prefix="1.">counsel reviewed the consent with the parent; and</section><section prefix="2.">the parent consents knowingly and voluntarily; and</section></section><section prefix="(v)">the consent is accompanied by an affidavit of counsel appointed under &#xA7; 5-307(a) of this subtitle stating that a parent who is a minor or has a disability consents knowingly and voluntarily.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Whenever a local department receives consent to guardianship of an individual before a guardianship petition is filed, the local department promptly shall:<section prefix="(i)">file the consent in the individual's CINA case; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">serve a copy of the consent on:<section prefix="1.">each living parent of the individual;</section><section prefix="2.">the parent's last attorney of record in the CINA case; and</section><section prefix="3.">the individual's last attorney of record in the CINA case.</section></section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Whenever a party obtains consent to guardianship after a guardianship petition is filed, the party promptly shall:<section prefix="(i)">file the consent with the juvenile court in which the petition is pending; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">serve a copy of the consent on each other party.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Subject to paragraph (2) of this subsection, a person may revoke consent to guardianship any time within the later of:<section prefix="(i)">30 days after the person signs the consent; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">30 days after the consent is filed as required under this section.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Consent to guardianship under subsection (a)(2) of this section is irrevocable.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">If, at any time before a juvenile court enters an order for adoption of a child, the juvenile court finds that a condition of consent to guardianship will not be fulfilled, the consent or acquiescence becomes invalid.</section>
  </text>
</law>
