<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gfl" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="5-714" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gfl-5-714</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Social Services Administration and each local department may maintain a central registry of cases reported under this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Each local department shall provide the information for a central registry.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Except for identifying information authorized under subsection (d) of this section, a central registry may not include information from a local department case file until any individual found responsible for indicated or unsubstantiated child abuse or neglect has:<section prefix="(i)">been found guilty of any criminal charge arising from the alleged abuse or neglect;</section><section prefix="(ii)">unsuccessfully appealed the finding in accordance with the procedures established under &#xA7; 5-706.1 of this subtitle; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">failed to exercise the appeal rights within the time frames specified in &#xA7; 5-706.1 of this subtitle, Title 10, Subtitle 2 of the State Government Article, or the Maryland Rules.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The information in a central registry shall be at the disposal of:<section prefix="(1)">the protective services staff of the Administration;</section><section prefix="(2)">the protective services staffs of local departments who are investigating a report of suspected abuse or neglect; and</section><section prefix="(3)">law enforcement personnel who are investigating a report of suspected abuse or neglect.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, and subject to subsection (e) of this section, a central registry may contain identifying information related to an investigation of abuse or neglect.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A central registry may not contain identifying information related to an investigation of abuse or neglect if:<section prefix="(i)">abuse or neglect has been ruled out; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">the abuse or neglect finding has been expunged in accordance with &#xA7; 5-707(b)(1) of this subtitle.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Department or a local department may identify an individual as responsible for abuse or neglect in a central registry only if the individual:<section prefix="(i)">has been found guilty of any criminal charge arising out of the alleged abuse or neglect; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">has been found responsible for indicated abuse or neglect and has:</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Department without the necessity of a request shall remove from the name of an individual described in paragraph (1) of this subsection the identification of that individual as responsible for abuse or neglect if no entry has been made for that individual for 7 years after the entry of the individual's name in a registry.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except for information entered in accordance with subsection (e) of this section, information in a central registry may not be used as a sole basis for responding to any request for background information for employment or voluntary service.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">An official or employee of the Department or a local department who releases information from a central registry in violation of paragraph (1) of this subsection is subject to the penalty provided in &#xA7; 1-202(f) of the Human Services Article.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the central registry may not include the identity of an individual related to an investigation of neglect or found responsible for neglect when:<section prefix="(1)">a child has been released from a hospital or other facility;</section><section prefix="(2)">the child has been diagnosed with a mental disorder or developmental disability; and</section><section prefix="(3)">the individual has failed to take the child home due to a reasonable fear for the safety of the child or child's family.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(h)">The Secretary of Human Resources:<section prefix="(1)">shall adopt regulations necessary to protect the rights of individuals suspected of abuse or neglect; and</section><section prefix="(2)">may adopt regulations to implement the provisions of this section.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
