<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gfl" order_by="" level="1">Family Law</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gfl-5-589</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>589</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Pilot program" means the child care centers established in State-occupied buildings or State complexes under this section.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">There is a pilot program for child care in State-occupied buildings and State complexes.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Department shall administer the pilot program established under this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The pilot program shall be:<section prefix="(1)">operated in at least 1 State-occupied building or State complex where 700 or more State employees are located;</section><section prefix="(2)">established to accommodate at least 29 children at each location; and</section><section prefix="(3)">established for at least 3 years.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Department shall contract with child care providers to operate the child care centers established under this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The contract for operating a child care center shall require the child care provider:<section prefix="(i)">to be responsible for entering into agreements, and making arrangements with the employees, for the provision of child care;</section><section prefix="(ii)">to provide proof of financial responsibility;</section><section prefix="(iii)">to be licensed under Part VII and this Part VIII of this subtitle;</section><section prefix="(iv)">to comply with any laws or regulations governing child care centers;</section><section prefix="(v)">to obtain and keep in effect liability insurance in an amount determined to be sufficient by the State Superintendent; and</section><section prefix="(vi)">to comply with any other requirement the State Superintendent considers reasonable and necessary.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The child care provider may not be held responsible for providing the necessary space for the operation of the child care center.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
