<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gfl" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="10-113" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gfl-10-113</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Each year, the Administration may certify to the State Comptroller any obligor who is in arrears of support payments amounting to more than $150 under the court order, if:<section prefix="(1)">the Administration has accepted an assignment of support under &#xA7; 5-312(b)(2) of the Human Services Article; or</section><section prefix="(2)">the recipient of support payments has filed an application for support enforcement services with the Administration.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Administration shall notify the obligor that:<section prefix="(1)">a certification has been made by the Administration; and</section><section prefix="(2)">the obligor may ask the Administration to investigate the arrearage.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The certification shall include, if known:<section prefix="(1)">the full name of the obligor, and any other names known to be used by the obligor;</section><section prefix="(2)">the address and the Social Security number of the obligor; and</section><section prefix="(3)">the amount of the arrearage.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">On receipt of notice of certification, any obligor who disputes the existence or amount of the arrearage may ask the Administration to investigate the arrearage.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">On receipt of a request for investigation from the obligor, the Administration shall:<section prefix="(i)">conduct an investigation as to the accuracy of the reported arrearage; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">if the Administration finds that there is an error, correct the amount of the reported arrearage or withdraw the certification.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The State Comptroller may not question the certification made by the Administration.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The State Comptroller shall:<section prefix="(1)">withhold and pay to the Administration any income tax refund due to the obligor, in an amount not more than the amount of the arrearage;</section><section prefix="(2)">pay to the obligor any part of the income tax refund over the amount of the arrearage; and</section><section prefix="(3)">notify the obligor of:<section prefix="(i)">the amount paid to the Administration; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">the rights of the obligor under subsection (g) of this section.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">On receipt of notice of intercept from the State Comptroller, any obligor who disputes the existence or amount of the arrearage may appeal to the Administration.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If the Administration finds that an excessive amount was withheld from the obligor's income tax refund or State lottery prize, the Administration promptly shall pay to the taxpayer the excess amount withheld.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(h)">The State Comptroller shall honor refund interception requests in the following order:<section prefix="(1)">a refund interception request to collect an unpaid State, county, or municipal tax;</section><section prefix="(2)">a refund interception request under this Part II of this subtitle for arrears of support payments;</section><section prefix="(3)">a refund interception request for converted funds under &#xA7; 15-122.2 of the Health - General Article; and</section><section prefix="(4)">any other refund interception request.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(i)">The Secretary of Human Resources and the State Comptroller may adopt rules and regulations to carry out this section.</section>
  </text>
</law>
