<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gfl" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="5-1104" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gfl-5-1104</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In reviewing and ranking proposals, the selection committees established under &#xA7;&#xA7; 5-1102 and 5-1103 of this subtitle shall place additional value on proposals that are designed to:<section prefix="(i)">reach the largest possible number of parents, children, and youth in a community;</section><section prefix="(ii)">involve local government officials and other community leaders; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">be supplemented by local or private funding.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The selection committees shall attempt to achieve a broad geographic distribution of funding, to the extent that a proposal has merit, in their recommendations to the Governor.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Based solely on the recommendations of the selection committees, the Governor shall award grants, not to exceed $10,000 each, to further the purposes of this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">All grant awards under this subtitle shall be identified and briefly described in annual reports developed by the Department of Human Resources for grants awarded under &#xA7; 5-1102 of this subtitle and by the Department of Health and Mental Hygiene for grants awarded under &#xA7; 5-1103 of this subtitle. These reports shall be presented to the Governor and, subject to &#xA7; 2-1246 of the State Government Article, to the General Assembly.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">In conjunction with the grant programs established under this subtitle, each year the Governor shall proclaim a Drug and Alcohol Abuse Prevention Awareness Week and a Child Abuse Prevention Awareness Week to focus public attention on these problems.</section>
  </text>
</law>
