<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gfl" order_by="" level="1">Family Law</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gfl-5-324</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>324</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In a separate order accompanying an order denying guardianship of a child, a juvenile court shall include:<section prefix="(1)">a specific factual finding on whether reasonable efforts have been made to finalize the child's permanency plan;</section><section prefix="(2)">any order under Title 3, Subtitle 8 of the Courts Article in the child's best interests; and</section><section prefix="(3)">a date, no later than 180 days after the date of the order, for the next review hearing under Title 3, Subtitle 8 of the Courts Article.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In a separate order accompanying an order granting guardianship of a child, a juvenile court:<section prefix="(i)">shall include a directive terminating the child's CINA case;</section><section prefix="(ii)">consistent with the child's best interests:<section prefix="1.">may place the child:</section><section prefix="2.">may direct provision of services by a local department to:</section><section prefix="3.">subject to a local department retaining legal guardianship, may award to a caregiver limited authority to make an emergency or ordinary decision as to the child's care, education, mental or physical health, or welfare;</section><section prefix="4.">may allow access to a medical or other record of the child;</section><section prefix="5.">may allow visitation for the child with a specific individual;</section><section prefix="6.">may appoint, or continue the appointment of, a court-appointed special advocate for any purpose set forth under &#xA7; 3-830 of the Courts Article;</section><section prefix="7.">shall direct the provision of any other service or taking of any other action as to the child's education, health, and welfare, including:</section><section prefix="8.">may co-commit the child to the custody of the Department of Health and Mental Hygiene and order the Department of Health and Mental Hygiene to provide a plan for the child of clinically appropriate services in the least restrictive setting, in accordance with federal and State law;</section></section><section prefix="(iii)">if entered under &#xA7; 5-322 of this subtitle, shall state each party's response to the petition;</section><section prefix="(iv)">shall state a specific factual finding on whether reasonable efforts have been made to finalize the child's permanency plan;</section><section prefix="(v)">shall state whether the child's parent has waived the right to notice; and</section><section prefix="(vi)">shall set a date, no later than 180 days after the date of the order, for the initial guardianship review hearing under &#xA7; 5-326 of this subtitle.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Except for emergency commitment in accordance with &#xA7; 10-617 of the Health - General Article or as expressly authorized by a juvenile court in accordance with the standards in &#xA7; 3-819(h) or (i) of the Courts Article, a child may not be committed or otherwise placed for inpatient care or treatment in a psychiatric facility or a facility for the developmentally disabled.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">A juvenile court shall include in a commitment order under this paragraph a requirement that the guardian:<section prefix="1.">file a progress report with the juvenile court at least every 180 days; and</section><section prefix="2.">provide a copy of each report to each person entitled to notice of a review hearing under &#xA7; 5-326 of this subtitle.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">Every 180 days during a commitment or placement under this paragraph, a juvenile court shall hold a hearing to determine whether the standards in &#xA7; 3-819(h) or (i) of the Courts Article continue to be met.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A juvenile court shall send a copy of an order entered under this section to:<section prefix="(1)">each party or, if represented, counsel;</section><section prefix="(2)">each of the child's living parents who has not waived the right to notice;</section><section prefix="(3)">each living parent's last attorney of record in the CINA case; and</section><section prefix="(4)">the child's last attorney of record in the CINA case.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
