<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gfl" order_by="gfl" level="1">Family Law</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gfl-5-505</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this section the following words have the meanings indicated....</catch_line>
  <order_by>505</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Beaded chain" means a series of small spheres, equally spaced on a cord or connected by metal shafts used to raise and lower a window covering.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Cord loop" means a curving or doubling of a beaded chain or cord to form a closed loop.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">"Cordless window covering" means:<section prefix="(i)">a horizontal blind or cellular shade that has no draw cord and the internal lift cord runs in the slats of the horizontal blind so that the cord is incapable of forming a loop greater than 7.25 inches;</section><section prefix="(ii)">a Roman shade, roll-up blind, or woven shade that has no draw cord and the lift cord is completely enclosed so that it is not accessible;</section><section prefix="(iii)">a vertical blind that has a wand as its operating mechanism and does not contain any beaded chains, corded pulleys, or other cord loop operating mechanisms; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">a roller shade that does not contain a cord or beaded chain.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(5)">"Draw cord" means any form of rope, strap, or string used to raise or lower a window covering.</section>
      <section prefix="(6)">"Internal lift cord" means a cord that is contained inside the body and rails of the blind or shade.</section>
      <section prefix="(7)">"Wand" means a rod used to:<section prefix="(i)">rotate a vertical blind; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">tilt a horizontal blind.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">This section applies only to foster homes, family child care homes, large family child care homes, and child care centers in the State.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">All new and replacement window coverings installed on or after October 1, 2010, shall be cordless window coverings.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">All window coverings in place before October 1, 2010, shall meet minimum safety standards established in regulations jointly adopted by the Department and the State Department of Education that include standards for:<section prefix="(i)">Roman shades, roll-up shades, woven shades, and all window coverings with exposed and unsecured cords;</section><section prefix="(ii)">horizontal blinds, cellular shades, and all window coverings that have draw cords for their operation; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">vertical blinds and other window covering products with loops utilized in their operation.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">If a person fails to comply with the requirements of subsection (c)(2) of this section, the appropriate agency may require replacement of existing window coverings with cordless window coverings.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
