<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gfl" order_by="" level="1">Family Law</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gfl-5-1010</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>1010</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">A complaint need not be in any particular form.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The complaint shall be written in simple, nontechnical language.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The complaint shall state the facts on which the complaint is based.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as otherwise provided in this subsection, a complaint filed under this subtitle shall be supported by the oath of the mother or pregnant woman, whether or not she is a party to the paternity proceeding.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The complaint may be filed without the oath if the mother or pregnant woman:<section prefix="(i)">is dead;</section><section prefix="(ii)">refuses to file a complaint;</section><section prefix="(iii)">refuses to disclose the identity of the father of the child;</section><section prefix="(iv)">is mentally or physically incapable of making an oath; or</section><section prefix="(v)">refuses to make the oath.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">If the complaint is filed without an oath under paragraph (2) of this subsection:<section prefix="(i)">the complainant shall verify the fact of the pregnancy or birth; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">if the mother or pregnant woman is living, she shall be made a defendant.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, the clerk of court may not receive a complaint starting paternity proceedings unless the consent of the State's Attorney is attached to the complaint.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The consent of the State's Attorney is not required if:<section prefix="(i)">the complaint is filed on behalf of the Administration; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">after considering testimony or information given by affidavit, or both, the court:<section prefix="1.">finds that the complaint is meritorious; and</section><section prefix="2.">rules that the consent is not required.</section></section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Except by an order of court for good cause shown, a proceeding under this subtitle may not be dismissed voluntarily without the consent of the State's Attorney.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
