<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gfl" order_by="gfl" level="1">Family Law</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gfl-2-402</section_number>
  <catch_line>An applicant for a license may apply to the clerk only at the office of the clerk during regular off...</catch_line>
  <order_by>402</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">An applicant for a license may apply to the clerk only at the office of the clerk during regular office hours.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Except as provided in subsections (d) and (e) of this section, to apply for a license, 1 of the parties to be married shall:<section prefix="(1)">appear before the clerk and give, under oath, the following information, which shall be placed on an application form by the clerk:<section prefix="(i)">the full name of each party;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the place of residence of each party;</section><section prefix="(iii)">the age of each party;</section><section prefix="(iv)">whether the parties are related by blood or marriage and, if so, in which degree of relationship;</section><section prefix="(v)">the marital status of each party; and</section><section prefix="(vi)">whether either party was married previously, and the date and place of each death or judicial determination that ended any former marriage;</section></section><section prefix="(2)">sign the application form; and</section><section prefix="(3)">provide the clerk with the Social Security number of each party who has a Social Security number.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Social Security numbers of the parties:<section prefix="(1)">shall be included in the electronic file for the marriage license application; and</section><section prefix="(2)">except as provided in &#xA7; 10-617 of the State Government Article, may not be disclosed as part of the public record of the marriage license application.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">If the parties to be married are not residents of the county where the marriage ceremony is to be performed, the clerk shall accept, instead of the application specified in subsection (b) of this section, an affidavit from 1 of the parties to be married. The affidavit shall:<section prefix="(1)">contain the information required by subsection (b) of this section; and</section><section prefix="(2)">be sworn to under oath before a clerk or other comparable official in the county, state, province, or country where the party resides.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">In Cecil County both parties to be married shall appear together before the clerk to apply for a license.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">Until a license becomes effective, a clerk may not disclose the fact that an application for a license has been made except to the parent or guardian of a party to be married.</section>
  </text>
</law>
