<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gfl" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="5-584" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gfl-5-584</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In addition to any other provision of law relating to child abuse and neglect, a local department that receives a report of suspected child abuse under &#xA7; 5-704 or &#xA7; 5-705 of this title that concerns a child care center, shall notify the State Superintendent's designee within 48 hours.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">On receipt of the notification required under subsection (a) of this section, the State Superintendent's designee shall convene, either in person or by telephone, a multidisciplinary team to coordinate procedures in accordance with the agreement developed under &#xA7; 5-706(f) of this title to be followed in investigating and otherwise responding to the report.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The multidisciplinary team shall be chaired by the State Superintendent's designee and shall include:<section prefix="(1)">representatives of the local department and law enforcement agency that are investigating the report under &#xA7; 5-706 of this title;</section><section prefix="(2)">representation from the office of the local State's Attorney; and</section><section prefix="(3)">appropriate medical, including mental health, expertise.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the members of the multidisciplinary team shall share information necessary to carry out the team's responsibility under this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">Any information shared by the multidisciplinary team shall be confidential and may be disclosed only in accordance with the provisions of &#xA7;&#xA7; 1-201, 1-202, 1-204, and 1-205 of the Human Services Article.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">On request, the Department of State Police shall provide technical assistance to a local law enforcement agency which is investigating a report of suspected child abuse concerning a child care center.</section>
  </text>
</law>
