<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gfl" order_by="" level="1">Family Law</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gfl-5-1201</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>1201</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"At-risk parent" means a parent of a child entering out-of-home placement or identified as at risk of entering out-of-home placement.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Child welfare personnel" means paraprofessionals, caseworkers, casework supervisors, and administrators who work in child welfare programs administered by the Department.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Repealed.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"Cross-training" means training of both child welfare and substance abuse treatment personnel, provided by qualified trainers with an approved curriculum in essential areas, including both substance abuse and child welfare practices, procedures, and laws.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">Repealed.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">"Out-of-home placement" means placement of a child into foster care, kinship care, group care, or residential treatment care.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">"Qualified addictions specialist" means an individual who meets the qualifications for substance abuse counseling and screening established by the Department of Health and Mental Hygiene.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">"Substance abuse testing" means testing that is performed by urinalysis, breathalyzer, dip stick, blood testing, or hair analysis to determine if an individual has used either drugs or alcohol.</section>
    <section prefix="(j)">"Substance abuse treatment" means a program that provides the intensity and type of treatment needed for parents and their children to maximize the likelihood of long-term abstinence, including detoxification, intensive outpatient treatment, intermediate care and other residential treatment (including programs in which parents and their children can live and receive treatment together), and aftercare programs such as transitional housing.</section>
    <section prefix="(k)">"Substance abuse treatment personnel" means personnel who work in a substance abuse treatment program.</section>
  </text>
</law>
