<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gfl" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="4-506" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gfl-4-506</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">A respondent under &#xA7; 4-505 of this subtitle shall have an opportunity to be heard on the question of whether the judge should issue a final protective order.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The temporary protective order shall state the date and time of the final protective order hearing.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">Except as provided in &#xA7; 4-505(c) of this subtitle, or unless continued for good cause, the final protective order hearing shall be held no later than 7 days after the temporary protective order is served on the respondent.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The temporary protective order shall include notice to the respondent:<section prefix="(i)">in at least 10-point bold type, that if the respondent fails to appear at the final protective order hearing, the respondent may be served by first-class mail at the respondent's last known address with the final protective order and all other notices concerning the final protective order;</section><section prefix="(ii)">specifying all the possible forms of relief under subsection (d) of this section that the final protective order may contain;</section><section prefix="(iii)">that the final protective order shall be effective for the period stated in the order, not to exceed 1 year or, under the circumstances described in subsection (i)(2) of this section, 2 years, unless the judge extends the term of the order under &#xA7; 4-507(a)(2) of this subtitle or the court issues a permanent order under subsection (j) of this section; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">in at least 10-point bold type, that the respondent must notify the court in writing of any change of address.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If the respondent appears before the court at a protective order hearing or has been served with an interim or temporary protective order, or the court otherwise has personal jurisdiction over the respondent, the judge:<section prefix="(i)">may proceed with the final protective order hearing; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">if the judge finds by clear and convincing evidence that the alleged abuse has occurred, or if the respondent consents to the entry of a protective order, the judge may grant a final protective order to protect any person eligible for relief from abuse.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A final protective order may be issued only to a person who has filed a petition under &#xA7; 4-504 of this subtitle.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Subject to the provisions of subparagraph (ii) of this paragraph, in cases where both parties file a petition under &#xA7; 4-504 of this subtitle, the judge may issue mutual protective orders if the judge finds by clear and convincing evidence that mutual abuse has occurred.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The judge may issue mutual final protective orders only if the judge makes a detailed finding of fact that:</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The final protective order may include any or all of the following relief:<section prefix="(1)">order the respondent to refrain from abusing or threatening to abuse any person eligible for relief;</section><section prefix="(2)">order the respondent to refrain from contacting, attempting to contact, or harassing any person eligible for relief;</section><section prefix="(3)">order the respondent to refrain from entering the residence of any person eligible for relief;</section><section prefix="(4)">where the person eligible for relief and the respondent are residing together at the time of the abuse, order the respondent to vacate the home immediately and award temporary use and possession of the home to the person eligible for relief or, in the case of alleged abuse of a child or alleged abuse of a vulnerable adult, award temporary use and possession of the home to an adult living in the home, provided that the court may not grant an order to vacate and award temporary use and possession of the home to a nonspouse person eligible for relief unless the name of the person eligible for relief appears on the lease or deed to the home or the person eligible for relief has shared the home with the respondent for a period of at least 90 days within 1 year before the filing of the petition;</section><section prefix="(5)">order the respondent to remain away from the place of employment, school, or temporary residence of a person eligible for relief or home of other family members;</section><section prefix="(6)">order the respondent to remain away from a child care provider of a person eligible for relief while a child of the person is in the care of the child care provider;</section><section prefix="(7)">award temporary custody of a minor child of the respondent and a person eligible for relief;</section><section prefix="(8)">establish temporary visitation with a minor child of the respondent and a person eligible for relief on a basis which gives primary consideration to the welfare of the minor child and the safety of any other person eligible for relief. If the court finds that the safety of a person eligible for relief will be jeopardized by unsupervised or unrestricted visitation, the court shall condition or restrict visitation as to time, place, duration, or supervision, or deny visitation entirely, as needed to guard the safety of any person eligible for relief;</section><section prefix="(9)">award emergency family maintenance as necessary to support any person eligible for relief to whom the respondent has a duty of support under this article, including an immediate and continuing withholding order on all earnings of the respondent in the amount of the ordered emergency family maintenance in accordance with the procedures specified in Title 10, Subtitle 1, Part III of this article;</section><section prefix="(10)">award temporary use and possession of a vehicle jointly owned by the respondent and a person eligible for relief to the person eligible for relief if necessary for the employment of the person eligible for relief or for the care of a minor child of the respondent or a person eligible for relief;</section><section prefix="(11)">direct the respondent or any or all of the persons eligible for relief to participate in professionally supervised counseling or a domestic violence program;</section><section prefix="(12)">order the respondent to pay filing fees and costs of a proceeding under this subtitle; or</section><section prefix="(13)">award temporary possession of any pet of the person eligible for relief or the respondent.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Before granting, denying, or modifying a final protective order under this section, the court shall review all open and shielded court records involving the person eligible for relief and the respondent, including records of proceedings under:<section prefix="(i)">the Criminal Law Article;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Title 3, Subtitle 15 of the Courts Article; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">this article.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The court's failure to review records under this subsection does not affect the validity of an order issued under this section.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The final protective order shall order the respondent to surrender to law enforcement authorities any firearm in the respondent's possession, and to refrain from possession of any firearm, for the duration of the protective order.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">If the judge awards temporary custody of a minor child under subsection (d)(7) of this section, the judge may order a law enforcement officer to use all reasonable and necessary force to return the minor child to the custodial parent after service of the final protective order.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">In determining whether to order the respondent to vacate the home under &#xA7; 4-505(a)(2)(iv) of this subtitle or subsection (d)(4) of this section, the judge shall consider the following factors:<section prefix="(1)">the housing needs of any minor child living in the home;</section><section prefix="(2)">the duration of the relationship between the respondent and any person eligible for relief;</section><section prefix="(3)">title to the home;</section><section prefix="(4)">pendency and type of criminal charges against the respondent;</section><section prefix="(5)">the history and severity of abuse in the relationship between the respondent and any person eligible for relief;</section><section prefix="(6)">the existence of alternative housing for the respondent and any person eligible for relief; and</section><section prefix="(7)">the financial resources of the respondent and the person eligible for relief.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(i)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A copy of the final protective order shall be served on the petitioner, the respondent, any affected person eligible for relief, the appropriate law enforcement agency, and any other person the judge determines is appropriate, in open court or, if the person is not present at the final protective order hearing, by first-class mail to the person's last known address.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A copy of the final protective order served on the respondent in accordance with paragraph (1) of this subsection constitutes actual notice to the respondent of the contents of the final protective order. Service is complete upon mailing.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(j)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in paragraphs (2) and (3) of this subsection, all relief granted in a final protective order shall be effective for the period stated in the order, not to exceed 1 year.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">All relief granted in a final protective order shall be effective for the period stated in the order, not to exceed 2 years if:<section prefix="(i)">the court issues a final protective order under this section against a respondent on behalf of a person eligible for relief for an act of abuse committed within 1 year after the date that a prior final protective order issued against the same respondent on behalf of the same person eligible for relief expires; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">the prior final protective order was issued for a period of at least 6 months.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A subsequent circuit court order pertaining to any of the provisions included in the final protective order shall supersede those provisions in the final protective order.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(k)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Notwithstanding any other provision of this section, the court shall issue a new final protective order against an individual if:<section prefix="(i)">the individual was previously a respondent under this subtitle against whom a final protective order was issued;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the individual was convicted and served a term of imprisonment of at least 5 years under &#xA7; 2-205, &#xA7; 2-206, &#xA7; 3-202, &#xA7; 3-303, &#xA7; 3-304, &#xA7; 3-305, &#xA7; 3-306, &#xA7; 3-309, &#xA7; 3-310, &#xA7; 3-311, or &#xA7; 3-312 of the Criminal Law Article for the act of abuse that led to the issuance of the final protective order; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">the victim of the abuse who was the person eligible for relief in the original final protective order requests the issuance of a new final protective order.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">In a final protective order issued under this subsection, the court may grant only the relief that was granted in the original protective order under subsection (d)(1) or (2) of this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Unless terminated at the request of the victim, a final protective order issued under this subsection shall be permanent.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
