<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gfl" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="2-503" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gfl-2-503</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">At the intervals that the Secretary of Health and Mental Hygiene sets, each clerk shall send to the Secretary:<section prefix="(1)">a copy of the record of each marriage that the clerk licenses and records;</section><section prefix="(2)">a report of each divorce that the court grants;</section><section prefix="(3)">a report of each annulment of a marriage that the court:<section prefix="(i)">grants; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">effects by entering a conviction of bigamy or of marrying within any prohibited degree; and</section></section><section prefix="(4)">a report of any change in a marriage, divorce, or annulment record, in which the clerk shall certify that the change is correct and conforms to the corresponding record of the clerk.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The report of a divorce or annulment or of a change in a marriage, divorce, or annulment record shall be made on the form that the Secretary of Health and Mental Hygiene provides.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Secretary of Health and Mental Hygiene may make photostatic, photographic, or microphotographic copies of the original marriage records of a clerk.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Secretary of Health and Mental Hygiene may not remove any original marriage record from the custody of the clerk.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Secretary of Health and Mental Hygiene shall:<section prefix="(i)">make the copies in a manner that does not interfere with the orderly transaction of business by the clerk; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">bear the cost of making the copies.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The clerk may not receive any extra compensation for sending a report or record to the Secretary or for making records available to the Secretary.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">A clerk who violates any provision of this section is guilty of a misdemeanor and on conviction is subject to a fine of $10 for each offense.</section>
  </text>
</law>
