<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gfl" order_by="gfl" level="1">Family Law</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gfl-9.5-310</section_number>
  <catch_line>Unless the court issues a temporary emergency order in accordance with &#xA7; 9.5-204 of this title, on ...</catch_line>
  <order_by>310</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Unless the court issues a temporary emergency order in accordance with &#xA7; 9.5-204 of this title, on a finding that a petitioner is entitled to immediate physical custody of the child, the court shall order that the petitioner may take immediate physical custody of the child unless the respondent establishes that:<section prefix="(1)">the child custody determination has not been registered and confirmed under &#xA7; 9.5-305 of this subtitle and that:<section prefix="(i)">the issuing court did not have jurisdiction under Subtitle 2 of this title;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the child custody determination for which enforcement is sought has been vacated, stayed, or modified by a court of a state having jurisdiction to do so under Subtitle 2 of this title; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">the respondent was entitled to notice, but notice was not given in accordance with the standards of &#xA7; 9.5-107 of this title, in the proceedings before the court that issued the order for which enforcement is sought; or</section></section><section prefix="(2)">the child custody determination for which enforcement is sought was registered and confirmed under &#xA7; 9.5-305 of this subtitle but has been vacated, stayed, or modified by a court of a state having jurisdiction to do so under Subtitle 2 of this title.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The court shall award the fees, costs, and expenses authorized under &#xA7; 9.5-312 of this subtitle and may grant additional relief, including a request for the assistance of law enforcement officials, and set a further hearing to determine whether additional relief is appropriate.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">If a party called to testify refuses to answer on the ground that the testimony may be self-incriminating, the court may draw an adverse inference from the refusal.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A privilege against disclosure of communications between spouses and a defense of immunity based on the relationship of husband and wife or parent and child may not be invoked in a proceeding under this subtitle.</section>
  </text>
</law>
