<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gfl" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="12-102" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gfl-12-102</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Accessible" means health insurance coverage that insures primary care services located within the lesser of 30 miles or 30 minutes from the child's primary residence.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Actual income" has the meaning stated in &#xA7; 12-201(b) of this title.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">"Adjusted actual income" has the meaning stated in &#xA7; 12-201 of this title.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">"Basic child support obligation" has the meaning stated in &#xA7; 12-201 of this title.</section>
      <section prefix="(6)">"Cash medical support" means an amount paid:<section prefix="(i)">toward the cost of health insurance provided by:</section><section prefix="(ii)">for other medical costs not covered by insurance, including extraordinary medical expenses.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(7)">"Extraordinary medical expenses" has the meaning stated in &#xA7; 12-201 of this title.</section>
      <section prefix="(8)">"Health insurance coverage" means any type of health care coverage under which medical care services can be provided to the child through an insurer.</section>
      <section prefix="(9)">"Insurer" means:<section prefix="(i)">an insurer, a nonprofit health service organization, or a health maintenance organization operating in this State under a certificate of authority issued by the Maryland Insurance Commissioner;</section><section prefix="(ii)">an entity that provides a group health plan, as defined in &#xA7; 607(1) of the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">an entity offering a service benefit plan as defined by federal law.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(10)">"Medical support notice" means a notice that is:<section prefix="(i)">in a format prescribed by federal law; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">issued by a child support agency to enforce the health insurance coverage provisions of a child support order.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(11)">"Tribunal" has the meaning stated in &#xA7; 10-301 of this article.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Except as provided in subsection (c) of this section, the court may include in any support order a provision requiring either parent to include the child in the parent's health insurance coverage if:<section prefix="(1)">the parent can obtain health insurance coverage through an employer or any form of group health insurance coverage; and</section><section prefix="(2)">the child can be included at a reasonable cost to the parent in that health insurance coverage.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This subsection applies only to a child support order under Title IV, Part D of the Social Security Act.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The court shall include in any support order that is established or modified a provision requiring one or both parents to include the child in the parent's health insurance coverage if:</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">For purposes of subparagraph (i)2 of this paragraph, the cost of health insurance coverage is reasonable if the cost of adding the child to existing health insurance coverage, or the difference between self-only and family coverage, does not exceed 5% of the actual income of the parent ordered to pay for health insurance coverage.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">If health insurance coverage at a reasonable cost is not available at the time a support order is established or modified, the court:<section prefix="(i)">may include a provision requiring one or both parents to include the child in the parent's health insurance coverage as described in paragraph (2) of this subsection if health insurance coverage at a reasonable cost becomes available in the future; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">shall include a provision requiring one or both parents to provide cash medical support in an amount not to exceed 5% of the actual income of the parent ordered to provide cash medical support.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">In addition to requiring one or both parents to provide health insurance coverage, the court may order one or both parents to provide cash medical support in an amount not to exceed 5% of the actual income of the parent ordered to provide cash medical support.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">Cash medical support ordered under this subsection shall be added to the basic child support obligation and divided by the parents in proportion to their adjusted actual incomes.</section>
      <section prefix="(6)">The court may not order the obligee to pay cash medical support toward the cost of health insurance provided by a public entity for which the obligee does not pay a premium, including the Maryland Children's Health Program under Title 15, Subtitle 3 of the Health - General Article.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">An order of a court requiring the provision of health insurance coverage for a child may be issued separate from or in conjunction with an earnings withholding order.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If a court orders a parent to provide health insurance coverage under this section, the parent under the order or the support enforcement agency shall send a copy of the order or medical support notice to the parent's employer by first-class mail, separate from or in conjunction with an earnings withholding order, as provided in &#xA7; 10-123 of this article.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Within 20 business days after the receipt of the order or medical support notice, the employer shall:<section prefix="(i)">send the appropriate part of the medical support notice to the employer's insurer;</section><section prefix="(ii)">if the employer determines that, based on reasons related to the employee's employment status, the employee's child is ineligible for health insurance coverage, complete the appropriate part of the medical support notice and return it to the issuing child support agency;</section><section prefix="(iii)">permit the parent, a child support enforcement agency, or the Department of Health and Mental Hygiene to enroll the child in any health insurance coverage available to the parent without regard to any enrollment season restrictions;</section><section prefix="(iv)">provide a statement to the support enforcement agency and to both parents that the child:</section><section prefix="(v)">provide information to both parents and to the support enforcement agency concerning the available health insurance coverage, including:</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">On receipt of the order or medical support notice, the employer:<section prefix="(1)">if the employee's child is eligible for health insurance coverage, shall withhold from the employee's next earnings the amount of the employee contribution required to enroll the employee's child;</section><section prefix="(2)">if the employee's child is not currently eligible for health insurance coverage but will become eligible, shall withhold from the employee's earnings, at the earliest time the employee's child becomes eligible, the amount of the employee contribution required to enroll the employee's child; or</section><section prefix="(3)">if federal or State withholding limitations or prioritization prevent withholding from the employee's wages the amount required for enrollment, shall complete and send, to the issuing child support agency, the appropriate part of the medical support notice indicating the employee's income is insufficient for enrollment.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">To the extent consistent with the federal Consumer Credit Protection Act, the employer shall deduct the premiums for health insurance coverage from the earnings of the employee on a regular and continuing basis and pay the premiums to the insurer.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The employer shall send to the insurer the amount deducted from the employee's earnings each pay period within 10 business days after the day on which the earnings are paid to the employee.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(h)">An employer or the child's parents may not disenroll or eliminate coverage for the child in any manner unless:<section prefix="(1)">the employer is provided satisfactory written evidence that:<section prefix="(i)">the court order is no longer in effect; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">the child has been or will be enrolled under other reasonable health insurance coverage, with the coverage to take effect no later than the effective date of disenrollment;</section></section><section prefix="(2)">the employer has eliminated family health coverage for all of its employees; or</section><section prefix="(3)">the employer no longer employs the parent under whose name the child has been enrolled for coverage except to the extent that if the parent elects to exercise the provisions of the Consolidated Omnibus Budget Reconciliation Act of 1985 (COBRA) then coverage must be provided for the child consistent with the employer's plan relating to postemployment medical coverage for dependents.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(i)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If the health insurance coverage for the child terminates, the employer shall notify the other parent and, if a support enforcement agency is involved in the case, the support enforcement agency within 15 days of termination of the insurance.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If, after a lapse in health insurance coverage, health insurance coverage becomes available to the employee for the child, the employer shall:<section prefix="(i)">enroll the child in health insurance coverage without regard to any enrollment season restrictions; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">within 15 days after health insurance coverage becomes available, provide notice to the support enforcement agency and the other parent of the enrollment.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(j)">Subject to the provisions of this section, the parent or the support enforcement agency may bring a civil action against an employer who willfully violates the provisions of this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(k)">This section does not limit the authority of a court to enter, modify, or enforce an order requiring payment of uninsured health expenses, health care costs, or health insurance premiums.</section>
    <section prefix="(l)">An employer may not use the existence of an order or a medical support notice requiring health insurance coverage as a basis for:<section prefix="(1)">reprisal against an employee;</section><section prefix="(2)">dismissal of an employee from employment; or</section><section prefix="(3)">refusal to hire a person or to promote an employee.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(m)">An order entered under this section is binding on a present and future employer of the parent on whom a copy of this order is served.</section>
  </text>
</law>
