<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gfl" order_by="gfl" level="1">Family Law</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gfl-5-350</section_number>
  <catch_line>A juvenile court may enter an order for a child's adoption under this Part IV of this subtitle only ...</catch_line>
  <order_by>350</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">A juvenile court may enter an order for a child's adoption under this Part IV of this subtitle only if:<section prefix="(1)">for an individual under the age of 18 years, the individual's guardian consents; and</section><section prefix="(2)">for an individual who is at least 10 years old, the individual consents.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">In this subsection, "disability" means:<section prefix="1.">a physical disability, infirmity, malformation, or disfigurement that is caused by bodily injury, birth defect, or illness, including epilepsy;</section><section prefix="2.">a mental impairment or deficiency;</section><section prefix="3.">a record of having a physical or mental impairment as defined under this paragraph; or</section><section prefix="4.">being regarded as having a physical or mental impairment as defined under this paragraph.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">"Disability" includes:<section prefix="1.">any degree of paralysis or amputation;</section><section prefix="2.">blindness or visual impairment;</section><section prefix="3.">deafness or hearing impairment;</section><section prefix="4.">muteness or speech impediment;</section><section prefix="5.">physical reliance on a service animal or a wheelchair or other remedial appliance or device; and</section><section prefix="6.">intellectual disability, as defined in &#xA7; 7-101 of the Health - General Article, and any other mental impairment or deficiency that may have necessitated remedial or special education and related services.</section></section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A guardian may not withhold consent for the sole reason that:<section prefix="(i)">the race, religion, color, or national origin of a prospective adoptive parent differs from that of the child or parent; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">a prospective adoptive parent has a disability.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
