<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gfl" order_by="gfl" level="1">Family Law</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gfl-12-105</section_number>
  <catch_line>The Child Support Enforcement Administration of the Department of Human Resources shall maintain a c...</catch_line>
  <order_by>105</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Child Support Enforcement Administration of the Department of Human Resources shall maintain a central registry of records of all identifying information that relates to parents who have deserted or who appear to have deserted their children.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Child Support Enforcement Administration shall list these parents in the registry whether or not their children are likely to become recipients of public assistance or foster care.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">In accordance with subsections (c) and (d) of this section, to carry out the purposes of this section, the Child Support Enforcement Administration may receive from any agency of this State, political subdivision of this State, employer, public service company, energy provider, or labor union information and assistance that will enable the Child Support Enforcement Administration, the local enforcement office, or the State's Attorney for the county involved:<section prefix="(1)">to locate an absent parent or a parent who has deserted or appears to have deserted a child;</section><section prefix="(2)">to enforce the liability of the parent for the support of a child of the parent; or</section><section prefix="(3)">to obtain other financial and location information concerning parents and putative fathers needed by the Administration to carry out its responsibilities under State and federal law.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Upon written request by the Child Support Enforcement Administration, any agency of this State, political subdivision of this State, employer, or labor union shall provide, if available, a person's:<section prefix="(i)">Social Security account number;</section><section prefix="(ii)">date of birth;</section><section prefix="(iii)">last known residence or mailing address;</section><section prefix="(iv)">present or last known employer;</section><section prefix="(v)">length of employment;</section><section prefix="(vi)">job classification;</section><section prefix="(vii)">name of person to be notified in case of emergency and the person's residence;</section><section prefix="(viii)">work hours;</section><section prefix="(ix)">amounts of wages or other assets; and</section><section prefix="(x)">medical insurance provider.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">As to individuals who were employed within the 3 years preceding a request for information by the Child Support Enforcement Administration, the State agency, political subdivision, employer, or labor union shall provide whatever information is available.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Upon request and a showing of cause by the Child Support Enforcement Administration, a circuit court may issue an order requiring an employer or labor union to comply with a request for information under this section.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">If an employer or labor union refuses to provide information from its employee or member files as required by an order by a circuit court issued under this paragraph, the employer or labor union shall be in contempt of court.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In accordance with a subpoena issued by the Administration under &#xA7; 10-108.6 of this article, a public service company or energy provider shall provide, if available:<section prefix="(i)">a person's name and address; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">the name and address of the person's employer.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If a public service company or energy provider fails to comply with a subpoena issued by the Administration, the Administration shall have available the remedies provided under &#xA7; 10-108.4 of this article.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">An employer, public service company, energy provider, or labor union that complies with a request from the Administration made under this section is not liable under State law to any person for any:<section prefix="(1)">disclosure of information to the Administration under this section; or</section><section prefix="(2)">other action taken in good faith to comply with the requirements of this section.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">Any record compiled from information provided under this section shall be available only to:<section prefix="(1)">an authorized representative of this State or of a local department of this State; or</section><section prefix="(2)">a person who has a statutory right to the records in an official capacity.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
