<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gfl" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="5-307" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gfl-5-307</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Unless the public defender is required under &#xA7; 16-204 of the Criminal Procedure Article to provide representation, in a case under Part II or Part III of this subtitle, a juvenile court shall appoint an attorney to represent a parent who:<section prefix="(i)">has a disability that makes the parent incapable of effectively participating in the case; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">when a petition for guardianship or adoption is filed or consent to guardianship or adoption is given, is a minor.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">To determine whether a disability makes a parent incapable of effectively participating in a case, a juvenile court, on its own motion or motion of a party, may order examination of the parent.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In accordance with paragraph (2) of this subsection, in a case under this subtitle, a juvenile court shall appoint an attorney to represent a child.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Unless a juvenile court finds that it is not in a child's best interests, the juvenile court:<section prefix="(i)">if the attorney who currently represents the child in a pending CINA case or guardianship case is under contract with the Department to provide services under this subsection, shall appoint that attorney; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">if the attorney who currently represents the child is not under contract with the Department, shall strike the appearance of that attorney.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">An attorney or firm may represent more than one party in a case under this subtitle only if the Maryland Lawyers' Rules of Professional Conduct allow.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">An attorney appointed under this section may be compensated for reasonable fees, as approved by a juvenile court.</section>
  </text>
</law>
