<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gfl" order_by="" level="1">Family Law</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gfl-5-564</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>564</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The Department shall conduct the criminal history records check and issue the printed statement provided for under this Part VI of this subtitle.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">It shall update an initial criminal history records check for an employee, employer, or individual identified in &#xA7; 5-561(c), (d), (e), or (f) of this subtitle and issue a revised printed statement in accordance with federal law and regulations on dissemination of FBI identification records.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Department shall adopt regulations requiring:<section prefix="(i)">employers to verify periodically the continuing employment of an employee and the continuing assignment of a volunteer;</section><section prefix="(ii)">State or local agencies that license, register, approve, or certify any of the facilities identified in &#xA7; 5-561(b) of this subtitle to verify periodically the continuing licensure, registration, approval, or certification of a facility or the continuing assignment of individuals identified in &#xA7; 5-561(e) of this subtitle; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">child placement agencies that place a child as described in &#xA7; 5-561(c) of this subtitle to verify periodically the continuing participation or presence of individuals identified in &#xA7; 5-561(c) of this subtitle.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The employee, employer, volunteer, or other individual identified in &#xA7; 5-561 of this subtitle is not responsible for payment of any fee to update criminal history records checks.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Department shall provide an initial and a revised statement of the applicant's State criminal record to:<section prefix="(i)">the recipients of the printed statement specified in subsection (c) of this section; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">the State Department of Education if the applicant is an employee of:<section prefix="1.">a child care center that is required to be licensed or to hold a letter of compliance under Part VII of this subtitle; or</section><section prefix="2.">a family child care home or large family child care home that is required to be registered under Part V of this subtitle.</section></section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Department shall distribute the printed statement in accordance with federal law and regulations on dissemination of FBI identification records.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Upon completion of the criminal history records check of an employee, the Department shall submit the printed statement to:<section prefix="(i)">the employee's current or prospective employer at the facility or program;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the employee; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">for an employee of a child care center that is required to be licensed or to hold a letter of compliance under Part VII of this subtitle or an employee of a family child care home that is required to be registered under Part V of this subtitle, the State Department of Education.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Upon receiving a written request from an employee, the Department shall submit the printed statement to additional employers, if the criminal history records check was completed during the prior 180 days.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Upon completion of the criminal history records check of an employer, the Department shall submit the printed statement to:<section prefix="(i)">the appropriate State or local agency responsible for the licensure, registration, approval, or certification of the employer's facility; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">the employer.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">Upon completion of the criminal history records check of an individual identified in &#xA7; 5-561(c), (d), (e), or (f) of this subtitle, the Department shall submit the printed statement to the appropriate child placement or registering agency.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Information obtained from the Department under this Part VI of this subtitle shall be confidential and may be disseminated only to the individual who is the subject of the criminal history records check and to the participants in the hiring or approval process.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">Information obtained from the Department under this Part VI of this subtitle may not:<section prefix="(1)">be used for any purpose other than that for which it was disseminated; or</section><section prefix="(2)">be redisseminated.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">Information obtained from the Department under this Part VI of this subtitle shall be maintained in a manner to insure the security of the information.</section>
  </text>
</law>
