<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gfl" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="5-313" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gfl-5-313</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Except as provided in &#xA7; 5-331 of this subtitle, a petition for guardianship shall precede a petition for adoption under this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Only the individual who would be subject to guardianship or a local department may file a petition for guardianship under this Part II of this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A petition for guardianship of an individual shall be filed before the individual attains 18 years of age.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A petitioner under this section shall attach to a petition:<section prefix="(1)">all written consents for the guardianship that the petitioner has;</section><section prefix="(2)">if applicable:<section prefix="(i)">proof of guardianship or relinquishment of parental rights granted by an administrative, executive, or judicial body of a state or other jurisdiction; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">certification that the guardianship or relinquishment was granted in compliance with the jurisdiction's laws; and</section></section><section prefix="(3)">a notice of filing that:<section prefix="(i)">states the date on which the petition was filed;</section><section prefix="(ii)">identifies each person whose consent was filed with the petition;</section><section prefix="(iii)">states the obligation of a parent to give the juvenile court and local department notice of each change in the parent's address;</section><section prefix="(iv)">has printed on it the website that the Department maintains under &#xA7; 2-302 of the Human Services Article; and</section><section prefix="(v)">includes no identifying information that would be in violation of an agreement or consent.</section></section></section>
  </text>
</law>
