<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gfl" order_by="gfl" level="1">Family Law</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gfl-2-410</section_number>
  <catch_line>Except as provided in this subsection, a judge, clerk, or deputy clerk may not receive any fee, remu...</catch_line>
  <order_by>410</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in this subsection, a judge, clerk, or deputy clerk may not receive any fee, remuneration, or gift for performing a marriage ceremony.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">
          <section prefix="1.">A Maryland judge's fee for performing a marriage ceremony is a nonrefundable fee, payable to the clerk before a marriage license is issued, in the amount of $30 in Cecil County and $25 in any other county.</section>
          <section prefix="2.">The clerk's or deputy clerk's fee for performing a marriage ceremony is $30 in Cecil County and $25 in any other county.</section>
        </section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">Except as provided in paragraph (10) of this subsection, each month the clerk shall pay $10 of each fee collected under this section into the general fund of the county.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">Except as otherwise provided in this subsection, the clerk shall retain the remainder of each fee and deposit and disburse it in the same manner as other fees collected by the clerk.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">In Allegany County, from the remaining $15, the clerk shall pay, quarterly, $2 of each fee to the Allegany County Historical Society.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">
        <section prefix="(i)">In Anne Arundel County, from the remaining $15, the clerk shall pay $4 of each fee to the Annarrundel County Trust for Preservation, Inc.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The Annarrundel County Trust for Preservation, Inc. shall report annually to the Anne Arundel County Executive and the Maryland Historical Trust on the use of all funds received under this section, including a detailed record of the expenditures and receipts of all funds transferred from the Anne Arundel County Committee of the Historical Trust.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">The Anne Arundel County Executive or the Maryland Historical Trust may request at any time an audit of the financial records of the Annarrundel County Trust for Preservation, Inc.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(5)">
        <section prefix="(i)">In Baltimore County, the clerk shall pay the remaining $15 to the Baltimore County Historical Trust, Inc.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The Baltimore County Historical Trust, Inc. shall report annually to the Baltimore County Executive and the Maryland Historical Trust on the use of all funds received under this section, including a detailed record of the expenditures and receipts of all funds collected before July 1, 1987.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">The Baltimore County Executive or the Maryland Historical Trust may request at any time an audit of the financial records of the Baltimore County Historical Trust, Inc.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(6)">In Cecil County:<section prefix="(i)">of the funds remaining after the payment into the general fund of the county under paragraph (2)(ii) of this subsection, the clerk shall pay:<section prefix="1.">$5 of each fee to the Cecil Historical Trust, Incorporated; and</section><section prefix="2.">$5 of each fee to the Historical Society of Cecil County;</section></section><section prefix="(ii)">the Historical Society of Cecil County shall report annually to the Cecil County Commissioners on the use of the funds received under this section;</section><section prefix="(iii)">the Cecil Historical Trust, Incorporated shall report annually to the Cecil County Commissioners and the Maryland Historical Trust on the use of all funds received under this section, including a detailed record of the expenditures and receipts of all funds transferred from the Cecil County Committee of the Maryland Historical Trust; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">the Cecil County Commissioners or the Maryland Historical Trust may request at any time an audit of the financial records of the Cecil Historical Trust, Incorporated.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(7)">In Garrett County, from the remaining $15, the clerk shall pay $5 of each fee to the Garrett County Historical Society.</section>
      <section prefix="(8)">In Montgomery County, from the remaining $15, the clerk shall pay:<section prefix="(i)">$2 of each fee to the Montgomery County Historical Society, Incorporated; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">$3 of each fee into the fund for the enhancement and beautification of the Montgomery County Courthouse and facilities.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(9)">
        <section prefix="(i)">In Prince George's County, from the remaining $15, the clerk shall pay $3 of each fee to Prince George's Heritage, Inc.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">Prince George's Heritage, Inc. shall report annually to the Prince George's County Executive and the Maryland Historical Trust on the use of all funds received under this section, including a detailed record of the expenditures and receipts of all funds collected before July 1, 1987.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">The Prince George's County Executive or the Maryland Historical Trust may request at any time an audit of the financial records of Prince George's Heritage, Inc.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(10)">In Harford County, from the $25 fee for performing a marriage ceremony, the clerk shall pay $20 of each fee to the Historical Society of Harford County, Inc.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A clerk or deputy clerk may not violate any provision of this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A clerk or deputy clerk who violates the provisions of this section is guilty of neglect of duty and on conviction is subject to removal from office.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
