<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gfl" order_by="" level="1">Family Law</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gfl-5-7A-02</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>02</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Council consists of up to 23 members including:<section prefix="(1)">one member of the Senate of Maryland appointed by the President of the Senate;</section><section prefix="(2)">one member of the House of Delegates appointed by the Speaker of the House;</section><section prefix="(3)">a representative of the Department of Human Resources, appointed by the Secretary of Human Resources;</section><section prefix="(4)">a representative of the Department of Health and Mental Hygiene, appointed by the Secretary of Health and Mental Hygiene;</section><section prefix="(5)">a representative of the Maryland State Department of Education, designated by the Superintendent;</section><section prefix="(6)">a representative of the Department of Juvenile Services, designated by the Secretary;</section><section prefix="(7)">a representative of the Judicial Branch, designated by the Chief Judge of the Maryland Court of Appeals;</section><section prefix="(8)">a representative of the State's Attorneys' Association, designated by the Association;</section><section prefix="(9)">a pediatrician with experience in diagnosing and treating injuries and child abuse and neglect, who shall be appointed by the Governor from a list submitted by the Maryland chapter of the American Academy of Pediatrics;</section><section prefix="(10)">members of the general public with interest or expertise in the prevention or treatment of child abuse and neglect who shall be appointed by the Governor and who shall include representatives from professional and advocacy groups, private social service agencies, and the medical, law enforcement, education, and religious communities; and</section><section prefix="(11)">at least two individuals who have personal experience with child abuse and neglect within their own families or who have been clients of the child protective services system who shall be appointed by the Governor.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The term of a member appointed under subsection (a)(9), (10), or (11) of this section is 3 years.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">An appointed member may serve up to two consecutive 3-year terms.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">In case of a vacancy, the Governor shall appoint a successor for the remainder of the unexpired term.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">All other members of the Council shall continue in office so long as they hold the required qualification and designation specified in subsection (a)(1) through (8) of this section.</section>
  </text>
</law>
