<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gfl" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="5-4B-04" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gfl-5-4B-04</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Except as provided in subsection (b) of this section, the Director shall provide the list of confidential intermediaries to an individual who applies for search, contact, and reunion services.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Director shall refer an individual who applies for search, contact, and reunion services to the child placement agency that placed the child for adoption if:<section prefix="(1)">the identity of the child placement agency that placed the child for adoption is known; and</section><section prefix="(2)">the child placement agency is a confidential intermediary, as defined in &#xA7; 5-4B-01 of this subtitle.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If the identity of the child placement agency that placed the child for adoption is unknown, the Director shall make reasonable efforts to determine the identity of the child placement agency that placed the child for adoption.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">For purposes of paragraph (1) of this subsection, the Director shall have access to any information that is contained in a birth record or public record described in &#xA7; 5-4B-06(b)(1) or (c)(1) of this subtitle.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The Director may charge an individual who applies for search, contact, and reunion services a reasonable fee for a search conducted in accordance with paragraph (2) of this subsection.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The overall amount of fees collected may not exceed the costs of providing the search.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The Director shall forward any information obtained from a search conducted in accordance with paragraph (2) of this subsection to the confidential intermediary for purposes of providing search, contact, and reunion services.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
