<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gfl" order_by="gfl" level="1">Family Law</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gfl-5-545</section_number>
  <catch_line>Each local board shall review children in out-of-home care in accordance with the regulations adopte...</catch_line>
  <order_by>545</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Each local board shall review children in out-of-home care in accordance with the regulations adopted by the State Board and the Secretary of Human Resources.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The regulations adopted by the State Board and the Secretary of Human Resources shall require that the local boards review cases based on priorities agreed upon by the Department and the State Board and stated in a memorandum of agreement.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Each local board shall report in writing to the juvenile court and the local department on each minor child whose case is reviewed by the local board.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">In the report, the local board shall include, where applicable, the following findings and recommendations:<section prefix="(1)">	the applicability of provisions authorizing the waiver of reunification services in &#xA7; 3-812 of the Courts Article;</section><section prefix="(2)">the appropriateness of the termination of parental rights for a minor child, including the applicability of the requirements and exceptions described in &#xA7; 5-525.1 of this subtitle;</section><section prefix="(3)">agreement or disagreement with the permanency plan;</section><section prefix="(4)">any reasonable efforts made toward the preservation of family relationships and connections;</section><section prefix="(5)">the identification of barriers to achieve timely permanency;</section><section prefix="(6)">whether the child is receiving appropriate services to achieve the stated permanency goal;</section><section prefix="(7)">any reasonable efforts made towards a permanent placement and preparing the child for independent living, if applicable;</section><section prefix="(8)">the level of safety of current and planned living arrangements and the adequacy of the Department's efforts to keep the child safe;</section><section prefix="(9)">the appropriateness of the current living arrangement and agreement or disagreement with the local department's placement plan;</section><section prefix="(10)">the appropriateness of efforts to meet the child's education and health care needs; and</section><section prefix="(11)">any reasonable efforts made towards promoting the child's relationship with individuals who will play a lasting, supportive role in the child's life.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If the local board finds under subsection (c)(7) of this section that a child's current living arrangement is not appropriate and the child is not placed in the jurisdiction of origin, the local board shall explain why the arrangement is inappropriate, including whether:<section prefix="(i)">resources are not available to meet the child's service needs;</section><section prefix="(ii)">family treatment services are not accessible;</section><section prefix="(iii)">distance is a barrier to family visitation; or</section><section prefix="(iv)">the local school system is not meeting the child's educational needs.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If the local board disagrees under subsection (c)(7) of this section with the local department's placement plan and the child would be placed outside the jurisdiction of origin, the local board shall explain why the plan is inappropriate, including whether:<section prefix="(i)">resources are not available to meet the child's service needs;</section><section prefix="(ii)">family treatment services are not accessible;</section><section prefix="(iii)">distance is a barrier to family visitation; or</section><section prefix="(iv)">the local school system is not meeting the child's educational needs.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The State Board shall tabulate and analyze the results of the case reviews and submit the results and findings for consideration as part of the local department self-assessment process in &#xA7; 5-1309 of this title.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The State Board shall tabulate and analyze results of case reviews, both on a jurisdictional and a statewide basis, and submit the results and findings to the Department on a quarterly basis.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
