<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gfl" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="4-515" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gfl-4-515</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Executive Director shall establish a program in the Governor's Office of Crime Control and Prevention to help victims of domestic violence and their children.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The purpose of the program is to provide for victims of domestic violence and their children, in each region of this State:<section prefix="(i)">temporary shelter or help in obtaining shelter;</section><section prefix="(ii)">counseling;</section><section prefix="(iii)">information;</section><section prefix="(iv)">referral; and</section><section prefix="(v)">rehabilitation.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">As a part of the domestic violence program, there shall be, in a major population center of this State, at least 1 program serving the area.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Any program established under this section shall be subject to the following conditions:<section prefix="(1)">the program shall provide victims of domestic violence and their children with a temporary home and necessary counseling;</section><section prefix="(2)">the Governor's Office of Crime Control and Prevention shall:<section prefix="(i)">supervise the program;</section><section prefix="(ii)">set standards of care and admission policies;</section><section prefix="(iii)">monitor the operation of the program and annually evaluate the effectiveness of the program;</section><section prefix="(iv)">adopt rules and regulations that set fees for services at and govern the operation of each program; and</section><section prefix="(v)">regularly consult, collaborate with, and consider the recommendations of the federally recognized State domestic violence coalition regarding domestic violence programs and policies, practices, and procedures that impact victims of domestic violence and their children;</section></section><section prefix="(3)">the program shall accept from the police or any other referral source in the community any victim of domestic violence and the child of any victim of domestic violence; and</section><section prefix="(4)">housing may not be provided under this subtitle to an applicant for housing who is not a resident of this State at the time the application for housing is made.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">As funds become available, the Executive Director may extend the domestic violence program to other areas in this State.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Expansion of the domestic violence program may include:<section prefix="(i)">establishing additional shelters; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">providing funds and technical assistance to a local organization or agency that shows that it is able and willing to run a domestic violence program.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
