<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gfl" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="4-501" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gfl-4-501</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Abuse" means any of the following acts:<section prefix="(i)">an act that causes serious bodily harm;</section><section prefix="(ii)">an act that places a person eligible for relief in fear of imminent serious bodily harm;</section><section prefix="(iii)">assault in any degree;</section><section prefix="(iv)">rape or sexual offense under &#xA7;&#xA7; 3-303 through 3-308 of the Criminal Law Article or attempted rape or sexual offense in any degree;</section><section prefix="(v)">false imprisonment; or</section><section prefix="(vi)">stalking under &#xA7; 3-802 of the Criminal Law Article.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If the person for whom relief is sought is a child, "abuse" may also include abuse of a child, as defined in Title 5, Subtitle 7 of this article. Nothing in this subtitle shall be construed to prohibit reasonable punishment, including reasonable corporal punishment, in light of the age and condition of the child, from being performed by a parent or stepparent of the child.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">If the person for whom relief is sought is a vulnerable adult, "abuse" may also include abuse of a vulnerable adult, as defined in Title 14, Subtitle 1 of this article.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Child care provider" means a person that provides supervision and care for a minor child.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">"Cohabitant" means a person who has had a sexual relationship with the respondent and resided with the respondent in the home for a period of at least 90 days within 1 year before the filing of the petition.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"Commissioner" means a District Court Commissioner appointed in accordance with Article IV, &#xA7; 41G of the Maryland Constitution.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">"Court" means the District Court or a circuit court in this State.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">"Emergency family maintenance" means a monetary award given to or for a person eligible for relief to whom the respondent has a duty of support under this article based on:<section prefix="(1)">the financial needs of the person eligible for relief; and</section><section prefix="(2)">the resources available to the person eligible for relief and the respondent.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(h)">"Executive Director" means the Executive Director of the Governor's Office of Crime Control and Prevention.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">"Final protective order" means a protective order issued under &#xA7; 4-506 of this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(j)">"Home" means the property in this State that:<section prefix="(1)">is the principal residence of a person eligible for relief; and</section><section prefix="(2)">is owned, rented, or leased by the person eligible for relief or respondent or, in a petition alleging child abuse or abuse of a vulnerable adult, an adult living in the home at the time of a proceeding under this subtitle.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(k)">"Interim protective order" means an order that a Commissioner issues under this subtitle pending a hearing by a judge on a petition.</section>
    <section prefix="(l)">"Local department" means the local department that has jurisdiction in the county:<section prefix="(1)">where the home is located; or</section><section prefix="(2)">if different, where the abuse is alleged to have taken place.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(m)">"Person eligible for relief" includes:<section prefix="(1)">the current or former spouse of the respondent;</section><section prefix="(2)">a cohabitant of the respondent;</section><section prefix="(3)">a person related to the respondent by blood, marriage, or adoption;</section><section prefix="(4)">a parent, stepparent, child, or stepchild of the respondent or the person eligible for relief who resides or resided with the respondent or person eligible for relief for at least 90 days within 1 year before the filing of the petition;</section><section prefix="(5)">a vulnerable adult; or</section><section prefix="(6)">an individual who has a child in common with the respondent.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(n)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Pet" means a domesticated animal.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Pet" does not include livestock.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(o)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Petitioner" means an individual who files a petition.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Petitioner" includes:<section prefix="(i)">a person eligible for relief; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">the following persons who may seek relief from abuse on behalf of a minor or vulnerable adult:</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(p)">"Residence" includes the yard, grounds, outbuildings, and common areas surrounding the residence.</section>
    <section prefix="(q)">"Respondent" means the person alleged in the petition to have committed the abuse.</section>
    <section prefix="(r)">"Temporary protective order" means a protective order issued under &#xA7; 4-505 of this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(s)">"Victim" includes a person eligible for relief.</section>
    <section prefix="(t)">"Vulnerable adult" has the meaning provided in &#xA7; 14-101(q) of this article.</section>
  </text>
</law>
