<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gfl" order_by="gfl" level="1">Family Law</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gfl-10-112.1</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this section, "Program" means the Child Support Payment Incentive Program....</catch_line>
  <order_by>112.1</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, "Program" means the Child Support Payment Incentive Program.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">By June 1, 2008, the Administration shall develop a statewide Child Support Payment Incentive Program to encourage payment of child support in cases in which an assignment has been made under &#xA7; 5-312(b)(2) of the Human Services Article by entering into agreements with child support obligors in exchange for reductions in the amount of arrearages as authorized under &#xA7; 10-112 of this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">To participate in the Program, the obligor's income shall meet the criteria described in &#xA7; 10-112(b)(1)(iii) of this subtitle.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">For purposes of determining the applicable federal poverty level for a Program applicant, the obligor's household shall include the children for whom the obligor is  required to pay child support under a child support order that is the subject of the application to the Program.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">In determining whether to authorize an obligor to participate in the Program, the Administration shall consider the following factors:<section prefix="1.">whether the obligor has a current ability to pay;</section><section prefix="2.">whether the reduction of arrearages will encourage the obligor's economic stability; and</section><section prefix="3.">whether the agreement serves the best interests of the children whom the obligor is required to support.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">If any of the factors specified in subparagraph (i) of this paragraph are met, there is a presumption that it is in the best interest of the State to authorize an obligor to participate in the Program.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Under the Program, the Administration shall agree to reduce the arrearages in accordance with the following schedule:<section prefix="(1)">after 12 months of uninterrupted court-ordered payments, the arrearages shall be reduced by 50% of the amount of arrearages owed before the agreement; and</section><section prefix="(2)">after 24 months of uninterrupted court-ordered payments, the arrearages balance shall be reduced to zero in full settlement of the arrearages.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The Administration shall distribute any child support arrearages received under this section in accordance with federal law.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, for the duration of an agreement under subsection (d) of this section, all child support enforcement actions shall be  suspended, unless the suspension would be in conflict with federal law.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">For the duration of an agreement under subsection (d) of this section, any earnings withholding shall continue in an amount consistent with the agreement.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">When the Administration enters into a Program agreement with an obligor, the Administration shall file a copy of the agreement with the court within 30 days after the agreement is executed.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If an obligor satisfies the requirements for a reduction in arrearages under the schedule specified in subsection (d) of this section, the Administration shall:<section prefix="(i)">file a notice of reduction of arrearages with the court; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">provide a copy of the notice to the obligor that reflects the adjusted amount of any arrearages that the obligor owes.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(h)">A Program agreement is effective without the necessity of judicial approval.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">
      <section prefix="(1)">An agreement under this section shall be terminated if the obligor fails to make payments equal to two times the monthly support obligation amount.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">An obligor who has been terminated from a Program agreement more than two times is not eligible for future participation in the Program.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(j)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Administration shall develop an application form for obligors to request participation in the Program.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Within 60 days after receipt of a request from an obligor, the Administration shall provide a written decision to the obligor.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">If the Administration does not authorize participation of an obligor in the Program, the Administration shall notify the obligor of the decision and of the obligor's right to appeal the decision to the Office of Administrative Hearings.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">An appeal under this subsection shall be conducted in accordance with Title 10, Subtitle 2 of the State Government Article.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(k)">If an unemployed obligor applies to participate in the Program, the Administration shall give the obligor a list of referrals to programs that prepare individuals for entry into the workforce.</section>
    <section prefix="(l)">The Administration and each local support enforcement office shall jointly develop a public awareness campaign to publicize statewide the availability of the Program and the manner of applying to participate in the Program.</section>
    <section prefix="(m)">The Secretary of Human Resources may adopt regulations to implement this section.</section>
  </text>
</law>
