<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gfl" order_by="gfl" level="1">Family Law</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gfl-5-3A-35</section_number>
  <catch_line>A court may enter an order for a child's adoption under this subtitle only if:...</catch_line>
  <order_by>35</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">A court may enter an order for a child's adoption under this subtitle only if:<section prefix="(1)">the child placement agency consents; and</section><section prefix="(2)">for a child who is at least 10 years old, the child consents.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">In this subsection, "disability" means:<section prefix="1.">a physical disability, infirmity, malformation, or disfigurement that is caused by bodily injury, birth defect, or illness, including epilepsy;</section><section prefix="2.">a mental impairment or deficiency;</section><section prefix="3.">a record of having a physical or mental impairment as defined under this paragraph; or</section><section prefix="4.">being regarded as having a physical or mental impairment as defined under this paragraph.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">"Disability" includes:<section prefix="1.">any degree of paralysis or amputation;</section><section prefix="2.">blindness or visual impairment;</section><section prefix="3.">deafness or hearing impairment;</section><section prefix="4.">muteness or speech impediment;</section><section prefix="5.">physical reliance on a service animal or a wheelchair or other remedial appliance or device; and</section><section prefix="6.">intellectual disability, as defined in &#xA7; 7-101 of the Health - General Article, and any other mental impairment or deficiency that may have necessitated remedial or special education and related services.</section></section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A child placement agency may not withhold consent for the sole reason that:<section prefix="(i)">the race, religion, color, or national origin of a prospective adoptive parent differs from that of the child or parent; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">a prospective adoptive parent has a disability.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Consent of a party to an adoption under this Part III of this subtitle is not valid unless:<section prefix="(1)">the consent is given in a language that the party understands;</section><section prefix="(2)">if given in a language other than English, the consent:<section prefix="(i)">is given before a judge on the record; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">is accompanied by the affidavit of a translator stating that the translation of the document of consent is accurate;</section></section><section prefix="(3)">the consent names the child;</section><section prefix="(4)">the consent contains enough information to identify the prospective adoptive parent; and</section><section prefix="(5)">the party has received written notice or on-the-record notice of:<section prefix="(i)">the revocation provisions in this section;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the search rights of adoptees and parents under &#xA7; 5-3A-42 of this subtitle and the search rights of adoptees, parents, and siblings under Subtitle 4B of this title; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">the right to file a disclosure veto under &#xA7; 5-3A-42 of this subtitle.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A child placement agency may revoke consent at any time within the later of:<section prefix="(i)">14 days after the child placement agency signs the consent; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">14 days after the adoption petition is filed.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A child who is at least 10 years old may revoke consent at any time before a court enters an order of adoption under this subtitle.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
