<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gfl" order_by="gfl" level="1">Family Law</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gfl-10-1A-02</section_number>
  <catch_line>An affidavit of support may be executed in the manner provided under this section if:...</catch_line>
  <order_by>02</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">An affidavit of support may be executed in the manner provided under this section if:<section prefix="(i)">a party is receiving child support enforcement services under Title IV, Part D, of the Social Security Act;</section><section prefix="(ii)">paternity of the child has been established;</section><section prefix="(iii)">a support conference has been conducted in which the Administration determined the amount of support in accordance with the child support guidelines provided in Title 12, Subtitle 2 of this article; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">the support conference resulted in an agreement by the parties.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The Administration shall set the amount of the support obligation in accordance with the guidelines.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">Unless the Administration determines that application of the guidelines would be unjust or inappropriate in a particular case, the amount specified in the guidelines shall apply.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">In determining whether application of the guidelines is unjust or inappropriate, the Administration may consider the factors stated in &#xA7; 12-202 of this article.</section>
        <section prefix="(iv)">If the Administration finds that application of the guidelines is unjust or inappropriate in a particular case, the Administration shall make a written finding on the record stating the reasons for departing from the guidelines.</section>
        <section prefix="(v)">The Administration's finding shall state:<section prefix="1.">the amount of child support that would have been required under the guidelines;</section><section prefix="2.">how the affidavit of support varies from the guidelines;</section><section prefix="3.">how the finding serves the best interests of the child; and</section><section prefix="4.">in cases in which items of value are conveyed instead of a portion of the support presumed under the guidelines, the estimated value of the items conveyed.</section></section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">An affidavit of support shall be completed on a standardized form developed by the Administration.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The completed affidavit of support form shall contain:<section prefix="(i)">a statement that the executed affidavit of support is a legal document and constitutes a legal finding of a support obligation;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the date of the signed affidavit of support;</section><section prefix="(iii)">the full names of the parties;</section><section prefix="(iv)">the full name and birth date of each child for whom support is to be paid;</section><section prefix="(v)">the support order amount, including an amount for current support, and an amount for arrears, if appropriate;</section><section prefix="(vi)">the frequency of child support to be paid, including the payment due date;</section><section prefix="(vii)">a provision for making child support payments payable to the State disbursement unit;</section><section prefix="(viii)">a provision for medical support;</section><section prefix="(ix)">a provision for immediate earnings withholding;</section><section prefix="(x)">a statement that if the obligor becomes delinquent in fulfilling the child support obligation, any enforcement remedy provided in accordance with State and federal law may be applied;</section><section prefix="(xi)">a statement that it is the responsibility of each party under the affidavit of support to advise the Administration of any change of address, employment, or medical support;</section><section prefix="(xii)">a statement that the provisions of the affidavit of support are subject to review by the Administration for possible modification on request of any party;</section><section prefix="(xiii)">a statement that the provisions of the affidavit of support remain in effect until the first of the following events occurs:<section prefix="1.">the child becomes an adult;</section><section prefix="2.">the child dies;</section><section prefix="3.">the child marries; or</section><section prefix="4.">the child becomes self-supporting;</section></section><section prefix="(xiv)">a statement that the provisions of the affidavit of support remain in effect until superseded by:<section prefix="1.">a court order; or</section><section prefix="2.">a subsequently executed affidavit of support;</section></section><section prefix="(xv)">any information that the Administration considers appropriate; and</section><section prefix="(xvi)">the signatures of all parties and the date of the signatures.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Before completing an affidavit of support form, the parties shall be advised orally and in writing of the legal consequences of executing the affidavit and of the right to seek legal counsel.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Administration shall provide each party with a copy of the executed affidavit of support.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">An executed affidavit of support constitutes a legal finding of a support obligation, subject to the right of any party to:<section prefix="(1)">rescind the affidavit in writing to the Administration within 60 days after execution of the affidavit; or</section><section prefix="(2)">challenge the affidavit of support in court on the basis of fraud, duress, or material mistake of fact or that the affidavit of support is not in accordance with the child support guidelines.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">Within 30 days after expiration of the 60-day recission period specified in subsection (d)(1) of this section, the Administration shall file an affidavit of support with the clerk of a circuit court for approval by the court.</section>
  </text>
</law>
