<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gfl" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="9.5-311" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gfl-9.5-311</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">On the filing of a petition seeking enforcement of a child custody determination, the petitioner may file a verified application for the issuance of a warrant to take physical custody of the child if the child is immediately likely to suffer serious physical harm or be removed from this State.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If the court, on the testimony of the petitioner or other witness, finds that the child is imminently likely to suffer serious physical harm or be removed from this State, it may issue a warrant to take physical custody of the child.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The petition shall be heard on the next judicial day after the warrant is executed unless that date is impossible.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">In that event, the court shall hold the hearing on the first judicial day possible.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The application for the warrant shall include the statements required by &#xA7; 9.5-308(b) of this subtitle.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A warrant to take physical custody of a child shall:<section prefix="(1)">recite the facts on which a conclusion of imminent serious physical harm or removal from the jurisdiction is based;</section><section prefix="(2)">direct law enforcement officers to take physical custody of the child immediately; and</section><section prefix="(3)">provide for the placement of the child pending final relief.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The respondent shall be served with the petition, warrant, and order immediately after the child is taken into physical custody.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A warrant to take physical custody of a child is enforceable throughout this State.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If the court finds on the basis of the testimony of the petitioner or other witness that a less intrusive remedy is not effective, the court may authorize law enforcement officers to enter private property to take physical custody of the child.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">If required by exigent circumstances of the case, the court may authorize law enforcement officers to make a forcible entry at any hour.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The court may impose conditions on placement of a child to ensure the appearance of the child and the child's custodian.</section>
  </text>
</law>
