<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gfl" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="11-106" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gfl-11-106</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The court shall determine the amount of and the period for an award of alimony.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The court may award alimony for a period beginning from the filing of the pleading that requests alimony.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">At the conclusion of the period of the award of alimony, no further alimony shall accrue.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">In making the determination, the court shall consider all the factors necessary for a fair and equitable award, including:<section prefix="(1)">the ability of the party seeking alimony to be wholly or partly self-supporting;</section><section prefix="(2)">the time necessary for the party seeking alimony to gain sufficient education or training to enable that party to find suitable employment;</section><section prefix="(3)">the standard of living that the parties established during their marriage;</section><section prefix="(4)">the duration of the marriage;</section><section prefix="(5)">the contributions, monetary and nonmonetary, of each party to the well-being of the family;</section><section prefix="(6)">the circumstances that contributed to the estrangement of the parties;</section><section prefix="(7)">the age of each party;</section><section prefix="(8)">the physical and mental condition of each party;</section><section prefix="(9)">the ability of the party from whom alimony is sought to meet that party's needs while meeting the needs of the party seeking alimony;</section><section prefix="(10)">any agreement between the parties;</section><section prefix="(11)">the financial needs and financial resources of each party, including:<section prefix="(i)">all income and assets, including property that does not produce income;</section><section prefix="(ii)">any award made under &#xA7;&#xA7; 8-205 and 8-208 of this article;</section><section prefix="(iii)">the nature and amount of the financial obligations of each party; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">the right of each party to receive retirement benefits; and</section></section><section prefix="(12)">whether the award would cause a spouse who is a resident of a related institution as defined in &#xA7; 19-301 of the Health - General Article and from whom alimony is sought to become eligible for medical assistance earlier than would otherwise occur.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The court may award alimony for an indefinite period, if the court finds that:<section prefix="(1)">due to age, illness, infirmity, or disability, the party seeking alimony cannot reasonably be expected to make substantial progress toward becoming self-supporting; or</section><section prefix="(2)">even after the party seeking alimony will have made as much progress toward becoming self-supporting as can reasonably be expected, the respective standards of living of the parties will be unconscionably disparate.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
