<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gfl" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="5-3A-19" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gfl-5-3A-19</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Consent of a parent may include a waiver of the right to notice of:<section prefix="(i)">the filing of a petition under this subtitle; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">further proceedings under this subtitle.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Consent to guardianship is not valid unless the consent:<section prefix="(i)">is given after the child for whom guardianship is sought is born;</section><section prefix="(ii)">is given in a language that the party understands;</section><section prefix="(iii)">if given in a language other than English:</section><section prefix="(iv)">contains an express notice of:</section><section prefix="(v)">is accompanied by an affidavit of counsel appointed under &#xA7; 5-3A-07(a) of this subtitle stating that a parent who is a minor or has a disability consents knowingly and voluntarily.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Subject to paragraph (2) of this subsection, a person may revoke consent to guardianship at any time within 30 days after the person signs the consent.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A parent may not revoke consent for guardianship of a child if:<section prefix="(i)">in the preceding year, the parent has revoked consent for or filed a notice of objection to guardianship of the child; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">the child is at least 30 days old and consent is given before a judge on the record.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">If a petitioner becomes aware, before a court rules on a petition, that a condition of consent under &#xA7; 5-3A-18(b) of this subtitle cannot be fulfilled, the petitioner promptly shall:<section prefix="(1)">file notice with the court;</section><section prefix="(2)">give notice to all of the other parties;</section><section prefix="(3)">if consent was received from a governmental unit or person who is not a party, give notice to that unit or person; and</section><section prefix="(4)"><section prefix="(i)">if the unit or person enters into a new consent, file the consent with the court; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">if the unit or person fails to enter into a new consent, dismiss the petition.</section></section></section>
  </text>
</law>
