<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gfl" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="5-506" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gfl-5-506</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The General Assembly intends that:<section prefix="(1)">all children whose care is the responsibility of this State shall have similar protection in terms of health, safety, and quality of care; and</section><section prefix="(2)">the rules and regulations of agencies that are charged with child care shall be comparable.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">In addition to other regulations adopted under this title, the Department may adopt regulations to carry out &#xA7;&#xA7; 5-507, 5-508, 5-509, and 5-509.1 of this subtitle, which relate to the licensing of child placement agencies, child care homes, child care institutions, and residential educational facilities.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">By regulation, the Department may delegate authority to child placement agencies to issue licenses or approve applicants for licenses under this subtitle.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Any regulation adopted by the Department under this subsection shall provide for an appeal to an administrative appellate authority from a decision of a child placement agency.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A child placement agency, child care home, child care institution, or residential educational facility may not be required to obtain a license from more than one State agency.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Any State agency authorized to license child placement agencies, child care homes, child care institutions, or residential educational facilities may make cooperative arrangements with any other State agency to give effect to paragraph (1) of this subsection.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The Department shall cooperate in planning and determining the cost of developing and implementing a system of evaluating the success of services to children in out-of-home placement.</section>
  </text>
</law>
