<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gfl" order_by="gfl" level="1">Family Law</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gfl-12-101</section_number>
  <catch_line>Unless the court finds from the evidence that the amount of the award will produce an inequitable re...</catch_line>
  <order_by>101</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Unless the court finds from the evidence that the amount of the award will produce an inequitable result, for an initial pleading that requests child support pendente lite, the court shall award child support for a period from the filing of the pleading that requests child support.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Notwithstanding paragraph (1) of this subsection, unless the court finds from the evidence that the amount of the award will produce an inequitable result, for an initial pleading filed by a child support agency that requests child support, the court shall award child support for a period from the filing of the pleading that requests child support.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">For any other pleading that requests child support, the court may award child support for a period from the filing of the pleading that requests child support.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The court shall give credit for payments that the court finds have been made during the period beginning from the filing of the pleading that requests child support.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Any support order or modification of a support order that is passed on or after July 1, 1997 shall include a statement that:<section prefix="(1)">each party is required to notify the court and any support enforcement agency ordered to receive payments, within 10 days of any change of address or employment; and</section><section prefix="(2)">failure to comply with paragraph (1) of this subsection may result in a party not receiving notice of the initiation of a proceeding to modify or enforce a support order.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The court may order either parent to pay all or part of:<section prefix="(i)">the mother's medical and hospital expenses for pregnancy, confinement, and recovery; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">medical support for the child, including neonatal expenses.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Subject to the right of any party to subpoena a custodian of records at least 10 days before trial, any records relating to the cost of the mother's medical and hospital expenses for pregnancy, childbirth, and recovery and any neonatal expenses of the child shall be admissible in evidence without the presence of a custodian of record and shall constitute prima facie evidence of the amount of expenses incurred.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
