<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gfl" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="5-569" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gfl-5-569</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, "emergency out-of-home placement" means an out-of-home placement in which a local department places a child in the home of a private individual, including a neighbor, friend, or relative, as a result of a sudden unavailability of the child's primary caretaker.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If a child is placed in an emergency out-of-home placement, a local department may request that a designated State or local law enforcement agency in the State or other location approved by the Department perform a federal name-based check on any individual described in &#xA7; 5-561(c)(4), (5)(ii), and (6)(ii) of this subtitle.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The designated agency described in paragraph (1) of this subsection may provide the results of the name-based check to the local department.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Within 15 calendar days after the local department receives the results of the name-based check, the local department shall submit a complete set of fingerprints to the Department for each individual described in paragraph (1) of this subsection on whom a name-based check was performed.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">Within 15 calendar days after the date on which the name-based check was performed, the Department shall perform a criminal history records check, in accordance with &#xA7; 5-564 of this subtitle.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A child shall be removed immediately from an emergency out-of-home placement if any individual required to submit to a name-based check fails to comply with this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">When the placement of a child in a home is denied as a result of a name-based criminal history records check of an individual and the individual contests that denial, the individual shall submit to the local department:<section prefix="(1)">a complete set of fingerprints; and</section><section prefix="(2)">written permission allowing the local department to forward the fingerprints to the Department for submission to the Federal Bureau of Investigation.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">An individual who is required to submit to a criminal history records check under this section shall pay the fees required under &#xA7; 5-561(h) of this subtitle.</section>
  </text>
</law>
