<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gfl" order_by="gfl" level="1">Family Law</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gfl-5-3A-36</section_number>
  <catch_line>This subsection does not limit the right of an individual to provide for distribution of property by...</catch_line>
  <order_by>36</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This subsection does not limit the right of an individual to provide for distribution of property by will.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Except as provided in &#xA7; 2-123 of the Real Property Article, after a court enters an order for adoption under this subtitle:<section prefix="(i)">the adoptee:<section prefix="1.">is the child of the adoptive parent for all intents and purposes; and</section><section prefix="2.">is entitled to all of the rights and privileges of and is subject to all of the obligations of offspring born to the adoptive parent;</section></section><section prefix="(ii)">each of the adoptee's living parents is:<section prefix="1.">relieved of all parental duties and obligations to the adoptee; and</section><section prefix="2.">divested of all parental rights as to the adoptee; and</section></section><section prefix="(iii)">the Estates and Trusts Article shall govern all of the rights of inheritance between the adoptee and parental relatives.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">An order for adoption under this subtitle terminates all pending guardianship cases as to the adoptee.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Adoption of an adult has the same legal effect as adoption of a minor.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">When a court enters an order for a child's adoption under this subtitle, the court shall send notice to:<section prefix="(i)">each court that has a pending guardianship case as to the adoptee;</section><section prefix="(ii)">each of the child's living, former parents who has not waived the right to notice; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">the former guardian of the child.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Service on a parent under this subsection shall be at the parent's last address known to the court.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
