<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gfl" order_by="" level="1">Family Law</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gfl-5-561</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>561</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Notwithstanding any provision of law to the contrary, an employee and employer in a facility identified in subsection (b) of this section and individuals identified in subsection (c) of this section shall apply for a national and State criminal history records check at any designated law enforcement office in this State or other location approved by the Department.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The following facilities shall require employees and employers to obtain a criminal history records check under this Part VI of this subtitle:<section prefix="(1)">a child care center required to be licensed under Part VII of this subtitle;</section><section prefix="(2)">a family child care home or large family child care home required to be registered under Part V of this subtitle;</section><section prefix="(3)">a child care home required to be licensed under this subtitle or under Title 9 of the Human Services Article;</section><section prefix="(4)">a child care institution required to be licensed under this subtitle or under Title 9 of the Human Services Article;</section><section prefix="(5)">a juvenile detention, correction, or treatment facility provided for in Title 9 of the Human Services Article;</section><section prefix="(6)">a public school as defined in Title 1 of the Education Article;</section><section prefix="(7)">a private or nonpublic school required to report annually to the State Board of Education under Title 2 of the Education Article;</section><section prefix="(8)">a foster care family home or group facility as defined under this subtitle;</section><section prefix="(9)">a recreation center or recreation program operated by the State, a local government, or a private entity primarily serving minors;</section><section prefix="(10)">a day or residential camp, as defined in Title 10, Subtitle 16 of the Code of Maryland Regulations, primarily serving minors; or</section><section prefix="(11)">a home health agency or residential service agency licensed by the Department of Health and Mental Hygiene and authorized under Title 19 of the Health - General Article to provide home- or community-based health services for minors.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The following individuals shall obtain a criminal history records check under this Part VI of this subtitle:<section prefix="(1)">an individual who is seeking to adopt a child through a child placement agency;</section><section prefix="(2)">an individual who is seeking to become a guardian through a local department;</section><section prefix="(3)">an individual whom the juvenile court appoints as a guardian of a child;</section><section prefix="(4)">an adult relative with whom a child, committed to a local department, is placed by the local department;</section><section prefix="(5)">any adult known by a local department to be residing in:<section prefix="(i)">a family child care home or large family child care home required to be registered under this title;</section><section prefix="(ii)">a home of an adult relative of a child with whom the child, committed to a local department, is placed by the local department;</section><section prefix="(iii)">a foster care home or child care home required to be approved under this title;</section><section prefix="(iv)">a home of an individual seeking to adopt a child through a child placement agency; or</section><section prefix="(v)">a home of an individual seeking to become a guardian through a local department; and</section></section><section prefix="(6)">if requested by a local department:<section prefix="(i)">a parent or guardian of a child who is committed to the local department and is or has been placed in an out-of-home placement within the past year; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">any adult known by the local department to be residing in the home of the parent or guardian.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">An employer at a facility under subsection (b) of this section may require a volunteer at the facility to obtain a criminal history records check under this Part VI of this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">A local department may require a volunteer of that department who works with children to obtain a criminal history records check under this Part VI of this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">An employer at a facility not identified in subsection (b) of this section who employs individuals to work with children may require employees, including volunteers, to obtain a criminal history records check under this Part VI of this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">An employer, as defined in &#xA7; 5-560(e)(2) of this subtitle, shall require an employee, as defined in &#xA7; 5-560(d)(2) of this subtitle, to obtain a criminal history records check under this Part VI of this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, a person who is required to have a criminal history records check under this Part VI of this subtitle shall pay for:<section prefix="(i)">the mandatory processing fee required by the Federal Bureau of Investigation for a national criminal history records check;</section><section prefix="(ii)">reasonable administrative costs to the Department, not to exceed 10% of the processing fee; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">the fee authorized under &#xA7; 10-221(b)(7) of the Criminal Procedure Article for access to Maryland criminal history records.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A volunteer under subsection (d), (e), or (f) of this section who volunteers for a program that is registered with the Maryland Mentoring Partnership is not required to pay for costs or fees under paragraph (1)(ii) and (iii) of this subsection.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(i)">
      <section prefix="(1)">An employer or other party may pay for the costs borne by the employee or other individual under subsection (h) of this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The local department shall reimburse:<section prefix="(i)">an adult residing in a foster care home for the costs borne by the individual under subsection (h) of this section; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">an individual described in subsection (c)(6)(ii) of this section for the costs borne by the individual under subsection (h) of this section.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
