<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gfl" order_by="" level="1">Family Law</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gfl-5-1028</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>1028</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">An unmarried father and mother shall be provided an opportunity to execute an affidavit of parentage in the manner provided under &#xA7; 4-208 of the Health - General Article.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The affidavit shall be completed on a standardized form developed by the Department.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The completed affidavit of parentage form shall contain:<section prefix="(i)">in ten point boldface type a statement that the affidavit is a legal document and constitutes a legal finding of paternity;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the full name and the place and date of birth of the child;</section><section prefix="(iii)">the full name of the attesting father of the child;</section><section prefix="(iv)">the full name of the attesting mother of the child;</section><section prefix="(v)">the signatures of the father and the mother of the child attesting, under penalty of perjury, that the information provided on the affidavit is true and correct;</section><section prefix="(vi)">a statement by the mother consenting to the assertion of paternity and acknowledging that her cosignatory is the only possible father;</section><section prefix="(vii)">a statement by the father that he is the natural father of the child; and</section><section prefix="(viii)">the Social Security numbers provided by each of the parents.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Before completing an affidavit of parentage form, the unmarried mother and the father shall be advised orally and in writing of the legal consequences of executing the affidavit and of the benefit of seeking legal counsel.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">An executed affidavit of parentage constitutes a legal finding of paternity, subject to the right of any signatory to rescind the affidavit:<section prefix="(i)">in writing within 60 days after execution of the affidavit; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">in a judicial proceeding relating to the child:<section prefix="1.">in which the signatory is a party; and</section><section prefix="2.">that occurs before the expiration of the 60-day period.</section></section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">After the expiration of the 60-day period, an executed affidavit of parentage may be challenged in court only on the basis of fraud, duress, or material mistake of fact.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The burden of proof shall be on the challenger to show fraud, duress, or material mistake of fact.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">The legal responsibilities of any signatory arising from the affidavit, including child support obligations, may not be suspended during the challenge, except for good cause shown.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The Administration shall prepare written information to be furnished to unmarried mothers under &#xA7; 4-208 of the Health - General Article concerning the benefits of having the paternity of their children established, including the availability of child support enforcement services.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The Department shall make the standardized affidavit forms available to all hospitals in the State.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">The Secretary, in consultation with the Department of Health and Mental Hygiene and the Maryland Hospital Association, shall adopt regulations governing the provisions of this section and &#xA7; 4-208 of the Health - General Article.</section>
  </text>
</law>
