<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gfl" order_by="gfl" level="1">Family Law</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gfl-5-3A-42</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this section the following words have the meanings indicated....</catch_line>
  <order_by>42</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Director" means the State Director of Social Services.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Secretary" means the Secretary of Health and Mental Hygiene.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">This section applies only to an adoption in which a court enters an order for adoption on or after January 1, 2000.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">This section does not bar:<section prefix="(1)">an adoptee or biological parent from applying for search, contact, and reunion services under Subtitle 4B of this title; or</section><section prefix="(2)">the Director or a confidential intermediary from obtaining a copy of a record under &#xA7; 5-4B-04(c) or &#xA7; 5-4B-06(b) or (c) of this title.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">An adoptee who is at least 21 years old may apply to the Secretary for a copy of:<section prefix="(i)">the adoptee's original certificate of birth;</section><section prefix="(ii)">all records that relate to the adoptee's new certificate of birth, if any; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">the report of the adoptee's order of adoption filed by the clerk of court under &#xA7; 4-211 of the Health - General Article.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If an adoptee is at least 21 years old, a biological parent of the adoptee may apply to the Secretary for a copy of:<section prefix="(i)">the adoptee's original certificate of birth;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the new certificate of birth, if any, substituted, under &#xA7; 4-211 of the Health - General Article, for the adoptee's original certificate of birth;</section><section prefix="(iii)">all records that relate to the adoptee's new certificate of birth; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">the report of the adoptee's order of adoption filed by the clerk of court under &#xA7; 4-211 of the Health - General Article.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Each applicant under this subsection shall:<section prefix="(i)">provide all proof of identity and other relevant information that the Secretary requires; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">pay the fee required under Title 4, Subtitle 2 of the Health - General Article for a copy of a record.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A biological parent may:<section prefix="(i)">file with the Director a disclosure veto, to bar disclosure of information about that parent in a record accessible under this section;</section><section prefix="(ii)">cancel a disclosure veto at any time; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">refile a disclosure veto at any time.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">An adoptee at least 21 years old may:<section prefix="(i)">file with the Director a disclosure veto, to bar disclosure of information about the adoptee in a record accessible under this section;</section><section prefix="(ii)">cancel a disclosure veto at any time; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">refile a disclosure veto at any time.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Immediately after the Director receives a disclosure veto or cancellation under this subsection, the Director shall forward a copy to the Secretary.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Secretary shall adopt regulations to carry out this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Subject to paragraphs (3) and (4) of this subsection, the Secretary shall give to each applicant who meets the requirements of this section a copy of each record that the applicant requested and that the Secretary has on file.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Whenever a biological parent applies for a record, the Secretary shall redact from the copy all information as to:<section prefix="(i)">the other biological parent, if that parent has filed a disclosure veto in accordance with this section; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">the adoptee and each adoptive parent, if the adoptee has filed a disclosure veto in accordance with this section.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">Whenever an adoptee applies for a record, the Secretary shall redact from the copy all information as to the biological parent, if that parent has filed a disclosure veto in accordance with this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">The Secretary shall give each applicant under this section notice of the adoption search, contact, and reunion services available under this title.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
