<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gfl" order_by="gfl" level="1">Family Law</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gfl-5-4B-06</section_number>
  <catch_line>The Director or the Adoption Program Manager of the Department may authorize a confidential intermed...</catch_line>
  <order_by>06</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Director or the Adoption Program Manager of the Department may authorize a confidential intermediary to obtain information described in subsection (b) or (c) of this section to locate an individual sought by an applicant.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Subject to paragraph (2) of this subsection, a confidential intermediary may apply to the Secretary of Health and Mental Hygiene for a copy of the following:<section prefix="(i)">the original certificate of birth and any records that relate to the new certificate of birth of an adopted individual;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the new certificate of birth that was substituted for the original certificate of birth of an adopted individual under &#xA7; 4-211 of the Health - General Article; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">the report of the decree or judgment of adoption filed by the clerk of the court under &#xA7; 4-211 of the Health - General Article.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">To apply for a copy of a record listed in paragraph (1) of this subsection, a confidential intermediary shall submit to the Secretary of Health and Mental Hygiene a written statement signed by the Director or the Adoption Program Manager of the Department and witnessed by a notary public that authorizes the confidential intermediary to obtain information necessary to locate an individual sought by an applicant.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">If a confidential intermediary complies with paragraph (2) of this subsection, the Secretary of Health and Mental Hygiene shall give a copy of a record requested under this subsection that is on file with the Secretary to the confidential intermediary.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Subject to paragraph (2) of this subsection, a confidential intermediary may access any information that is contained in a public record, as defined in &#xA7; 10-611 of the State Government Article, including a court record.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">To have access to information contained in a public record, a confidential intermediary shall submit to the custodian of a public record a written statement signed by the Director or the Adoption Program Manager of the Department and witnessed by a notary public that authorizes the confidential intermediary to obtain information necessary to locate an individual sought by an applicant.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">If a confidential intermediary complies with paragraph (2) of this subsection, a custodian shall permit inspection of a public record requested under this subsection by the confidential intermediary.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
