<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gfl" order_by="gfl" level="1">Family Law</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gfl-5-601</section_number>
  <catch_line>The Interstate Compact on the Placement of Children is hereby entered into by this State with all st...</catch_line>
  <order_by>601</order_by>
  <text>The Interstate Compact on the Placement of Children is hereby entered into by this State with all states legally joining in the compact in the form substantially as follows:<section prefix=""><section prefix="(1)">Financial responsibility for any child placed pursuant to the provisions of the Interstate Compact on the Placement of Children shall be determined in accordance with the provisions of &#xA7; 5-606 of this subtitle. However, in the event of partial or complete default of performance thereunder, the provisions of state laws fixing responsibility for the support of children also may be invoked.</section><section prefix="(2)">The "appropriate public authorities" as used in &#xA7; 5-604 of the Interstate Compact on the Placement of Children shall, with reference to this State, mean the Department of Human Resources. This Department shall receive and act with reference to notices required by &#xA7; 5-604 of this subtitle.</section><section prefix="(3)">As used in &#xA7; 5-606(a) of the Interstate Compact on the Placement of Children, the phrase "appropriate authority in the receiving state" with reference to this State shall mean the Department of Human Resources.</section><section prefix="(4)">The officers and agencies of this State and its subdivisions having authority to place children are hereby empowered to enter into agreements with appropriate officers or agencies of or in other party states pursuant to &#xA7; 5-606(b) of the Interstate Compact on the Placement of Children. Any such agreement which contains a financial commitment or imposes a financial obligation on this State or subdivision or agency thereof shall not be binding unless it has the approval in writing of the Department of Human Resources.</section><section prefix="(5)">Any requirements for visitation, inspection or supervision of children, homes, institutions or other agencies in another party state which may apply shall be deemed to be met if performed pursuant to an agreement entered into by appropriate officers or agencies of this State or a subdivision thereof as contemplated by &#xA7; 5-606(b) of the Interstate Compact on the Placement of Children.</section><section prefix="(6)">Any provisions of law restricting out-of-state placement shall not apply to placements made pursuant to the Interstate Compact on the Placement of Children.</section><section prefix="(7)">Any court having jurisdiction to place delinquent children may place such a child in an institution of or in another state pursuant to &#xA7; 5-607 of the Interstate Compact on the Placement of Children and shall retain jurisdiction as provided in &#xA7; 5-606 of this subtitle.</section><section prefix="(8)">As used in &#xA7; 5-608 of the Interstate Compact on the Placement of Children, the term "executive head" means the Governor. The Governor is hereby authorized to appoint a compact administrator in accordance with the terms of &#xA7; 5-608 of this subtitle.</section><section prefix="(9)">The definitions in &#xA7; 1-101 of this article do not apply to the Interstate Compact on the Placement of Children set forth in this subtitle.</section></section></text>
</law>
