<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gfl" order_by="gfl" level="1">Family Law</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gfl-2-403</section_number>
  <catch_line>A license shall read substantially as follows:...</catch_line>
  <order_by>403</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A license shall read substantially as follows:</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A license shall contain:<section prefix="(i)">appropriate spaces in which the clerk shall enter:<section prefix="1.">the relationship of the parties to be married, if any; and</section><section prefix="2.">as to each party, the name, age, state or foreign country in which born, residence, and marital status (single, widowed, or divorced); and</section></section><section prefix="(ii)">a statement that the license is valid only:<section prefix="1.">for 6 months from the effective date and time stated on the license; and</section><section prefix="2.">in the county in which it is issued.</section></section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Attached to a license shall be 2 certificate forms that:<section prefix="(i)">read, "I hereby certify that on this ............ day of ............. (state here month and year), ........ (state here time), at .............. (state here location), in accordance with the license issued by the Clerk of the Circuit Court for ................. (state here jurisdiction), I united in marriage the following individuals:</section><section prefix="(ii)">restate all information concerning the individuals married that is stated on the marriage license; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">provide a space for the signature of the authorized official who performs the marriage ceremony.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Attached to a license, in the case of a Society of Friends marriage ceremony, shall be 2 certificate forms that:<section prefix="(i)">read, "We hereby certify that on this .......... day of ........... (state here month and year), ........ (state here time), at ........... (state here location), we, ............... (state here name of husband) and ............... (state here name of wife) were united in marriage in accordance with the ceremony of the Society of Friends and in accordance with the license issued by the Clerk of the Circuit Court for ........ (state here jurisdiction)";</section><section prefix="(ii)">restate all information concerning the individuals married that is stated on the marriage license; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">provide spaces for the signatures of the parties and the 2 overseers of the marriage ceremony.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
