<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gfl" order_by="gfl" level="1">Family Law</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gfl-10-108.1</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this section, "consumer reporting agency" means any person or entity that, for monetary fees or d...</catch_line>
  <order_by>108.1</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, "consumer reporting agency" means any person or entity that, for monetary fees or dues, or on a cooperative nonprofit basis, regularly engages in whole or in part in the practice of assembling or evaluating consumer credit information or other information on consumers for the purpose of furnishing consumer credit reports to third parties.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If a child support obligation owed by an obligor and enforced by the Administration or a local support enforcement office becomes 60 days or more in arrears, the Administration shall make available, upon request in a format acceptable to the consumer reporting agency and the Administration, information regarding the arrears to all consumer reporting agencies that operate in the State.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Administration shall:<section prefix="(i)">designate one or more persons to receive and process requests from the consumer reporting agencies regarding the reverification of information; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">respond to requests made by the consumer reporting agencies in a timely manner.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Before supplying any information to a consumer reporting agency under this section, the Administration shall:<section prefix="(i)">send written notice of the proposed action to the obligor including the obligor's right to contest the accuracy of the reported arrearage; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">give the obligor a reasonable opportunity to contest the accuracy of the information.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The obligor may appeal a decision of the Administration to provide the information regarding arrears to consumer reporting agencies in accordance with Title 10 of the State Government Article.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Secretary of Human Resources shall adopt rules and regulations to implement the provisions of this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, a consumer reporting agency that receives information regarding child support arrears under this section shall comply with the provisions of Title 14, Subtitle 12 of the Commercial Law Article.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If the Administration finds that it has supplied erroneous information concerning arrears owed by an obligor to a consumer reporting agency:<section prefix="(i)">the Administration shall notify the consumer reporting agency; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">the consumer reporting agency shall remove any information concerning the erroneous arrears from the obligor's credit file.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
