<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gfl" order_by="gfl" level="1">Family Law</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gfl-5-345</section_number>
  <catch_line>If, after termination of parental rights as to a child, there is an open guardianship case, a petiti...</catch_line>
  <order_by>345</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">If, after termination of parental rights as to a child, there is an open guardianship case, a petition for adoption of the child may be filed only as provided in this Part IV of this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Any adult may petition a juvenile court for an adoption under this Part IV of this subtitle.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If a petitioner under this section is married, the petitioner's spouse shall join in the petition unless the spouse:<section prefix="(i)">is separated from the petitioner under a circumstance that gives the petitioner a ground for annulment or divorce; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">is not competent to join in the petition.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A petitioner under this section shall attach to a petition:<section prefix="(i)"><section prefix="1.">all written consents required under &#xA7; 5-350 of this subtitle; or</section><section prefix="2.">if applicable:</section></section><section prefix="(ii)">a copy of an agreement, if any, for postadoption contact; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">a notice of filing that:<section prefix="1.">states the date on which the petition was filed;</section><section prefix="2.">identifies each governmental unit or person whose consent was filed with the petition;</section><section prefix="3.">if applicable, states that a postadoption agreement was filed with the petition; and</section><section prefix="4.">includes no identifying information that would be in violation of an agreement or consent.</section></section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">In addition to a copy of an agreement for postadoption contact, a petitioner shall file the original agreement under seal.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">If the marital status of a petitioner changes before entry of an order, the petitioner shall amend the petition accordingly.</section>
  </text>
</law>
