<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gfl" order_by="gfl" level="1">Family Law</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gfl-5-706</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this section, "alternative response" means a component of the child protective services program t...</catch_line>
  <order_by>706</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section, "alternative response" means a component of the child protective services program that provides for a comprehensive assessment of:<section prefix="(i)">risk of harm to the child;</section><section prefix="(ii)">risk of subsequent child abuse or neglect;</section><section prefix="(iii)">family strengths and needs; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">the provision of or referral for necessary services.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Alternative response" does not include:<section prefix="(i)">an investigation; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">a formal determination as to whether child abuse or neglect has occurred.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Promptly after receiving a report of suspected abuse or neglect of a child who lives in this State that is alleged to have occurred in this State, the local department or the appropriate law enforcement agency, or both, if jointly agreed on, shall make a thorough investigation of a report of suspected abuse or neglect to protect the health, safety, and welfare of the child or children.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Within 24 hours after receiving a report of suspected physical or sexual abuse of a child who lives in this State that is alleged to have occurred in this State, and within 5 days after receiving a report of suspected neglect or suspected mental injury of a child who lives in this State that is alleged to have occurred in this State, the local department or the appropriate law enforcement agency shall:<section prefix="(1)">see the child;</section><section prefix="(2)">attempt to have an on-site interview with the child's caretaker;</section><section prefix="(3)">decide on the safety of the child, wherever the child is, and of other children in the household; and</section><section prefix="(4)">decide on the safety of other children in the care or custody of the alleged abuser.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The investigation under subsection (c) of this section shall include:<section prefix="(1)">a determination of the nature, extent, and cause of the abuse or neglect, if any;</section><section prefix="(2)">if mental injury is suspected, an assessment by two of the following:<section prefix="(i)">a licensed physician, as defined in &#xA7; 14-101 of the Health Occupations Article;</section><section prefix="(ii)">a licensed psychologist, as defined in &#xA7; 18-101 of the Health Occupations Article; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">a licensed social worker, as defined in &#xA7; 19-101 of the Health Occupations Article; and</section></section><section prefix="(3)">if the suspected abuse or neglect is verified:<section prefix="(i)">a determination of the identity of the person or persons responsible for the abuse or neglect;</section><section prefix="(ii)">a determination of the name, age, and condition of any other child in the household;</section><section prefix="(iii)">an evaluation of the parents and the home environment;</section><section prefix="(iv)">a determination of any other pertinent facts or matters; and</section><section prefix="(v)">a determination of any needed services.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">On request by the local department, the local State's Attorney shall assist in an investigation under subsections (c) and (d) of this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The local department, the appropriate law enforcement agencies, the State's Attorney within each county and Baltimore City, the local department's office responsible for child care regulation, and the local health officer shall enter into a written agreement that specifies standard operating procedures for the investigation under subsections (c) and (d) of this section and prosecution of reported cases of suspected abuse or neglect.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The agencies responsible for investigating reported cases of suspected sexual abuse, including the local department, the appropriate law enforcement agencies, and the local State's Attorney, shall implement a joint investigation procedure for conducting joint investigations of sexual abuse under subsections (c) and (d) of this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The joint investigation procedure shall:<section prefix="(i)">include appropriate techniques for expediting validation of sexual abuse complaints;</section><section prefix="(ii)">include investigation techniques designed to:<section prefix="1.">decrease the potential for physical harm to the child; and</section><section prefix="2.">decrease any trauma experienced by the child in the investigation and prosecution of the case; and</section></section><section prefix="(iii)">establish an ongoing training program for personnel involved in the investigation or prosecution of sexual abuse cases.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(h)">
      <section prefix="(1)">To the extent possible, an investigation under subsections (c) and (d) of this section shall be completed within 10 days after receipt of the first notice of the suspected abuse or neglect by the local department or law enforcement agencies.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">An investigation under subsections (c) and (d) of this section that is not completed within 30 days shall be completed within 60 days of receipt of the first notice of the suspected abuse or neglect.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(i)">Within 10 days after the local department or law enforcement agency receives the first notice of suspected abuse of a child who lives in this State that is alleged to have occurred in this State, the local department or law enforcement agency shall report to the local State's Attorney the preliminary findings of the investigation.</section>
    <section prefix="(j)">Within 5 business days after completion of the investigation of suspected abuse of a child who lives in this State that is alleged to have occurred in this State, the local department and the appropriate law enforcement agency, if that agency participated in the investigation, shall make a complete written report of its findings to the local State's Attorney.</section>
    <section prefix="(k)">Promptly after receiving a report of suspected abuse or neglect of a child who lives in this State that is alleged to have occurred outside of this State, the local department shall:<section prefix="(1)">forward the report to the appropriate agency outside of this State that is authorized to receive and investigate reports of suspected abuse or neglect;</section><section prefix="(2)">cooperate to the extent requested with the out-of-state agency investigating the report; and</section><section prefix="(3)">if determined appropriate by the local department:<section prefix="(i)">interview the child to assess whether the child is safe; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">provide services to the child and the child's family.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(l)">Notwithstanding the provisions of this section, the Secretary may implement an alternative response program for selected reports of abuse or neglect.</section>
    <section prefix="(m)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Department shall convene a multidisciplinary alternative response advisory council.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The advisory council shall consist of the following members:<section prefix="(i)">the Secretary of Human Resources, or the Secretary's designee;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the Secretary of Health and Mental Hygiene, or the Secretary's designee;</section><section prefix="(iii)">the State Superintendent of Schools, or the Superintendent's designee;</section><section prefix="(iv)">a representative from the Maryland Disability Law Center;</section><section prefix="(v)">a representative from a child advocacy organization;</section><section prefix="(vi)">a representative from a community partner or a local service provider;</section><section prefix="(vii)">a pediatrician with experience in diagnosing and treating injuries related to abuse and neglect;</section><section prefix="(viii)">an attorney with experience representing children or adults in abuse and neglect cases;</section><section prefix="(ix)">a representative from the Office of the Public Defender;</section><section prefix="(x)">a parent or guardian who has personal experience with the child protective services system;</section><section prefix="(xi)">a child who has personal experience with the child protective services system;</section><section prefix="(xii)">two representatives from local departments of social services; and</section><section prefix="(xiii)">two representatives from local citizens review panels.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Secretary of Human Resources or the Secretary's designee shall be the chair of the advisory council.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The advisory council shall advise the Department on:<section prefix="(i)">the development of the alternative response implementation plan, which may include a pilot program;</section><section prefix="(ii)">oversight and monitoring of the alternative response implementation plan;</section><section prefix="(iii)">consulting with local citizens review panels, local services affiliates, and other local partners for feedback and recommendations on the alternative response implementation plan;</section><section prefix="(iv)">defining the scope of the independent evaluation of the implementation of the alternative response program; and</section><section prefix="(v)">defining the scope of the ongoing evaluation of the alternative response program.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(n)">Only a low risk report of abuse or neglect may be considered for an alternative response.</section>
    <section prefix="(o)">A report that is not assigned for an alternative response shall be assigned for investigation in accordance with this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(p)">The following reports of suspected abuse or neglect may not be assigned for an alternative response:<section prefix="(1)">sexual abuse; and</section><section prefix="(2)">abuse or neglect:<section prefix="(i)">occurring in an out-of-home placement;</section><section prefix="(ii)">resulting in death or serious physical or mental injury;</section><section prefix="(iii)">if, in the previous 3 years, the individual suspected of abuse or neglect has been identified as responsible for abuse or neglect as documented in the records of the local department; or</section><section prefix="(iv)">if the individual suspected of abuse or neglect has had one report assigned for an alternative response within the past 12 months or two reports assigned for an alternative response within the past 24 months.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(q)">A report assigned for an alternative response may be reassigned at any time for an immediate investigation based on any of the following factors and circumstances:<section prefix="(1)">a reassessment of the report or relevant facts;</section><section prefix="(2)">a determination that the case satisfies a criterion in subsection (p) of this section; or</section><section prefix="(3)">a family's inability or refusal to participate in the alternative response assessment.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(r)">A report assigned for an investigation may be reassigned for an alternative response at any time based on:<section prefix="(1)">a reassessment of the report or relevant facts that demonstrate that the case meets the criteria for an alternative response;</section><section prefix="(2)">a determination that accepted services would address all issues of risk of abuse or neglect and child safety; and</section><section prefix="(3)">approval by a caseworker supervisor.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(s)">When a report is referred for an alternative response, the local department shall:<section prefix="(1)">see the child and the child's parent or primary caretaker within 24 hours of receiving a report of physical abuse;</section><section prefix="(2)">see the child and the child's parent or primary caretaker within 5 days of receiving a report of neglect;</section><section prefix="(3)">attempt to have an on-site interview with the child's parent or primary caretaker;</section><section prefix="(4)">evaluate the child's home environment;</section><section prefix="(5)">decide on the safety of the child, wherever the child is, and of other children in the household;</section><section prefix="(6)">decide on the safety of other children in the care or custody of the individual suspected of abuse or neglect;</section><section prefix="(7)">advise the appropriate law enforcement agency that the report has been assigned for an alternative response, if the law enforcement agency made the report of abuse or neglect;</section><section prefix="(8)">inform the individual suspected of child abuse or neglect of the allegations made against the individual in a manner consistent with laws protecting the rights of the person who made the report;</section><section prefix="(9)">complete an alternative response assessment within 60 days after the receipt of the report;</section><section prefix="(10)">within 10 days after completing the alternative response assessment, provide a written report to the family members who are participating in the alternative response assessment as to whether and what services are necessary to address:<section prefix="(i)">the safety of the child or other children in the household; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">the risk of subsequent abuse or neglect; and</section></section><section prefix="(11)">consistent with the assessment and any safety or services plans:<section prefix="(i)">render any appropriate services in the best interests of the child;</section><section prefix="(ii)">refer the family or child for additional services; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">as necessary for the safety of the child or other children in the household, establish a plan to monitor the safety plan and the provision or completion of appropriate services.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(t)">The local department:<section prefix="(1)">shall:<section prefix="(i)">maintain complete records related to an alternative response and services for 3 years after the report was received if there is no subsequent child welfare involvement; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">expunge complete records related to an alternative response and services if there is no subsequent child welfare involvement after 3 years;</section></section><section prefix="(2)">may not use or disclose records related to an alternative response for purposes of responding to a request for background information for employment or voluntary services; and</section><section prefix="(3)">shall protect from disclosure records related to an alternative response in accordance with &#xA7; 1-202 of the Human Services Article.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
