<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gfl" order_by="gfl" level="1">Family Law</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gfl-10-119</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this section the following words have the meanings indicated....</catch_line>
  <order_by>119</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"License" has the meaning stated in &#xA7; 11-128 of the Transportation Article.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Motor Vehicle Administration" means the Motor Vehicle Administration of the Department of Transportation.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Subject to the provisions of subsection (c) of this section, the Administration may notify the Motor Vehicle Administration of any obligor who is 60 days or more out of compliance with the most recent order of the court in making child support payments if:<section prefix="(i)">the Administration has accepted an assignment of support under &#xA7; 5-312(b)(2) of the Human Services Article; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">the recipient of support payments has filed an application for support enforcement services with the Administration.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Upon notification by the Administration under this subsection, the Motor Vehicle Administration:<section prefix="(i)">shall suspend the obligor's license or privilege to drive in the State; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">may issue a work-restricted license or work-restricted privilege to drive in the State in accordance with &#xA7; 16-203 of the Transportation Article.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Before supplying any information to the Motor Vehicle Administration under this section, the Administration shall:<section prefix="(i)">send written notice of the proposed action to the obligor, including notice of the obligor's right to request an investigation on any of the following grounds:<section prefix="1.">the information regarding the reported arrearage is inaccurate;</section><section prefix="2.">suspension of the obligor's license or privilege to drive would be an impediment to the obligor's current or potential employment; or</section><section prefix="3.">suspension of the obligor's license or privilege to drive would place an undue hardship on the obligor because of the obligor's:</section></section><section prefix="(ii)">give the obligor a reasonable opportunity to request an investigation of the proposed action of the Administration.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Upon receipt of a request for investigation from the obligor, the Administration shall conduct an investigation to determine if any of the grounds under paragraph (1)(i) of this subsection exist.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The Administration shall:<section prefix="1.">send a copy of the obligor's request for an investigation to the obligee by first-class mail;</section><section prefix="2.">give the obligee a reasonable opportunity to respond; and</section><section prefix="3.">consider the obligee's response.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">Upon completion of the investigation, the Administration shall notify the obligor of the results of the investigation and the obligor's right to appeal to the Office of Administrative Hearings.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">An appeal under this section shall be conducted in accordance with Title 10, Subtitle 2 of the State Government Article.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">An appeal shall be made in writing and shall be received by the Office of Administrative Hearings within 20 days after the notice to the obligor of the results of the investigation.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(4)">If, after the investigation or appeal to the Office of Administrative Hearings, the Administration finds that one of the grounds under paragraph (1)(i) of this subsection exists, the Administration may not send any information about the obligor to the Motor Vehicle Administration.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">The Administration may not send any information about an obligor to the Motor Vehicle Administration if:<section prefix="(i)">the Administration reaches an agreement with the obligor regarding a scheduled payment of the obligor's child support arrearage or a court issues an order for a scheduled payment of the child support arrearage; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">the obligor is complying with the agreement or court order.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">If, after information about an obligor is supplied to the Motor Vehicle Administration, the obligor's arrearage is paid in full, the obligor has demonstrated good faith by paying the ordered amount of support for 6 consecutive months, or the Administration finds that one of the grounds under subsection (c)(1)(i) of this section exists, the Administration shall notify the Motor Vehicle Administration to reinstate the obligor's license or privilege to drive.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The Secretary of Human Resources, in cooperation with the Secretary of Transportation and the Office of Administrative Hearings, shall adopt regulations to implement this section.</section>
  </text>
</law>
