<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gfl" order_by="gfl" level="1">Family Law</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gfl-5-580.3</section_number>
  <catch_line>The requirements of this subsection apply only to an employee hired on or after October 1, 2005....</catch_line>
  <order_by>580.3</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The requirements of this subsection apply only to an employee hired on or after October 1, 2005.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Each employee, as defined in &#xA7; 5-560 of this subtitle, of a child care center that is required to be licensed or to hold a letter of compliance under this subtitle shall apply to the Department of Human Resources, on or before the first day of actual employment, for a child abuse and neglect clearance.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Department may prohibit the operator of a child care center that is required to be licensed or to hold a letter of compliance under this subtitle from employing an individual who:<section prefix="(1)">has received a conviction, a probation before judgment disposition, a not criminally responsible disposition, or a pending charge for any crime or attempted crime enumerated in the regulations adopted by the Department of Public Safety and Correctional Services under Part VI of this subtitle; or</section><section prefix="(2)">has been identified as responsible for child abuse or neglect.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The operator of a child care center that is required to be licensed or to hold a letter of compliance under this subtitle shall immediately notify the Department of a criminal history records check of an employee that reports a conviction, a probation before judgment disposition, a not criminally responsible disposition, or a pending charge for any crime or attempted crime enumerated in the regulations adopted by the Department of Public Safety and Correctional Services under Part VI of this subtitle.</section>
  </text>
</law>
