<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gfl" order_by="" level="1">Family Law</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gfl-14-101</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>101</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this title the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Abuse" means the sustaining of any physical injury by a vulnerable adult as a result of cruel or inhumane treatment or as a result of a malicious act by any person.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Director" means the director of the local department in the county where the vulnerable adult lives.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">"Disabled person" has the meaning stated in &#xA7; 13-101(e) of the Estates and Trusts Article.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"Emergency" means any condition in which an individual is living that presents a substantial risk of death or immediate and serious physical harm to the individual or others.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">"Exploitation" means any action which involves the misuse of a vulnerable adult's funds, property, or person.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">"Health practitioner" includes any person who is authorized to practice healing under the Health Occupations Article.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Human service worker" means any professional employee of any public or private health or social services agency or provider.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Human service worker" includes:<section prefix="(i)">any social worker; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">any caseworker.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(i)">"Law enforcement agency" means a State, county, or municipal police department, bureau, or agency.</section>
    <section prefix="(j)">Except as provided in &#xA7;&#xA7; 14-201, 14-402, and 14-403 of this title, "local department" means the local department that has jurisdiction in the county:<section prefix="(1)">where the vulnerable adult lives; or</section><section prefix="(2)">where the abuse is alleged to have taken place.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(k)">"Local State's Attorney" means the State's Attorney for the county:<section prefix="(1)">where the vulnerable adult lives; or</section><section prefix="(2)">where the abuse is alleged to have taken place.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(l)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Neglect" means the willful deprivation of a vulnerable adult of adequate food, clothing, essential medical treatment or habilitative therapy, shelter, or supervision.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Neglect" does not include the providing of nonmedical remedial care and treatment for the healing of injury or disease, with the consent of the vulnerable adult, recognized by State law instead of medical treatment.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(m)">"Police officer" means any State or local officer who is authorized to make arrests as part of the officer's official duty.</section>
    <section prefix="(n)">"Review board" means the adult public guardianship review board.</section>
    <section prefix="(o)">"Secretary" means the Secretary of Human Resources.</section>
    <section prefix="(p)">"Self-neglect" means the inability of a vulnerable adult to provide the vulnerable adult with the services:<section prefix="(1)">that are necessary for the vulnerable adult's physical and mental health; and</section><section prefix="(2)">the absence of which impairs or threatens the vulnerable adult's well-being.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(q)">"Vulnerable adult" means an adult who lacks the physical or mental capacity to provide for the adult's daily needs.</section>
  </text>
</law>
