<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gfl" order_by="gfl" level="1">Family Law</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gfl-5-501</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated....</catch_line>
  <order_by>501</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Administration" means:<section prefix="(1)">the Social Services Administration of the Department; or</section><section prefix="(2)">any other unit within the Department to which the Secretary of Human Resources has delegated in writing specified responsibilities of the Administration under this subtitle.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Child care provider" means the adult who has primary responsibility for the operation of a family child care home or large family child care home.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">"Family child care" means the care given to a child under the age of 13 years or to any developmentally disabled person under the age of 21 years, in place of parental care for less than 24 hours a day, in a residence other than the child's residence, for which the child care provider is paid.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"Family child care home" means a residence in which family child care is provided for up to 8 children.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">"Foster care" means continuous 24-hour care and supportive services provided for a minor child placed by a child placement agency in an approved family home.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">"Group care" means continuous 24-hour care and supportive services provided for a minor child placed in a licensed group facility.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">"Kinship care" means continuous 24-hour care and supportive services provided for a minor child placed by a child placement agency in the home of a relative related by blood or marriage within the 5th degree of consanguinity or affinity under the civil law rule.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">"Large family child care home" means a residence in which family child care is provided for at least 9 but not more than 12 children.</section>
    <section prefix="(j)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"License" means a license issued by the Administration under this subtitle.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"License" includes:<section prefix="(i)">a child placement agency license;</section><section prefix="(ii)">a child care home license;</section><section prefix="(iii)">a child care institution license; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">a residential educational facility license.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(k)">"Local board" means a local citizen board of review for children in out-of-home care.</section>
    <section prefix="(l)">"Out-of-home care" means:<section prefix="(1)">out-of-home placement; and</section><section prefix="(2)">the monitoring of and services provided to a child in aftercare following a child's out-of-home placement.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(m)">"Out-of-home placement" means placement of a child into foster care, kinship care, group care, or residential treatment care.</section>
    <section prefix="(n)">"Residential educational facility" means:<section prefix="(1)">a facility that:<section prefix="(i)">provides special education and related services for students with disabilities;</section><section prefix="(ii)">holds a certificate of approval issued by the State Board of Education; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">provides continuous 24-hour care and supportive services to children in a residential setting; or</section></section><section prefix="(2)">one of the following schools:<section prefix="(i)">the Benedictine School;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the Linwood School;</section><section prefix="(iii)">the Maryland School for the Blind; or</section><section prefix="(iv)">the Maryland School for the Deaf.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(o)">"Residential treatment care" means continuous 24-hour care and supportive services for a minor child placed in a facility that provides formal programs of basic care, social work, and health care services.</section>
    <section prefix="(p)">"State Board" means the State Citizens Review Board for Children.</section>
    <section prefix="(q)">"Unregistered family child care home" means a residence in which family child care is provided and in which the child care provider:<section prefix="(1)">has not obtained a certificate of registration from the State Department of Education;</section><section prefix="(2)">is not related by blood or marriage to each child in the provider's care;</section><section prefix="(3)">is not a friend of each child's parents or legal guardian and is providing care on a regular basis; and</section><section prefix="(4)">has not received the care of the child from a child placement agency licensed by the Administration or by a local department.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(r)">"Voluntary placement agreement" means a binding, written agreement voluntarily entered into between a local department and the parent or legal guardian of a minor child that specifies, at a minimum, the legal status of the child and the rights and obligations of the parent or legal guardian, the child, and the local department while the child is in placement.</section>
  </text>
</law>
