<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gfl" order_by="gfl" level="1">Family Law</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gfl-5-705.1</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this section, "local department" means a department of social services for a county in this State...</catch_line>
  <order_by>705.1</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, "local department" means a department of social services for a county in this State.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The following provisions of this subtitle shall apply to the reporting of suspected abuse or neglect under this section:<section prefix="(1)">except as provided in subsection (a) of this section, the definitions set forth in &#xA7; 5-701 of this subtitle;</section><section prefix="(2)">the provisions relating to the confidentiality of reports specified in &#xA7; 5-707(a)(1) and (2) of this subtitle; and</section><section prefix="(3)">the provisions relating to immunity from civil liability or criminal penalty specified in &#xA7; 5-708 of this subtitle.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If suspected abuse or neglect is alleged to have occurred outside of this State and the victim is currently a child who lives outside of this State, a person who would be required to report suspected abuse or neglect under the provisions of &#xA7; 5-704 or &#xA7; 5-705 of this subtitle shall report the suspected abuse or neglect to any local department in accordance with paragraph (2) of this subsection.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A person described in &#xA7; 5-704 of this subtitle shall make:<section prefix="(i)">an oral report, by telephone or direct communication, as soon as possible; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">a written report not later than 48 hours after the contact, examination, attention, or treatment that caused the person to believe that the child had been subjected to abuse or neglect.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A person described in &#xA7; 5-705 of this subtitle shall make an oral or a written report.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">To the extent possible, a report under this subsection shall include the information specified in &#xA7; 5-704(c) of this subtitle.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Promptly after receiving a report of suspected abuse or neglect under this section, the local department shall forward the report to the appropriate agency outside of this State that is authorized to receive and investigate reports of suspected abuse or neglect.</section>
  </text>
</law>
