<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gfl" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="5-4B-01" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gfl-5-4B-01</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Administration" means the Social Services Administration of the Department.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Confidential intermediary" means an individual or child placement agency qualified by the Director for the purpose of providing search, contact, and reunion services under this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">"Director" means the Director of the Administration.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"Member of the adoptive family" means an adoptive parent, grandparent, brother, or sister of an adopted individual.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">"Relative" means a parent, brother, sister, child, aunt, or uncle of a biological parent.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">"Search, contact, and reunion services" means services:<section prefix="(1)">to locate adopted individuals, biological parents of adopted individuals, siblings of adopted individuals, and, as provided in &#xA7; 5-4B-11 of this subtitle, relatives and members of the adoptive family;</section><section prefix="(2)">to assess the mutual desire for communication or disclosure of information:<section prefix="(i)">between adopted individuals and biological parents of adopted individuals;</section><section prefix="(ii)">between adopted individuals and siblings of adopted individuals; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">as provided in &#xA7; 5-4B-11 of this subtitle, between:</section></section><section prefix="(3)">to provide, or provide referral to, counseling for adopted individuals, biological parents of adopted individuals, siblings of adopted individuals, relatives, and members of the adoptive family; and</section><section prefix="(4)">if siblings of a minor in out-of-home placement were adopted through a local department, to contact the siblings to develop a placement resource or facilitate a family connection with the siblings of the minor.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(h)">"Sibling" means a brother or sister of the whole or half blood who:<section prefix="(1)">is at least 21 years old; and</section><section prefix="(2)">has been adopted.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
