<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gfl" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="5-308" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gfl-5-308</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A prospective adoptive parent and parent of a prospective adoptee under this subtitle may enter into a written agreement to allow contact, after the adoption, between:<section prefix="(i)">the parent or other relative of the adoptee; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">the adoptee or adoptive parent.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">An adoptive parent and former parent of an adoptee under this subtitle may enter into a written agreement to allow contact between:<section prefix="(i)">a relative or former parent of the adoptee; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">the adoptee or adoptive parent.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">An agreement made under this section applies to contact with an adoptee only while the adoptee is a minor.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">An individual who prepares an agreement described in subsection (a)(1) of this section:<section prefix="(1)">shall provide a copy to each party in a case pending as to the prospective adoptee under this subtitle or in a CINA case pending as to the prospective adoptee; and</section><section prefix="(2)">if the agreement so provides, shall redact identifying information from the copies.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Failure to comply with a condition of an agreement made under this section is not a ground for revoking consent to, or setting aside an order for, an adoption or guardianship.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">If a dispute as to an agreement made under this section arises, a court may refer the parties to mediation to try to resolve the dispute.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A juvenile court or other court of competent jurisdiction shall enforce a written agreement made in accordance with this section unless enforcement is not in the adoptee's best interests.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If a party moves in juvenile court or another court of competent jurisdiction to modify a written agreement made in accordance with this section and satisfies the court that modification is justified because an exceptional circumstance has arisen and the court finds modification to be in an adoptee's best interests, the court may modify the agreement.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
