<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gfl" order_by="" level="1">Family Law</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gfl-12-202</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>202</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Subject to the provisions of paragraph (2) of this subsection, in any proceeding to establish or modify child support, whether pendente lite or permanent, the court shall use the child support guidelines set forth in this subtitle.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">There is a rebuttable presumption that the amount of child support which would result from the application of the child support guidelines set forth in this subtitle is the correct amount of child support to be awarded.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The presumption may be rebutted by evidence that the application of the guidelines would be unjust or inappropriate in a particular case.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">In determining whether the application of the guidelines would be unjust or inappropriate in a particular case, the court may consider:<section prefix="1.">the terms of any existing separation or property settlement agreement or court order, including any provisions for payment of mortgages or marital debts, payment of college education expenses, the terms of any use and possession order or right to occupy the family home under an agreement, any direct payments made for the benefit of the children required by agreement or order, or any other financial considerations set out in an existing separation or property settlement agreement or court order; and</section><section prefix="2.">the presence in the household of either parent of other children to whom that parent owes a duty of support and the expenses for whom that parent is directly contributing.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(iv)">The presumption may not be rebutted solely on the basis of evidence of the presence in the household of either parent of other children to whom that parent owes a duty of support and the expenses for whom that parent is directly contributing.</section>
        <section prefix="(v)">
          <section prefix="1.">If the court determines that the application of the guidelines would be unjust or inappropriate in a particular case, the court shall make a written finding or specific finding on the record stating the reasons for departing from the guidelines.</section>
          <section prefix="2.">The court's finding shall state:</section>
        </section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The adoption or revision of the guidelines set forth in this subtitle is not a material change of circumstance for the purpose of a modification of a child support award.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">On or before January 1, 1993, and at least every 4 years after that date, the Child Support Enforcement Administration of the Department of Human Resources shall:<section prefix="(1)">review the guidelines set forth in this subtitle to ensure that the application of the guidelines results in the determination of appropriate child support award amounts; and</section><section prefix="(2)">report its findings and recommendations to the General Assembly, subject to &#xA7; 2-1246 of the State Government Article.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
