<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gfl" order_by="" level="1">Family Law</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gfl-9-403</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>403</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">There is a State Clearinghouse for Missing Children operated by the Department of State Police that is responsible for:<section prefix="(1)">the receipt, collection, and distribution of general information and annual statistics regarding missing children; and</section><section prefix="(2)">coordination of law enforcement agencies and other interested persons or groups within and outside the State regarding information on children who have disappeared from, or are thought to be located in, Maryland.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">For children who have disappeared from or are thought to be located in the State, the State Clearinghouse for Missing Children:<section prefix="(1)">shall publish:<section prefix="(i)">the names of and relevant available information on missing children; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">annual statistics regarding missing children; and</section></section><section prefix="(2)">may establish and maintain a list of organizations and groups that provide volunteer search teams or resources relating to missing children.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Secretary of State Police may develop, in cooperation with local law enforcement agencies, a plan for voluntary fingerprinting programs for children.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">An advisory council shall be appointed having the following responsibilities:<section prefix="(i)">review of the activities of the State Clearinghouse;</section><section prefix="(ii)">review of the training provided for, and investigatory procedures used by, law enforcement personnel in the locating of missing children;</section><section prefix="(iii)">examine possible methods for identifying missing children prior to enrollment in a public or nonpublic school; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">explore the feasibility and effectiveness of utilizing the Federal Parent Locator Service in locating missing children.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The advisory council shall consist of the following members:<section prefix="(i)">1 person from the Department of Juvenile Services, to be designated by the Secretary of Juvenile Services;</section><section prefix="(ii)">1 person from the Maryland State Department of Education, to be designated by the State Superintendent of Schools;</section><section prefix="(iii)">1 person from the Department of State Police, to be appointed by the Secretary of State Police;</section><section prefix="(iv)">the Special Secretary of the Office for Children, Youth, and Families, who shall serve as chairman of the advisory council;</section><section prefix="(v)">the President of the Governor's Youth Advisory Council or a designee of the President from the Council;</section><section prefix="(vi)">1 member from the State Sheriff's Association, to be designated by the President of the Association;</section><section prefix="(vii)">1 member from the State Chiefs of Police Association, to be designated by the President of the Association; and</section><section prefix="(viii)">2 members from the public at-large, to be appointed by the Governor.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The term of council members from the public shall be 2 years.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">At the end of a term, a council member from the public shall continue to serve until a successor is appointed.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Council members from the public may serve successive terms.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
