<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gfl" order_by="" level="1">Family Law</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gfl-10-119.3</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>119.3</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"License" means any license, certificate, registration, permit, or other authorization that:<section prefix="(i)">is issued by a licensing authority;</section><section prefix="(ii)">is subject to suspension, revocation, forfeiture, or termination by a licensing authority; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">is necessary for an individual to practice or engage in a particular business, occupation, or profession.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">"Licensing authority" means a department, unit of a department, commission, board, office, or court of the State.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">"Licensing authority" includes:<section prefix="1.">the Department of Labor, Licensing, and Regulation;</section><section prefix="2.">the Department of Health and Mental Hygiene;</section><section prefix="3.">the Department of Human Resources;</section><section prefix="4.">the Department of Transportation;</section><section prefix="5.">the Department of the Environment;</section><section prefix="6.">the Comptroller of the Treasury;</section><section prefix="7.">the Department of Agriculture;</section><section prefix="8.">the Maryland Insurance Administration;</section><section prefix="9.">the Public Service Commission;</section><section prefix="10.">the Secretary of State;</section><section prefix="11.">the State Department of Education;</section><section prefix="12.">the Department of Natural Resources;</section><section prefix="13.">the Office of the Attorney General;</section><section prefix="14.">the clerks of the court that are authorized to issue a license or certificate for professional services or recreational uses; and</section><section prefix="15.">the Court of Appeals.</section></section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A licensing authority shall:<section prefix="(1)">require each applicant for a license to disclose the Social Security number of the applicant; and</section><section prefix="(2)">record the applicant's Social Security number on the application.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">To carry out its responsibility under State and federal law, the Administration may request from a licensing authority information concerning any obligor in arrears in paying child support through a support enforcement agency.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A request for information by the Administration under paragraph (1) of this subsection:<section prefix="(i)">shall contain:<section prefix="1.">the full name of the obligor; and</section><section prefix="2.">the Social Security number of the obligor; and</section></section><section prefix="(ii)">may be transmitted to a licensing authority using an electronic format.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A request for information may not be made by the Administration to a licensing authority more frequently than four times in each calendar year except with respect to an obligor whom the Administration has reason to believe is licensed by, or has applied for a license from, the licensing authority.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">In addition to requests for information under this subsection, the Administration may request a licensing authority to periodically share its licensing database with the Administration.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Upon receipt of a request for information under subsection (c) of this section, a licensing authority shall submit the following information to the Administration with respect to each obligor who is licensed by, or has applied for a license from, the licensing authority:<section prefix="(i)">the full name of the obligor;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the address of the obligor, if known;</section><section prefix="(iii)">the Social Security number of the obligor, if known; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">a description of the license held by the obligor.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The information may be transmitted to the Administration in an electronic format.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Except as otherwise provided by law, any record compiled under this subsection shall be made available only to a person who has a right to the record in an official capacity.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in paragraph (3) of this subsection and subject to the provisions of subsection (f) of this section, the Administration may request a licensing authority to suspend or deny an individual's license if:<section prefix="(i)"><section prefix="1.">the individual is in arrears amounting to more than 120 days under the most recent order; and</section><section prefix="2."/></section><section prefix="(ii)">the individual has failed to comply with a subpoena issued by the Administration under &#xA7; 10-108.6 of this subtitle.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Except as provided in paragraph (3) of this subsection, upon notification by the Administration under this section, a licensing authority shall:<section prefix="(i)">suspend an individual's license; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">deny the license of an individual who is an applicant for a license from the licensing authority.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">This paragraph applies if the licensing authority is the Court of Appeals.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">If an individual meets the criteria specified in paragraph (1) of this subsection, the Administration may make a referral to the Attorney Grievance Commission for proceedings in accordance with the Maryland Rules governing attorney discipline.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">On recommendation of the Attorney Grievance Commission, the Court of Appeals may suspend an individual's license or take other action against the individual as authorized by the Maryland Rules governing attorney discipline.</section>
        <section prefix="(iv)">The Court of Appeals may adopt rules to implement the provisions of this paragraph.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">At least 30 days before requesting a licensing authority to suspend or deny a license or at least 30 days before making a referral under subsection (e)(3) of this section, the Administration shall:<section prefix="(i)">send written notice of the proposed action to the individual whose license is subject to suspension under this section, including notice of the individual's right to request an investigation; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">give the individual a reasonable opportunity to contest the accuracy of the information.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Upon receipt of a request for investigation from an individual whose license is subject to suspension, the Administration shall conduct an investigation.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">Upon completion of the investigation, the Administration shall notify the individual of the result of the investigation and the individual's right to appeal to the Office of Administrative Hearings.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">An appeal under this section shall be conducted in accordance with Title 10, Subtitle 2 of the State Government Article.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">An appeal shall be made in writing and shall be received by the Office of Administrative Hearings within 30 days after the notice to the individual whose license is subject to suspension of the results of the investigation.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(4)">If, after the investigation or appeal to the Office of Administrative Hearings, the Administration finds that it erred in making a decision, the Administration may not send a notification about an individual to a licensing authority or make a referral under subsection (e)(3) of this section.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">The Administration may not send a notification about an individual to a licensing authority or make a referral under subsection (e)(3) of this section if:<section prefix="(1)">with respect to an individual with a child support arrearage:<section prefix="(i)">the Administration reaches an agreement with the individual regarding a scheduled payment of the child support arrearage or a court issues an order for a scheduled payment of the child support arrearage; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">the individual is complying with the agreement or court order; or</section></section><section prefix="(2)">with respect to an individual who failed to comply with a subpoena issued under &#xA7; 10-108.5 of this subtitle, the individual has complied with the subpoena.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(h)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, prior to the suspension or denial of a license under subsection (e) of this section, a licensing authority shall send written notice of the proposed action to the individual whose license is subject to suspension or denial, including notice of the individual's right to contest the identity of the individual whose license or application is to be suspended or denied.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If the licensing authority is the Court of Appeals, notice shall be as provided in the Maryland Rules governing attorney discipline.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(i)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, an individual may appeal a decision of a licensing authority to suspend or deny the individual's license in accordance with Title 10, Subtitle 2 of the State Government Article.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">At a hearing under this paragraph, the issue shall be limited to whether the Administration has mistaken the identity of the individual whose license has been suspended or denied.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If the licensing authority is the Court of Appeals, an individual may appeal a decision in accordance with the Maryland Rules governing attorney discipline.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(j)">The Administration shall notify the licensing authority to reinstate any license suspended or denied under this section within 10 days after the occurrence of any of the following events:<section prefix="(1)">the Administration receives a court order to reinstate the suspended license; or</section><section prefix="(2)">with respect to an individual with a child support arrearage, the individual has:<section prefix="(i)">paid the support arrearage in full; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">demonstrated good faith by paying the ordered amount of support for 4 consecutive months; or</section></section><section prefix="(3)">with respect to an individual whose license was suspended or denied because of a failure to comply with a subpoena issued under &#xA7; 10-108.5 of this subtitle, the individual has complied with the subpoena.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(k)">A licensing authority shall immediately reinstate any license suspended, or process an application for any license denied, under this section if:<section prefix="(1)">notified by the Administration that the license should be reinstated; and</section><section prefix="(2)">the individual otherwise qualifies for the license.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
