<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gfl" order_by="" level="1">Family Law</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gfl-2-404</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>404</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The fee for a license is $10.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The clerk shall:<section prefix="(i)">retain $5 of the fee; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">pay $5 of the fee into the general fund of the county.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">A party to be married may obtain a replacement for a valid marriage license while the license is valid.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The fee for a replacement license is $10, payable into the General Fund of the State.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Except as otherwise provided in this section:<section prefix="(1)">any county or group of 2 or more counties may set an additional fee of up to $25 for each license; and</section><section prefix="(2)">the proceeds shall be used to fund domestic violence programs.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">In Anne Arundel County:<section prefix="(1)">the County Council may set by ordinance an additional fee of up to $45 for each license;</section><section prefix="(2)">the clerk shall pay the proceeds from the additional fee to the general fund of the county each month; and</section><section prefix="(3)">the County Council shall distribute the proceeds to promote or fund domestic violence programs.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">In Baltimore City:<section prefix="(1)">the Mayor and City Council shall set by resolution an additional fee of up to $75 for each license;</section><section prefix="(2)">the clerk shall pay the proceeds from the additional fee to the Mayor and City Council each month; and</section><section prefix="(3)">the proceeds shall be used to fund domestic violence programs that have 24-hour intake ability.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">In Baltimore County:<section prefix="(1)">in addition to the fee authorized under subsection (b)(1) of this section, the County Council may set by resolution an additional fee of up to $15 for each license;</section><section prefix="(2)">the clerk shall pay the proceeds from the additional fee to the Director of Finance of the county each month;</section><section prefix="(3)">the proceeds, in addition to designated federal, State, and county funds, shall be used to fund battered spouse shelters and domestic violence programs established under Title 4, Subtitle 5 of this article; and</section><section prefix="(4)">the County Executive shall prepare and make available an annual report on or before December 1 of each year on the disposition of fees collected under this subsection during the previous fiscal year.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">In Calvert County:<section prefix="(1)">the Board of County Commissioners may set an additional fee of up to $55 for each license;</section><section prefix="(2)">the clerk shall pay the proceeds from the additional fee to the County Commissioners each month; and</section><section prefix="(3)">the proceeds shall be used to fund battered spouse shelters and domestic violence programs in Calvert County.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(g)">In Cecil County:<section prefix="(1)">the Board of County Commissioners shall set an additional fee of $20 for each license;</section><section prefix="(2)">the clerk shall pay the proceeds from the additional fee to the County Treasurer each month;</section><section prefix="(3)">the proceeds in addition to designated federal funds and county funds shall be given to the Cecil County Department of Social Services Advisory Board to be used to fund battered spouse shelters and domestic violence programs; and</section><section prefix="(4)">the Cecil County Department of Social Services Advisory Board shall prepare and make available to the Board of County Commissioners an annual report on or before December 1 of each year of the disposition of fees collected under this subsection during the previous fiscal year.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(h)">In Charles County:<section prefix="(1)">the Board of County Commissioners may set an additional fee of up to $35 for each license;</section><section prefix="(2)">the clerk shall pay the proceeds from the additional fee to the County Commissioners each month; and</section><section prefix="(3)">the proceeds shall be used to fund domestic violence programs located in Charles County.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(i)">In Frederick County:<section prefix="(1)">the Board of County Commissioners may set an additional fee, in an amount not to exceed $65, for each license;</section><section prefix="(2)">the clerk shall pay the proceeds from the additional fee to the County Commissioners each month; and</section><section prefix="(3)">the proceeds, in addition to designated federal, State, and county funds, shall be used to fund domestic violence programs established under Title 4, Subtitle 5 of this article.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(j)">In Garrett County:<section prefix="(1)">the Board of County Commissioners may set an additional fee of up to $40 for each license;</section><section prefix="(2)">the clerk shall pay the proceeds from the additional fee to the County Commissioners each month; and</section><section prefix="(3)">the proceeds shall be used to fund domestic violence programs in Garrett County.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(k)">In Harford County:<section prefix="(1)">the County Council may set by resolution an additional fee of up to $40 for each license;</section><section prefix="(2)">the clerk shall:<section prefix="(i)">retain 3% of the proceeds from the additional fee for processing;</section><section prefix="(ii)">pay $5 of the proceeds from each license to the Harford County Sexual Assault/Spousal Abuse Resource Center, Inc.; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">pay the remaining proceeds to the Treasurer of Harford County each month;</section></section><section prefix="(3)">the county:<section prefix="(i)">shall use the proceeds, in addition to designated federal, State, and county funds, to fund battered spouse shelters and domestic violence programs; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">may make in-kind contributions to battered spouse and domestic violence programs; and</section></section><section prefix="(4)">the County Executive shall prepare and make available an annual report on or before December 1 of each year on the disposition of fees collected under this subsection during the previous fiscal year.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(l)">In Howard County:<section prefix="(1)">the County Council may set by resolution an additional fee of up to $50 for each license;</section><section prefix="(2)">the clerk shall pay the proceeds from the additional fee to the Director of Finance of the county each month;</section><section prefix="(3)">the proceeds, in addition to designated federal, State, and county funds, shall be used to fund battered spouse shelters and domestic violence programs established under Title 4, Subtitle 5 of this article; and</section><section prefix="(4)">the County Executive shall prepare and make available an annual report on or before December 1 of each year on the disposition of fees collected under this subsection during the previous fiscal year.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(m)">In Montgomery County:<section prefix="(1)">the County Council may set by resolution an additional fee of up to $45 for each license;</section><section prefix="(2)">the clerk shall pay the proceeds from the additional fee to the Director of Finance of the county each month;</section><section prefix="(3)">the proceeds, in addition to designated federal, State, and county funds, shall be used to fund battered spouse shelters and domestic violence programs; and</section><section prefix="(4)">the County Executive shall prepare and make available an annual report on or before December 1 of each year on the disposition of fees collected under this subsection during the previous fiscal year.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(n)">In Prince George's County:<section prefix="(1)">the County Council may set by resolution an additional fee of up to $60 for each license;</section><section prefix="(2)">the clerk shall pay the proceeds from the additional fee to the Director of Finance of the county, who shall distribute the proceeds to the Family Crisis Center of Prince George's County each month;</section><section prefix="(3)">if the Family Crisis Center of Prince George's County changes its name or objectives or ceases to exist, the proceeds, in addition to designated federal, State, and county funds, shall be used to fund battered spouse shelters and domestic violence programs; and</section><section prefix="(4)">the County Executive shall prepare and make available an annual report on or before December 1 of each year on the disposition of fees collected under this subsection during the previous fiscal year.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(o)">In Washington County:<section prefix="(1)">the Board of County Commissioners may set an additional fee of up to $50 for each license;</section><section prefix="(2)">the clerk shall pay the proceeds from the additional fee to the County Commissioners each month; and</section><section prefix="(3)">the proceeds shall be used to fund battered spouse shelters and domestic violence programs in Washington County.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
