<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gfl" order_by="gfl" level="1">Family Law</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gfl-14-404</section_number>
  <catch_line>Except as provided in subparagraph (ii) of this paragraph, at least every 6 months the review board ...</catch_line>
  <order_by>404</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Except as provided in subparagraph (ii) of this paragraph, at least every 6 months the review board shall review each guardianship that a public agency holds.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">At least once a year the review board shall review each guardianship that a public agency has held for more than 1 year.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">At least every 6 months the review board shall conduct a file review of each guardianship that a public agency has held for more than 1 year based on a written report to the board including the present place of residence and health status of the ward, the guardian's plan for preserving and maintaining the future well-being of the ward, the need for continuation or cessation of the guardianship or for any plans in altering the powers of the guardian, and the most recent dates of visits by the guardian or the guardian's designee.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The review board may review a case more frequently if:<section prefix="(i)">the disabled individual, the disabled individual's guardian, or the disabled individual's attorney files a petition for review; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">the review board, on its own motion, schedules a review.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Notwithstanding the provisions of &#xA7; 13-708(b)(7) of the Estates and Trusts Article, each time that the review board reviews a guardianship, the review board shall recommend that the guardianship be:<section prefix="(i)">continued;</section><section prefix="(ii)">modified; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">terminated.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Notwithstanding that the review board recommends that a guardianship be continued, the court may order that the guardianship be modified or terminated.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The disabled individual shall:<section prefix="(1)">attend each review board hearing if the disabled individual is able to attend; and</section><section prefix="(2)">be represented at each review board hearing by:<section prefix="(i)">the lawyer that the disabled individual chooses; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">a lawyer who is appointed by the court.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Except for purposes of a judicial proceeding under this title, all records of the review board are confidential.</section>
  </text>
</law>
