<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gfl" order_by="gfl" level="1">Family Law</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gfl-4-507</section_number>
  <catch_line>A protective order may be modified or rescinded during the term of the protective order after:...</catch_line>
  <order_by>507</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A protective order may be modified or rescinded during the term of the protective order after:<section prefix="(i)">giving notice to all affected persons eligible for relief and the respondent; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">a hearing.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">For good cause shown, a judge may extend the term of the protective order for 6 months beyond the period specified in &#xA7; 4-506(j) of this subtitle, after:<section prefix="(i)">giving notice to all affected persons eligible for relief and the respondent; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">a hearing.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">If, during the term of a protective order, a judge finds by clear and convincing evidence that the respondent named in the protective order has committed a subsequent act of abuse against a person eligible for relief named in the protective order, the judge may extend the term of the protective order for a period not to exceed 2 years from the date the extension is granted, after:<section prefix="1.">giving notice to all affected persons eligible for relief and the respondent; and</section><section prefix="2.">a hearing.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">In determining the period of extension of a protective order under subparagraph (i) of this paragraph, the judge shall consider the following factors:<section prefix="1.">the nature and severity of the subsequent act of abuse;</section><section prefix="2.">the history and severity of abuse in the relationship between the respondent and any person eligible for relief named in the protective order;</section><section prefix="3.">the pendency and type of criminal charges against the respondent; and</section><section prefix="4.">the nature and extent of the injury or risk of injury caused by the respondent.</section></section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If a District Court judge grants or denies relief under a petition filed under this subtitle, a respondent, any person eligible for relief, or a petitioner may appeal to the circuit court for the county where the District Court is located.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">An appeal taken under this subsection to the circuit court shall be heard de novo in the circuit court.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">If an appeal is filed under this subsection, the District Court judgment shall remain in effect until superseded by a judgment of the circuit court. Unless the circuit court orders otherwise, modification or enforcement of the District Court order shall be by the District Court.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
