<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gfl" order_by="gfl" level="1">Family Law</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gfl-5-560</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this Part VI of this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated....</catch_line>
  <order_by>560</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this Part VI of this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Conviction" means a plea or verdict of guilty or a plea of nolo contendere.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Department" means the Department of Public Safety and Correctional Services.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Employee" means a person that for compensation is employed to work in a facility identified in &#xA7; 5-561 of this subtitle and who:<section prefix="(i)">cares for or supervises children in the facility; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">has access to children who are cared for or supervised in the facility.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Employee" includes a person who:<section prefix="(i)">participates in a pool described in subsection (e)(2) of this section;</section><section prefix="(ii)">for compensation will be employed on a substitute or temporary basis to work in a facility identified in &#xA7; 5-561(b)(1) or (2) of this subtitle; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">will care for or supervise children in the facility or will have access to children who are cared for or supervised in the facility.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Employee" does not include any person employed to work for compensation by the Department of Juvenile Services.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Employer" means an owner, operator, proprietor, or manager of a facility identified in &#xA7; 5-561 of this subtitle who has frequent contact with children who are cared for or supervised in the facility.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">For purposes of &#xA7;&#xA7; 5-561(g), 5-564(a)(2)(i) and (c)(1)(i) and (2), and 5-567 of this subtitle, "employer" includes a child care resource and referral center, an association of registered family child care providers, and an association of licensed child care centers to the extent that the center or association establishes and maintains a pool of individuals who are qualified to work as substitute or temporary employees in a facility identified in &#xA7; 5-561(b)(1) or (2) of this subtitle.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Employer" does not include a State or local agency responsible for the temporary or permanent placement of children in a facility identified in &#xA7; 5-561 of this subtitle.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">"Private entity" means a nongovernmental agency, organization, or employer.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">"Secretary" means the Secretary of Public Safety and Correctional Services.</section>
  </text>
</law>
