<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gfl" order_by="gfl" level="1">Family Law</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gfl-10-113.2</section_number>
  <catch_line>The Administration may certify to the State Comptroller any obligor who is in arrears under a child ...</catch_line>
  <order_by>113.2</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Administration may certify to the State Comptroller any obligor who is in arrears under a child support order, if:<section prefix="(1)">the amount of arrears exceeds $150; and</section><section prefix="(2)">the Administration is providing services in the case under Title IV, Part D, of the federal Social Security Act.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Administration shall notify the obligor that:<section prefix="(1)">a certification has been made by the Administration; and</section><section prefix="(2)">the obligor has a right to request an investigation as provided under subsection (d) of this section.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The certification shall include, if known:<section prefix="(1)">the full name of the obligor, and any other names known to be used by the obligor;</section><section prefix="(2)">the address and Social Security number of the obligor; and</section><section prefix="(3)">the amount of the arrearage.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Within 30 days of the date of the notice of certification, an obligor who disputes the existence or amount of the arrearage may request that the Administration conduct an investigation of the arrearage.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">On receipt of a request for investigation from the obligor, the Administration shall conduct an investigation as to the existence or amount of the arrearage.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">On completion of the investigation, the Administration shall notify the obligor of the outcome of the investigation.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">If, after the investigation the Administration finds there is an error, the Administration shall correct the amount of the reported arrears, or, if appropriate, withdraw the certification.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The State Comptroller shall:<section prefix="(1)">withhold the amount of the arrearage from:<section prefix="(i)">any payment due to the obligor; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">any abandoned property delivered to the State Comptroller under Title 17 of the Commercial Law Article in which the obligor has an interest;</section></section><section prefix="(2)">forward the amount withheld to the Administration; and</section><section prefix="(3)">notify the obligor of:<section prefix="(i)">the amount paid to the Administration; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">the right to appeal the intercept to the Office of Administrative Hearings as provided in subsection (g) of this section.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">On receipt of the intercepted payment, the Administration shall:<section prefix="(1)">retain any part of the payment that does not exceed the amount of arrearage owed at the time the payment was received; and</section><section prefix="(2)">pay to the obligor any part of the payment that exceeds the amount of arrearage owed at the time the payment was received.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Within 30 days of the date of the notice of intercept from the State Comptroller, an obligor who disputes the existence or amount of the arrearage may appeal to the Office of Administrative Hearings.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">An appeal to the Office of Administrative Hearings shall be conducted in accordance with Title 10, Subtitle 2 of the State Government Article.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(h)">The Secretary of Human Resources and the State Comptroller may adopt regulations to carry out this section.</section>
  </text>
</law>
