<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gfl" order_by="gfl" level="1">Family Law</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gfl-2-409</section_number>
  <catch_line>Each marriage certificate shall contain:...</catch_line>
  <order_by>409</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Each marriage certificate shall contain:<section prefix="(1)">the name, signature, and title of the authorized official who performs the marriage ceremony; or</section><section prefix="(2)">if the individuals are married in a Society of Friends marriage ceremony, the signatures of the individuals and the attestation of the certificate by 2 overseers of the marriage ceremony.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The authorized official who performs the marriage ceremony shall:<section prefix="(i)">hand 1 marriage certificate to the individuals; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">return, within 5 days from the date of the marriage ceremony, the other marriage certificate to the clerk who issued the license to which the certificates were attached, but if the authorized official who performs the marriage ceremony dies or resigns, some other individual shall return the certificate.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If the individuals are married in a Society of Friends marriage ceremony, they:<section prefix="(i)">may keep 1 marriage certificate; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">within 5 days from the date of the marriage ceremony, shall return the other marriage certificate to the clerk who issued the license to which the certificates were attached.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">If the marriage certificate is not returned within 6 months after the date on which the license becomes effective, the clerk who issued the license shall attempt to determine whether the marriage ceremony was performed and, if so, the name of the authorized official who performed the marriage ceremony.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">An individual who performs a marriage ceremony or who is married in a Society of Friends marriage ceremony may not violate the provisions of subsection (b)(1)(ii) or (2)(ii) of this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">An individual who violates any provision of this subsection is guilty of a misdemeanor and on conviction is subject to a fine in an amount that the court considers appropriate.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
