<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gfl" order_by="" level="1">Family Law</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gfl-5-325</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>325</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">An order for guardianship of an individual:<section prefix="(1)">except as otherwise provided in this subtitle, &#xA7; 4-414 of the Estates and Trusts Article, and &#xA7; 2-123 of the Real Property Article, terminates a parent's duties, obligations, and rights toward the individual;</section><section prefix="(2)">eliminates the need for a further consent by a parent to adoption of the individual;</section><section prefix="(3)">grants a local department guardianship with the right to consent to the individual's adoption or other planned permanent living arrangement; and</section><section prefix="(4)">terminates the individual's CINA case.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Unless a juvenile court gives legal custody to another person, a child's guardian under this subtitle has legal custody.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Unless a juvenile court orders otherwise and subject to review by the juvenile court, a child's guardian may make all decisions affecting the child's education, health, and welfare, including consenting:<section prefix="1.">to adoption of the child;</section><section prefix="2.">to application by the child for a driver's license;</section><section prefix="3.">to enlistment by the child in the armed forces;</section><section prefix="4.">to marriage of the child; and</section><section prefix="5.">subject to subparagraphs (ii) and (iii) of this paragraph, to medical, psychiatric, or surgical treatment.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">A child's guardian:<section prefix="1.">may have the child admitted to an inpatient psychiatric facility in accordance with the standards for emergency commitment in &#xA7; 10-617 of the Health - General Article for not more than 20 days;</section><section prefix="2.">except as provided in item 1 of this subparagraph, may not place the child in an inpatient psychiatric facility without express authorization of the juvenile court.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">
          <section prefix="1.">A child's guardian may not withhold or withdraw a life-sustaining procedure without the prior authorization of a juvenile court.</section>
          <section prefix="2.">In deciding whether to grant authorization, a juvenile court shall apply the factors set forth in &#xA7; 13-711(b) of the Estates and Trusts Article.</section>
        </section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A local department shall notify a juvenile court, a child's attorney, and the attorney for each other party who has not waived the right to notice:<section prefix="(i)">within 2 business days after the child's placement changes or the time required under &#xA7; 5-326(b) of this subtitle, whichever is shorter;</section><section prefix="(ii)">within 2 business days after the child is placed in a psychiatric facility; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">within 2 business days after the child is absent from a placement for more than a week.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">A local department shall give a child's attorney the child's new address and telephone number within 2 business days after the address or telephone number changes.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
