<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gfl" order_by="" level="1">Family Law</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gfl-5-562</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>562</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">On or before the 1st day of actual employment, an employee shall apply to the Department for a printed statement.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">On or before the 1st day of actual operation of a facility identified in &#xA7; 5-561 of this subtitle, an employer shall apply to the Department for a printed statement.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Within 5 days after a local department places a child who is committed to the local department with an adult relative, an individual identified in &#xA7; 5-561(c) or (e) of this subtitle shall apply to the Department for a printed statement.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">As part of the application for a criminal history records check, the employee, employer, and individual identified in &#xA7; 5-561(c), (d), (e), or (f) of this subtitle shall submit:<section prefix="(1)">except as provided in subsection (c) of this section, a complete set of legible fingerprints at any designated State or local law enforcement office in the State or other location approved by the Department;</section><section prefix="(2)">the disclosure statement required under &#xA7; 5-563 of this subtitle; and</section><section prefix="(3)">payment for the costs of the criminal history records check.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The requirement that a complete set of legible fingerprints be submitted as part of the application for a criminal history records check may be waived by the Department if:<section prefix="(1)">the application is submitted by a person who has attempted to have a complete set of fingerprints taken on at least 2 occasions;</section><section prefix="(2)">the taking of a complete set of legible fingerprints is not possible because of a physical or medical condition of the person's fingers or hands;</section><section prefix="(3)">the person submits documentation satisfactory to the Department of the requirements of this subsection; and</section><section prefix="(4)">the person submits the other information required for a criminal history records check.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
