<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gfl" order_by="gfl" level="1">Family Law</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gfl-5-534</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this section, "kinship parent" means an individual who is related by blood or marriage within fiv...</catch_line>
  <order_by>534</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, "kinship parent" means an individual who is related by blood or marriage within five degrees of consanguinity or affinity under the civil law rule to a child who is in the care, custody, or guardianship of the local department and with whom the child may be placed for temporary or long-term care other than adoption.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Administration shall establish a kinship care program.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In selecting a placement that is in the best interests of a child in need of out-of-home placement, the local department shall, as a first priority, attempt to place the child with a kinship parent.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The local department shall exhaust all reasonable resources to locate a kinship parent for initial placement of the child.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">If no kinship parent is located at the time of the initial placement, the child shall be placed in a foster care setting.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">If a kinship parent is located subsequent to the placement of a child in a foster care setting, the local department may, if it is in the best interest of the child, place the child with the kinship parent.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A kinship parent may not be less than 21 years of age.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The local department may waive the age requirement of paragraph (1) of this subsection if a potential kinship parent:<section prefix="(i)">is at least 18 years of age; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">lives with a spouse who is at least 21 years of age.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The Administration shall adopt regulations to implement this section that are consistent with the provisions of this section.</section>
  </text>
</law>
