<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gfl" order_by="gfl" level="1">Family Law</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gfl-2-406</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this subsection, "judge" means:...</catch_line>
  <order_by>406</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this subsection, "judge" means:<section prefix="(i)">a judge of the District Court, a circuit court, the Court of Special Appeals, or the Court of Appeals;</section><section prefix="(ii)">a judge approved under Article IV, &#xA7; 3A of the Maryland Constitution and &#xA7; 1-302 of the Courts Article for recall and assignment to the District Court, a circuit court, the Court of Special Appeals, or the Court of Appeals;</section><section prefix="(iii)">a judge of a United States District Court, a United States Court of Appeals, or the United States Tax Court; or</section><section prefix="(iv)">a judge of a state court if the judge is active or retired but eligible for recall.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A marriage ceremony may be performed in this State by:<section prefix="(i)">any official of a religious order or body authorized by the rules and customs of that order or body to perform a marriage ceremony;</section><section prefix="(ii)">any clerk;</section><section prefix="(iii)">any deputy clerk designated by the county administrative judge of the circuit court for the county; or</section><section prefix="(iv)">a judge.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Within 6 months after a license becomes effective, any authorized official may perform the marriage ceremony of the individuals named in the license.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">An individual may not perform a marriage ceremony unless the individual is authorized to perform a marriage ceremony under subsection (a) of this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">An individual who violates this subsection is guilty of a misdemeanor and on conviction is subject to a fine of $500.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">An individual may not knowingly perform a marriage ceremony between individuals who are prohibited from marrying under &#xA7; 2-202 of this title.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">An individual who violates the provisions of this subsection is guilty of a misdemeanor and on conviction is subject to a fine of $500.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">An individual may not perform a marriage ceremony without a license that is effective under this subtitle.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">An individual who violates the provisions of this subsection is guilty of a misdemeanor and on conviction is subject to a fine not exceeding $500.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The county administrative judge of the circuit court for the county shall designate:<section prefix="(1)">when and where the clerk or deputy clerk may perform a marriage ceremony; and</section><section prefix="(2)">the form of the marriage ceremony to be recited by the clerk or deputy clerk and the parties being married.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(g)">This section does not affect the right of any religious denomination to perform a marriage ceremony in accordance with the rules and customs of the denomination.</section>
  </text>
</law>
