<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gfl" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="5-704.1" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gfl-5-704.1</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">An individual may notify the local department or the appropriate law enforcement agency if the individual has reason to believe that a parent, guardian, or caregiver of a child allows the child to reside with or be in the regular presence of an individual, other than the child's parent or guardian, who:<section prefix="(1)">is registered under Title 11, Subtitle 7 of the Criminal Procedure Article based on the commission of an offense against a child; and</section><section prefix="(2)">based on additional information, poses a substantial risk of sexual abuse to the child.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A report under subsection (a) of this section may be oral or in writing.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If acting as a staff member of a hospital, public health agency, child care institution, juvenile detention center, school, or similar institution, an individual who notifies the appropriate authorities under subsection (a) of this section immediately shall notify and give all of the information required by this section to the head of the institution or the designee of the head of the institution.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">To the extent reasonably possible, an individual who makes a report under this section shall include in the report the following information:<section prefix="(1)">the name, age, and home address of the child;</section><section prefix="(2)">the name and home address of the child's parent or other person who is responsible for the child's care;</section><section prefix="(3)">the whereabouts of the child;</section><section prefix="(4)">the nature and extent of the substantial risk of sexual abuse of the child, including any evidence or information available to the reporter concerning possible previous instances of sexual abuse; and</section><section prefix="(5)">any other information that would help to determine:<section prefix="(i)">the cause of the substantial risk of sexual abuse; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">the identity of any individual responsible for the substantial risk of sexual abuse.</section></section></section>
  </text>
</law>
