<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gfl" order_by="gfl" level="1">Family Law</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gfl-5-701</section_number>
  <catch_line>Except as otherwise provided in &#xA7; 5-705.1 of this subtitle, in this subtitle the following words ha...</catch_line>
  <order_by>701</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Except as otherwise provided in &#xA7; 5-705.1 of this subtitle, in this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Abuse" means:<section prefix="(1)">the physical or mental injury of a child by any parent or other person who has permanent or temporary care or custody or responsibility for supervision of a child, or by any household or family member, under circumstances that indicate that the child's health or welfare is harmed or at substantial risk of being harmed; or</section><section prefix="(2)">sexual abuse of a child, whether physical injuries are sustained or not.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Administration" means the Social Services Administration of the Department.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, "central registry" means any component of the Department's confidential computerized database that contains information regarding child abuse and neglect investigations.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Central registry" does not include a local department case file.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"Child" means any individual under the age of 18 years.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">Repealed.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Educator or human service worker" means any professional employee of any correctional, public, parochial or private educational, health, juvenile service, social or social service agency, institution, or licensed facility.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Educator or human service worker" includes:<section prefix="(i)">any teacher;</section><section prefix="(ii)">any counselor;</section><section prefix="(iii)">any social worker;</section><section prefix="(iv)">any caseworker; and</section><section prefix="(v)">any probation or parole officer.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(h)">"Family member" means a relative by blood, adoption, or marriage of a child.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Health practitioner" includes any person who is authorized to practice healing under the Health Occupations Article or &#xA7; 13-516 of the Education Article.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Health practitioner" does not include an emergency medical dispatcher.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(j)">"Household" means the location:<section prefix="(1)">in which the child resides;</section><section prefix="(2)">where the abuse or neglect is alleged to have taken place; or</section><section prefix="(3)">where the person suspected of abuse or neglect resides.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(k)">"Household member" means a person who lives with, or is a regular presence in, a home of a child at the time of the alleged abuse or neglect.</section>
    <section prefix="(l)">"Identifying information" means the name of:<section prefix="(1)">the child who is alleged to have been abused or neglected;</section><section prefix="(2)">a member of the household of the child;</section><section prefix="(3)">a parent or legal guardian of the child; or</section><section prefix="(4)">an individual suspected of being responsible for abuse or neglect of the child.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(m)">"Indicated" means a finding that there is credible evidence, which has not been satisfactorily refuted, that abuse, neglect, or sexual abuse did occur.</section>
    <section prefix="(n)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Law enforcement agency" means a State, county, or municipal police department, bureau, or agency.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Law enforcement agency" includes:<section prefix="(i)">a State, county, or municipal police department or agency;</section><section prefix="(ii)">a sheriff's office;</section><section prefix="(iii)">a State's Attorney's office; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">the Attorney General's office.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(o)">Except as provided in &#xA7;&#xA7; 5-705.1 and 5-714 of this subtitle, "local department" means the local department that has jurisdiction in the county:<section prefix="(1)">where the allegedly abused or neglected child lives; or</section><section prefix="(2)">if different, where the abuse or neglect is alleged to have taken place.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(p)">"Local department case file" means that component of the Department's confidential computerized database that contains information regarding child abuse and neglect investigations to which access is limited to the local department staff responsible for the investigation.</section>
    <section prefix="(q)">"Local State's Attorney" means the State's Attorney for the county:<section prefix="(1)">where the allegedly abused or neglected child lives; or</section><section prefix="(2)">if different, where the abuse or neglect is alleged to have taken place.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(r)">"Mental injury" means the observable, identifiable, and substantial impairment of a child's mental or psychological ability to function.</section>
    <section prefix="(s)">"Neglect" means the leaving of a child unattended or other failure to give proper care and attention to a child by any parent or other person who has permanent or temporary care or custody or responsibility for supervision of the child under circumstances that indicate:<section prefix="(1)">that the child's health or welfare is harmed or placed at substantial risk of harm; or</section><section prefix="(2)">mental injury to the child or a substantial risk of mental injury.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(t)">"Police officer" means any State or local officer who is authorized to make arrests as part of the officer's official duty.</section>
    <section prefix="(u)">"Record" means the original or any copy of any documentary material, in any form, including a report of suspected child abuse or neglect, that is made by, received by, or received from the State, a county, or a municipal corporation in the State, or any subdivision or agency concerning a case of alleged child abuse or neglect.</section>
    <section prefix="(v)">"Report" means an allegation of abuse or neglect, made or received under this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(w)">"Ruled out" means a finding that abuse, neglect, or sexual abuse did not occur.</section>
    <section prefix="(x)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Sexual abuse" means any act that involves sexual molestation or exploitation of a child by a parent or other person who has permanent or temporary care or custody or responsibility for supervision of a child, or by any household or family member.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Sexual abuse" includes:<section prefix="(i)">allowing or encouraging a child to engage in:<section prefix="1.">obscene photography, films, poses, or similar activity;</section><section prefix="2.">pornographic photography, films, poses, or similar activity; or</section><section prefix="3.">prostitution;</section></section><section prefix="(ii)">human trafficking;</section><section prefix="(iii)">incest;</section><section prefix="(iv)">rape;</section><section prefix="(v)">sexual offense in any degree;</section><section prefix="(vi)">sodomy; and</section><section prefix="(vii)">unnatural or perverted sexual practices.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(y)">"Unsubstantiated" means a finding that there is an insufficient amount of evidence to support a finding of indicated or ruled out.</section>
  </text>
</law>
