<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gfl" order_by="gfl" level="1">Family Law</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gfl-10-123</section_number>
  <catch_line>Except as otherwise provided for in this section and notwithstanding any other provision of this Par...</catch_line>
  <order_by>123</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Except as otherwise provided for in this section and notwithstanding any other provision of this Part III, a court shall immediately authorize service of an earnings withholding order when:<section prefix="(1)"><section prefix="(i)">a support order or modification of support order is passed on or after April 9, 1991;</section><section prefix="(ii)">a case is being enforced by a support enforcement agency; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">the recipient or support enforcement agency requests service of an earnings withholding order; or</section></section><section prefix="(2)">the Department of Health and Mental Hygiene requests service of an earnings withholding order for court ordered medical support.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Except as provided in subsection (d) of this section, for all child support orders that are initially issued in the State on or after January 1, 1994, regardless of whether child support payments are in arrears, a court shall immediately authorize service of an earnings withholding order on the effective date of the order.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">When a court orders immediate service of an earnings withholding order on or after July 1, 1994, the court shall order payments through the State disbursement unit.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A court may not authorize the immediate service of an earnings withholding order if:<section prefix="(1)">any party demonstrates, and the court finds, that there is good cause to not require immediate earnings withholding; or</section><section prefix="(2)">the court approves of the terms of a written agreement of the parties providing for an alternative method of payment.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">If the court authorizes the immediate service of an earnings withholding order, the court shall immediately cause a copy of the earnings withholding order to be served on any employer of the obligor.</section>
  </text>
</law>
