<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gfl" order_by="gfl" level="1">Family Law</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gfl-4-522</section_number>
  <catch_line>Any of the following individuals may apply to participate in the Program:...</catch_line>
  <order_by>522</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Any of the following individuals may apply to participate in the Program:<section prefix="(1)">an individual acting on the individual's own behalf;</section><section prefix="(2)">a parent or guardian acting on behalf of a minor who resides with the parent or guardian; or</section><section prefix="(3)">a guardian acting on behalf of a disabled person.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">An application to participate in the Program shall be in the form required by the Secretary of State and shall contain:<section prefix="(1)">a statement that:<section prefix="(i)">the applicant is a victim of domestic violence; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">the applicant fears for the applicant's safety or the safety of the applicant's child;</section></section><section prefix="(2)">evidence that the applicant is a victim of domestic violence, including:<section prefix="(i)">certified law enforcement, court, or other federal or State agency records or files;</section><section prefix="(ii)">documentation from a domestic violence program; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">documentation from a religious, medical, or other professional from whom the applicant has sought assistance or treatment as a victim of domestic violence;</section></section><section prefix="(3)">a statement that disclosure of the applicant's actual address would endanger the applicant's safety or the safety of the applicant's child;</section><section prefix="(4)">a knowing and voluntary designation of the Secretary of State as agent for purposes of service of process and receipt of first-class, certified, or registered mail;</section><section prefix="(5)">the mailing address and telephone number where the applicant may be contacted by the Secretary of State;</section><section prefix="(6)">the actual address that the applicant requests not be disclosed by the Secretary of State because it would increase the risk of domestic violence;</section><section prefix="(7)">a statement as to whether there is any existing court order or pending court action involving the applicant and related to divorce proceedings, child support, child custody, or child visitation, and the court that issued the order or has jurisdiction over the action;</section><section prefix="(8)">a sworn statement by the applicant that to the best of the applicant's knowledge all of the information contained in the application is true;</section><section prefix="(9)">the signature of the applicant and the date on which the applicant signed the application; and</section><section prefix="(10)">a voluntary release and waiver of all future claims against the State for any claim that may arise from participation in the Program except for a claim based on gross negligence.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">On the filing of a properly completed application and release, the Secretary of State shall:<section prefix="1.">review the application and release; and</section><section prefix="2.">if the application and release are properly completed and accurate, designate the applicant as a Program participant.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">An applicant shall be a participant for 4 years from the date of filing unless the participation is canceled or withdrawn prior to the end of the 4-year period.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A Program participant may withdraw from participation by filing a signed, notarized request for withdrawal with the Secretary of State.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
