<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gfl" order_by="gfl" level="1">Family Law</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gfl-5-316</section_number>
  <catch_line>Promptly after a petition for guardianship is filed under this Part II of this subtitle, a juvenile ...</catch_line>
  <order_by>316</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Promptly after a petition for guardianship is filed under this Part II of this subtitle, a juvenile court shall issue a show-cause order that requires the party to whom it is issued to respond as required under the Maryland Rules.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">On issuance of a show-cause order as to guardianship of a child, a petitioner shall serve the order on:<section prefix="(1)">each of the child's living parents who has not consented to the guardianship;</section><section prefix="(2)">each living parent's last attorney of record in the CINA case; and</section><section prefix="(3)">the child's last attorney of record in the CINA case.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Service under this section shall be:<section prefix="(1)">on a parent, by:<section prefix="(i)">personal service; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">certified mail, restricted delivery, return receipt requested; and</section></section><section prefix="(2)">on an attorney, by:<section prefix="(i)">personal service; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">certified mail, return receipt requested.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Subject to paragraph (2) of this subsection, service on a parent under this section shall be attempted at:<section prefix="(i)">each address in records of a juvenile court kept under &#xA7; 3-822 of the Courts Article within the 270 days immediately preceding the filing of the petition for guardianship;</section><section prefix="(ii)">each address in records of, or known to, the local department within the 270 days immediately preceding the filing of the petition for guardianship;</section><section prefix="(iii)">the last address in records of a child support agency; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">each other address provided by the child's caregiver.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If a local department has proof that a parent does not live at an address, the local department need not attempt service there.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If a juvenile court never notified a parent of the requirements of &#xA7; 3-822 of the Courts Article and a petitioner cannot serve the parent at any of the addresses listed in subsection (d) of this section, the petitioner shall make a reasonable, good faith effort to identify an address for the parent and serve the parent at that address.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A juvenile court shall find that a petitioner has met the requirements of paragraph (1) of this subsection if the petitioner shows, by affidavit or testimony, that the petitioner made inquiries after or within the 180 days immediately preceding the filing of the petition for guardianship:<section prefix="(i)">with the Motor Vehicle Administration;</section><section prefix="(ii)">with the Department;</section><section prefix="(iii)">with the Department of Public Safety and Correctional Services, including its Division of Parole and Probation;</section><section prefix="(iv)">with the detention center of the county where the petition is filed;</section><section prefix="(v)">with the juvenile court;</section><section prefix="(vi)">if the local department is aware that the parent has received benefits from a particular social services entity within the 180 days immediately preceding the filing of the petition, with that entity;</section><section prefix="(vii)">if the local department is aware that the parent has been confined in a particular detention facility within the 180 days immediately preceding the filing of the petition, with that facility;</section><section prefix="(viii)">with the child's caregiver;</section><section prefix="(ix)">if the petitioner is able to contact the child's other parent, with that parent;</section><section prefix="(x)">if the petitioner is able to contact known members of the parent's immediate family, with those members; and</section><section prefix="(xi)">if the petitioner is able to contact the parent's current or last known employer, with that employer.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A juvenile court shall consider an inquiry under this subsection sufficient if made by searching the computer files of, or making an inquiry by first-class mail to, a governmental unit or person listed in this subsection.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">A juvenile court shall consider failure to receive a response within 30 days after the petitioner mails an inquiry under this subsection to be a negative response to the inquiry.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If a juvenile court is satisfied, by affidavit or testimony, that a petitioner met the requirements of subsection (d) and, if applicable, subsection (e) of this section but could not effect service on a parent, the juvenile court shall order service through notice by publication as to that parent.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Notice under this subsection shall consist of substantially the following statement:</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Service under this subsection shall be by:<section prefix="(i)">publication at least once in one or more newspapers in general circulation in the county where the parent last resided or, if unknown, where the petition is filed; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">posting for at least 30 days on a website of the Department.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
