<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gfl" order_by="gfl" level="1">Family Law</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gfl-4-506.1</section_number>
  <catch_line>If a respondent surrenders a firearm under &#xA7; 4-505 or &#xA7; 4-506 of this subtitle, a law enforcement ...</catch_line>
  <order_by>506.1</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">If a respondent surrenders a firearm under &#xA7; 4-505 or &#xA7; 4-506 of this subtitle, a law enforcement officer shall:<section prefix="(1)">provide to the respondent information on the process for retaking possession of the firearm; and</section><section prefix="(2)">transport and store the firearm in a protective case, if one is available, and in a manner intended to prevent damage to the firearm during the time the protective order is in effect.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The respondent may retake possession of the firearm at the expiration of a temporary protective order unless:<section prefix="(i)">the respondent is ordered to surrender the firearm in a protective order issued under &#xA7; 4-506 of this subtitle; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">the respondent is not otherwise legally entitled to own or possess the firearm.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The respondent may retake possession of the firearm at the expiration of a final protective order unless:<section prefix="(i)">the protective order is extended under &#xA7; 4-507(a)(2) of this subtitle; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">the respondent is not otherwise legally entitled to own or possess the firearm.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Notwithstanding any other law, a respondent may transport a firearm if the respondent is carrying a protective order requiring the surrender of the firearm and:<section prefix="(1)">the firearm is unloaded;</section><section prefix="(2)">the respondent has notified the law enforcement unit, barracks, or station that the firearm is being transported in accordance with the protective order; and</section><section prefix="(3)">the respondent transports the firearm directly to the law enforcement unit, barracks, or station.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
