<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gfl" order_by="gfl" level="1">Family Law</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gfl-10-115</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this section, "legal proceeding" means:...</catch_line>
  <order_by>115</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, "legal proceeding" means:<section prefix="(1)">a civil action for child support;</section><section prefix="(2)">a paternity proceeding under Title 5, Subtitle 10 of this article; and</section><section prefix="(3)">a proceeding under Subtitle 3 of this title.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">In any support action in which the Administration is providing child support services under federal law, the Administration may initiate a legal proceeding to establish, modify, or enforce a duty of support.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">In a legal proceeding, the Administration shall be represented by:<section prefix="(1)">the Attorney General;</section><section prefix="(2)">the State's Attorney, if the State's Attorney has agreed to provide representation under subsection (g) of this section; or</section><section prefix="(3)">a qualified lawyer who is appointed by and subject to supervision and removal by the Attorney General.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">An attorney who initiates or participates in a legal proceeding under this section shall represent the Administration.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">Representation of the Administration by an attorney under this section:<section prefix="(1)">creates an attorney-client relationship between that attorney and the Administration; and</section><section prefix="(2)">does not create an attorney-client relationship between that attorney and any other person.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The attorney representing the Administration in a legal proceeding under this section shall advise the person whom the Administration has approved for child support services that the attorney's representation of the Administration does not create an attorney-client relationship between the attorney and that person.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A State's Attorney may make a written agreement with the Secretary of Human Resources and the county to provide legal representation for a fiscal year. An agreement shall be made by September 1 of the year preceding the fiscal year for which representation will be provided.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">An agreement shall establish reasonable administrative and fiscal requirements for:<section prefix="(i)">providing and continuing representation; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">reimbursement.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
