<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gfl" order_by="gfl" level="1">Family Law</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gfl-5-1309</section_number>
  <catch_line>The Department shall enter into a memorandum of understanding with an entity that has expertise in c...</catch_line>
  <order_by>1309</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Department shall enter into a memorandum of understanding with an entity that has expertise in child welfare best practices to assist in the development and implementation of a local department self-assessment process to monitor the quality of:<section prefix="(1)">child welfare services provided by the local departments; and</section><section prefix="(2)">the management of the child welfare system by the Administration.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A local department self-assessment shall be conducted every 3 years.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">In conducting the self-assessment, a local department shall be required to:<section prefix="(1)">incorporate the results from the outcome measures in &#xA7;&#xA7; 5-1303 through 5-1306 of this subtitle;</section><section prefix="(2)">incorporate the results of the quality assessment of casework services in &#xA7; 5-1308 of this subtitle; and</section><section prefix="(3)">consider the results of the case reviews conducted by the Citizens' Review Board for Children.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">After a local department self-assessment is accepted by the Administration, the local departments shall develop a plan to:<section prefix="(1)">maintain performance that meets standards;</section><section prefix="(2)">strengthen areas needing improvement; and</section><section prefix="(3)">describe how areas needing improvement will be addressed and how improvements will be measured.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The Secretary shall adopt regulations governing the local department self-assessment process, including:<section prefix="(1)">the development of quality assurance procedures;</section><section prefix="(2)">performance standards;</section><section prefix="(3)">the timing of the assessment;</section><section prefix="(4)">the scope of the assessment;</section><section prefix="(5)">the process by which the Administration may accept or reject the local assessment and the plan;</section><section prefix="(6)">the process by which the Administration shall monitor the implementation of the local plans described in subsection (d) of this section; and</section><section prefix="(7)">the process by which the Administration shall use the assessments of the local departments to develop the statewide assessment under Title 45 &#xA7; 1355.33(b) of the Code of Federal Regulations.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Department shall enter into a memorandum of understanding with an entity with expertise in child welfare best practices to collect and maintain information necessary to conduct a local department self-assessment and statewide assessment.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">On or before January 1, 2008, and annually thereafter, the entity that enters into a memorandum of understanding with the Department, as required by this subtitle, subject to &#xA7; 2-1246 of the State Government Article, shall report to the General Assembly on:<section prefix="(i)">the measurement of performance of the local departments and the Administration, as provided in subsection (a) of this section; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">the information collected and maintained under paragraph (1) of this subsection.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Any unit of State government substantively involved with abused or neglected children may contribute information to the entity provided in paragraph (1) of this subsection.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
