<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gfl" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="5-4C-06" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gfl-5-4C-06</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">To register with the Registry, an individual shall submit a notarized affidavit containing the following information:<section prefix="(i)">the individual's current name and any previous name by which the individual was known;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the individual's address and telephone number;</section><section prefix="(iii)">if the individual is a natural parent of the adoptee, the original and adopted names, if known, of the adoptee;</section><section prefix="(iv)">if the individual is an adoptee who is seeking information regarding the adoptee's natural parents, any names, if known, by which the natural parents are or were known;</section><section prefix="(v)">if the individual is an adoptee who is seeking information regarding a natural sibling, any names, if known, by which the natural sibling is or was known;</section><section prefix="(vi)">if known, the place and date of birth of the adoptee;</section><section prefix="(vii)">if known, the name and address of the child placement agency, if any, that placed the adoptee;</section><section prefix="(viii)">if known, the names of the adoptive parents of the adoptee;</section><section prefix="(ix)">the name and address of the court that issued the adoption or guardianship order; and</section><section prefix="(x)">a statement of the individual's consent to be identified to other registrants.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A registrant shall notify the Administration of changes in information occurring after the affidavit is filed.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A registrant may withdraw from the Registry at any time by submitting a notarized affidavit to that effect to the Administration.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Administration shall obtain information necessary for identifying an adoptee, a natural mother of an adoptee, a natural father, or a natural sibling.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Administration may not obtain information regarding:<section prefix="(i)">the adoptive parents of the adoptee;</section><section prefix="(ii)">a child of the adoptive parents who is not a natural sibling; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">the financial status of the adoptive parents of the adoptee.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
