<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gfl" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="10-128" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gfl-10-128</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">An earnings withholding order or an earnings withholding notice sent to the obligor's employer shall:<section prefix="(1)">be a separate document, and not include any other orders or pleadings; and</section><section prefix="(2)">include only the following information:<section prefix="(i)">the amount to be withheld from the obligor's earnings including explanation of the application of the federal Consumer Credit Protection Act limits;</section><section prefix="(ii)">that subject to further orders of the tribunal, the employer is required to withhold the stated amount on a regular and continuing basis commencing on the beginning of the next pay period after receipt of the earnings withholding order or the earnings withholding notice;</section><section prefix="(iii)">that the employer may deduct and retain from the employee's earnings an additional $2 for each deduction made under the earnings withholding order or earnings withholding notice;</section><section prefix="(iv)">that the net amount withheld is to be sent promptly to the State disbursement unit; and</section><section prefix="(v)">any other information that the employer needs to comply with the earnings withholding order or earnings withholding notice.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">An earnings withholding order or earnings withholding notice is binding on each present and future employer of the obligor on whom a copy of the earnings withholding order or earnings withholding notice is served.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Subject to federal law, an earnings withholding order or earnings withholding notice under this Part III of this subtitle has priority over any other lien or legal process.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The copy of the earnings withholding order or earnings withholding notice served on the employer of the obligor shall contain a statement that upon willful violation of the earnings withholding order or earnings withholding notice the employer shall be subject to civil penalties.</section>
  </text>
</law>
