<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gfl" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="5-7A-06" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gfl-5-7A-06</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In addition to any duties set forth elsewhere, the Council shall, by examining the policies and procedures of State and local agencies and specific cases that the Council considers necessary to perform its duties under this section, evaluate the extent to which State and local agencies are effectively discharging their child protection responsibilities in accordance with:<section prefix="(1)">the State plan under 42 U.S.C. &#xA7; 5106a(b);</section><section prefix="(2)">the child protection standards set forth in 42 U.S.C. &#xA7; 5106a(b); and</section><section prefix="(3)">any other criteria that the Council considers important to ensure the protection of children, including:<section prefix="(i)">a review of the extent to which the State child protective services system is coordinated with the foster care and adoption program established under Part E of Title IV of the Social Security Act; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">a review of child fatalities and near fatalities.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Council may request that a local citizens review panel established under &#xA7; 5-539.2 of this title conduct a review under this section and report its findings to the Council.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Council shall coordinate its activities under this section with the State Citizens Review Board for Children, local citizens review panels, and the child fatality review teams in order to avoid unnecessary duplication of effort.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The chairperson of the Council may designate members of the Children's Justice Act Committee as special members of the Council for the purpose of carrying out the duties set forth in this section.</section>
  </text>
</law>
