<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gfl" order_by="gfl" level="1">Family Law</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gfl-4-512</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this section the following words have the meanings indicated....</catch_line>
  <order_by>512</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">"Court record" means an official record of a court about a proceeding that the clerk of a court or other court personnel keeps.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">"Court record" includes:<section prefix="1.">an index, a docket entry, a petition, a memorandum, a transcription of proceedings, an electronic recording, an order, and a judgment; and</section><section prefix="2.">any electronic information about a proceeding on the website maintained by the Maryland Judiciary.</section></section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Shield" means to remove information from public inspection in accordance with this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">"Shielding" means:<section prefix="(i)">with respect to a record kept in a courthouse, removing the record to a separate secure area to which persons who do not have a legitimate reason for access are denied access; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">with respect to electronic information about a proceeding on the website maintained by the Maryland Judiciary, completely removing all information concerning the proceeding from the public Web site, including the names of the parties, case numbers, and any reference to the proceeding or any reference to the removal of the proceeding from the public Web site.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(5)">"Victim services provider" means a nonprofit organization that has been authorized by the Governor's Office of Crime Control and Prevention or the Department of Human Resources to have access to records of shielded protective orders in order to assist victims of abuse.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">If a petition filed under this subtitle is denied or dismissed at the interim, temporary, or final protective order stage of a proceeding under this subtitle, the respondent may file a written request to shield all court records relating to the proceeding.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A request for shielding under this section may not be filed within 3 years after the denial or dismissal of the petition, unless the respondent files with the request a general waiver and release of all the respondent's tort claims related to the proceeding under this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">On the filing of a request for shielding under this section, the court shall schedule a hearing on the request.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The court shall give notice of the hearing to the petitioner or the petitioner's counsel of record.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Except as provided in paragraphs (4) and (5) of this subsection, after the hearing, the court shall order the shielding of all court records relating to the proceeding if the court finds:<section prefix="(i)">that the petition was denied or dismissed at the interim, temporary, or final protective order stage of the proceeding;</section><section prefix="(ii)">that a final protective order or peace order has not been previously issued against the respondent in a proceeding between the petitioner and the respondent; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">that none of the following are pending at the time of the hearing:<section prefix="1.">an interim or temporary protective order or peace order issued against the respondent in a proceeding between the petitioner and the respondent; or</section><section prefix="2.">a criminal charge against the respondent arising from alleged abuse against the petitioner.</section></section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">
        <section prefix="(i)">If the petitioner appears at the shielding hearing and objects to the shielding, the court may, for good cause, deny the shielding.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">In determining whether there is good cause to grant the request to shield court records, the court shall balance the privacy of the respondent and potential danger of adverse consequences to the respondent against the potential risk of future harm and danger to the petitioner and the community.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(5)">Information about the proceeding may not be removed from the Domestic Violence Central Repository.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This section does not preclude the following persons from accessing a shielded record for a legitimate reason:<section prefix="(i)">a law enforcement officer;</section><section prefix="(ii)">an attorney who represents or has represented the petitioner or the respondent in a proceeding;</section><section prefix="(iii)">a State's Attorney;</section><section prefix="(iv)">an employee of a local department; or</section><section prefix="(v)">a victim services provider.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">A person not listed in paragraph (1) of this subsection may subpoena, or file a motion for access to, a record shielded under this section.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">If the court finds that the person has a legitimate reason for access, the court may grant the person access to the shielded record under the terms and conditions that the court determines.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">In ruling on a motion under this paragraph, the court shall balance the person's need for access to the record with the respondent's right to privacy and the potential harm of unwarranted adverse consequences to the respondent that the disclosure may create.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">Within 60 days after entry of an order under subsection (d)(3) of this section, each custodian of court records that are subject to the order of shielding shall advise in writing the court and the respondent of compliance with the order.</section>
  </text>
</law>
