<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghg" order_by="ghg" level="1">Health - General</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghg-18-329</section_number>
  <catch_line>Prior to the administration of pertussis vaccine, the health care provider shall provide to the indi...</catch_line>
  <order_by>329</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Prior to the administration of pertussis vaccine, the health care provider shall provide to the individual's parent or guardian written information, satisfying the requirements of this subsection, and by appropriate inquiries attempt to elicit the information necessary to make the determinations required by &#xA7; 18-332(b) of this subtitle.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The information required under paragraph (1) of this subsection shall include:<section prefix="(i)">The frequency, severity, and potential long-term effects of pertussis;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Possible adverse reactions to pertussis vaccine which, if they occur, should be brought to the immediate attention of the health care provider;</section><section prefix="(iii)">A form listing symptoms to be monitored and containing places where information can be recorded to assist in reporting to the health care provider, local health officer, and the Department;</section><section prefix="(iv)">Measures parents should take to reduce the risk of, or to respond to, any major adverse reaction;</section><section prefix="(v)">Early warning signs or symptoms to which parents should be alert as possible precursors to a major adverse reaction;</section><section prefix="(vi)">When and to whom parents should report any major adverse reaction;</section><section prefix="(vii)">A summary of the immunization requirements adopted under &#xA7; 7-403(a) of the Education Article, including those related to pertussis vaccine; and</section><section prefix="(viii)">The information required under &#xA7; 18-332(a)(1) through (3) of this subtitle.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Department by guideline and consistent with &#xA7; 18-331(b) of this subtitle shall prescribe the form and content of the information provided to parents in accordance with this section.</section>
  </text>
</law>
