<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghg" order_by="ghg" level="1">Health - General</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghg-19-1808</section_number>
  <catch_line>The Department, in consultation with the Maryland Health Care Commission and stakeholders, including...</catch_line>
  <order_by>1808</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Department, in consultation with the Maryland Health Care Commission and stakeholders, including advocates, consumers, and providers of assisted living services, shall develop a standard assisted living program services disclosure statement.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The purpose of the assisted living program services disclosure statement is to inform potential consumers about the services provided by an assisted living program in order to assist a consumer in choosing the most appropriate assisted living program.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">An assisted living program, as part of the application for licensure, shall file with the Office of Health Care Quality the assisted living program services disclosure statement developed by the Department.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If an assisted living program changes the services reported on the assisted living program services disclosure statement, the assisted living program shall file with the Office of Health Care Quality an amended assisted living program services disclosure statement within 30 days of the change in services.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If an individual requests a copy of an assisted living program's services disclosure statement, the assisted living program shall provide a copy of the services disclosure statement to the individual making the request.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">An assisted living program shall provide a copy of the services disclosure statement to individuals as part of the program's marketing materials.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
