<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghg" order_by="" level="1">Health - General</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghg-19-705.5</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>705.5</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">"Inherited metabolic disease" means a disease caused by an inherited abnormality of body chemistry.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">"Inherited metabolic disease" includes a disease for which the State screens newborn babies.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">"Low protein modified food product" means a food product that is:<section prefix="1.">Specially formulated to have less than 1 gram of protein per serving; and</section><section prefix="2.">Intended to be used under the direction of a physician for the dietary treatment of an inherited metabolic disease.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">"Low protein modified food product" does not include a natural food that is naturally low in protein.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(4)">"Medical food" means a food that is:<section prefix="(i)">Intended for the dietary treatment of a disease or condition for which nutritional requirements are established by medical evaluation; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Formulated to be consumed or administered enterally under the direction of a physician.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A health maintenance organization shall include as part of its benefit package of health care services to be provided to members and subscribers coverage for medical foods and low protein modified food products for the treatment of inherited metabolic diseases if the medical foods and low protein modified food products are:<section prefix="(1)">Prescribed as medically necessary for the therapeutic treatment of inherited metabolic diseases; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Administered under the direction of a physician.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
