<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghg" order_by="ghg" level="1">Health - General</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghg-7-512</section_number>
  <catch_line>Each board consists of 7 members appointed by the Governor....</catch_line>
  <order_by>512</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Each board consists of 7 members appointed by the Governor.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The board for each State residential center shall reflect adequately the composition of the community that the State residential center serves.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Of the 7 members of the board for a State residential center:<section prefix="(i)">At least 2 shall be parents or other relatives or guardians of residents of that State residential center; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Each of the others shall be individuals who:<section prefix="1.">Are known for their interest in civic and public affairs; and</section><section prefix="2.">Have expressed an active interest in the care of individuals with an intellectual disability, or generally in intellectual disability endeavors.</section></section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The Governor shall appoint the members from a list of qualified individuals submitted to the Governor by the Secretary. The number of names on the list shall be at least twice the number of vacancies.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Each member of the board for a State residential center shall be a resident of the region that the State residential center serves.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The term of a member is 4 years.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">At the end of a term, a member continues to serve until a successor is appointed and qualifies.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A member who is appointed after a term has begun serves only for the rest of the term and until a successor is appointed and qualifies.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">A member who serves 2 consecutive full 4-year terms may not be reappointed for 4 years after the completion of those terms.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
