<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghg" order_by="" level="1">Health - General</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghg-7-611</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>611</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">When an application for certificate of approval is filed, the Department shall have an investigation made of:<section prefix="(1)">The applicant;</section><section prefix="(2)">The private group home for which approval is sought;</section><section prefix="(3)">The facts stated in the application;</section><section prefix="(4)">The number of other group homes or alternative living units in the neighborhood;</section><section prefix="(5)">The public utilities and services available; and</section><section prefix="(6)">The access to transportation, shopping and recreational facilities, and health-related services.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">When an application for certificate of approval is filed, the Secretary shall hold a public hearing on the application.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Secretary shall publish a notice of the hearing within 60 days of receipt of the completed application.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The notice shall state:<section prefix="(i)">The name of the applicant;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The type of approval that is sought;</section><section prefix="(iii)">The location of the proposed private group home; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">The time and place that the Secretary sets for the hearing, which shall be at least 7 but not more than 15 days after the last publication of the notice.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The notice shall be published at least twice in 1 week:<section prefix="(1)">In 2 newspapers published in the county where the private group home is to be located;</section><section prefix="(2)">If only 1 newspaper is published in that county, in that newspaper; or</section><section prefix="(3)">If a newspaper is not published in that county, any newspaper with substantial circulation in that county.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
