<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghg" order_by="ghg" level="1">Health - General</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghg-19-214.2</section_number>
  <catch_line>Each hospital shall submit to the Commission, at times prescribed by the Commission, the hospital's ...</catch_line>
  <order_by>214.2</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Each hospital shall submit to the Commission, at times prescribed by the Commission, the hospital's policy on the collection of debts owed by patients.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The policy shall:<section prefix="(1)">Provide for active oversight by the hospital of any contract for collection of debts on behalf of the hospital;</section><section prefix="(2)">Prohibit the hospital from selling any debt;</section><section prefix="(3)">Prohibit the charging of interest on bills incurred by self-pay patients before a court judgment is obtained;</section><section prefix="(4)">Describe in detail the consideration by the hospital of patient income, assets, and other criteria;</section><section prefix="(5)">Describe the hospital's procedures for collecting a debt;</section><section prefix="(6)">Describe the circumstances in which the hospital will seek a judgment against a patient;</section><section prefix="(7)">In accordance with subsection (c) of this section, provide for a refund of amounts collected from a patient or the guarantor of a patient who was later found to be eligible for free care on the date of service;</section><section prefix="(8)">If the hospital has obtained a judgment against or reported adverse information to a consumer reporting agency about a patient who later was found to be eligible for free care on the date of the service for which the judgment was awarded or the adverse information was reported, require the hospital to seek to vacate the judgment or strike the adverse information; and</section><section prefix="(9)">Provide a mechanism for a patient to:<section prefix="(i)">Request the hospital to reconsider the denial of free or reduced-cost care; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">File with the hospital a complaint against the hospital or an outside collection agency used by the hospital regarding the handling of the patient's bill.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Beginning October 1, 2010, a hospital shall provide for a refund of amounts exceeding $25 collected from a patient or the guarantor of a patient who, within a 2-year period after the date of service, was found to be eligible for free care on the date of service.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A hospital may reduce the 2-year period under paragraph (1) of this subsection to no less than 30 days after the date the hospital requests information from a patient, or the guarantor of a patient, to determine the patient's eligibility for free care at the time of service, if the hospital documents the lack of cooperation of the patient or the guarantor of a patient in providing the requested information.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">If a patient is enrolled in a means-tested government health care plan that requires the patient to pay out-of-pocket for hospital services, a hospital's refund policy shall provide for a refund that complies with the terms of the patient's plan.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">For at least 120 days after issuing an initial patient bill, a hospital may not report adverse information about a patient to a consumer reporting agency or commence civil action against a patient for nonpayment unless the hospital documents the lack of cooperation of the patient or the guarantor of the patient in providing information needed to determine the patient's obligation with regard to the hospital bill.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A hospital shall report the fulfillment of a patient's payment obligation within 60 days after the obligation is fulfilled to any consumer reporting agency to which the hospital had reported adverse information about the patient.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A hospital may not force the sale or foreclosure of a patient's primary residence to collect a debt owed on a hospital bill.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If a hospital holds a lien on a patient's primary residence, the hospital may maintain its position as a secured creditor with respect to other creditors to whom the patient may owe a debt.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">If a hospital delegates collection activity to an outside collection agency, the hospital shall:<section prefix="(1)">Specify the collection activity to be performed by the outside collection agency through an explicit authorization or contract;</section><section prefix="(2)">Require the outside collection agency to abide by the hospital's credit and collection policy;</section><section prefix="(3)">Specify procedures the outside collection agency must follow if a patient appears to qualify for financial assistance; and</section><section prefix="(4)">Require the outside collection agency to:<section prefix="(i)">In accordance with the hospital's policy, provide a mechanism for a patient to file with the hospital a complaint against the hospital or the outside collection agency regarding the handling of the patient's bill; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Forward the complaint to the hospital if a patient files a complaint with the collection agency.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The board of directors of each hospital shall review and approve the financial assistance and debt collection policies of the hospital at least every 2 years.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A hospital may not alter its financial assistance or debt collection policies without approval by the board of directors.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(h)">The Commission shall review each hospital's implementation of and compliance with the hospital's policies and the requirements of this section.</section>
  </text>
</law>
