<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghg" order_by="" level="1">Health - General</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghg-4-302.3</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>302.3</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"State designated exchange" means the health information exchange designated by the Maryland Health Care Commission and the Health Services Cost Review Commission under &#xA7; 19-143 of this article.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Standard request" means a request for clinical information from a health information exchange that conforms to the major standards version specified by the Office of the National Coordinator for Health Information Technology.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">This section applies to:<section prefix="(1)">Except for the State designated exchange, a health information exchange operating in the State; and</section><section prefix="(2)">A payor that:<section prefix="(i)">Holds a valid certificate of authority issued by the Maryland Insurance Commissioner; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Acts as, operates, or owns a health information exchange.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">An entity to which this section applies shall connect to the State designated exchange in a manner consistent with applicable federal and State privacy laws.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">When a standard request for clinical information is received through the State designated exchange, an entity to which this section applies shall respond to the request to the extent authorized under federal and State privacy laws.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">A consent from a patient to release clinical information to a provider obtained by an entity to which this section applies shall apply to information transmitted through the State designated exchange or by other means.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The Maryland Health Care Commission:<section prefix="(1)">May adopt regulations for implementing the connectivity to the State designated exchange required under this section; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Shall seek, through any regulations adopted under item (1) of this subsection, to promote technology standards and formats that conform to those specified by the Office of the National Coordinator for Health Information Technology.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Maryland Health Care Commission may adopt regulations specifying the scope of clinical information to be exchanged under this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Any regulations adopted under paragraph (1) of this subsection shall limit the scope of the clinical information to purposes that promote:<section prefix="(i)">Improved access to clinical records by treating clinicians; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">Uses of the State designated exchange important to public health agencies.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(h)">This section does not:<section prefix="(1)">Require an entity to which this section applies to collect clinical information or obtain any authorizations, not otherwise required by federal or State law, relating to information to be sent or received through the State designated exchange;</section><section prefix="(2)">Prohibit an entity to which this section applies from directly receiving or sending information to providers or subscribers outside of the State designated exchange; or</section><section prefix="(3)">Prohibit an entity to which this section applies from connecting and interoperating with the State designated exchange in a manner and scope beyond that required under this section.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
