<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghg" order_by="ghg" level="1">Health - General</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghg-19-1901</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated....</catch_line>
  <order_by>1901</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Adult dependent care program" means:<section prefix="(1)">An adult day care facility regulated under Title 14, Subtitle 2 of this article;</section><section prefix="(2)">An assisted living program facility regulated under Subtitle 18 of this title;</section><section prefix="(3)">A group home regulated under Title 10, Subtitle 5 or Title 7, Subtitle 6 of this article;</section><section prefix="(4)">A home health agency regulated under Subtitle 4 of this title;</section><section prefix="(5)">A congregate housing services program regulated under Title 10, Subtitle 2 of the Human Services Article;</section><section prefix="(6)">A residential service agency as defined under &#xA7; 19-4A-01 of this title;</section><section prefix="(7)">An alternative living unit as defined under &#xA7; 7-101 of this article;</section><section prefix="(8)">A hospice facility regulated under Subtitle 9 of this title; or</section><section prefix="(9)">A related institution regulated under Subtitle 3 of this title.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Background check" means a check of court and other records by a private agency.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">"Conviction" means a:<section prefix="(1)">Plea or verdict of guilty;</section><section prefix="(2)">Plea of nolo contendere;</section><section prefix="(3)">Disposition of probation before judgment; or</section><section prefix="(4)">Disposition of not criminally responsible.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"Criminal history records check" means a check of criminal history record information, as defined in &#xA7; 10-201 of the Criminal Procedure Article, by the Department of Public Safety and Correctional Services.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">"Department" means the Department of Public Safety and Correctional Services.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">"Disclosure statement" means a sworn statement or affirmation of the existence of a criminal conviction or pending criminal charges without a final disposition.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Eligible employee" means an individual:<section prefix="(i)">Who, for compensation, works for an adult dependent care program;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Who has routine, direct access to dependent adults in the program; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Who is not licensed or certified under the Health Occupations Article.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Eligible employee" does not include an individual delivering or retrieving medical equipment.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(i)">"Printed statement" means a document issued by the Criminal Justice Information System Central Repository in the Department of Public Safety and Correctional Services in response to an application for a criminal history records check.</section>
    <section prefix="(j)">"Private agency" means a person that:<section prefix="(1)">Is licensed as a private detective agency under Title 13, Subtitle 3 of the Business Occupations and Professions Article;</section><section prefix="(2)">Maintains an errors and omissions insurance policy in an amount not less than $1,000,000;</section><section prefix="(3)">Offers customer assistance in the use of background checks for employment purposes; and</section><section prefix="(4)">Is capable of conducting a background check within the State within 2 working days of a request and outside the State within 5 working days of a request.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(k)">"Secretary" means the Secretary of Public Safety and Correctional Services.</section>
  </text>
</law>
