<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghg" order_by="" level="1">Health - General</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghg-20-306</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>306</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The health officer for each county:<section prefix="(1)">May investigate any suspected nuisance; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Shall investigate and report on the sanitary conditions of schools, places of business, and places of employment in the county.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If the health officer finds that a nuisance exists, the health officer shall serve a written notice to the person who is causing the nuisance, ordering the person to abate the nuisance within a time specified in the notice.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The notice shall be served:<section prefix="(i)">On the person who is causing the nuisance; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">If the person who is causing the nuisance cannot be found, on the owner or occupant of the property where the nuisance exists.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Failure to comply with the requirements of a notice served under this section is a violation of this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">If a question arises between health officers as to the jurisdiction or duties of a health officer in the abatement of a nuisance, the question shall be referred to the Secretary for resolution.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A health officer may file a complaint in the circuit court for the county where the nuisance exists if:<section prefix="(i)">The person served with the notice under this section fails to comply with the requirements of the notice; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">Although the person served with a notice under this section complies with the requirements of the notice, the nuisance is likely to recur on the same property.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A complaint filed under this subsection may seek a court order requiring the individual served with a notice under subsection (b) of this section to:<section prefix="(i)">Comply with the requirements of the health officer's abatement notice;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Abate the nuisance within a specified time;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Prevent the nuisance from recurring; or</section><section prefix="(iv)">Pay a fine of not more than $1,000.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
