<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghg" order_by="" level="1">Health - General</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghg-18-336</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>336</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"HIV" means the human immunodeficiency virus that causes acquired immune deficiency syndrome.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Health care facility" has the same meaning stated in &#xA7; 18-338.2 of this subtitle.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">"Health care provider" means a physician, nurse, or designee of a health care facility.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Except as provided in Title 11, Subtitle 1, Part II of the Criminal Procedure Article or &#xA7; 18-338.3 of this subtitle, before obtaining a fluid or tissue sample from the body of an individual for the purpose of testing the fluid or tissue for the presence of HIV infection, a health care provider shall:<section prefix="(1)">Obtain informed consent from the individual after:<section prefix="(i)">Informing the individual that an HIV test will be administered; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Advising the individual of the right to refuse the HIV test without penalty;</section></section><section prefix="(2)">Document in the medical record the provision of informed consent; and</section><section prefix="(3)">Provide the individual with pretest counseling as provided in regulations adopted by the Department.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Pretest counseling may be provided in writing, verbally, by video, or a combination of these strategies as appropriate based on the individual's informational needs and testing history.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If the HIV test is ordered at a location that is not a health care facility, informed consent shall be in writing and signed by the individual on an informed consent for HIV testing document that is approved by the Department.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The informed consent for HIV testing document shall be distinct and separate from all other consent forms.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A patient identifying number obtained from an anonymous and confidential test site which is approved by the Department may be evidence of a patient's informed consent in lieu of a patient's signature.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">Refusal to consent to the HIV antibody test or a positive test result may not be used as the sole basis by an institution or laboratory to deny services or treatment.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">If the individual is unable to give informed consent, substitute consent may be given under &#xA7; 5-605 of this article.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">A physician or physician's designee who obtains a result from an HIV antibody test conducted in accordance with the provisions of subsection (b) of this section shall:<section prefix="(1)">Notify the individual from whom the fluid or tissue sample was obtained of the  result; and</section><section prefix="(2)">If the test is positive:<section prefix="(i)">Provide a referral for treatment and supportive services;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Counsel the individual to inform all sexual and needle-sharing partners of the individual's positive HIV status;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Offer to assist in notifying the individual's sexual and needle-sharing partners or refer the individual to the local health officer to assist the individual with notifying the individual's sexual and needle-sharing partners; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">If necessary, take action appropriate to comply with &#xA7; 18-337 of this subtitle.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(h)">Local health officers shall make available to health care providers in their jurisdiction information on referral resources for an individual with an HIV positive status, including counseling, testing, needs assessment, treatment, and support services.</section>
  </text>
</law>
