<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="ghg" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="19-319" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghg-19-319</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">To qualify for a license, an applicant and the hospital or related institution to be operated shall meet the requirements of this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">An applicant who is an individual, and any individual who is applying on behalf of a corporation, association, or government agency shall be:<section prefix="(1)">At least 18 years old; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Of reputable and responsible character.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The applicant shall have a certificate of need, as required under Subtitle 1 of this title, for the hospital, residential treatment center, or related institution to be operated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The hospital, residential treatment center, or related institution to be operated shall meet the requirements that the Secretary adopts under this subtitle and Subtitle 12 of this title.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">As a condition of licensure, each hospital shall establish a utilization review program for all patients admitted to the hospital. The utilization review program:<section prefix="(i)">May be conducted by an independent, nonhospital-affiliated review agent;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Shall be performed by registered nurses, medical records technicians, or similar qualified personnel supported and supervised by physicians as may be required;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Shall be certified by the Secretary if the program meets the minimum standards established under paragraph (4) of this subsection; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">Shall be recertified by the Secretary if the hospital makes any changes to the program after the initial certification.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Any change made to a certified utilization review program shall be reported to the Secretary by the hospital within 30 days of the date the change was made.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">If a hospital fails to provide the utilization review program required under this subsection, the Secretary may impose the following penalties:<section prefix="(i)">Delicensure of hospital; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">$500 per day for each day the violation continues.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The Secretary shall, by regulation and in consultation with health care providers and payors, establish minimum standards for a utilization review program, directed at appropriateness and quality of inpatient care, as enumerated in the following items:<section prefix="(i)">Preadmission review of elective admissions;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Postadmission review of emergency admissions;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Concurrent or retrospective review of all admissions as appropriate;</section><section prefix="(iv)">Preauthorization of certain selected procedures if proposed to be performed on an inpatient basis;</section><section prefix="(v)">Continued stay review based on recognized objective criteria;</section><section prefix="(vi)">Discharge planning review; and</section><section prefix="(vii)">Readmission review.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(5)">A patient may not be charged for any days disallowed as a result of retrospective review under paragraph (4) of this subsection unless the patient refuses to leave the hospital when it is medically appropriate to do so and the disallowed days occur:<section prefix="(i)">After the hospital has notified the patient in writing of the potential disallowance; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">As a direct result of the noncompliance by the patient to treatment or hospital regulations.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(6)">A hospital shall be exempt from requiring a utilization review program for a patient if:<section prefix="(i)"/><section prefix="(ii)">The patient is a subscriber or member of a health maintenance organization as defined in &#xA7; 19-701 of this title.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(7)">Where federal regulations or guidelines for a federally mandated utilization review program for federally insured patients differ from standards established under paragraph (4) of this subsection, the Secretary may waive a specific standard if the program achieves the same objectives as the standards established by the Secretary.</section>
      <section prefix="(8)">The Secretary may establish record keeping and reporting requirements:<section prefix="(i)">To evaluate the effectiveness of hospitals' utilization review programs; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">To determine if the utilization review programs are in compliance with the provisions of this section and regulations adopted by the Secretary to administer this section.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this subsection, "uniform standard credentialing form" means:<section prefix="(i)">The form designated by the Secretary through regulation for credentialing physicians who seek to be employed by or have staff privileges at a hospital; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">The uniform credentialing form that the Insurance Commissioner designates under &#xA7; 15-112.1 of the Insurance Article.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">As a condition of licensure, each hospital shall:<section prefix="(i)">Establish a credentialing process for the physicians who are employed by or who have staff privileges at the hospital; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Use the uniform standard credentialing form as the initial application of a physician seeking to be credentialed.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Use of the uniform standard credentialing form does not preclude a hospital from requiring supplemental or additional information as part of the hospital's credentialing process.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The Secretary shall, by regulation and in consultation with hospitals, physicians, interested community and advocacy groups, and representatives of the Maryland Defense Bar and Plaintiffs' Bar, establish minimum standards for a credentialing process which shall include:<section prefix="(i)">A formal written appointment process documenting the physician's education, clinical expertise, licensure history, insurance history, medical history, claims history, and professional experience.</section><section prefix="(ii)">A requirement that an initial appointment to staff not be complete until the physician has successfully completed a probationary period.</section><section prefix="(iii)">A formal, written reappointment process to be conducted at least every 2 years. The reappointment process shall document the physician's pattern of performance by analyzing:</section></section>
      <section prefix="(5)">If requested by the Department, a hospital shall provide documentation that, prior to employing or granting privileges to a physician, the hospital has complied with the requirements of this subsection and that, prior to renewing employment or privileges, the hospital has complied with the requirements of this subsection.</section>
      <section prefix="(6)">If a hospital fails to establish or maintain a credentialing process required under this subsection, the Secretary may impose the following penalties:<section prefix="(i)">Delicensure of the hospital; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">$500 per day for each day the violation continues.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">As a condition of licensure, each accredited and nonaccredited hospital shall develop a protocol for the procurement of organs and tissues.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">As a condition of licensure, each hospital shall establish a risk management program.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Secretary shall, by regulation and in consultation with hospitals, physicians, interested community and advocacy groups, and representatives of the Maryland Defense Bar and Plaintiffs' Bar establish minimum standards for a risk management program which shall include:<section prefix="(i)">A board policy statement indicating commitment to the risk management program;</section><section prefix="(ii)">A requirement that one person be assigned the responsibility for coordinating the program;</section><section prefix="(iii)">An internal staff committee structure to conduct ongoing review and evaluation of risk management activities;</section><section prefix="(iv)">A formal written program for addressing patient complaints;</section><section prefix="(v)">A documented facility-wide risk reporting system;</section><section prefix="(vi)">Ongoing risk management education programs for all staff; and</section><section prefix="(vii)">Documentation that the risk management and quality assurance programs share relevant information.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">If a hospital fails to establish or maintain a risk management program required under this subsection, the Secretary may impose the following penalties:<section prefix="(i)">Delicensure of the hospital; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">$500 per day for each day the violation continues.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(h)">
      <section prefix="(1)">As a condition of licensure, each hospital and related institution shall:<section prefix="(i)">Adopt, implement, and enforce a policy that requires, except in an emergency life-threatening situation where it is not feasible or practicable, all employees and medical staff involved in patient care services to comply with the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention guidelines on universal precautions; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Display the notice developed under &#xA7; 1-207 of the Health Occupations Article at the entrance to the hospital or related institution.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If a hospital or related institution fails to comply with the requirements of this subsection, the Secretary may impose a fine of up to $500 per day per violation for each day a violation continues.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(i)">
      <section prefix="(1)">As a condition of licensure, each hospital shall establish a practitioner performance evaluation process that objectively evaluates the performance of each member of the medical staff at the hospital.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The practitioner performance evaluation process shall include a review of care provided to patients at the hospital by the members of the medical staff.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The review of care shall:<section prefix="(i)">Be undertaken for cases chosen at random and for cases with unexpected adverse outcomes;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Be based on objective review standards;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Include a review of the appropriateness of the plan of care for the patient, particularly any medical procedures performed on the patient, in relation to the patient's condition; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">Be conducted by members of the medical staff or, at the discretion of the hospital, external reviewers, who:</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">A hospital shall take into account the results of the practitioner performance evaluation process for a member of the medical staff in the reappointment process established under subsection (e) of this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">If a hospital fails to comply with the requirements of this subsection, the Secretary may impose a fine of up to $500 per day per violation for each day a violation continues.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
