<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghg" order_by="ghg" level="1">Health - General</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghg-10-713</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this section, "program or facility" means an inpatient or residential treatment setting, resident...</catch_line>
  <order_by>713</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section, "program or facility" means an inpatient or residential treatment setting, residential crisis service, group home, or residential rehabilitation program.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Upon notification of the death of an individual in a State funded or operated program or facility, the administrative head of the program or facility shall report the death:<section prefix="(i)">Immediately to the sheriff, police, or chief law enforcement official in the jurisdiction in which the death occurred;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Immediately to the Secretary; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">By the close of business of the next working day to:<section prefix="1.">The Director;</section><section prefix="2.">The health officer in the jurisdiction where the death occurred; and</section><section prefix="3.">The designated State protection and advocacy system.</section></section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">An initial report:<section prefix="(i)">May be:<section prefix="1.">Oral if followed by a written report within 5 working days from the date of the death; or</section><section prefix="2.">Written;</section></section><section prefix="(ii)">Shall contain the following relevant information:<section prefix="1.">The name, age, and sex of the deceased;</section><section prefix="2.">The time of discovery of the death;</section><section prefix="3.">The deceased's place of residence at the time of death;</section><section prefix="4.">The location of the body at the time of discovery;</section><section prefix="5.">The place where the body was found;</section><section prefix="6.">The name of the person who took custody of the body;</section><section prefix="7.">The name of the person evaluating the death, if known;</section><section prefix="8.">Whether or not an autopsy is being performed, if known; and</section><section prefix="9.">The name, address, and telephone number of the next of kin or legal guardian, if known; and</section></section><section prefix="(iii)">Shall contain any other information the administrative head of the facility determines should be provided to the medical examiner and the persons listed in paragraph (1) of this subsection on the deaths occurring:<section prefix="1.">By violence;</section><section prefix="2.">By suicide;</section><section prefix="3.">By casualty;</section><section prefix="4.">Suddenly, if the deceased was in apparent good health; or</section><section prefix="5.">In any suspicious or unusual manner.</section></section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The written report shall be available for the Director, the health officer in the jurisdiction where the death occurred, and the designated State protection and advocacy system within 5 working days from the date of the death.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">If the death occurred in a program or facility that operates more than one treatment program and where the deceased individual attended more than one treatment program, the facility is required to make only one report.</section>
      <section prefix="(6)">The sheriff, police, or chief law enforcement officer shall inform the medical examiner in accordance with &#xA7; 5-309(b) of this article and the medical examiner, if necessary, shall conduct an investigation in accordance with the provisions of that section.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">If the death occurred in a nonresidential psychiatric rehabilitation program, the administrative head of the program shall report the death to the Director by the close of business of the next working day.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Director shall compile annually a status report for the Secretary on patient deaths reported under this subtitle.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">At a minimum, the status report shall note:<section prefix="(i)">The number of deaths;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The location of each death;</section><section prefix="(iii)">The cause of each death, if known; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">Other data the Secretary determines to be relevant to the status report.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
