<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="ghg" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="5-305" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghg-5-305</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Commission may employ a staff in accordance with the State budget for the operation of the Commission and to maintain accreditation.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The staff shall include:<section prefix="(i)">1 chief medical examiner;</section><section prefix="(ii)">2 deputy chief medical examiners;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Assistant medical examiners;</section><section prefix="(iv)">1 chief State toxicologist, 1 deputy chief State toxicologist, lead toxicologists, and assistant toxicologists;</section><section prefix="(v)">1 serologist;</section><section prefix="(vi)">4 resident medical doctors who are training in forensic pathology;</section><section prefix="(vii)">1 chief forensic investigator, 2 deputy chief forensic investigators, lead forensic investigators, and assistant forensic investigators; and</section><section prefix="(viii)">1 autopsy services supervisor, 1 deputy supervisor, lead autopsy technicians, and assistant autopsy technicians.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Commission may employ any physician on a contract basis for part-time services.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Chief Medical Examiner and deputy chief medical examiners shall be board certified in anatomic and forensic pathology by the American Board of Pathology.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Assistant medical examiners appointed on or after October 1, 2008, shall be certified by the American Board of Pathology in anatomic and forensic pathology or obtain that certification within 3 years of appointment.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">With the approval of the Secretary of Budget and Management, the Commission shall set the compensation for personnel appointed under subsection (a)(2) of this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">For the use of these medical examiners, the Commission shall see that proper equipment is provided.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The Chief Medical Examiner, a deputy chief medical examiner, or an assistant medical examiner shall be on call at all times to perform the duties set forth in this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The State budget shall include an appropriation to carry out this subtitle, including provisions for:<section prefix="(1)">The fee for an authorized pathologist;</section><section prefix="(2)">The necessary expenses for transportation of a body for examination by a medical examiner or for autopsy; and</section><section prefix="(3)">In the case of a victim of homicide, the necessary expenses for transportation of the body from the site of the autopsy or examination to a location within the State specified by the victim's family.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
