<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghg" order_by="ghg" level="1">Health - General</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghg-19-1806</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this section the following words have the meanings indicated....</catch_line>
  <order_by>1806</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Continuing care" has the meaning stated in &#xA7; 10-401 of the Human Services Article.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Continuing care agreement" has the meaning stated in &#xA7; 10-401 of the Human Services Article.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">This section applies to assisted living programs that offer assisted living program services as part of a continuum of care in accordance with a continuing care agreement that does not require a subscriber to execute a separate assisted living agreement to receive those services.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">An assisted living program subject to this section that meets the requirements of Title 10, Subtitle 4 of the Human Services Article with regard to assisted living is not required to execute a separate assisted living resident agreement that is in addition to the continuing care agreement.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">For purposes of paragraph (1) of this subsection, if a separate assisted living resident agreement is not utilized, references to a resident agreement in any regulations adopted under this subtitle shall mean the continuing care agreement.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A continuing care agreement that contains a provision to provide assisted living program services and does not require a subscriber to execute a separate assisted living agreement to receive those services is not required to contain general or specific contract provisions, except as required under Title 10, Subtitle 4 of the Human Services Article, that apply to assisted living programs that are not subject to this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In addition to subsection (c) of this section, an assisted living program subject to this section is not required to provide a disclosure statement relating to its assisted living program separate from any disclosure statement required by Title 10, Subtitle 4 of the Human Services Article for continuing care.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Any disclosure statement required to be provided to a resident under Title 10, Subtitle 4 of the Human Services Article shall include information that is required to be disclosed by an assisted living program in accordance with this subtitle.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">A transfer of a resident from an assisted living program subject to this section to another assisted living or continuing care arrangement governed by the same continuing care agreement may not be considered a relocation or discharge from the assisted living program for purposes of triggering any regulatory requirements adopted under this subtitle for matters relating to notice, financial accounting, or refunds.</section>
  </text>
</law>
