<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghg" order_by="" level="1">Health - General</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghg-22-310</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>310</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Except as otherwise provided in this section, a dangerous household substance that is subject to a child resistant packaging standard may be provided in single size conventional packages designed for easy opening by elderly individuals or individuals with disabilities if:<section prefix="(1)">Elderly individuals or individuals with disabilities would be unable to use the dangerous household substance if packaged in accordance with the child resistant packaging standard;</section><section prefix="(2)">The dangerous household substance is at the same time provided in packages that meet the child resistant packaging standards adopted under this subtitle; and</section><section prefix="(3)">The single size conventional package of the dangerous household substance bears a conspicuous label on which is printed:<section prefix="(i)">"This Package for Households Without Young Children"; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">If the package is too small for that statement, a substitute statement as required by rule or regulation.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If the Secretary finds that a dangerous household substance offered in a single size conventional package under subsection (a) of this section is not offered at the same time in a popular size package that conforms to the child resistant packaging standards, the Secretary may notify the manufacturer or packer of the dangerous household substance of the violation and of a time period within which the violation is to be corrected.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If the violation remains uncorrected at the end of the specified time period, the Secretary, after giving the manufacturer or packer an opportunity for a hearing, may order the manufacturer or packer to package the dangerous household substance only in packages that conform to the child resistant packaging standards.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
