<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="ghg" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="18-214" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghg-18-214</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, "vaccine" means a product intended to elicit, in humans, active or passive immunity against an infectious agent or product of an infectious agent.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">There is a Statewide Advisory Commission on Immunizations.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Commission consists of the following members:<section prefix="(1)">One physician member of MedChi, The Maryland State Medical Society;</section><section prefix="(2)">The chair of the Maryland Childhood Immunization Partnership;</section><section prefix="(3)">Two physician members of the Maryland Chapter of the American Academy of Pediatrics with experience in private practice and infectious diseases;</section><section prefix="(4)">One physician member of the Maryland Academy of Family Physicians;</section><section prefix="(5)">One physician member of the American College of Physicians - Internal Medicine Society of Maryland;</section><section prefix="(6)">The executive director of the Maryland Partnership for Prevention;</section><section prefix="(7)">One local health officer;</section><section prefix="(8)">One representative from the Department's Vaccines for Children Program;</section><section prefix="(9)">One representative from the Maryland school system with knowledge of the immunizations required of children entering schools;</section><section prefix="(10)">The Maryland State Epidemiologist;</section><section prefix="(11)">One representative from a public health consumer advocacy group;</section><section prefix="(12)">One nurse practitioner;</section><section prefix="(13)">One representative from a health insurance carrier;</section><section prefix="(14)">One consumer; and</section><section prefix="(15)">One pharmacist.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Secretary shall appoint the membership of the Commission, based on the recommendation of the appropriate medical society or agency.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Secretary, in consultation with MedChi, The Maryland State Medical Society, shall appoint the chair of the Commission.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The chair of the Commission shall:<section prefix="(i)">Establish subcommittees to facilitate the work of the Commission; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Appoint subcommittee chairs from among the Commission members.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The term of an appointed member is 3 years.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A member who is appointed after a term has begun serves only for the rest of the term and until a successor is appointed and qualifies.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">At the end of a term, a member continues to serve until a successor is appointed and qualifies.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">A member may be appointed for more than one term.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">The terms of the members of the Commission are staggered as required by the terms provided for the members of the Commission on June 1, 2010.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">A member of the Commission may not receive compensation but is entitled to reimbursement for expenses under the Standard State Travel Regulations, as provided in the State budget.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">The Department shall provide the staffing for the Commission.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">The Commission shall:<section prefix="(1)">Determine where community vaccine shortages exist and which vaccines are in short supply;</section><section prefix="(2)">Develop a recommendation for a plan to effectuate the equitable distribution of vaccines;</section><section prefix="(3)">Review:<section prefix="(i)">Potential provider reimbursement barriers to increasing immunizations;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The relative effectiveness of outreach programs that educate the public about the benefits of immunizations;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Potential cost-shifting of immunization expenses for privately insured patients who receive immunizations at local health departments; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">Potential administrative burdens associated with State purchasing of vaccines;</section></section><section prefix="(4)">Based on the review required under item (3) of this subsection, make recommendations on how to increase immunizations, including catch-up immunizations, among adults, adolescents, and children who are recommended to receive immunizations; and</section><section prefix="(5)">Study and make recommendations about other related issues as determined by the Commission, including:<section prefix="(i)">Immunizations required of children entering schools;</section><section prefix="(ii)">All available options for the purchasing of vaccines, including the development of a Universal Vaccine Purchasing System, or a similar program to increase access to necessary vaccines, for the State;</section><section prefix="(iii)">An update on the status of the use of thimerosal in vaccines, including the availability and affordability of thimerosal-free vaccines, and any other issue related to the use of thimerosal in vaccines that is identified by the Commission;</section><section prefix="(iv)">Elimination of any vaccine distribution disparities;</section><section prefix="(v)">A public education campaign in the event of a vaccine shortage or public health emergency involving immunizations; and</section><section prefix="(vi)">The availability and affordability of adult, adolescent, and childhood vaccines.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(j)">The Commission may recommend to the Department that information on vaccine safety be communicated to health care providers.</section>
    <section prefix="(k)">On or before December 15 of each year, the Commission shall submit a report on its findings and recommendations to the Governor and, in accordance with &#xA7; 2-1246 of the State Government Article, to the Senate Education, Health, and Environmental Affairs Committee and the House Health and Government Operations Committee.</section>
  </text>
</law>
