<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghg" order_by="" level="1">Health - General</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghg-19-133</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>133</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, "code" means:<section prefix="(1)">The applicable Current Procedural Terminology (CPT) code as adopted by the American Medical Association; or</section><section prefix="(2)">If a CPT code is not available, the applicable code under an appropriate uniform coding scheme approved by the Commission.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Commission shall establish a Maryland medical care data base to compile statewide data on health services rendered by health care practitioners and facilities selected by the Commission.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">In addition to any other information the Commission may require by regulation, the medical care data base shall:<section prefix="(1)">Collect for each type of patient encounter with a health care practitioner or facility designated by the Commission:<section prefix="(i)">The demographic characteristics of the patient;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The principal diagnosis;</section><section prefix="(iii)">The procedure performed;</section><section prefix="(iv)">The date and location of where the procedure was performed;</section><section prefix="(v)">The charge for the procedure;</section><section prefix="(vi)">If the bill for the procedure was submitted on an assigned or nonassigned basis;</section><section prefix="(vii)">If applicable, a health care practitioner's universal identification number; and</section><section prefix="(viii)">If the health care practitioner rendering the service is a certified registered nurse anesthetist or certified nurse midwife, identification modifiers for the certified registered nurse anesthetist or certified nurse midwife;</section></section><section prefix="(2)">Collect appropriate information relating to prescription drugs for each type of patient encounter with a pharmacist designated by the Commission; and</section><section prefix="(3)">Collect appropriate information relating to health care costs, utilization, or resources from payors and governmental agencies.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Commission shall adopt regulations governing the access and retrieval of all medical claims data and other information collected and stored in the medical care data base and any claims clearinghouse licensed by the Commission and may set reasonable fees covering the costs of accessing and retrieving the stored data.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">These regulations shall ensure that confidential or privileged patient information is kept confidential.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Records or information protected by the privilege between a health care practitioner and a patient, or otherwise required by law to be held confidential, shall be filed in a manner that does not disclose the identity of the person protected.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">To the extent practicable, when collecting the data required under subsection (c) of this section, the Commission shall utilize any standardized claim form or electronic transfer system being used by health care practitioners, facilities, and payors.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Commission shall develop appropriate methods for collecting the data required under subsection (c) of this section on subscribers or enrollees of health maintenance organizations.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">Until the provisions of &#xA7; 19-134 of this subtitle are fully implemented, where appropriate, the Commission may limit the data collection under this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">By October 1, 1995 and each year thereafter, the Commission shall publish an annual report on those health care services selected by the Commission that:<section prefix="(i)">Describes the variation in fees charged by health care practitioners and facilities on a statewide basis and in each health service area for those health care services; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Describes the geographic variation in the utilization of those health care services.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">On an annual basis, the Commission shall publish:<section prefix="1.">The total reimbursement for all health care services over a 12-month period;</section><section prefix="2.">The total reimbursement for each health care specialty over a 12-month period;</section><section prefix="3.">The total reimbursement for each code over a 12-month period; and</section><section prefix="4.">The annual rate of change in reimbursement for health services by health care specialties and by code.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">In addition to the information required under subparagraph (i) of this paragraph, the Commission may publish any other information that the Commission deems appropriate, including information on capitated health care services.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(h)">In developing the medical care data base, the Commission shall consult with representatives of the Health Services Cost Review Commission, health care practitioners, payors, and hospitals to ensure that the medical care data base is compatible with information collected by the Health Services Cost Review Commission.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">The Commission, in consultation with the Insurance Commissioner, payors, health care practitioners, and hospitals, may adopt by regulation standards for the electronic submission of data and submission and transfer of the uniform claims forms established under &#xA7; 15-1003 of the Insurance Article.</section>
  </text>
</law>
