<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghg" order_by="" level="1">Health - General</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghg-8-505</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>505</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Before or during a criminal trial, before or after sentencing, or before or during a term of probation, the court may order the Department to evaluate a defendant to determine whether, by reason of drug or alcohol abuse, the defendant is in need of and may benefit from treatment if:<section prefix="(i)">It appears to the court that the defendant has an alcohol or drug abuse problem; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">The defendant alleges an alcohol or drug dependency.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A court shall set and may change the conditions under which an examination is to be conducted under this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Department shall ensure that each evaluation under this section is conducted in accordance with regulations adopted by the Department.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Except in a capital case, on consideration of the nature of the charge, the court:<section prefix="(1)">May require or permit an examination to be conducted on an outpatient basis; and</section><section prefix="(2)">If an outpatient examination is authorized, shall set bail for the defendant or authorize the release of the defendant on personal recognizance.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If a defendant is to be held in custody for examination under this section:<section prefix="(i)">The defendant may be confined in a detention facility until the Department is able to conduct the examination; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">The court may order confinement of the defendant in a medical wing or other isolated and secure unit of a detention facility, if the court finds it appropriate for the health or safety of the defendant.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">If the court finds that, because of the apparent severity of the alcohol or drug dependency or other medical or psychiatric complications, a defendant in custody would be endangered by confinement in a jail, the court may order the Department to either:<section prefix="1.">Place the defendant, pending examination, in an appropriate health care facility; or</section><section prefix="2.">Immediately conduct an evaluation of the defendant.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">Unless the Department retains a defendant, the defendant shall be promptly returned to the court after an examination.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">A defendant who is detained for an examination under this section may question at any time the legality of the detention by a petition for a writ of habeas corpus.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If a court orders an evaluation under this section, the evaluator shall:<section prefix="(i)">Conduct an evaluation of the defendant; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Submit a complete report of the evaluation within 7 days to the:<section prefix="1.">Court;</section><section prefix="2.">Department; and</section><section prefix="3.">Defendant or the defendant's attorney.</section></section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">On good cause shown, a court may extend the time for an evaluation under this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Whenever an evaluator recommends treatment, the evaluator's report shall:<section prefix="(i)">Name a specific program able to provide the recommended treatment; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Give an actual or estimated date when the program can begin treatment of the defendant.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Department shall provide the services required by this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A designee of the Department may carry out any of its duties under this section if appropriate funding is provided.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">Evaluations performed in facilities operated by the Department of Public Safety and Correctional Services shall be conducted by the Administration.</section>
  </text>
</law>
