<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghg" order_by="" level="1">Health - General</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghg-21-812</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>812</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">A license expires on the first anniversary of its effective date, unless the license is renewed for a 1-year term as provided in this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">At least 1 month before the license expires, the Secretary shall send to the licensee, by first-class mail to the last known address of the licensee, a renewal notice that states:<section prefix="(1)">The date on which the current license expires;</section><section prefix="(2)">The date by which the renewal application must be received by the Secretary for the renewal to be issued and mailed before the license expires; and</section><section prefix="(3)">The amount of the renewal fee.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Before a license expires, the licensee periodically may renew it for an additional 1-year term, if the licensee:<section prefix="(1)">Otherwise is entitled to a license;</section><section prefix="(2)">Pays to the Secretary a renewal fee established by the Secretary under &#xA7; 2-104 of this article; and</section><section prefix="(3)">Submits to the Secretary:<section prefix="(i)">A renewal application on the form that the Secretary requires; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Satisfactory evidence of compliance with the requirements of this section for renewal.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The renewal fee under this section shall be based on:<section prefix="(1)">If the licensee has a manufacturing facility located in this State, the annual production of any frozen dessert or frozen dessert mix in this State; and</section><section prefix="(2)">If the licensee has a manufacturing facility not located in this State, the annual sales of any frozen dessert or frozen dessert mix in this State.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The Secretary shall renew the license of each licensee who meets the requirements of this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">A license is not transferable.</section>
  </text>
</law>
