<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghg" order_by="ghg" level="1">Health - General</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghg-10-901</section_number>
  <catch_line>The Secretary shall adopt rules and regulations that set standards for:...</catch_line>
  <order_by>901</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Secretary shall adopt rules and regulations that set standards for:<section prefix="(i)">Eligibility for State funding of local mental health programs under Part I of this subtitle;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Qualifications of staff and quality of professional services of eligible programs;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Eligibility for receiving services under eligible programs; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">Accreditation of a facility as defined in &#xA7; 10-101(e) of this title.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Secretary may consider accreditation by the Joint Commission on Accreditation of Healthcare Organizations (JCAHO) or the Commission on Accreditation of Rehabilitation Facilities (CARF), whichever is appropriate, as meeting the rules and regulations adopted under this subtitle.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The rules and regulations shall ensure:<section prefix="(i)">That an individual is not discriminated against based on an inability to pay for services; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">That an individual is not discriminated against or denied community-based mental health services based on the individual's lack of a fixed address or because the individual is homeless.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The rules and regulations shall require that, prior to approval for receipt of State funding under Part I of this subtitle, a nonprofit organization or private community-based organization shall submit the following to the Department:<section prefix="(i)">A written list of the names of the members of the board of directors and corporate officers of the organization;</section><section prefix="(ii)">A business plan that clearly demonstrates the ability of the organization to provide services in accordance with Maryland regulations and funding requirements;</section><section prefix="(iii)">A summary of the organization's demonstrated experience in the field of mental health, in accordance with standards developed by the Department;</section><section prefix="(iv)">Prior licensing reports issued within the previous 10 years from any in-State or out-of-state entities associated with the organization, including deficiency reports and compliance records on which the State may make reasoned decisions about the qualifications of the organization; and</section><section prefix="(v)">A written quality assurance plan, approved by the Mental Hygiene Administration, to address how the organization will ensure the health and safety of the individuals served by the organization and the quality of services provided to individuals by the organization.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(5)">In order for a nonprofit organization or private community-based organization to be eligible to receive funds under Part I of this subtitle:<section prefix="(i)">An immediate family member of an employee of an organization may not serve as a voting member of the governing body of the organization; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">A member of the governing body of the organization may not have served as a member of a governing body of an organization that has had a license revoked by the Department within the previous 10 years.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(6)">Before determining that a nonprofit organization or private community-based organization is eligible to receive funds under Part I of this subtitle, the Department shall perform an on-site investigation of the organization.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Secretary shall:<section prefix="(1)">Through the regional mental health director, provide a county with consultative staff services to help ascertain local needs and plan and establish local mental health programs;</section><section prefix="(2)">Review and evaluate local programs and personnel practices;</section><section prefix="(3)">Make recommendations to the governing body, health officer of a county, and the director of the Montgomery County Department of Health and Human Services on the local program and personnel practices;</section><section prefix="(4)">Review and either approve or disapprove the plans and budgets that a county governing body submits for State funding under Part I of this subtitle; and</section><section prefix="(5)">Exercise any other power or duty required to carry out Part I of this subtitle.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
