<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="ghg" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="4-403" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghg-4-403</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section, a "health care provider" means:<section prefix="(i)">An acupuncturist;</section><section prefix="(ii)">An audiologist;</section><section prefix="(iii)">A chiropractor;</section><section prefix="(iv)">A dietitian;</section><section prefix="(v)">A dentist;</section><section prefix="(vi)">An electrologist;</section><section prefix="(vii)">A health care facility that is:</section><section prefix="(viii)">A massage therapist;</section><section prefix="(ix)">A mortician;</section><section prefix="(x)">A nurse;</section><section prefix="(xi)">A nutritionist;</section><section prefix="(xii)">An occupational therapist;</section><section prefix="(xiii)">An optometrist;</section><section prefix="(xiv)">A physical therapist;</section><section prefix="(xv)">A physician;</section><section prefix="(xvi)">A podiatrist;</section><section prefix="(xvii)">A professional counselor;</section><section prefix="(xviii)">A psychologist;</section><section prefix="(xix)">A social worker; and</section><section prefix="(xx)">A speech-language pathologist.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Health care provider" includes an agent, employee, officer, or director of any entity listed under paragraph (1) of this subsection.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Except for a minor patient, unless a patient is notified, a health care provider may not destroy a medical record or laboratory or X-ray report about a patient for 5 years after the record or report is made.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">In the case of a minor patient, a medical record or laboratory or X-ray report about a minor patient may not be destroyed until the patient attains the age of majority plus 3 years or for 5 years after the record or report is made, whichever is later, unless:<section prefix="(1)">The parent or guardian of the minor patient is notified; or</section><section prefix="(2)">If the medical care documented in the record was provided under &#xA7; 20-102(c) or &#xA7; 20-103(c) of this article, the minor patient is notified.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The notice under subsections (b) and (c) of this section shall:<section prefix="(1)">Be made by first-class mail to the last known address of the patient;</section><section prefix="(2)">Include the date on which the record of the patient shall be destroyed; and</section><section prefix="(3)">Include a statement that the record or synopsis of the record, if wanted, must be retrieved at a designated location within 30 days of the proposed date of destruction.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">After the death, retirement, surrender of the license, or discontinuance of the practice or business of a health care provider, the health care provider, the administrator of the estate, or a designee who agrees to provide for the maintenance of the medical records of the practice or business and who states, in writing to the appropriate health occupation board within a reasonable time, that the records will be maintained in compliance with this section, shall:<section prefix="(1)">Forward the notice required in this section before the destruction or transfer of medical records; or</section><section prefix="(2)">Publish a notice in a daily newspaper that is circulated locally for 2 consecutive weeks:<section prefix="(i)">Stating the date that the medical records will be destroyed or transferred; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Designating a location, date, and time where the medical records may be retrieved, if wanted.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">After consulting with the Association of Maryland Hospitals and Health Systems, the Maryland State Medical Society, and other interested parties, including consumers and payors, the Secretary shall adopt regulations governing the destruction of medical records.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The regulations adopted under this subsection shall:<section prefix="(i)">Specify the manner in which a health care provider shall maintain and store medical records to:</section><section prefix="(ii)">Ensure that the method of destruction renders the medical records unreadable.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The regulations adopted under this subsection may not:<section prefix="(i)">Require or encourage the destruction of medical records; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">Be inconsistent with any provision of law applicable to the maintenance or destruction of medical records.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A health care provider or any other person who knowingly violates any provision of this subtitle is liable for actual damages.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">In addition to any other penalties provided under this article, a health care facility that knowingly violates this section is subject to an administrative fine not exceeding $10,000 for all violations cited in a single day.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)"/>
      </section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
