<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="ghg" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="19-143" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghg-19-143</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">On or before October 1, 2009, the Commission and the Health Services Cost Review Commission shall designate a health information exchange for the State.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">On or before January 1, 2010, the Commission shall:<section prefix="(1)">Report, in accordance with &#xA7; 2-1246 of the State Government Article, to the Senate Finance Committee and the House Health and Government Operations Committee on progress in implementing the requirements of subsections (a) and (d) of this section; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Include in the report recommendations for legislation specifying how incentives required for State-regulated payors that are national carriers shall take into account existing carrier activities that promote the adoption and meaningful use of electronic health records.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">On or before January 1, 2011, following consultations with appropriate stakeholders, the Commission shall post on its website for public comment and submit to the Governor and, in accordance with &#xA7; 2-1246 of the State Government Article, the Senate Finance Committee and the House Health and Government Operations Committee a report on:<section prefix="(i)">The development of a coordinated public-private approach to improve the State's health information infrastructure;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Any changes in State laws that are necessary to protect the privacy and security of health information stored in electronic health records or exchanged through a health information exchange in the State;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Any changes in State laws that are necessary to provide for the effective operation of a health information exchange;</section><section prefix="(iv)">Any actions that are necessary to align funding opportunities under the federal American Recovery and Reinvestment Act of 2009 with other State and private sector initiatives related to health information technology, including:</section><section prefix="(v)">Recommended language for the regulations required under subsection (d) of this section.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Senate Finance Committee and the House Health and Government Operations Committee shall have 60 days from receipt of the report for review and comment.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">On or before September 1, 2011, the Commission, in consultation with the Department, payors, and health care providers, shall adopt regulations that require State-regulated payors to provide incentives to health care providers to promote the adoption and meaningful use of electronic health records.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Incentives required under the regulations:<section prefix="(i)">Shall have monetary value;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Shall facilitate the use of electronic health records by health care providers in the State;</section><section prefix="(iii)">To the extent feasible, shall recognize and be consistent with existing payor incentives that promote the adoption and meaningful use of electronic health records;</section><section prefix="(iv)">Shall take into account:</section><section prefix="(v)">May include:</section><section prefix="(vi)">Shall be paid in cash, unless the State-regulated payor and the health care provider agree on an incentive of equivalent value.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The regulations need not require incentives for the adoption and meaningful use of electronic health records, for each type of health care provider listed in &#xA7; 19-142(e) of this subtitle.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">If federal law is amended to allow the State to regulate payments made by entities that self-insure their health benefit plans, regulations adopted under this section shall apply to those entities to the same extent to which they apply to State-regulated payors.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">Regulations adopted under this subsection:<section prefix="(i)">May not require a group model health maintenance organization, as defined in &#xA7; 19-713.6 of this title, to provide an incentive to a health care provider who is employed by the multispecialty group of physicians under contract with the group model health maintenance organization; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Shall allow a State-regulated payor to:</section></section>
      <section prefix="(6)">The Commission may:<section prefix="(i)">Audit the State-regulated payor or the health care provider for compliance with the regulations adopted under this subsection; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">If it finds noncompliance, request corrective action.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(7)">It is the intent of the General Assembly that the State Employee and Retiree Health and Welfare Benefits Program support the incentives provided under this subsection through contracts between the Program and the third party administrators arranging for the delivery of health care services to members covered under the Program.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The Health Services Cost Review Commission, in consultation with hospitals, payors, and the federal Centers for Medicare and Medicaid Services, shall take the actions necessary to:<section prefix="(1)">Assure that hospitals in the State receive the payments provided under &#xA7; 4102 of the federal American Recovery and Reinvestment Act of 2009 and any subsequent federal rules and regulations; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Implement any changes in hospital rates required by the federal Centers for Medicare and Medicaid Services to ensure compliance with &#xA7; 4102 of the federal American Recovery and Reinvestment Act of 2009 and any subsequent federal rules and regulations.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The Department, in consultation with the Commission, shall develop a mechanism to assure that health care providers that participate in the Maryland Medical Assistance Program receive the payments provided for adoption and use of electronic health records technology under &#xA7; 4201 of the federal American Recovery and Reinvestment Act of 2009 and any subsequent federal rules and regulations.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">On or before October 1, 2012, the Commission shall report to the Governor and, in accordance with &#xA7; 2-1246 of the State Government Article, the General Assembly on progress achieved toward adoption and meaningful use of electronic health records by health care providers in the State and recommendations for any changes in State laws that may be necessary to achieve optimal adoption and use.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">
      <section prefix="(1)">On or before October 1, 2012, the Commission shall designate one or more management service organizations to offer services throughout the State.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Commission may use federal grants and loans to help subsidize the use of the designated management service organizations by health care providers.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(i)">On and after the later of January 1, 2015, or the date established for the imposition of penalties under &#xA7; 4102 of the federal American Recovery and Reinvestment Act of 2009:<section prefix="(1)">Each health care provider using an electronic health record that seeks payment from a State-regulated payor shall use electronic health records that are:<section prefix="(i)">Certified by a national certification organization designated by the Commission; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Capable of connecting to and exchanging data with the health information exchange designated by the Commission under subsection (a) of this section; and</section></section><section prefix="(2)">The incentives required under subsection (d) of this section may include reductions in payments to a health care provider that does not use electronic health records that meet the requirements of paragraph (1) of this subsection.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
