<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghg" order_by="" level="1">Health - General</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghg-15-108</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>108</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, "board" means an appeal board established under this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Secretary may:<section prefix="(i)">Establish one or more boards for purposes of this section; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Designate the jurisdiction of a board.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A board shall consist of 3 members.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Of the 3 board members:<section prefix="(i)">2 shall be appointed by the Secretary; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">1 shall be chosen by the appointed members.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">Of the 2 appointed members of a board:<section prefix="(i)">1 shall be a representative of the industry affected who is an individual knowledgeable in Medicare and Medicaid reimbursement principles; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">1 shall be an individual who is employed by this State and knowledgeable in Medicare and Medicaid reimbursement principles and who does not participate directly in the field verifications.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If the Department or an agent of the Department does a field verification of the costs and allowable charges of a facility that participates in the Program, the Department or agent shall notify the facility of the results of the field verification.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Within 60 days after the facility receives the notification required under paragraph (1) of this subsection, the Department shall pay the facility the amount the Department has determined is due the facility by the Department regardless of whether or not the facility files an appeal.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A facility may appeal the results of a field verification by filing written notice with the appropriate board within 30 days after the facility receives the notice from the Department or its agent.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Within 30 days after the filing of an appeal to the board by a facility that the Department has determined owes money to the State, the Department shall recalculate the amount that is due to the State based on the field verification, exclusive of the amount in controversy which is subject to the appeal, and shall notify the facility of that amount.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">Subject to the provisions of subparagraphs (iii) and (iv) of this paragraph, payment for the amount due the State, if any, after the recalculation shall be made within 60 days after the facility receives notification of the recalculation.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">If a facility requests a longer payment schedule within 60 days after the facility receives notification of the recalculation, the Department may establish, after consultation with the facility, a longer payment schedule.</section>
        <section prefix="(iv)">The Department shall establish a longer payment schedule if, in the Department's reasonable judgment, failure to grant a longer payment schedule would:<section prefix="1.">Result in financial hardship to the facility; or</section><section prefix="2.">Have an adverse effect on the quality of patient care furnished by the facility.</section></section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">If a facility files an appeal, the portion of the amount in controversy that is actually paid shall be subject to an award of interest that is:<section prefix="1.">Calculated from the date the appeal was filed through the date of payment; and</section><section prefix="2.">Determined in accordance with a rate of interest established by regulation.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">Interest paid by a facility under subparagraph (i) of this paragraph is not an allowable cost.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">Interest paid to a facility under subparagraph (i) of this paragraph is not subject to any offset or other reduction against otherwise allowable costs.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(4)">If a facility other than a hospital, or if the Department is aggrieved by a final decision of the board under this section, the facility or the Department shall place any money due from the facility or from the Department in an interest bearing escrow account. The money shall remain in escrow until a final decision has been rendered.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">Upon a final determination of the dispute, the appropriate person administering the escrow account shall distribute the money in that account, including any interest accrued, in conformity with the final determination.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">After the Department receives the findings of a board, the Department shall determine the amount that is due either to this State or to the facility and notify the facility of that amount.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If the facility has accepted the determination made under paragraph (1) of this subsection, within 60 days after the facility receives the notification under paragraph (1) of this subsection the Department shall pay the amount the Department has determined is due the facility, if any.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Subject to the provisions of paragraphs (4) and (5) of this subsection, within 60 days after the facility receives notification, the facility shall pay the amount due the Department, if any.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">If a facility requests a longer payment schedule within 30 days after the facility receives notification of the amount due the Department, the Department may establish, after consultation with the facility, a longer payment schedule.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">The Department shall establish a longer payment schedule if, in the Department's reasonable judgment, failure to grant a longer payment schedule would:<section prefix="(i)">Result in financial hardship to the facility; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">Have an adverse effect on the quality of patient care furnished by the facility.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Department or any facility aggrieved by a reimbursement decision of the board under this section may not appeal to the Board of Review but may take a direct judicial appeal.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The appeal shall be made as provided for judicial review of final decisions in the Administrative Procedure Act.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
