<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghg" order_by="" level="1">Health - General</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghg-4-302.2</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>302.2</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Maryland Health Care Commission shall adopt regulations for the privacy and security of protected health information obtained or released through a health information exchange by:<section prefix="(1)">A health care provider;</section><section prefix="(2)">A payor that holds a valid certificate of authority issued by the Maryland Insurance Commissioner;</section><section prefix="(3)">A health care consumer; or</section><section prefix="(4)">Any person authorized by a health care consumer to act on behalf of the health care consumer.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The regulations adopted under subsection (a) of this section shall include protections for the secondary use of protected health information obtained or released through a health information exchange.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Data obtained or released through a health information exchange:<section prefix="(1)">May not be sold for financial remuneration until the regulations required under subsections (a) and (b) of this section are adopted; and</section><section prefix="(2)">May be sold for financial remuneration only in accordance with the regulations adopted under subsections (a) and (b) of this section.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Regulations adopted under subsections (a) and (b) of this section may not apply to protected health information exchanged:<section prefix="(1)">Between a hospital and credentialed members of the hospital's medical staff;</section><section prefix="(2)">Among credentialed members of a hospital's medical staff; or</section><section prefix="(3)">Between a hospital and ancillary clinical service providers that are affiliated with the hospital and have signed a business associate agreement.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The Maryland Health Care Commission shall consult with health care providers, payors, State health agencies, consumer advocates, and employers before adopting regulations under subsections (a) and (b) of this section.</section>
  </text>
</law>
