<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="ghg" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="19-362" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghg-19-362</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">An intermediate sanction may be imposed consistent with this section when a hazardous condition exists in a related institution and that condition is not remedied pursuant to the following sections.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">In determining whether a hazardous condition exists, the following factors shall be considered:<section prefix="(i)">The potential impact of the condition on the health, life, or safety of patients;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The period of time during which the condition has existed;</section><section prefix="(iii)">The frequency of occurrence of the condition; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">The efforts made by the related institution to correct the condition.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Upon determination by the Department that a hazardous condition exists, the Department will notify the facility that a hazardous condition exists which may subject the facility to a sanction.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Department shall order that a plan of correction which is acceptable to the Department be submitted within 10 working days.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Department shall notify the related institution within 3 working days of receipt of the plan of correction as to whether it is or is not acceptable.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">If the Department determines that the plan is not acceptable, the related institution will resubmit a revised plan within 5 working days of such notification.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The Department will schedule reinspections of the facility based on time frames established in the plan of correction.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If the Department determines that an acceptable plan of correction has not been submitted, that the hazardous condition has not been corrected, or that progress satisfactory to the Department has not been accomplished, the Department shall order the facility ownership and appropriate administrative personnel to appear before a representative of the Department.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Following the appearance, or if the facility ownership fails to appear, a decision may be issued which:<section prefix="(i)">Extends the time frame in which the hazardous condition must be corrected; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">Proposes the imposition of the sanction.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If a sanction is proposed, or if at the end of the extended time frame the hazardous condition has not been corrected, the Secretary may issue a sanction order.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The sanction order shall state the number of days within which the hazardous condition must be corrected and shall require the related institution to establish an escrow account in accordance with &#xA7; 19-363 of this subtitle.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
