<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghg" order_by="ghg" level="1">Health - General</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghg-16-101</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this title the following words have the meanings indicated....</catch_line>
  <order_by>101</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this title the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">As to a recipient of services under the Maryland Developmental Disabilities Law, a word used in this title has the same meaning as is indicated by a definition of the word in &#xA7; 7-101 of this article.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">As to a recipient of services under the Maryland Mental Hygiene Law, a word used in this title has the same meaning as is indicated by a definition of the word in &#xA7; 10-101 of this article.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Chargeable person" means:<section prefix="(1)">Any responsible relative;</section><section prefix="(2)">Except for a recipient of services, any other person who is legally responsible for the care of the individual; and</section><section prefix="(3)">Any person who maintains a policy of health insurance under which a recipient of services is insured.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Cost of care" means the cost of care, maintenance, treatment, and support of a recipient of services.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Cost of care" includes the cost of:<section prefix="(i)">An evaluation of an individual required under the Maryland Developmental Disabilities Law; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Any juvenile screening or treatment service provided to an individual under &#xA7; 9-227(b)(1)(ii) of the Human Services Article.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Recipient of services" means an individual who receives care, maintenance, treatment, or support in a facility or program that is operated or funded wholly or partly by the Department.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Recipient of services" includes:<section prefix="(i)">An individual in a public facility under the Maryland Mental Hygiene Law;</section><section prefix="(ii)">An individual in a facility for an evaluation required under the Maryland Developmental Disabilities Law;</section><section prefix="(iii)">An individual in a residential, public facility or a facility from which this State obtains residential care under the Maryland Developmental Disabilities Law;</section><section prefix="(iv)">An individual to whom juvenile screening or treatment services are provided under &#xA7; 9-227(b)(1)(ii) of the Human Services Article; and</section><section prefix="(v)">An individual in a private therapeutic group home from which this State obtains residential care under the Maryland Mental Hygiene Law.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">"Responsible relative" means:<section prefix="(1)">The spouse of a recipient of services;</section><section prefix="(2)">The parents of a recipient of services who is a minor; and</section><section prefix="(3)">The children of a recipient of services.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
