<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghg" order_by="" level="1">Health - General</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghg-19-4B-03</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>03</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A nursing referral service agency may receive a fee or other compensation for providing its services.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A contractual arrangement may provide that a nursing referral service agency is not responsible for paying any part of the compensation to the licensed health care professionals or care providers that the nursing referral service agency screens or refers to clients.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A nursing referral service agency may provide administrative assistance.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A nursing referral service agency shall:<section prefix="(1)">Obtain a license from the Department prior to operating as a nursing referral service agency;</section><section prefix="(2)">Develop and implement a procedure to screen licensed health professionals and care providers that includes the following:<section prefix="(i)">In accordance with subsection (c) of this section:<section prefix="1.">A State criminal history records check; or</section><section prefix="2.">A private agency background check;</section></section><section prefix="(ii)">Verification of current licensure or certification under the Health Occupations Article;</section><section prefix="(iii)">A basic health screening, including a tuberculosis screening;</section><section prefix="(iv)">Verification of references;</section><section prefix="(v)">Verification of employment history;</section><section prefix="(vi)">Completion of I-9 forms; and</section><section prefix="(vii)">An in-person interview of a licensed health professional and care provider before any referral of the individual is made to a client;</section></section><section prefix="(3)">Institute an internal client complaint investigation process that includes:<section prefix="(i)">Notice to the client or client's representative of the complaint process; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Protocols to investigate complaints;</section></section><section prefix="(4)">Provide notice to clients of the Department's complaint hotline number for complaints about the services provided by an individual referred by the nursing referral service agency; and</section><section prefix="(5)">Allow clients to accept or reject, at their discretion, any licensed health professional or care provider referred by the nursing referral service agency.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">For each licensed health professional and care provider, a nursing referral service agency shall:<section prefix="(i)">Apply to the Central Repository for a State criminal history records check; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">Request a private agency to conduct a background check.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">As part of the application for a criminal history records check, the nursing referral service agency shall submit to the Central Repository:<section prefix="1.">Two complete sets of legible fingerprints of the licensed health professional or care provider taken on forms approved by the Director of the Central Repository; and</section><section prefix="2.">The fee authorized under &#xA7; 10-221(b)(7) of the Criminal Procedure Article for access to Maryland criminal history records.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">In accordance with &#xA7;&#xA7; 10-201 through 10-228 of the Criminal Procedure Article, the Central Repository shall forward to the licensed health professional or care provider and the nursing referral service agency a printed statement listing the criminal convictions of the licensed health professional or care provider.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">Information obtained from the Central Repository under this subsection:<section prefix="1.">Is confidential and may not be redisseminated; and</section><section prefix="2.">May be used only for the screening purpose authorized by this subsection.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(iv)">The subject of a criminal history records check under this subsection may contest the contents of the printed statement issued by the Central Repository as provided in &#xA7; 10-223 of the Criminal Procedure Article.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">If a nursing referral service agency requests a private agency to conduct a background check:<section prefix="(i)">The private agency shall:<section prefix="1.">Conduct a background check in each state in which the nursing referral service agency knows or has reason to know the licensed health professional or care provider worked or resided during the past 7 years; and</section><section prefix="2.">Issue a statement of its findings to:</section></section><section prefix="(ii)">The licensed health professional or care provider shall have an opportunity to contest the findings.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
