<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghg" order_by="ghg" level="1">Health - General</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghg-13-1403</section_number>
  <catch_line>The Board consists of 11 members....</catch_line>
  <order_by>1403</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Board consists of 11 members.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Of the 11 members of the Board:<section prefix="(i)">One shall be a member of the Maryland House of Delegates appointed by the Speaker of the House;</section><section prefix="(ii)">One shall be a member of the Senate of Maryland appointed by the President of the Senate;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Four shall be individuals with knowledge and expertise concerning spinal cord injuries appointed by the Governor from separate lists submitted to the Governor by the University of Maryland School of Medicine and the Johns Hopkins School of Medicine, with:<section prefix="1.">Two individuals from the University of Maryland School of Medicine; and</section><section prefix="2.">Two individuals from the Johns Hopkins School of Medicine;</section></section><section prefix="(iv)">Two shall be nurses with knowledge and expertise concerning spinal cord injuries appointed by the Governor from separate lists submitted to the Governor by the University of Maryland School of Nursing and the Johns Hopkins School of Nursing, with:<section prefix="1.">One nurse from the University of Maryland School of Nursing; and</section><section prefix="2.">One nurse from the Johns Hopkins School of Nursing;</section></section><section prefix="(v)">Two members, appointed by the Governor from a list submitted by the Department of Disabilities, shall be individuals who have a spinal cord injury or who have a family member with a spinal cord injury; and</section><section prefix="(vi)">One member, appointed by the Governor, shall be an individual from the general public with knowledge and expertise concerning spinal cord injuries.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Subject to paragraph (2) of this subsection, the term of a member is 4 years.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Governor shall stagger the terms of the initial members.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">At the end of a term, a member continues to serve until a successor is appointed and qualifies.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">A member who is appointed after a term has begun serves only for the remainder of the term and until a successor is appointed and qualifies.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">A member who serves 2 consecutive 4-year terms may not be reappointed until 4 years after completion of those terms.</section>
      <section prefix="(6)">
        <section prefix="(i)">If a vacancy occurs, the Governor promptly shall appoint a successor who will serve until the term expires.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The successor may be reappointed for a full term.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
