<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="ghg" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="4-213" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghg-4-213</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">If a fetal death occurs after a gestation period of 20 weeks or more, then within 72 hours after delivery, a certificate of fetal death shall be filed by:<section prefix="(1)">The mortician who first takes custody of a fetus;</section><section prefix="(2)">The person in charge of the institution or the person's designated representative when a fetus is delivered in an institution;</section><section prefix="(3)">The physician in attendance at or immediately after delivery when a fetus is delivered outside an institution; or</section><section prefix="(4)">The medical examiner when a fetal death occurs without medical attendance at or immediately after the delivery when a medical examiner's inquiry is required.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The person who files the fetal death certificate shall obtain:<section prefix="(1)">The personal information from the next of kin or the best qualified individual or source available; and</section><section prefix="(2)">The medical certification of cause of death:<section prefix="(i)">From the medical examiner, within 24 hours after the medical examiner takes charge of the fetus; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">If the medical examiner does not take charge of the fetus, from the attending physician within 24 hours after delivery.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">When a fetal death occurs on a common carrier and the fetus is first removed from the carrier in this State or when a fetus is found in this State and the place of fetal death is unknown, the fetal death shall be reported in this State.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The place where the fetus was first removed from the carrier or the fetus was found shall be considered the place of fetal death.</section>
  </text>
</law>
