<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="ghg" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="24-1001" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghg-24-1001</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Assisted living facility" means a residential facility or facility-based program that:<section prefix="(1)">Meets the definition in &#xA7; 19-1801 of this article; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Is licensed by the Department.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Facility" means an assisted living facility that is wholly owned by and operated under the authority of:<section prefix="(1)">A county;</section><section prefix="(2)">A municipal corporation; or</section><section prefix="(3)">A nonprofit organization.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">"Nonprofit organization" means:<section prefix="(1)">A bona fide religious organization, no part of the earnings of which inures to the benefit of any individual or is used for any purpose other than the maintenance and operation of a facility, the purchase of equipment to be used in a facility, or the expansion of a facility; or</section><section prefix="(2)">An organization:<section prefix="(i)">That is chartered as a nonprofit corporation and classified by the Internal Revenue Service as nonprofit; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">No part of the earnings of which inures to the benefit of any individual or is used for any purpose other than the maintenance and operation of a facility, the purchase of equipment to be used in a facility, or the expansion of a facility.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"Wholly owned" includes leased, if:<section prefix="(1)"><section prefix="(i)">The lease is for a minimum term of 30 years following project completion; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">The lease agreement extends the right of purchase to the lessee; and</section></section><section prefix="(2)">The lessor consents to the recording in the land records of the county or Baltimore City in which the facility is located, of a notice of the State's right of recovery as provided under &#xA7; 24-1006 of this subtitle.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
