<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghg" order_by="ghg" level="1">Health - General</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghg-16-405</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this section, "taxable income" has the meaning that federal law gives to it for purposes of the I...</catch_line>
  <order_by>405</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, "taxable income" has the meaning that federal law gives to it for purposes of the Internal Revenue Code.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">For purposes of &#xA7; 16-404(b)(2) of this subtitle, the liability of a chargeable person for the cost of care of an individual with an intellectual disability shall be determined in accordance with either of the following schedules, at the option of the chargeable person.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">To establish the taxable income, the chargeable person shall provide either a copy of a federal income tax return or an affidavit as to the taxable income reported on that federal income tax return.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Any modification of liability for charges based on a federal income tax return shall become effective as of July 1 in each calendar year.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Within the time that the Secretary sets and on the forms that the Secretary provides, each chargeable person shall elect the schedule under which the chargeable person is to be billed.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The election is effective as of the day that the individual with an intellectual disability first is admitted for service and remains in force until changed by the chargeable person.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A change in the election is effective on July 1 after the date on which the Department is notified of the change.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">If a person fails to elect within the time that the Secretary sets, the Secretary shall determine which schedule is to apply.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">A person whose taxable income is less than $4,000 a year may not be charged any amount under this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">For purposes of this section, both parents of an individual with an intellectual disability shall be considered a single responsible relative.</section>
  </text>
</law>
