<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghg" order_by="" level="1">Health - General</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghg-18-102</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>102</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Secretary shall adopt rules and regulations necessary to prevent:<section prefix="(1)">The introduction of an infectious or contagious disease into this State or other disease that endangers public health in this State; or</section><section prefix="(2)">The spread of an infectious or contagious disease or other disease that endangers public health in this State.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">When the Secretary has reason to believe that an infectious or contagious disease or other disease that endangers public health exists within the State, the Secretary shall:<section prefix="(1)">Investigate the suspected disease; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Act properly to prevent the spread of the disease.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, an individual enrolled in an institution of higher education who resides in on-campus student housing shall be vaccinated against meningococcal disease.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">An individual is exempt from the vaccination requirement in paragraph (1) of this subsection if:<section prefix="(i)">The institution of higher education provides detailed information on the risks associated with meningococcal disease and the availability and effectiveness of any vaccine to:<section prefix="1.">The individual, if the individual is 18 years of age or older; or</section><section prefix="2.">The individual's parent or guardian, if the individual is a minor; and</section></section><section prefix="(ii)"><section prefix="1.">The individual is 18 years of age or older and the individual signs a written waiver in a form approved by the Secretary stating that the individual has received and reviewed the information provided and has chosen not to be vaccinated against meningococcal disease; or</section><section prefix="2.">The individual is a minor and the individual's parent or guardian signs a written waiver in a form approved by the Secretary stating that the parent or guardian has received and reviewed the information provided and has chosen to not have the individual vaccinated against meningococcal disease.</section></section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Nothing in this subsection shall be construed to require any institution of higher education to provide or pay for vaccinations against meningococcal disease.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The Secretary, in consultation with the Maryland Higher Education Commission, shall adopt regulations necessary to implement this subsection.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Secretary may enter on and inspect private property to determine the presence, cause, and source of an infectious or contagious disease or other disease that endangers public health in this State.</section>
  </text>
</law>
