<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghg" order_by="" level="1">Health - General</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghg-19-7A-01</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>01</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Commissioner" means the Maryland Insurance Commissioner.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Health care services" means a health or medical care procedure or service rendered by a health care provider that:<section prefix="(1)">Provides testing, diagnosis, or treatment of a human disease or dysfunction; or</section><section prefix="(2)">Dispenses drugs, medical devices, medical appliances, or medical goods for the treatment of a human disease or dysfunction.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">"License" includes a certificate of authority, as defined in &#xA7; 1-101 of the Insurance Article.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"Provider" means any person, including a physician or hospital, that is licensed or otherwise authorized in this State to provide health care services.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">"Provider-sponsored organization" means an entity that:<section prefix="(1)">Is a legal aggregation of providers operating collectively for the purpose of providing health care services to Medicare beneficiaries under the federal Medicare+Choice Program;</section><section prefix="(2)">Acts through a licensed entity, such as a partnership, corporation, limited liability company, limited liability partnership, or sole proprietorship, that has authority over the entity's activities and responsibility for satisfying the requirements of &#xA7; 19-7A-02 of this subtitle; and</section><section prefix="(3)">Provides a substantial proportion of the health care services required to be provided under the federal Medicare+Choice Program directly through providers or affiliated groups of providers.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
