<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghg" order_by="ghg" level="1">Health - General</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghg-19-1402</section_number>
  <catch_line>If a deficiency exists, the Secretary may impose sanctions that include:...</catch_line>
  <order_by>1402</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">If a deficiency exists, the Secretary may impose sanctions that include:<section prefix="(1)">A directed plan of correction with corrective measures necessary to protect residents;</section><section prefix="(2)">Imposing adequate staffing levels in a nursing home;</section><section prefix="(3)">Appointing a State monitor subject to &#xA7; 19-1405 of this subtitle; and</section><section prefix="(4)">Imposing a civil money penalty.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A civil money penalty may be imposed when a deficiency exists or an ongoing pattern of deficiencies exists in a nursing home.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">In determining whether a civil money penalty is to be imposed, the Secretary shall consider, pursuant to guidelines set forth in regulations promulgated by the Secretary, the following factors:<section prefix="(1)">The number, nature, and seriousness of the deficiencies;</section><section prefix="(2)">The extent to which the deficiency or deficiencies are part of an ongoing pattern during the preceding 24 months;</section><section prefix="(3)">The degree of risk to the health, life, or safety of the residents of the nursing home caused by the deficiency or deficiencies;</section><section prefix="(4)">The efforts made by, and the ability of, the nursing home to correct the deficiency or deficiencies; and</section><section prefix="(5)">A nursing home's prior history of compliance.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Upon determination by the Department that a deficiency or deficiencies exist, the Department shall notify the nursing home that:<section prefix="(1)">Unless corrective action taken pursuant to this section is substantially completed, a civil money penalty will be imposed; or</section><section prefix="(2)">An order imposing a civil money penalty will be issued, pursuant to &#xA7; 19-1403 of this subtitle which shall include a list of all deficiencies and notice that a civil money penalty may be imposed until the time that the cited deficiencies have been rectified.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
