<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghg" order_by="ghg" level="1">Health - General</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghg-21-304.2</section_number>
  <catch_line>A restaurant with an outdoor dining area may allow a patron's dog to accompany the patron in the out...</catch_line>
  <order_by>304.2</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">A restaurant with an outdoor dining area may allow a patron's dog to accompany the patron in the outdoor dining area during the hours designated by the owner of the restaurant.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The owner of a restaurant:<section prefix="(1)">Shall provide written notice to the local health department that the owner intends to allow a patron's dog to accompany the patron in the outdoor dining area of the restaurant not less than 30 days prior to the day on which dogs will be allowed in the outdoor dining area;</section><section prefix="(2)">May determine the location and the amount of space in the outdoor dining area designated for a patron accompanied by a dog;</section><section prefix="(3)">May establish limits on the size and type of dogs and any other limitations relating to dogs that may accompany a patron into the outdoor dining area of a restaurant;</section><section prefix="(4)">May deny entry to the restaurant or eject from the restaurant any patron accompanied by a dog at the discretion of the owner; and</section><section prefix="(5)">Shall place on permanent display a written notice that is in a typeface that is large enough to be easily legible to the average person from a distance of 8 feet and that is in a location that is plainly visible to the patrons of the restaurant notifying the patrons of the policy of the restaurant allowing dogs in the outdoor dining area.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A patron accompanied by a dog:<section prefix="(1)">May not allow the dog to travel through an indoor space of a restaurant to enter or exit an outdoor dining area;</section><section prefix="(2)">Shall keep the dog on a leash at all times with the patron at the table at which the patron is seated;</section><section prefix="(3)">May not leave the dog unattended at any time in the restaurant;</section><section prefix="(4)">Shall be an adult who is responsible for the behavior of the dog; and</section><section prefix="(5)">Is liable for any damages caused by the dog to the restaurant or any other patron of the restaurant.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">This section does not affect the right of an individual to use a service animal, as defined in &#xA7; 7-701 of the Human Services Article.</section>
  </text>
</law>
