<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="ghg" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="20-1403" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghg-20-1403</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>// EFFECTIVE UNTIL JUNE 30, 2016 PER CHAPTER 3 OF 2012 //<section prefix="(a)">In order for an area to receive designation as a Health Enterprise Zone, a nonprofit community-based organization or a local government agency shall apply to the Secretary on behalf of the area to receive designation.</section><section prefix="(b)">The application shall be in the form and manner and contain the information that the Commission and the Secretary require.</section><section prefix="(c)">The application shall contain an effective and sustainable plan to reduce health disparities, reduce costs or produce savings to the health care system, and improve health outcomes, including:<section prefix="(1)">A description of the plan of the nonprofit community-based organization or local government agency to utilize funding available under this subtitle to address health care provider capacity, improve health services delivery, effectuate community improvements, or conduct outreach and education efforts; and</section><section prefix="(2)">A proposal to use funding available under this subtitle to provide for loan repayment incentives to induce Health Enterprise Zone practitioners to practice in the area.</section></section><section prefix="(d)">The application may also contain a plan to utilize other benefits, including:<section prefix="(1)">Tax credits available under this subtitle and &#xA7; 10-731 of the Tax - General Article to encourage Health Enterprise Zone practitioners to establish or expand health care practices in the area;</section><section prefix="(2)">A proposal to use innovative public health strategies to reduce health disparities in the area, such as the use of community health workers, health coaches, registered dieticians, optometrists, peer learning, and community-based disease management activities, that could be supported by grants awarded under this subtitle; and</section><section prefix="(3)">A proposal to use other incentives or mechanisms to address health disparities that focus on ways to expand access to care, expand access to fresh produce through grocery stores and farmer's markets, promote hiring, and reduce costs to the health care system.</section></section></text>
</law>
