<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="ghg" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="7-1011" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghg-7-1011</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">An individual with developmental disability or person who is authorized to act on behalf of the individual may:<section prefix="(1)">Contest a record that the licensee keeps on the individual;</section><section prefix="(2)">Ask for an addition to or other change in the record; and</section><section prefix="(3)">Contest disclosure of the record.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Within 14 days after a licensee receives a request to change a record, the licensee shall acknowledge receipt of the request.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Within 14 days after a licensee acknowledges receipt of the request, the licensee shall:<section prefix="(i)">Make or refuse to make the requested change; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Give the person who requested the change written notice of the licensee's action.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A notice of refusal shall contain:<section prefix="(i)">Each reason for the refusal; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Any procedures that the Director has set for review of the refusal.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">An individual with developmental disability or person who is authorized to act on behalf of the individual may ask the Director to review the refusal.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Within 45 days after the request for review, the Director shall:<section prefix="(i)">Complete the review;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Make a final determination; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Give the individual with developmental disability or person who is authorized to act on behalf of the individual written notice of the final determination.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">If the final determination of the Director is a refusal to change a record, the written notice shall include:<section prefix="(1)">Each reason for the refusal;</section><section prefix="(2)">The procedure for inserting in the record a concise statement of the reason that the individual with developmental disability or person who is authorized to act on behalf of the individual disagrees with that refusal; and</section><section prefix="(3)">Information on the right to seek judicial review of the decision of the Director.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
