<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghg" order_by="ghg" level="1">Health - General</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghg-14-402</section_number>
  <catch_line>This subtitle and the regulations issued under this subtitle do not apply to:...</catch_line>
  <order_by>402</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">This subtitle and the regulations issued under this subtitle do not apply to:<section prefix="(1)">Purely social activities of a family or the guests of a family;</section><section prefix="(2)">Subject to subsection (b) of this section, programs or activities directed or operated by a board of recreation, recreation department, or similar public unit of a county, a municipal corporation, as defined by Article 23A of the Code, or the Maryland-National Capital Park and Planning Commission, that involve use of neighborhood facilities, including:<section prefix="(i)">Schools;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Playgrounds;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Parks; or</section><section prefix="(iv)">Recreation centers;</section></section><section prefix="(3)">Subject to subsection (c) of this section, programs or activities directed or operated by an agency of the State that involve occasional use of public facilities including:<section prefix="(i)">Schools;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Playgrounds;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Parks; or</section><section prefix="(iv)">Recreation centers; or</section></section><section prefix="(4)">Youth overnight programs sponsored by religious or community organizations operating or conducted for not more than 5 consecutive days during any 1 calendar year, such as a vacation bible school, youth bike trip, and similar activities.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Subject to the provisions of paragraph (2) of this subsection, each local government shall adopt health and safety standards pertaining to the operation of youth camps.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Each unit of local government, or the Maryland-National Capital Park and Planning Commission, that directs or operates a program or activity under subsection (a)(2) of this section shall certify in writing on or before April 1 of each year to the Department of Health and Mental Hygiene that all of those programs and activities operated by the unit comply with the applicable health and safety standards of the local jurisdiction in which the program or activity is located and any State law the enforcement of which has been delegated to local government. However, a unit may annually elect to comply with this subtitle and the regulations adopted under it.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Each agency of the State that directs or operates a program or activity that is not exempt under subsection (a)(3) of this section shall annually certify in writing to the Department of Health and Mental Hygiene that each program or activity operated by the agency complies with this subtitle and the regulations adopted under it.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Department shall:<section prefix="(1)">Conduct inspections of:<section prefix="(i)">A random 5 percent sample of programs or activities described under subsection (b) or (c) of this section to ensure that each program or activity is in compliance with all applicable health and safety laws and standards; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Any program or activity about which a complaint has been filed; and</section></section><section prefix="(2)">Advise the unit or agency of any significant violation of State regulations that would adversely impact the health or safety of children participating in a program or activity.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
