<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghg" order_by="ghg" level="1">Health - General</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghg-21-410</section_number>
  <catch_line>Except as otherwise provided in this section, a person shall obtain a permit with a Grade A or a man...</catch_line>
  <order_by>410</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Except as otherwise provided in this section, a person shall obtain a permit with a Grade A or a manufactured grade classification from the Secretary before that person may:<section prefix="(1)">Bring, send, or receive a milk product into this State for sale;</section><section prefix="(2)">Offer a milk product for sale;</section><section prefix="(3)">Give a milk product away;</section><section prefix="(4)">Store a milk product; or</section><section prefix="(5)">Transport a milk product.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A permit is required to:<section prefix="(1)">Be a bobtailer;</section><section prefix="(2)">Be a bulk milk hauler/sampler;</section><section prefix="(3)">Be a certified industry dairy farm inspector;</section><section prefix="(4)">Be a milk processor;</section><section prefix="(5)">Be a milk processor - farmstead cheese producer;</section><section prefix="(6)">Be a milk producer;</section><section prefix="(7)">Operate a distribution station;</section><section prefix="(8)">Operate a milk transportation company;</section><section prefix="(9)">Operate a receiving station; or</section><section prefix="(10)">Operate a transfer station.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A permit is not required for:<section prefix="(1)">A milk producer who is outside the departmental inspection area if the raw milk from that milk producer is processed by a milk processor who holds a permit issued under this subtitle;</section><section prefix="(2)">A bulk milk hauler/sampler who receives raw milk from outside the departmental inspection area;</section><section prefix="(3)">A grocery store, restaurant, soda fountain, or similar establishment where milk products are served or sold at retail if:<section prefix="(i)">The establishment complies with all applicable provisions of this subtitle and all applicable rules or regulations adopted under this subtitle; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">The milk product is received from a permit holder; or</section></section><section prefix="(4)">A bulk milk hauler/sampler who is transporting a sealed tanker and not producers' samples.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Secretary shall designate all permits with one of the following classifications, as required by rules and regulations:<section prefix="(1)">Grade A milk; or</section><section prefix="(2)">Manufactured milk.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
