<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghg" order_by="ghg" level="1">Health - General</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghg-4-217</section_number>
  <catch_line>Except as provided in subsection (b) of this section, the Secretary shall provide, on request, any p...</catch_line>
  <order_by>217</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in subsection (b) of this section, the Secretary shall provide, on request, any person authorized by regulations adopted under this subtitle with a certified or abridged copy of a birth, death, or fetal death certificate registered under this subtitle or of the certificate of a marriage performed after June 1, 1951.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Except as provided in subsection (b) of this section, a local health department may:<section prefix="(i)">Access electronically from the Department a certified or abridged copy of a birth certificate registered under this subtitle; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">On request, provide any person authorized by regulations adopted under this subtitle with a certified or abridged copy of a birth certificate registered under this subtitle.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The Secretary shall provide on request, to any person authorized by regulation adopted under this subtitle, a commemorative birth certificate.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The Department shall set a fee for the commemorative birth certificate.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">The commemorative birth certificate shall:<section prefix="1.">Be in a form consistent with the need to protect the integrity of vital records but suitable for display; and</section><section prefix="2.">Have the same status as evidence as the original birth certificate.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(iv)">A portion of the funds collected under this paragraph shall go to the Department for the production costs of issuing the commemorative birth certificates. The remainder of the funds collected shall be paid into the Children's Trust Fund established under &#xA7; 13-2207 of this article to provide funding for the Child Abuse Medical Providers (Maryland CHAMP) Initiative.</section>
        <section prefix="(v)">The Secretary shall adopt regulations to implement the provisions of this paragraph.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A certified or abridged copy of a birth certificate may be issued only:<section prefix="(i)">On order of a court of competent jurisdiction;</section><section prefix="(ii)">On request of the individual to whom the record relates;</section><section prefix="(iii)">On request of a parent, guardian, surviving spouse, or other authorized representative of the individual; or</section><section prefix="(iv)">In accordance with Title 5, Subtitle 3A or Subtitle 4B of the Family Law Article.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A certified or abridged copy of a birth certificate may contain only the personal information that appears on the birth certificate and may not include any confidential medical information that appears on the birth certificate.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Birth certificate information may not be given if it is to be used for commercial solicitation or private gain.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">A noncertified copy of a birth certificate including confidential medical information may be provided to a unit of the Department to carry out its legal mandate or to conduct Institutional Review Board (IRB) approved research or study. Any report resulting from this research or study may not contain personal identifiers unless authorized by the subject of the record or the subject's parent or authorized representative.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">A copy of a birth certificate may be given to the Maryland Immunization Program to improve childhood immunization rates.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as otherwise provided by law:<section prefix="(i)">The Department shall collect a $12 fee:<section prefix="1.">For each certified or abridged copy of a fetal death, marriage, or divorce verification certificate;</section><section prefix="2.">For a report that a search of the fetal death, marriage, or divorce verification certificate files was made and the requested record is not on file;</section><section prefix="3.">For each change to a  fetal death, marriage, or divorce verification certificate made later than one year after the certificate has been registered with the Department; or</section><section prefix="4.">To process an adoption, foreign adoption, or legitimation;</section></section><section prefix="(ii)">The Department shall collect a $24 fee:<section prefix="1.">For each certified or abridged copy of a birth certificate;</section><section prefix="2.">For the first copy of a certified or abridged death certificate issued in a single transaction;</section><section prefix="3.">For a report that a search of the birth or death certificate files was made and the requested record is not on file; or</section><section prefix="4.">For each change to a birth or death certificate made later than 1 year after the certificate has been registered with the Department; and</section></section><section prefix="(iii)">The Department shall collect a $12 fee for each additional certified or abridged copy of a death certificate provided concurrently with an initial requested death certificate.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">From the fee the Department collects under paragraph (1) of this subsection, the Department shall transfer the entire fee to the General Fund.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Any local health department may set and collect a fee for processing and issuing a birth certificate, or for a report that a search of the files was made and the requested record is not on file, that covers:<section prefix="1.">The administrative costs of providing this service; and</section><section prefix="2.">The requirements of subparagraph (iii) of this paragraph.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The fee set by the local health department for processing and issuing a birth certificate or for a report under subparagraph (i) of this paragraph may not exceed the actual costs to the local health department for processing and issuing a birth certificate or a report.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">From the fee the local health department collects under subparagraph (i) of this paragraph, $20 shall be transferred to the General Fund.</section>
        <section prefix="(iv)">Prior to setting and collecting a fee for processing and issuing a birth certificate or for a report under subparagraph (i) of this paragraph, the local health department shall enter into a memorandum of understanding with the Department of Health and Mental Hygiene that outlines the local health department's fee structure.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The Department or a local health department may collect a fee for a certificate requested by an agency of the State or any of its political subdivisions.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">The Secretary may waive all or part of a fee if chargeable to an agency of the United States.</section>
      <section prefix="(6)">The Department may not collect a fee for a copy of a vital record issued to:<section prefix="(i)">A current or former member of the armed forces of the United States; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">The surviving spouse or child of the member, if the copy will be used in connection with a claim for a dependent or beneficiary of the member.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Any local health department may set and collect a fee for processing and issuing a death certificate that covers the administrative costs of providing this service.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The fee set by the local health department for processing and issuing a death certificate under this subsection may not exceed the actual costs to the local health department for processing and issuing a death certificate.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The Secretary shall include with every copy of a death certificate, in a form prescribed and provided by the Insurance Commissioner, a notice which advises that certain individuals may be entitled to continuation of group health insurance benefits under &#xA7; 15-407 of the Insurance Article.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The Secretary shall include with every copy of a death certificate that is completed by the Chief Medical Examiner a notice that advises a person in interest, as defined in &#xA7; 10-611(e)(3) of the State Government Article, of the right to appeal a denial by the Chief Medical Examiner of a request to correct findings and conclusions as to the cause and manner of death recorded on a death certificate as provided under &#xA7; 5-310(d) of this article.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">A person may use a photocopy of a birth, death, fetal death, or marriage certificate for any nonfraudulent and nondeceptive purpose.</section>
  </text>
</law>
