<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghg" order_by="ghg" level="1">Health - General</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghg-10-622</section_number>
  <catch_line>A petition for emergency evaluation of an individual may be made under this section only if the peti...</catch_line>
  <order_by>622</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">A petition for emergency evaluation of an individual may be made under this section only if the petitioner has reason to believe that the individual:<section prefix="(1)">Has a mental disorder; and</section><section prefix="(2)">The individual presents a danger to the life or safety of the individual or of others.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The petition for emergency evaluation of an individual may be made by:<section prefix="(i)">A physician, psychologist, clinical social worker, licensed clinical professional counselor, clinical nurse specialist in psychiatric and mental health nursing, psychiatric nurse practitioner, licensed clinical marriage and family therapist, or health officer or designee of a health officer who has examined the individual;</section><section prefix="(ii)">A peace officer who personally has observed the individual or the individual's behavior; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">Any other interested person.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">An individual who makes a petition for emergency evaluation under paragraph (1)(i) or (ii) of this subsection may base the petition on:<section prefix="(i)">The examination or observation; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">Other information obtained that is pertinent to the factors giving rise to the petition.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A petition under this section shall:<section prefix="(i)">Be signed and verified by the petitioner;</section><section prefix="(ii)">State the petitioner's:<section prefix="1.">Name;</section><section prefix="2.">Address; and</section><section prefix="3.">Home and work telephone numbers;</section></section><section prefix="(iii)">State the emergency evaluee's:<section prefix="1.">Name; and</section><section prefix="2.">Description;</section></section><section prefix="(iv)">State the following information, if available:<section prefix="1.">The address of the emergency evaluee; and</section><section prefix="2.">The name and address of the spouse or a child, parent, or other relative of the emergency evaluee or any other individual who is interested in the emergency evaluee;</section></section><section prefix="(v)">If the individual who makes the petition for emergency evaluation is an individual authorized to do so under subsection (b)(1)(i) of this section, contain the license number of the individual;</section><section prefix="(vi)">Contain a description of the behavior and statements of the emergency evaluee or any other information that led the petitioner to believe that the emergency evaluee has a mental disorder and that the individual presents a danger to the life or safety of the individual or of others; and</section><section prefix="(vii)">Contain any other facts that support the need for an emergency evaluation.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The petition form shall contain a notice that the petitioner:<section prefix="(i)">May be required to appear before a court; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Makes the statements under penalties of perjury.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A petitioner who is a physician, psychologist, clinical social worker, licensed clinical professional counselor, clinical nurse specialist in psychiatric and mental health nursing, psychiatric nurse practitioner, licensed clinical marriage and family therapist, health officer, or designee of a health officer shall give the petition to a peace officer.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The peace officer shall explain to the petitioner:<section prefix="(i)">The serious nature of the petition; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">The meaning and content of the petition.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
