<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghg" order_by="ghg" level="1">Health - General</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghg-19-214</section_number>
  <catch_line>The Commission shall assess the underlying causes of hospital uncompensated care and make recommenda...</catch_line>
  <order_by>214</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Commission shall assess the underlying causes of hospital uncompensated care and make recommendations to the General Assembly on the most appropriate alternatives to:<section prefix="(1)">Reduce uncompensated care; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Assure the integrity of the payment system.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Commission may adopt regulations establishing alternative methods for financing the reasonable total costs of hospital uncompensated care and the disproportionate share hospital payment provided that the alternative methods:<section prefix="(1)">Are in the public interest;</section><section prefix="(2)">Will equitably distribute the reasonable costs of uncompensated care and the disproportionate share hospital payment;</section><section prefix="(3)">Will fairly determine the cost of reasonable uncompensated care and the disproportionate share hospital payment included in hospital rates;</section><section prefix="(4)">Will continue incentives for hospitals to adopt fair, efficient, and effective credit and collection policies; and</section><section prefix="(5)">Will not result in significantly increasing costs to Medicare or the loss of Maryland's Medicare Waiver under &#xA7; 1814(b) of the Social Security Act.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Any funds generated through hospital rates under an alternative method adopted by the Commission in accordance with subsection (b) of this section may only be used to finance the delivery of hospital uncompensated care and the disproportionate share hospital payment.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">On or after July 1, 2009, if the expansion of health care coverage under Chapter 7 of the Acts of the General Assembly of the 2007 Special Session reduces hospital uncompensated care, the Commission:<section prefix="(i)">Shall determine the savings realized in averted uncompensated care for each hospital individually; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">May assess an amount in each hospital's rates equal to a portion of the savings realized in averted uncompensated care for that hospital.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Commission shall ensure that any savings realized in averted uncompensated care not subject to the assessment under paragraph (1) of this subsection be shared among purchasers of hospital services in a manner that the Commission determines is most equitable.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Each hospital shall remit any assessment under this subsection to the Health Care Coverage Fund established under &#xA7; 15-701 of this article.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
