<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghg" order_by="ghg" level="1">Health - General</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghg-10-520</section_number>
  <catch_line>Within 60 days after an application for a license is received, the Secretary shall:...</catch_line>
  <order_by>520</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Within 60 days after an application for a license is received, the Secretary shall:<section prefix="(1)">Have an investigation made of the application; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Give the governing body for the county where the private group home is to be located notice of:<section prefix="(i)">The filing of the application; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">The findings of the investigation.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Within 60 days after the application is received, the Secretary shall hold a public information hearing on the application.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Secretary shall hold the public information hearing in the county where the private group home is to be located and as close as possible to the proposed location.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Secretary shall publish a notice of the hearing.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The notice shall state:<section prefix="(i)">The name of the applicant;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The type of license that is sought;</section><section prefix="(iii)">The location of the proposed private group home; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">The time, place, and date that the Secretary sets for the hearing.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The notice shall be published at least twice in 1 week:<section prefix="(i)">In 2 newspapers published in the county where the private group home is to be located;</section><section prefix="(ii)">If only 1 newspaper is published in that county, in that newspaper; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">If a newspaper is not published in that county, in any newspaper with a substantial circulation in that county.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The written report of the investigation of the application may be submitted to the Secretary or the Secretary's designee if:<section prefix="(1)">At least 10 working days before the hearing, a copy of the report:<section prefix="(i)">Was sent to the applicant; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Was on file for public inspection; and</section></section><section prefix="(2)">The author of the report is available to answer questions from any person at the hearing.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
