<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghg" order_by="" level="1">Health - General</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghg-13-601</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>601</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Hearing-impaired infant" means an infant who has an impairment that is a dysfunction of the auditory system of any type or degree which is sufficient to interfere with the acquisition and development of speech and language skills with or without the use of sound amplification.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Infant" means a child who is under the age of 1 year.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">"Newborn" means a child up to 29 days old who is born in or receives care in a hospital in the State.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"Program" means the program that the Secretary establishes to provide for the universal hearing screening of newborns and early identification and follow-up of hearing-impaired infants and infants who have a risk factor of developing a hearing impairment.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">"Risk factor" includes any of the following factors that an infant may display and are considered relevant in determining the possibility of a hearing impairment:<section prefix="(1)">An admission for more than 48 hours to a neonatal intensive care nursery;</section><section prefix="(2)">An anatomical malformation that involves the head or neck, including:<section prefix="(i)">A dysmorphic appearance;</section><section prefix="(ii)">A morphologic abnormality of the pinna;</section><section prefix="(iii)">An overt or submucous cleft palate; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">Any syndromal or nonsyndromal abnormality;</section></section><section prefix="(3)">A severe asphyxia, including:<section prefix="(i)">An infant with an Apgar score of 0-3 who fails to institute spontaneous respiration within 10 minutes; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">An infant with hypotonia that persists during the 1st 2 hours of the infant's life;</section></section><section prefix="(4)">A bacterial meningitis, especially H. influenza;</section><section prefix="(5)">A birth weight of less than 1500 grams;</section><section prefix="(6)">A congenital perinatal infection, including cytomegalovirus, herpes, rubella, syphilis, and toxoplasmosis;</section><section prefix="(7)">A family history of a childhood hearing impairment; and</section><section prefix="(8)">A hyperbilirubinemia at a level that exceeds indications for exchange transfusion.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
