<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghg" order_by="ghg" level="1">Health - General</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghg-3-302</section_number>
  <catch_line>The health officer for a county shall be nominated by the county and appointed by the Secretary....</catch_line>
  <order_by>302</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The health officer for a county shall be nominated by the county and appointed by the Secretary.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The governing body of each county shall establish, by ordinance or resolution, the process by which the county nominates an individual for health officer.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If the Secretary finds that a nominee meets the qualifications of this section, the Secretary shall appoint the nominee as health officer.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If the Secretary finds that the nominee does not meet the qualifications of this section, the Secretary shall reject the nomination, and the county shall provide the Secretary with another nomination.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Each health officer:<section prefix="(1)">Shall have:<section prefix="(i)">A master's degree in public health and at least 2 years' work in the field of public health; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">At least 5 years' work in the field of public health;</section></section><section prefix="(2)">Shall have any other qualifications and training in the field of public health that the Secretary requires by rule or regulation; and</section><section prefix="(3)">Need not be a physician, if the health officer has a deputy who:<section prefix="(i)">Is a physician; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Meets the qualifications of this subsection.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">Before taking office, each appointee to the office of health officer shall take the oath required by Article I, &#xA7; 9 of the Maryland Constitution.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The health officer for a county serves at the pleasure of the governing body of that county and the Secretary.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">The health officer for a county may be removed from office with the concurrence of the governing body of that county and the Secretary.</section>
  </text>
</law>
