<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghg" order_by="ghg" level="1">Health - General</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghg-13-506</section_number>
  <catch_line>The Advisory Council consists of 15 members appointed by the Governor....</catch_line>
  <order_by>506</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Advisory Council consists of 15 members appointed by the Governor.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Of the 15 members:<section prefix="(i)">2 shall be representatives of the physicians and arthritis health professionals at the State's 2 medical schools;</section><section prefix="(ii)">1 shall be a representative of the Department;</section><section prefix="(iii)">1 shall be a representative of the Division of Rehabilitation Services;</section><section prefix="(iv)">1 shall be a representative of the Department of Aging;</section><section prefix="(v)">1 shall be a representative of the Governor's Committee on Employment of the Handicapped;</section><section prefix="(vi)">3 shall be members of voluntary agencies, including the Maryland Chapter of the Arthritis Foundation, the Maryland Lupus Foundation, and Home Health Care Inc.;</section><section prefix="(vii)">2 shall be representatives from hospitals or health professionals or both outside of the major metropolitan areas;</section><section prefix="(viii)">2 shall be representatives from the health care industry, including the pharmaceutical industry and third-party payors; and</section><section prefix="(ix)">2 shall be arthritic patients or family members of arthritic patients.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The term of a member is 4 years.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The terms of members are staggered as required by the terms provided for members of the Advisory Council on July 1, 1989.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">At the end of a term, a member continues to serve until a successor is appointed and qualifies.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">A member who is appointed after a term has begun serves only for the rest of the term and until a successor is appointed and qualifies.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Governor may remove a member for incompetence or misconduct.</section>
  </text>
</law>
