<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghg" order_by="" level="1">Health - General</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghg-19-3B-01</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>01</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Ambulatory surgical facility" means any center, service, office facility, or other entity that:<section prefix="(i)">Operates primarily for the purpose of providing surgical services to patients requiring a period of postoperative observation but not requiring overnight hospitalization; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Seeks reimbursement from payors as an ambulatory surgery center.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Ambulatory surgical facility" does not include:<section prefix="(i)">The office of one or more health care practitioners seeking only professional reimbursement for the provisions of medical services, unless:<section prefix="1.">The office operates under contract or other agreement with a payor as an ambulatory surgical facility regardless of whether it is paid a technical or facility fee; or</section><section prefix="2.">The office is designated to receive ambulatory surgical referrals in accordance with utilization review or other policies adopted by a payor;</section></section><section prefix="(ii)">Any facility or service owned or operated by a hospital and regulated under Subtitle 2 of this title;</section><section prefix="(iii)">The office of a health care practitioner with not more than one operating room if:<section prefix="1.">The office does not receive a technical or facility fee; and</section><section prefix="2.">The operating room is used exclusively by the health care practitioner for patients of the health care practitioner;</section></section><section prefix="(iv)">The office of a group of health care practitioners with not more than one operating room if:<section prefix="1.">The office does not receive a technical or facility fee; and</section><section prefix="2.">The operating room is used exclusively by members of the group practice for patients of the group practice; or</section></section><section prefix="(v)">An office owned or operated by one or more dentists licensed under the Health Occupations Article.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Freestanding ambulatory care facility" means:<section prefix="(1)">An ambulatory surgical facility;</section><section prefix="(2)">A freestanding endoscopy facility;</section><section prefix="(3)">A freestanding facility utilizing major medical equipment;</section><section prefix="(4)">A kidney dialysis center; or</section><section prefix="(5)">A freestanding birthing center.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Freestanding birthing center" means a facility that provides nurse midwife services under Title 8, Subtitle 6 of the Health Occupations Article.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Freestanding birthing center" does not include:<section prefix="(i)">A hospital regulated under Subtitle 2 of this title; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">The private residence of the mother.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Freestanding endoscopy facility" means a facility:<section prefix="(i)">For the testing, diagnosis, or treatment of a medical disorder in conjunction with the use of microscopic, endoscopic, or laparoscopic equipment that is inserted in a naturally occurring orifice of the body; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">That seeks reimbursement as a freestanding endoscopy facility from payors or Medicare.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Freestanding endoscopy facility" does not include:<section prefix="(i)">The office of one or more health care practitioners unless:<section prefix="1.">The office operates under a contract or other agreement with a payor as a freestanding endoscopy facility regardless of whether it is paid a technical or facility fee; or</section><section prefix="2.">The office is designated to receive endoscopic referrals in accordance with utilization review or other policies adopted by a payor; or</section></section><section prefix="(ii)">Any facility or service operated by a hospital and regulated under Subtitle 2 of this title.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Freestanding facility operating major medical equipment" means a facility using major medical equipment.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Freestanding facility operating major medical equipment" does not include any facility or service owned or operated by a hospital and regulated under Subtitle 2 of this title.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">"Health care practitioner" means a person who is licensed, certified, or otherwise authorized under the Health Occupations Article to provide medical services in the ordinary course of business or practice of a profession.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Kidney dialysis center" means a facility that provides hemodialysis or chronic peritoneal dialysis.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Kidney dialysis center" does not include any facility or service owned or operated by a hospital and regulated under Subtitle 2 of this title.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(i)">"License" means a license issued by the Secretary under this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(j)">"Major medical equipment" means:<section prefix="(1)">Cardiac catheterization equipment;</section><section prefix="(2)">A computer tomography (CT) scanner;</section><section prefix="(3)">A lithotripter;</section><section prefix="(4)">Radiation therapy equipment, including a linear accelerator; or</section><section prefix="(5)">A magnetic resonance imager (MRI).</section></section>
    <section prefix="(k)">"Payor" means:<section prefix="(1)">A health insurer, nonprofit health service plan, or health maintenance organization that holds a certificate of authority to offer health insurance policies or contracts in the State in accordance with this article or the Insurance Article;</section><section prefix="(2)">A third party administrator or any other entity under contract with a Maryland business to administer health benefits; or</section><section prefix="(3)">A self-insured group.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(l)">"Surgical services" means any invasive procedure whether therapeutic or diagnostic involving the use of:<section prefix="(1)">Any cutting instrument;</section><section prefix="(2)">Microscopic, endoscopic, arthroscopic, or laparoscopic equipment; or</section><section prefix="(3)">A laser for the removal or repair of an organ or other tissue.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
