<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghg" order_by="" level="1">Health - General</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghg-7-403</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>403</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as otherwise provided in this title, an applicant for services provided or funded, wholly or partly, by this State shall submit an application to the Department in writing.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The application shall contain the information that the Department requires.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Within 60 days after the Department receives an application for services for an individual, the Secretary, on the basis of the application, shall:<section prefix="(1)">Determine whether there is a reasonable likelihood that the individual:<section prefix="(i)">Has developmental disability; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">Does not have developmental disability, but may be eligible for individual support services under subsection (c) of this section; and</section></section><section prefix="(2)">If a positive determination is made under item (1)(i) or (ii) of this subsection:<section prefix="(i)">Approve the application;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Determine the nature of the disability;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Determine the nature of services that the individual may require;</section><section prefix="(iv)">Determine the type of environment in which any needed services could be provided with the least restriction on the liberty of the individual;</section><section prefix="(v)">Determine what types of evaluations, if any, the individual requires;</section><section prefix="(vi)">Inform the individual of these determinations; and</section><section prefix="(vii)">Inform the individual that these determinations are preliminary and may be subject to modification as a result of further evaluation.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">To be eligible for individual support services, an individual shall have a severe chronic disability that:<section prefix="(1)">Is attributable to a physical or mental impairment, other than the sole diagnosis of mental illness, or to a combination of mental and physical impairments; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Is likely to continue indefinitely.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">If the Secretary determines, based on the application, that the individual has a sole diagnosis of mental disorder, the Secretary shall refer the individual to the Mental Hygiene Administration.</section>
  </text>
</law>
