<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghg" order_by="ghg" level="1">Health - General</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghg-13-2504</section_number>
  <catch_line>The Office of Oral Health shall conduct an annual evaluation of the Program....</catch_line>
  <order_by>2504</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Office of Oral Health shall conduct an annual evaluation of the Program.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The evaluation required under this subsection shall include:<section prefix="(i)">Data on any progress resulting from each grant awarded under this subtitle;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Data on any progress of the overall Program;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Data demonstrating any increase in the use of restorative dental care among underserved populations; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">Data from any statewide survey conducted by the Department that demonstrates any progress of the Program.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Department, in conjunction with the Office of Oral Health, shall report to the Governor and, in accordance with &#xA7; 2-1246 of the State Government Article, the General Assembly on or before September 30 of each year on:<section prefix="(1)">The results of the Program;</section><section prefix="(2)">Findings and recommendations for the Oral Health Program and any other oral health programs established under Title 18, Subtitle 8 of this article;</section><section prefix="(3)">The availability and accessibility of dentists throughout the State participating in the Maryland Medical Assistance Program;</section><section prefix="(4)">The outcomes that managed care organizations and dental managed care organizations under the Maryland Medical Assistance Program achieve concerning the utilization of targets required by the Five Year Oral Health Care Plan, including:<section prefix="(i)">Loss ratios that the managed care organizations and dental managed care organizations experience for providing dental services; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Corrective action by managed care organizations and dental managed care organizations to achieve the utilization targets; and</section></section><section prefix="(5)">The allocation and use of funds authorized for dental services under the Maryland Medical Assistance Program.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
