<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghg" order_by="ghg" level="1">Health - General</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghg-5-703</section_number>
  <catch_line>The State Team shall be a multidisciplinary and multiagency review team, composed of at least 25 mem...</catch_line>
  <order_by>703</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The State Team shall be a multidisciplinary and multiagency review team, composed of at least 25 members, including:<section prefix="(1)">The Attorney General;</section><section prefix="(2)">The Chief Medical Examiner;</section><section prefix="(3)">The Secretary of Human Resources;</section><section prefix="(4)">The Secretary of Health and Mental Hygiene;</section><section prefix="(5)">The State Superintendent of Schools;</section><section prefix="(6)">The Secretary of Juvenile Services;</section><section prefix="(7)">The Special Secretary for Children, Youth, and Families;</section><section prefix="(8)">The Secretary of State Police;</section><section prefix="(9)">The president of the State's Attorneys' Association;</section><section prefix="(10)">The chief of the Division of Vital Records of the Department;</section><section prefix="(11)">A representative of the State SIDS Information and Counseling Program;</section><section prefix="(12)">The Director of the Alcohol and Drug Abuse Administration of the Department;</section><section prefix="(13)">Two pediatricians with experience in diagnosing and treating injuries and child abuse and neglect, appointed by the Governor from a list submitted by the State Chapter of the American Academy of Pediatrics; and</section><section prefix="(14)">Eleven members of the general public with interest or expertise in child safety and welfare, appointed by the Governor, including child advocates, CASA volunteers, health and mental health professionals, and attorneys who represent children.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The members described under subsection (a)(1) through (12) of this section may designate representatives from their departments or offices to represent them on the State Team.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The State Team may employ a staff in accordance with the State budget. Each member of the Team under subsection (a)(1) through (12) of this section shall provide sufficient staff support to complete the State Team's responsibilities.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Members of the State Team shall serve without compensation, but may be reimbursed for reasonable expenses incurred in the performance of their duties in accordance with the Standard State Travel Regulations and as provided in the State budget.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The State Team shall select a chairperson from among its members.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The State Team shall meet not less than once every 3 months.</section>
  </text>
</law>
