<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghg" order_by="" level="1">Health - General</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghg-19-1907</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>1907</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Department shall conduct the criminal history records check and issue the printed statement provided for under this subtitle.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Department shall update an initial criminal history records check and issue a revised printed statement, listing any of the convictions or pending charges occurring in the State after the date of the initial criminal history records check.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Department shall provide an initial and a revised statement of an eligible employee's State criminal record to the recipients of the acknowledgments specified in &#xA7; 19-1905(b) of this subtitle.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The Department shall adopt regulations requiring employers to verify periodically the continuing employment of an employee.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Department shall provide a printed statement of the eligible employee's State criminal record to the recipients of the acknowledgments specified in &#xA7; 19-1905(b) of this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Information obtained from the Department or a private agency under this subtitle shall be confidential and may be disseminated only to the eligible employee who is the subject of the criminal history records check or private agency background check and to an adult dependent care program seeking to hire the eligible employee.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Information obtained from the Department or a private agency under this subtitle may not:<section prefix="(1)">Be used for any purpose other than that for which it was disseminated; or</section><section prefix="(2)">Be redisseminated.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">Information obtained from the Department or a private agency under this subtitle shall be maintained in a manner to insure the security of the information.</section>
  </text>
</law>
