<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghg" order_by="" level="1">Health - General</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghg-19-220</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>220</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">To have the statistical information needed for rate review and approval, the Commission shall compile all relevant financial and accounting information.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The information shall include:<section prefix="(i)">Necessary operating expenses;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Appropriate expenses that are incurred in providing services to patients who cannot or do not pay;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Incurred interest charges; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">Reasonable depreciation expenses that are based on the expected useful life of property or equipment.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Commission shall define, by regulation, the types and classes of charges that may not be changed, except as specified in &#xA7; 19-222 of this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Commission shall obtain from each facility its current rate schedule and each later change in the schedule that the Commission requires.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Commission shall:<section prefix="(1)">Permit a nonprofit facility to charge reasonable rates that will permit the facility to provide, on a solvent basis, effective and efficient service that is in the public interest; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Permit a proprietary profit-making facility to charge reasonable rates that:<section prefix="(i)">Will permit the facility to provide effective and efficient service that is in the public interest; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Based on the fair value of the property and investments that are related directly to the facility, include enough allowance for and provide a fair return to the owner of the facility.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">In the determination of reasonable rates for each facility, as specified in this section, the Commission shall take into account all of the cost of complying with recommendations made, under Subtitle 1 of this title, on comprehensive health planning.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">In reviewing rates or charges or considering a request for change in rates or charges, the Commission shall permit a facility to charge rates that, in the aggregate, will produce enough total revenue to enable the facility to meet reasonably each requirement specified in this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">Except as otherwise provided by law, in reviewing rates or charges or considering a request for changes in rates or charges, the Commission may not hold executive sessions.</section>
  </text>
</law>
