<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="ghg" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="19-116" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghg-19-116</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Secretary shall provide for a study of systems capacity in health services.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The study shall:<section prefix="(i)">Determine for all health delivery facilities and settings where capacity should be increased or decreased to better meet the needs of the population;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Examine and describe the implementation methods and tools by which capacity should be altered to better meet the needs; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Assess the impact of those methods and tools on the communities and health care delivery system.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In addition to information that an applicant for a certificate of need must provide, the Commission may request, collect, and report any statistical or other information that:<section prefix="(i)">Is needed by the Commission to perform its duties described in this Part II of this subtitle; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Is described in regulations of the Commission.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If a health care facility fails to provide information as required in this subsection, the Commission may:<section prefix="(i)">Impose a penalty of not more than $100 per day for each day the violation continues after consideration of the willfulness and seriousness of the withholding, as well as any past history of withholding of information;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Issue an administrative order that requires the applicant to provide the information; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">Apply to the circuit court in the county in which the facility is located for legal relief considered appropriate by the Commission.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Commission may send to the Department or a local health planning agency any statistical or other information the Commission is authorized to collect under paragraph (1) of this subsection.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
