<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="ghg" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="20-109" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghg-20-109</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, "Alzheimer's special care unit or program" means a secured or segregated special unit or program specifically designed for individuals with a probable or confirmed diagnosis of Alzheimer's disease or a related disorder.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">An assisted living program that provides care for or offers to provide care for persons with Alzheimer's disease or a related disorder by means of an Alzheimer's special care unit or program, shall disclose how the form of care and treatment provided by the Alzheimer's special care unit or program is specifically designed for the specialized care of individuals diagnosed with Alzheimer's disease or a related disorder.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">At the time of licensure or license renewal, an assisted living program with an Alzheimer's special care unit or program shall send to the Department a written description of the special care unit or program.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">An assisted living program with an Alzheimer's special care unit or program shall disclose the written description of the special care unit to:<section prefix="(1)">Any person on request; and</section><section prefix="(2)">The family or party responsible for any resident prior to admission of the resident to the Alzheimer's special care unit or program.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The description of the Alzheimer's special care unit or program shall include:<section prefix="(1)">A statement of philosophy or mission;</section><section prefix="(2)">Staff training and staff job titles;</section><section prefix="(3)">Admission procedures including screening criteria;</section><section prefix="(4)">Assessment and care planning protocol;</section><section prefix="(5)">Staffing patterns;</section><section prefix="(6)">A description of the physical environment and any unique design features appropriate to support the functioning of cognitively impaired individuals;</section><section prefix="(7)">A description of activities including frequency and type;</section><section prefix="(8)">Charges to residents for services provided by the Alzheimer's special care unit or program;</section><section prefix="(9)">Discharge procedures;</section><section prefix="(10)">Any services, training, or other procedures that are over and above those that are provided in the existing assisted living program; and</section><section prefix="(11)">Any other information that the Department may require.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The Department, in consultation with the Alzheimer's Association, the Health Facilities Association of Maryland, and Lifespan, may adopt regulations that govern the submission of disclosure materials to the Department and to consumers.</section>
  </text>
</law>
