<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="ghg" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="20-103" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghg-20-103</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Except as provided in subsections (b) and (c) of this section, a physician may not perform an abortion on an unmarried minor unless the physician first gives notice to a parent or guardian of the minor.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The physician may perform the abortion without notice to a parent or guardian if:<section prefix="(1)">The minor does not live with a parent or guardian; and</section><section prefix="(2)">A reasonable effort to give notice to a parent or guardian is unsuccessful.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The physician may perform the abortion, without notice to a parent or guardian of a minor if, in the professional judgment of the physician:<section prefix="(i)">Notice to the parent or guardian may lead to physical or emotional abuse of the minor;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The minor is mature and capable of giving informed consent to an abortion; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">Notification would not be in the best interest of the minor.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The physician is not liable for civil damages or subject to a criminal penalty for a decision under this subsection not to give notice.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The postal receipt that shows an article of mail was sent by certified mail, return receipt requested, bearing a postmark from the United States Postal Service, to the last known address of a parent or guardian and that is attached to a copy of the notice letter that was sent in that article of mail shall be conclusive evidence of notice or a reasonable effort to give notice, as the case may be.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">A physician may not provide notice to a parent or guardian if the minor decides not to have the abortion.</section>
  </text>
</law>
