<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghg" order_by="ghg" level="1">Health - General</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghg-21-2A-05</section_number>
  <catch_line>There is an Advisory Board on Prescription Drug Monitoring in the Department....</catch_line>
  <order_by>05</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">There is an Advisory Board on Prescription Drug Monitoring in the Department.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Board shall consist of the following members:<section prefix="(1)">The Secretary, or the Secretary's designee;</section><section prefix="(2)">The President of the Maryland Board of Pharmacy, or the President's designee;</section><section prefix="(3)">The Chair of the Maryland Board of Physicians, or the Chair's designee;</section><section prefix="(4)">The President of the Maryland Board of Nursing, or the President's designee;</section><section prefix="(5)">The Chairman of the Maryland Health Care Commission, or the Chairman's designee;</section><section prefix="(6)">Four physicians and one nurse practitioner with expertise in clinical treatment using controlled dangerous substances, including pain management, substance abuse, and behavioral disorders, appointed by the Secretary after consultation with:<section prefix="(i)">For the physician appointments, the Medical and Chirurgical Faculty of Maryland, the Maryland Physical Medicine and Rehabilitation Society, the Maryland Society of Anesthesiologists, the Maryland-D.C. Society of Clinical Oncology, the Hospice and Palliative Care Network of Maryland, and the Maryland Chapter of the American Academy of Pediatrics; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">For the nurse practitioner appointment, the Maryland Nurses Association;</section></section><section prefix="(7)">One pediatrician, appointed by the Secretary after consultation with the Maryland Chapter of the American Academy of Pediatrics;</section><section prefix="(8)">Three pharmacists who represent the perspective of independent and chain pharmacies, appointed by the Secretary after consultation with the Maryland Pharmacists Association, the Maryland Association of Chain Drug Stores, and any other appropriate organization;</section><section prefix="(9)">A local law enforcement official, appointed by the Secretary after consultation with the Maryland Chiefs of Police Association and the Maryland Sheriff's Association; and</section><section prefix="(10)">Two Maryland residents who represent the perspective of patients, appointed by the Secretary.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Secretary shall designate the chair of the Board.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The term of a member appointed by the Secretary is 3 years.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The terms of members appointed by the Secretary are staggered as required by the terms provided for members of the Board on October 1, 2011.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">If a vacancy occurs during the term of an appointed member, the Secretary shall appoint a successor who shall serve until the term expires.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">A member of the Board:<section prefix="(1)">May not receive compensation as a member of the Board; but</section><section prefix="(2)">Is entitled to reimbursement for expenses under the Standard State Travel Regulations, as provided in the State budget.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The Board shall:<section prefix="(1)">Meet not fewer than three times annually;</section><section prefix="(2)">Make recommendations to the Secretary relating to the design and implementation of the Program, including recommendations relating to:<section prefix="(i)">Regulations;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Legislation; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Sources of funding, including grant funds under the Harold Rogers Prescription Drug Monitoring Program and other sources of federal, private, or State funds;</section></section><section prefix="(3)"><section prefix="(i)">Provide within 180 days after its first meeting, in accordance with &#xA7; 2-1246 of the State Government Article, an interim report to the General Assembly setting forth the Board's analysis and recommendations under item (2) of this subsection relating to the design, implementation, and funding of the Program; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Provide annually to the Governor and, in accordance with &#xA7; 2-1246 of the State Government Article, the General Assembly an analysis of the impact of the Program on patient access to pharmaceutical care and on curbing prescription drug diversion in the State, including any recommendations related to modification or continuation of the Program; and</section></section><section prefix="(4)">Provide ongoing advice and consultation on the implementation and operation of the Program, including recommendations relating to:<section prefix="(i)">Changes in the Program to reflect advances in technology and best practices in the field of electronic health records and electronic prescription monitoring;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Changes to statutory requirements; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">The design and implementation of an ongoing evaluation component of the Program.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(g)">The Secretary and the Board shall consult with stakeholders and professionals knowledgeable about prescription drug monitoring programs as appropriate to obtain input and guidance about implementation of the Program.</section>
  </text>
</law>
