<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="ghg" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="2-604" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghg-2-604</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">A person may file a civil action on behalf of the person and the State in a court of competent jurisdiction within the State against a person who has acted or is acting in violation of &#xA7; 2-602(a) of this subtitle.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">A civil action filed under subparagraph (i) of this paragraph shall be brought in the name of the State.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A person filing an action under this section may seek:<section prefix="(i)">The penalties provided under &#xA7; 2-602(b) of this subtitle; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Subject to the guidelines set forth in &#xA7; 2-605(a)(4) of this subtitle, court costs and attorney's fees.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The person shall serve on the State a copy of the complaint and a written disclosure of substantially all material evidence and information that the person possesses, in accordance with the provisions of Title 2 of the Maryland Rules for serving process on the State.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)"/>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(4)">
        <section prefix="(i)">For good cause shown, the State may move the court for extensions of the time during which the complaint remains under seal under paragraph (3)(ii)1 of this subsection.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">Any motions made under subparagraph (i) of this paragraph may be supported by affidavits or other submissions in camera.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(5)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The defendant may not be required to answer a complaint filed under this section until after the complaint is:</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">When answering a complaint filed under this section, a defendant shall follow the time frames and other provisions for filing answers to a complaint as required under Title 2, Chapter 300 of the Maryland Rules.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">During the period in which the complaint is under seal, if the State's investigation reveals that the act, transaction, or occurrence that gave rise to the alleged violation of this subtitle is reasonably likely to be continuing, the State shall notify the defendant as soon as practicable without jeopardizing the course and conduct of the State's or the federal government's investigation of the violation, compromising the development of evidence, or violating any State or federal law.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(6)">Before the later of the expiration of the 60-day period during which the complaint remains under seal under paragraph (3)(ii)1 of this subsection or any extension of the 60-day period obtained under paragraph (4) of this subsection, the State shall:<section prefix="(i)">Intervene and proceed with the action in a court of competent jurisdiction within the State; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">Notify the court that it will not intervene and proceed with the action.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(7)">If the State does not elect to intervene and proceed with the action under paragraph (6) of this subsection, before unsealing the complaint, the court shall dismiss the action.</section>
      <section prefix="(8)">If a person initiates an action under this section, no person other than the State may intervene in the action or initiate a related action based on the facts underlying the pending action.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If the State intervenes and proceeds with the action under subsection (a)(6)(i) of this section:<section prefix="(i)">The State shall have the primary responsibility for proceeding with the action and may not be bound by any act of the person who initiated the action; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Subject to paragraphs (3) through (6) of this subsection, the person who initiated the action may continue as a party to the action.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">During an investigation by the State conducted either independently or in conjunction with a civil action filed under this subtitle, the Attorney General shall have the same rights of discovery as a civil litigant in the circuit court under Title 2, Chapter 400 of the Maryland Rules.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">A person from whom the Attorney General seeks discovery shall be considered a party under Title 2, Chapter 400 of the Maryland Rules.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Notwithstanding the objections of the person initiating the action, the State may elect at any point to withdraw its intervention as a party to the action.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">If the State elects to withdraw as a party to the action:</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(4)">Notwithstanding the objections of the person initiating the action, if the court determines after a hearing that a proposed settlement is fair, adequate, and reasonable under the circumstances, the State may settle a civil action filed under this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">On motion of the State or the defendant or on the court's own motion, the court may impose limitations on the participation of the person initiating an action under this section if:<section prefix="(i)">The State shows that the person's unrestricted participation in the action would:</section><section prefix="(ii)">The defendant shows that unrestricted participation by the person initiating the action would harass the defendant or cause the defendant undue burden or unnecessary expense.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(6)">Limitations imposed by the court under paragraph (5) of this subsection may include:<section prefix="(i)">A limitation on the number of witnesses the person may call to testify;</section><section prefix="(ii)">A limitation on the length of the testimony of witnesses called by the person;</section><section prefix="(iii)">A limitation on the person's cross-examination of witnesses; or</section><section prefix="(iv)">A limitation on the participation of the person in the litigation.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Instead of proceeding with a civil action filed under this subtitle, the State may pursue any alternative remedy available to the State, including any appropriate administrative proceeding to determine a civil money penalty.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If the State seeks an alternative remedy in another proceeding after intervening in a civil action filed under this section, the person initiating the action shall have the same rights in the alternative proceeding as the person would have had if the civil action had continued under this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">A finding of fact or conclusion of law made in any alternative proceeding that has become final shall be conclusive on all parties to an action filed under this subtitle.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">For purposes of subparagraph (i) of this paragraph, a finding or conclusion is final if:</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">On a showing in camera by the State that certain actions of discovery by the person initiating the action would interfere with the State's investigation or prosecution of a criminal or civil matter arising out of the same facts, the court may stay the discovery for a period of not more than 60 days.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The court may extend the 60-day period on a further showing in camera that:<section prefix="(i)">The State has pursued the criminal or civil investigation or proceeding with reasonable diligence; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Any proposed discovery in the civil action will interfere with the ongoing criminal or civil investigation or proceeding.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
