<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghg" order_by="ghg" level="1">Health - General</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghg-19-347</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this section the following words have the meanings indicated....</catch_line>
  <order_by>347</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">"Abuse" means the non-therapeutic infliction of physical pain or injury, or any persistent course of conduct intended to produce or resulting in mental or emotional distress.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">"Abuse" does not include the performance of an accepted medical procedure that a physician orders.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Law enforcement agency" means the Department of State Police or a police agency of a county or municipal corporation.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A person who believes that a resident of a related institution has been abused shall report promptly the alleged abuse to an appropriate law enforcement agency, the Secretary, or the Department of Aging.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A report:<section prefix="(i)">May be oral or written; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Shall contain as much information as the reporter is able to provide.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The recipient of the report promptly shall notify:<section prefix="(i)">The other parties referred to in paragraph (1) of this subsection; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Unless the administrator is the alleged abuser, the administrator of the related institution.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Any employee of a related institution who is required to report alleged abuse under subsection (b) of this section, and who fails to report the alleged abuse within 3 days after learning of the alleged abuse, is liable for a civil penalty of not more than $1,000.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Unless otherwise provided, the law enforcement agency, with the assistance of the Secretary, shall:<section prefix="(i)">Investigate thoroughly each report of an alleged abuse; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Attempt to insure the protection of the alleged victim.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The investigation shall include:<section prefix="(i)">A determination of the nature, extent, and cause of the abuse;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The identity of the alleged abuser; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Any other pertinent fact or matter.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Within 10 working days after the completion of the investigation, the law enforcement agency shall submit a written report of its findings to:<section prefix="(i)">The State's Attorney;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The Secretary;</section><section prefix="(iii)">The local ombudsman as designated by the Secretary of Aging;</section><section prefix="(iv)">Unless the administrator is the alleged abuser, the administrator of the related institution; and</section><section prefix="(v)">The Division of Licensing and Certification of the Department of Health and Mental Hygiene.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The law enforcement agency:<section prefix="(1)">Shall refer to the Secretary for investigation reported instances of abuse involving any persistent course of conduct intended to produce or resulting in mental or emotional distress; and</section><section prefix="(2)">May refer to the Secretary for investigation reported instances of patient-to-patient abuse.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">Within 10 working days after the completion of an investigation under subsection (d) of this section, the Secretary shall submit a written report of its findings to:<section prefix="(1)">The State's Attorney;</section><section prefix="(2)">The local ombudsman as designated by the Secretary of Aging; and</section><section prefix="(3)">Unless the administrator is the alleged abuser, the administrator of the related institution.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(g)">A person shall have the immunity from liability described under &#xA7; 5-631 of the Courts and Judicial Proceedings Article for:<section prefix="(1)">Making a report under this section;</section><section prefix="(2)">Participating in an investigation arising out of a report under this section;</section><section prefix="(3)">Participating in a judicial proceeding arising out of a report under this section; or</section><section prefix="(4)">Participating in transferring, suspending, or terminating the employment of any individual who is believed to have abused or aided in abusing a resident under this section.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(h)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Department shall provide each related institution with signs that set forth the reporting requirements under this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The related institution shall post the signs conspicuously in the employee and public areas of the related institution.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
