<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghg" order_by="ghg" level="1">Health - General</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghg-13-1101</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated....</catch_line>
  <order_by>1101</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Administrative Component" means the component of the Program established under &#xA7; 13-1119 of this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Baseline Cancer Study" means the study conducted under &#xA7; 13-1103 of this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">"Cancer Research Plan" means a plan developed under &#xA7; 13-1116 of this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"Cigarette Restitution Fund" means the fund that is established under &#xA7; 7-317 of the State Finance and Procurement Article.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">"Community Health Coalition" means a coalition established under &#xA7; 13-1109(c)(1) or &#xA7; 13-1115(b)(1) of this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">"Comprehensive Plan for Cancer Prevention, Education, Screening, and Treatment" means a plan developed under &#xA7; 13-1109(c)(2) or &#xA7; 13-1115(b)(2) of this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">"County" includes Baltimore City.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">"Education" means information provided to the public regarding the purpose of, availability of, and access to screening programs.</section>
    <section prefix="(j)">"Federally qualified health center" has the meaning stated in 42 U.S.C. &#xA7; 254b.</section>
    <section prefix="(k)">"Johns Hopkins Institutions" means the Johns Hopkins University and the Johns Hopkins Health System.</section>
    <section prefix="(l)">"Local health officer" means:<section prefix="(1)">The head of a county health department; or</section><section prefix="(2)">A person designated by the Department under &#xA7; 13-1109(h) or &#xA7; 13-1115(f) of this subtitle.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(m)">"Local Public Health Cancer Grant" means a grant distributed by the Department to a county under &#xA7;&#xA7; 13-1107 through 13-1113 of this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(n)">"Local Public Health Component" means the component of the Program that is established under &#xA7; 13-1107 of this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(o)">"Maryland Cancer Registry" means the computerized data system, operated by the Community Public Health Administration in the Department with the assistance of the Maryland State Council on Cancer Control, that registers cases of cancer that are diagnosed and treated in the State.</section>
    <section prefix="(p)">"Maryland Technology Development Corporation" means the entity that is established under Title 10, Subtitle 4 of the Economic Development Article.</section>
    <section prefix="(q)">"Minority individual" means a woman or an individual of African American, Hispanic, Native American, or Asian descent.</section>
    <section prefix="(r)">"Outreach efforts" means activities that are related to encouraging individuals to seek screening services.</section>
    <section prefix="(s)">"Prevention" means activities relating to early detection, screening, and risk factor reduction.</section>
    <section prefix="(t)">"Program" means the Cancer Prevention, Education, Screening, and Treatment Program that is established under &#xA7; 13-1102 of this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(u)">"Screening" includes screening, early detection, identification, diagnosis, and outreach efforts associated with screening and early detection programs.</section>
    <section prefix="(v)">"Statewide Academic Health Center" means the University of Maryland Medical Group or the Johns Hopkins Institutions.</section>
    <section prefix="(w)">"Statewide Academic Health Center Cancer Research Grant" means a grant that is distributed under &#xA7; 13-1116 of this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(x)">"Statewide Academic Health Center Component" means the component established under &#xA7; 13-1114 of this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(y)">"Statewide Academic Health Center Public Health Grant" means a grant that is distributed under &#xA7; 13-1115 of this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(z)">"Statewide Academic Health Center Tobacco-Related Diseases Research Grant" means a grant that is distributed under &#xA7; 13-1017 of this title.</section>
    <section prefix="(aa)">"Statewide Public Health Component" means the component of the Program that is established under &#xA7; 13-1106 of this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(bb)">"Surveillance and Evaluation Component" means the component of the Program that is established under &#xA7; 13-1103 of this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(cc)">"Targeted cancer" means a cancer that is identified by the Department under &#xA7; 13-1102(d) of this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(dd)">"Task Force Report" means the report entitled "Report of the Governor's Task Force to Conquer Cancer" that was issued in December 1999.</section>
    <section prefix="(ee)">"Tobacco-related diseases" means cardiovascular disease, chronic pulmonary disease, peripheral vascular disease, stroke, and infant mortality due to low birth weight.</section>
    <section prefix="(ff)">"Treatment" includes appropriate access to:<section prefix="(1)">Local hospitals, community clinics, physicians, and other health care providers; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Clinical trials, transportation, case management, hospice care, and cancer support groups.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(gg)">"Uninsured individual" means an individual:<section prefix="(1)">For whom the appropriate treatment is not covered by private health insurance, Medicaid, Medicare, or the Maryland Children's Health Program; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Who the Department determines does not have the financial means to pay for appropriate treatment.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(hh)">"University of Maryland Medical Group" means the University of Maryland Medical System Corporation, the University of Maryland Medical School, and the University of Maryland, Baltimore.</section>
  </text>
</law>
