<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghg" order_by="ghg" level="1">Health - General</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghg-2-607</section_number>
  <catch_line>A person may not take a retaliatory action against an employee, contractor, or grantee because the e...</catch_line>
  <order_by>607</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">A person may not take a retaliatory action against an employee, contractor, or grantee because the employee, contractor, or grantee:<section prefix="(1)">Acts lawfully in furtherance of an action filed under this subtitle, including an investigation for, initiation of, testimony for, or assistance in an action filed or to be filed under this subtitle;</section><section prefix="(2)">Discloses or threatens to disclose to a supervisor or to a public body an activity, policy, or practice of the person that the employee, contractor, or grantee reasonably believes is in violation of &#xA7; 2-602(a) of this subtitle or a regulation adopted under this subtitle;</section><section prefix="(3)">Provides information to, or testifies before, a public body conducting an investigation, hearing, or inquiry into a violation of &#xA7; 2-602(a) of this subtitle or a regulation adopted under this subtitle that is allegedly or actually committed by the person; or</section><section prefix="(4)">Objects to or refuses to participate in any activity, policy, or practice that the employee, contractor, or grantee reasonably believes is in violation of &#xA7; 2-602(a) of this subtitle or a regulation adopted under this subtitle.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">An employee, contractor, or grantee may file a civil action against a person other than a supervisor in State government, an appointing authority in State government, or the head of a principal unit in State government if the person takes a retaliatory action against the employee, contractor, or grantee in violation of subsection (a) of this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The employee, contractor, or grantee may seek in the civil action:<section prefix="(i)">An injunction to restrain a continuing violation of subsection (a) of this section;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Reinstatement to the same seniority status held before the retaliatory action;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Reinstatement of full fringe benefits and seniority rights;</section><section prefix="(iv)">Two times the amount of lost wages, benefits, and other remuneration, including any interest accumulated;</section><section prefix="(v)">Payment by the person of reasonable costs and attorney's fees;</section><section prefix="(vi)">Punitive damages;</section><section prefix="(vii)">An assessment of a civil penalty:<section prefix="1.">Not exceeding $1,000 for the first violation; and</section><section prefix="2.">Not exceeding $5,000 for each subsequent violation; and</section></section><section prefix="(viii)">Any other relief necessary to make the employee, contractor, or grantee whole.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The remedies provided under this section do not diminish or affect the rights, privileges, or remedies available to the employee, contractor, or grantee under:<section prefix="(i)">Any other federal or State statute or regulation; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">Any collective bargaining agreement or employee contract.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">This section does not apply to an employee as defined in &#xA7; 1-501 of the Health Occupations Article or a State employee.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">An employee as defined in &#xA7; 1-501 of the Health Occupations Article who is subject to retaliatory action in violation of subsection (a) of this section may file a civil action under Title 1, Subtitle 5 of the Health Occupations Article.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A State employee who is subject to retaliatory action in violation of subsection (a) of this section may file a complaint under Title 5, Subtitle 3 of the State Personnel and Pensions Article.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
