<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghg" order_by="ghg" level="1">Health - General</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghg-19-1812</section_number>
  <catch_line>Except as provided in subsections (g) and (h) of this section, the Department shall require that eac...</catch_line>
  <order_by>1812</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Except as provided in subsections (g) and (h) of this section, the Department shall require that each assisted living program facility that provides services to 50 or more individuals have an emergency electrical power generator on the premises.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Department shall require that each facility provide emergency electrical power as provided in this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The emergency power source shall be a generating set and prime mover located on the facility premises with automatic transfer.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">An emergency power system shall meet the following requirements:<section prefix="(i)">In the event of failure of the normal electric service, the emergency electrical power shall be activated immediately;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The emergency generator set shall come to full speed and load acceptance within 10 seconds; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">The emergency generator shall have the capability of 48 hours of operation from fuel stored on-site.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The emergency power system shall be tested one time each month.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The emergency power system test shall require that the generator be exercised for a minimum of 30 minutes under normal emergency facility connected load.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">The test shall be recorded in a permanent log book maintained for that purpose.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The emergency power system shall provide lighting in the following areas of the facility:<section prefix="(1)">Areas of egress and protection as required by the State Fire Prevention Code and Life Safety Code 101 adopted by the State Fire Prevention Commission;</section><section prefix="(2)">Nurses' station;</section><section prefix="(3)">Drug distribution station or unit dose station;</section><section prefix="(4)">An area for emergency telephone use;</section><section prefix="(5)">Boiler or mechanical room;</section><section prefix="(6)">Kitchen;</section><section prefix="(7)">Emergency generator location and switch gear location;</section><section prefix="(8)">Elevator, if operable on emergency power;</section><section prefix="(9)">Areas where life support equipment is used;</section><section prefix="(10)">If applicable, common areas or areas of refuge; and</section><section prefix="(11)">If applicable, toilet rooms of common areas or areas of refuge.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">Emergency electrical power shall be provided for the following:<section prefix="(1)">Nurses' call system;</section><section prefix="(2)">At least one telephone in order to make and receive calls;</section><section prefix="(3)">Fire pump;</section><section prefix="(4)">Sewerage pump and sump pump;</section><section prefix="(5)">If required for evacuation purposes, an elevator;</section><section prefix="(6)">If necessary, heating equipment needed to maintain a minimum temperature of 70 degrees Fahrenheit (24 degrees Celsius) in all common areas or areas of refuge;</section><section prefix="(7)">Life support equipment; and</section><section prefix="(8)">Nonflammable medical gas systems.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If the emergency power system does not provide heat to all patient rooms or toilet rooms in the event of a loss of electricity from the main source of power, the facility shall provide common areas or areas of refuge for all patients.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Department shall adopt regulations regarding the requirements for designating parts of the facility as common areas or areas of refuge.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">An assisted living program facility shall be exempt from the requirements of this section if the facility can safely transfer residents through an enclosed corridor to a building that is equipped with an electrical power generator that satisfies the requirements of this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Department may grant a facility a waiver from the requirements of this section if the facility:<section prefix="(i)">Provides evidence to the Department that the requirements of this section will create an undue financial burden on the facility and will require the facility to cease operation; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Discloses to the residents of the facility that the facility does not have an emergency electrical power generator that meets the requirements of this section.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Subject to paragraph (3) of this subsection, a waiver granted under paragraph (1) of this subsection may not exceed a period of 3 years.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Department may extend a waiver granted under paragraph (1) of this subsection for an additional period of 2 years beyond the period specified in paragraph (2) of this subsection.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
