<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghg" order_by="ghg" level="1">Health - General</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghg-18-907</section_number>
  <catch_line>A person may not knowingly and willfully fail to comply with any order, regulation, or directive iss...</catch_line>
  <order_by>907</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A person may not knowingly and willfully fail to comply with any order, regulation, or directive issued in accordance with &#xA7; 18-905 of this subtitle.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A person who violates paragraph (1) of this subsection is guilty of a misdemeanor and on conviction is subject to imprisonment not exceeding 1 year or a fine not exceeding $3,000 or both.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">If a health care facility fails to comply with an order, regulation, or directive issued under &#xA7; 18-903 or &#xA7; 18-904 of this subtitle, the Secretary may impose a civil penalty not to exceed $3,000 for each offense.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">If a health care practitioner fails to comply with an order, regulation, or directive issued under &#xA7; 18-903 or &#xA7; 18-904 of this subtitle, the Secretary may request the appropriate licensing board to take disciplinary action against the health care practitioner, including:<section prefix="(1)">Placing the licensee or certificate holder on probation;</section><section prefix="(2)">Suspending or revoking the license or certificate holder; or</section><section prefix="(3)">Imposing a civil penalty not to exceed $3,000 for each offense.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A health care provider acting in good faith and in accordance with a catastrophic health emergency disease surveillance and response program is immune from civil or criminal liability related to those actions, unless the health care provider acts with willful misconduct.</section>
  </text>
</law>
