<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghg" order_by="" level="1">Health - General</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghg-7-909</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>909</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, the word "licensee" means a person who is licensed by the Administration under this title to provide services.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Administration or its agent shall inspect each site or office operated by a licensee at least once annually and at any other time that the Administration considers necessary.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Administration or its agent shall evaluate periodically the performance of surveyors who carry out inspections under this subsection to ensure the consistent and uniform interpretation and application of licensing requirements.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Administration shall keep a report of each inspection.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Administration shall bring any deficiencies to the attention of:<section prefix="(1)">The executive officer of the licensee; or</section><section prefix="(2)">In the case of an intermediate care facility-intellectual disability, the State Planning Council and the State-designated protection and advocacy agency.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Administration, in conjunction with the Office of Health Care Quality, shall adopt regulations that establish a system of prioritization to respond to and investigate serious reportable incidents, as defined by the Administration, in the areas of abuse, neglect, serious injury, and medication errors that threaten the health, safety, and well-being of individuals receiving services funded by the Administration in State-operated and community programs licensed by the Administration.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Administration shall seek input from individuals with disabilities and their families, licensees, and advocacy organizations in developing the regulations, prior to publishing the regulations in the Maryland Register for public comment.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The regulations shall define and address:<section prefix="(i)">The procedures and timelines that providers must follow when reporting serious reportable incidents and deaths to the Administration and the Office of Health Care Quality;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The Department's protocol to determine the necessity to investigate a serious reportable incident that takes into account:<section prefix="1.">The severity of the incident;</section><section prefix="2.">The quality of the licensee's internal investigation; and</section><section prefix="3.">The number and frequency of serious reportable incidents reported by the licensee to the Department;</section></section><section prefix="(iii)">The specific roles and responsibilities of each governmental unit involved in any follow-up investigations that may occur due to a licensee's report of a serious reportable incident or death;</section><section prefix="(iv)">Methods of investigations, including on-site investigations;</section><section prefix="(v)">Time lines for response to serious reportable incidents and deaths and investigation of serious reportable incidents and deaths;</section><section prefix="(vi)">Time lines for issuing specified reports, including corrective action plans, to the Administration, licensee, Mortality and Quality Review Committee, Medicaid Fraud Unit, individuals receiving services from the licensee involved in the incident and their guardians or family members, and others; and</section><section prefix="(vii)">Follow-up protocols for the Office of Health Care Quality and the Administration to ensure that corrective action has been implemented by the licensee.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
