<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghg" order_by="" level="1">Health - General</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghg-19-308</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>308</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Secretary shall adopt reasonable rules and regulations that set standards of services for related institutions, accredited hospitals, nonaccredited hospitals, accredited residential treatment centers, and nonaccredited residential treatment centers in the following areas:<section prefix="(1)">The care of patients;</section><section prefix="(2)">The medical supervision of patients;</section><section prefix="(3)">The physical environment;</section><section prefix="(4)">Disease control;</section><section prefix="(5)">Sanitation;</section><section prefix="(6)">Safety; and</section><section prefix="(7)">Dietary matters.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">To assure compliance with the standards adopted under this subtitle, the Secretary shall have an inspection made:<section prefix="(i)">Of each related institution, each accredited hospital or nonaccredited hospital, and each accredited residential treatment center or nonaccredited residential treatment center for which a license is sought; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Periodically of each related institution, each accredited hospital or nonaccredited hospital, and each accredited residential treatment center or nonaccredited residential treatment center for which a license has been issued.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">At least 2 inspections a year of each related institution shall be unannounced.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The part of a building that contains part of a hospital, residential treatment center, or related institution and any outbuilding are considered part of the facility and are subject to inspection to determine occupancy status for licensing purposes.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">Subject to &#xA7; 2-1246 of the State Government Article, during each regular session of the General Assembly, the Department shall submit to the General Assembly a report on the inspections.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">
        <section prefix="(i)">An employee of the Department may not inform a hospital, residential treatment center, or related institution of any proposed inspection activity, unless the chief of the employee's division directs the employee to do so.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">An employee who violates any provision of this paragraph is guilty of a misdemeanor and on conviction is subject to a fine not exceeding $1,000 or imprisonment not exceeding 1 year or both.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
