<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghg" order_by="" level="1">Health - General</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghg-19-142</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>142</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this Part IV of this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Carrier" means:<section prefix="(1)">An insurer;</section><section prefix="(2)">A nonprofit health service plan;</section><section prefix="(3)">A health maintenance organization; or</section><section prefix="(4)">Any other person that provides health benefit plans subject to regulation by the State.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Electronic health record" means an electronic record of health-related information on an individual that:<section prefix="(1)">Includes patient demographic and clinical health information; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Has the capacity to:<section prefix="(i)">Provide clinical decision support;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Support physician order entry;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Capture and query information relevant to health care quality; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">Exchange electronic health information with and integrate the information from other sources.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Health benefit plan" means a hospital or medical policy, contract, or certificate issued by a carrier.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Health benefit plan" does not include:<section prefix="(i)">Coverage for accident or disability income insurance;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Coverage issued as a supplement to liability insurance;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Liability insurance, including general liability insurance and automobile liability insurance;</section><section prefix="(iv)">Workers' compensation or similar insurance;</section><section prefix="(v)">Automobile or property medical payment insurance;</section><section prefix="(vi)">Credit-only insurance;</section><section prefix="(vii)">Coverage for on-site medical clinics;</section><section prefix="(viii)">Dental or vision insurance;</section><section prefix="(ix)">Long-term care insurance or benefits for nursing home care, home health care, community-based care, or any combination of these;</section><section prefix="(x)">Coverage only for a specified disease or illness;</section><section prefix="(xi)">Hospital indemnity or other fixed indemnity insurance; or</section><section prefix="(xii)">The following benefits if offered as a separate insurance policy:<section prefix="1.">Medicare supplemental health insurance, as defined in &#xA7; 1882(g)(1) of the Social Security Act;</section><section prefix="2.">Coverage supplemental to the coverage provided under Chapter 55 of Title 10, U.S.C.; or</section><section prefix="3.">Similar supplemental coverage provided to coverage under an employer-sponsored plan.</section></section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Health care provider" means:<section prefix="(i)">A person who is licensed, certified, or otherwise authorized under the Health Occupations Article to provide health care in the ordinary course of business or practice of a profession or in an approved education or training program; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">A facility where health care is provided to patients or recipients, including:<section prefix="1.">A facility, as defined in &#xA7; 10-101(e) of this article;</section><section prefix="2.">A hospital, as defined in &#xA7; 19-301 of this title;</section><section prefix="3.">A related institution, as defined in &#xA7; 19-301 of this title;</section><section prefix="4.">An outpatient clinic;</section><section prefix="5.">A freestanding medical facility, as defined in &#xA7; 19-3A-01 of this title;</section><section prefix="6.">An ambulatory surgical facility, as defined in &#xA7; 19-3B-01 of this title; and</section><section prefix="7.">A nursing home, as defined in &#xA7; 19-1401 of this title.</section></section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Health care provider" does not include a health maintenance organization as defined in &#xA7; 19-701 of this title.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">"Health information exchange" means a statewide infrastructure that provides organizational and technical capabilities to enable the electronic exchange of health information between health care providers and other health services organizations authorized by the Commission.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">"Management service organization" means an organization that offers one or more hosted electronic health record solutions and other management services to multiple health care providers.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"State-regulated payor" means a carrier issuing or delivering health benefit plans in the State.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"State-regulated payor" does not include a managed care organization as defined in Title 15, Subtitle 1 of this article.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
