<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="ghg" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="10-705" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghg-10-705</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">"Abuse" means cruel or inhumane treatment that causes:</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">"Abuse" does not include:</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Sexual harassment" means intimidation, bullying, or coercion of a sexual nature or unwelcome sexual advances, requests for sexual favors, and other verbal or physical conduct of a sexual nature that tends to create a hostile or offensive environment.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A person or any employee of a facility or of the Department who receives a complaint of abuse, or who observes or has reason to believe that abuse has occurred, shall promptly report the alleged abuse to:<section prefix="(i)">An appropriate law enforcement agency; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">The administrative head of the facility, who promptly shall report the alleged abuse to an appropriate law enforcement agency.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A report:<section prefix="(i)">May be oral or written; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Shall contain as much information as the reporter is able to provide.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A State facility shall report complaints of sexual abuse and sexual harassment to the State designated protection and advocacy system.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The law enforcement agency shall:<section prefix="(i)">Investigate thoroughly each report of an alleged abuse; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Attempt to ensure the protection of the alleged victim.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The investigation shall include:<section prefix="(i)">A determination of the nature, extent, and cause of the abuse, if any;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The identity of the alleged abuser; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Any other pertinent fact or matter.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">As soon as possible, but no later than 10 working days after the completion of the investigation, the law enforcement agency shall submit a written report of its findings to the State's Attorney, the State designated protection and advocacy system, and the administrative head of the facility.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">A person shall have the immunity from liability described under &#xA7; 5-626 of the Courts and Judicial Proceedings Article for:<section prefix="(1)">Making a report under this section;</section><section prefix="(2)">Participating in an investigation arising out of a report under this section; or</section><section prefix="(3)">Participating in a judicial proceeding arising out of a report under this section.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The Administration shall ensure that State facilities:<section prefix="(1)">Develop uniform policies and procedures on making and responding to allegations of sexual abuse or sexual harassment;</section><section prefix="(2)">Ensure that staff provide assistance to patients who have requested assistance in making complaints about sexual abuse or sexual harassment;</section><section prefix="(3)">Develop and oversee training for staff on how to identify and prevent sexual abuse and sexual harassment, how to respond to complaints, and how to support victims in an appropriate manner; and</section><section prefix="(4)">Develop and oversee patient education on identifying sexual abuse and sexual harassment and on reporting incidents of sexual abuse and sexual harassment.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(g)">The Administration shall develop and implement a plan to secure the sleeping quarters of male and female patients at all State facilities that maximizes the use of available resources and infrastructure.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">Each State facility shall:<section prefix="(1)">Use evidence-based screening tools to identify on admission a patient's risk of being a victim of sexual or physical abuse, or being a sexual or physical abuser, and shall consider the assessment of risk in making any unit and room assignment;</section><section prefix="(2)">Reassign any patient accused of sexual assault promptly to another unit and ensure that any alleged victim and the alleged assailant are not housed in the same unit;</section><section prefix="(3)">Provide a patient who has a history of sexual trauma with treatment and education that is evidence-based or reflective of best practices to reduce the likelihood of the patient being the victim of repeated sexual abuse; and</section><section prefix="(4)">Ensure that designated clinical staff are trained in at least one trauma recovery modality that is considered to be a best practice.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
