<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="ghg" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="19-132" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghg-19-132</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this Part III of this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Ambulatory surgical facility" has the meaning stated in &#xA7; 19-3B-01 of this title.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Carrier" means:<section prefix="(1)">An insurer or nonprofit health service plan that holds a certificate of authority and provides health insurance policies or contracts in the State in accordance with the Insurance Article; or</section><section prefix="(2)">A health maintenance organization that holds a certificate of authority in the State.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">"Comprehensive standard health benefit plan" means the comprehensive standard health benefit plan adopted in accordance with &#xA7; 15-1207 of the Insurance Article.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Health benefit plan" means a hospital or medical policy, contract, or certificate issued by a carrier.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Health benefit plan" does not include:<section prefix="(i)">Coverage for accident or disability income insurance;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Coverage issued as a supplement to liability insurance;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Liability insurance, including general liability insurance and automobile liability insurance;</section><section prefix="(iv)">Workers' compensation or similar insurance;</section><section prefix="(v)">Automobile or property medical payment insurance;</section><section prefix="(vi)">Credit-only insurance;</section><section prefix="(vii)">Coverage for on-site medical clinics;</section><section prefix="(viii)">Dental or vision insurance;</section><section prefix="(ix)">Long-term care insurance or benefits for nursing home care, home health care, community-based care, or any combination of these;</section><section prefix="(x)">Coverage only for a specified disease or illness;</section><section prefix="(xi)">Hospital indemnity or other fixed indemnity insurance; or</section><section prefix="(xii)">The following benefits if offered as a separate insurance policy:</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">"Health care practitioner" means any individual who is licensed, certified, or otherwise authorized under the Health Occupations Article to provide health care services.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Health care provider" means:<section prefix="(i)">A person who is licensed, certified, or otherwise authorized under the Health Occupations Article to provide health care in the ordinary course of business or practice of a profession or in an approved education or training program; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">A facility where health care is provided to patients or recipients, including:</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Health care provider" includes the agents and employees of a facility who are licensed or otherwise authorized to provide health care, the officers and directors of a facility, and the agents and employees of a health care provider who are licensed or otherwise authorized to provide health care.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(h)">"Health care service" means any health or medical care procedure or service rendered by a health care practitioner that:<section prefix="(1)">Provides testing, diagnosis, or treatment of human disease or dysfunction; or</section><section prefix="(2)">Dispenses drugs, medical devices, medical appliances, or medical goods for the treatment of human disease or dysfunction.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(i)">"Hospital" has the meaning stated in &#xA7; 19-301 of this title.</section>
    <section prefix="(j)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Mandated health insurance service" means a legislative proposal or statute that would require a particular health care service to be provided or offered in a health benefit plan, by a carrier or other organization authorized to provide health benefit plans in the State.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Mandated health insurance service", as applicable to all carriers, does not include services enumerated to describe a health maintenance organization under &#xA7; 19-701(g)(2) of this title.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(k)">"Nursing facility" has the meaning stated in &#xA7; 19-1401 of this title.</section>
    <section prefix="(l)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Office facility" means the office of one or more health care practitioners in which health care services are provided to individuals.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Office facility" includes a facility that provides:<section prefix="(i)">Ambulatory surgery;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Radiological or diagnostic imagery; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">Laboratory services.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Office facility" does not include any office, facility, or service operated by a hospital and regulated under Part II of this subtitle.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(m)">"Payor" means:<section prefix="(1)">A health insurer or nonprofit health service plan that holds a certificate of authority and provides health insurance policies or contracts in the State in accordance with this article or the Insurance Article;</section><section prefix="(2)">A health maintenance organization that holds a certificate of authority in the State; or</section><section prefix="(3)">For the purposes of this Part III of this subtitle only, a person that is registered as an administrator under Title 8, Subtitle 3 of the Insurance Article.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
