<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghg" order_by="" level="1">Health - General</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghg-21-309.2</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>309.2</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">A county may establish a seasonal farmer's market producer sampling license to be required for a producer of a farm product to prepare and offer samples of the farm product for human consumption at a farmer's market or at a public festival or event.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A county seasonal farmer's market producer sampling license established under this section shall:<section prefix="(1)">Be valid at all farmer's markets in the county;</section><section prefix="(2)">Be valid at any public festival or event in the county;</section><section prefix="(3)">Be valid for the entire season for which it is issued; and</section><section prefix="(4)">Have a single fee as set by the county.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A seasonal farmer's market producer sampling licensee shall use the license only to offer samples of a farm product that has been produced by the licensee.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Department shall adopt regulations that:<section prefix="(1)">Establish eligibility for the license;</section><section prefix="(2)">Provide for the authorized uses of the license;</section><section prefix="(3)">Establish standards and approved methods under which sampling shall be conducted;</section><section prefix="(4)">Specify the duration of the season during which the license is valid; and</section><section prefix="(5)">Include other provisions that are necessary to protect public health and control foodborne illnesses.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">A county issuing a seasonal  farmer's market  producer sampling license shall adopt an ordinance that:<section prefix="(1)">Sets the fee for the license;</section><section prefix="(2)">Provides for the enforcement of provisions of law under which the license is issued; and</section><section prefix="(3)">Provides penalties for violations of provisions of law under which the license is issued.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
