<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghg" order_by="" level="1">Health - General</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghg-22-301</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>301</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Child resistant packaging" means packaging that is designed so that the average child under the age of 5 years finds it significantly difficult to open the package or to obtain a harmful amount of the contents of the package within a reasonable time, and so that it is not difficult for a normal adult to open or use.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Household substance" means any substance that is customarily used or stored by individuals in or about the household and that is:<section prefix="(1)">A hazardous substance as defined in the Federal Hazardous Substances Act;</section><section prefix="(2)">A pesticide as defined in the Federal Insecticide, Fungicide, and Rodenticide Act;</section><section prefix="(3)">A food, drug, or cosmetic as defined in the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act; or</section><section prefix="(4)">A fuel that is:<section prefix="(i)">Intended for use in the heating, cooking, or refrigeration system of a house; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Stored in a portable container.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">"Labeling" means any label or other written or graphic matter that is on or accompanies a household substance or its package.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Package" means the immediate container or wrapping of a household substance or the outer container or wrapping used in displaying a household substance to retail consumers.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Package" does not include any container or wrapping that is used only for:<section prefix="(i)">Transportation of a household substance in bulk or quantity to a manufacturer, packer, processor, or wholesale or retail distributor; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">Shipment or delivery of a household substance to a retail consumer, unless the container or wrapping is the only package or wrapping of the household substance.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">"State adopted federal regulation" means any rule or regulation adopted by the federal government under the federal Poison Prevention Packaging Act that becomes a rule or regulation of this State by automatic adoption under &#xA7; 22-303 of this subtitle.</section>
  </text>
</law>
