<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghg" order_by="ghg" level="1">Health - General</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghg-8-101</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this title the following words have the meanings indicated....</catch_line>
  <order_by>101</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this title the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Administration" means the Alcohol and Drug Abuse Administration.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Administrator" means the program director or the clinical director of an alcohol or drug abuse treatment facility or a health care facility.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">"Alcohol abuse" means a disease that is characterized by a pattern of pathological use of alcohol with repeated attempts to control its use, and with significant negative consequences in at least one of the following areas of life: medical, legal, financial, or psycho-social.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"Alcohol dependence" means a disease characterized by:<section prefix="(1)">Alcohol abuse; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Physical symptoms of withdrawal or tolerance.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">"Alcohol misuse" means:<section prefix="(1)">Unlawful use of alcohol;</section><section prefix="(2)">Alcohol abuse; or</section><section prefix="(3)">Alcohol dependence.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(g)">"Detoxification facility" means a facility that provides direct or indirect services to an acutely intoxicated individual to fulfill the physical, social, and emotional needs of the individual by:<section prefix="(1)">Monitoring the amount of alcohol and other toxic agents in the body of the individual;</section><section prefix="(2)">Managing withdrawal symptoms; and</section><section prefix="(3)">Motivating the individual to participate in the appropriate addictions treatment programs for alcohol or drug abuse.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(h)">"Director" means the Director of the Administration.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">"Drug" means:<section prefix="(1)">A controlled dangerous substance that is regulated under the Maryland Controlled Dangerous Substances Act;</section><section prefix="(2)">A prescription medication; or</section><section prefix="(3)">A chemical substance when used for unintended and harmful purposes.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(j)">"Drug abuse" means a disease which is characterized by a pattern of pathological use of a drug with repeated attempts to control the use, and with significant negative consequences in at least one of the following areas of life: medical, legal, financial, or psycho-social.</section>
    <section prefix="(k)">"Drug dependence" means a disease characterized by:<section prefix="(1)">Drug abuse; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Physical symptoms of withdrawal or tolerance.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(l)">"Drug misuse" means:<section prefix="(1)">Unlawful use of a drug;</section><section prefix="(2)">Drug abuse; or</section><section prefix="(3)">Drug dependence.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
