<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghg" order_by="" level="1">Health - General</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghg-5-804</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>804</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Committee shall consist of 18 members appointed by the Secretary, including the following:<section prefix="(1)">A licensed physician who is board certified in an appropriate specialty;</section><section prefix="(2)">A psychopharmacologist;</section><section prefix="(3)">A licensed physician on staff with the Department;</section><section prefix="(4)">Two specialists, one in the field of developmental disabilities and one in the field of mental health;</section><section prefix="(5)">Two licensed providers of community services, one for persons with developmental disabilities and one for persons with mental illnesses;</section><section prefix="(6)">Two consumers, one with a developmental disability and one with a mental illness;</section><section prefix="(7)">Two family members, one representing a consumer with a developmental disability and one representing a consumer with a mental illness;</section><section prefix="(8)">The Deputy Secretary of Behavioral Health and Disabilities or the Deputy Secretary's designee;</section><section prefix="(9)">The Director of the Office of Health Care Quality;</section><section prefix="(10)">A licensed physician representative from the Medical Examiner's Office;</section><section prefix="(11)">A licensed nurse who works with persons with developmental disabilities in a program operated by a State licensed provider in the community;</section><section prefix="(12)">A member of an advocacy group for persons with disabilities; and</section><section prefix="(13)">Two members of advocacy groups, one for persons with developmental disabilities and one for persons with mental illnesses.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The term of each member appointed under subsection (a)(1), (2), (4), (5), (6), and (10) of this section is 3 years.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A member who is appointed after a term has begun serves only for the rest of the term and until a successor is appointed.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A member may not be appointed for more than two consecutive full terms.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The terms of the members are as follows:<section prefix="(i)">One-third of the members shall be appointed for terms of 3 years commencing October 1, 2000;</section><section prefix="(ii)">One-third of the members shall be appointed for terms of 2 years commencing October 1, 2000; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">One-third of the members shall be appointed for terms of 1 year commencing October 1, 2000.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(5)">At the end of a term, a member continues to serve until a successor is appointed.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Secretary may remove any member of the Committee for good cause.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A member of the Committee:<section prefix="(1)">May not receive compensation for service on the Committee; but</section><section prefix="(2)">Is entitled to reimbursement for expenses under the Standard State Travel Regulations, as provided in the State budget.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The Committee shall be staffed by the Department.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">An employee of the Developmental Disabilities Administration or the Mental Hygiene Administration may not be a member of the Committee or any subcommittee of the Committee.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Director of the Office of Health Care Quality may not serve on a subcommittee of the Committee or vote on the disposition of an individual mortality review that was previously reviewed by the Office of Health Care Quality.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">The Secretary shall select a chairperson from among the members of the Committee.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">A quorum of the Committee shall be a majority of the appointed membership of the Committee.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">The Committee shall meet not less than three times a year.</section>
  </text>
</law>
