<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghg" order_by="ghg" level="1">Health - General</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghg-18-338.2</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this section the following words have the meanings indicated....</catch_line>
  <order_by>338.2</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Health care facility" means a facility or office where health or medical care is provided to patients by a health care provider, including:<section prefix="(i)">A hospital as defined in &#xA7; 19-301 of this article;</section><section prefix="(ii)">A facility operated by the Department or a health officer; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">The office of a health care provider.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Health care provider" means a physician, nurse, or designee of a health care facility.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">"HIV" means the human immunodeficiency virus that causes acquired immune deficiency syndrome (AIDS).</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">"Prenatal care" means obstetric and gynecologic service performed as part of a prenatal care program, including:<section prefix="(i)">Screening;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Physical examination;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Laboratory and diagnostic testing procedures and interpretation; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">Counseling.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A health care provider who provides prenatal medical care shall:<section prefix="(1)">Notify each pregnant patient that she will be tested for HIV infection as part of the routine prenatal blood tests;</section><section prefix="(2)">Advise the pregnant patient that she has the right to refuse the test for HIV infection without penalty;</section><section prefix="(3)">Obtain informed consent from the pregnant patient to test her for HIV infection;</section><section prefix="(4)">Test the patient, unless the patient declines the test;</section><section prefix="(5)">Document in the medical record if the patient declines the test;</section><section prefix="(6)">Offer an HIV test in the third trimester to a pregnant woman who was not tested earlier in her pregnancy;</section><section prefix="(7)">Consider routinely offering a repeat HIV test in the third trimester to all pregnant women:<section prefix="(i)">At health care facilities in areas of high rates of HIV prevalence; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Who are at a high risk of acquiring HIV; and</section></section><section prefix="(8)">Provide a referral for treatment and supportive services, including case management services.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A health care provider who provides labor and delivery services to pregnant women shall offer:<section prefix="(1)">A rapid HIV test to pregnant women with unknown or undocumented HIV status during labor and delivery; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Antiretroviral prophylaxis prior to receiving the results of the confirmatory test if a rapid HIV test during labor and delivery is positive.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">As part of a health care provider's patient acceptance procedures or protocol, a health care provider shall provide a pregnant woman with counseling concerning being tested for the presence of HIV as part of the woman's prenatal care program.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The counseling shall include:<section prefix="(i)">Information required for pretest counseling under &#xA7; 18-336 of this subtitle; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Education on:<section prefix="1.">The effect of a positive HIV test result on the pregnant woman and the fetus concerning the risk of transmission of HIV to the fetus; and</section><section prefix="2.">Recognized methods of reducing that risk, including the use of pharmaceuticals during pregnancy known to reduce the risk of transmission of HIV to the fetus.</section></section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as otherwise provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, the record of an HIV test performed under this section is confidential and not discoverable or admissible in evidence in any criminal, civil, or administrative action.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Provided that the identity or any other information that could readily be associated with the identity of the pregnant woman is not disclosed, the results of an HIV test performed under this section may be introduced into evidence in any criminal, civil, or administrative action, including the adjudication of a workers' compensation claim.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">A health care provider, including a health care facility, acting in good faith to provide the counseling required under subsection (d) of this section may not be held liable in any cause of action related to a woman's decision to consent or not to consent to have an HIV test.</section>
  </text>
</law>
