<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghg" order_by="" level="1">Health - General</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghg-13-203</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>203</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Advisory Council consists of 24 members appointed by the Governor.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Of the 24 Advisory Council members:<section prefix="(i)">Except as provided in paragraph (4) of this subsection, 1 member shall be appointed from a list of qualified individuals submitted to the Governor by each of the following organizations:<section prefix="1.">The American Heart Association - Mid-Atlantic, Inc.;</section><section prefix="2.">The Department;</section><section prefix="3.">The Johns Hopkins Medical Institutions;</section><section prefix="4.">The Maryland Association of County Health Officers;</section><section prefix="5.">The Maryland Hospital Association, Inc.;</section><section prefix="6.">The Maryland Nurses Association;</section><section prefix="7.">The Medical and Chirurgical Faculty of the State of Maryland;</section><section prefix="8.">The Monumental City Medical Society;</section><section prefix="9.">The Baltimore Alliance for the Prevention and Control of Hypertension and Diabetes;</section><section prefix="10.">The University of Maryland Hospital and School of Medicine;</section><section prefix="11.">The Maryland Academy of Family Physicians;</section><section prefix="12.">The American College of Emergency Physicians Maryland Chapter;</section><section prefix="13.">The American Stroke Association;</section><section prefix="14.">The American Society of Internal Medicine;</section><section prefix="15.">The Maryland Institute for Emergency Medical Services Systems;</section><section prefix="16.">The Maryland State Council on Physical Fitness;</section><section prefix="17.">The Maryland Chapter of the American College of Cardiology; and</section><section prefix="18.">The Maryland Pharmacy Association; and</section></section><section prefix="(ii)">Six shall be members of the general public.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The number of names on a list shall be 3.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">If a vacancy occurs for a reason other than expiration of the term, the Governor may appoint any individual without the list.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The term of a member is 4 years.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The terms of 16 of the members are staggered as required by the terms provided for members of the Advisory Council as of July 1, 1982.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The terms of eight of the members are staggered as required by the terms provided as of July 1, 2001.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">At the end of a term, a member continues to serve until a successor is appointed and qualifies.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">A member who is appointed after a term has begun serves only for the rest of the term and until a successor is appointed and qualifies.</section>
      <section prefix="(6)">A member who serves 2 consecutive full 4-year terms may not be reappointed for 4 years after the completion of those terms.</section>
      <section prefix="(7)">If a vacancy occurs, the Governor promptly shall appoint a successor.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
