<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghg" order_by="ghg" level="1">Health - General</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghg-8-507</section_number>
  <catch_line>Subject to the limitations in this section, a court that finds in a criminal case or during a term o...</catch_line>
  <order_by>507</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Subject to the limitations in this section, a court that finds in a criminal case or during a term of probation that a defendant has an alcohol or drug dependency may commit the defendant as a condition of release, after conviction, or at any other time the defendant voluntarily agrees to participate in treatment, to the Department for treatment that the Department recommends, even if:<section prefix="(1)">The defendant did not timely file a motion for reconsideration under Maryland Rule 4-345; or</section><section prefix="(2)">The defendant timely filed a motion for reconsideration under Maryland Rule 4-345 which was denied by the court.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Before a court commits a defendant to the Department under this section, the court shall:<section prefix="(1)">Offer the defendant the opportunity to receive treatment;</section><section prefix="(2)">Obtain the written consent of the defendant:<section prefix="(i)">To receive treatment; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">To have information reported back to the court;</section></section><section prefix="(3)">Order an evaluation of the defendant under &#xA7; 8-505 or &#xA7; 8-506 of this subtitle;</section><section prefix="(4)">Consider the report on the defendant's evaluation; and</section><section prefix="(5)">Find that the treatment that the Department recommends to be appropriate and necessary.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Immediately on receiving an order for treatment under this section, the Department shall order a report of all pending cases, warrants, and detainers for the defendant and forward a copy of the report to the court, the defendant, and the defendant's last attorney of record.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Department shall provide the services required by this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A designee of the Department may carry out any of the Department's duties under this section if appropriate funding is provided.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A court may not order that the defendant be delivered for treatment until:<section prefix="(i)">The Department gives the court notice that an appropriate treatment program is able to begin treatment of the defendant;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Any detainer based on an untried indictment, information, warrant, or complaint for the defendant has been removed; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Any sentence of incarceration for the defendant is no longer in effect.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Department shall facilitate the prompt treatment of a defendant.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">For a defendant committed for treatment under this section, a court shall order supervision of the defendant:<section prefix="(1)">By an appropriate pretrial release agency, if the defendant is released pending trial;</section><section prefix="(2)">By the Division of Parole and Probation under appropriate conditions in accordance with &#xA7;&#xA7; 6-219 through 6-225 of the Criminal Procedure Article and Maryland Rule 4-345, if the defendant is released on probation; or</section><section prefix="(3)">By the Department, if the defendant remains in the custody of a local correctional facility.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(g)">A court may order law enforcement officials, detention center staff, Department of Public Safety and Correctional Services staff, or sheriff's department staff within the appropriate local jurisdiction to transport a defendant to and from treatment under this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">The Department shall promptly report to a court a defendant's withdrawal of consent to treatment and have the defendant returned to the court within 7 days for further proceedings.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">A defendant who is committed for treatment under this section may question at any time the legality of the commitment by a petition for a writ of habeas corpus.</section>
    <section prefix="(j)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A commitment under this section shall be for at least 72 hours and not more than 1 year.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">On good cause shown by the Department, the court, or the State, the court may extend the time period for providing the necessary treatment services in increments of 6 months.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Except during the first 72 hours after admission of a defendant to a treatment program, the Department may terminate the treatment if the Department determines that:<section prefix="(i)">Continued treatment is not in the best interest of the defendant; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">The defendant is no longer amenable to treatment.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(k)">When a defendant is to be released from treatment under this section, the Department shall notify the court that ordered the treatment.</section>
    <section prefix="(l)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If a defendant leaves treatment without authorization, the responsibility of the Department is limited to the notification of the court that ordered the defendant's treatment as soon as it is reasonably possible.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Notice under this subsection shall constitute probable cause for a court to issue a warrant for the arrest of a defendant.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(m)">Nothing in this section imposes any obligation on the Department:<section prefix="(1)">To treat any defendant who knowingly and willfully declines to consent to further treatment; or</section><section prefix="(2)">In reporting to the court under this section, to include an assessment of a defendant's dangerousness to one's self, to another individual, or to the property of another individual by virtue of a drug or alcohol problem.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(n)">Time during which a defendant is held under this section for inpatient evaluation or inpatient or residential treatment shall be credited against any sentence imposed by the court that ordered the evaluation or treatment.</section>
    <section prefix="(o)">This section may not be construed to limit a court's authority to order drug treatment in lieu of incarceration under Title 5 of the Criminal Law Article.</section>
  </text>
</law>
