<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghg" order_by="" level="1">Health - General</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghg-24-205</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>205</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, "smoking" means the act of smoking or carrying a burning:<section prefix="(1)">Cigar;</section><section prefix="(2)">Cigarette;</section><section prefix="(3)">Pipe; or</section><section prefix="(4)">Other tobacco product of any kind.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Every director of a nursing home, health clinic, or physician's office shall make and carry out a plan that adequately protects the health of nonsmoking patients by regulating the smoking of tobacco products on the premises.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">An individual may not smoke in any area of a hospital.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The hospital director shall provide for the posting and placement of conspicuous signs that clearly indicate that smoking is not permitted in the hospital.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Notwithstanding the provisions of &#xA7; 24-504 of this title, this section does not apply to patients who are:<section prefix="(i)">In a facility for the treatment of mental disorders as defined in &#xA7; 10-101(e) of this article;</section><section prefix="(ii)">In a facility where the average patient stay is more than 30 days; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">In an acute care hospital and the attending physician authorizes smoking, in writing, as part of the care for the patient.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Smoking permitted under this section shall be in designated areas that are considered safe and provide nonsmoking patients, family members, and employees protection from tobacco smoke.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Smoking may not be permitted where nonsmoking patients sleep.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
