<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghg" order_by="" level="1">Health - General</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghg-7-101</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>101</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this title the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Administration" means the Developmental Disabilities Administration.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Admission" means the process by which an individual with an intellectual disability is accepted as a resident in a State residential center.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Admission" includes the physical act of the individual entering the facility.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Alternative living unit" means a residence that:<section prefix="(i)">Provides residential services for individuals who, because of developmental disability, require specialized living arrangements;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Admits not more than 3 individuals; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Provides 10 or more hours of supervision per unit, per week.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Alternative living unit" does not include a residence that is owned or rented by:<section prefix="(i)">1 or more of its residents; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">A person who:<section prefix="1.">Is an agent for any of the residents; but</section><section prefix="2.">Is not a provider of residential supervision.</section></section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"Developmental disability" means a severe chronic disability of an individual that:<section prefix="(1)">Is attributable to a physical or mental impairment, other than the sole diagnosis of mental illness, or to a combination of mental and physical impairments;</section><section prefix="(2)">Is manifested before the individual attains the age of 22;</section><section prefix="(3)">Is likely to continue indefinitely;</section><section prefix="(4)">Results in an inability to live independently without external support or continuing and regular assistance; and</section><section prefix="(5)">Reflects the need for a combination and sequence of special, interdisciplinary, or generic care, treatment, or other services that are individually planned and coordinated for the individual.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">"Director" means the Director of the Developmental Disabilities Administration.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">"External support" means:<section prefix="(1)">Periodic monitoring of the circumstances of an individual with respect to:<section prefix="(i)">Personal management;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Household management; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">The use of community resources; and</section></section><section prefix="(2)">Rendering appropriate advice or assistance that may be needed.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(h)">"Group home" means a residence that:<section prefix="(1)">Provides residential services for individuals who, because of developmental disability, require specialized living arrangements;</section><section prefix="(2)">Admits at least 4 but not more than 8 individuals; and</section><section prefix="(3)">Provides 10 or more hours of supervision per home, per week.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(i)">"Habilitation" means a process by which a provider of services enables an individual to acquire and maintain life skills to cope more effectively with the demands of the individual's own person and environment and to raise the level of the individual's mental, physical, social, and vocational functioning.</section>
    <section prefix="(j)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Individual support services" means an array of services that are designed to increase or maintain an individual's ability to live alone or in a family setting.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Individual support services" include:<section prefix="(i)">In-home assistance with meals and personal care;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Counseling;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Physical, occupational, or other therapies;</section><section prefix="(iv)">Architectural modification; and</section><section prefix="(v)">Any other services that the Administration considers appropriate to meet the individual's needs.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Individual support services" does not include full day or residential services.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(k)">"Intellectual disability" means a developmental disability that is evidenced by significantly subaverage intellectual functioning and impairment in the adaptive behavior of an individual.</section>
    <section prefix="(l)">"Live independently" means:<section prefix="(1)">For adults:<section prefix="(i)">Managing personal care, such as clothing and medication;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Managing a household, such as menu planning, food preparation and shopping, essential care of the premises, and budgeting; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Using community resources, such as commercial establishments, transportation, and services of public agencies; or</section></section><section prefix="(2)">For minors, functioning in normal settings without the need for supervision or assistance other than supervision or assistance that is age appropriate.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(m)">"Release" means a permanent, temporary, absolute, or conditional release of an individual from a State residential center.</section>
    <section prefix="(n)">"Services" means residential, day, or other services that provide for evaluation, diagnosis, treatment, care, supervision, assistance, or attention to individuals with developmental disability and that promote habilitation of these individuals.</section>
    <section prefix="(o)">"Services coordination" means a service that consists of the following 3 major functions that are designed to assist an individual in obtaining the needed services and programs that the individual desires in order to gain as much control over the individual's own life as possible:<section prefix="(1)">Planning services;</section><section prefix="(2)">Coordinating services; and</section><section prefix="(3)">Monitoring service delivery to the individual.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(p)">"State residential center" means a place that:<section prefix="(1)">Is owned and operated by this State;</section><section prefix="(2)">Provides residential services for individuals with an intellectual disability and who, because of that intellectual disability, require specialized living arrangements; and</section><section prefix="(3)">Admits 9 or more individuals with an intellectual disability.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(q)">"Treatment" means any education, training, professional care or attention, or other program that is given to an individual with developmental disability.</section>
    <section prefix="(r)">"Vocational services" means a service that provides job training and placement, supported employment and training in acceptable work behaviors, and vocationally-related social and other skills.</section>
  </text>
</law>
