<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghg" order_by="ghg" level="1">Health - General</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghg-15-805</section_number>
  <catch_line>To the extent possible, a consumer may select, manage, and control the consumer's community attendan...</catch_line>
  <order_by>805</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">To the extent possible, a consumer may select, manage, and control the consumer's community attendant services and supports.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A consumer may choose between a consumer-directed individual provider model or an agency-provider model.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Under a consumer-directed model, a consumer may use a fiscal agent to obtain services.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Attendant services and supports shall be designed to assist a consumer in accomplishing activities of daily living and health-related functions through:<section prefix="(i)">Hands-on assistance;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Supervision; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">Cueing, prompting, or reminding the consumer about an activity.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Attendant services and supports shall be provided in a consumer's home or other independent or supported living environment, including school, work, recreational, and religious settings.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Attendant services and supports may not be provided in:<section prefix="(i)">A nursing facility;</section><section prefix="(ii)">An intermediate care facility for individuals with an intellectual disability; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">A facility that provides food, shelter, and treatment services to four or more individuals unrelated to the proprietor.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Community attendant services and supports shall be available 24 hours a day, 7 days a week, and provide backup and emergency community attendant services and supports when necessary.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A consumer may select or hire anyone, including a family member, as a personal assistant.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Based on consumer recommendations, the Department may waive certain qualifications required by regulation for a personal assistant, if the personal assistant is a family member or is known and chosen by the consumer.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A family member, except the consumer's spouse, may receive medical assistance payments for providing services.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The Department shall offer a consumer training on:<section prefix="(i)">How to select, manage, and dismiss an attendant or personal assistant; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">The financial management of community attendant services and supports.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
