<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghg" order_by="" level="1">Health - General</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghg-10-609</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>609</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Application for voluntary admission of an individual to a facility may be made under this section by the individual, if the individual is 16 years old or older.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The applicant shall:<section prefix="(1)">Submit a formal, written application that contains the personal information and is on the form required by the Administration; or</section><section prefix="(2)">Informally request admission.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A facility may not admit an individual under this section unless:<section prefix="(1)">The individual has a mental disorder;</section><section prefix="(2)">The mental disorder is susceptible to care or treatment;</section><section prefix="(3)">The individual understands the nature of the request for admission;</section><section prefix="(4)">The individual is able to give continuous assent to retention by the facility; and</section><section prefix="(5)">The individual is able to ask for release.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In addition to the limitations in subsection (c) of this section, a State facility may not admit an individual who is 65 years old or older unless a geriatric evaluation team determines that there is no available, less restrictive form of care or treatment that is adequate for the needs of the individual.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If admission is denied because of the determination of the geriatric evaluation team, the team shall:<section prefix="(i)">Inform the individual; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Help the individual obtain the less restrictive form of care or treatment that the geriatric evaluation team finds would be adequate for the needs of the individual.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
