<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghg" order_by="" level="1">Health - General</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghg-2-108</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>108</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">On the Secretary's initiative or on request of a community or voluntary, nonprofit organization, the Secretary may conduct a survey to identify any area in this State that has a substantial deficiency in general or specific medical or health care facilities, staff, or services.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">In cooperation with appropriate county and State groups, the Secretary may provide the community or organization with counsel and other help to establish medical or health care facilities or services and to recruit medical or health care staff in an underserved area identified as a result of the survey conducted in accordance with subsection (a) of this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">If the counsel and other help provided under subsection (b) of this section do not result in feasible or successful proposals, or if other action is necessary to assure the public health of the underserved area, the Secretary may:<section prefix="(1)">Provide the needed health care facilities, staff, or services by contract with one or more physicians, hospitals, or other medical groups or personnel; or</section><section prefix="(2)">To facilitate the provision of State health care services to the underserved area, approve a contract or other written arrangement with a public or private health care entity, including:<section prefix="(i)">A federally qualified health center;</section><section prefix="(ii)">A health care facility, as defined in &#xA7; 19-114 of this article;</section><section prefix="(iii)">A health benefit plan or insurance carrier;</section><section prefix="(iv)">A health maintenance organization;</section><section prefix="(v)">A managed care organization; and</section><section prefix="(vi)">Any other entity that finances the provision of or delivers health care services to the area.</section></section></section>
  </text>
</law>
