<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="ghg" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="4-214" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghg-4-214</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">A certificate or record registered under this subtitle may be amended only in accordance with this subtitle and any rules and regulations that the Secretary adopts to protect the integrity and accuracy of vital records.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If any certificate of birth, death, or fetal death is amended, the facts shall be certified to the Secretary and entered on the original certificate with the date of the amendment, over the signature or initials of a designee of the Secretary and with a line drawn through the original data.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">All amendments may be stored on electronic media approved by the Secretary.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">All copies of certificates that are amended shall contain a notation that an amendment has been made.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">A record shall be maintained which identifies the evidence upon which the amendment was based, the date of the amendment, and the identity of the person making the amendment.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">Upon receipt of a certified copy of an order of a court of competent jurisdiction indicating the sex of an individual born in this State has been changed by surgical procedure and whether such individual's name has been changed, the Secretary shall amend the certificate of birth of the individual as prescribed by regulation.</section>
      <section prefix="(6)">When an informant does not submit the minimum documentation required in the regulations for amending a vital record or when the Secretary has cause to question the validity or adequacy of the applicant's sworn statements or the documentary evidence, and if the deficiencies are not corrected, the Secretary shall not amend the vital record and shall advise the applicant of the reason for this action and shall further advise the applicant of the right of appeal to the Office of Administrative Hearings.</section>
      <section prefix="(7)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Except as provided in subparagraph (ii) of this paragraph, any amendments to death certificates requested beyond 3 years or more after the death shall require a court order.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The Office of the Chief Medical Examiner may amend the cause of death on a certificate of death at any time after registration without a court order.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">On receipt of a court order that changes the name of an individual who was born in this State and on request of the individual or a parent, guardian, or legal representative of the individual, the Secretary shall amend the certificate of birth to reflect the new name.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Department may change the name on a birth certificate once without a court order if, within 12 months after the birth, the Department receives from both parents of a child:<section prefix="(i)">A written request for the change of name; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">An affidavit that has been sworn before a notary public of this State and states that they are the parents of the child and are making this request of their own free will.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
