<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="ghg" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="13-1406" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghg-13-1406</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">There is a Spinal Cord Injury Research Trust Fund.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Fund shall consist of moneys transferred to the Fund under &#xA7; 6-103.1 of the Insurance Article or received from any other lawful source.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Moneys in the Fund shall be used to make grants for spinal cord injury research that is focused on basic, preclinical, and clinical research for developing new therapies to restore neurological function in individuals with spinal cord injuries.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">For the purpose specified in paragraph (1) of this subsection, a grant may include an award to or for:<section prefix="(i)">A public or private entity;</section><section prefix="(ii)">A university researcher;</section><section prefix="(iii)">A research institution;</section><section prefix="(iv)">Private industry;</section><section prefix="(v)">A clinical trial;</section><section prefix="(vi)">A supplement to an existing charitable or private industry grant;</section><section prefix="(vii)">A matching fund;</section><section prefix="(viii)">A fellowship in spinal cord injury research;</section><section prefix="(ix)">A research meeting concerning spinal cord injury research; or</section><section prefix="(x)">Any other recipient or purpose which the Board determines is consistent with the purpose specified in paragraph (1) of this subsection.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Fund is a continuing, nonlapsing fund, not subject to &#xA7; 7-302 of the State Finance and Procurement Article.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The Fund shall be used exclusively to offset the actual documented direct costs of fulfilling the statutory and regulatory duties of the Board under this subtitle.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The Department shall pay the indirect costs the Board incurs in fulfilling the statutory and regulatory duties of the Board under this subtitle.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Any unspent portions of the Fund may not be transferred or revert to the General Fund of the State, but shall remain in the Fund to be used for the purpose specified in subsection (c) of this section.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The chairman of the Board or the designee of the chairman shall administer the Fund.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The Legislative Auditor shall audit the accounts and transactions of the Fund as provided in &#xA7; 2-1220 of the State Government Article.</section>
  </text>
</law>
