<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghg" order_by="ghg" level="1">Health - General</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghg-10-923</section_number>
  <catch_line>Application for placement of a child or adolescent in a private therapeutic group home may be made u...</catch_line>
  <order_by>923</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Application for placement of a child or adolescent in a private therapeutic group home may be made under this section by:<section prefix="(1)">An individual who is 16 years old or older;</section><section prefix="(2)">A parent or guardian on behalf of the child or adolescent;</section><section prefix="(3)">With the consent of the parent or guardian of the child or adolescent, a psychiatrist or psychologist who treats the child or adolescent;</section><section prefix="(4)">On behalf of a child or adolescent, a local department of social services that has custody or guardianship of the child or adolescent under &#xA7; 3-819 of the Courts Article;</section><section prefix="(5)">The Department of Education or the local education agency with the consent of a parent or guardian;</section><section prefix="(6)">On behalf of a child or adolescent, the Department of Juvenile Services when the Department has custody or guardianship of the child or adolescent under &#xA7; 3-819 of the Courts Article; or</section><section prefix="(7)">The circuit court of a county sitting as the juvenile court.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The applicant shall submit a formal, written application to the Director that contains the personal information and is on the form required by the Administration.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A private therapeutic group home may not accept an individual under this section unless:<section prefix="(1)">The individual is under the age of 18 years;</section><section prefix="(2)">The individual has a mental disorder;</section><section prefix="(3)">The individual, because of the mental disorder, requires residential services not available in the home;</section><section prefix="(4)">The individual needs 24-hour supervision in a structured private therapeutic group home;</section><section prefix="(5)">The individual is or should be receiving treatment for the mental disorder; and</section><section prefix="(6)">There is no less restrictive form of treatment that is consistent with the welfare and safety of the child or adolescent.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Within 60 days after the Director receives an application for placement of a child or adolescent in a private therapeutic group home, the Director or the county health officer shall:<section prefix="(1)">Determine whether the child or adolescent meets the requirements for placement under this section; and</section><section prefix="(2)">If so:<section prefix="(i)">Approve the application for placement in a private therapeutic group home; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Determine the date of placement in a private therapeutic group home in accordance with the plan submitted under &#xA7; 10-925 of this subtitle.</section></section></section>
  </text>
</law>
