<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghg" order_by="ghg" level="1">Health - General</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghg-19-219</section_number>
  <catch_line>The Commission may review costs and rates and make any investigation that the Commission considers n...</catch_line>
  <order_by>219</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Commission may review costs and rates and make any investigation that the Commission considers necessary to assure each purchaser of health care facility services that:<section prefix="(1)">The total costs of all hospital services offered by or through a facility are reasonable;</section><section prefix="(2)">The aggregate rates of the facility are related reasonably to the aggregate costs of the facility; and</section><section prefix="(3)">The rates are set equitably among all purchasers or classes of purchasers without undue discrimination or preference.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">To carry out its powers under subsection (a) of this section, the Commission may review and approve or disapprove the reasonableness of any rate that a facility sets or requests.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A facility shall charge for services only at a rate set in accordance with this subtitle.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">In determining the reasonableness of rates, the Commission may take into account objective standards of efficiency and effectiveness.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">To promote the most efficient and effective use of health care facility services and, if it is in the public interest and consistent with this subtitle, the Commission may promote and approve alternate methods of rate determination and payment that are of an experimental nature.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this subsection, "base hospital rate" means the aggregate value to participating commercial health insurance carriers of the substantial, available, and affordable coverage purchaser differential as determined by the Commission for the calendar year 2002.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Commission, in accordance with this subsection, shall calculate the amount of funds necessary to operate and administer the Maryland Health Insurance Plan established under Title 14, Subtitle 5 of the Insurance Article.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The Commission shall determine the percentage of total net patient revenue received in calendar year 2002 by all hospitals for which the Commission approved hospital rates that is represented by the base hospital rate.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The percentage under subparagraph (i) of this paragraph shall be determined by dividing the base hospital rate by the total net patient revenue received in calendar year 2002 by all hospitals for which the Commission approved hospital rates.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(4)">On or before May 1 of each year, the Commission shall:<section prefix="(i)">Determine the amount of funding to allocate to the Maryland Health Insurance Plan by multiplying the percentage determined under paragraph (3) of this subsection by the value of the total net patient revenues received in the immediately preceding State fiscal year by all hospitals for which rates were approved by the Commission; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Determine the share of total funding owed by each hospital for which rates have been approved by the Commission proportionate to the percentage of the base hospital rate attributable to each hospital.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(5)">Each hospital shall remit monthly one-twelfth of the amount determined under paragraph (4)(ii) of this subsection to the Maryland Health Insurance Plan Fund.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Commission shall adjust hospital rates to ensure that the assessment collected under subsection (d) of this section is revenue neutral to each hospital.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Commission may not consider the assessment required under subsection (d) of this section in determining:<section prefix="(i)">The reasonableness of rates under this section; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">Hospital financial performance.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
