<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghg" order_by="" level="1">Health - General</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghg-10-406</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>406</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The following State facilities shall be maintained under the direction of the Administration:<section prefix="(1)">Clifton T. Perkins Hospital Center;</section><section prefix="(2)">Eastern Shore Hospital Center;</section><section prefix="(3)">Regional Institutes for Children and Adolescents - Baltimore and Rockville;</section><section prefix="(4)">Springfield Hospital Center;</section><section prefix="(5)">Spring Grove Hospital Center; and</section><section prefix="(6)">Thomas B. Finan Hospital Center.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">As a facility is built or transferred to the Administration, the facility may be made a State facility.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">By January 1, 1985, the Department shall adopt rules and regulations for admission to all Regional Institutes for Children and Adolescents in cooperation with representatives from the advisory committees of the Regional Institutes for Children and Adolescents, the mental health advisory committees in each region, the local education agencies, and the Mental Health Association of Maryland.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">In determining these rules and regulations, the Department shall provide that no bona fide candidate for admission may be rejected solely because of residence outside the regular catchment area served by the institution.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">In determining these rules and regulations, the Department shall provide that candidates for admission who reside in the regular catchment area served by the institution shall be granted priority in admissions to the institution.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Beginning in fiscal year 2007, the Department may not bill a local board of education for any services provided by the State at a regional institute for children and adolescents.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Notwithstanding paragraph (1) of this subsection:<section prefix="(i)">Beginning in fiscal year 2007, the Department shall continue to provide the same scope of services at regional institutes for children and adolescents that were provided as of January 1, 2005; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">A local board of education may make a contribution toward the cost of services provided by the State at a regional institute for children and adolescents.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
