<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghg" order_by="" level="1">Health - General</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghg-21-416</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>416</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">While it is effective, a bobtailer permit authorizes the holder, on a Grade A milk route that the holder operates or controls, to distribute Grade A pasteurized milk products that the holder purchased from a Grade A distributor or a Grade A milk processor.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">While it is effective, a certified industry dairy farm inspector permit authorizes the holder to inspect dairy farms in accordance with this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">While it is effective, a distribution station permit authorizes the holder, for redistribution and sale, whether from a fixed location or from a vehicle:<section prefix="(1)">To receive Grade A pasteurized milk products;</section><section prefix="(2)">To store Grade A pasteurized milk products; and</section><section prefix="(3)">To transfer Grade A pasteurized milk products for redistribution and sale.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">While it is effective, a milk processor permit authorizes the holder:<section prefix="(i)">To collect raw milk;</section><section prefix="(ii)">To handle raw milk;</section><section prefix="(iii)">To process raw milk;</section><section prefix="(iv)">To pasteurize raw milk;</section><section prefix="(v)">To store pasteurized milk;</section><section prefix="(vi)">To bottle or package pasteurized milk;</section><section prefix="(vii)">To prepare pasteurized milk for distribution; and</section><section prefix="(viii)">To distribute pasteurized milk.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">While it is effective, a milk processor - farmstead cheese producer permit authorizes the holder:<section prefix="(i)">To perform all the functions set forth in paragraph (1) of this subsection; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">To produce farmstead cheese.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">While it is effective, a milk producer permit authorizes the holder:<section prefix="(1)">To operate a dairy farm; and</section><section prefix="(2)">To sell raw milk from the dairy farm to:<section prefix="(i)">A receiving station;</section><section prefix="(ii)">A transfer station; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">A milk plant.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">While it is effective, a bulk milk hauler/sampler permit authorizes the holder, while operating a milk tank truck:<section prefix="(1)">To receive raw milk products from a milk producer, milk plant, receiving station, or transfer station;</section><section prefix="(2)">To transport raw milk products that have been received from a milk producer, milk plant, receiving station, or transfer station; and</section><section prefix="(3)">To deliver raw milk products that have been received from a milk producer, milk plant, receiving station, or transfer station.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(g)">While it is effective, a receiving station permit authorizes the holder:<section prefix="(1)">To collect raw milk;</section><section prefix="(2)">To cool raw milk;</section><section prefix="(3)">To process raw milk;</section><section prefix="(4)">To store raw milk; and</section><section prefix="(5)">To prepare raw milk for delivery to a milk plant.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(h)">While it is effective, a transfer station permit authorizes the holder to operate a place where raw milk is transferred between milk tank trucks for eventual delivery to a milk plant.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">A permittee authorized to perform a function under this subtitle shall only exercise that authority as to the classification for which it is designated, except that:<section prefix="(1)">Unless otherwise specified in this subtitle, a milk producer permittee with a Grade A classification authorized to perform a function under this subtitle may exercise that authority for manufactured milk; and</section><section prefix="(2)">A milk processor, receiving station, or transfer station with a manufactured milk classification may exercise that authority using Grade A raw milk.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(j)">While it is effective, a milk transportation company permit authorizes the holder to operate one or more milk tank trucks.</section>
  </text>
</law>
