<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghg" order_by="ghg" level="1">Health - General</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghg-15-124.2</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this section, "Program" means the Maryland Medbank Program established under this section....</catch_line>
  <order_by>124.2</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, "Program" means the Maryland Medbank Program established under this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">There is a Maryland Medbank Program.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The purpose of the Program is to improve the health status of individuals throughout the State who lack prescription drug coverage by providing access to medically necessary prescription drugs through patient assistance programs sponsored by pharmaceutical drug manufacturers.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Subject to paragraph (2) of this subsection, the Program shall be administered by the Medbank of Maryland, Inc.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Medbank of Maryland, Inc. shall contract with one or more government or nonprofit entities to operate the Program.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Program shall be funded through a grant provided by the Department.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Program funds may be used in part to:<section prefix="(i)">Purchase interim supplies of prescription drugs for enrollees who have applied to participate in a manufacturer's patient assistance program but have not yet received the approved prescription drug; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Distribute medication to enrollees who have been approved to participate in a manufacturer's patient assistance program.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Medbank of Maryland, Inc. shall ensure that the Program is available to residents in each of the following geographic regions of the State:<section prefix="(i)">Western Maryland;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The Eastern Shore;</section><section prefix="(iii)">The Baltimore metropolitan area;</section><section prefix="(iv)">The Maryland counties in the Washington, D.C. metropolitan area; and</section><section prefix="(v)">Southern Maryland, including Anne Arundel County.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Medbank of Maryland, Inc. shall be the central coordinating office for the State.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">Eligibility for the Program shall be limited only by the criteria established by pharmaceutical manufacturers for their patient assistance programs.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Department shall require detailed financial reports at least quarterly from Medbank of Maryland, Inc.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Medbank of Maryland, Inc. shall release funds to the entities that operate the Program as needed and justified by the quarterly reports filed in accordance with paragraph (1) of this subsection.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(i)">On or before December 1, 2001, and annually thereafter, the Department and Medbank of Maryland, Inc. shall report to the Governor and, in accordance with &#xA7; 2-1246 of the State Government Article, to the General Assembly, on the status of the Maryland Medbank Program established under this section, including:<section prefix="(1)">The number and demographic characteristics of the State residents served by the Program;</section><section prefix="(2)">The types and retail value of prescription drugs accessed through the Program;</section><section prefix="(3)">The nature and extent of outreach performed to inform State residents of the assistance available through the Program; and</section><section prefix="(4)">The total volume and retail value of each brand name drug, by manufacturer, accessed through the Program.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
