<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghg" order_by="" level="1">Health - General</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghg-4-201</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>201</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Attending physician" means the physician in charge of the patient's care for the illness or condition which resulted in death.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"County registrar" means the registrar of vital records for a county.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Dead body" means:<section prefix="(i)">A dead human body; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">Parts or bones of a human body if, from their condition, an individual reasonably may conclude that death has occurred.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Dead body" does not include an amputated part.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"Fetal death" means death of a product of human conception, before its complete expulsion or extraction from the mother, regardless of the duration of the pregnancy, as indicated by the fact that, after the expulsion or extraction, the fetus does not breathe or show any other evidence of life, such as heart beat, pulsation of the umbilical cord, or definite movement of voluntary muscle.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">"File" means to present for registration any certificate, report, or other record including records transmitted by approved electronic media, including facsimile, of birth, death, fetal death, adoption, marriage, or divorce for which this subtitle provides and to have the Secretary accept the record.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">"Filing date" means the date a vital record is accepted for registration by the Secretary.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">"Final disposition" means the burial, cremation, or other final disposition of a body or fetus.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">"Institution" means any public or private establishment:<section prefix="(1)">To which individuals are committed by law; or</section><section prefix="(2)">That provides to 2 or more unrelated individuals:<section prefix="(i)">Any inpatient or outpatient medical, surgical, or diagnostic care or treatment; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">Any nursing, custodial, or domiciliary care.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(j)">"Live birth" means the complete expulsion or extraction of a product of human conception from the mother, regardless of the period of gestation, if, after the expulsion or extraction, it breathes or shows any other evidence of life, such as heart beat, pulsation of the umbilical cord, or definite movement of voluntary muscle, whether or not the umbilical cord is cut or the placenta is attached.</section>
    <section prefix="(k)">"Mortician" means a funeral director, mortician, or other person who is authorized to make final disposition of a body.</section>
    <section prefix="(l)">"Physician" means a person authorized or licensed to practice medicine or osteopathy pursuant to the laws of this State.</section>
    <section prefix="(m)">"Registration" means acceptance by the Secretary and incorporation in the records of the Department of any certificate, report, or other record of birth, death, fetal death, adoption, marriage, divorce, or dissolution or annulment of marriage for which this subtitle provides.</section>
    <section prefix="(n)">"Vital record" means a certificate or report of birth, death, fetal death, marriage, divorce, dissolution or annulment of marriage, adoption, or adjudication of paternity that is required by law to be filed with the Secretary.</section>
    <section prefix="(o)">"Vital statistics" means the data derived from certificates and reports of birth, death, fetal death, marriage, divorce, dissolution or annulment of marriage, and reports related to any of these certificates and reports.</section>
  </text>
</law>
