<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghg" order_by="ghg" level="1">Health - General</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghg-19-301</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated....</catch_line>
  <order_by>301</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Accredited hospital" means a hospital accredited by the Joint Commission on Accreditation of Healthcare Organizations.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Accredited residential treatment center" means a residential treatment center that is accredited by the Joint Commission on Accreditation of Healthcare Organizations.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">"Apartment unit" means any space, in a residential building, that is enclosed and self-contained and has a sanitary environment, if the space includes:<section prefix="(1)">2 or more rooms;</section><section prefix="(2)">A direct exit to a thoroughfare or to a common element leading to a thoroughfare;</section><section prefix="(3)">Facilities for living, sleeping, and eating; and</section><section prefix="(4)">At least the following facilities for cooking:<section prefix="(i)">Storage space for food and utensils;</section><section prefix="(ii)">A refrigerator;</section><section prefix="(iii)">A cook top; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">Adequate electrical capacity and outlets for small appliances.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Domiciliary care" means services that are provided to aged or disabled individuals in a protective, institutional or home-type environment.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Domiciliary care" includes:<section prefix="(i)">Shelter;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Housekeeping services;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Board;</section><section prefix="(iv)">Facilities and resources for daily living; and</section><section prefix="(v)">Personal surveillance or direction in the activities of daily living.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">"Hospital" means an institution that:<section prefix="(1)">Has a group of at least 5 physicians who are organized as a medical staff for the institution;</section><section prefix="(2)">Maintains facilities to provide, under the supervision of the medical staff, diagnostic and treatment services for 2 or more unrelated individuals; and</section><section prefix="(3)">Admits or retains the individuals for overnight care.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(g)">"License" means a license issued by the Secretary:<section prefix="(1)">To operate a hospital in this State;</section><section prefix="(2)">To operate a related institution in this State; or</section><section prefix="(3)">To operate a residential treatment center in this State.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(h)">"Limited service hospital" means a health care facility that:<section prefix="(1)">Is licensed as a hospital on or after January 1, 1999;</section><section prefix="(2)">Changes the type or scope of health care services offered by eliminating the facility's capability to admit or retain patients for overnight hospitalization;</section><section prefix="(3)">Retains an emergency or urgent care center; and</section><section prefix="(4)">Complies with the regulations adopted by the Secretary under &#xA7; 19-307.1 of this subtitle.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(i)">"Nonaccredited hospital" means a hospital not accredited by the Joint Commission on Accreditation of Healthcare Organizations.</section>
    <section prefix="(j)">"Nonaccredited residential treatment center" means a residential treatment center that is not accredited by the Joint Commission on Accreditation of Healthcare Organizations.</section>
    <section prefix="(k)">"Nursing care" means service for a patient that is:<section prefix="(1)">Ordered by a physician; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Provided or supervised by a registered or practical nurse who is licensed to practice in this State.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(l)">"Nursing facility" means a related institution that provides nursing care for 2 or more unrelated individuals.</section>
    <section prefix="(m)">"Person" includes this State or a county or municipal corporation.</section>
    <section prefix="(n)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Personal care" means a service that an individual normally would perform personally, but for which the individual needs help from another because of advanced age, infirmity, or physical or mental limitation.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Personal care" includes:<section prefix="(i)">Help in walking;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Help in getting in and out of bed;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Help in bathing;</section><section prefix="(iv)">Help in dressing;</section><section prefix="(v)">Help in feeding; and</section><section prefix="(vi)">General supervision and help in daily living.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(o)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Related institution" means an organized institution, environment, or home that:<section prefix="(i)">Maintains conditions or facilities and equipment to provide domiciliary, personal, or nursing care for 2 or more unrelated individuals who are dependent on the administrator, operator, or proprietor for nursing care or the subsistence of daily living in a safe, sanitary, and healthful environment; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Admits or retains the individuals for overnight care.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Related institution" does not include a nursing facility or visiting nurse service that is conducted only by or for adherents of a bona fide church or religious organization, in accordance with tenets and practices that include reliance on treatment by spiritual means alone for healing.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(p)">"Residential treatment center" means a psychiatric institution that provides campus-based intensive and extensive evaluation and treatment of children and adolescents with severe and chronic emotional disturbances who require a self-contained therapeutic, educational, and recreational program in a residential setting.</section>
    <section prefix="(q)">"Unrelated individual" means anyone who is not:<section prefix="(1)">A child, grandchild, parent, grandparent, sibling, stepparent, stepchild, or spouse of the proprietor; or</section><section prefix="(2)">An in-law of any of these individuals.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
