<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghg" order_by="ghg" level="1">Health - General</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghg-21-301</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated....</catch_line>
  <order_by>301</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Bottled water" means any water that is sealed in bottles, packages, or other containers and offered for sale for human consumption, including bottled mineral water.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Bottled water" does not include:<section prefix="(i)">Soft drinks; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">A beverage that is labeled "club soda" or "seltzer water".</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b-1)">"Cottage food business" means a business that:<section prefix="(1)">Produces or packages cottage food products in a residential kitchen;</section><section prefix="(2)">Sells the cottage food products in accordance with &#xA7; 21-330.1 of this subtitle and regulations adopted by the Department; and</section><section prefix="(3)">Has annual revenues from the sale of cottage food products in an amount not exceeding $25,000.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b-2)">"Cottage food product" means a nonhazardous food, as specified in regulations adopted by the Department, that is sold at a farmer's market or public event in accordance with &#xA7; 21-330.1 of this subtitle and regulations adopted by the Department.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Crab meat" means the edible meat of steamed or cooked crabs.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">"Crab meat plant" means:<section prefix="(1)">A picking plant; or</section><section prefix="(2)">A place where crab meat is heat-treated to improve the keeping quality of the crab meat.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"Excluded organization" means:<section prefix="(1)">A bona fide nonprofit fraternal, civic, war veterans', religious, or charitable organization or corporation that does not serve food to the public more often than 4 days per week except that once a year an organization may serve food to the public for up to 14 consecutive days; and</section><section prefix="(2)">A volunteer fire company that does not serve food to the public more often than 4 days per week except that once a year a volunteer fire company may serve food to the public for up to 30 consecutive days.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">"Food establishment" means:<section prefix="(1)">A food service facility; or</section><section prefix="(2)">A food processing plant.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Food processing plant" means any place used for, or in connection with, the commercial manufacturing, preparing, processing, packaging, canning, freezing, storing, distributing, labeling, or holding of food or drink for human consumption.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Food processing plant" includes:<section prefix="(i)">A bakery plant;</section><section prefix="(ii)">A cannery;</section><section prefix="(iii)">A confectionery plant;</section><section prefix="(iv)">A crab meat picking plant;</section><section prefix="(v)">A food manufacturing plant;</section><section prefix="(vi)">A food warehouse or distribution center;</section><section prefix="(vii)">A frozen food processing plant;</section><section prefix="(viii)">An ice manufacturing plant;</section><section prefix="(ix)">A shellfish plant;</section><section prefix="(x)">A soft drink manufacturing plant; or</section><section prefix="(xi)">A bottled water plant.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Food processing plant" does not include:<section prefix="(i)">A warehouse or distribution center that:<section prefix="1.">Does not process food; and</section><section prefix="2.">Stores only sealed containers of whole bean, ground or instant coffee, leaf or instant teas, nondairy dehydrated whiteners, sugar, or sugar-free sweeteners; or</section></section><section prefix="(ii)">A cottage food business.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(h)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Food service facility" means:<section prefix="(i)">A place where food or drink is prepared for sale or service on the premises or elsewhere; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">Any operation where food is served to or provided for the public, with or without charge.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Food service facility" does not include:<section prefix="(i)">A kitchen in a private home where food is prepared at no charge for guests in the home, for guests at a social gathering, or for service to unemployed, homeless, or other disadvantaged populations;</section><section prefix="(ii)">A food preparation or serving area where only nonpotentially hazardous food, as defined by the United States Food and Drug Administration, is prepared or served only by an excluded organization;</section><section prefix="(iii)">A location in a farmer's market or at a public festival or event where raw agricultural products, as defined in &#xA7; 21-304(d)(1)(iii) of this subtitle, are sold; or</section><section prefix="(iv)">A cottage food business.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(i)">"License" means a license issued by the Department under this subtitle to operate a food establishment.</section>
    <section prefix="(j)">"Picking plant" means a place where:<section prefix="(1)">Crabs are steamed or cooked;</section><section prefix="(2)">Crab meat is picked from crabs; and</section><section prefix="(3)">Crab meat is packed for sale.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(j-1)">"Public festival or event" means a planned gathering that is open to the public and is regulated by the State or local jurisdiction in which it takes place.</section>
    <section prefix="(j-2)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Semipermanent food service facility" means a food service facility that:<section prefix="(i)">Is built at a location other than where it operates;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Is transported as a complete unit that does not require a building permit to install on the location at which it operates;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Has no indoor seating for patrons; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">When serving cooked food, serves only foods cooked for immediate service.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Semipermanent food service facility" does not include a food service facility that is a mechanically, electrically, manually, or otherwise propelled vehicle operating on land or water that moves as part of its routine operation to:<section prefix="(i)">Change location for sales;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Obtain food and other supplies;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Fill potable water supply holding tanks;</section><section prefix="(iv)">Empty wastewater holding tanks; or</section><section prefix="(v)">Provide for the cleaning and sanitation of equipment and utensils.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(k)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided under paragraph (2) of this subsection, "soft drink" means any nonalcoholic beverage.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Soft drink" does not include:<section prefix="(i)">Apple cider;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Soft drinks that are manufactured on the premises of a soda fountain and used at that soda fountain; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">Bottled water.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(l)">"Surimi" means an intermediate manufactured seafood product derived from minced fish meat, washed to remove water-soluble protein and blood or other undesirable components and mixed with additives to enhance its frozen storage and functional characteristics.</section>
  </text>
</law>
