<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghg" order_by="ghg" level="1">Health - General</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghg-15-134</section_number>
  <catch_line>If the Department applies for a Medical Assistance Program waiver, modifies or amends an existing Me...</catch_line>
  <order_by>134</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">If the Department applies for a Medical Assistance Program waiver, modifies or amends an existing Medical Assistance Program waiver, or amends the Medicaid State Plan, the Department shall give notice of the application or amendment by:<section prefix="(1)">Publication in the Maryland Register; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Submission of the application or amendment to the Medicaid Advisory Committee for discussion at a Medicaid Advisory Committee meeting.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">For 30 days following publication of any notice published under subsection (a) of this section, the Department shall:<section prefix="(1)">Make the Medical Assistance Program waiver application or amendment to the Medicaid State Plan available to the public during business hours; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Provide an opportunity to receive public comments on the Medical Assistance Program waiver application or amendment to the Medicaid State Plan.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">If the Department submits to the federal Centers for Medicare and Medicaid Services an amendment to the Medicaid State Plan or Medical Assistance Program waiver application, the Department shall submit a copy of the amendment or waiver application to the members of the Medicaid Advisory Committee no later than five business days after the Department submits the amendment or waiver application to the federal Centers for Medicare and Medicaid Services.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Subject to the limitations of the State budget and notwithstanding any other provision of law, the following are effective on the date specified in a Maryland Register notice:<section prefix="(1)">Amendments or modifications to the Medicaid State Plan or Medical Assistance Program; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Medical Assistance Program waiver applications and modifications.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
