<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghg" order_by="ghg" level="1">Health - General</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghg-24-1404</section_number>
  <catch_line>The allocation and use of State funds under this subtitle are subject to the following terms and con...</catch_line>
  <order_by>1404</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The allocation and use of State funds under this subtitle are subject to the following terms and conditions:<section prefix="(1)">State funds may be used only for projects approved by the Secretary under this subtitle.</section><section prefix="(2)"><section prefix="(i)">Any federal grant that is available for this purpose shall be applied first to a project approved under this subtitle; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">In this subtitle, community development block grants shall be considered as local matching funds and may not be considered as federal grant funds.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A State grant shall provide up to 50% of the eligible cost remaining after the federal grant has been applied, except as provided in subsection (c) of this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">For projects designated under federal regulations, State plans, or departmental regulations as eligible for poverty area funding, a State grant may cover up to 75% of the eligible cost remaining after any federal grants have been applied.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The amount of the State grant for any project shall be determined after consideration of:<section prefix="(1)">All eligible applications;</section><section prefix="(2)">The total amount of unallocated State funds available at the time the application is received; and</section><section prefix="(3)">The priorities of area need established by the Department.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">No portion of the proceeds of a State grant may be used:<section prefix="(i)">To further sectarian religious instruction; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">In connection with the design, acquisition, or construction of any buildings used or to be used as a place of sectarian religious worship or instruction.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Upon the request of the Board of Public Works, the applicant shall submit evidence satisfactory to the Board of Public Works that none of the proceeds of the grant have been or are being used for a purpose prohibited by this subtitle.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
