<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="ghg" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="18-213.2" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghg-18-213.2</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">"Body fluids" means:</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">"Body fluids" does not include saliva, stool, nasal secretions, sputum, tears, urine, or vomitus.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Contagious disease or virus" means:<section prefix="(i)">Human immunodeficiency virus (HIV);</section><section prefix="(ii)">Meningococcal meningitis;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Tuberculosis;</section><section prefix="(iv)">Mononucleosis;</section><section prefix="(v)">Any form of viral hepatitis, including but not limited to hepatitis A, B, C, D, E, F, and G;</section><section prefix="(vi)">Diphtheria;</section><section prefix="(vii)">Plague;</section><section prefix="(viii)">Hemorrhagic fevers; or</section><section prefix="(ix)">Rabies.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">"Contact exposure" means as between a decedent and a first responder:<section prefix="(i)">Percutaneous contact with blood or body fluids;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Mucocutaneous contact with blood or body fluids;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Open wound, including dermatitis, exudative lesions, or chapped skin, contact with blood or body fluids for a prolonged period; or</section><section prefix="(iv)">Intact skin contact with large amounts of blood or body fluids for a prolonged period.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(5)">"Correctional institution" means a place of detention or correctional confinement operated by or for the State or a local government.</section>
      <section prefix="(6)">
        <section prefix="(i)">"Correctional officer" means a member of a correctional unit who is charged with and actually performs those duties that relate to the investigation, care, custody, control, or supervision of individuals confined to places of incarceration.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">"Correctional officer" includes any sheriff, warden, superintendent, or other individual having the equivalent title.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(7)">"First responder" means a:<section prefix="(i)">Fire fighter;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Emergency medical technician;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Rescue squad member;</section><section prefix="(iv)">Law enforcement officer;</section><section prefix="(v)">Correctional officer; or</section><section prefix="(vi)">Sworn member of the State Fire Marshal's office.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(8)">"Law enforcement officer" means any individual who, in an official capacity, is authorized by law to make arrests and who is a member of one of the following law enforcement agencies:<section prefix="(i)">The Department of State Police;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The Baltimore City Police Department;</section><section prefix="(iii)">The police department, bureau, or force of any county;</section><section prefix="(iv)">The police department, bureau, or force of any incorporated city or town;</section><section prefix="(v)">The office of the sheriff of any county;</section><section prefix="(vi)">The police department, bureau, or force of any bicounty agency or constituent institution of the University System of Maryland, Morgan State University, St. Mary's College, or of any institution under the jurisdiction of the Maryland Higher Education Commission;</section><section prefix="(vii)">The Maryland Aviation Administration police force of the Department of Transportation, the Maryland Transit Administration police force of the Department of Transportation, the Maryland Transportation Authority police force, and the Maryland Port Administration police force of the Department of Transportation;</section><section prefix="(viii)">The law enforcement officers of the Department of Natural Resources;</section><section prefix="(ix)">The Field Enforcement Bureau of the Comptroller's Office; or</section><section prefix="(x)">The Internal Investigative Unit of the Department of Public Safety and Correctional Services.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(9)">"Medical care facility" means a hospital, or a health care facility of a correctional institution.</section>
      <section prefix="(10)">"Physician performing a postmortem examination" means any of the following persons who perform a postmortem examination on a decedent:<section prefix="(i)">The Chief Medical Examiner; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">The Chief Medical Examiner's designee.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">If, while transporting a person to a medical care facility or while acting in the performance of duty, a first responder comes into contact exposure while treating or transporting a person who dies at the scene or while being transported and who is subsequently determined, as a result of information obtained in conjunction with a postmortem examination by the Chief Medical Examiner or a designee of the Chief Medical Examiner to have had a contagious disease or virus at the time of death, the physician performing the postmortem examination shall notify the first responder and the first responder's employer or the employer's designee of the first responder's possible contact exposure to the contagious disease or virus.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The notification required under subsection (b) of this section shall:<section prefix="(1)">Be made within 48 hours of confirmation of the determination that the deceased person had a contagious disease or virus at the time of death;</section><section prefix="(2)">Include subsequent written confirmation of possible contact exposure to the contagious disease or virus;</section><section prefix="(3)">Be conducted in a manner that will protect the confidentiality of the deceased person; and</section><section prefix="(4)">To the extent possible, be conducted in a manner that will protect the confidentiality of the first responder.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The written confirmation required under subsection (c)(2) of this section shall constitute compliance with this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">A medical care facility or physician performing a postmortem examination acting in good faith to provide notification in accordance with this section is not liable in any cause of action related to a breach of patient confidentiality.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">A medical care facility or physician performing a postmortem examination acting in good faith to provide notification in accordance with this section is not liable in any cause of action for:<section prefix="(1)">The failure to give the required notice if the first responder fails to properly initiate the notification procedures developed by the medical care facility and the Chief Medical Examiner under subsection (g) of this section; or</section><section prefix="(2)">The failure of the employer or the employer's designee to subsequently notify the first responder of the possible contact exposure to a contagious disease or virus.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The State Fire Marshal, the Chief Medical Examiner, and each fire department, rescue squad company, medical care facility, correctional institution, and law enforcement agency in the State shall develop written procedures for the implementation of this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">On request, the State Fire Marshal and each fire department, rescue squad company, medical care facility, correctional institution, and law enforcement agency shall make copies of the procedures developed in this subtitle available to employees, employee unions, volunteer associations, and the Secretary.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(h)">A person covered under subsection (a)(5), (6), (7), (8), (9), and (10) of this section may not refuse to treat or transport a deceased person because the deceased person was HIV positive at the time of death.</section>
  </text>
</law>
