<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="ghg" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="7-703" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghg-7-703</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">There is a Family Support Services Program.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Administration shall contract with private nonprofit community-based organizations for the provision of family support services in each county of the State.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Administration shall base the amount of a grant to a county upon the needs of the eligible families in each locality in accordance with the data available through the Family Support Services Consortium Project for localities of comparable size.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Administration shall implement a sliding payment scale for reimbursement from families financially able to pay for all or part of the services under the Program.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Before using Program funds, the Program shall coordinate and assist any eligible child and family in receiving services available under existing programs including:<section prefix="(i)">Respite care under Title 7, Subtitle 2 of the Human Services Article;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Day care services;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Homemaker services;</section><section prefix="(iv)">Personal care;</section><section prefix="(v)">Services to families with children under &#xA7; 4-402 of the Family Law Article;</section><section prefix="(vi)">Children's medical services under &#xA7; 15-125 of this article;</section><section prefix="(vii)">Attendant care services under Title 7, Subtitle 4 of the Human Services Article; and</section><section prefix="(viii)">Other applicable federal and local programs.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Program shall assist in providing family support services that are not otherwise available.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
