<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghg" order_by="ghg" level="1">Health - General</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghg-10-632</section_number>
  <catch_line>Any individual proposed for involuntary admission under Part III of this subtitle shall be afforded ...</catch_line>
  <order_by>632</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Any individual proposed for involuntary admission under Part III of this subtitle shall be afforded a hearing to determine whether the individual is to be admitted to a facility or a Veterans' Administration hospital as an involuntary patient or released without being admitted.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The hearing shall be conducted within 10 days of the date of the initial confinement of the individual.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The hearing may be postponed for good cause for no more than 7 days, and the reasons for the postponement shall be on the record.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A decision shall be made within the time period provided in paragraph (1) of this subsection.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Secretary shall:<section prefix="(1)">Adopt rules and regulations on hearing procedures; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Designate an impartial hearing officer to conduct the hearings.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The hearing officer shall:<section prefix="(1)">Consider all the evidence and testimony of record; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Order the release of the individual from the facility unless the record demonstrates by clear and convincing evidence that at the time of the hearing each of the following elements exist as to the individual whose involuntary admission is sought:<section prefix="(i)">The individual has a mental disorder;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The individual needs in-patient care or treatment;</section><section prefix="(iii)">The individual presents a danger to the life or safety of the individual or of others;</section><section prefix="(iv)">The individual is unable or unwilling to be voluntarily admitted to the facility;</section><section prefix="(v)">There is no available less restrictive form of intervention that is consistent with the welfare and safety of the individual; and</section><section prefix="(vi)">If the individual is 65 years old or older and is to be admitted to a State facility, the individual has been evaluated by a geriatric evaluation team and no less restrictive form of care or treatment was determined by the team to be appropriate.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The parent, guardian, or next of kin of an individual involuntarily admitted under this subtitle:<section prefix="(1)">Shall be given notice of the hearing on the admission; and</section><section prefix="(2)">May testify at the hearing.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
