<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="ghg" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="4-215" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghg-4-215</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, "cemetery" includes a crematory or other place for final disposition.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Within 72 hours after death or after delivery in a fetal death and before final disposition or removal of the body or fetus from this State, the mortician who first takes custody of the body or fetus shall obtain a burial-transit permit.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If the death or fetal death certificate is on a multicopy form, one copy of which is designated specifically as a "burial-transit permit" and is signed by the attending physician or medical examiner, that copy shall provide for the later entry of final disposition information and serves as a burial-transit permit.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A person in charge of a cemetery may not permit the final disposition of a body or fetus unless it is accompanied by a burial-transit permit.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The person in charge of a cemetery shall:<section prefix="(i)">Write on the permit the date of final disposition;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Sign the permit; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Within 10 days after final disposition, return the permit to the Secretary.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">If there is no person in charge of the cemetery, the mortician shall fill out the burial-transit permit.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A burial-transit permit issued by any state or a foreign country is sufficient authority for transit through this State or final disposition in any cemetery in this State.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A permit for disinterment and reinterment is required before the disinterment of human remains if reinterment is not to be made in the same cemetery. The Secretary or a health officer shall issue the permit after receipt of an application on the form that the Secretary requires.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If all human remains in a cemetery are to be disinterred for purposes of relocation or abandonment of the cemetery, one application is sufficient for that purpose.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Department shall keep a record of each permit issued for the disinterment and reinterment of human remains.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">Except as provided in paragraph (5) of this subsection, the Department may not disclose or allow public inspection of information in a permit record about the location of the site of a disinterment or reinterment if a local burial sites advisory board or the Director of the Maryland Historical Trust determines that:<section prefix="(i)">The site is historic property, as defined in &#xA7; 5A-301 of the State Finance and Procurement Article; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Disclosure would create a substantial risk of harm, theft, or destruction to the site.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(5)">The Department may not deny inspection of a permit record to:<section prefix="(i)">The owner of the site of the disinterment or reinterment;</section><section prefix="(ii)">A governmental entity that has the power of eminent domain; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">The spouse, domestic partner, next of kin, or appointed personal representative of the deceased whose human remains have been disinterred or reinterred.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
