<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghg" order_by="" level="1">Health - General</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghg-19-1415</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>1415</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, "change in condition" means a significant change in the resident's physical, mental, or psychological status including:<section prefix="(1)">Life-threatening conditions such as heart attack or stroke;</section><section prefix="(2)">Clinical complications such as:<section prefix="(i)">Development of a pressure sore;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Onset of recurrent periods of delirium;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Onset of recurrent urinary tract infection;</section><section prefix="(iv)">Onset of depression; or</section><section prefix="(v)">Onset of aggressive or inappropriate behavior;</section></section><section prefix="(3)">The need to discontinue a medication or treatment because of:<section prefix="(i)">Adverse consequences; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">The need to begin a new form of treatment;</section></section><section prefix="(4)">Evaluation at or admission to a hospital; and</section><section prefix="(5)">Accidents that result in injury having the potential for requiring a physician's intervention.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Consistent with State and federal confidentiality laws and in a timely manner, a nursing home shall notify a resident and, if applicable, the resident's representative or interested family member of any:<section prefix="(1)">Change in condition;</section><section prefix="(2)">Adverse event that may result in a change in condition;</section><section prefix="(3)">Outcome or care that results in an unanticipated consequence; or</section><section prefix="(4)">Corrective action, if appropriate.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">If the Department determines that a nursing home failed to notify a resident, resident's representative, or interested family member under subsection (b) of this section, the Department shall require as part of a plan of correction that the nursing home notify the resident, the resident's representative, or interested family member as soon as possible.</section>
  </text>
</law>
