<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghg" order_by="ghg" level="1">Health - General</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghg-19-705.2</section_number>
  <catch_line>With the advice of the Secretary, the Commissioner shall adopt regulations to establish a system for...</catch_line>
  <order_by>705.2</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">With the advice of the Secretary, the Commissioner shall adopt regulations to establish a system for the receipt and timely investigation of complaints of members and subscribers of health maintenance organizations concerning the operation of any health maintenance organization in this State.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The complaint system shall include:<section prefix="(1)">A procedure for the timely acknowledgment of receipt of a complaint;</section><section prefix="(2)">Criteria that the Secretary shall adopt by regulation for determining the appropriate level of investigation for a complaint concerning quality of care, including:<section prefix="(i)">A determination as to whether the member or subscriber with the complaint previously attempted to have the complaint resolved; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">A determination as to whether a complaint should be sent to the member's or subscriber's health maintenance organization for resolution prior to investigation under the provisions of this section; and</section></section><section prefix="(3)">A procedure for the referral of quality of care complaints to the Secretary for an appropriate investigation.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">If a determination is made to investigate a complaint under the provisions of this section prior to the member or subscriber attempting to otherwise resolve the complaint, the reasons for that determination shall be documented.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Notice of the complaint system established under the provisions of this section shall be included in all contracts between a health maintenance organization and a member or subscriber of a health maintenance organization.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">For quality of care complaints referred to the Secretary for investigation under subsection (b)(3) of this section, the Secretary shall report to the Commissioner in a timely manner on the results and findings of each investigation.</section>
  </text>
</law>
