<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghg" order_by="ghg" level="1">Health - General</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghg-19-319.2</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this section, "facility" means a special psychiatric hospital or an acute general care hospital w...</catch_line>
  <order_by>319.2</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, "facility" means a special psychiatric hospital or an acute general care hospital with separately identified inpatient psychiatric service.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">As a condition of licensure, each facility shall adopt written policies and procedures to implement the requirements of &#xA7;&#xA7; 10-701 through 10-709 of this article. The policies and procedures:<section prefix="(i)">May expand the rights provided in &#xA7;&#xA7; 10-701 through 10-709 of this article;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Shall provide for a mechanism for patients and others to report suspected violations of &#xA7;&#xA7; 10-701 through 10-709 of this article to a designated official of the hospital;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Shall provide a system for investigating suspected violations; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">Shall ensure that there is a timely appropriate response to any suspected violation.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Secretary may inspect any document necessary to ensure compliance with this subsection and &#xA7;&#xA7; 10-701 through 10-709 of this article.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">If a hospital that is a facility fails to adopt and implement the policies and procedures required by this subsection or maintains a continuing pattern of conditions or practices in knowing violation of &#xA7;&#xA7; 10-701 through 10-709 of this article, the Secretary may impose the following penalties, but only after the Secretary has satisfied the conditions in &#xA7; 19-360 of this subtitle:<section prefix="(i)">Delicensure of the specialty psychiatric hospital;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Delicensure of the separately identified psychiatric service of the acute general care hospital; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">A fine not to exceed $500 per day for each day the violation continues.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
