<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="ghg" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="7-717" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghg-7-717</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this part, "low intensity support services" means a program designed to:<section prefix="(i)">Enable a family to provide for the needs of a child or an adult with developmental disability living in the home; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">Support an adult with developmental disability living in the community.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Low intensity support services" includes the services and items listed in &#xA7;&#xA7; 7-701(d) and 7-706(c) of this subtitle.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">There is a Low Intensity Support Services Program in the Administration.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Low intensity support services shall be flexible to meet the needs of individuals or families.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Administration shall establish a cap of no less than $3,000 of low intensity support services per individual per fiscal year to a qualifying individual.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Administration may waive the cap on low intensity support services provided under paragraph (1) of this subsection.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">An individual seeking low intensity support services is not required to:<section prefix="(i)">Submit an application to the Department as provided in &#xA7; 7-403 of this title; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">Complete an application for the Medical Assistance Program if the low intensity support services will be provided to a minor.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Department may develop a simplified application process for low intensity support services.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The Administration shall deliver services to an eligible individual seeking low intensity support services dependent on the availability and allocation of funds provided by the Administration.</section>
  </text>
</law>
