<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghg" order_by="" level="1">Health - General</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghg-15-122.2</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>122.2</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, "converted funds" means the amount received in payment by a person from an insurer for the cost of health services provided to a child which was not used to reimburse the Department for Medicaid costs incurred.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Each year the Department may refer to the Central Collection Unit of the Department of Budget and Management for certification to the State Comptroller the name of any person who has received converted funds for the interception of any State tax refund.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Department shall notify the person certified under subsection (b) of this section that a certification has been made by the Department.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The certification by the Central Collection Unit shall include, if known:<section prefix="(1)">The full name of the person certified and any other names known to be used by that person;</section><section prefix="(2)">The address and the Social Security number of the person certified; and</section><section prefix="(3)">The amount of the converted funds.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The State Comptroller shall:<section prefix="(1)">Pay to the Department any income tax refund due to the person certified in an amount not more than the amount certified by the Department;</section><section prefix="(2)">Pay to the person certified any part of the income tax refund over the amount of the converted funds; and</section><section prefix="(3)">Notify the person certified of:<section prefix="(i)">The amount paid to the Department; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">The rights of the person certified under subsection (b) of this section.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">On receipt of a notice of intercept from the State Comptroller, any person certified by the Department who disputes the existence or amount of the converted funds may file an appeal in accordance with Title 10 of the State Government Article.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If the Department finds that an excessive amount was withheld from the person's income tax refund, the Department promptly shall pay to the taxpayer the excess amount withheld.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">The Comptroller shall honor refund interception requests in the following order:<section prefix="(1)">A refund interception request to collect an unpaid State, county, or municipal tax;</section><section prefix="(2)">A refund interception request under &#xA7; 10-113 of the Family Law Article for arrears of support payments;</section><section prefix="(3)">A refund interception request for converted funds under this subtitle; and</section><section prefix="(4)">Any other refund interception request.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(h)">The Secretary and the State Comptroller may adopt regulations to carry out this section.</section>
  </text>
</law>
