<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghg" order_by="ghg" level="1">Health - General</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghg-4-302</section_number>
  <catch_line>A health care provider shall:...</catch_line>
  <order_by>302</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">A health care provider shall:<section prefix="(1)">Keep the medical record of a patient or recipient confidential; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Disclose the medical record only:<section prefix="(i)">As provided by this subtitle; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">As otherwise provided by law.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The provisions of this subtitle do not apply to information:<section prefix="(1)">Not kept in the medical record of a patient or recipient that is related to the administration of a health care facility, including:<section prefix="(i)">Risk management;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Quality assurance; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Any activities of a medical or dental review committee that are confidential under the provisions of Title 4, Subtitle 5 and Title 14, Subtitle 5 of the Health Occupations Article and any activities of a pharmacy review committee;</section></section><section prefix="(2)">Governed by the federal confidentiality of alcohol and drug abuse patient records regulations, 42 C.F.R. Part 2 and the provisions of &#xA7; 8-601(c) of this article; or</section><section prefix="(3)">Governed by the developmental disability confidentiality provisions in &#xA7;&#xA7; 7-1008 through 7-1011 of this article.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A health care provider may disclose directory information about a patient without the authorization of a person in interest, except if the patient has instructed the health care provider in writing not to disclose directory information.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A person to whom a medical record is disclosed may not redisclose the medical record to any other person unless the redisclosure is:<section prefix="(1)">Authorized by the person in interest;</section><section prefix="(2)">Otherwise permitted by this subtitle;</section><section prefix="(3)">Permitted under &#xA7; 1-202(b) or (c) of the Human Services Article; or</section><section prefix="(4)">Directory information.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, a person may not disclose by sale, rental, or barter any medical record.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">This subsection shall not prohibit the transfers of medical records relating to the transfer of ownership of a health care practice or facility if the transfer is in accord with the ethical guidelines of the applicable health care profession or professions.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The provisions of this subtitle may not be construed to constitute an exception to the reporting requirements of Title 5, Subtitle 7 and Title 14, Subtitle 3 of the Family Law Article.</section>
  </text>
</law>
