<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghg" order_by="ghg" level="1">Health - General</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghg-2-605</section_number>
  <catch_line>If the State intervenes and proceeds with an action filed under &#xA7; 2-604 of this subtitle and the St...</catch_line>
  <order_by>605</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If the State intervenes and proceeds with an action filed under &#xA7; 2-604 of this subtitle and the State prevails, the court shall award the person initiating the action an amount that is:<section prefix="(i)">Not less than 15% and not more than 25% of the proceeds of the action or settlement of the claim; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Proportional to the amount of time and effort that the person substantially contributed to the final resolution of the civil action.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">If the court finds that the action is based primarily on disclosures of specific information relating to allegations or transactions in a criminal, civil, or administrative hearing, in a legislative or administrative report, hearing, audit, or investigation, or from the news media, the court may make an award to the person initiating the action that:<section prefix="1.">The court considers appropriate, taking into account the significance of the information and the role of the person initiating the action in advancing the case to litigation; and</section><section prefix="2.">Does not exceed 10% of the proceeds of the action.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The information described in subparagraph (i) of this paragraph does not include information disclosed and provided by the person initiating the action.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Any payment to a person under paragraph (1) or (2) of this subsection shall be made from the proceeds of the action.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">
        <section prefix="(i)">In addition to the amount provided under paragraphs (1) and (2) of this subsection, a court may award the person initiating the action:<section prefix="1.">An amount for reasonable expenses that the court finds to have been necessarily incurred; and</section><section prefix="2.">Reasonable attorney's fees and costs.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">In determining the amount of any award under subparagraph (i) of this paragraph, the court shall consider the amount of any penalties and damages recovered in the action and any other factor as justice may require.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">Any expenses, fees, and costs awarded under this paragraph shall be awarded against the defendant.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If a court finds that the action is initiated by a person who planned and initiated or otherwise deliberately participated in the violation on which the action was based, the court may, to the extent it considers appropriate, reduce the share of the proceeds of the action that the person otherwise would have received under this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">In reducing the share of the proceeds of the person initiating the action under this subsection, the court shall consider:<section prefix="(i)">The role of the person in advancing the case to litigation; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Any relevant circumstances relating to the underlying violation.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">If the person initiating a civil action under &#xA7; 2-604 of this subtitle is convicted of criminal conduct arising from the person's participation in the violation on which the action was based prior to a final determination of the action, the person:<section prefix="1.">Shall be dismissed from the action; and</section><section prefix="2.">May not receive any share of the proceeds of the action.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The dismissal of the person initiating the action in accordance with this paragraph does not prejudice the right of the State to continue the action.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(4)">If the person initiating a civil action under &#xA7; 2-604 of this subtitle is convicted of criminal conduct arising from the person's participation in the violation on which the action was based after the proceeds from the action are awarded to that person, the court shall order the person to repay the proceeds previously awarded.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A court may award reasonable attorney's fees and expenses to a defendant and against the person initiating the action if:<section prefix="(1)">The defendant prevails in the action; and</section><section prefix="(2)">The court finds that the claim of the person initiating the action was brought primarily for purposes of harassment or otherwise brought in bad faith.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
