<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghg" order_by="" level="1">Health - General</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghg-24-508</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>508</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Subject to subsection (c) of this section and except as  provided in subsection (d) of this section, a person who violates a  provision of this subtitle or a regulation adopted under &#xA7; 24-507(a)  of this subtitle:<section prefix="(1)">For a first violation, shall be issued a written  reprimand by the Secretary or the Secretary's designee;</section><section prefix="(2)">For a second violation, is subject to a civil penalty  of $100; and</section><section prefix="(3)">For each subsequent violation, is subject to a civil  penalty not less than $250.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Secretary may waive a penalty established under  subsection (a) of this section, giving consideration to factors that  include:<section prefix="(1)">The seriousness of the violation; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Any demonstrated good faith measures to comply  with the provisions of this subtitle.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This subsection does not apply to an alleged  violation of subsection (d) of this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">It is an affirmative defense to a complaint brought  against a person for a violation of a provision of this subtitle or a  regulation adopted under this subtitle that the person or an  employee of the person:<section prefix="(i)">Posted a "No Smoking" sign as required under &#xA7;  24-506 of this subtitle;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Removed all ashtrays and other smoking  paraphernalia from all areas where smoking is prohibited; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">If the violation occurred in a bar, tavern, or  restaurant:<section prefix="1.">Refused to seat or serve any individual  who was smoking in a prohibited area; and</section><section prefix="2.">If the individual continued to smoke after  an initial warning, asked the individual to leave the establishment.</section></section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">An employer who discharges or discriminates against an employee because that employee has made a complaint, has given information to the Department in accordance with this subtitle, has caused to be instituted or is about to cause to be instituted a proceeding under this subtitle, or has testified or is about to testify in a proceeding under this subtitle, shall be deemed in violation of this subtitle and shall be subject to a civil penalty of at least $2,000 but not more than $10,000 for each violation.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">An employee may not:<section prefix="(i)">Make a groundless or malicious complaint  under this subtitle to the Secretary or an authorized  representative of the Secretary;</section><section prefix="(ii)">In bad faith, bring an action under this  subtitle; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">In bad faith, testify in an action under this  subtitle or a proceeding that relates to the subject of this  subtitle.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Secretary may bring an action for injunctive  relief and damages against a person who violates the provisions of  paragraph (1) of this subsection.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">A penalty collected by the Secretary under this section  shall be paid to the Cigarette Restitution Fund established under &#xA7;  7-317 of the State Finance and Procurement Article.</section>
  </text>
</law>
