<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="ghg" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="7-1010" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghg-7-1010</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Except as otherwise expressly provided in this section, a licensee may not disclose any record that the licensee keeps on an individual who has been served by the licensee, unless the individual gives written, informed consent to the disclosure.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Subject to the limitations of this subsection, a licensee shall disclose a record of an individual who is served by a licensee to:<section prefix="(i)">The individual with developmental disability, if:</section><section prefix="(ii)">A parent or guardian of the person with developmental disability who is:</section><section prefix="(iii)">A lawyer or other individual who is authorized:</section><section prefix="(iv)">To the executive director or a designee of the executive director of the State-designated protection and advocacy agency, if:</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A licensee shall comply within 14 days after an individual with developmental disability or a person who is authorized to act on behalf of that individual, asks in writing:<section prefix="(i)">To receive a copy of a record; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">To see and copy the record disclosed.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">If a licensee refuses to disclose a record under subsection (b)(1)(i) of this section, the executive officer or administrative head of a licensee shall apply, within 10 working days after the refusal, to the circuit court for the county where the individual making the request resides or where the site of services to the individual occurred for an order to permit the executive officer or administrative head of the licensee to continue to refuse disclosure to the individual with developmental disability.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A licensee shall disclose a record that is sought:<section prefix="(1)">By the staff of the licensee to carry out a purpose for which the record is kept;</section><section prefix="(2)">By any other person who provides or coordinates services in accordance with the individual's plan of habilitation;</section><section prefix="(3)">By the Director or a designee of the Director; and</section><section prefix="(4)">By a person to further the purposes of:<section prefix="(i)">A medical review committee;</section><section prefix="(ii)">An accreditation board or commission;</section><section prefix="(iii)">A licensing agency that is authorized by statute to review records;</section><section prefix="(iv)">A court order;</section><section prefix="(v)">A representative of the Division of Reimbursement of the Department;</section><section prefix="(vi)">An auditor of the Department;</section><section prefix="(vii)">An auditor of the Office of Legislative Audits of the Department of Legislative Services; or</section><section prefix="(viii)">The Clients' Rights Committee of the licensee unless the individual with developmental disability objects.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A licensee may require a person who asks for a copy of a record to pay a reasonable fee.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The fee may not exceed the cost of copying the record.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except for a disclosure that is made to the staff for its routine use under subsection (d)(1) of this section, a licensee shall keep a list of all disclosures of a record.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The list shall state:<section prefix="(i)">The date, nature, and purpose of each disclosure; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">The name and address of each person to whom the disclosure is made.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
