<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghg" order_by="ghg" level="1">Health - General</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghg-13-810</section_number>
  <catch_line>// EFFECTIVE UNTIL SEPTEMBER 30, 2016 PER CHAPTER 94 OF 2011 //...</catch_line>
  <order_by>810</order_by>
  <text>// EFFECTIVE UNTIL SEPTEMBER 30, 2016 PER CHAPTER 94 OF 2011 //<section prefix="(a)">The findings and recommendations of the Commission shall be considered each year in the development of the budgets of the Department, the Developmental Disabilities Administration, and the Mental Hygiene Administration.</section><section prefix="(b)"><section prefix="(1)">The Mental Hygiene Administration and the Developmental Disabilities Administration shall respond to the recommendations of the Commission in writing within 30 days after the report required in &#xA7; 13-809 of this subtitle has been issued.</section><section prefix="(2)">The written response of the Mental Hygiene Administration and the Developmental Disabilities Administration shall include:<section prefix="(i)">An explanation of the actions being taken to implement the recommendations of the Commission; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">An explanation of why no action has been taken on the recommendations of the Commission.</section></section></section><section prefix="(c)"><section prefix="(1)">The Mental Hygiene Administration and the Developmental Disabilities Administration shall provide to the Commission, in advance of or at the same time as they are provided to the public, copies of any new or revised regulations regarding payment rates for community services.</section><section prefix="(2)">The Board of Nursing shall provide to the Commission, in advance of or at the same time as they are provided to the public, copies of any new or revised regulations that would be expected to impact on the costs incurred by providers of community services that are paid for by the Mental Hygiene Administration or the Developmental Disabilities Administration.</section></section></text>
</law>
