<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="ghg" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="24-304" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghg-24-304</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section, "child care article" means an empty bottle or cup to be filled with food or liquid that is designed or intended by a manufacturer to be used by a child under the age of 4 years.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If a federal law regulating the use of bisphenol-A in child care articles is enacted, "child care article" shall be defined as specified in the federal law.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">On or after January 1, 2012, a person may not manufacture, knowingly sell, or distribute in commerce any child care article containing bisphenol-A.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Except as provided in subsection (g) of this section, on or after July 1, 2014:<section prefix="(1)">The State may not purchase infant formula in containers containing more than 0.5 parts per billion of bisphenol-A; and</section><section prefix="(2)">A person may not manufacture, knowingly sell, or distribute in commerce a container of infant formula containing more than 0.5 parts per billion of bisphenol-A.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">In complying with subsections (b) and (c) of this section, a person:<section prefix="(1)">Shall use a safe and legal alternative when replacing bisphenol-A; and</section><section prefix="(2)">May not replace bisphenol-A with:<section prefix="(i)">Carcinogens rated by the United States Environmental Protection Agency as Group A, B, or C carcinogens; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">Reproductive toxicants that cause birth defects, reproductive harm, or developmental harm as identified by the United States Environmental Protection Agency.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">A person that violates this section is guilty of a misdemeanor and on conviction is subject to a fine not exceeding $10,000 for each violation.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">On or before January 1, 2012, the Department shall adopt regulations to carry out subsection (b) of this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">If the Secretary certifies that the safety concerns for bisphenol-A are resolved by additional research or if implementation of subsection (c) of this section would adversely affect the health or well-being of children or adults, the Secretary may suspend implementation of subsection (c) of this section.</section>
  </text>
</law>
