<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghg" order_by="ghg" level="1">Health - General</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghg-10-1303</section_number>
  <catch_line>This subsection applies whenever the executive authority of any state:...</catch_line>
  <order_by>1303</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This subsection applies whenever the executive authority of any state:<section prefix="(i)">Demands of the Governor, a fugitive within the purview of &#xA7; 10-1302 of this subtitle; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Produces a copy of the commitment, decree, or other judicial process and proceedings, certified as authentic by the governor or chief magistrate of the state whence the person so charged has fled, with an affidavit made before a proper officer showing the person to be a fugitive.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Governor shall:<section prefix="(i)">Cause a person subject to this subsection to be apprehended and secured, if found in this State;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Cause immediate notice of the apprehension to be given to the executive authority making a demand for the person, or to the agent of the executive authority appointed to receive the fugitive; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Cause the fugitive to be delivered to the agent when the agent appears.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">If an agent does not appear within 30 days from the time of the apprehension, the fugitive may be discharged.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">All costs and expenses incurred in the apprehending, securing, maintaining, and transmitting the fugitive to the state making the demand for the fugitive shall be paid by the demanding state.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Any agent so appointed who receives the fugitive into custody shall be empowered to transmit the fugitive to the state from which the fugitive has fled.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">On application of any person interested, the Governor may demand the return to this State of any fugitive within the purview of this subtitle.</section>
  </text>
</law>
