<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghg" order_by="" level="1">Health - General</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghg-19-303</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>303</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Commission" means the Health Services Cost Review Commission.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Community benefit" means an activity that is intended to address community needs and priorities primarily through disease prevention and improvement of health status, including:<section prefix="(i)">Health services provided to vulnerable or underserved populations such as Medicaid, Medicare, or Maryland Children's Health Program enrollees;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Financial or in-kind support of public health programs;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Donations of funds, property, or other resources that contribute to a community priority;</section><section prefix="(iv)">Health care cost containment activities; and</section><section prefix="(v)">Health education, screening, and prevention services.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">"Community needs assessment" means the process by which unmet community health care needs and priorities are identified.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">In identifying community health care needs, a nonprofit hospital:<section prefix="(1)">Shall consider, if available, the most recent community needs assessment developed by the Department or the local health department for the county in which the nonprofit hospital is located;</section><section prefix="(2)">May consult with community leaders and local health care providers; and</section><section prefix="(3)">May consult with any appropriate person that can assist the hospital in identifying community health needs.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Each nonprofit hospital shall submit an annual community benefit report to the Health Services Cost Review Commission detailing the community benefits provided by the hospital during the preceding year.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The community benefit report shall include:<section prefix="(i)">The mission statement of the hospital;</section><section prefix="(ii)">A list of the initiatives that were undertaken by the hospital;</section><section prefix="(iii)">The cost to the hospital of each community benefit initiative;</section><section prefix="(iv)">The objectives of each community benefit initiative;</section><section prefix="(v)">A description of efforts taken to evaluate the effectiveness of each community benefit initiative;</section><section prefix="(vi)">A description of gaps in the availability of specialist providers to serve the uninsured in the hospital; and</section><section prefix="(vii)">A description of the hospital's efforts to track and reduce health disparities in the community that the hospital serves.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Commission shall compile the reports required under subsection (c) of this section and issue an annual Nonprofit Hospital Community Health Benefit Report.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">In addition to the information required under paragraph (1) of this subsection, the Nonprofit Hospital Community Health Benefit Report shall contain a list of the unmet community health care needs identified in the most recent community needs assessment prepared by the Department or local health department for each county.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Nonprofit Hospital Community Health Benefit Report shall be made available to the public free of charge.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The Commission shall submit a copy of the annual Nonprofit Hospital Community Health Benefit Report, subject to &#xA7; 2-1246 of the State Government Article, to the House Health and Government Operations Committee and the Senate Finance Committee.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The Commission shall adopt regulations, in consultation with representatives of nonprofit hospitals, that establish:<section prefix="(1)">A standard format for reporting the information required under this section;</section><section prefix="(2)">The date on which nonprofit hospitals must submit the annual community benefit reports; and</section><section prefix="(3)">The period of time that the annual community benefit report must cover.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
