<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="ghg" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="5-608.1" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghg-5-608.1</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, "health care facility" means:<section prefix="(1)">An assisted living program;</section><section prefix="(2)">A home health agency;</section><section prefix="(3)">A hospice;</section><section prefix="(4)">A hospital;</section><section prefix="(5)">A kidney dialysis center; or</section><section prefix="(6)">A nursing home.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The Department, in conjunction with the Maryland Institute for Emergency Medical Services Systems and the State Board of Physicians, shall develop and revise periodically a "Medical Orders for Life-Sustaining Treatment" form and instructions for completing and using the form.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The "Medical Orders for Life-Sustaining Treatment" form and the instructions for its completion and use shall be developed in consultation with:</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The "Medical Orders for Life-Sustaining Treatment" form developed under paragraph (1) of this subsection shall be suitable for containing a physician's or nurse practitioner's written medical orders relating to a patient's medical condition, including:<section prefix="(i)">The use of life-sustaining procedures;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The use of medical tests;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Transfer of the patient to a hospital from a nonhospital setting; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">Any other matter considered appropriate by the Department to implement treatment preferences and orders regarding life-sustaining treatments across health care settings.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The "Medical Orders for Life-Sustaining Treatment" form is not an advance directive.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A health care facility shall:<section prefix="(i)"/><section prefix="(ii)">Complete a "Medical Orders for Life-Sustaining Treatment" form:</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">When a health care facility updates or completes a "Medical Orders for Life-Sustaining Treatment" form under paragraph (1) of this subsection, the health care facility shall:<section prefix="(i)">Offer the patient, health care agent, or surrogate decision maker the opportunity to participate in updating or completing the form;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Note in the medical record when a patient, health care agent, or surrogate decision maker declines to participate in updating or completing the form, indicating the date and with whom the form was discussed;</section><section prefix="(iii)">On request of the patient, offer any physician or nurse practitioner selected by the patient the opportunity to participate in updating or completing the form; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">Inform the patient, health care agent, or surrogate decision maker that the form will become a part of the patient's medical record and can be accessed through the procedures used to access a medical record.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Except as provided for a treatment that has been certified as medically ineffective in accordance with &#xA7; 5-611 of this subtitle, the "Medical Orders for Life-Sustaining Treatment" form shall be consistent with:<section prefix="(i)">The known decisions of:</section><section prefix="(ii)">Any known advance directive of the patient if the patient is incapable of making an informed decision.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A health care provider other than a health care facility may choose to use a "Medical Orders for Life-Sustaining Treatment" form.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A health care provider who chooses to use a "Medical Orders for Life-Sustaining Treatment" form shall offer a patient, health care agent, or surrogate decision maker the opportunity to participate in the completion of the form.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The original or a copy of a "Medical Orders for Life-Sustaining Treatment" form shall:<section prefix="(1)">Be kept by a health care provider in the patient's medical record;</section><section prefix="(2)">Physically accompany the patient or be transmitted electronically or by facsimile in accordance with the instructions for the use of the form when the patient is transferred to a health care facility; and</section><section prefix="(3)">Be given to the patient, health care agent, or surrogate decision maker within 48 hours of completion of the form or sooner if the patient is transferred or discharged.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">Except as provided in &#xA7; 5-611 or &#xA7; 5-613 of this subtitle, a health care facility shall comply with all medical orders contained in a "Medical Orders for Life-Sustaining Treatment" form regardless of whether the physician or nurse practitioner who signed the form has admitting privileges or is otherwise credentialed at the health care facility.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">In the event of a conflict between more than one "Medical Orders for Life-Sustaining Treatment" form, the most recent form shall be followed.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">A health care provider may rely in good faith on the presumed validity of a "Medical Orders for Life-Sustaining Treatment" form.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Department shall adopt regulations that specify the "Medical Orders for Life-Sustaining Treatment" form and the instructions for the completion and use of the form that are developed as required by subsection (b) of this section, including instructions on how a "Medical Orders for Life-Sustaining Treatment" form is revised or revoked.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Regulations adopted under paragraph (1) of this subsection shall be consistent with the Health Care Decisions Act.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(j)">The Department shall make the "Medical Orders for Life-Sustaining Treatment" form and the instructions for the completion and use of the form, including instructions on how the form is revised or revoked, available on its Web site and may print and distribute the form, the instructions, and training materials.</section>
  </text>
</law>
