<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="ghg" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="19-111" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghg-19-111</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Fund" means the Maryland Health Care Commission Fund.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Health benefit plan" has the meaning stated in &#xA7; 15-1201 of the Insurance Article.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">"Health care practitioner" means any individual who is licensed, certified, or otherwise authorized under the Health Occupations Article to provide health care services.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">"Nursing home" means a related institution that is classified as a nursing home.</section>
      <section prefix="(6)">"Payor" means:<section prefix="(i)">A health insurer or nonprofit health service plan that holds a certificate of authority and provides health insurance policies or contracts in the State in accordance with this article or the Insurance Article; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">A health maintenance organization that holds a certificate of authority in the State.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Subject to the provisions of subsection (d) of this section, the Commission shall assess a fee on:<section prefix="(1)">All hospitals;</section><section prefix="(2)">All nursing homes;</section><section prefix="(3)">All payors; and</section><section prefix="(4)">All health care practitioners.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The total fees assessed by the Commission may not exceed $12,000,000.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The fees assessed by the Commission shall be used exclusively to cover the actual documented direct costs of fulfilling the statutory and regulatory duties of the Commission in accordance with the provisions of this subtitle.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The costs of the Commission include the administrative costs incurred by the Department on behalf of the Commission.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">The amount to be paid by the Commission to the Department for administrative costs, not to exceed 18% of the salaries of the Commission, shall be based on indirect costs or services benefiting the Commission, less overhead costs paid directly by the Commission.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Commission shall pay all funds collected from the fees assessed in accordance with this section into the Fund.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The fees assessed may be expended only for purposes authorized by the provisions of this subtitle.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">The amount in paragraph (1) of this subsection limits only the total fees the Commission may assess in a fiscal year.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">In determining assessments of the total fees, the Commission shall:<section prefix="(1)">Use a methodology that accounts for the portion of the Commission's workload attributable to each industry assessed; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Recalculate workload distribution every 4 years.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The fees assessed in accordance with this section on health care practitioners shall be:<section prefix="(i)">Included in the licensing fee paid to the health care practitioner's licensing board; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Transferred by the health care practitioner's licensing board to the Commission on a quarterly basis.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Commission may adopt regulations that waive the fee assessed under this section for a specific class of health care practitioners.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Subject to subparagraph (ii) of this paragraph, the Commission shall adopt regulations to permit a waiver of the fee assessment requirements for certain health care practitioners.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">In adopting regulations to permit a waiver of the fee assessment requirements for certain health care practitioners, the Commission shall:</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">There is a Maryland Health Care Commission Fund.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Fund is a special continuing, nonlapsing fund that is not subject to &#xA7; 7-302 of the State Finance and Procurement Article.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Treasurer shall separately hold, and the Comptroller shall account for, the Fund.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The Fund shall be invested and reinvested in the same manner as other State funds.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">Any investment earnings shall be retained to the credit of the Fund.</section>
      <section prefix="(6)">The Fund shall be subject to an audit by the Office of Legislative Audits as provided for in &#xA7; 2-1220 of the State Government Article.</section>
      <section prefix="(7)">This section may not be construed to prohibit the Fund from receiving funds from any other source.</section>
      <section prefix="(8)">The Fund shall be used only to provide funding for the Commission and for the purposes authorized under this subtitle.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">The Commission shall:<section prefix="(1)"><section prefix="(i)">Assess fees on payors in a manner that apportions the total amount of the fees to be assessed on payors under subsection (d)(1) of this section among each payor based on the ratio of each payor's total premiums written in the State for health benefit plans to the total written premiums of all payors written in the State; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">On or before June 30 of each year, assess each payor a fee in accordance with item (i) of this item;</section></section><section prefix="(2)"><section prefix="(i)">Assess fees for each hospital equal to the sum of:</section><section prefix="(ii)">Establish minimum and maximum assessments; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">On or before June 30 of each year, assess each hospital a fee in accordance with item (i) of this item; and</section></section><section prefix="(3)"><section prefix="(i)">Assess fees for each nursing home equal to the sum of:</section><section prefix="(ii)">Establish minimum and maximum assessments; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">On or before June 30 of each year, assess each nursing home a fee in accordance with item (i) of this item.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(h)">
      <section prefix="(1)">On or before September 1 of each year, each payor, hospital, and nursing home assessed under this section shall make payment to the Commission.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Commission shall make provisions for partial payments.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(i)">Any bill not paid within 30 days of the payment due date may be subject to an interest penalty to be determined and collected by the Commission.</section>
  </text>
</law>
