<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="ghg" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="15-103" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghg-15-103</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Secretary shall administer the Maryland Medical Assistance Program.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Program:<section prefix="(i)">Subject to the limitations of the State budget, shall provide medical and other health care services for indigent individuals or medically indigent individuals or both;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Shall provide, subject to the limitations of the State budget, comprehensive medical and other health care services for all eligible pregnant women whose family income is at or below 250 percent of the poverty level, as permitted by the federal law;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Shall provide, subject to the limitations of the State budget, comprehensive medical and other health care services for all eligible children currently under the age of 1 whose family income falls below 185 percent of the poverty level, as permitted by federal law;</section><section prefix="(iv)">Beginning on January 1, 2012, shall provide, subject to the limitations of the State budget, family planning services to all women whose family income is at or below 200 percent of the poverty level, as permitted by federal law;</section><section prefix="(v)">Shall provide, subject to the limitations of the State budget, comprehensive medical and other health care services for all children from the age of 1 year up through and including the age of 5 years whose family income falls below 133 percent of the poverty level, as permitted by the federal law;</section><section prefix="(vi)">Shall provide, subject to the limitations of the State budget, comprehensive medical care and other health care services for all children who are at least 6 years of age but are under 19 years of age whose family income falls below 100 percent of the poverty level, as permitted by federal law;</section><section prefix="(vii)">Shall provide, subject to the limitations of the State budget, comprehensive medical care and other health care services for all legal immigrants who meet Program eligibility standards and who arrived in the United States before August 22, 1996, the effective date of the federal Personal Responsibility and Work Opportunity Reconciliation Act, as permitted by federal law;</section><section prefix="(viii)">Shall provide, subject to the limitations of the State budget and any other requirements imposed by the State, comprehensive medical care and other health care services for all legal immigrant children under the age of 18 years and pregnant women who meet Program eligibility standards and who arrived in the United States on or after August 22, 1996, the effective date of the federal Personal Responsibility and Work Opportunity Reconciliation Act;</section><section prefix="(ix)">Beginning on July 1, 2008, shall provide, subject to the limitations of the State budget, and as permitted by federal law, comprehensive medical care and other health care services for all parents and caretaker relatives:</section><section prefix="(x)">Beginning on July 1, 2008, shall provide, subject to the limitations of the State budget, and as permitted by federal law, medical care and other health care services for adults:</section><section prefix="(xi)">Shall provide, subject to the limitations of the State budget, and as permitted by federal law, comprehensive medical care and other health care services for independent foster care adolescents:</section><section prefix="(xii)">May include bedside nursing care for eligible Program recipients; and</section><section prefix="(xiii)">Shall provide services in accordance with funding restrictions included in the annual State budget bill.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Subject to restrictions in federal law or waivers, the Department may:<section prefix="(i)">Impose cost-sharing on Program recipients; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">For adults who do not meet requirements for a federal category of eligibility for Medicaid:</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">In fiscal year 2011 and each fiscal year thereafter, the Governor shall include in the State budget funding sufficient to provide the substance abuse benefits required under paragraph (3)(ii)2 of this subsection.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">As permitted by federal law or waiver, the Secretary may establish a program under which Program recipients are required to enroll in managed care organizations.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The benefits required by the program developed under paragraph (1) of this subsection shall be adopted by regulation and shall be equivalent to the benefit level required by the Maryland Medical Assistance Program on January 1, 1996.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">Subject to the limitations of the State budget and as permitted by federal law or waiver, the Department shall provide reimbursement for medically necessary and appropriate inpatient, intermediate care, and halfway house substance abuse treatment services for substance abusing enrollees 21 years of age or older who are recipients of temporary cash assistance under the Family Investment Program.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">Each managed care organization participating in the program developed under paragraph (1) of this subsection shall provide or arrange for the provision of the benefits described in subparagraph (ii) of this paragraph.</section>
        <section prefix="(iv)">Nothing in this paragraph may be construed to prohibit a managed care organization from offering additional benefits, if the managed care organization is not receiving capitation payments based on the provision of the additional benefits.</section>
        <section prefix="(v)">Notwithstanding subparagraph (i) of this paragraph, the benefits required by the program developed under paragraph (1) of this subsection shall include dental services for pregnant women.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Subject to the limitations of the State budget and as permitted by federal law or waiver, the program developed under paragraph (1) of this subsection and the program developed under &#xA7; 15-301 of this title may provide guaranteed eligibility for each enrollee for up to 6 months, unless an enrollee obtains health insurance through another source.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The Secretary may exclude specific populations or services from the program developed under paragraph (1) of this subsection.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">For any populations or services excluded under this paragraph, the Secretary may authorize a managed care organization, to provide the services or provide for the population, including authorization of a separate dental managed care organization or a managed care organization to provide services to Program recipients with special needs.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(5)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Except for a service excluded by the Secretary under paragraph (4) of this subsection, each managed care organization shall provide all the benefits required by regulations adopted under paragraph (2) of this subsection.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">For a population or service excluded by the Secretary under paragraph (4) of this subsection, the Secretary may authorize a managed care organization to provide only for that population or provide only that service.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">A managed care organization may subcontract specified required services to a health care provider that is licensed or authorized to provide those services.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(6)">Except for the Program of All-inclusive Care for the Elderly ("PACE") Program, the Secretary may not include the long-term care population or long-term care services in the program developed under paragraph (1) of this subsection.</section>
      <section prefix="(7)">The program developed under paragraph (1) of this subsection shall ensure that enrollees have access to a pharmacy that:<section prefix="(i)">Is licensed in the State; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Is within a reasonable distance from the enrollee's residence.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(8)">For cause, the Department may disenroll enrollees from a managed care organization and enroll them in another managed care organization.</section>
      <section prefix="(9)">Each managed care organization shall:<section prefix="(i)">Have a quality assurance program in effect which is subject to the approval of the Department and which, at a minimum:</section><section prefix="(ii)">Submit to the Department:</section><section prefix="(iii)">Promote timely access to and continuity of health care services for enrollees;</section><section prefix="(iv)">Demonstrate organizational capacity to provide special programs, including outreach, case management, and home visiting, tailored to meet the individual needs of all enrollees;</section><section prefix="(v)">Provide assistance to enrollees in securing necessary health care services;</section><section prefix="(vi)">Provide or assure alcohol and drug abuse treatment for substance abusing pregnant women and all other enrollees of managed care organizations who require these services;</section><section prefix="(vii)">Educate enrollees on health care prevention and good health habits;</section><section prefix="(viii)">Assure necessary provider capacity in all geographic areas under contract;</section><section prefix="(ix)">Be accountable and hold its subcontractors accountable for standards established by the Department and, upon failure to meet those standards, be subject to one or more of the following penalties:</section><section prefix="(x)">Subject to applicable federal and State law, include incentives for enrollees to comply with provisions of the managed care organization;</section><section prefix="(xi)">Provide or arrange to provide primary mental health services;</section><section prefix="(xii)">Provide or arrange to provide all Medicaid-covered services required to comply with State statutes and regulations mandating health and mental health services for children in State supervised care:</section><section prefix="(xiii)">Submit to the Department aggregate information from the quality assurance program, including complaints and resolutions from the enrollee and provider grievance systems, the enrollee hotline, and enrollee satisfaction surveys;</section><section prefix="(xiv)">Maintain as part of the enrollee's medical record the following information:</section><section prefix="(xv)">Upon provision of information specified by the Department under paragraph (19) of this subsection, pay school-based clinics for services provided to the managed care organization's enrollees; and</section><section prefix="(xvi)">In coordination with participating dentists, enrollees, and families of enrollees, develop a process to arrange to provide dental therapeutic treatment to individuals under 21 years of age that requires:</section></section>
      <section prefix="(10)">The Department shall adopt regulations that assure that managed care organizations employ appropriate personnel to:<section prefix="(i)">Assure that individuals with special needs obtain needed services; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Coordinate those services.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(11)">
        <section prefix="(i)">A managed care organization shall reimburse a hospital emergency facility and provider for:</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">A provider may not be required to obtain prior authorization or approval for payment from a managed care organization in order to obtain reimbursement under this paragraph.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(12)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Each managed care organization shall notify each enrollee when the enrollee should obtain an immunization, examination, or other wellness service.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">Each managed care organization shall:</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">A managed care organization that does not comply with subparagraph (i) of this paragraph for at least 90% of its new enrollees:</section>
        <section prefix="(iv)">If a managed care organization does not comply with the requirements of paragraph (9) of this subsection, the Department may contract with any community-based health organization that the Department determines is willing and able to perform comprehensive outreach services to enrollees.</section>
        <section prefix="(v)">In addition to the provisions of subparagraph (iv) of this paragraph, if a managed care organization does not comply with the requirements of paragraph (9) of this subsection or fails to provide evidence of compliance to the Department under subparagraph (ii) of this paragraph, the Department may:</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(13)">The Department shall:<section prefix="(i)">Establish and maintain an ombudsman program and a locally accessible enrollee hotline;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Perform focused medical reviews of managed care organizations that include reviews of how the managed care organizations are providing health care services to special populations;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Provide timely feedback to each managed care organization on its compliance with the Department's quality and access system;</section><section prefix="(iv)">Establish and maintain within the Department a process for handling provider complaints about managed care organizations; and</section><section prefix="(v)">Adopt regulations relating to appeals by managed care organizations of penalties imposed by the Department, including regulations providing for an appeal to the Office of Administrative Hearings.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(14)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Except as provided in subparagraph (iii) of this paragraph, the Department shall delegate responsibility for maintaining the ombudsman program for a county to that county's local health department on the request of the local health department.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">A local health department may not subcontract the ombudsman program.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">Before the Department delegates responsibility to a local health department to maintain the ombudsman program for a county, a local health department that is also a Medicaid provider must receive the approval of the Secretary and the local governing body.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(15)">A managed care organization may not:<section prefix="(i)">Without authorization by the Department, enroll an individual who at the time is a Program recipient; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">Have face-to-face or telephone contact, or otherwise solicit with an individual who at the time is a Program recipient before the Program recipient enrolls in the managed care organization unless:</section></section>
      <section prefix="(16)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The Department shall be responsible for enrolling Program recipients into managed care organizations.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The Department may contract with an entity to perform the enrollment function.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">The Department or its enrollment contractor shall administer a health risk assessment developed by the Department to ensure that individuals who need special or immediate health care services will receive the services on a timely basis.</section>
        <section prefix="(iv)">The Department or its enrollment contractor:</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(17)">For a managed care organization with which the Secretary contracts to provide services to Program recipients under this subsection, the Secretary shall establish a mechanism to initially assure that each historic provider that meets the Department's quality standards has the opportunity to continue to serve Program recipients as a subcontractor of at least one managed care organization.</section>
      <section prefix="(18)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The Department shall make capitation payments to each managed care organization as provided in this paragraph.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">In consultation with the Insurance Commissioner, the Secretary shall:</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">In actuarially adjusting capitation payments under subparagraph (ii)2 of this paragraph, the Secretary, in consultation with the Insurance Commissioner, shall take into account, to the extent allowed under federal law, the expenses incurred by the managed care organization applicable to the business of providing care to enrolled individuals.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(19)">
        <section prefix="(i)">School-based clinics and managed care organizations shall collaborate to provide continuity of care to enrollees.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">School-based clinics shall be defined by the Department in consultation with the State Department of Education.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">Each managed care organization shall require a school-based clinic to provide to the managed care organization certain information, as specified by the Department, about an encounter with an enrollee of the managed care organization prior to paying the school-based clinic.</section>
        <section prefix="(iv)">Upon receipt of information specified by the Department, the managed care organization shall pay, at Medicaid-established rates, school-based clinics for covered services provided to enrollees of the managed care organization.</section>
        <section prefix="(v)">The Department shall work with managed care organizations and school-based clinics to develop collaboration standards, guidelines, and a process to assure that the services provided are covered and medically appropriate and that the process provides for timely notification among the parties.</section>
        <section prefix="(vi)">Each managed care organization shall maintain records of all health care services:</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(20)">The Department shall establish standards for the timely delivery of services to enrollees.</section>
      <section prefix="(21)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The Department shall establish a delivery system for specialty mental health services for enrollees of managed care organizations.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The Mental Hygiene Administration shall:</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">The Department shall collaborate with managed care organizations to develop standards and guidelines for the provision of specialty mental health services.</section>
        <section prefix="(iv)">The delivery system shall:</section>
        <section prefix="(v)">The Department may contract with a managed care organization for delivery of specialty mental health services if the managed care organization meets the performance standards adopted by the Department in regulations.</section>
        <section prefix="(vi)">The provisions of &#xA7; 15-1005 of the Insurance Article apply to the delivery system for specialty mental health services established under this paragraph and administered by an administrative services organization.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(22)">The Department shall include a definition of medical necessity in its quality and access standards.</section>
      <section prefix="(23)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The Department shall adopt regulations relating to enrollment, disenrollment, and enrollee appeals.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">Program recipients shall have the right to choose:</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">If a recipient is disenrolled and reenrolls within 120 days of the recipient's disenrollment, the Department shall:</section>
        <section prefix="(iv)">Whenever a recipient has to select a new managed care organization because the recipient's managed care organization has departed from the HealthChoice Program, the departing managed care organization:</section>
        <section prefix="(v)">On receiving the list provided by the managed care organization, the Department shall provide the list to:</section>
        <section prefix="(vi)">Subject to subsection (f)(4) and (5) of this section, an enrollee may disenroll from a managed care organization:</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(24)">The Department or its subcontractor, to the extent feasible in its marketing or enrollment programs, shall hire individuals receiving assistance under the program of Aid to Families with Dependent Children established under Title IV, Part A, of the Social Security Act, or the successor to the program.</section>
      <section prefix="(25)">The Department shall disenroll an enrollee who is a child in State-supervised care if the child is transferred to an area outside of the territory of the managed care organization.</section>
      <section prefix="(26)">The Secretary shall adopt regulations to implement the provisions of this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(27)">
        <section prefix="(i)"/>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The Committee members shall include:</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">A designee of each of the following shall serve as an ex-officio member of the Committee:</section>
        <section prefix="(iv)">In addition to any duties imposed by federal law and regulation, the Committee shall:</section>
        <section prefix="(v)">Except as specified in subparagraphs (ii) and (iii) of this paragraph, the members of the Maryland Medicaid Advisory Committee shall be appointed by the Secretary and serve for a 4-year term.</section>
        <section prefix="(vi)">In making appointments to the Committee, the Secretary shall provide for continuity and rotation.</section>
        <section prefix="(vii)">In appointing consumer members to the Committee, the Secretary shall seek recommendations from:</section>
        <section prefix="(viii)">The Secretary shall appoint the chair of the Committee.</section>
        <section prefix="(ix)">The Secretary shall appoint nonvoting members from managed care organizations who may participate in Committee meetings, unless the Committee meets in closed session as provided in &#xA7; 10-508 of the State Government Article.</section>
        <section prefix="(x)">The Department shall provide staff for the Committee.</section>
        <section prefix="(xi)">The Committee shall determine the times and places of its meetings.</section>
        <section prefix="(xii)"/>
        <section prefix="(xiii)"/>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(28)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The Department shall ensure that payments for services provided by a hospital located in a contiguous state or in the District of Columbia to an enrollee under the Program shall be reduced by 20% if the hospital fails to submit discharge data on all Maryland patients receiving care in the hospital to the Health Services Cost Review Commission in a form and manner the Commission specifies.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">Subparagraph (i) of this paragraph does not apply to a hospital that presently provides discharge data to the public in a form the Health Services Cost Review Commission determines is satisfactory.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(29)">A managed care organization shall provide coverage for hearing loss screenings of newborns provided by a hospital before discharge.</section>
      <section prefix="(30)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The Department shall provide enrollees and health care providers with an accurate directory or other listing of all available providers:</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The Department shall update the Internet database at least every 30 days.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">The written directory shall include a conspicuous reference to the Internet database.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">In this subsection the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">"Certified nurse practitioner" means a registered nurse who is licensed in this State, has completed a nurse practitioner program approved by the State Board of Nursing, and has passed an examination approved by that Board.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">"Nurse anesthetist" means a registered nurse who is:</section>
        <section prefix="(iv)">"Nurse midwife" means a registered nurse who is licensed in this State and has been certified by the American College of Nurse-Midwives as a nurse midwife.</section>
        <section prefix="(v)">"Optometrist" has the meaning stated in &#xA7; 11-101 of the Health Occupations Article.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Secretary may contract for the provision of care under the Program to eligible Program recipients.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Secretary may contract with insurance companies or nonprofit health service plans or with individuals, associations, partnerships, incorporated or unincorporated groups of physicians, chiropractors, dentists, podiatrists, optometrists, pharmacists, hospitals, nursing homes, nurses, including nurse anesthetists, nurse midwives and certified nurse practitioners, opticians, and other health practitioners who are licensed or certified in this State and perform services on the prescription or referral of a physician.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">For the purposes of this section, the nurse midwife need not be under the supervision of a physician.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">Except as otherwise provided by law, a contract that the Secretary makes under this subsection shall continue unless terminated under the terms of the contract by the Program or by the provider.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">As permitted by federal law or waiver, the Secretary may administer the Medicare Option Prescription Drug Program, established under &#xA7; 15-124.3 of this subtitle, as part of the Maryland Medical Assistance Program.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">By regulation, the Department shall adopt a methodology to ensure that federally qualified health centers are paid reasonable cost-based reimbursement that is consistent with federal law.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Department shall establish mechanisms for:<section prefix="(i)">Identifying a Program recipient's primary care provider at the time of enrollment into a managed care program; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Maintaining continuity of care with the primary care provider if:</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If a Program recipient enrolls in a managed care organization and requests assignment to a particular primary care provider who has a contract with the managed care organization or a contracted group of the managed care organization, the managed care organization shall assign the recipient to the primary care provider.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A Program recipient may request a change of primary care providers within the same managed care organization at any time and, if the primary care provider has a contract with the managed care organization or a contracted group of the managed care organization, the managed care organization shall honor the request.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">In accordance with the federal Health Care Financing Administration's guidelines, a Program recipient may elect to disenroll from a managed care organization if the managed care organization terminates its contract with the Department.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">A Program recipient may disenroll from a managed care organization to maintain continuity of care with a primary care provider if:<section prefix="(i)">The contract between the primary care provider and the managed care organization or contracted group of the managed care organization terminates because:</section><section prefix="(ii)"/></section>
      <section prefix="(6)">The Department shall provide timely notification to the affected managed care organization of an enrollee's intention to disenroll under the provisions of paragraph (5) of this subsection.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
