<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghg" order_by="ghg" level="1">Health - General</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghg-10-805</section_number>
  <catch_line>Subject to the limitations in this section, a petition for the release of an individual who is held ...</catch_line>
  <order_by>805</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Subject to the limitations in this section, a petition for the release of an individual who is held under this title from the facility or a Veterans' Administration hospital may be filed, at any time by:<section prefix="(1)">The individual; or</section><section prefix="(2)">Any person who has a legitimate interest in the welfare of the individual.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The petition shall be filed in an equity court in the county where the individual resides or resided at the time of the admission or where the facility is located.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If the individual is in a public facility, the Administration shall be the respondent.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If the individual is in a private facility or a Veterans' Administration hospital, it shall be the respondent.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The petition shall be in the form and contain the information the Maryland Rules require.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">If the petitioner requests trial by jury, the trial shall be held with a jury as in a civil action at law.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The trier of fact shall determine:<section prefix="(1)">Whether the individual has a mental disorder; and</section><section prefix="(2)">If so, whether the individual needs inpatient medical care or treatment for the protection of the individual or another.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If the trier of fact finds that the individual has a mental disorder and needs inpatient medical care or treatment, the court shall remand the individual to the custody of the facility or Veterans' Administration hospital.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If the trier of fact finds that the individual does not have a mental disorder or has a mental disorder, but does not need inpatient medical care or treatment, the individual shall be released from the facility or Veterans' Administration hospital.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(h)">Any party may appeal from a decision on the petition as in any other civil case.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">Appropriate records of the proceeding under this section shall be made a permanent part of the individual's record.</section>
    <section prefix="(j)">
      <section prefix="(1)">After a determination on the merits of a petition filed under this section, a court may not hear a later petition for the individual within 1 year after that determination, unless the petition is accompanied by a valid affidavit that the court, after review of the petition and affidavit, determines to show an improvement in the mental condition of the individual after the determination.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">An affidavit is not valid if executed by an individual under care or treatment in a facility or Veterans' Administration hospital.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">If the matter is reopened, the petition shall be heard as provided in this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">If the affidavit does not show improvement in the individual's mental condition, the petition shall be dismissed.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
