<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="ghg" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="19-901" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghg-19-901</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Home-based hospice care program" means a program that directly or through a contractual arrangement provides a hospice care program in the residence of the patient.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Hospice facility" means a facility that:<section prefix="(1)">Provides a hospice care program;</section><section prefix="(2)">Is separate from any other facility; and</section><section prefix="(3)">Admits at least 2 individuals who:<section prefix="(i)">Are unrelated; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Have no reasonable prospect of a cure.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">"General hospice care program" means a coordinated, interdisciplinary program of hospice care services for meeting the special physical, psychological, spiritual, and social needs of dying individuals and their families, by providing palliative and supportive medical, nursing, and other health services through home or inpatient care during the illness and bereavement:<section prefix="(1)">To individuals who have no reasonable prospect of cure as estimated by a physician; and</section><section prefix="(2)">To the families of those individuals.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"General license" means a license issued by the Secretary to operate a general hospice care program.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">"Limited hospice care program" means a coordinated, interdisciplinary program of hospice care services for meeting the special physical, psychological, spiritual, and social needs of dying individuals and their families, by providing palliative and supportive nonskilled services through a home-based hospice care program during illness and bereavement:<section prefix="(1)">To individuals who have no reasonable prospect of cure as estimated by a physician; and</section><section prefix="(2)">To the families of those individuals.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(g)">"Limited license" means a license issued by the Secretary to operate a limited hospice care program.</section>
  </text>
</law>
