<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="ghg" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="10-620" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghg-10-620</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In Part IV of this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Court" means a district or circuit court of this State.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Emergency evaluee" means an individual for whom an emergency evaluation is sought or made under Part IV of this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Emergency facility" means a facility that the Department designates, in writing, as an emergency facility.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Emergency facility" includes a licensed general hospital that has an emergency room, unless the Department, after consultation with the health officer, exempts the hospital.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Mental disorder" means the behavioral or other symptoms that indicate:<section prefix="(i)">To a lay petitioner who is submitting an emergency petition, a clear disturbance in the mental functioning of another individual; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">To the following health professionals doing an examination, at least one mental disorder that is described in the version of the American Psychiatric Association's "Diagnostic and Statistical Manual - Mental Disorders" that is current at the time of the examination:</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Mental disorder" does not include intellectual disability.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">"Peace officer" means a sheriff, a deputy sheriff, a State police officer, a county police officer, a municipal or other local police officer, or a Secret Service agent who is a sworn special agent of the United States Secret Service or Department of Homeland Security authorized to exercise powers delegated under 18 U.S.C. &#xA7; 3056.</section>
  </text>
</law>
