<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghg" order_by="ghg" level="1">Health - General</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghg-18-4A-02</section_number>
  <catch_line>Subject to the provisions of this section, a parent may delegate verbally or in writing the parent's...</catch_line>
  <order_by>02</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Subject to the provisions of this section, a parent may delegate verbally or in writing the parent's authority to consent to the immunization of a minor to any of the following individuals, not in order of priority:<section prefix="(1)">A grandparent;</section><section prefix="(2)">An adult brother or sister;</section><section prefix="(3)">An adult aunt or uncle;</section><section prefix="(4)">A stepparent; or</section><section prefix="(5)">Any other adult who has care and control of the minor.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">If a parent verbally delegates the parent's authority to consent to the immunization of a minor under this subtitle, the person delegated the authority shall confirm the verbal delegation in writing and the written confirmation shall be included in the minor's medical record.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A grandparent, adult brother or sister, adult aunt or uncle, or stepparent of a minor who is the primary caregiver of the minor and who may consent to the immunization of the minor under subsection (a) of this section may delegate the authority to consent to immunization of the minor to another adult in the manner permitted under subsection (b) of this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A health care provider may rely on a notarized document from another state or country that contains substantially the same information as is required in any immunization consent regulations of the Department if the document is presented for consent by a person listed in subsection (a) of this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">A person who consents to immunization of a minor under this subtitle shall provide the health care provider with sufficient and accurate health information about the minor for whom the consent is given and, if necessary, sufficient and accurate health information about the minor's family to enable the person providing the consent and the health care provider to determine adequately the risks and benefits inherent in the proposed immunization and determine whether the immunization is advisable.</section>
  </text>
</law>
