<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghg" order_by="ghg" level="1">Health - General</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghg-19-120</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this section the following words have the meanings indicated....</catch_line>
  <order_by>120</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Consolidation" and "merger" include increases and decreases in bed capacity or services among the components of an organization that:<section prefix="(i)">Operates more than one health care facility; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">Operates one or more health care facilities and holds an outstanding certificate of need to construct a health care facility.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">"Health care service" means any clinically related patient service.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">"Health care service" includes a medical service.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(4)">"Limited service hospital" means a health care facility that:<section prefix="(i)">Is licensed as a hospital on or after January 1, 1999;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Changes the type of scope of health care services offered by eliminating the facility's capability to admit or retain patients for overnight hospitalization;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Retains an emergency or urgent care center; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">Complies with the regulations adopted by the Secretary under &#xA7; 19-307.1 of this title.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(5)">"Medical service" means:<section prefix="(i)">Any of the following categories of health care services:<section prefix="1.">Medicine, surgery, gynecology, addictions;</section><section prefix="2.">Obstetrics;</section><section prefix="3.">Pediatrics;</section><section prefix="4.">Psychiatry;</section><section prefix="5.">Rehabilitation;</section><section prefix="6.">Chronic care;</section><section prefix="7.">Comprehensive care;</section><section prefix="8.">Extended care;</section><section prefix="9.">Intermediate care; or</section><section prefix="10.">Residential treatment; or</section></section><section prefix="(ii)">Any subcategory of the rehabilitation, psychiatry, comprehensive care, or intermediate care categories of health care services for which need is projected in the State health plan.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Commission may set an application fee for a certificate of need for health care facilities not assessed a user fee under this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Commission shall adopt rules and regulations for applying for and issuing certificates of need.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Commission may adopt, after October 1, 1983, new thresholds or methods for determining the circumstances or minimum cost requirements under which a certificate of need application must be filed.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A person shall have a certificate of need issued by the Commission before the person develops, operates, or participates in any of the health care projects for which a certificate of need is required under this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A certificate of need issued before January 13, 1987, may not be rendered wholly or partially invalid solely because certain conditions have been imposed, if an appeal concerning the certificate of need, challenging the power of the Commission to impose certain conditions on a certificate of need, has not been noted by an aggrieved party before January 13, 1987.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">Except as provided in subsection (g)(2)(iii) of this section, a certificate of need is required before a new health care facility is built, developed, or established.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A certificate of need is required before an existing or previously approved, but unbuilt, health care facility is moved to another site.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">This subsection does not apply if:<section prefix="(i)">The Commission adopts limits for relocations and the proposed relocation does not exceed those limits;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The relocation is the result of a partial or complete replacement of an existing hospital or related institution, as defined in &#xA7; 19-301 of this title, and the relocation is to another part of the site or immediately adjacent to the site of the existing hospital or related institution;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Subject to the provisions of subsections (i) and (j) of this section, the relocation is of an existing health care facility owned or controlled by a merged asset system and is to:<section prefix="1.">A site within the primary service area of the health care facility to be relocated if:</section><section prefix="2.">A site outside the primary service area of the health care facility to be relocated but within the primary service area of the merged asset system if:</section><section prefix="3.">For a limited service hospital, a site within the immediate area as defined in regulation by the Commission; or</section></section><section prefix="(iv)">The relocation involves moving a portion of a complement of comprehensive care beds previously approved by the Commission after January 1, 1995, for use in a proposed new related institution, as defined in &#xA7; 19-301 of this title, but unbuilt on October 1, 1998, if:<section prefix="1.">The comprehensive care beds that were originally approved by the Commission in a prior certificate of need review were approved for use in a proposed new related institution to be located in a municipal corporation within Carroll County in which a related institution is not located;</section><section prefix="2.">The comprehensive care beds being relocated will be used to establish an additional new related institution that is located in another municipal corporation within Carroll County in which a related institution is not located;</section><section prefix="3.">The comprehensive care beds not being relocated are intended to be used to establish a related institution on the original site; and</section><section prefix="4.">Both the previously approved comprehensive care beds for use on the original site and the relocated comprehensive care beds for use on the new site will be used as components of single buildings on each site that also offer independent or assisted living residential units.</section></section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Notwithstanding any other provision of this subtitle, a certificate of need is not required for a relocation described under paragraph (2)(iv) of this subsection.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(h)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A certificate of need is required before the bed capacity of a health care facility is changed.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">This subsection does not apply to any increase or decrease in bed capacity if:<section prefix="(i)">For a health care facility that is not a hospital, during a 2-year period the increase or decrease would not exceed the lesser of 10 percent of the total bed capacity or 10 beds;</section><section prefix="(ii)"><section prefix="1.">The increase or decrease would change the bed capacity for an existing medical service; and</section><section prefix="2."/></section><section prefix="(iii)"><section prefix="1.">At least 45 days before increasing or decreasing bed capacity, written notice of intent to change bed capacity is filed with the Commission;</section><section prefix="2.">The Commission in its sole discretion finds that the proposed change:</section><section prefix="3.">Within 45 days of receiving notice, the Commission notifies the health care facility of its finding; or</section></section><section prefix="(iv)">The increase or decrease in bed capacity is the result of the annual licensed bed recalculation provided under &#xA7; 19-307 of this title.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(i)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, for a hospital located in a county with three or more hospitals, a certificate of need is not required before the bed capacity is increased or decreased if the change:<section prefix="(i)">Occurs on or after July 1, 2000;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Is between hospitals in a merged asset system located within the same health service area;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Does not involve comprehensive or extended care beds; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">Does not occur earlier than 45 days after a notice of intent to reallocate bed capacity is filed with the Commission.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A hospital may not create a new health care service through the relocation of beds from one county to another county pursuant to this subsection.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(j)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A certificate of need is required before the type or scope of any health care service is changed if the health care service is offered:<section prefix="(i)">By a health care facility;</section><section prefix="(ii)">In space that is leased from a health care facility; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">In space that is on land leased from a health care facility.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">This subsection does not apply if:<section prefix="(i)">The Commission adopts limits for changes in health care services and the proposed change would not exceed those limits;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The proposed change and the annual operating revenue that would result from the addition is entirely associated with the use of medical equipment;</section><section prefix="(iii)">The proposed change would establish, increase, or decrease a health care service and the change would not result in the:<section prefix="1.">Establishment of a new medical service or elimination of an existing medical service;</section><section prefix="2.">Establishment of a cardiac surgery, organ transplant surgery, or burn or neonatal intensive health care service;</section><section prefix="3.">Except as provided in &#xA7; 19-120.1 of this subtitle, establishment of percutaneous coronary intervention services;</section><section prefix="4.">Establishment of a home health program, hospice program, or freestanding ambulatory surgical center or facility; or</section><section prefix="5.">Expansion of a comprehensive care, extended care, intermediate care, residential treatment, psychiatry, or rehabilitation medical service, except for an expansion related to an increase in total bed capacity in accordance with subsection (h)(2)(i) of this section; or</section></section><section prefix="(iv)"><section prefix="1.">At least 45 days before increasing or decreasing the volume of one or more health care services, written notice of intent to change the volume of health care services is filed with the Commission;</section><section prefix="2.">The Commission in its sole discretion finds that the proposed change:</section><section prefix="3.">Within 45 days of receiving notice under item 1 of this item, the Commission notifies the health care facility of its finding.</section></section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Notwithstanding the provisions of paragraph (2) of this subsection, a certificate of need is required:<section prefix="(i)">Before an additional home health agency, branch office, or home health care service is established by an existing health care agency or facility;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Before an existing home health agency or health care facility establishes a home health agency or home health care service at a location in the service area not included under a previous certificate of need or license;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Before a transfer of ownership of any branch office of a home health agency or home health care service of an existing health care facility that separates the ownership of the branch office from the home health agency or home health care service of an existing health care facility which established the branch office; or</section><section prefix="(iv)">Before the expansion of a home health service or program by a health care facility that:<section prefix="1.">Established the home health service or program without a certificate of need between January 1, 1984 and July 1, 1984; and</section><section prefix="2.">During a 1-year period, the annual operating revenue of the home health service or program would be greater than $333,000 after an annual adjustment for inflation, based on an appropriate index specified by the Commission.</section></section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(k)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A certificate of need is required before any of the following capital expenditures are made by or on behalf of a hospital:<section prefix="(i)">Any expenditure that, under generally accepted accounting principles, is not properly chargeable as an operating or maintenance expense, if:<section prefix="1.">The expenditure is made as part of an acquisition, improvement, or expansion, and, after adjustment for inflation as provided in the regulations of the Commission, the total expenditure, including the cost of each study, survey, design, plan, working drawing, specification, and other essential activity, is more than $10,000,000;</section><section prefix="2.">The expenditure is made as part of a replacement of any plant and equipment of the hospital and is more than $10,000,000 after adjustment for inflation as provided in the regulations of the Commission;</section><section prefix="3.">The expenditure results in a substantial change in the bed capacity of the hospital; or</section><section prefix="4.">The expenditure results in the establishment of a new medical service in a hospital that would require a certificate of need under subsection (i) of this section; or</section></section><section prefix="(ii)">Any expenditure that is made to lease or, by comparable arrangement, obtain any plant or equipment for the hospital, if:<section prefix="1.">The expenditure is made as part of an acquisition, improvement, or expansion, and, after adjustment for inflation as provided in the rules and regulations of the Commission, the total expenditure, including the cost of each study, survey, design, plan, working drawing, specification, and other essential activity, is more than $10,000,000;</section><section prefix="2.">The expenditure is made as part of a replacement of any plant and equipment and is more than $10,000,000 after adjustment for inflation as provided in the regulations of the Commission;</section><section prefix="3.">The expenditure results in a substantial change in the bed capacity of the hospital; or</section><section prefix="4.">The expenditure results in the establishment of a new medical service in a hospital that would require a certificate of need under subsection (i) of this section.</section></section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A certificate of need is required before any of the following capital expenditures are made by or on behalf of a health care facility other than a hospital:<section prefix="(i)">Any expenditure that, under generally accepted accounting principles, is not properly chargeable as an operating or maintenance expense, if:<section prefix="1.">The expenditure is made as part of an acquisition, improvement, or expansion, and, after adjustment for inflation as provided in the regulations of the Commission, the total expenditure, including the cost of each study, survey, design, plan, working drawing, specification, and other essential activity, is more than $5,000,000;</section><section prefix="2.">The expenditure is made as part of a replacement of any plant and equipment of the health care facility other than a hospital and is more than $5,000,000 after adjustment for inflation as provided in the regulations of the Commission;</section><section prefix="3.">The expenditure results in a substantial change in the bed capacity of the health care facility other than a hospital; or</section><section prefix="4.">The expenditure results in the establishment of a new medical service in a health care facility other than a hospital that would require a certificate of need under subsection (i) of this section; or</section></section><section prefix="(ii)">Any expenditure that is made to lease or, by comparable arrangement, obtain any plant or equipment for the health care facility other than a hospital, if:<section prefix="1.">The expenditure is made as part of an acquisition, improvement, or expansion, and, after adjustment for inflation as provided in the regulations of the Commission, the total expenditure, including the cost of each study, survey, design, plan, working drawing, specification, and other essential activity, is more than $5,000,000;</section><section prefix="2.">The expenditure is made as part of a replacement of any plant and equipment and is more than $5,000,000 after adjustment for inflation as provided in the regulations of the Commission;</section><section prefix="3.">The expenditure results in a substantial change in the bed capacity of the health care facility other than a hospital; or</section><section prefix="4.">The expenditure results in the establishment of a new medical service in a health care facility other than a hospital that would require a certificate of need under subsection (i) of this section.</section></section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A certificate of need is required before any equipment or plant is donated to a health care facility, if a certificate of need would be required under paragraph (1) or (2) of this subsection for an expenditure by the health care facility to acquire the equipment or plant directly.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">A certificate of need is required before any equipment or plant is transferred to a health care facility at less than fair market value if a certificate of need would be required under paragraph (1) or (2) of this subsection for the transfer at fair market value.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">A certificate of need is required before a person acquires a health care facility if a certificate of need would be required under paragraph (1) or (2) of this subsection for the acquisition by or on behalf of the health care facility.</section>
      <section prefix="(6)">This subsection does not apply to:<section prefix="(i)">Site acquisition;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Acquisition of a health care facility if, at least 30 days before making the contractual arrangement to acquire the facility, written notice of the intent to make the arrangement is filed with the Commission and the Commission does not find, within 30 days after the Commission receives notice, that the health services or bed capacity of the facility will be changed, provided that, for a merger with or acquisition of an existing general hospice, the purchaser of the general hospice may only acquire the authority to provide home-based hospice services in jurisdictions in which the seller of the general hospice is licensed to provide home-based hospice services;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Acquisition of business or office equipment that is not directly related to patient care;</section><section prefix="(iv)">Capital expenditures to the extent that they are directly related to the acquisition and installation of major medical equipment;</section><section prefix="(v)">A capital expenditure made as part of a consolidation or merger of two or more health care facilities, or conversion of a health care facility or part of a facility to a nonhealth-related use if:<section prefix="1.">At least 45 days before an expenditure is made, written notice of intent is filed with the Commission;</section><section prefix="2.">Within 45 days of receiving notice, the Commission in its sole discretion finds that the proposed consolidation, merger, or conversion:</section><section prefix="3.">Within 45 days of receiving notice, the Commission notifies the health care facility of its finding;</section></section><section prefix="(vi)">A capital expenditure by a nursing home for equipment, construction, or renovation that:<section prefix="1.">Is not directly related to patient care; and</section><section prefix="2.">Is not directly related to any change in patient charges or other rates;</section></section><section prefix="(vii)">A capital expenditure by a hospital, as defined in &#xA7; 19-301 of this title, for equipment, construction, or renovation that:<section prefix="1.">Is not directly related to patient care; and</section><section prefix="2.">Does not increase patient charges or hospital rates;</section></section><section prefix="(viii)">A capital expenditure by a hospital, as defined in &#xA7; 19-301 of this title, for a project in excess of $10,000,000 for construction or renovation that:<section prefix="1.">May be related to patient care;</section><section prefix="2.">Does not require, over the entire period or schedule of debt service associated with the project, a total cumulative increase in patient charges or hospital rates of more than $1,500,000 for the capital costs associated with the project as determined by the Commission, after consultation with the Health Services Cost Review Commission;</section><section prefix="3.">At least 45 days before the proposed expenditure is made, the hospital notifies the Commission;</section><section prefix="4."/><section prefix="5.">The relevant financial information to be submitted by the hospital is defined in regulations adopted by the Commission, after consultation with the Health Services Cost Review Commission; or</section></section><section prefix="(ix)">A plant donated to a hospital, as defined in &#xA7; 19-301 of this title, that does not require a cumulative increase in patient charges or hospital rates of more than $1,500,000 for capital costs associated with the donated plant as determined by the Commission, after consultation with the Health Services Cost Review Commission, if:<section prefix="1.">At least 45 days before the proposed donation is made, the hospital notifies the Commission;</section><section prefix="2."/><section prefix="3.">The relevant financial information to be submitted by the hospital is defined in regulations adopted by the Commission after consultation with the Health Services Cost Review Commission.</section></section></section>
      <section prefix="(7)">Paragraph (6)(vi), (vii), (viii), and (ix) of this subsection may not be construed to permit a facility to offer a new health care service for which a certificate of need is otherwise required.</section>
      <section prefix="(8)">Subject to the notice requirements of paragraph (6)(ii) of this subsection, a hospital may acquire a freestanding ambulatory surgical facility or office of one or more health care practitioners or a group practice with one or more operating rooms used primarily for the purpose of providing ambulatory surgical services if the facility, office, or group practice:<section prefix="(i)">Has obtained a certificate of need;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Has obtained an exemption from certificate of need requirements; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">Did not require a certificate of need in order to provide ambulatory surgical services after June 1, 1995.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(9)">Nothing in this subsection may be construed to permit a hospital to build or expand its ambulatory surgical capacity in any setting owned or controlled by the hospital without obtaining a certificate of need from the Commission if the building or expansion would increase the surgical capacity of the State's health care system.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(l)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A certificate of need is not required to close any health care facility or part of a health care facility if at least 45 days before the closing or partial closing of the health care facility, including a State hospital, a person proposing to close all or part of the health care facility files notice of the proposed closing or partial closing with the Commission.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A hospital located in a county with fewer than three hospitals that files a notice of its proposed closing or partial closing with the Commission shall hold a public informational hearing in the county where the hospital is located.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Commission may require a health care facility other than a hospital described in paragraph (2) of this subsection that files notice of its proposed closing or partial closing to hold a public informational hearing in the county where the health care facility is located.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">A public informational hearing required under paragraph (2) or (3) of this subsection shall be held by the health care facility, in consultation with the Commission, within 30 days after the health care facility files a notice of its proposed closing or partial closing with the Commission.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(m)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Notwithstanding any other provision of this section, the Commission shall consider the special needs and circumstances of a county where a medical service, as defined in this section, does not exist; and</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Commission shall consider and may approve under this subsection a certificate of need application to establish, build, operate, or participate in a health care project to provide a new medical service in a county if the Commission, in its sole discretion, finds that:<section prefix="(i)">The proposed medical service does not exist in the county that the project would be located;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The proposed medical service is necessary to meet the health care needs of the residents of that county;</section><section prefix="(iii)">The proposed medical service would have a positive impact on the existing health care system;</section><section prefix="(iv)">The proposed medical service would result in the delivery of more efficient and effective health care services to the residents of that county; and</section><section prefix="(v)">The application meets any other standards or regulations established by the Commission to approve applications under this subsection.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(n)">The Commission may not issue a certificate of need or a determination with respect to an acquisition that authorizes a general hospice to provide home-based hospice services on a statewide basis.</section>
  </text>
</law>
