<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghg" order_by="" level="1">Health - General</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghg-13-1504</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>1504</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Advisory Council shall be composed of 18 members as follows:<section prefix="(i)">One member of the Senate of Maryland, appointed by the President of the Senate;</section><section prefix="(ii)">One member of the House of Delegates, appointed by the Speaker of the House;</section><section prefix="(iii)">The Secretary of Health and Mental Hygiene, or the Secretary's designee;</section><section prefix="(iv)">The Secretary of the Environment, or the Secretary's designee;</section><section prefix="(v)">The Secretary of Agriculture, or the Secretary's designee;</section><section prefix="(vi)">The Secretary of Education, or the Secretary's designee;</section><section prefix="(vii)">The Secretary of Human Resources, or the Secretary's designee;</section><section prefix="(viii)">The Secretary of Housing and Community Development, or the Secretary's designee;</section><section prefix="(ix)">The Special Secretary of the Governor's Office for Children, Youth, and Families, or the Special Secretary's designee;</section><section prefix="(x)">Two licensed pediatric health care providers with expertise in the field of children's environmental health, appointed by the Governor;</section><section prefix="(xi)">One representative from the Johns Hopkins University who has expertise in studying the impact of environmental allergies on childhood asthma, appointed by the Governor;</section><section prefix="(xii)">One parent or guardian whose child has been clinically diagnosed as having been exposed to environmental health hazards including lead paint or pesticides, appointed by the Governor;</section><section prefix="(xiii)">One environmental epidemiologist with expertise in children's environmental health, appointed by the Governor;</section><section prefix="(xiv)">One economist skilled in measuring the economic costs of illness and the benefits of prevention, appointed by the Governor;</section><section prefix="(xv)">One environmental toxicologist with expertise in issues of importance to children's environmental health, appointed by the Governor;</section><section prefix="(xvi)">One representative from the Maryland Association of Counties, appointed by the Governor; and</section><section prefix="(xvii)">One individual from private industry representing the regulated community, appointed by the Governor.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Secretary of Health and Mental Hygiene or the Secretary's designee shall serve as the chairman.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Secretary of the Environment or the Secretary's designee shall serve as the vice chairman.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The term of a member is 4 years.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The terms of the members are staggered as required by the terms provided for members of the Advisory Council on October 1, 2000.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">At the end of a term, a member continues to serve until a successor is appointed and qualifies.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">A member who is appointed after a term has begun serves only for the rest of the term and until a successor is appointed and qualifies.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
