<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghg" order_by="" level="1">Health - General</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghg-19-1404</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>1404</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">A civil money penalty imposed under this section for potential for more than minimal harm deficiencies:<section prefix="(1)">May not exceed $10,000 per instance; or</section><section prefix="(2)">May not exceed $1,000 per day for an ongoing pattern of deficiencies until the nursing home is in compliance.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A civil money penalty imposed under this subtitle for actual harm deficiencies:<section prefix="(1)">May not exceed $10,000 per instance; or</section><section prefix="(2)">May not exceed $5,000 per day for an ongoing pattern of deficiencies until the nursing home is in compliance.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A civil money penalty imposed under this section for a serious and immediate threat:<section prefix="(1)">May not exceed $10,000 per instance; or</section><section prefix="(2)">May not exceed $10,000 per day for an ongoing pattern of deficiencies until the nursing home is in compliance.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">In setting the amount of a civil money penalty under this section, the Secretary shall consider, pursuant to guidelines set forth in regulations promulgated by the Secretary, the following factors:<section prefix="(1)">The number, nature, and seriousness of the deficiencies;</section><section prefix="(2)">The degree of risk to the health, life, or safety of the residents of the nursing home caused by the deficiency or deficiencies;</section><section prefix="(3)">The efforts made by the nursing home to correct the deficiency or deficiencies;</section><section prefix="(4)">Current federal guidelines for money penalties;</section><section prefix="(5)">Whether the amount of the proposed civil money penalty will jeopardize the financial ability of the nursing home to continue operating as a nursing home; and</section><section prefix="(6)">Such other factors as justice may require.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
