<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghg" order_by="ghg" level="1">Health - General</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghg-13-1103</section_number>
  <catch_line>There is a Surveillance and Evaluation Component in the Program....</catch_line>
  <order_by>1103</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">There is a Surveillance and Evaluation Component in the Program.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The purpose of the Surveillance and Evaluation Component is to:<section prefix="(1)">Collect, analyze, and monitor data relating to:<section prefix="(i)">Targeted cancers;</section><section prefix="(ii)">As determined by the Department, nontargeted cancers; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Cancer prevention, education, screening, and treatment programs in the State;</section></section><section prefix="(2)">Measure and evaluate the results of the Program, including the results of each component of the Program;</section><section prefix="(3)">Conduct the Baseline Cancer Study, as provided under subsections (c) and (d) of this section; and</section><section prefix="(4)">Conduct a Biennial Cancer Study, as provided under &#xA7; 13-1104 of this subtitle.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">To initiate the Surveillance and Evaluation Component, the Department shall conduct a comprehensive statewide Baseline Cancer Study as provided in this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Department may:<section prefix="(i)">Conduct the Baseline Cancer Study or any part of the Study; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">Contract with a higher education institution or private entity to conduct the Baseline Cancer Study or any part of the Study.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Baseline Cancer Study shall measure:<section prefix="(1)">The number and percentage of individuals who have each targeted cancer, both statewide and in each county;</section><section prefix="(2)">The number and percentage of individuals within each minority population who have each targeted cancer, both statewide and in each county;</section><section prefix="(3)">The mortality rate for each targeted cancer, both statewide and in each county;</section><section prefix="(4)">The mortality rate for different minority populations for each targeted cancer, both statewide and in each county;</section><section prefix="(5)">The number of identifiable cancers with a high incidence in the State for which there are effective methods of:<section prefix="(i)">Early detection; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Prevention and treatment after detection;</section></section><section prefix="(6)">Any aspect of targeted and nontargeted cancers that the Department seeks to measure; and</section><section prefix="(7)">Any other factor that the Department determines to be important for measuring rates of cancers in the State or for evaluating whether the Program meets its objectives.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">In order to maximize the cost effectiveness of the Baseline Cancer Study, the Department may use data in the Maryland Cancer Registry or provided by other sources, to the extent that these sources provide reliable data relating to the factors listed in subsection (d) of this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If the Department chooses to have a higher education institution or private entity conduct the Baseline Cancer Study or any part of the Study, the Department shall issue a request for proposal to select the entity that will conduct the Study or the relevant part of the Study.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The request for proposal shall require that any methodology or model that is used by the entity to conduct the Baseline Cancer Study or the relevant part of the Study, any data collected under the Study, and any electronic files, codes, and definitions relating to the Study be provided to the State for use in subsequent studies, regardless of whether the studies are conducted by the same entity.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Department may contract with an entity to conduct the Baseline Cancer Study and one or more biennial cancer studies as required under &#xA7; 13-1104 of this subtitle.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">On or before September 1, 2000, the Department shall submit a report to the Governor and, subject to &#xA7; 2-1246 of the State Government Article, the General Assembly, on the results of the Baseline Cancer Study.</section>
  </text>
</law>
