<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghg" order_by="" level="1">Health - General</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghg-2-505</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>505</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">A person is not civilly liable for:<section prefix="(1)">Making a report in good faith of fraud, waste, or abuse; or</section><section prefix="(2)">Participating in any investigation related to fraud, waste, or abuse.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This subsection does not apply to an employee as defined in &#xA7; 1-501(c) of the Health Occupations Article or a State employee.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A provider may not take a retaliatory action against an employee because the employee:<section prefix="(i)">Discloses or threatens to disclose to a supervisor or to a public body an activity, policy, or practice of the provider that the employee reasonably believes is in violation of this subtitle or a regulation adopted under this subtitle;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Provides information to, or testifies before, a public body conducting an investigation, hearing, or inquiry into a suspected violation by the provider under this subtitle or a regulation adopted under this subtitle; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">Objects to or refuses to participate in any activity, policy, or practice that the employee reasonably believes is in violation of this subtitle or regulations adopted under this subtitle.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Any employee who is subject to an action in violation of paragraph (2) of this subsection may institute a civil action in the county where:<section prefix="(i)">The alleged violation occurred;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The employee resides; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">The provider maintains its principal office in the State.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The action shall be brought within 1 year after the alleged violation of paragraph (2) of this subsection or within 1 year after the employee first became aware of the alleged violation of paragraph (1) of this subsection.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">In any action brought under this subsection, a court may:<section prefix="(i)">Issue an injunction to restrain continued violation of this subsection;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Reinstate the employee to the same or an equivalent position held before the violation of paragraph (2) of this subsection;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Remove any adverse personnel record entries based on or related to the violation of paragraph (2) of this subsection;</section><section prefix="(iv)">Reinstate full fringe benefits and seniority rights;</section><section prefix="(v)">Require compensation for lost wages, benefits, and other remuneration; and</section><section prefix="(vi)">Assess reasonable attorney's fees and other litigation expenses against:<section prefix="1.">The provider, if the employee prevails; or</section><section prefix="2.">The employee, if the court determines that the action was brought by the employee in bad faith and without basis in law or fact.</section></section></section>
      <section prefix="(6)">A provider shall:<section prefix="(i)">Conspicuously display notices of its employee protections under this subsection; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Use appropriate means to inform its employees of the protections and obligations provided under this subsection.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
