<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghg" order_by="ghg" level="1">Health - General</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghg-19-343</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this section and &#xA7;&#xA7; 19-344 and 19-345 of this subtitle, "facility" means a related institution ...</catch_line>
  <order_by>343</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section and &#xA7;&#xA7; 19-344 and 19-345 of this subtitle, "facility" means a related institution that, under the rules and regulations of the Department, is a comprehensive care facility or an extended care facility.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The General Assembly intends to promote the interests and well-being of each resident of a facility.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">It is the policy of this State that, in addition to any other rights, each resident of a facility has the following basic rights:<section prefix="(i)">The right to be treated with consideration, respect, and full recognition of human dignity and individuality;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The right to receive treatment, care, and services that are adequate, appropriate, and in compliance with relevant State and federal laws, rules, and regulations;</section><section prefix="(iii)">The right to privacy;</section><section prefix="(iv)">The right to be free from mental and physical abuse;</section><section prefix="(v)">The right to expect and receive appropriate assessment, management, and treatment of pain as an integral component of the patient's care;</section><section prefix="(vi)">The right to be free from physical and chemical restraints, except for restraints that a physician authorizes for a clearly indicated medical need;</section><section prefix="(vii)">The right to receive respect and privacy in a medical care program; and</section><section prefix="(viii)">The right to manage personal financial affairs.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Each facility shall:<section prefix="(1)">Post, conspicuously in a public place, the policy set forth in subsection (b) of this section and the provisions in &#xA7;&#xA7; 19-344(b) through (m), 19-345, and 19-346(i)(2) of this subtitle;</section><section prefix="(2)">Give a copy of the policy and those provisions:<section prefix="(i)">On admission, to the resident;</section><section prefix="(ii)">To the guardian, next of kin, or sponsoring agency of the resident; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">To a representative payee of the resident;</section></section><section prefix="(3)">Keep a receipt for the copy that is signed by the person who received the copy; and</section><section prefix="(4)">Provide appropriate staff training to carry out the policy and those provisions.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
