<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghg" order_by="" level="1">Health - General</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghg-10-806</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>806</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, "responsible official" means:<section prefix="(1)">If the individual is held in a Veterans' Administration hospital, the chief officer of the Veterans' Administration hospital; or</section><section prefix="(2)">If the individual is held in any other facility, the Director or the administrative head of the facility.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">At the direction of the responsible official, an individual who has been admitted under this title shall be released from a facility or a Veterans' Administration hospital if the individual:<section prefix="(1)">Does not have a mental disorder; or</section><section prefix="(2)">Has a mental disorder but:<section prefix="(i)">Does not need inpatient medical care or treatment to protect the individual or another;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Would not endanger the individual or the person or property of another; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Would be cared for properly by the individual or by a responsible person who is able and willing to care for the individual.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">At the direction of the responsible official, any individual who has been admitted under this title shall be released conditionally from a State facility within 2 weeks after the responsible official, with the written consent of the individual:<section prefix="(i)">Certifies that the individual:<section prefix="1.">Would not endanger the individual or the person or property of another; and</section><section prefix="2.">Could live in the community with appropriate assistance under the protective services program provided for in &#xA7; 14-201 of the Family Law Article; and</section></section><section prefix="(ii)">Notifies the provider of the protective services and the local department of social services in the county where the individual would live.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">At the direction of the responsible official, any individual who has been admitted under this title may be released conditionally from a facility other than a State facility or from a Veterans' Administration hospital, if, in the judgment of the responsible official, the individual:<section prefix="(i)">Would be cared for properly by the individual or by a responsible person who is able and willing to care for the individual; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Would not endanger the individual or the person or property of another.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The responsible official may set the conditions for release that the responsible official considers reasonable. The conditions may relate to:<section prefix="(i)">The duration of the release; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">Care or treatment during release.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">As resources allow, services shall be provided to individuals released from a State facility in accordance with the aftercare plan required by &#xA7; 10-809 of this subtitle, as follows:<section prefix="(i)">The Mental Hygiene Administration shall provide community mental health services that are suitable to the needs of the individual;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The Division of Rehabilitation Services shall provide, to individuals determined to be eligible, vocational rehabilitation services and occupational placement opportunities consistent with the assessed needs and abilities of the individual; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">The Department of Human Resources shall provide needed case management services and shall make arrangements for housing suitable to the needs of the individual.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(5)">For purposes of annual examination and execution of new admission documents, an individual released conditionally is considered to be held by the facility or Veterans' Administration hospital from which the individual was released.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A facility shall release an individual who has been admitted to the facility within 1 year after the admission if, before the expiration of that 1-year period:<section prefix="(1)">The individual, whether admitted on a formal, written application or on informal request, does not execute a new application for the voluntary admission;</section><section prefix="(2)">The parent or guardian does not execute a new request for the voluntary admission of the minor individual; or</section><section prefix="(3)">The physician and psychologist or 2 physicians do not execute the new certificates required for involuntary admission of the individual.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">Each determination on any release of an individual, whether full or conditional, including a summary of the reasons for the determination, shall be made a permanent part of the individual's record.</section>
  </text>
</law>
