<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghg" order_by="" level="1">Health - General</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghg-13-1110</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>1110</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The local health officers of two or more counties may join together as a region to apply for a Local Public Health Cancer Grant.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Department may require that two or more counties join together as a region to apply for a Local Public Health Cancer Grant if the Department determines that:<section prefix="(1)">It would be cost-effective to fund cancer prevention, education, screening, and treatment programs for targeted cancers on a regional basis; and</section><section prefix="(2)">It would serve the public health interests of the counties to fund cancer prevention, education, screening, and treatment programs for targeted cancers on a regional basis.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The amount of a Local Public Health Cancer Grant that is distributed to a region under this section shall be equal to the sum of the Local Public Health Cancer Grants that otherwise would have been distributed to each county under the formula established under &#xA7; 13-1108 of this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">If the local health officers of two or more counties choose to join together as a region to apply for a Local Public Health Cancer Grant or are required to do so by the Department, the local health officers shall act jointly to:<section prefix="(1)">Develop a Comprehensive Plan for Cancer Prevention, Education, Screening, and Treatment, as required under &#xA7; 13-1109(c) of this subtitle;</section><section prefix="(2)">Establish a Community Health Coalition, as provided under &#xA7; 13-1111 of this subtitle;</section><section prefix="(3)">Demonstrate that the base-year funding requirement established under &#xA7; 13-1112 of this subtitle has been met; and</section><section prefix="(4)">Otherwise satisfy the requirements of &#xA7;&#xA7; 13-1107 through 13-1113 of this subtitle.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
