<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghg" order_by="" level="1">Health - General</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghg-14-403</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>403</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In addition to the powers set forth elsewhere in this article and subject to the provisions of Title 10 of the State Government Article, on or before October 1, 1987, the Secretary shall adopt regulations for certifying youth camps and for issuing letters of compliance.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">An applicant for a certificate shall submit an application to the Department on the form that the Secretary requires.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">An application for a certificate or for a letter of compliance shall include:<section prefix="1.">The name and permanent mailing address of the applicant;</section><section prefix="2.">The proposed location of the youth camp; and</section><section prefix="3.">Any other information and fee that the Department requires.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">For a unit or agency subject to the provisions of this subtitle, the Secretary shall require the unit or agency to complete only one application for certification for all youth camps directed or operated by that unit or agency.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The Department shall be solely responsible for implementing and enforcing the provisions of this subtitle.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">Except as provided in subparagraph (iii) of this paragraph, the Secretary may impose a fee for the purpose of inspecting, monitoring, and regulating youth camps in accordance with &#xA7; 2-104 of this article.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">A camp accredited or certified in accordance with the provisions of subsection (b)(9) of this section may not be charged a fee under the provisions of this article.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(4)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The operator of a youth camp directed or operated by a bona fide religious organization shall:<section prefix="1.">Submit an application for certification;</section><section prefix="2.">Submit an application for a letter of compliance and have the youth camp inspected by the Department; or</section><section prefix="3.">Submit an application for a letter of compliance and proof of an alternative form of accreditation acceptable to the Secretary under subsection (b)(9) of this section.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">When a youth camp is operating under subparagraph (i) of this paragraph, and an inspection reveals health or safety violations of the regulations adopted under this subtitle, the Secretary may issue an order to abate the violation or to cease operation.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">With due consideration for conditions existing in nature and for the importance of outdoor adventure experiences, the regulations shall include:<section prefix="(1)">Safety procedures for:<section prefix="(i)">Aquatic programs;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Horseback riding;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Firearms control;</section><section prefix="(iv)">Riflery;</section><section prefix="(v)">Archery;</section><section prefix="(vi)">Adventure camps;</section><section prefix="(vii)">Artistic gymnastics;</section><section prefix="(viii)">Hang gliding;</section><section prefix="(ix)">Road cycling;</section><section prefix="(x)">Skiing;</section><section prefix="(xi)">Rock climbing;</section><section prefix="(xii)">Spelunking;</section><section prefix="(xiii)">Motorized vehicle activities;</section><section prefix="(xiv)">Rappelling; or</section><section prefix="(xv)">High ropes;</section></section><section prefix="(2)">Except for outdoor cookouts, sanitation regulations pertaining to the facilities and personnel for the storage, preparation, and serving of food products;</section><section prefix="(3)">Personal health, first aid, and medical services, health supervision, and the maintenance of health records for campers;</section><section prefix="(4)">Water supplies, sewage disposal systems, and refuse collection and disposal procedures;</section><section prefix="(5)">Fire and safety standards relating to the buildings and the occupants of buildings;</section><section prefix="(6)">Systems for the routine reporting of fatalities and serious illnesses or accidents;</section><section prefix="(7)">Any personnel screening procedures that are required for operators and employees of group day care centers;</section><section prefix="(8)">Procedures for conducting inspection, monitoring compliance, and verifying information;</section><section prefix="(9)">Alternate accreditation which has been approved by the Secretary; and</section><section prefix="(10)">Minimum standards for the supervision of campers during routine activities.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Secretary may not adopt regulations that set ratios for camper to medical staff personnel except for:<section prefix="(1)">Camp health supervisors at a camp where 50% or more of the campers have identified medical problems;</section><section prefix="(2)">Personnel required to meet emergency safety standards, for example the number of persons that require certification in cardiopulmonary resuscitation (CPR) and first aid; and</section><section prefix="(3)">Camp health supervisors, or their designees, trained to administer medicine to campers.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Secretary shall cooperate with other departments or agencies to facilitate the activities of the departments or agencies in carrying out responsibilities for enforcing the laws and regulations relating to youth camps.</section>
  </text>
</law>
