<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghg" order_by="" level="1">Health - General</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghg-5-513</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>513</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">On taking custody of the body of a decedent in accordance with all authorizations required by law, a funeral establishment or crematory shall maintain the body in a manner that provides for complete coverage of the body and prevents leakage or spillage except during:<section prefix="(1)">Identification, embalming, or preparation of an unembalmed body for final disposition;</section><section prefix="(2)">Restoration and dressing of a body in preparation for final disposition; and</section><section prefix="(3)">Viewing during a visitation or funeral service.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">If the unembalmed body of a decedent is to be stored for more than 48 hours before final disposition, a funeral establishment or crematory shall maintain the body with refrigeration and at a temperature determined by regulation.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If a funeral establishment or crematory cannot secure the body of a decedent or cannot store the body as required in subsection (b) of this section due to an unforeseen circumstance, the funeral establishment or crematory shall notify the State Board of Morticians and Funeral Directors or the Office of Cemetery Oversight and the person authorized to arrange for the final disposition of the body under &#xA7; 5-509 of this subtitle.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The notification required under paragraph (1) of this subsection shall:<section prefix="(i)">Be made within 24 hours after the occurrence of the unforeseen circumstance; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Include the name and location of the facility where the body is being transferred, the reason for the transfer, and the method of storage.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The body of a decedent may not be embalmed or artificially preserved without:<section prefix="(1)">The express permission of the person authorized to arrange for the final disposition of the body under &#xA7; 5-509 of this subtitle; or</section><section prefix="(2)">A court order.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">A funeral establishment or crematory shall store the body of a decedent until final disposition at:<section prefix="(1)">A funeral establishment licensed under Title 7 of the Health Occupations Article;</section><section prefix="(2)">A crematory licensed under Title 7 of the Health Occupations Article;</section><section prefix="(3)">A crematory permitted under Title 5 of the Business Regulation Article; or</section><section prefix="(4)">Another facility that has passed an inspection with the State Board of Morticians and Funeral Directors or the Office of Cemetery Oversight within the past 2 years.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">A funeral establishment, crematory, or transportation service may not transport or store the body of a decedent together with animal remains in the same confined space.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, while the body of a decedent is in the custody of a funeral establishment or crematory in the State, the body may not be transported for preparation or storage to a facility that is not within the jurisdiction of the State, licensed by the State Board of Morticians and Funeral Directors, or permitted by the Office of Cemetery Oversight.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The body of a decedent may be transported for preparation or storage to a facility that is not within the jurisdiction of the State, licensed by the State Board of Morticians and Funeral Directors, or permitted by the Office of Cemetery Oversight if:<section prefix="(i)">The facility has entered into a written agreement with the State Board of Morticians and Funeral Directors or the Office of Cemetery Oversight to allow the State to make unannounced inspections of the facility; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">The person authorized to arrange for the final disposition of the body under &#xA7; 5-509 of this subtitle:<section prefix="1.">Has given written permission for the body to be transported to the facility; or</section><section prefix="2."/></section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
