<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghg" order_by="" level="1">Health - General</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghg-24-804</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>804</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Mayor of Baltimore City shall appoint an oversight committee for the Program.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The oversight committee shall consist of:<section prefix="(1)">Two representatives from academia who specialize in public health issues;</section><section prefix="(2)">One representative from law enforcement, nominated by the Secretary of the Department of Public Safety and Correctional Services;</section><section prefix="(3)">One representative of the Baltimore City Police Department;</section><section prefix="(4)">Two representatives from the Department of Health and Mental Hygiene, the Department of Juvenile Services, or the Department of Education, nominated by the Secretary of Health and Mental Hygiene;</section><section prefix="(5)">One representative of a Baltimore City community group;</section><section prefix="(6)">One representative of an AIDS advocacy group;</section><section prefix="(7)">One drug abuse treatment counselor;</section><section prefix="(8)">One recovering injecting drug user; and</section><section prefix="(9)">Up to three other individuals whom the Mayor of Baltimore City determines to be appropriate for appointment to the oversight committee.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The oversight committee shall:<section prefix="(1)">Provide advice to the Commissioner of Health and the Program Director on developing:<section prefix="(i)">Program operating procedures for the furnishing and one-for-one exchange of hypodermic needles and syringes to injecting drug users;</section><section prefix="(ii)">A plan for community outreach and education;</section><section prefix="(iii)">A protocol for providing a linkage for Program participants to substance abuse treatment and rehabilitation; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">A plan for evaluating the Program;</section></section><section prefix="(2)">Before the Program begins operating, review and make a recommendation to the Commissioner of Health for the approval or disapproval of:<section prefix="(i)">The Program operating procedures for the furnishing and one-for-one exchange of hypodermic needles and syringes to injecting drug users;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The community outreach and education plan;</section><section prefix="(iii)">The protocol for providing a linkage for Program participants to substance abuse treatment and rehabilitation; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">The plan for evaluating the Program; and</section></section><section prefix="(3)">Provide ongoing oversight of the Program and make recommendations to the Program Director or the Commissioner of Health regarding any aspect of Program procedures, operation, or evaluation.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
