<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghg" order_by="" level="1">Health - General</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghg-14-501</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>501</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Concussion" means a traumatic injury to the brain causing an immediate and, usually, short-lived change in mental status or an alteration of normal consciousness resulting from:<section prefix="(i)">A fall;</section><section prefix="(ii)">A violent blow to the head or body; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">The shaking or spinning of the head or body.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Youth athlete" means an individual who participates in an athletic activity in association with a youth sports program conducted:<section prefix="(i)">At a public school facility; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">By a recreational athletic organization.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">"Youth sports program" means a program organized for recreational athletic competition or instruction for participants who are under the age of 19 years.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A youth sports program shall make available information on concussions and head injuries developed by the State Department of Education under &#xA7; 7-433 of the Education Article to coaches, youth athletes, and the parents or guardians of youth athletes.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A coach of a youth sports program shall review the information provided in paragraph (1) of this subsection.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A youth athlete who is suspected of sustaining a concussion or other head injury in a practice or game shall be removed from play at that time.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A youth athlete who has been removed from play may not return to play until the youth athlete has obtained written clearance from a licensed health care provider trained in the evaluation and management of concussions.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Before a youth sports program may use a facility owned or operated by a local government, the local government shall provide notice to the youth sports program of the requirements of this section.</section>
  </text>
</law>
