<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="ghg" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="18-906" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghg-18-906</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If the Secretary requires an individual or a group of individuals to go to and remain in places of isolation or quarantine under &#xA7; 18-905 of this subtitle, the Secretary shall issue a directive to the individual or group of individuals.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The directive shall specify:<section prefix="(i)">The identity of the individual or group of individuals subject to isolation or quarantine;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The premises subject to isolation or quarantine;</section><section prefix="(iii)">The date and time at which isolation or quarantine commences;</section><section prefix="(iv)">The suspected deadly agent causing the outbreak or disease, if known;</section><section prefix="(v)">The basis upon which isolation or quarantine is justified; and</section><section prefix="(vi)">The availability of a hearing to contest the directive.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Except as provided in subparagraph (ii) of this paragraph, the directive shall be in writing and given to the individual or group of individuals prior to the individual or group of individuals being required to go to and remain in places of isolation and quarantine.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)"/>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">An individual or group of individuals isolated or quarantined under subsection (a) of this section may request a hearing in circuit court contesting the isolation or quarantine.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A request for a hearing may not stay or enjoin an isolation or quarantine directive.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Upon receipt of a request under this subsection, the court shall conduct a hearing within 3 days from receipt of the request.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">
        <section prefix="(i)">In any proceedings brought for relief under this subsection, the court may extend the time for a hearing upon a showing by the Secretary or other designated official that extraordinary circumstances exist that justify the extension.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">In granting or denying an extension, the court shall consider the rights of the affected individual, the protection of the public health, the severity of the catastrophic health emergency, and the availability, if necessary, of witnesses and evidence.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(5)">
        <section prefix="(i)"/>
        <section prefix="(ii)"/>
        <section prefix="(iii)">An order authorizing isolation or quarantine is effective for a period not to exceed 30 days.</section>
        <section prefix="(iv)"/>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(6)">In the event that an individual cannot personally appear before the court, proceedings may be conducted:<section prefix="(i)">By an individual's authorized representative; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Through any means that allow other individuals to fully participate.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(7)">In any proceedings brought under this subsection, the court may order the consolidation of individual claims into group claims where:<section prefix="(i)">The number of individuals involved or affected is so large as to render individual participation impractical;</section><section prefix="(ii)">There are questions of law or fact common to the individual claims or rights to be determined;</section><section prefix="(iii)">The group claims or rights to be determined are typical of the affected individual's claims or rights; or</section><section prefix="(iv)">The entire group will be adequately represented in the consolidation.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The court shall appoint counsel to represent individuals or a group of individuals who are not otherwise represented by counsel.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The court of appeals shall develop emergency rules of procedure to facilitate the efficient adjudication of any proceedings brought under this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">It shall be unlawful for any public or private employer to discharge an employee who is under an order of isolation or quarantine or because of such an order.</section>
  </text>
</law>
