<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="ghg" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="16-201.1" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghg-16-201.1</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Secretary shall make an assessment of the Department's health care services and ability-to-pay schedule for prenatal and infant care services offered through local health agencies.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The assessment shall include the following:<section prefix="(1)">The availability of efficient health care services and providers;</section><section prefix="(2)">The identification of health care services that are not available;</section><section prefix="(3)">Access to health care;</section><section prefix="(4)">The need for specific health care;</section><section prefix="(5)">An evaluation of alternative means of providing health care services; and</section><section prefix="(6)">Financial and manpower resources required and available.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">An applicant for services under this section shall receive:<section prefix="(1)">A personal financial consultation without charge to assess the applicant's ability to pay for health care offered through local health agencies; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Notification of the right to obtain services offered through local health agencies regardless of ability to pay.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Secretary shall adopt regulations necessary to carry out the provisions of this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Local health agencies shall implement uniform procedures to notify and consult potential prenatal and infant care services recipients.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Reduced rates for recipients of services shall be applied fairly and uniformly, and according to the sliding fee scale developed by the Department.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
