<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghg" order_by="" level="1">Health - General</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghg-15-103</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>103</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Secretary shall administer the Maryland Medical Assistance Program.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Program:<section prefix="(i)">Subject to the limitations of the State budget, shall provide medical and other health care services for indigent individuals or medically indigent individuals or both;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Shall provide, subject to the limitations of the State budget, comprehensive medical and other health care services for all eligible pregnant women whose family income is at or below 250 percent of the poverty level, as permitted by the federal law;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Shall provide, subject to the limitations of the State budget, comprehensive medical and other health care services for all eligible children currently under the age of 1 whose family income falls below 185 percent of the poverty level, as permitted by federal law;</section><section prefix="(iv)">Beginning on January 1, 2012, shall provide, subject to the limitations of the State budget, family planning services to all women whose family income is at or below 200 percent of the poverty level, as permitted by federal law;</section><section prefix="(v)">Shall provide, subject to the limitations of the State budget, comprehensive medical and other health care services for all children from the age of 1 year up through and including the age of 5 years whose family income falls below 133 percent of the poverty level, as permitted by the federal law;</section><section prefix="(vi)">Shall provide, subject to the limitations of the State budget, comprehensive medical care and other health care services for all children who are at least 6 years of age but are under 19 years of age whose family income falls below 100 percent of the poverty level, as permitted by federal law;</section><section prefix="(vii)">Shall provide, subject to the limitations of the State budget, comprehensive medical care and other health care services for all legal immigrants who meet Program eligibility standards and who arrived in the United States before August 22, 1996, the effective date of the federal Personal Responsibility and Work Opportunity Reconciliation Act, as permitted by federal law;</section><section prefix="(viii)">Shall provide, subject to the limitations of the State budget and any other requirements imposed by the State, comprehensive medical care and other health care services for all legal immigrant children under the age of 18 years and pregnant women who meet Program eligibility standards and who arrived in the United States on or after August 22, 1996, the effective date of the federal Personal Responsibility and Work Opportunity Reconciliation Act;</section><section prefix="(ix)">Beginning on July 1, 2008, shall provide, subject to the limitations of the State budget, and as permitted by federal law, comprehensive medical care and other health care services for all parents and caretaker relatives:<section prefix="1.">Who have a dependent child living in the parents' or caretaker relatives' home; and</section><section prefix="2.">Whose annual household income is at or below 116 percent of the poverty level;</section></section><section prefix="(x)">Beginning on July 1, 2008, shall provide, subject to the limitations of the State budget, and as permitted by federal law, medical care and other health care services for adults:<section prefix="1.">Who do not meet requirements, such as age, disability, or parent or caretaker relative of a dependent child, for a federal category of eligibility for Medicaid;</section><section prefix="2.">Whose annual household income is at or below 116 percent of the poverty level; and</section><section prefix="3.">Who are not enrolled in the federal Medicare program, as enacted by Title XVIII of the Social Security Act;</section></section><section prefix="(xi)">Shall provide, subject to the limitations of the State budget, and as permitted by federal law, comprehensive medical care and other health care services for independent foster care adolescents:<section prefix="1.">Who are not otherwise eligible for Program benefits; and</section><section prefix="2.">Whose annual household income is at or below 300 percent of the poverty level;</section></section><section prefix="(xii)">May include bedside nursing care for eligible Program recipients; and</section><section prefix="(xiii)">Shall provide services in accordance with funding restrictions included in the annual State budget bill.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Subject to restrictions in federal law or waivers, the Department may:<section prefix="(i)">Impose cost-sharing on Program recipients; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">For adults who do not meet requirements for a federal category of eligibility for Medicaid:<section prefix="1.">Cap enrollment; and</section><section prefix="2.">Limit the benefit package, except that substance abuse services shall be provided that are at least equivalent to the substance abuse services provided to adults under paragraph (2)(ix) of this subsection.</section></section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">In fiscal year 2011 and each fiscal year thereafter, the Governor shall include in the State budget funding sufficient to provide the substance abuse benefits required under paragraph (3)(ii)2 of this subsection.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">As permitted by federal law or waiver, the Secretary may establish a program under which Program recipients are required to enroll in managed care organizations.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The benefits required by the program developed under paragraph (1) of this subsection shall be adopted by regulation and shall be equivalent to the benefit level required by the Maryland Medical Assistance Program on January 1, 1996.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">Subject to the limitations of the State budget and as permitted by federal law or waiver, the Department shall provide reimbursement for medically necessary and appropriate inpatient, intermediate care, and halfway house substance abuse treatment services for substance abusing enrollees 21 years of age or older who are recipients of temporary cash assistance under the Family Investment Program.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">Each managed care organization participating in the program developed under paragraph (1) of this subsection shall provide or arrange for the provision of the benefits described in subparagraph (ii) of this paragraph.</section>
        <section prefix="(iv)">Nothing in this paragraph may be construed to prohibit a managed care organization from offering additional benefits, if the managed care organization is not receiving capitation payments based on the provision of the additional benefits.</section>
        <section prefix="(v)">Notwithstanding subparagraph (i) of this paragraph, the benefits required by the program developed under paragraph (1) of this subsection shall include dental services for pregnant women.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Subject to the limitations of the State budget and as permitted by federal law or waiver, the program developed under paragraph (1) of this subsection and the program developed under &#xA7; 15-301 of this title may provide guaranteed eligibility for each enrollee for up to 6 months, unless an enrollee obtains health insurance through another source.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The Secretary may exclude specific populations or services from the program developed under paragraph (1) of this subsection.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">For any populations or services excluded under this paragraph, the Secretary may authorize a managed care organization, to provide the services or provide for the population, including authorization of a separate dental managed care organization or a managed care organization to provide services to Program recipients with special needs.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(5)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Except for a service excluded by the Secretary under paragraph (4) of this subsection, each managed care organization shall provide all the benefits required by regulations adopted under paragraph (2) of this subsection.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">For a population or service excluded by the Secretary under paragraph (4) of this subsection, the Secretary may authorize a managed care organization to provide only for that population or provide only that service.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">A managed care organization may subcontract specified required services to a health care provider that is licensed or authorized to provide those services.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(6)">Except for the Program of All-inclusive Care for the Elderly ("PACE") Program, the Secretary may not include the long-term care population or long-term care services in the program developed under paragraph (1) of this subsection.</section>
      <section prefix="(7)">The program developed under paragraph (1) of this subsection shall ensure that enrollees have access to a pharmacy that:<section prefix="(i)">Is licensed in the State; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Is within a reasonable distance from the enrollee's residence.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(8)">For cause, the Department may disenroll enrollees from a managed care organization and enroll them in another managed care organization.</section>
      <section prefix="(9)">Each managed care organization shall:<section prefix="(i)">Have a quality assurance program in effect which is subject to the approval of the Department and which, at a minimum:<section prefix="1.">Complies with any health care quality improvement system developed by the Centers for Medicare and Medicaid Services;</section><section prefix="2.">Complies with the quality requirements of applicable State licensure laws and regulations;</section><section prefix="3.">Complies with practice guidelines and protocols specified by the Department;</section><section prefix="4.">Provides for an enrollee grievance system, including an enrollee hotline;</section><section prefix="5.">Provides a provider grievance system;</section><section prefix="6.">Provides for enrollee and provider satisfaction surveys, to be taken at least annually;</section><section prefix="7.">Provides for a consumer advisory board to receive regular input from enrollees;</section><section prefix="8.">Provides for an annual consumer advisory board report to be submitted to the Secretary; and</section><section prefix="9.">Complies with specific quality, access, data, and performance measurements adopted by the Department for treating enrollees with special needs;</section></section><section prefix="(ii)">Submit to the Department:<section prefix="1.">Service-specific data by service type in a format to be established by the Department;</section><section prefix="2.">Utilization and outcome reports, such as the Health Plan Employer Data and Information Set (HEDIS), as directed by the Department; and</section><section prefix="3.">At least semiannually, aggregate data that includes:</section></section><section prefix="(iii)">Promote timely access to and continuity of health care services for enrollees;</section><section prefix="(iv)">Demonstrate organizational capacity to provide special programs, including outreach, case management, and home visiting, tailored to meet the individual needs of all enrollees;</section><section prefix="(v)">Provide assistance to enrollees in securing necessary health care services;</section><section prefix="(vi)">Provide or assure alcohol and drug abuse treatment for substance abusing pregnant women and all other enrollees of managed care organizations who require these services;</section><section prefix="(vii)">Educate enrollees on health care prevention and good health habits;</section><section prefix="(viii)">Assure necessary provider capacity in all geographic areas under contract;</section><section prefix="(ix)">Be accountable and hold its subcontractors accountable for standards established by the Department and, upon failure to meet those standards, be subject to one or more of the following penalties:<section prefix="1.">Fines;</section><section prefix="2.">Suspension of further enrollments;</section><section prefix="3.">Withholding of all or part of the capitation payment;</section><section prefix="4.">Termination of the contract;</section><section prefix="5.">Disqualification from future participation in the Program; and</section><section prefix="6.">Any other penalties that may be imposed by the Department;</section></section><section prefix="(x)">Subject to applicable federal and State law, include incentives for enrollees to comply with provisions of the managed care organization;</section><section prefix="(xi)">Provide or arrange to provide primary mental health services;</section><section prefix="(xii)">Provide or arrange to provide all Medicaid-covered services required to comply with State statutes and regulations mandating health and mental health services for children in State supervised care:<section prefix="1.">According to standards set by the Department; and</section><section prefix="2.">Locally, to the extent the services are available locally;</section></section><section prefix="(xiii)">Submit to the Department aggregate information from the quality assurance program, including complaints and resolutions from the enrollee and provider grievance systems, the enrollee hotline, and enrollee satisfaction surveys;</section><section prefix="(xiv)">Maintain as part of the enrollee's medical record the following information:<section prefix="1.">The basic health risk assessment conducted on enrollment;</section><section prefix="2.">Any information the managed care organization receives that results from an assessment of the enrollee conducted for the purpose of any early intervention, evaluation, planning, or case management program;</section><section prefix="3.">Information from the local department of social services regarding any other service or benefit the enrollee receives, including assistance or benefits from a program administered by the Department of Human Resources under the Human Services Article; and</section><section prefix="4.">Any information the managed care organization receives from a school-based clinic, a core services agency, a local health department, or any other person that has provided health services to the enrollee;</section></section><section prefix="(xv)">Upon provision of information specified by the Department under paragraph (19) of this subsection, pay school-based clinics for services provided to the managed care organization's enrollees; and</section><section prefix="(xvi)">In coordination with participating dentists, enrollees, and families of enrollees, develop a process to arrange to provide dental therapeutic treatment to individuals under 21 years of age that requires:<section prefix="1.">A participating dentist to notify a managed care organization when an enrollee is in need of therapeutic treatment and the dentist is unable to provide the treatment;</section><section prefix="2.">A managed care organization to provide the enrollee or the family of the enrollee with a list of participating providers who offer therapeutic dental services; and</section><section prefix="3.">A managed care organization to notify the enrollee or the family of the enrollee that the managed care organization will provide further assistance if the enrollee has difficulty obtaining an appointment with a provider of therapeutic dental services.</section></section></section>
      <section prefix="(10)">The Department shall adopt regulations that assure that managed care organizations employ appropriate personnel to:<section prefix="(i)">Assure that individuals with special needs obtain needed services; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Coordinate those services.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(11)">
        <section prefix="(i)">A managed care organization shall reimburse a hospital emergency facility and provider for:<section prefix="1.">Health care services that meet the definition of emergency services in &#xA7; 19-701 of this article;</section><section prefix="2.">Medical screening services rendered to meet the requirements of the federal Emergency Medical Treatment and Active Labor Act;</section><section prefix="3.">Medically necessary services if the managed care organization authorized, referred, or otherwise allowed the enrollee to use the emergency facility and the medically necessary services are related to the condition for which the enrollee was allowed to use the emergency facility; and</section><section prefix="4.">Medically necessary services that relate to the condition presented and that are provided by the provider in the emergency facility to the enrollee if the managed care organization fails to provide 24-hour access to a physician as required by the Department.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">A provider may not be required to obtain prior authorization or approval for payment from a managed care organization in order to obtain reimbursement under this paragraph.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(12)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Each managed care organization shall notify each enrollee when the enrollee should obtain an immunization, examination, or other wellness service.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">Each managed care organization shall:<section prefix="1.">Maintain evidence of compliance with paragraph (9) of this subsection; and</section><section prefix="2.">Provide to the Department, upon initial application to provide health care services to enrollees and on an annual basis thereafter, evidence of compliance with paragraph (9) of this subsection, including submission of a written plan.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">A managed care organization that does not comply with subparagraph (i) of this paragraph for at least 90% of its new enrollees:<section prefix="1.">Within 90 days of their enrollment may not receive more than 80% of its capitation payments;</section><section prefix="2.">Within 180 days of their enrollment may not receive more than 70% of its capitation payments; and</section><section prefix="3.">Within 270 days of their enrollment may not receive more than 50% of its capitation payments.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(iv)">If a managed care organization does not comply with the requirements of paragraph (9) of this subsection, the Department may contract with any community-based health organization that the Department determines is willing and able to perform comprehensive outreach services to enrollees.</section>
        <section prefix="(v)">In addition to the provisions of subparagraph (iv) of this paragraph, if a managed care organization does not comply with the requirements of paragraph (9) of this subsection or fails to provide evidence of compliance to the Department under subparagraph (ii) of this paragraph, the Department may:<section prefix="1.">Impose a fine on the managed care organization which shall be deposited in the HealthChoice Performance Incentive Fund established under &#xA7; 15-103.3 of this subtitle;</section><section prefix="2.">Suspend further enrollment into the managed care organization;</section><section prefix="3.">Withhold all or part of the capitation rate from the managed care organization;</section><section prefix="4.">Terminate the provider agreement; or</section><section prefix="5.">Disqualify the managed care organization from future participation in the Maryland Medicaid Managed Care Program.</section></section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(13)">The Department shall:<section prefix="(i)">Establish and maintain an ombudsman program and a locally accessible enrollee hotline;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Perform focused medical reviews of managed care organizations that include reviews of how the managed care organizations are providing health care services to special populations;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Provide timely feedback to each managed care organization on its compliance with the Department's quality and access system;</section><section prefix="(iv)">Establish and maintain within the Department a process for handling provider complaints about managed care organizations; and</section><section prefix="(v)">Adopt regulations relating to appeals by managed care organizations of penalties imposed by the Department, including regulations providing for an appeal to the Office of Administrative Hearings.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(14)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Except as provided in subparagraph (iii) of this paragraph, the Department shall delegate responsibility for maintaining the ombudsman program for a county to that county's local health department on the request of the local health department.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">A local health department may not subcontract the ombudsman program.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">Before the Department delegates responsibility to a local health department to maintain the ombudsman program for a county, a local health department that is also a Medicaid provider must receive the approval of the Secretary and the local governing body.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(15)">A managed care organization may not:<section prefix="(i)">Without authorization by the Department, enroll an individual who at the time is a Program recipient; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">Have face-to-face or telephone contact, or otherwise solicit with an individual who at the time is a Program recipient before the Program recipient enrolls in the managed care organization unless:<section prefix="1.">Authorized by the Department; or</section><section prefix="2.">The Program recipient initiates contact.</section></section></section>
      <section prefix="(16)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The Department shall be responsible for enrolling Program recipients into managed care organizations.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The Department may contract with an entity to perform the enrollment function.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">The Department or its enrollment contractor shall administer a health risk assessment developed by the Department to ensure that individuals who need special or immediate health care services will receive the services on a timely basis.</section>
        <section prefix="(iv)">The Department or its enrollment contractor:<section prefix="1.">May administer the health risk assessment only after the Program recipient has chosen a managed care organization; and</section><section prefix="2.">Shall forward the results of the health risk assessment to the managed care organization chosen by the Program recipient within 5 business days.</section></section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(17)">For a managed care organization with which the Secretary contracts to provide services to Program recipients under this subsection, the Secretary shall establish a mechanism to initially assure that each historic provider that meets the Department's quality standards has the opportunity to continue to serve Program recipients as a subcontractor of at least one managed care organization.</section>
      <section prefix="(18)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The Department shall make capitation payments to each managed care organization as provided in this paragraph.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">In consultation with the Insurance Commissioner, the Secretary shall:<section prefix="1.">Set capitation payments at a level that is actuarially adjusted to the benefits provided; and</section><section prefix="2.">Actuarially adjust the capitation payments to reflect the relative risk assumed by the managed care organization.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">In actuarially adjusting capitation payments under subparagraph (ii)2 of this paragraph, the Secretary, in consultation with the Insurance Commissioner, shall take into account, to the extent allowed under federal law, the expenses incurred by the managed care organization applicable to the business of providing care to enrolled individuals.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(19)">
        <section prefix="(i)">School-based clinics and managed care organizations shall collaborate to provide continuity of care to enrollees.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">School-based clinics shall be defined by the Department in consultation with the State Department of Education.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">Each managed care organization shall require a school-based clinic to provide to the managed care organization certain information, as specified by the Department, about an encounter with an enrollee of the managed care organization prior to paying the school-based clinic.</section>
        <section prefix="(iv)">Upon receipt of information specified by the Department, the managed care organization shall pay, at Medicaid-established rates, school-based clinics for covered services provided to enrollees of the managed care organization.</section>
        <section prefix="(v)">The Department shall work with managed care organizations and school-based clinics to develop collaboration standards, guidelines, and a process to assure that the services provided are covered and medically appropriate and that the process provides for timely notification among the parties.</section>
        <section prefix="(vi)">Each managed care organization shall maintain records of all health care services:<section prefix="1.">Provided to its enrollees by school-based clinics; and</section><section prefix="2.">For which the managed care organization has been billed.</section></section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(20)">The Department shall establish standards for the timely delivery of services to enrollees.</section>
      <section prefix="(21)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The Department shall establish a delivery system for specialty mental health services for enrollees of managed care organizations.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The Mental Hygiene Administration shall:<section prefix="1.">Design and monitor the delivery system;</section><section prefix="2.">Establish performance standards for providers in the delivery system; and</section><section prefix="3.">Establish procedures to ensure appropriate and timely referrals from managed care organizations to the delivery system that include:</section></section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">The Department shall collaborate with managed care organizations to develop standards and guidelines for the provision of specialty mental health services.</section>
        <section prefix="(iv)">The delivery system shall:<section prefix="1.">Provide all specialty mental health services needed by enrollees;</section><section prefix="2.">For enrollees who are dually diagnosed, coordinate the provision of substance abuse services provided by the managed care organizations of the enrollees;</section><section prefix="3.">Consist of a network of qualified mental health professionals from all core disciplines;</section><section prefix="4.">Include linkages with other public service systems; and</section><section prefix="5.">Comply with quality assurance, enrollee input, data collection, and other requirements specified by the Department in regulation.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(v)">The Department may contract with a managed care organization for delivery of specialty mental health services if the managed care organization meets the performance standards adopted by the Department in regulations.</section>
        <section prefix="(vi)">The provisions of &#xA7; 15-1005 of the Insurance Article apply to the delivery system for specialty mental health services established under this paragraph and administered by an administrative services organization.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(22)">The Department shall include a definition of medical necessity in its quality and access standards.</section>
      <section prefix="(23)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The Department shall adopt regulations relating to enrollment, disenrollment, and enrollee appeals.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">Program recipients shall have the right to choose:<section prefix="1.">The managed care organization with which they are enrolled; and</section><section prefix="2.">The primary care provider to whom they are assigned within the managed care organization.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">If a recipient is disenrolled and reenrolls within 120 days of the recipient's disenrollment, the Department shall:<section prefix="1.">Assign the recipient to the managed care organization in which the recipient previously was enrolled; and</section><section prefix="2.">Require the managed care organization to assign the recipient to the primary care provider of record at the time of the recipient's disenrollment.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(iv)">Whenever a recipient has to select a new managed care organization because the recipient's managed care organization has departed from the HealthChoice Program, the departing managed care organization:<section prefix="1.">Shall provide a written notice to the recipient 60 days before departing from the Program;</section><section prefix="2.">Shall include in the notice the name and provider number of the primary care provider assigned to the recipient and the telephone number of the enrollment broker; and</section><section prefix="3.">Within 30 days after departing from the Program, shall provide the Department with a list of enrollees and the name of each enrollee's primary care provider.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(v)">On receiving the list provided by the managed care organization, the Department shall provide the list to:<section prefix="1.">The enrollment broker to assist and provide outreach to recipients in selecting a managed care organization; and</section><section prefix="2.">The remaining managed care organizations for the purpose of linking recipients with a primary care provider in accordance with federal law and regulation.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(vi)">Subject to subsection (f)(4) and (5) of this section, an enrollee may disenroll from a managed care organization:<section prefix="1.">Without cause in the month following the anniversary date of the enrollee's enrollment; and</section><section prefix="2.">For cause, at any time as determined by the Secretary.</section></section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(24)">The Department or its subcontractor, to the extent feasible in its marketing or enrollment programs, shall hire individuals receiving assistance under the program of Aid to Families with Dependent Children established under Title IV, Part A, of the Social Security Act, or the successor to the program.</section>
      <section prefix="(25)">The Department shall disenroll an enrollee who is a child in State-supervised care if the child is transferred to an area outside of the territory of the managed care organization.</section>
      <section prefix="(26)">The Secretary shall adopt regulations to implement the provisions of this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(27)">
        <section prefix="(i)">
          <section prefix="1.">The Department shall establish the Maryland Medicaid Advisory Committee, composed of no more than 25 members.</section>
          <section prefix="2.">The majority of the members of the Committee shall be enrollees or enrollee advocates.</section>
          <section prefix="3.">At least five members of the Committee shall be enrollees representative of the entire Medicaid population.</section>
        </section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The Committee members shall include:<section prefix="1.">At least five current or former enrollees or the parents or guardians of current or former enrollees;</section><section prefix="2.">Providers who are familiar with the medical needs of low-income population groups, including board-certified physicians;</section><section prefix="3.">Hospital representatives;</section><section prefix="4.">At least five but not more than 10 advocates for the Medicaid population, including representatives of special needs populations, such as:</section><section prefix="5.">Two members of the Finance Committee of the Senate of Maryland, appointed by the President of the Senate; and</section><section prefix="6.">Three members of the Maryland House of Delegates, appointed by the Speaker of the House.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">A designee of each of the following shall serve as an ex-officio member of the Committee:<section prefix="1.">The Secretary of Human Resources;</section><section prefix="2.">The Executive Director of the Maryland Health Care Commission; and</section><section prefix="3.">The Maryland Association of County Health Officers.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(iv)">In addition to any duties imposed by federal law and regulation, the Committee shall:<section prefix="1.">Advise the Secretary on the implementation, operation, and evaluation of managed care programs under this section;</section><section prefix="2.">Review and make recommendations on the regulations developed to implement managed care programs under this section;</section><section prefix="3.">Review and make recommendations on the standards used in contracts between the Department and managed care organizations;</section><section prefix="4.">Review and make recommendations on the Department's oversight of quality assurance standards;</section><section prefix="5.">Review data collected by the Department from managed care organizations participating in the Program and data collected by the Maryland Health Care Commission;</section><section prefix="6.">Promote the dissemination of managed care organization performance information, including loss ratios, to enrollees in a manner that facilitates quality comparisons and uses layman's language;</section><section prefix="7.">Assist the Department in evaluating the enrollment process; and</section><section prefix="8.">Review reports of the ombudsmen.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(v)">Except as specified in subparagraphs (ii) and (iii) of this paragraph, the members of the Maryland Medicaid Advisory Committee shall be appointed by the Secretary and serve for a 4-year term.</section>
        <section prefix="(vi)">In making appointments to the Committee, the Secretary shall provide for continuity and rotation.</section>
        <section prefix="(vii)">In appointing consumer members to the Committee, the Secretary shall seek recommendations from:<section prefix="1.">The State Protection and Advocacy System Organization;</section><section prefix="2.">The Statewide Independent Living Council;</section><section prefix="3.">The Developmental Disabilities Council;</section><section prefix="4.">The Department of Disabilities;</section><section prefix="5.">The Department of Aging;</section><section prefix="6.">Consumer advocacy organizations; and</section><section prefix="7.">The public.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(viii)">The Secretary shall appoint the chair of the Committee.</section>
        <section prefix="(ix)">The Secretary shall appoint nonvoting members from managed care organizations who may participate in Committee meetings, unless the Committee meets in closed session as provided in &#xA7; 10-508 of the State Government Article.</section>
        <section prefix="(x)">The Department shall provide staff for the Committee.</section>
        <section prefix="(xi)">The Committee shall determine the times and places of its meetings.</section>
        <section prefix="(xii)">
          <section prefix="1.">The chair of the Committee and the staff for the Committee shall provide the agenda, minutes, and any written materials to be presented or discussed at a meeting to the members of the Committee at least 5 days prior to the meeting.</section>
          <section prefix="2.">The agenda, minutes, and written materials shall be provided to members of the Committee in a manner and format that reasonably accommodates the specific needs of the member.</section>
        </section>
        <section prefix="(xiii)">
          <section prefix="1.">Except as provided in subsubparagraph 2 of this subparagraph, a member of the Committee:</section>
          <section prefix="2.">A member of the Committee who is an enrollee is entitled to reimbursement for:</section>
          <section prefix="3.">On request, the Department shall provide for a dedicated Department staff person:</section>
        </section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(28)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The Department shall ensure that payments for services provided by a hospital located in a contiguous state or in the District of Columbia to an enrollee under the Program shall be reduced by 20% if the hospital fails to submit discharge data on all Maryland patients receiving care in the hospital to the Health Services Cost Review Commission in a form and manner the Commission specifies.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">Subparagraph (i) of this paragraph does not apply to a hospital that presently provides discharge data to the public in a form the Health Services Cost Review Commission determines is satisfactory.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(29)">A managed care organization shall provide coverage for hearing loss screenings of newborns provided by a hospital before discharge.</section>
      <section prefix="(30)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The Department shall provide enrollees and health care providers with an accurate directory or other listing of all available providers:<section prefix="1.">In written form, made available upon request; and</section><section prefix="2.">On an Internet database.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The Department shall update the Internet database at least every 30 days.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">The written directory shall include a conspicuous reference to the Internet database.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">In this subsection the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">"Certified nurse practitioner" means a registered nurse who is licensed in this State, has completed a nurse practitioner program approved by the State Board of Nursing, and has passed an examination approved by that Board.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">"Nurse anesthetist" means a registered nurse who is:<section prefix="1.">Certified under the Health Occupations Article to practice nurse anesthesia; and</section><section prefix="2.">Certified by the Council on Certification or the Council on Recertification of Nurse Anesthetists.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(iv)">"Nurse midwife" means a registered nurse who is licensed in this State and has been certified by the American College of Nurse-Midwives as a nurse midwife.</section>
        <section prefix="(v)">"Optometrist" has the meaning stated in &#xA7; 11-101 of the Health Occupations Article.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Secretary may contract for the provision of care under the Program to eligible Program recipients.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Secretary may contract with insurance companies or nonprofit health service plans or with individuals, associations, partnerships, incorporated or unincorporated groups of physicians, chiropractors, dentists, podiatrists, optometrists, pharmacists, hospitals, nursing homes, nurses, including nurse anesthetists, nurse midwives and certified nurse practitioners, opticians, and other health practitioners who are licensed or certified in this State and perform services on the prescription or referral of a physician.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">For the purposes of this section, the nurse midwife need not be under the supervision of a physician.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">Except as otherwise provided by law, a contract that the Secretary makes under this subsection shall continue unless terminated under the terms of the contract by the Program or by the provider.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">As permitted by federal law or waiver, the Secretary may administer the Medicare Option Prescription Drug Program, established under &#xA7; 15-124.3 of this subtitle, as part of the Maryland Medical Assistance Program.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">By regulation, the Department shall adopt a methodology to ensure that federally qualified health centers are paid reasonable cost-based reimbursement that is consistent with federal law.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Department shall establish mechanisms for:<section prefix="(i)">Identifying a Program recipient's primary care provider at the time of enrollment into a managed care program; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Maintaining continuity of care with the primary care provider if:<section prefix="1.">The provider has a contract with a managed care organization or a contracted medical group of a managed care organization to provide primary care services; and</section><section prefix="2.">The recipient desires to continue care with the provider.</section></section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If a Program recipient enrolls in a managed care organization and requests assignment to a particular primary care provider who has a contract with the managed care organization or a contracted group of the managed care organization, the managed care organization shall assign the recipient to the primary care provider.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A Program recipient may request a change of primary care providers within the same managed care organization at any time and, if the primary care provider has a contract with the managed care organization or a contracted group of the managed care organization, the managed care organization shall honor the request.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">In accordance with the federal Health Care Financing Administration's guidelines, a Program recipient may elect to disenroll from a managed care organization if the managed care organization terminates its contract with the Department.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">A Program recipient may disenroll from a managed care organization to maintain continuity of care with a primary care provider if:<section prefix="(i)">The contract between the primary care provider and the managed care organization or contracted group of the managed care organization terminates because:<section prefix="1.">The managed care organization or contracted group of the managed care organization terminates the provider's contract for a reason other than quality of care or the provider's failure to comply with contractual requirements related to quality assurance activities;</section><section prefix="2."/><section prefix="3.">The provider contract between the provider and the managed care organization is terminated because the managed care organization is acquired by another entity; and</section></section><section prefix="(ii)"><section prefix="1.">The Program recipient desires to continue to receive care from the primary care provider;</section><section prefix="2.">The provider contracts with at least one other managed care organization or contracted group of a managed care organization; and</section><section prefix="3.">The enrollee notifies the Department or the Department's designee of the enrollee's intention within 90 days after the contract termination.</section></section></section>
      <section prefix="(6)">The Department shall provide timely notification to the affected managed care organization of an enrollee's intention to disenroll under the provisions of paragraph (5) of this subsection.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
