<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghg" order_by="" level="1">Health - General</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghg-17-2A-01</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>01</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Forensic analysis" means a medical, chemical,  toxicologic, firearms, or other expert examination or test  performed on physical evidence, including DNA evidence, for the  purpose of determining the connection of the evidence to a  criminal act.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Forensic analysis" includes an examination or test  required by a law enforcement agency, prosecutor, criminal  suspect or defendant, or court.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Forensic analysis" does not include:<section prefix="(i)">A test of a specimen of breath or blood to  determine alcohol concentration or controlled dangerous  substance content;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Forensic information technology;</section><section prefix="(iii)">A presumptive test performed at a crime scene;</section><section prefix="(iv)">A presumptive test performed for the purpose  of determining compliance with a term or condition of community  supervision or parole and conducted by or under contract with a  county department of corrections or the State Department of  Public Safety and Correctional Services; or</section><section prefix="(v)">An expert examination or test conducted  principally for the purpose of scientific research, medical  practice, civil or administrative litigation, or any other purpose  unrelated to determining the connection of physical evidence to a  criminal act.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Forensic information technology" means digital or  electronic evidence that is stored or transmitted electronically.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Forensic laboratory" means a facility, entity, or site that offers or performs forensic analysis.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Forensic laboratory" includes a laboratory owned or operated by the State, a county or municipal corporation in the State, or another governmental entity.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Forensic laboratory" does not include:<section prefix="(i)">A forensic laboratory operated by the federal  government; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">A laboratory licensed or certified by the  Department of Agriculture.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"License" means a permit, letter of exception, certificate, or other document issued by the Secretary granting approval or authority to offer or perform forensic laboratory tests, examinations, or analyses in the State.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">"Limited forensic analysis" means a forensic laboratory  test or analysis defined in regulations adopted by the Secretary.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">"Physical evidence" means any object, thing, or substance  relating to a criminal act.</section>
  </text>
</law>
