<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghg" order_by="" level="1">Health - General</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghg-17-503</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>503</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Any local or county health department may submit to the Secretary its cholesterol testing plan for review.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Secretary shall review all submissions under this section as soon as reasonably possible after the submission in order to determine whether it meets the standards necessary for adequate off-site cholesterol testing in accordance with this subtitle.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If a plan submitted under this section meets the standards of this subtitle, the Secretary may waive the permit requirements of the subtitle and permit the submitting local or county health department to conduct cholesterol testing under this subtitle for a period of 12 months, provided that:<section prefix="(i)">The submission adequately describes the cholesterol testing plan for the effective 12 months;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The local or county health department provides all information that the Secretary may reasonably require to determine compliance with this section;</section><section prefix="(iii)">The local or county health department agrees to make records available and submit reports to the Secretary as the Secretary may require;</section><section prefix="(iv)">Changes and amendments to the plan are submitted 60 days prior to proposed implementation; and</section><section prefix="(v)">All changes and amendments to the plan are approved by the Secretary.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">If a plan submitted under this section does not meet the standards of this subtitle, or if the information supplied in the submission is considered by the Secretary to be insufficient for a determination, the submitting local or county health department shall apply for a permit in accordance with this subtitle.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Secretary may cancel a waiver granted under this section at any time if the Secretary finds that the local or county health department does not continue to meet the standards of this subtitle.</section>
  </text>
</law>
