<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="ghg" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="20-117" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghg-20-117</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Cancer research" includes research to develop and advance the understanding of cancer and the techniques and modalities effective in the prevention, cure, screening, and treatment of cancer.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Fund" means the Maryland Cancer Fund established under this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">"Income tax checkoff system" means the checkoff system established under &#xA7; 2-112 of the Tax - General Article.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">There is a Maryland Cancer Fund.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The net proceeds from contributions under the income tax checkoff system and any other donations to the Fund shall be credited to the Fund.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Secretary shall administer the Fund.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The Fund shall be used only for cancer research, prevention, and treatment as provided in subsection (c) of this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">The Fund shall be maintained for the purposes stated in this section and unspent portions of the Fund shall remain in the Fund and may not revert to the General Fund of the State.</section>
      <section prefix="(6)">Moneys expended from the Fund for cancer research, prevention, and treatment are supplemental and are not intended to take the place of funding that would otherwise be appropriated to the Department for cancer research, prevention, and treatment.</section>
      <section prefix="(7)">All expenditures from the Fund shall be made only in accordance with an appropriation approved by the General Assembly in the annual State budget or through an approved budget amendment under &#xA7;&#xA7; 7-209 and 7-210 of the State Finance and Procurement Article.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Secretary may distribute not more than 5% of the net proceeds of the Fund to a promotional account to be used to promote further donations to the Fund.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">After making the distribution allowed under paragraph (1) of this subsection, the Secretary shall use the remainder of the net proceeds of the Fund only to provide grants to eligible physicians, hospitals, laboratories, educational institutions, and other organizations and persons to conduct cancer research, prevention, and treatment.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">On or before August 31 of each year, the Secretary shall submit a report to the General Assembly, pursuant to &#xA7; 2-1246 of the State Government Article, on the administration of the Maryland Cancer Fund.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The report required under this subsection shall include:<section prefix="(i)">The gross amount of donations to the Fund through the income tax checkoff system and otherwise;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The costs of administration by the Comptroller of the income tax checkoff system;</section><section prefix="(iii)">A description of promotional efforts undertaken with money from the Fund; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">A detailed accounting of the use of the Fund.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The Secretary shall adopt regulations to implement a Maryland Cancer Grant Program under this section.</section>
  </text>
</law>
