<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="ghg" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="18-4A-03" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghg-18-4A-03</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Subject to the provisions of this section, the following individuals, not in order of priority, may consent to the immunization of a minor if a parent is not reasonably available and the authority to consent is not denied under subsection (b) or (c) of this section:<section prefix="(1)">A grandparent;</section><section prefix="(2)">An adult brother or sister;</section><section prefix="(3)">An adult aunt or uncle;</section><section prefix="(4)">A stepparent;</section><section prefix="(5)">Any other adult who has care and control of the minor;</section><section prefix="(6)">A court that has jurisdiction of a suit affecting the parent-child relationship of which the minor is the subject;</section><section prefix="(7)">An adult who has care and control of the minor under an order of a court or by commitment by a court to the care of an agency of the State or county if the adult reasonably believes the minor needs immunization; or</section><section prefix="(8)">For minors in its care and custody, the Department of Juvenile Services.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A person may not consent to the immunization of a minor under subsection (a) of this section if:<section prefix="(1)">The person has actual knowledge that the parent has expressly refused to give consent to the immunization; or</section><section prefix="(2)">The parent has told the person that the person may not consent to the immunization of the minor or, in the case of a written authorization, has withdrawn the authorization in writing.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">When a parent has been contacted and requested to consent to the immunization of a minor, the Department of Juvenile Services may consent to the immunization of a minor in its care and custody if the parent:<section prefix="(1)">Has not acted on the request; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Has not expressly denied to the Department of Juvenile Services the authority to consent to the immunization of the minor.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">For purposes of this section, a person is not reasonably available if:<section prefix="(1)">The location of the person is unknown;</section><section prefix="(2)"><section prefix="(i)">A reasonable effort made by a person listed in subsection (a) of this section to locate and communicate with the parent for the purpose of obtaining consent has failed; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Not more than 90 days have passed since the date that the effort was made; or</section></section><section prefix="(3)">The parent has been contacted by a person listed in subsection (a) of this section and requested to consent to the immunization of the minor, and the parent:<section prefix="(i)">Has not acted on the request; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Has not expressly denied authority to the person listed in subsection (a) of this section to consent to immunization of the minor.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">A person authorized to consent to the immunization of a minor under this section shall confirm that the parent is not reasonably available in writing and the written confirmation shall be included in the minor's medical record.</section>
  </text>
</law>
