<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghg" order_by="" level="1">Health - General</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghg-19-703</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>703</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">This subtitle does not:<section prefix="(1)">Authorize any person to engage directly or indirectly in the practice of any health occupation except as otherwise authorized by law;</section><section prefix="(2)">Authorize any person to regulate, interfere, or intervene in the relationship between any provider of health care services and the patients of the provider; or</section><section prefix="(3)">Prohibit any health maintenance organization from meeting the requirements of any federal law that authorizes the health maintenance organization to:<section prefix="(i)">Receive federal financial assistance; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">Enroll beneficiaries assisted by federal funds.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A health maintenance organization or a part of it that is also a community health center organized under the federal Public Health Service Act and receives federal funds under 42 U.S.C. &#xA7; 254c is not required to provide hospitalization for individuals for whom services are provided by those funds.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Health maintenance organizations shall offer as an option to all of their members or subscribers benefits for hospice services provided by a hospice care program, as defined in &#xA7; 19-901(c) of this title.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Health maintenance organizations shall provide continuation coverage required under &#xA7;&#xA7; 15-407 through 15-409 of the Insurance Article.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Notwithstanding any other provision of this subtitle, a health maintenance organization may offer a benefit package that provides at a minimum benefits required by former Article 48A, &#xA7; 490-O for a limited benefits policy.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A benefit package offered under paragraph (1) of this subsection shall:<section prefix="(i)">Be subject to the approval of the Insurance Commissioner; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Satisfy the requirements of former Article 48A, &#xA7; 490-O.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">Notwithstanding any other provision of this subtitle, a health maintenance organization may provide a limited set of health benefits if the limited set of health benefits is for subscribers or members who are enrolled in a county program to provide health care services for low-income individuals.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In addition to the requirements of &#xA7; 19-706(i) of this subtitle and &#xA7; 15-10B-09 of the Insurance Article, whenever a mother is required to remain hospitalized after childbirth for medical reasons and the mother requests that the newborn remain in the hospital, a health maintenance organization shall provide as part of its hospitalization services provided to members and subscribers payment for the cost of additional hospitalization for the newborn for up to 4 days.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The attending physician or certified nurse midwife of the mother, or the designee of the attending physician or certified nurse midwife, shall provide notice to the mother of the provisions of paragraph (1) of this subsection.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
