<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="ghg" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="3-306" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghg-3-306</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Except as provided by agreement between the Secretary and the local governing body, and in addition to the powers and duties set forth elsewhere, each health officer has the powers and duties set forth in this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A health officer may obtain samples of food and drugs for analysis.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The health officer for a county is the executive officer and secretary of the county board of health.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Except in Montgomery County, the health officer for a county shall appoint the staff of the county health department.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The health officer for a county shall have an office at an accessible place in the county.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The health officer for a county shall enforce throughout the county:</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The health officer for a county shall enforce in each municipality or special taxing district in the county the rules or regulations that the county board of health adopts unless the municipality or district has a charter provision or ordinance that:</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(5)">A health officer shall perform any investigation or other duty or function directed by the Secretary or the county board of health and submit appropriate reports to them.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Subject to the consent of the governing body of the county and the written approval of the Secretary, a health officer for a county may enter into a contract or any other written agreement to assist or participate in the delivery of health care services with a person that is authorized to provide, finance, coordinate, facilitate, or otherwise deliver health care services in the State.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The Secretary may delegate duties, powers, and functions as provided in this article to a health officer for a county or other county official authorized to administer and enforce health and environmental laws.</section>
  </text>
</law>
