<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="ghg" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="7-713" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghg-7-713</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Secretary shall develop a plan for community supported living arrangements services that addresses:<section prefix="(1)">How services will be structured to meet the needs and preferences of eligible individuals;</section><section prefix="(2)">The number of eligible individuals estimated to need services and the number of individuals actually provided services sufficient to meet their needs under the Program;</section><section prefix="(3)">A recipient-based evaluation system on which to base individual and State policy changes to the Program that includes recipient satisfaction with provided services;</section><section prefix="(4)">Technical assistance and information on how to access and to utilize the Program to recipients, family members of recipients, advocacy organizations, and other interested persons; and</section><section prefix="(5)">Technical assistance and information to service providers on how to structure services to meet the needs and preferences of recipients.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Community advocacy and provider organizations shall be involved in the development of the State plan for community supported living arrangements services.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">In order to offer eligible individuals creative housing alternatives, the Administration shall include in the State plan for community supported living arrangements services a provision for collaboration with the Department of Housing and Community Development and other appropriate agencies and organizations.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In addition to any other provisions required under this section, the State plan for community supported living arrangements services shall provide, to the extent that funds are available, that the first 500 individuals to receive community supported living arrangements services shall be:<section prefix="(i)">Eligible individuals who have applied for community-based residential or support services under this title and are not currently receiving these services; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">In equal numbers, eligible individuals who are currently receiving residential services and eligible individuals who have applied for community residential or support services and are not currently receiving these services.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">After the first 500 individuals have received community supported living arrangements services under paragraph (1) of this subsection, to determine the distribution of available funds, the Secretary shall review:<section prefix="(i)">The needs of eligible individuals who have applied for community-based residential or support services under this title and are not receiving these services; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">The needs of eligible individuals currently receiving community-based residential or support services.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
