<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghg" order_by="" level="1">Health - General</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghg-18-904</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>904</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, "information" means medical, epidemiological, or other data concerning a specific individual or a group of individuals, regardless of whether the information is otherwise deemed confidential under Title 4 of this article or as otherwise provided under law.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">In order to maintain an effective disease surveillance system for detecting whether individuals have been exposed to a deadly agent, the Secretary may by order, directive, or regulation:<section prefix="(1)">Require a health care provider or other person to report information to the Secretary or other public official on the following:<section prefix="(i)">The presence of an individual or group of individuals with specified illnesses or symptoms;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Diagnostic and laboratory findings relating to diseases caused by deadly agents;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Statistical or utilization trends relating to potential disease outbreaks;</section><section prefix="(iv)">Information needed to conduct contact tracing for exposed individuals; and</section><section prefix="(v)">Other data deemed by the Secretary to have epidemiological significance in detecting possible catastrophic health emergencies;</section></section><section prefix="(2)">Obtain access to information in the possession of a health care provider;</section><section prefix="(3)">Require or authorize a health care provider to disclose information to an agency of the federal, State, or local government or another health care provider;</section><section prefix="(4)">Require a health care provider or other person to submit reports to the Department containing information detailing the presence and use of deadly agents;</section><section prefix="(5)">Obtain access to premises in order to secure environmental samples and otherwise investigate actual or potential exposures to deadly agents; and</section><section prefix="(6)">Require a veterinarian or other person to report data relating to specified illnesses or symptoms in animal populations.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Secretary, in acquiring information under subsection (b) of this section, shall:<section prefix="(1)">Request and use nonidentifying information whenever possible; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Limit the use of confidential information to the extent necessary to detect and investigate actual or potential exposures to a deadly agent.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Any information that the Secretary receives under subsection (b) of this section is confidential and may be used or disclosed only in accordance with this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If the information requested in subsection (b) of this section is otherwise confidential under Title 4 of this article or as otherwise provided under law, the Secretary or person that receives the information may not redisclose the information except as provided in paragraph (3) of this subsection.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A person may redisclose the information to another health care provider or public official provided that:<section prefix="(i)">The health care provider or public agency to whom the information is disclosed will maintain the confidentiality of the disclosure; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">The Secretary determines the disclosure is necessary to treat, prevent, or reduce the spread of the disease or outbreak believed to have been caused by the exposure to a deadly agent.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
