<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="ghg" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="15-301" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghg-15-301</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">There is a Maryland Children's Health Program.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Maryland Children's Health Program shall provide, subject to the limitations of the State budget and any other requirements imposed by the State and as permitted by federal law or waiver, comprehensive medical care and other health care services to an individual who has a family income at or below 300 percent of the federal poverty guidelines and who is under the age of 19 years.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Maryland Children's Health Program shall be administered:<section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in item (3) of this subsection, for individuals whose family income is at or below 200 percent of the federal poverty guidelines, through the Program under Subtitle 1 of this title requiring individuals to enroll in managed care organizations;</section><section prefix="(2)">For eligible individuals whose family income is above 200 percent, but at or below 300 percent of the federal poverty guidelines, through the MCHP premium plan under &#xA7; 15-301.1 of this subtitle; or</section><section prefix="(3)">In fiscal year 2004 only, for eligible individuals whose family income is above 185 percent, but at or below 300 percent of the federal poverty guidelines, through the MCHP premium plan under &#xA7; 15-301.1 of this subtitle.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Department shall provide eligible individuals and health care providers with an accurate directory or other listing of all available providers:<section prefix="(i)">In written form, made available upon request; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">On an Internet database.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Department shall update the Internet database at least every 30 days.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The written directory shall include a conspicuous reference to the Internet database.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
