<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="ghg" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="19-345" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghg-19-345</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">A resident of a facility may not be transferred or discharged from the facility involuntarily except for the following reasons:<section prefix="(1)">The transfer or discharge is necessary for the resident's welfare and the resident's needs cannot be met in the facility;</section><section prefix="(2)">The transfer or discharge is appropriate because the resident's health has improved sufficiently so that the resident no longer needs the services provided by the facility;</section><section prefix="(3)">The health or safety of an individual in a facility is endangered;</section><section prefix="(4)">The resident has failed, after reasonable and appropriate notice, to pay for, or under Medicare or Medicaid or otherwise, to have paid for a stay at the facility; or</section><section prefix="(5)">The facility ceases to operate.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A Medicaid certified facility may not:<section prefix="(i)">Include in the admission contract of a resident any requirement that, to stay at the facility, the resident will be required to pay for any period of time or amount of money as a private pay resident for any period when the resident is eligible for Medicaid benefits; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">Transfer or discharge a resident involuntarily because the resident is a Medicaid benefits recipient.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Except as provided in subparagraph (ii) of this paragraph, a Medicaid certified facility is presumed to be transferring or discharging a resident in violation of this subsection, if the resident is or becomes eligible for Medicaid benefits.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">A Medicaid certified facility is not presumed to be transferring or discharging a resident in violation of this subsection for transferring or discharging a resident for nonpayment for services while the resident was ineligible for assistance under the medical assistance program.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
