<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghg" order_by="ghg" level="1">Health - General</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghg-10-708</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this section the following words have the meanings indicated....</catch_line>
  <order_by>708</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Panel" means a clinical review panel that determines, under the provisions of this section, whether to approve that medication be administered to an individual who objects to the medication.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Medication" means psychiatric medication prescribed for the treatment of a mental disorder.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">"Lay advisor" means an individual at a facility, who is knowledgeable about mental health practice and who assists individuals with rights complaints.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Medication may not be administered to an individual who refuses the medication, except:<section prefix="(1)">In an emergency, on the order of a physician where the individual presents a danger to the life or safety of the individual or others; or</section><section prefix="(2)">In a nonemergency, when the individual is hospitalized involuntarily or committed for treatment by order of a court and the medication is approved by a panel under the provisions of this section.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A panel shall consist of the following individuals appointed by the chief executive officer of the facility or the chief executive officer's designee, one of whom shall be appointed chairperson:<section prefix="(i)">The clinical director of the psychiatric unit, if the clinical director is a physician, or a physician designated by the clinical director;</section><section prefix="(ii)">A psychiatrist; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">A mental health professional, other than a physician.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If a member of the clinical review panel also is directly responsible for implementing the individualized treatment plan for the individual under review, the chief executive officer of the facility or the chief executive officer's designee shall designate another panel member for that specific review.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The chief executive officer of the facility or the chief executive officer's designee shall give the individual and the lay advisor written notice at least 24 hours prior to convening a panel.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Except in an emergency under subsection (b)(1) of this section, medication or medications being refused may not be administered to an individual prior to the decision of the panel.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The notice under subsection (d)(1) of this section shall include the following information:<section prefix="(i)">The date, time, and location that the panel will convene;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The purpose of the panel; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">A complete description of the rights of an individual under paragraph (2) of this subsection.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">At a panel, an individual has the following rights:<section prefix="(i)">To attend the meeting of the panel, excluding the discussion conducted to arrive at a decision;</section><section prefix="(ii)">To present information, including witnesses;</section><section prefix="(iii)">To ask questions of any person presenting information to the panel;</section><section prefix="(iv)">To request assistance from a lay advisor; and</section><section prefix="(v)">To be informed of:<section prefix="1.">The name, address, and telephone number of the lay advisor;</section><section prefix="2.">The individual's diagnosis; and</section><section prefix="3.">An explanation of the clinical need for the medication or medications, including potential side effects, and material risks and benefits of taking or refusing the medication.</section></section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The chairperson of the panel may:<section prefix="(i)">Postpone or continue the panel for good cause, for a reasonable time; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Take appropriate measures necessary to conduct the panel in an orderly manner.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">Prior to determining whether to approve the administration of medication, the panel shall:<section prefix="(1)">Review the individual's clinical record, as appropriate;</section><section prefix="(2)">Assist the individual and the treating physician to arrive at a mutually agreeable treatment plan; and</section><section prefix="(3)">Meet for the purpose of receiving information and clinically assessing the individual's need for medication by:<section prefix="(i)">Consulting with the individual regarding the reason or reasons for refusing the medication or medications and the individual's willingness to accept alternative treatment, including other medication;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Consulting with facility personnel who are responsible for initiating and implementing the individual's treatment plan, including discussion of the current treatment plan and alternative modes of treatment, including medications that were considered;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Receiving information presented by the individual and other persons participating in the panel;</section><section prefix="(iv)">Providing the individual with an opportunity to ask questions of anyone presenting information to the panel; and</section><section prefix="(v)">Reviewing the potential consequences of requiring the administration of medication and of withholding the medication from the individual.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(g)">The panel may approve the administration of medication or medications and may recommend and approve alternative medications if the panel determines that:<section prefix="(1)">The medication is prescribed by a psychiatrist for the purpose of treating the individual's mental disorder;</section><section prefix="(2)">The administration of medication represents a reasonable exercise of professional judgment; and</section><section prefix="(3)">Without the medication, the individual is at substantial risk of continued hospitalization because of:<section prefix="(i)">Remaining seriously mentally ill with no significant relief of the mental illness symptoms that cause the individual to be a danger to the individual or to others;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Remaining seriously mentally ill for a significantly longer period of time with mental illness symptoms that cause the individual to be a danger to the individual or to others; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">Relapsing into a condition in which the individual is in danger of serious physical harm resulting from the individual's inability to provide for the individual's essential human needs of health or safety.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(h)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A panel shall base its decision on its clinical assessment of the information contained in the individual's record and information presented to the panel.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A panel may meet privately to reach a decision.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A panel may not approve the administration of medication where alternative treatments are available and are acceptable to both the individual and the facility personnel who are directly responsible for implementing the individual's treatment plan.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(i)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A panel shall document its consideration of the issues and the basis for its decision on the administration of medication or medications.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A panel shall provide a written decision on the administration of medication or medications, and the decision shall be provided to the individual, the lay advisor, and the individual's treatment team for inclusion in the individual's medical record.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">If a panel approves the administration of medication, the decision shall specify:<section prefix="(i)">The medication or medications approved and the dosage and frequency range;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The duration of the approval, not to exceed the maximum time provided under subsection (m) of this section; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">The reason that alternative treatments, including the medication, if any, were rejected by the panel.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">If a panel approves the administration of medication, the decision shall contain:<section prefix="(i)">Notice of the right to request a hearing under subsection (k) of this section;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The right to request representation or assistance of a lawyer or other advocate of the individual's choice; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">The name, address, and telephone number of the designated State protection and advocacy agency and the Lawyer Referral Service.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(j)">If a panel approves the administration of medication, the lay advisor promptly shall:<section prefix="(1)">Inform the individual of the individual's right to appeal the decision under subsection (k) of this section;</section><section prefix="(2)">Ensure that the individual has access to a telephone as provided under &#xA7; 10-702(b) of this subtitle;</section><section prefix="(3)">If the individual requests a hearing, notify the chief executive officer of the facility or the chief executive officer's designee pursuant to subsection (k)(1) of this section and give the individual written notice of the date, time, and location of the hearing; and</section><section prefix="(4)">Advise the individual of the provision for renewal of an approval under subsection (m) of this section.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(k)">
      <section prefix="(1)">An individual may request an administrative hearing to appeal the panel's decision by filing a request for hearing with the chief executive officer of the facility or the chief executive officer's designee within 48 hours of receipt of the decision of the panel.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Within 24 hours of receipt of a request for hearing, the chief executive officer of the facility or the chief executive officer's designee shall forward the request to the Office of Administrative Hearings.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">An initial panel decision authorizing the administration of medication shall be stayed for 48 hours. If a request for hearing is filed, the stay shall remain in effect until the issuance of the administrative decision.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The Office of Administrative Hearings shall conduct a hearing and issue a decision within 7 calendar days of the decision by the panel.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">The administrative hearing may be postponed by agreement of the parties or for good cause shown.</section>
      <section prefix="(6)">The administrative law judge shall conduct a de novo hearing to determine if the standards and procedures in this section are met.</section>
      <section prefix="(7)">At the hearing, the individual representing the facility:<section prefix="(i)">May introduce the decision of the panel as evidence; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Shall prove, by a preponderance of the evidence, that the standards and procedures of this section have been met.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(8)">The administrative law judge shall state on the record the findings of fact and conclusions of law.</section>
      <section prefix="(9)">The determination of the administrative law judge is a final decision for the purpose of judicial review of a final decision under the Administrative Procedure Act.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(l)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Within 14 calendar days from the decision of the administrative law judge, the individual or the facility may appeal the decision and the appeal shall be to the circuit court on the record from the hearing conducted by the Office of Administrative Hearings.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The scope of review shall be as a contested case under the Administrative Procedure Act.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Review shall be on the audiophonic tape without the necessity of transcription of the tape, unless either party to the appeal requests transcription of the tape.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">A request for transcription of the tape shall be made at the time the appeal is filed.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">The Office of Administrative Hearings shall prepare the transcription prior to the appeal hearing, and the party requesting the transcription shall bear the cost of transcription.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The circuit court shall hear and issue a decision on an appeal within 7 calendar days from the date the appeal was filed.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(m)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Treatment pursuant to this section may not be approved for longer than 90 days.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Prior to expiration of an approval period and if the individual continues to refuse medication, a panel may be convened to decide whether renewal is warranted.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">Notwithstanding the provisions of paragraph (1) of this subsection, if a clinical review panel approves the renewal of the administration of medication or medications, the administration of medication or medications need not be interrupted if the individual appeals the renewal of approval.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(n)">When medication is ordered pursuant to the approval of a panel under this section and at a minimum of every 15 days, the treating physician shall document any known benefits and side effects to the individual.</section>
  </text>
</law>
