<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghg" order_by="" level="1">Health - General</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghg-5-706</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>706</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The purpose of the local team is to prevent child deaths by:<section prefix="(1)">Promoting cooperation and coordination among agencies involved in investigations of child deaths or in providing services to surviving family members;</section><section prefix="(2)">Developing an understanding of the causes and incidence of child deaths in the county;</section><section prefix="(3)">Developing plans for and recommending changes within the agencies the members represent to prevent child deaths; and</section><section prefix="(4)">Advising the State Team on changes to law, policy, or practice to prevent child deaths.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">To achieve its purpose, the local team shall:<section prefix="(1)">In consultation with the State Team, establish and implement a protocol for the local team;</section><section prefix="(2)">Set as its goal the investigation of child deaths in accordance with national standards;</section><section prefix="(3)">Meet at least quarterly to review the status of child fatality cases, recommend actions to improve coordination of services and investigations among member agencies, and recommend actions within the member agencies to prevent child deaths;</section><section prefix="(4)">Collect and maintain data as required by the State Team;</section><section prefix="(5)">Provide requested reports to the State Team, including discussion of individual cases, steps taken to improve coordination of services and investigations, steps taken to implement changes recommended by the local team within member agencies, and recommendations on needed changes to State and local law, policy, and practice to prevent child deaths; and</section><section prefix="(6)">In consultation with the State Team:<section prefix="(i)">Define "near fatality"; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Develop procedures and protocols that local teams and the State Team may use to review cases of near fatality.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">In addition to the duties specified in subsection (b) of this section, a local team may investigate the information and records of a child convicted of a crime or adjudicated as having committed a delinquent act that caused a death or near fatality described in &#xA7; 5-707 of this subtitle.</section>
  </text>
</law>
