<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghg" order_by="" level="1">Health - General</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghg-5-615</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>615</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, "health care facility" has the meaning stated in &#xA7; 19-114 of this article.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Each health care facility shall provide each individual on admittance to the facility information concerning the rights of the individual to make decisions concerning health care, including the right to accept or refuse treatment, and the right to make an advance directive, including a living will.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Department, in consultation with the Office of the Attorney General, shall develop an information sheet that provides information relating to advance directives, which shall include:<section prefix="(i)">Written statements informing an individual that an advance directive:<section prefix="1.">Is a useful, legal, and well established way for an individual to direct medical care;</section><section prefix="2.">Allows an individual to specify the medical care that the individual will receive and can alleviate conflict among family members and health care providers;</section><section prefix="3.">Can ensure that an individual's religious beliefs are considered when directing medical care;</section><section prefix="4.">Is most effective if completed in consultation with family members, or legal and religious advisors, if an individual desires;</section><section prefix="5.">Can be revoked or changed at any time;</section><section prefix="6.">Is available in many forms, including model forms developed by religious organizations, estate planners, and lawyers;</section><section prefix="7.">Does not have to be on any specific form and can be personalized; and</section><section prefix="8.">If completed, should be copied for an individual's family members, physicians, and legal advisors; and</section></section><section prefix="(ii)">The following written statements:<section prefix="1.">That an individual should discuss the appointment of a health care agent with the potential appointee;</section><section prefix="2.">That advance directives are for individuals of all ages;</section><section prefix="3.">That in the absence of an appointed health care agent, the next of kin make an individual's health care decisions when the individual is incapable of making those decisions; and</section><section prefix="4.">That an individual is not required to complete an advance directive.</section></section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The information sheet developed by the Department under this subsection shall be provided by:<section prefix="(i)">The Department, in accordance with &#xA7; 15-109.1 of this article;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The Motor Vehicle Administration, in accordance with &#xA7; 12-303.1 of the Transportation Article; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">A carrier, in accordance with &#xA7; 15-122.1 of the Insurance Article.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The information sheet developed by the Department under this subsection may not contain or promote a specific advance directive form.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
