<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghg" order_by="ghg" level="1">Health - General</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghg-18-107</section_number>
  <catch_line>The Secretary shall:...</catch_line>
  <order_by>107</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Secretary shall:<section prefix="(1)">Devise and institute means to prevent and control morbidity and mortality associated with:<section prefix="(i)">Pregnancy;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Childbirth;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Infancy; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">Early childhood; and</section></section><section prefix="(2)">Promote the welfare and hygiene of maternity and infancy.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Secretary shall establish a Morbidity, Mortality, and Quality Review Committee in the Department.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Committee shall:<section prefix="(i)">Conduct confidential and anonymous case reviews of morbidity and mortality associated with pregnancy, childbirth, infancy, and early childhood; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Develop and implement interventions to improve the system of care for pregnancy, childbirth, infancy, and early childhood based on the findings from case reviews conducted under item (i) of this paragraph.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The Secretary shall adopt regulations to implement the requirements of this section.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The regulations shall include:<section prefix="1.">The types of case reviews conducted by the Committee;</section><section prefix="2.">The confidentiality of case reviews;</section><section prefix="3.">A description of the types of records and information needed by the Committee to conduct the case reviews under this section; and</section><section prefix="4.">The process for obtaining records, including patient medical records, and any other necessary information in accordance with &#xA7; 4-305(b) of this article.</section></section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">This section does not enable the Secretary:<section prefix="(1)">To take charge of a child if the parent, guardian, or other person who has custody of the child objects; or</section><section prefix="(2)">To treat the child for a disease without the consent of the parent, guardian, or other person who has custody of the child.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
