<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghg" order_by="" level="1">Health - General</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghg-21-804</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>804</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">To prevent deception in the sale of frozen desserts and to safeguard the health and welfare of consumers, the Secretary shall adopt rules and regulations that:<section prefix="(1)">Provide definitions and set standards of identity for frozen desserts and the mixes used in the manufacture of frozen desserts;</section><section prefix="(2)">Set packaging, labeling, and sanitary requirements for frozen desserts; and</section><section prefix="(3)">Govern any other condition that relates to the manufacture, processing, distribution, or sale of frozen desserts, whether manufactured or processed in a regular manufacturing plant, in a counter freezer, or otherwise.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">So far as practicable, the Secretary may conform any rule or regulation adopted under this subtitle to the rules and regulations adopted under the federal act.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Secretary may not adopt a rule or regulation under this section unless the requirements of this subsection and the Administrative Procedure Act are met.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A public hearing shall be held on any rule or regulation that the Secretary considers under this section. Based on the record of the hearing, the Secretary shall issue a proposed decision on the rule or regulation.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Secretary shall provide any interested party an opportunity to file exceptions to the proposed decision based on the hearing record.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">When issuing a final decision regarding a rule or regulation, the Secretary also shall:<section prefix="(i)">Rule on any exception to the Secretary's proposed decision; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">State the reasons for the ruling.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
