<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghg" order_by="ghg" level="1">Health - General</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghg-13-111</section_number>
  <catch_line>The Department shall establish a coordinated statewide system for screening all newborn infants in t...</catch_line>
  <order_by>111</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Department shall establish a coordinated statewide system for screening all newborn infants in the State for certain hereditary and congenital disorders associated with severe problems of health or development, except when the parent or guardian of the newborn infant objects.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Except as provided in &#xA7; 13-112 of this subtitle, the Department's public health laboratory is the sole laboratory authorized to perform tests on specimens from newborn infants collected to screen for hereditary and congenital disorders as determined under subsection (d)(2) of this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The system for newborn screening shall include:<section prefix="(1)">Laboratory testing and the reporting of test results; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Follow-up activities to facilitate the rapid identification and treatment of an affected child.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">In consultation with the State Advisory Council on Hereditary and Congenital Disorders, the Department shall:<section prefix="(1)">Establish protocols for a health care provider to obtain and deliver test specimens to the Department's public health laboratory;</section><section prefix="(2)">Determine the screening tests that the Department's public health laboratory is required to perform;</section><section prefix="(3)">Maintain a coordinated statewide system for newborn screening that carries out the purpose described in subsection (c) of this section that includes:<section prefix="(i)">Communicating the results of screening tests to the health care provider of the newborn infant;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Locating newborn infants with abnormal test results;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Sharing newborn screening information between hospitals, health care providers, treatment centers, and laboratory personnel; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">Delivering needed clinical, diagnostic, and treatment information to health care providers, parents, and caregivers; and</section></section><section prefix="(4)">Adopt regulations that set forth the standards and requirements for newborn screening for hereditary and congenital disorders that are required under this subtitle, including:<section prefix="(i)">Performing newborn screening tests;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Coordinating the reporting, follow-up, and treatment activities with parents, caregivers, and health care providers; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Establishing fees for newborn screening that do not exceed an amount sufficient to cover the administrative, laboratory, and follow-up costs associated with the performance of screening tests under this subtitle.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, if the Secretary of Health and Human Services issues federal recommendations on critical congenital heart disease screening of newborns, the Department shall adopt the federal screening recommendations.</section>
  </text>
</law>
