<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghg" order_by="ghg" level="1">Health - General</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghg-10-631</section_number>
  <catch_line>The Administration shall prepare and provide each facility with standard forms that provide, in clea...</catch_line>
  <order_by>631</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Administration shall prepare and provide each facility with standard forms that provide, in clear and simple words, at least the following information:<section prefix="(1)">Notice of the admission of the individual;</section><section prefix="(2)">The right of the individual to consult with a lawyer that the individual chooses;</section><section prefix="(3)">The availability of the services of the legal aid bureaus, lawyer referral services, and other agencies that exist for the referral of individuals who need legal counsel;</section><section prefix="(4)">The right of the individual to call or write a lawyer or a referral agency or to have someone do so on behalf of the individual; and</section><section prefix="(5)">In substance:<section prefix="(i)">Those provisions of this subtitle under which the individual is admitted;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The provisions of this section; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">The provisions of Subtitle 7 of this title.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Within 12 hours after initial confinement of an individual to any facility or a Veterans' Administration hospital, the form provided for in this section shall be read and given to the individual.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If the individual does not understand the notice required by this section and its legal effect, the notice also shall be given to:<section prefix="(i)">The parent, guardian, or next of kin of the individual;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The applicant for an involuntary admission of the individual; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Any other individual who has a significant interest in the status of the individual.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">In any event, if possible, notice of the admission shall be given to the parent, guardian, or next of kin of the individual. Notice of the admission of a minor shall be given as promptly as possible.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The form shall be read in English or, if the individual does not understand English, in the language or manner best calculated to inform the individual of the applicable provisions of the law.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The facility shall keep in the individual's records a copy of the form and a certification of the administrative head of the facility as to the compliance with this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">Notice under this section shall be given again to an individual when:<section prefix="(1)">A new application is made under this subtitle for a voluntary admission; and</section><section prefix="(2)">New certificates are made under this subtitle for an involuntary admission.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
