<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="ghg" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="19-713.6" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghg-19-713.6</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Documented informed consent" means:<section prefix="(i)">A written consent form signed by a patient; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">Verbal or otherwise communicated consent signified by a notation in a patient's electronic medical record maintained by a group model health maintenance organization.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Drug therapy management" means treatment of a patient using drug therapy, laboratory tests, or medical devices under conditions or limitations set forth in a protocol specified in a physician-pharmacist agreement for the purpose of improving patient outcome.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">"Group model health maintenance organization" means a health maintenance organization that:<section prefix="(i)">Contracts with one multispecialty group of physicians who are employed by and shareholders of the multispecialty group; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Provides and arranges for the provision of physician services to patients at medical facilities operated by the health maintenance organization.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(5)">"Licensed pharmacist" means an individual who is licensed to practice pharmacy under Title 12 of the Health Occupations Article.</section>
      <section prefix="(6)">"Licensed physician" means an individual who is licensed to practice medicine under Title 14 of the Health Occupations Article.</section>
      <section prefix="(7)">"Patient" means:<section prefix="(i)">A patient who is a member of a group model health maintenance organization; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">An individual to whom the group model health maintenance organization is contractually or legally obligated to provide, or arrange to provide, health care services.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(8)">"Physician-pharmacist agreement" means an approved agreement between a licensed physician and a licensed pharmacist that is disease-state specific and specifies the protocols that may be used.</section>
      <section prefix="(9)">"Protocol" means a course of treatment predetermined by the licensed physician and licensed pharmacist according to generally accepted medical practice for the proper completion of a particular therapeutic or diagnostic intervention.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In a group model health maintenance organization, a licensed physician and a licensed pharmacist who wish to provide drug therapy management to patients shall have a physician-pharmacist agreement that is approved by the State Board of Pharmacy and the State Board of Physicians.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Drug therapy management shall be provided under this section only:<section prefix="(i)">In accordance with a physician-pharmacist agreement; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Through the internal pharmacy operations of the group model health maintenance organization.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A licensed pharmacist is authorized to enter into a physician-pharmacist agreement if the licensed pharmacist:<section prefix="(1)">Has a Doctor of Pharmacy Degree or equivalent training as established in regulations adopted by the State Board of Pharmacy;</section><section prefix="(2)">Is approved by the State Board of Pharmacy to enter into a physician-pharmacist agreement with a licensed physician; and</section><section prefix="(3)">Meets any other requirements established by regulation by the State Board of Pharmacy.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A physician-pharmacist agreement shall prohibit the substitution of a chemically dissimilar drug product by the pharmacist for the product prescribed by the physician, unless permitted in the protocol specified in the physician-pharmacist agreement.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The Board of Physicians and the Board of Pharmacy may not approve a physician-pharmacist agreement if the boards find that there is:<section prefix="(1)">Inadequate training, experience, or education of the physicians or pharmacists to implement the protocol or protocols specified in the physician-pharmacist agreement; or</section><section prefix="(2)">A failure to satisfy the requirements of:<section prefix="(i)">This section or Title 14 of the Health Occupations Article; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">Any regulations adopted by the Board of Physicians and the Board of Pharmacy under this section.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">A physician-pharmacist agreement under this section shall be valid for 2 years from the date of its final approval by the Board of Physicians and the Board of Pharmacy and may be renewed for additional 2-year terms with approval from the Board of Physicians and the Board of Pharmacy.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">A patient may decline to participate or withdraw from participating in drug therapy management in a group model health maintenance organization at any time.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">A licensed physician or licensed pharmacist or both shall inform a patient:<section prefix="(1)">Regarding the procedures that will be utilized for drug therapy management under the associated protocols;</section><section prefix="(2)">That the patient may decline to participate or withdraw from participating in the drug therapy management at any time; and</section><section prefix="(3)">That neither the physician nor the pharmacist has been coerced, given economic incentives, excluding normal reimbursement for services rendered, or involuntarily required to participate.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(i)">A licensed physician or a licensed pharmacist or both shall obtain documented informed consent from a patient after disclosing the information required to be disclosed under subsection (h) of this section.</section>
  </text>
</law>
