<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="ghg" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="18-214.1" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghg-18-214.1</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>// EFFECTIVE UNTIL JUNE 30, 2015 PER CHAPTER 136 OF 2010 //<section prefix="(a)"><section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section><section prefix="(2)">"Commissioner" means the Commissioner of Health of the Baltimore City Health Department.</section><section prefix="(3)">"Program" means the Expedited Partner Therapy Pilot Program.</section></section><section prefix="(b)">There is an Expedited Partner Therapy Pilot Program  in the Baltimore City Health Department.</section><section prefix="(c)">The purpose of the Program is to provide antibiotic therapy to the partner of a patient diagnosed with a sexually transmitted infection identified in subsection (d) of this section in order to contain the infection and stop the further spread of it.</section><section prefix="(d)">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, in a public health clinic established by the Commissioner in Baltimore City, the following health care providers may dispense or otherwise provide antibiotic therapy to any sexual partner of a patient diagnosed with chlamydia or gonorrhea without making a personal physical assessment of the patient's partner:<section prefix="(1)">A physician licensed under Title 14 of the Health Occupations Article;</section><section prefix="(2)">A certified nurse practitioner in accordance with &#xA7; 8-508 of the Health Occupations Article; and</section><section prefix="(3)">An authorized physician assistant in accordance with &#xA7; 15-302.2 of the Health Occupations Article.</section></section><section prefix="(e)">The Secretary shall adopt regulations to implement the requirements of this section.</section><section prefix="(f)">On or before December 31, 2007, and each year thereafter, the Baltimore City Health Department shall report to the Governor and, subject to &#xA7; 2-1246 of the State Government Article, the General Assembly, on the operation and performance of the Expedited Partner Therapy Pilot Program.</section></text>
</law>
