<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="ghg" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="18-324" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghg-18-324</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Secretary or a health officer may have an individual examined, if the Secretary or the health officer knows or is notified in writing by a physician that the individual is suspected of having tuberculosis.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If, after the examination, the Secretary or the health officer finds that the individual has tuberculosis and that the condition of the individual endangers, or may endanger, the public health of the community, the Secretary or the health officer may order the individual to receive appropriate medical care.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If the individual fails to comply with the order, the Secretary or the health officer may order the individual to be placed in any of the following types of medical quarantine in order to protect the public health:<section prefix="(i)">Medical isolation at home;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Domiciliary care, nursing home care, or hospital care; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">Other medically appropriate living arrangement.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The order of the Secretary or the health officer may also contain such other conditions as the Secretary or the health officer believes are necessary to protect either the health of the infected individual or the public health.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Secretary or a health officer may not require an individual to have a physical examination, other than a chest X ray and to render sputum samples. The Secretary or a health officer may not restrict the right of the individual to select a treatment method, if the individual:<section prefix="(1)">In good faith relies on spiritual means through prayer for healing; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Complies with the laws, rules, and regulations that relate to sanitation for and quarantine of infectious, contagious, and communicable diseases.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
