<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="ghg" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="20-1404" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghg-20-1404</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>// EFFECTIVE UNTIL JUNE 30, 2016 PER CHAPTER 3 OF 2012 //<section prefix="(a)">The Commission shall make recommendations to the Secretary on the designation of Health Enterprise Zones under this subtitle.</section><section prefix="(b)"><section prefix="(1)">The Secretary shall designate areas as Health Enterprise Zones in accordance with this subtitle.</section><section prefix="(2)">The Secretary shall consider geographic diversity, among other factors, when designating areas as Health Enterprise Zones and may direct the Commission to conduct outreach efforts to facilitate a geographically diverse pool of applicants, including promoting applications from rural areas.</section><section prefix="(3)">After receiving all applications submitted to the Commission, the Commission shall report, in accordance with &#xA7; 2-1246 of the State Government Article, to the Senate Finance Committee and the House Health and Government Operations Committee on the names of applicants and geographic areas in which applicants are located.</section></section><section prefix="(c)">The Secretary may limit the number of areas designated as Health Enterprise Zones in accordance with the State budget.</section><section prefix="(d)">The Commission and the Secretary shall give priority to applications that demonstrate the following:<section prefix="(1)">Support from and participation of key stakeholders in the public and private sectors, including residents of the area and local government;</section><section prefix="(2)">A plan for long-term funding and sustainability;</section><section prefix="(3)">Inclusion of supporting funds from the private sector;</section><section prefix="(4)">Integration with the State Health Improvement Process and the goals set out in the strategic plan of the local health improvement coalition;</section><section prefix="(5)">A plan for evaluation of the impact of designation of the proposed area as a Health Enterprise Zone; and</section><section prefix="(6)">Other factors that the Commission and the Secretary determine are appropriate to demonstrate a commitment to reduce disparities and improve health outcomes.</section></section><section prefix="(e)">The decision of the Secretary to designate an area as a Health Enterprise Zone is final.</section></text>
</law>
