<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="ghg" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="10-1202" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghg-10-1202</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">A core service agency shall:<section prefix="(1)">Be an agent of a county or Baltimore City government which may include a local health department;</section><section prefix="(2)">Unless an exception is requested by an individual county and is granted by the Secretary, serve a county or counties with an estimated population of over 80,000 people;</section><section prefix="(3)">Either purchase services or provide the services directly;</section><section prefix="(4)">Annually submit a program plan to the secretaries of the affected State departments for review and to the Secretary for approval; and</section><section prefix="(5)">Meet the standards required under this subtitle and, as needed, the rules and regulations set by the Secretary.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A core service agency may not be a for-profit entity.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Each core service agency shall function under the Secretary's authority.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Once established in a jurisdiction, the core service agency shall:<section prefix="(1)">Submit, on an annual basis, a program plan to the Secretary for approval;</section><section prefix="(2)">Incorporate in its method of governance a mechanism for the local county mental health advisory committee or joint mental health and substance abuse committee to serve as the advisory committee to the core service agency and, if serving more than 1 unit of government, a method of representation serving those jurisdictions;</section><section prefix="(3)">Implement guidelines developed by the Secretary which establish or designate the local mental health advisory committee's authority to advise and assist in the planning and evaluation of the publicly funded mental health services;</section><section prefix="(4)">In accordance with guidelines developed by the Secretary, develop planning, management, and accountability mechanisms for the delivery of services including:<section prefix="(i)">Case management;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Data collection which satisfies the Department's requirements for client tracking and incorporates clear outcome measures to enable the local entity to govern itself and monitor and evaluate the system; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">A yearly summary which includes at a minimum:</section></section><section prefix="(5)">As an agent of county government, function in any of the following organizational structures:<section prefix="(i)">A unit of county or Baltimore City government;</section><section prefix="(ii)">A local health department;</section><section prefix="(iii)">A quasi-public authority; or</section><section prefix="(iv)">A private, nonprofit corporation;</section></section><section prefix="(6)">Be authorized to screen individuals for whom voluntary or involuntary admission is being initiated to determine whether a less restrictive alternative can be provided; and</section><section prefix="(7)">Provide clear guidelines to avoid either the appearance or occurrence of conflicts of interest in the direction and operation of the core service agency or organizations which provide mental health services.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
