<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghg" order_by="ghg" level="1">Health - General</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghg-20-108</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this section the following words have the meanings indicated....</catch_line>
  <order_by>108</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Disabled individual" means an individual with actual or potential limitations in self-care, mobility, hygiene, vocation, family role, or coping mechanisms.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Reportable condition" means a:<section prefix="(i)">Spinal cord injury;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Stroke;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Amputation; or</section><section prefix="(iv)">Head injury.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Each hospital shall report to the Department within 7 days of the occurrence of a reportable condition.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The report shall contain the individual's name, age, residence, the type of disability, and any additional information that the Department requires.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The information collected under this section is confidential and not open to inspection nor considered a public record. The information shall only be used statistically for the use of the Department in the performance of its duties, except that the identities of individuals reported may be disclosed for research purposes in accordance with the criteria set forth in &#xA7; 10-624(e) of the State Government Article.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The report form shall be developed by the Department with input from physicians, disabled individuals, and consumer advocates. The Department shall be responsible for distributing the form to physicians and institutions.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Department shall establish a central registry to compile information about disabled individuals with reportable conditions.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Within 15 days of receiving a report of an individual with a reportable condition, the Department shall notify the individual or the individual's parent or guardian of any assistance or services that may be available from the State and of the eligibility requirements for such assistance or services.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Upon request, the Department shall refer the individual to appropriate divisions of the Department and other agencies, public or private, which provide rehabilitation services for persons with reportable conditions.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Department shall make each public and private health and social agency aware of the rehabilitation information provided by the Department and advise them how to contact the Department to obtain the information.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">All other agencies of the State shall cooperate with the Department to provide available, appropriate rehabilitation services to an individual with a reportable condition who meets the eligibility requirements for such services.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
