<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghg" order_by="ghg" level="1">Health - General</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghg-19-305</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this section the following words have the meanings indicated....</catch_line>
  <order_by>305</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Adverse event" means an unexpected occurrence that:<section prefix="(i)">Is related to a resident's medical or behavioral treatment; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Is not related to the natural course of the resident's illness or underlying disease condition.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Change in condition" means a significant change in a resident's physical, mental, or psychological status including:<section prefix="(i)">Life-threatening conditions;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Clinical complications including significant somatic symptoms that require the assessment of or treatment by qualified medical personnel;</section><section prefix="(iii)">The need to discontinue a medication or treatment because of:<section prefix="1.">Adverse consequences; or</section><section prefix="2.">The need to begin a new form of treatment;</section></section><section prefix="(iv)">Evaluation at or admission to a hospital;</section><section prefix="(v)">Injuries that require the assessment of or treatment by qualified medical personnel;</section><section prefix="(vi)">The use of restraint or seclusion; and</section><section prefix="(vii)">Suicide attempts.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Within 24 hours, in accordance with State and federal confidentiality laws, a residential treatment center shall attempt to notify a resident and a resident's representative, family member, legal guardian, or custodian of:<section prefix="(i)">A change in condition;</section><section prefix="(ii)">An adverse event; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Corrective action, if appropriate.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If a residential treatment center sends a notice to an individual under paragraph (1) of this subsection, the individual may send a written response to the residential treatment center instructing the residential treatment center that:<section prefix="(i)">The individual waives the notification required under paragraph (1) of this subsection; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">The individual only requires notification in the circumstances specified in writing by the individual.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A residential treatment center shall document the notification required under subsection (b)(1) of this section and the response of the resident and the resident's representative, family member, legal guardian, or custodian in the resident's medical record.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">If the Department determines that a residential treatment center failed to notify a resident and a resident's representative, family member, legal guardian, or custodian under subsection (b)(1) of this section, the Department shall require the residential treatment center, as part of a plan of correction, to notify the resident and the resident's representative, family member, legal guardian, or custodian as soon as possible.</section>
  </text>
</law>
