<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghg" order_by="" level="1">Health - General</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghg-13-2702</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>2702</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Subject to the limitations of its budget, the Department:<section prefix="(1)">In collaboration with the United States Department of Veterans Affairs, the Maryland Department of Veterans Affairs, the Maryland National Guard, and the Maryland Defense Force, shall provide behavioral health service coordination for veterans in all geographic regions of the State to connect them to behavioral health services which may be available through the United States Department of Veterans Affairs;</section><section prefix="(2)"><section prefix="(i)">Where behavioral health services are not yet available or accessible through the United States Department of Veterans Affairs, shall provide service coordination for veterans in all geographic regions of the State to connect them to behavioral health services which may be available through the Mental Hygiene Administration or the Alcohol and Drug Abuse Administration, until such federal services can be accessed and obtained; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Shall provide behavioral health services through the Mental Hygiene Administration or the Alcohol and Drug Abuse Administration based on eligibility and medical necessity criteria established by these administrations; and</section></section><section prefix="(3)">Shall provide veterans up-to-date information about behavioral health services and resources through a Web-based resource program.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Subject to the limitations of its budget and in addition to the service coordination provided under subsection (a) of this section, the Department shall provide or fund certain behavioral health services for veterans who:<section prefix="(1)">Meet the eligibility and medical necessity criteria of the Mental Hygiene Administration and the Alcohol and Drug Abuse Administration; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Cannot obtain immediate access to behavioral health services through the United States Department of Veterans Affairs.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The behavioral health services provided under subsection (b) of this section may include:<section prefix="(i)">Crisis services in all geographic regions of the State; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Short-term behavioral health services, where existing federal and State behavioral health services are determined by the Department to be inadequate or inaccessible.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The short-term behavioral health services provided under paragraph (1)(ii) of this subsection:<section prefix="(i)">Shall be available only until a veteran is able to access and obtain adequate behavioral health services through the United States Department of Veterans Affairs; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">May include:<section prefix="1.">Screening assessments;</section><section prefix="2.">Individual, family, and group therapy;</section><section prefix="3.">Substance abuse early intervention and detoxification services; and</section><section prefix="4.">Substance abuse medication-assisted treatment.</section></section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Department shall seek reimbursement from the United States Department of Veterans Affairs or other responsible public or private payer for any behavioral health services provided under subsection (b) of this section.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Department shall account separately for funds used to provide behavioral health services to veterans under subsection (b) of this section.</section>
  </text>
</law>
