<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghg" order_by="ghg" level="1">Health - General</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghg-21-336</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this section, "approved source" means a source of water that is:...</catch_line>
  <order_by>336</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section, "approved source" means a source of water that is:<section prefix="(i)">Sampled and found through laboratory analysis to comply with:<section prefix="1.">The microbiological standards adopted by the Department, with testing on a monthly basis; and</section><section prefix="2.">The chemical and radiological standards adopted by the Department, which shall meet or exceed the standards prescribed by the federal Food and Drug Administration, with testing annually for chemical analyses and once every 4 years for radiological analyses; and</section></section><section prefix="(ii)">If applicable, constructed and inspected in accordance with regulations adopted by the Department of the Environment under &#xA7;&#xA7; 9-204, 9-1305, and 9-1306 of the Environment Article.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Approved source" includes:<section prefix="(i)">An artesian well;</section><section prefix="(ii)">A drilled well;</section><section prefix="(iii)">A glacier;</section><section prefix="(iv)">A public water supply;</section><section prefix="(v)">A spring; and</section><section prefix="(vi)">A source of mineral water that complies with the standards specified in paragraph (1) of this subsection but fails to meet the standards with respect to those properties of mineral water related to the limitations on chloride, iron, manganese, sulfate, total dissolved solids, zinc, or any other exemptions listed under 21 C.F.R. 165.110.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Department may approve a source that does not meet standards regulated by the United States Environmental Protection Agency as a secondary standard if the bottler shows by analysis that a particular treatment used reduces the level of contaminants in the bottled water to a level below the maximum contaminant level.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The requirements of this section are in addition to any other provision of law.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Artesian water, mineral water, natural water, purified water, spring water, well water, and any other type of bottled water shall meet the requirements of the standard of identity for bottled water under 21 C.F.R. 165.110(a).</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A person may not bottle water unless the person is licensed by the Department under &#xA7; 21-305 of this subtitle.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Department may not issue a license if the Department determines that the water is:<section prefix="(i)">Not from an approved source; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">In any way injurious to the public health.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">To apply for a license to bottle water, a bottler shall:<section prefix="(i)">Submit an application to the Department on the form that the Department requires;</section><section prefix="(ii)">List on the application form the types of bottled water that the applicant proposes to bottle; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Pay to the Department an annual fee established by the Secretary under &#xA7; 2-104 of this article.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">While it is effective, a license to bottle water authorizes a bottler to bottle and sell in the State the types of bottled water identified in the license.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">A person who is licensed under this section shall submit to the Department the results of:<section prefix="1.">Annual chemical and radiological analyses of a representative sample of the person's source water and bottled water; and</section><section prefix="2.">A monthly microbiological analysis of a representative sample of the source water and bottled water.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The analyses shall demonstrate that the source water and bottled water comply with the chemical, radiological, and microbiological standards adopted by the Department, which shall meet or exceed the standards prescribed by the federal Food and Drug Administration.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">
          <section prefix="1.">Except as otherwise required by law, mineral water is not subject to the limitations on chloride, iron, manganese, sulfate, total dissolved solids, zinc, or any other exemptions listed under 21 C.F.R. 165.110.</section>
          <section prefix="2.">Bottled water may not exceed:</section>
        </section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Analyses required under this subsection may be performed by a laboratory certified by:<section prefix="1.">A state's Laboratory Certification Program in accordance with the United States Environmental Protection Agency's primacy conditions under the Agency's Public Water System Supervision Program; or</section><section prefix="2.">The United States Environmental Protection Agency.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The Department shall accept analyses performed by any laboratory authorized under subparagraph (i) of this paragraph.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A person licensed or registered under this section shall:<section prefix="(i)">For at least 2 years, maintain all inspection and sampling records at the person's principal place of business; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Make inspection and sampling records available to the Department upon request.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">Notwithstanding the analyses required under paragraph (1) of this subsection, the Department may sample and analyze any bottled water.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">The provisions of this subsection do not prevent the Department from prohibiting the use or sale of bottled water in the State, if, in the judgment of the Department:<section prefix="(i)">The water is shown by analysis to be unfit for drinking;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The water has been misbranded under &#xA7; 21-210 of this title; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">Its quality is in any way injurious to the public health.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">Bottled water in individual containers shall be marked on each container with a stencil, stamp, or label that clearly indicates:<section prefix="(1)">The identifying batch code for the water; and</section><section prefix="(2)">In compliance with subsection (g) of this section, the type of water and any additional ingredients.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(g)">Labeling of the type of bottled water and any additional ingredients, as required under subsection (f) of this section, shall conform to the labeling requirements for bottled water under 21 C.F.R. 165.110(a).</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">In accordance with regulations adopted by the Department, a person licensed under this section shall establish written procedures and implement those procedures to:<section prefix="(1)">Prevent contamination during the processing, packaging, transportation, or storage of bottled water; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Recall bottled water when the person, the Department, or any other government agency determines that a supply is injurious in any way to the public health.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(i)">The Department may suspend or revoke a license issued under this section if the licensee:<section prefix="(1)">Violates or fails to satisfy any requirement of this title or any regulation adopted under this title; or</section><section prefix="(2)">Fraudulently or deceptively obtains a license.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(j)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In addition to any other penalty applicable at law, a person who violates any provision of this section shall be liable for a civil penalty of:<section prefix="(i)">Not less than $1,000 and not more than $5,000 for a first offense; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Not less than $5,000 and not more than $10,000 for a second offense within 2 years of the first offense.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Each day on which a violation occurs constitutes a separate offense.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(k)">By October 1, 2008, the Department shall adopt regulations to implement the provisions of this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(l)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Department shall establish a Bottled Water Advisory Committee to advise and assist the Department in the development and adoption of the regulations required under subsection (k) of this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Advisory Committee shall consist of the following representatives:<section prefix="(i)">The Secretary of Health and Mental Hygiene or the Secretary's designee, who shall serve as chairman of the Advisory Committee;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The Secretary of the Environment or the Secretary's designee;</section><section prefix="(iii)">A hydrogeologist;</section><section prefix="(iv)">At least two individuals from the bottled water processing industry;</section><section prefix="(v)">At least one individual from the bottled water distribution industry;</section><section prefix="(vi)">At least one individual from the environmental community or consumer advocacy community; and</section><section prefix="(vii)">At least one consumer of bottled water.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
