<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghg" order_by="ghg" level="1">Health - General</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghg-5-705</section_number>
  <catch_line>Except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, there shall be a multidisciplinary and multi...</catch_line>
  <order_by>705</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, there shall be a multidisciplinary and multiagency child fatality review team in each county.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Instead of a local team in each county, two or more counties may agree to establish a single multicounty local team.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A multicounty local team shall execute a memorandum of understanding on membership, staffing, and operation.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The local team membership shall be drawn from the following individuals, organizations, agencies, and areas of expertise, when available:<section prefix="(1)">The county health officer;</section><section prefix="(2)">The director of the local department of social services;</section><section prefix="(3)">The State's Attorney;</section><section prefix="(4)">The superintendent of schools;</section><section prefix="(5)">A State, county, or municipal law enforcement officer;</section><section prefix="(6)">The director of the county substance abuse treatment program;</section><section prefix="(7)">The chief attorney who represents the local department of social services in child welfare proceedings;</section><section prefix="(8)">The Early Childhood Development Division in the State Department of Education;</section><section prefix="(9)">The director of the county mental health agency or core service agency;</section><section prefix="(10)">A pediatrician with experience in diagnosing and treating injuries and child abuse and neglect, appointed by the county health officer;</section><section prefix="(11)">A psychiatrist or psychologist with experience in child abuse and neglect or child injury, appointed by the director of the county mental health agency or core service agency;</section><section prefix="(12)">A member of the general public with interest or expertise in the prevention and treatment of child abuse and neglect, appointed by the county health officer; and</section><section prefix="(13)">Any other individual necessary to the work of the local team, recommended by the local team and appointed by the county health officer.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The members described under subsection (b)(1) through (9) of this section may designate representatives from their departments or offices to represent them on the local team.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">From among its members, each local team shall elect a chairperson by majority vote.</section>
  </text>
</law>
