<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghg" order_by="ghg" level="1">Health - General</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghg-2-501</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated....</catch_line>
  <order_by>501</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Abuse" means provider practices that are inconsistent with sound fiscal, business, or medical practices and result in unnecessary costs to a program, or in reimbursement for services that are not medically necessary or that fail to meet professionally recognized health care standards.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Claim" means a request or demand for money, property, or services made under contract or otherwise, by a contractor, grantee, provider, or other person seeking money for the provision of health services if:<section prefix="(1)">The State or Department provides any portion of the money or property that is requested or demanded; or</section><section prefix="(2)">The State or Department reimburses the contractor, grantee, provider, or other person for any portion of the money or property that is requested or demanded.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">"Employee" means any individual who performs services for, or under the control or direction of, a provider for wages or other remuneration.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Fraud" means an intentional material deception or misrepresentation made by a person with the knowledge that the deception or misrepresentation could result in some unauthorized benefit or payment.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Fraud" includes any act that constitutes fraud under applicable State or federal law.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">"Program" means the Medical Assistance Program, the Cigarette Restitution Fund Program, the Mental Hygiene Administration, the Developmental Disabilities Administration, the Alcohol and Drug Abuse Administration, the Family Health Administration, the Community Health Administration, or any other unit of the Department that pays a provider for a service rendered or claimed to have been rendered to a recipient.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Provider" means:<section prefix="(i)">An individual licensed or certified under the Health Occupations Article to provide health care;</section><section prefix="(ii)">A licensed facility that provides health care to individuals;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Any other person who or entity that provides health care, products, or services to a program recipient; or</section><section prefix="(iv)">A contractor, subcontractor, or vendor who directly or indirectly provides the Department or its recipients supplies, drugs, equipment, or services.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Provider" does not include a State agency that receives grant funding from or through the Department if that agency has in place a corporate compliance program that meets departmental requirements.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(h)">"Recipient" means an individual who receives benefits under a program.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">"Recovery" means the repayment of moneys to the Department by a provider through return, reimbursement, recoupment, withholding of future payments, offsets, or any other method.</section>
  </text>
</law>
