<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="ghg" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="5-408" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghg-5-408</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A person may not sell or buy any body or any part of a body that is under the exclusive control of the Board.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A person other than a nonprofit organization that qualifies under &#xA7; 501(c)(3) of the Internal Revenue Code, may not sell, buy, or act as a broker for a profit in the transfer of any human organ that:<section prefix="(i)">Is removed from a human body that is alive or dead at the time of removal; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Is not under the exclusive control of the Board.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">In this section, "human organ" does not include blood and plasma.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in paragraphs (2) and (3) of this subsection, a person may not send, transport, or permit or cause to be sent or transported out of the State any body or any part of a body that is under the exclusive control of the Board.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Board may authorize, by regulation, the transporting of human specimens under its exclusive control to an out-of-state medical study program, provided that:<section prefix="(i)">The needs of the schools of the State are met;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The requesting party demonstrates the need for a specimen;</section><section prefix="(iii)">The circumstances of the request are that:</section><section prefix="(iv)">The requesting party bears the responsibility for transporting and the specialized care of the specimen and all associated costs; and</section><section prefix="(v)">The Board retains the right of exclusive control of the specimen including the final disposition when appropriate or necessary to fulfill an obligation to return the remains of a donated specimen to the donor's family.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Board may authorize a physician, teacher, demonstrator, or investigator of advanced human biological sciences to send or transport human specimens out of the State for use by medical study programs.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
