<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghg" order_by="" level="1">Health - General</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghg-19-2201</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>2201</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, "Fund" means the Community Health Resources Commission Fund.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">There is a Community Health Resources Commission Fund.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Fund is a special, nonlapsing fund that is not subject to &#xA7; 7-302 of the State Finance and Procurement Article.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Treasurer shall hold the Fund separately, and the Comptroller shall account for the Fund.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Fund consists of:<section prefix="(1)">Money collected from a nonprofit health service plan in accordance with &#xA7; 14-106.1 of the Insurance Article;</section><section prefix="(2)">Interest earned on investments;</section><section prefix="(3)">Money donated to the Fund;</section><section prefix="(4)">Money awarded to the Fund through grants; and</section><section prefix="(5)">Any other money from any other source accepted for the benefit of the Fund.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Fund may be used only to:<section prefix="(i)">Cover the administrative costs of the Commission;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Cover the actual documented direct costs of fulfilling the statutory and regulatory duties of the Commission in accordance with the provisions of this subtitle;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Provide operating grants to qualifying community health resources; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">Provide funding for the development, support, and monitoring of a unified data information system among primary and specialty care providers, hospitals, and other providers of services to community health resource members.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The funding for a unified data information system under paragraph (1)(iv) of this subsection shall be limited to:<section prefix="(i)">$500,000 in fiscal year 2006; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">$1,700,000 in fiscal year 2007 and annually thereafter.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The Commission shall adopt regulations that:<section prefix="(1)">Establish the criteria for a community health resource to qualify for a grant;</section><section prefix="(2)">Establish the procedures for disbursing grants to qualifying community health resources;</section><section prefix="(3)">Develop a formula for disbursing grants to qualifying community health resources;</section><section prefix="(4)">Establish criteria and mechanisms for funding a unified data information system; and</section><section prefix="(5)">In consultation with the Secretary, implement a program to provide subsidies to community health resources for office-based specialty care visits, diagnostic testing, and laboratory tests.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(g)">In developing regulations under subsection (f)(1) of this section, the Commission shall:<section prefix="(1)">Consider geographic balance; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Give priority to community health resources that:<section prefix="(i)">In addition to normal business hours, have evening and weekend hours of operation;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Have partnered with a hospital to establish a reverse referral program at the hospital;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Reduce the use of the hospital emergency department for nonemergency services;</section><section prefix="(iv)">Assist patients in establishing a medical home with a community health resource;</section><section prefix="(v)">Coordinate and integrate the delivery of primary and specialty care services;</section><section prefix="(vi)">Promote the integration of mental and somatic health with federally qualified health centers or other somatic care providers;</section><section prefix="(vii)">Fund medication management or therapy services for uninsured individuals up to 200% of the federal poverty level who meet medical necessity criteria but who are ineligible for the public mental health system;</section><section prefix="(viii)">Provide a clinical home for individuals who access hospital emergency departments for mental health services, substance abuse services, or both; and</section><section prefix="(ix)">Support the implementation of evidence-based clinical practices.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(h)">Grants awarded to a community health resource under this section may be used:<section prefix="(1)">To provide operational assistance to a community health resource; and</section><section prefix="(2)">For any other purpose the Commission determines is appropriate to assist a community health resource.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(i)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Treasurer shall invest the money in the Fund in the same manner as other State money may be invested.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Any investment earnings of the Fund shall be retained to the credit of the Fund.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(j)">The Fund shall be subject to an audit by the Office of Legislative Audits as provided for in &#xA7; 2-1220 of the State Government Article.</section>
  </text>
</law>
