<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghg" order_by="" level="1">Health - General</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghg-10-910</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>910</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">There is an advisory committee for the program.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The advisory committee consists of 13 members appointed by the Secretary.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Of the 13 members:<section prefix="(i)">3 shall be members of the Maryland Association of the Deaf;</section><section prefix="(ii)">2 shall be mental health practitioners who are hearing impaired individuals;</section><section prefix="(iii)">2 shall be mental health practitioners who are not hearing impaired individuals;</section><section prefix="(iv)">2 shall be individuals in the field of deaf education;</section><section prefix="(v)">1 shall be a parent of a hearing impaired individual;</section><section prefix="(vi)">1 shall be from the Maryland Association for Hearing Impaired Children; and</section><section prefix="(vii)">2 shall be public members who represent the community at large.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Secretary shall appoint the advisory committee from recommendations made by:<section prefix="(i)">The Maryland Association of the Deaf;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The National Association of the Deaf;</section><section prefix="(iii)">The International Association of Parents of the Deaf;</section><section prefix="(iv)">The Maryland School for the Deaf;</section><section prefix="(v)">The Alexander Graham Bell Association of the Deaf;</section><section prefix="(vi)">The Maryland Regional Council of Child Psychiatry;</section><section prefix="(vii)">The Maryland Chapter of the National Association of Social Workers;</section><section prefix="(viii)">The Maryland Psychological Association; and</section><section prefix="(ix)">The State Department of Education.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The advisory committee shall:<section prefix="(1)">Be consulted about the administration of the program; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Link the program to the community of hearing impaired individuals.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The advisory committee shall meet at the times and places that it determines.</section>
  </text>
</law>
