<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghg" order_by="ghg" level="1">Health - General</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghg-8-601</section_number>
  <catch_line>If any individual seeks counseling, treatment, or therapy, for any form of drug or alcohol abuse, fr...</catch_line>
  <order_by>601</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">If any individual seeks counseling, treatment, or therapy, for any form of drug or alcohol abuse, from a health professional licensed under the Health Occupations Article treating patients within the scope of the professional's practice, or hospital, or a person who is certified by the Administration for counseling or treating drug or alcohol abuse, the oral or written statements that the individual makes and the observations and conclusions that the health professional, hospital, or other person derives or the results of an examination to determine the existence of an illegal or prohibited drug in the body of an individual are not admissible in any proceeding against the individual, other than and subject to the federal regulations concerning the confidentiality of alcohol and drug abuse patient records:<section prefix="(1)">A proceeding that relates to parole or probation or conditional release from a not criminally responsible finding, if the examination had been ordered as a condition of parole or probation or the conditional release from a not criminally responsible finding; or</section><section prefix="(2)">A proceeding under Subtitle 5 of this title, if the examination had been ordered for that proceeding.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The results of a proceeding under Subtitle 5 of this title and evidence in the proceeding may not be used against that individual in any other proceeding.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The disclosure and use of the records of individuals served by alcohol abuse and drug abuse treatment programs shall be governed by the federal regulations on the confidentiality of alcohol and drug abuse patient records, 42 C.F.R. Part 2.</section>
  </text>
</law>
