<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghg" order_by="" level="1">Health - General</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghg-21-2A-03</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>03</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Department shall implement the Program, subject to the availability of funds.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Secretary may:<section prefix="(1)">Assign responsibility for the operation of the Program to any unit in the Department; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Contract with any qualified person for the efficient and economical operation of the Program.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Except as provided in subsection (d) of this section, each dispenser shall submit prescription monitoring data to the Program by electronic means, in accordance with regulations adopted by the Secretary.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Secretary, for good cause shown, may authorize a dispenser to submit prescription monitoring data by an alternative form of submission.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The Secretary, in consultation with the Maryland Health Care Commission and the Board, shall:<section prefix="(1)">Determine the appropriate technology to support the operation of the Program; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Educate dispensers, prescribers, and consumers about the purpose and operation of the Program.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Secretary shall grant a waiver to a pharmacy that dispenses medications to an inpatient hospice from reporting to the Program prescription monitoring data for hospice inpatients if:<section prefix="(i)">The pharmacy demonstrates how it will distinguish hospice inpatients from other consumers receiving medications from the pharmacy; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">The pharmacy agrees that it will be subject to onsite, unannounced inspections by the Department to verify its reporting of the prescription data of consumers who are not hospice inpatients.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A waiver granted under this subsection may remain in effect for up to 2 years.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Secretary may establish an application process for a pharmacy to apply for a waiver under this subsection.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
