<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="ghg" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="21-401" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghg-21-401</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Bobtailer" means a person who operates or controls a Grade A milk route and distributes Grade A pasteurized milk products that the person buys from a Grade A distributor or a milk processor.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Bulk milk hauler/sampler" means any person who collects official samples and transports raw milk from a farm or raw milk products or both to or from a milk plant, receiving station, or transfer station and who possesses a permit from any state to sample the milk or raw milk products.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">"Certified industry dairy farm inspector" means an individual who is certified by the Secretary under &#xA7; 21-414 of this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"Dairy farm" means a place where at least 1 cow or goat is kept, and from which the milk is sold or offered for sale.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">"Departmental inspection area" means the area in which the Department routinely makes inspections under this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">"Farmstead cheese" means cheese made on a farm:<section prefix="(1)">Using only the raw milk produced by the herd on the farm; and</section><section prefix="(2)">That meets the definitions and standards of a hard cheese established in 21 C.F.R. 133.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(h)">"Grade A distribution station" means any place or vehicle where, for redistribution and sale, Grade A pasteurized milk products routinely are received, stored, or transferred.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">"Grade A distributor" means a person who sells a Grade A pasteurized milk product.</section>
    <section prefix="(j)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Grade A milk product" means:<section prefix="(i)">Grade A milk;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Grade A cream; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">Any other Grade A milk product that the Secretary designates.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Manufactured grade milk product" means:<section prefix="(i)">Manufactured grade milk;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Manufactured grade cream; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">Any other manufactured grade milk product that the Secretary designates.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(k)">"Grade A Pasteurized Milk Ordinance" means the recommended Grade "A" Pasteurized Milk Ordinance published by the federal government.</section>
    <section prefix="(l)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Milk" means the milk of a cow or goat.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Grade A milk" means the milk of a cow or goat produced, processed, pasteurized, bottled, packaged, or prepared in accordance with the Grade A Pasteurized Milk Ordinance.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Manufactured milk" means the milk of a cow or goat which is not Grade A milk and which is produced, processed, pasteurized, bottled, packaged, or prepared in accordance with "Milk for Manufacturing Purposes and Its Production and Processing: Recommended Requirements".</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(m)">"Milk fat" means the natural fat of milk.</section>
    <section prefix="(n)">"Milk for Manufacturing Purposes and Its Production and Processing: Recommended Requirements" means the Milk for Manufacturing Purposes and Its Production and Processing: Recommended Requirements published by the U.S. Department of Agriculture.</section>
    <section prefix="(o)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Milk plant" means any place where, for distribution, milk products are:<section prefix="(i)">Processed;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Pasteurized;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Bottled or packaged; or</section><section prefix="(iv)">Prepared.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Milk plant" does not include a place where milk products are sold at retail only.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(p)">"Milk processor" means a person who owns, operates, or controls a milk plant.</section>
    <section prefix="(q)">"Milk producer" means a person who operates a dairy farm.</section>
    <section prefix="(r)">"Milk tank truck" means a truck and its equipment that are used to transport milk products.</section>
    <section prefix="(s)">"Milk transportation company" means a person responsible for a milk tank truck.</section>
    <section prefix="(t)">"Misbranded milk product" means a milk product:<section prefix="(1)">That is in a container that bears or is accompanied by any false or misleading written, printed, or graphic material; or</section><section prefix="(2)">That is not labeled in accordance with this subtitle.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(u)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Pasteurized" means having undergone the process of uniformly heating each particle of milk product, holding it in the heated state, and cooling it, in approved and properly operated equipment and under the conditions of temperature and time that the Secretary by rule or regulation establishes, to make the milk product safe and free of pathogens.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Pasteurized" includes having undergone any other process that:<section prefix="(i)">Is recognized by the appropriate federal authority to be equally as effective as the process described in paragraph (1) of this subsection in making milk products safe and free of pathogens; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Is approved by the Secretary.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(v)">"Permit" means a permit issued by the Secretary under this subtitle that authorizes the holder of the permit to do any act that is within the scope of the permit.</section>
    <section prefix="(w)">"Raw milk" means unpasteurized milk.</section>
    <section prefix="(x)">"Receiving station" means any place where, for delivery to a milk plant, raw milk is collected, cooled, and stored.</section>
    <section prefix="(y)">"Transfer station" means a place where milk is transferred directly from a milk tank truck to another milk tank truck for delivery to a milk plant.</section>
  </text>
</law>
