<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghg" order_by="ghg" level="1">Health - General</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghg-7-206</section_number>
  <catch_line>Upon notification of the death of an individual in a program or facility funded or operated by the A...</catch_line>
  <order_by>206</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Upon notification of the death of an individual in a program or facility funded or operated by the Administration, the administrative head of the program or facility shall report the death:<section prefix="(i)">Immediately to the sheriff, police, or chief law enforcement official in the jurisdiction in which the death occurred;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Immediately to the Secretary; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">By the close of business the next working day to:<section prefix="1.">The Director;</section><section prefix="2.">The health officer in the jurisdiction where the death occurred; and</section><section prefix="3.">The designated State protection and advocacy system.</section></section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A report may be:<section prefix="(i)">Oral if followed by a written report within 5 working days from the date of the death; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">Written.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A written report shall contain:<section prefix="(i)">The name, age, and sex of the deceased;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The time of discovery of the death;</section><section prefix="(iii)">The deceased's place of residence at the time of death;</section><section prefix="(iv)">The location where the body was discovered;</section><section prefix="(v)">The name of the person who took custody of the body;</section><section prefix="(vi)">The name of the person evaluating the death, if known;</section><section prefix="(vii)">Whether or not an autopsy is being performed, if known;</section><section prefix="(viii)">The name, address, and telephone number of the next of kin or legal guardian, if known; and</section><section prefix="(ix)">Any other information the administrative head of the service or program determines should be provided to the medical examiner and the persons listed in paragraph (1) of this subsection on the deaths occurring:<section prefix="1.">By violence;</section><section prefix="2.">By suicide;</section><section prefix="3.">By casualty;</section><section prefix="4.">Suddenly, if the deceased was in apparent good health; or</section><section prefix="5.">In any suspicious or unusual manner.</section></section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The sheriff, police, or chief law enforcement officer shall inform a medical examiner in accordance with &#xA7; 5-309(b) of this article, and the medical examiner, if necessary, shall conduct an investigation in accordance with the provisions of that section.</section>
  </text>
</law>
