<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghg" order_by="" level="1">Health - General</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghg-19-401</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>401</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Home health agency" means a health-related institution, organization, or a part of an institution that:<section prefix="(1)">Is owned or operated by 1 or more persons, whether or not for profit and whether as a public or private enterprise; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Directly or through a contractual arrangement, provides to a sick or disabled individual in the residence of that individual skilled nursing services, home health aid services, and at least one other home health care service that are centrally administered.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Home health care" means any of the following services that are provided under the general direction of a licensed health professional practicing within the scope of their practice:<section prefix="(i)">Audiology and speech pathology;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Dietary and nutritional services;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Drug services;</section><section prefix="(iv)">Home health aid;</section><section prefix="(v)">Laboratory;</section><section prefix="(vi)">Medical social services;</section><section prefix="(vii)">Nursing;</section><section prefix="(viii)">Occupational therapy;</section><section prefix="(ix)">Physical therapy; or</section><section prefix="(x)">Provision of medically necessary sickroom equipment and supplies.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">However, the provisions of this subsection do not apply to:<section prefix="(i)">A nursing referral service agency that is licensed as a nursing referral service agency under the provisions of Subtitle 4B of this title; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">A home-based hospice care program that is licensed as a home-based hospice care program under the provisions of Subtitle 9 of this title.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A home health agency shall also be licensed as a hospice care program if the home health agency operates a hospice care program that is distinct from its other services.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
