<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghg" order_by="ghg" level="1">Health - General</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghg-19-1A-02</section_number>
  <catch_line>// EFFECTIVE UNTIL DECEMBER 31, 2015 PER CHAPTERS 5 AND 6 OF 2010 //...</catch_line>
  <order_by>02</order_by>
  <text>// EFFECTIVE UNTIL DECEMBER 31, 2015 PER CHAPTERS 5 AND 6 OF 2010 //<section prefix="(a)">Subject to &#xA7; 19-1A-03(a) of this subtitle, the Commission shall establish the Maryland Patient Centered Medical Home Program to promote development of patient centered medical homes.</section><section prefix="(b)"><section prefix="(1)">A carrier may elect to participate in the Maryland Patient Centered Medical Home Program.</section><section prefix="(2)">Notwithstanding the provisions of paragraph (1) of this subsection, a prominent carrier shall participate in the Maryland Patient Centered Medical Home Program.</section><section prefix="(3)">Subject to the limitations of the State budget, the Department:<section prefix="(i)">May require that certain managed care organizations participate in the Maryland Patient Centered Medical Home Program as allowed by law; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Notwithstanding any other provision of this article, may mandate the participation in the Maryland Patient Centered Medical Home Program of Maryland Medical Assistance Program enrollees.</section></section><section prefix="(4)">The Department shall ensure that participation in the Maryland Patient Centered Medical Home Program of managed care organizations and Maryland Medical Assistance Program enrollees shall support the quality and efficiency standards established in the HealthChoice Program.</section></section><section prefix="(c)">The Commission may also authorize a carrier to implement a single carrier patient centered medical home program that:<section prefix="(1)">Pays and shares medical information with a patient centered medical home in accordance with &#xA7; 15-1802 of the Insurance Article; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Conforms with the principles of the patient centered medical home as adopted by a national coalition of physicians, carriers, purchasers, and consumers.</section></section><section prefix="(d)">Nothing in this section shall be construed to limit or prohibit a carrier from providing a bonus, fee based incentives, bundled incentives, or other incentive-based compensation:<section prefix="(1)">As authorized by the Commission for a patient centered medical home; or</section><section prefix="(2)">As allowed under &#xA7; 15-113 of the Insurance Article.</section></section></text>
</law>
