<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghg" order_by="" level="1">Health - General</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghg-19-108.2</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>108.2</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">''Health care service" has the meaning stated in &#xA7; 15-10A-01 of the Insurance Article.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Payor" means:<section prefix="(i)">An insurer or nonprofit health service plan that provides hospital, medical, or surgical benefits to individuals or groups on an expense-incurred basis under health insurance policies or contracts that are issued or delivered in the State;</section><section prefix="(ii)">A health maintenance organization that provides hospital, medical, or surgical benefits to individuals or groups under contracts that are issued or delivered in the State; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">A pharmacy benefits manager that is registered with the Maryland Insurance Commissioner.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">"Provider" has the meaning stated in &#xA7; 19-7A-01 of this title.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">In addition to the duties stated elsewhere in this subtitle, the Commission shall work with payors and providers to attain benchmarks for standardizing and automating the process required by payors for preauthorizing health care services.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The benchmarks described in subsection (b) of this section shall include:<section prefix="(1)">On or before October 1, 2012 ("Phase 1"), establishment of online access for providers to each payor's:<section prefix="(i)">List of health care services that require preauthorization; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Key criteria for making a determination on a preauthorization request;</section></section><section prefix="(2)">On or before March 1, 2013 ("Phase 2"), establishment by each payor of an online process for:<section prefix="(i)">Accepting electronically a preauthorization request from a provider; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Assigning to a preauthorization request a unique electronic identification number that a provider may use to track the request during the preauthorization process, whether or not the request is tracked electronically, through a call center, or by fax;</section></section><section prefix="(3)">On or before July 1, 2013 ("Phase 3"), establishment by each payor of an online preauthorization system to approve:<section prefix="(i)">In real time, electronic preauthorization requests for pharmaceutical services:<section prefix="1.">For which no additional information is needed by the payor to process the preauthorization request; and</section><section prefix="2.">That meet the payor's criteria for approval;</section></section><section prefix="(ii)">Within 1 business day after receiving all pertinent information on requests not approved in real time, electronic preauthorization requests for pharmaceutical services that:<section prefix="1.">Are not urgent; and</section><section prefix="2.">Do not meet the standards for real-time approval under item (i) of this item; and</section></section><section prefix="(iii)">Within 2 business days after receiving all pertinent information, electronic preauthorization requests for health care services, except pharmaceutical services, that are not urgent; and</section></section><section prefix="(4)">On or before July 1, 2015, utilization by providers of:<section prefix="(i)">The online preauthorization system established by payors; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">If a national transaction standard has been established and adopted by the health care industry, as determined by the Commission, the provider's practice management, electronic health record, or e-prescribing system.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The benchmarks described in subsections (b) and (c) of this section do not apply to preauthorizations of health care services requested by providers employed by a group model health maintenance organization as defined in &#xA7; 19-713.6 of this title.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The online preauthorization system described in subsection (c)(3) of this section shall:<section prefix="(1)">Provide real-time notice to providers about preauthorization requests approved in real time; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Provide notice to providers, within the time frames specified in subsection (c)(3)(ii) and (iii) of this section and in a manner that is able to be tracked by providers, about preauthorization requests not approved in real time.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Commission shall establish by regulation a process through which a payor or provider may be waived from attaining the benchmarks described in subsections (b) and (c) of this section for extenuating circumstances.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">For a provider, the extenuating circumstances may include:<section prefix="(i)">The lack of broadband Internet access;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Low patient volume; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">Not making medical referrals or prescribing pharmaceuticals.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">For a payor, the extenuating circumstances may include:<section prefix="(i)">Low premium volume; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">For a group model health maintenance organization, as defined in &#xA7; 19-713.6 of this title, preauthorizations of health care services requested by providers not employed by the group model health maintenance organization.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">On or before October 1, 2012, the Commission shall reconvene the multistakeholder workgroup whose collaboration resulted in the 2011 report "Recommendations for Implementing Electronic Prior Authorizations".</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The workgroup shall:<section prefix="(i)">Review the progress to date in attaining the benchmarks described in subsections (b) and (c) of this section; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Make recommendations to the Commission for adjustments to the benchmark dates.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(h)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Payors shall report to the Commission:<section prefix="(i)">On or before March 1, 2013, on:<section prefix="1.">The status of their attainment of the Phase 1 and Phase 2 benchmarks; and</section><section prefix="2.">An outline of their plans for attaining the Phase 3 benchmarks; and</section></section><section prefix="(ii)">On or before December 1, 2013, on their attainment of the Phase 3 benchmarks.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Commission shall specify the criteria payors must use in reporting on their attainment and plans.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(i)">
      <section prefix="(1)">On or before March 31, 2013, the Commission shall report to the Governor and, in accordance with &#xA7; 2-1246 of the State Government Article, the General Assembly, on:<section prefix="(i)">The progress in attaining the benchmarks for standardizing and automating the process required by payors for preauthorizing health care services; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Taking into account the recommendations of the multistakeholder workgroup under subsection (g) of this section, any adjustment needed to the Phase 2 or Phase 3 benchmark dates.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">On or before December 31, 2013, and on or before December 31 in each succeeding year through 2016, the Commission shall report to the Governor and, in accordance with &#xA7; 2-1246 of the State Government Article, the General Assembly on the attainment of the benchmarks for standardizing and automating the process required by payors for preauthorizing health care services.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(j)">If necessary to attain the benchmarks, the Commission may adopt regulations to:<section prefix="(1)">Adjust the Phase 2 or Phase 3 benchmark dates;</section><section prefix="(2)">Require payors and providers to comply with the benchmarks; and</section><section prefix="(3)">Establish penalties for noncompliance.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
