<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghg" order_by="" level="1">Health - General</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghg-15-109</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>109</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">An individual is not ineligible under the Program solely because Social Security benefits received by the individual are increased, unless:<section prefix="(1)">The individual is considered ineligible because of the increase under applicable rules or regulations of the United States Department of Health and Human Services; and</section><section prefix="(2)">As to that individual, federal matching funds for the State Program are not available.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Except as provided in &#xA7; 15-103(a)(2)(ii) of this subtitle, to determine eligibility under the Program, the Department annually shall set the allowable yearly income levels in amounts at least equal to the following:<section prefix="(1)">Family of 1 - $2,500.</section><section prefix="(2)">Family of 2 - $3,000.</section><section prefix="(3)">Family of 3 - $3,500.</section><section prefix="(4)">Family of 4 - $4,000.</section><section prefix="(5)">Family of 5 or more - $4,500 plus an increase of $500 for each family member in excess of 5.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">This section is effective only to the extent that its provisions do not conflict with federal requirements for the administration of the Program in this State.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">As a condition of eligibility for medical assistance, a recipient is deemed to have assigned to the Secretary of Health and Mental Hygiene or the Secretary's designee any rights to payment for medical care services from any third party who has the legal liability to make payments for those services, to the extent of any payments made by the Department on behalf of the recipient.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Each resident of a nursing home who is a recipient of medical assistance shall receive a personal needs allowance.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">After a determination of income eligibility is made for a nursing home resident under the Program, the personal needs allowance shall be deducted from the total income of the resident.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The personal needs allowance for each resident of a nursing home who is a recipient of medical assistance shall be:<section prefix="(i)">If on or before June 30, 2002, the federal Centers for Medicare and Medicaid Services approve the Department's application for an amendment to the State's existing &#xA7; 1115 demonstration waiver necessary to implement the Maryland Pharmacy Discount Program established under &#xA7; 15-124.1 of this subtitle:<section prefix="1.">Beginning April 1, 2003, $50 per month;</section><section prefix="2.">Beginning July 1, 2004, $60 per month; and</section><section prefix="3.">Beginning July 1, 2005, adjusted annually by an amount not exceeding 5% to reflect the percentage by which benefits under Title II of the Social Security Act (42 U.S.C. 401 et seq.) are increased by the federal government to reflect changes in the cost of living, as that percentage change is reported in the Federal Register in accordance with 42 U.S.C. 415(a)(1)(D); or</section></section><section prefix="(ii)">If on or before June 30, 2002, the federal Centers for Medicare and Medicaid Services do not approve the Department's application for an amendment to the State's existing &#xA7; 1115 demonstration waiver necessary to implement the Maryland Pharmacy Discount Program established under &#xA7; 15-124.1 of this subtitle:<section prefix="1.">Beginning July 1, 2003, $50 per month;</section><section prefix="2.">Beginning July 1, 2004, $60 per month; and</section><section prefix="3.">Beginning July 1, 2005, adjusted annually by an amount not exceeding 5% to reflect the percentage by which benefits under Title II of the Social Security Act (42 U.S.C. 401 et seq.) are increased by the federal government to reflect changes in the cost of living, as that percentage change is reported in the Federal Register in accordance with 42 U.S.C. 415(a)(1)(D).</section></section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The Secretary shall adopt regulations to implement this subsection.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">Subject to the confidentiality requirements of State and federal law, the courts of this State shall admit a certified copy of a 206N form, also known as a long-term care transaction form, into evidence.</section>
  </text>
</law>
