<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghg" order_by="ghg" level="1">Health - General</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghg-19-717</section_number>
  <catch_line>Except as provided in subsections (b) and (c) of this section and unless, for good cause shown, the ...</catch_line>
  <order_by>717</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Except as provided in subsections (b) and (c) of this section and unless, for good cause shown, the Commissioner extends the time for a reasonable period:<section prefix="(1)">On or before March 1 of each year, each health maintenance organization shall file with the Commissioner a report that shows the financial condition of the health maintenance organization on the last day of the preceding calendar year and any other information that the Commissioner requires by rule or regulation; and</section><section prefix="(2)">On or before June 1 of each year, each health maintenance organization shall file with the Commissioner an audited financial report for the preceding calendar year.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A health maintenance organization that has a fiscal year other than the calendar year may request permission to file both the annual report required under subsection (a)(1) of this section and the audited financial report required under subsection (a)(2) of this section at the end of its fiscal year rather than the preceding calendar year. If the Commissioner grants this permission, the health maintenance organization shall file the annual report with the Commissioner within 60 days after the end of its fiscal year, and the health maintenance organization shall file the audited financial report with the Commissioner within 150 days after the end of its fiscal year.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">With 90 days' advance notice, the Commissioner may require a health maintenance organization to file an audited financial report earlier than the date specified in subsection (a) of this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The annual report shall:<section prefix="(1)">Be on the forms that the Commissioner requires; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Include a description of any changes in the information submitted under &#xA7; 19-708 of this subtitle.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The audited financial report shall:<section prefix="(1)">Be on the forms that the Commissioner requires; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Be certified by an audit of a certified public accounting firm.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">Each financial report filed under this section is a public record.</section>
  </text>
</law>
