<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghg" order_by="" level="1">Health - General</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghg-24-1304</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>1304</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The allocation and use of State funds under this subtitle are subject to the terms and conditions set forth in this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">State funds may only be used for the purposes listed under &#xA7; 24-1302 of this subtitle and approved by the Secretary under &#xA7; 24-1303 of this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The allocation and use of State funds under this subtitle are subject to the following terms and conditions:<section prefix="(1)">Any federal or other grant that is received for an eligible project shall be applied first to the cost of the project;</section><section prefix="(2)">Except as provided in subsection (d) of this section, a State grant may not exceed 50% of the cost of eligible work remaining unpaid after all federal grants have been applied; and</section><section prefix="(3)">For purposes of this subtitle, community development block grant funds shall be considered as local matching funds and may not be considered as federal grant funds.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">For a project designated as eligible for poverty area funding under federal regulations, State plans, or departmental regulations, a State grant may cover up to 75% of the cost of eligible work remaining unpaid after all federal grants have been applied.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The amount of the State grant recommended to the Board of Public Works for any project shall be determined after consideration of:<section prefix="(1)">All eligible projects;</section><section prefix="(2)">The total of unallocated State funds available at the time the grant recommendation is made to the Board of Public Works; and</section><section prefix="(3)">The priorities of area need established by the Department.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">No portion of the proceeds of a State grant may be used:<section prefix="(i)">To further sectarian religious instruction;</section><section prefix="(ii)">In connection with the design, acquisition, or construction of any building to be used as a place of sectarian religious worship or instruction; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">In connection with any program or department of divinity for any religious denomination.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">On the request of the Board of Public Works, the applicant shall submit evidence satisfactory to the Board that the proceeds of the grant are not being used for a purpose prohibited under this subsection or under applicable federal law.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">Beginning in fiscal year 2007 and continuing every fiscal year thereafter, the Governor shall include an appropriation in the State capital budget to be distributed and managed in accordance with this subtitle.</section>
  </text>
</law>
