<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="ghg" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="10-308" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghg-10-308</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Except as otherwise provided in subsections (c) and (d) of this section, the governing body of each county shall establish a mental health advisory committee.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The purpose of a mental health advisory committee shall be to serve as advocate for a comprehensive mental health system for persons of all ages.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The governing bodies of two or more counties may establish, by agreement, an intercounty mental health advisory committee if:<section prefix="(1)">The population of one of the counties is too small to warrant the establishment of a mental health advisory committee for that county; and</section><section prefix="(2)">The Director consents.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The governing body of a county may establish a joint mental health and addictions advisory committee.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">In Howard County, if a quasi-public authority is established under Subtitle 12 of this title, the governing body may designate the authority as the mental health advisory committee for the county.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">In Baltimore City, the governing body may designate Baltimore Mental Health Systems, Inc., the core service agency for Baltimore City under Subtitle 12 of this title, as the mental health advisory committee for Baltimore City.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">In Anne Arundel County, the governing body may designate Anne Arundel County Mental Health Agency, Inc., the core service agency for Anne Arundel County under Subtitle 12 of this title, as the mental health advisory committee for Anne Arundel County.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">In Washington County, the governing body may designate Washington County Mental Health Authority, Inc., the core service agency for Washington County under Subtitle 12 of this title, as the mental health advisory committee for Washington County.</section>
  </text>
</law>
