<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghg" order_by="" level="1">Health - General</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghg-2-601</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>601</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Claim" means a request or demand, under a contract or otherwise, for money or other property, whether or not the State has title to the money or property, that is:<section prefix="(i)">Presented through a State health plan or a State health program to an officer, employee, or agent of the State; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">Made to a contractor, grantee, or other recipient, if the money or other property is to be spent or used on the State's behalf or to advance a State interest through a State health plan or State health program, and the State:<section prefix="1.">Provides or has provided any portion of the money or other property requested or demanded; or</section><section prefix="2.">Will reimburse the contractor, grantee, or other recipient for any portion of the money or other property that is requested or demanded.</section></section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Claim" does not include requests or demands for money or other property that the State through a State health plan or State health program has paid to an individual as compensation for State employment or as an income subsidy with no restrictions on that individual's use of the money or other property.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Documentary material" includes:<section prefix="(1)">The original or a copy of:<section prefix="(i)">A book;</section><section prefix="(ii)">A record;</section><section prefix="(iii)">A report;</section><section prefix="(iv)">A memorandum;</section><section prefix="(v)">A paper;</section><section prefix="(vi)">A communication;</section><section prefix="(vii)">A tabulation;</section><section prefix="(viii)">A chart;</section><section prefix="(ix)">A document; or</section><section prefix="(x)">Data compilation stored in or accessible through a computer or other information retrieval system, including instructions and all other materials necessary to use or interpret the data compilation; and</section></section><section prefix="(2)">Any product of discovery, including:<section prefix="(i)">The original or duplicate of any deposition, interrogatory, document, thing, result of an inspection of land or other property, examination, or admission that is obtained by any method of discovery in any judicial or administrative proceeding of an adversarial nature;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Any digest, analysis, selection, compilation, or derivation of any item listed in item (i) of this item; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Any index or other manner of access to any item listed in item (i) of this item.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">"Employee" means an individual who performs services:<section prefix="(1)">For and under the control and direction of an employer; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Under an employer's promise or implied promise of payment of wages or other remuneration.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"Employer" means a person or group of persons who, acting directly or indirectly on behalf of another person or group of persons:<section prefix="(1)">Allows an employee to perform services under the employer's control and direction; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Promises or implies that the employee will receive wages or other remuneration in payment for the performance of those services.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Knowing" or "knowingly" means, with respect to information and without requiring proof of specific intent to defraud, that a person:<section prefix="(i)">Has actual knowledge of the information;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Acts in deliberate ignorance of the truth or falsity of the information; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">Acts in reckless disregard of the truth or falsity of the information.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Knowing" or "knowingly" does not mean, with respect to information, that a person acts in a manner that constitutes mistake or negligence.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">"Material" means having a natural tendency to influence or be capable of influencing the payment or receipt of money or other property.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">"Obligation" means an established duty, whether or not fixed, arising from:<section prefix="(1)">An express or implied:<section prefix="(i)">Contractual relationship;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Grantor-grantee relationship; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">Licensor-licensee relationship;</section></section><section prefix="(2)">A fee-based or similar relationship;</section><section prefix="(3)">Statute or regulation; or</section><section prefix="(4)">The retention of an overpayment.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(i)">"Provider" has the meaning stated in &#xA7; 2-501 of this title.</section>
    <section prefix="(j)">"Public body" means:<section prefix="(1)">The General Assembly or any other elected body;</section><section prefix="(2)">A member or an employee of the General Assembly or other elected body;</section><section prefix="(3)">A State court;</section><section prefix="(4)">A member or an employee of a State court;</section><section prefix="(5)">A State or local regulatory, administrative, or public agency or authority;</section><section prefix="(6)">An instrumentality of a State or local regulatory, administrative, or public agency or authority;</section><section prefix="(7)">A State or local law enforcement agency, prosecutorial office, or police or peace officer;</section><section prefix="(8)">A State or local department of an executive branch of government; or</section><section prefix="(9)">A division, board, bureau, office, committee, or commission of any of the public bodies listed in this subsection.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(k)">"Retaliatory action" means:<section prefix="(1)">Discharging, suspending, demoting, threatening, harassing, or discriminating against an employee, contractor, or agent; or</section><section prefix="(2)">Any other adverse action taken against an employee, contractor, or agent relating to the conditions of employment, contract, or agency.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(l)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"State health plan" means:<section prefix="(i)">The State Medical Assistance Plan established in accordance with the federal Social Security Act of 1939, as amended;</section><section prefix="(ii)">A medical assistance plan established by the State; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">A private health insurance carrier, health maintenance organization, managed care organization as defined in &#xA7; 15-101 of this article, health care cooperative or alliance, or another person that provides or contracts to provide health care services that are wholly or partially reimbursed by, or are a required benefit of, a health plan established in accordance with the federal Social Security Act of 1939, as amended, or by the State.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"State health plan" includes a person who provides or contracts or subcontracts to provide health care services for an entity described in paragraph (1) of this subsection.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(m)">"State health program" means the Medical Assistance Program, the Cigarette Restitution Fund Program, the Mental Hygiene Administration, the Developmental Disabilities Administration, the Alcohol and Drug Abuse Administration, the Family Health Administration, the Infectious Disease and Environmental Health Administration, or any other unit of the Department that pays a provider for a service rendered or claimed to have been rendered to a recipient.</section>
    <section prefix="(n)">"Supervisor" means an individual within an employer's organization who has the authority to:<section prefix="(1)">Direct and control the work performance of an employee; or</section><section prefix="(2)">Take corrective action regarding the violation of a law or regulation that is the subject of a complaint or charge under this subtitle.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
