<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="ghg" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="14-401" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghg-14-401</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Alternative accreditation" means a national camping standard that is acceptable to the Secretary as providing adequate health and safety protection for the campers, such as the American Camping Association standards for camp programs and services and the Boy Scouts of America standards, which includes an annual monitoring process to verify compliance with the standard.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Camper" means any child under 18 years of age who is attending a youth camp.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">"Certificate" means a single certificate issued by the Department to a youth camp under this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"Council" means the Youth Camp Safety Advisory Council.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">"Day" means all or part of a 24-hour period.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">"Day camp" means a youth camp that:<section prefix="(1)">Is operated for all or part of the day but less than 24 hours a day;</section><section prefix="(2)">Is conducted for at least 7 days during a 3-week period; and</section><section prefix="(3)">Provides 3 or more recreational activities or any 1 specialized activity including:<section prefix="(i)">Aquatic programs;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Horseback riding;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Firearms control;</section><section prefix="(iv)">Riflery;</section><section prefix="(v)">Archery;</section><section prefix="(vi)">Adventure camps;</section><section prefix="(vii)">Artistic gymnastics;</section><section prefix="(viii)">Hang gliding;</section><section prefix="(ix)">Road cycling;</section><section prefix="(x)">Skiing;</section><section prefix="(xi)">Rock climbing;</section><section prefix="(xii)">Spelunking;</section><section prefix="(xiii)">Motorized vehicle activities;</section><section prefix="(xiv)">Rappelling; or</section><section prefix="(xv)">High ropes.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(h)">"Occasional use" means periodic involvement in a program where there is no expectation of regular attendance.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">"Operate" means to supervise, control, conduct, or manage a youth camp as:<section prefix="(1)">An owner;</section><section prefix="(2)">An agent of the owner;</section><section prefix="(3)">A lessee of the owner;</section><section prefix="(4)">A director; or</section><section prefix="(5)">An independent contractor.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(j)">"Residential camp" means a youth camp operating at a facility or campsite at which a camper either lives apart or intends to live apart from the camper's relatives, parents, or legal guardians for at least 5 consecutive days.</section>
    <section prefix="(k)">"Routine activity" means any type of activity other than a specialized activity as set forth in subsection (g)(3) of this section that is conducted for children by a youth camp.</section>
    <section prefix="(l)">"Travel camp" means a residential camp that:<section prefix="(1)">Operates for at least 5 consecutive days; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Provides for campers to use motorized transportation to move as a group to or among sites for experiences in different environments.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(m)">"Trip camp" means a residential camp:<section prefix="(1)">That operates for at least 5 consecutive days; and</section><section prefix="(2)">In which a group of individuals move from 1 site to another under their own power or by transportation which permits individual guidance of a vehicle or animal.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(n)">"Unit" means a board, department, agency, or other component of a county or a municipal corporation.</section>
    <section prefix="(o)">"Youth camp" or "camp" means any day camp, residential camp, travel camp, or trip camp that:<section prefix="(1)">Accommodates 7 or more campers who are unrelated to the person operating the camp;</section><section prefix="(2)">Provides primarily recreational activities or has a substantial outdoor recreational component;</section><section prefix="(3)">Has permanent buildings, temporary buildings, or no buildings; and</section><section prefix="(4)">Operates on:<section prefix="(i)">Owned private property;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Owned private facilities;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Leased private property;</section><section prefix="(iv)">Leased private facilities;</section><section prefix="(v)">Public property; or</section><section prefix="(vi)">Public facilities.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(p)">"Youth overnight program" means an activity sponsored by a religious or a community organization at a facility or site at which an individual less than 18 years old either lives apart or intends to live apart from the individual's relatives, parent, or legal guardians for fewer than 5 consecutive days.</section>
  </text>
</law>
