<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="ghg" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="21-418" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghg-21-418</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Subject to the hearing provisions of &#xA7; 21-419 of this subtitle, the Secretary shall suspend a permit issued under this subtitle if:<section prefix="(1)">The holder of the permit has obtained the permit fraudulently or deceptively;</section><section prefix="(2)">The holder of the permit has violated this subtitle or a rule or regulation adopted under this subtitle;</section><section prefix="(3)">A violation of this subtitle or a rule or regulation adopted under this subtitle exists at the place for which the permit has been issued under this subtitle;</section><section prefix="(4)">A health hazard exists at the place for which the permit has been issued or exists as to the individual who holds the permit; or</section><section prefix="(5)">The holder of the permit has interfered with the Secretary in the performance of the Secretary's duties.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as otherwise provided in this section, before suspending a permit, the Secretary shall give to the holder of the permit notice of intent to suspend.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The notice shall:<section prefix="(i)">Specify with particularity the condition or violation that the Secretary believes to justify the suspension; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">State that the holder has an opportunity to correct the condition or violation before a time that is:</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Secretary is not required to give notice of intent to suspend a permit if:<section prefix="(1)">The violation creates an imminent hazard to public health; or</section><section prefix="(2)">The holder of the permit has willfully refused to permit an authorized inspection.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">If a permit has been suspended more than once, the Secretary may revoke the permit.</section>
  </text>
</law>
