<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghg" order_by="" level="1">Health - General</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghg-8-402</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>402</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Administration shall:<section prefix="(1)">Plan and encourage development of, and coordinate the facilities and services that offer treatment, care, or rehabilitation for alcohol and drug abusers; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Adopt regulations:<section prefix="(i)">To set standards for treatment, care, and rehabilitation of alcohol and drug abusers; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">To ensure that before a facility is certified under this title to provide treatment, care, or rehabilitation of alcohol or drug abusers, an opportunity to comment, concerning whether the facility meets certification requirements, is provided to representatives of the county government and, if in a municipal corporation, the municipal government and to private citizens in the community where the facility is proposed to be located.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Administration may establish and operate or identify facilities and services, including evaluation facilities to determine if an individual is a drug abuser or alcohol abuser or dependent on drugs or alcohol.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A facility that the Administration operates or contracts to be operated is a health facility and is not, for any purpose, a correctional institution.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">An individual may not be discriminated against based on an inability to pay for any services provided by the Administration either directly or by contract.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">To carry out the purposes of this title, the Administration may contract with any appropriate public or private agency that has proper and adequate treatment facilities, services, and staff.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Administration annually shall evaluate all publicly funded substance abuse treatment programs certified under this subtitle using federal outcomes measures or other subsequently adopted federal standards to determine the extent that individuals who have received treatment under these programs have:<section prefix="(i)">Been successfully retained in the treatment program;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Been successfully discharged from the treatment program;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Reduced substance use;</section><section prefix="(iv)">Successfully attained, maintained, or increased their employment;</section><section prefix="(v)">Demonstrated a decrease in engaging in criminal activity; and</section><section prefix="(vi)">Successfully established or maintained stable living arrangements.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Administration shall adopt regulations necessary to allow it to conduct the performance and outcome research required under paragraph (1) of this subsection.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
