<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghg" order_by="" level="1">Health - General</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghg-18-506</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>506</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, "Steering Committee" means the Statewide Steering Committee on Services for Adults with Sickle Cell Disease.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">There is a Statewide Steering Committee on Services for Adults with Sickle Cell Disease.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Steering Committee shall include representatives from:<section prefix="(1)">Local and national groups that advocate for individuals with sickle cell disease;</section><section prefix="(2)">Interest and support groups for individuals with sickle cell disease;</section><section prefix="(3)">The Genetic Alliance;</section><section prefix="(4)">Faith-based organizations;</section><section prefix="(5)">Community and consumer groups;</section><section prefix="(6)">Academic and private clinical settings with knowledge and experience caring for adults with sickle cell disease;</section><section prefix="(7)">Area hospitals caring for individuals with sickle cell disease; and</section><section prefix="(8)">Pediatric clinics that care for children with sickle cell disease.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Steering Committee shall:<section prefix="(1)">Establish institution and community partnerships;</section><section prefix="(2)">Establish a statewide network of stakeholders who care for individuals with sickle cell disease;</section><section prefix="(3)">Educate individuals with sickle cell disease, the public, and health care providers about the State options for care of sickle cell disease; and</section><section prefix="(4)">Seek grant funding to:<section prefix="(i)">Develop and establish a case management  system for adults with sickle cell disease;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Establish an adult sickle cell disease day  infusion center;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Develop, implement, and lead a State comprehensive education and treatment program for adults with sickle cell disease; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">Develop and implement a health care provider awareness and education campaign to increase provider awareness of health disparities, community dynamics, cultural practice, behavioral and psychosocial issues, and the use of standardized treatment and emergency room protocols.</section></section></section>
  </text>
</law>
