<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghg" order_by="ghg" level="1">Health - General</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghg-18-334</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this section the following words have the meanings indicated....</catch_line>
  <order_by>334</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"HIV" means the human immunodeficiency virus that causes acquired immune deficiency syndrome.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Institution" means:<section prefix="(i)">An ambulatory surgical facility or center, as defined in &#xA7; 19-114 of this article;</section><section prefix="(ii)">A health maintenance organization, as defined in &#xA7; 19-701 of this article;</section><section prefix="(iii)">A hospital or related institution, as defined in &#xA7; 19-301 of this article;</section><section prefix="(iv)">A tissue bank; or</section><section prefix="(v)">The office of 1 or more physicians.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">"Laboratory" means a public laboratory, medical laboratory, or medical test unit as those terms are defined in Title 17 of this article.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">"Physician" means a person licensed to practice under Title 14 of the Health Occupations Article.</section>
      <section prefix="(6)">
        <section prefix="(i)">"Tissue bank" means an establishment that obtains, stores, processes, distributes, or sells human blood or other human tissue for use in the human body.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">"Tissue bank" includes a blood bank or sperm bank.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Subject to the provisions of paragraph (2) of this subsection, an institution that obtains or processes semen, blood, or tissue shall obtain and send a blood sample from each potential donor of semen, blood, or tissue to a laboratory approved by the Department to test for HIV antibodies.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Before obtaining a blood sample from a potential semen, blood, or tissue donor the institution shall:<section prefix="(i)">Inform the potential donor, in layman's terms, that a blood sample of the donor will be tested for HIV antibodies and if the donor's blood sample tests positive for HIV antibodies the result will be reported to the Department; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Obtain written consent from the potential donor on a form provided by the Department for the administration of the HIV antibody tests and for the disclosure of a positive test result to the Department.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">An institution that obtains a positive HIV antibody test result under subsection (b) of this section shall:<section prefix="(1)">Notify the potential donor from whom the blood sample was obtained of the positive result;</section><section prefix="(2)">Inform the individual of available counseling; and</section><section prefix="(3)">Report the result to the Department on the form the Department provides.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A test result reported by an institution under subsection (c) of this section may not contain any information that identifies the subject of the test.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">An institution may not use a semen, blood, or tissue specimen from a donor with a positive HIV antibody test result obtained under the provisions of this section.</section>
  </text>
</law>
