<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="ghg" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="4-303" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghg-4-303</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">A health care provider shall disclose a medical record on the authorization of a person in interest in accordance with this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Except as otherwise provided in subsections (c) and (d) of this section, an authorization shall:<section prefix="(1)">Be in writing, dated, and signed by the person in interest;</section><section prefix="(2)">State the name of the health care provider;</section><section prefix="(3)">Identify to whom the information is to be disclosed;</section><section prefix="(4)">State the period of time that the authorization is valid, which may not exceed 1 year, except:<section prefix="(i)">In cases of criminal justice referrals, in which case the authorization shall be valid until 30 days following final disposition; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">In cases where the patient on whom the medical record is kept is a resident of a nursing home, in which case the authorization shall be valid until revoked, or for any time period specified in the authorization; and</section></section><section prefix="(5)">Apply only to a medical record developed by the health care provider unless in writing:<section prefix="(i)">The authorization specifies disclosure of a medical record that the health care provider has received from another provider; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">The other provider has not prohibited redisclosure.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A health care provider shall disclose a medical record on receipt of a preauthorized form that is part of an application for insurance.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A health care provider shall disclose a medical record on receipt of an authorization for the release of relevant medical information that is included with the claim application form filed with the Workers' Compensation Commission in accordance with &#xA7; 9-709(a), &#xA7; 9-710(b), or &#xA7; 9-711(a) of the Labor and Employment Article.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except in cases of criminal justice referrals, a person in interest may revoke an authorization in writing.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A revocation of an authorization becomes effective on the date of receipt by the health care provider.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A disclosure made before the effective date of a revocation is not affected by the revocation.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">A copy of the following shall be entered in the medical record of a patient or recipient:<section prefix="(1)">A written authorization;</section><section prefix="(2)">Any action taken in response to an authorization; and</section><section prefix="(3)">Any revocation of an authorization.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
