<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="ghg" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="19-713" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghg-19-713</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Each health maintenance organization shall file with the Commissioner and pay the applicable filing fee as provided in &#xA7; 2-112 of the Insurance Article, before they become effective:<section prefix="(i)">All rates that the health maintenance organization charges subscribers or groups of subscribers; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">The form and content of each contract between the health maintenance organization and its subscribers or groups of subscribers.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">A health maintenance organization that offers a health benefit plan, as defined in &#xA7; 11-601 of the Insurance Article, is subject to Title 11, Subtitle 6 of the Insurance Article for the health benefit plan.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">If the provisions of Title 11, Subtitle 6 of the Insurance Article conflict with the provisions of this section, the provisions of Title 11, Subtitle 6 of the Insurance Article shall prevail.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Rates of a health maintenance organization may not be excessive, inadequate, or unfairly discriminatory in relation to the services offered.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A health maintenance organization that includes a subrogation provision in its contract as authorized under &#xA7; 19-713.1(d) of this subtitle shall:<section prefix="(i)">Use in its rating methodology an adjustment that reflects the subrogation; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Identify in its rate filing with the Maryland Insurance Administration, and annually in a form approved by the Insurance Commissioner, all amounts recovered through subrogation.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If, at any time, a health maintenance organization wishes to amend any contract with its subscribers or change any rate charged, the health maintenance organization shall file with the Commissioner the number of copies of the amendment or rate change that the Commissioner requires.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Commissioner shall provide the Department with the number of copies it requires.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Commissioner shall coordinate the contract and related rate filing review under this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If within 60 days after a filing made pursuant to this section, the Commissioner finds the filing does not meet the requirements of subsection (f) of this section, the filer shall be sent notice of disapproval specifying in what respects the Commissioner finds that the filing fails to meet the requirements of this section and stating that the filing shall not become effective.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Commissioner may not issue a notice of disapproval of a filing under subsection (f) of this section without a statutory or regulatory basis for the disapproval and an explanation of the application of the statutory or regulatory basis which resulted in the disapproval.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The Commissioner shall disapprove any form filed, or withdraw any previous approval, if the form:<section prefix="(1)">Is in any respect in violation or does not comply with this article or applicable regulations;</section><section prefix="(2)">Contains, or incorporates by reference, any inconsistent or inapplicable clauses, exceptions, or conditions which affect the risk purported to be assumed in the general coverage of the contract;</section><section prefix="(3)">Has any title, heading, or other indication of its provisions which is likely to mislead the subscriber or member;</section><section prefix="(4)">Includes provisions that are inequitable, or provisions that lack any substantial benefit to the subscriber or member;</section><section prefix="(5)">Is printed or otherwise reproduced in a manner as to render any provision of the form substantially illegible; or</section><section prefix="(6)">Provides benefits that are unreasonable in relation to the premium charged.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, unless the Commissioner disapproves a filing under this section, the filing becomes effective 60 days after the office of the Commissioner receives the filing or on any other date that the Commissioner sets.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Commissioner may adopt regulations to allow a type or kind of form to be effective upon receipt of the filing by the Commissioner.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">If a health maintenance organization uses a form which becomes effective in accordance with the provisions of paragraph (2) of this subsection and the form would be subject to disapproval under subsection (f) of this section, the Commissioner may:<section prefix="(i)">Subsequently disapprove the form; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Find the health maintenance organization to be in violation of &#xA7; 19-729 of this subtitle and impose a penalty as provided in &#xA7; 19-730 of this subtitle.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">If a health maintenance organization files a form with the Commissioner which becomes effective in accordance with the provisions of paragraph (2) of this subsection, the health maintenance organization shall pay the applicable filing fee provided in &#xA7; 2-112 of the Insurance Article.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
