<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="ghg" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="21-217" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghg-21-217</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">For purposes of this subtitle, a drug or device is misbranded if the standards in this section or in &#xA7; 21-218 or &#xA7; 21-220(d) or (e) of this subtitle apply.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A drug or device is misbranded if:<section prefix="(1)">Its labeling is false or misleading in any way;</section><section prefix="(2)">Its labeling or packaging does not conform with any provision of &#xA7; 21-248 of this subtitle;</section><section prefix="(3)">It is in package form and it does not bear a label that contains the name and place of business of the manufacturer, packer, or distributor;</section><section prefix="(4)">Any word, statement, or other information required under this subtitle to appear on its labeling is not placed prominently on the labeling in a manner that is:<section prefix="(i)">Conspicuous as compared with other words, statements, designs, or symbols on the labeling; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">In terms likely to be read and understood by the ordinary individual under customary conditions of purchase and use;</section></section><section prefix="(5)">Its labeling does not include, in whatever manner and form that may be necessary to protect the user of the drug or device:<section prefix="(i)">Adequate directions for the use of the drug or device; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Adequate warnings against:</section></section><section prefix="(6)">It is dangerous to health when used in the dosage, with the frequency, or for the duration specified, recommended, or suggested in the labeling of the drug or device; or</section><section prefix="(7)">The trademark, trade name, imprint, symbol, or other identifying mark of another drug or any likeness of any of these markings of another drug or device is placed on the drug or device or its container with the intent to defraud.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Subsection (b)(5)(i) of this section, which concerns the provision of directions for the use of a drug or device, does not apply to a drug or device that is exempted by:<section prefix="(i)">A rule or regulation adopted under the federal act; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">A rule or regulation adopted by the Secretary under this subsection.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If the Secretary finds that, as applied to a particular drug or device, any requirement of subsection (b)(5)(i) of this section is not necessary for the protection of the public health, the Secretary shall adopt a rule or regulation to exempt the drug or device from that requirement.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
