<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="ghg" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="17-2A-10" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghg-17-2A-10</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, "discriminate or retaliate" includes:<section prefix="(1)">Failing to promote an individual or to provide another employment-related benefit for which the individual would otherwise be eligible;</section><section prefix="(2)">Making an adverse evaluation or decision in relation to accreditation, certification, credentialing, or licensing of the individual; or</section><section prefix="(3)">Taking a personnel action that is adverse to the individual concerned.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">An employee who works in a forensic laboratory may  disclose information to the Secretary that the employee believes  evidences a violation of standards and requirements for forensic  laboratories in the State.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A forensic laboratory may not discriminate or retaliate  against an employee because the employee:<section prefix="(1)">Discloses information under subsection (b) of this  section; or</section><section prefix="(2)">Has agreed to cooperate with an investigation of  the forensic laboratory.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Secretary shall develop, through regulation, a  document that informs the employees of a forensic laboratory of  the procedures to report instances of noncompliance or other  violations of the standards and requirements for forensic  laboratories in the State.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Secretary shall distribute the document  developed under paragraph (1) of this subsection to forensic  laboratories in the State.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">A forensic laboratory shall post the document  developed under subsection (d) of this section in a conspicuous  place.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">An employee of a forensic laboratory who has been discriminated or retaliated against in violation of subsection (c) of this section may initiate an action and, on prevailing, shall be entitled to:<section prefix="(1)">Reinstatement;</section><section prefix="(2)">Reimbursement for lost wages;</section><section prefix="(3)">Work benefits lost as a result of the unlawful acts of the employing laboratory; and</section><section prefix="(4)">Reasonable attorney's fees and costs associated with pursuing the action.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(g)">No action may be brought under this  subsection more than 2 years after the discrimination or retaliation that is the basis for the action.</section>
  </text>
</law>
