<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghg" order_by="" level="1">Health - General</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghg-13-1114</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>1114</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">There is a Statewide Academic Health Center Component in the Program.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The purpose of the Statewide Academic Health Center Component is to maximize the effectiveness of the Program by involving the University of Maryland Medical Group and the Johns Hopkins Institutions in the implementation of the Program.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Subject to &#xA7;&#xA7; 13-1115 and 13-1116 of this subtitle, the Department may implement the Statewide Academic Health Center Component by distributing:<section prefix="(1)">Statewide Academic Health Center Public Health Grants, as provided under &#xA7; 13-1115 of this subtitle; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Statewide Academic Health Center Cancer Research Grants, as provided under &#xA7; 13-1116 of this subtitle.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Subject to paragraph (2) of this subsection, the University of Maryland Medical Group and the Johns Hopkins Institutions, at the request of a Community Health Coalition in Montgomery County or Prince George's County, as provided under &#xA7; 13-1109(e) of this subtitle, shall collaborate with the Community Health Coalition for the purpose of developing and implementing a specific plan as to how the expertise of the institution will be used to assist the Community Health Coalition in achieving the goals established for the county under &#xA7; 13-1108 of this subtitle as they relate to enhancing the capacity for cancer screening and treatment at one or more major community hospitals in the county.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Paragraph (1) of this subsection does not apply with respect to the implementation of a plan unless funds are specifically allocated in the State budget for this purpose.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The University of Maryland Medical Group and the Johns Hopkins Institutions shall coordinate their efforts with regard to initiatives that are funded with grants that are distributed under the Statewide Academic Health Center Component to maximize the benefits received from the use of these grant funds and to eliminate unnecessary duplication of efforts.</section>
  </text>
</law>
