<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="ghg" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="18-338.3" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghg-18-338.3</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">"Body fluids" means:</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">"Body fluids" does not include saliva, stool, nasal secretions, sputum, tears, urine, or vomitus.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Exposure" means:<section prefix="(i)">Percutaneous contact with blood or body fluids;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Mucocutaneous contact with blood or body fluids;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Open wound, including dermatitis, exudative lesions, or chapped skin, contact with blood or body fluids for a prolonged period; or</section><section prefix="(iv)">Intact skin contact with large amounts of blood or body fluids for a prolonged period.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">"First responder" means an individual who:<section prefix="(i)">Is licensed or certified under &#xA7; 13-516 of the Education Article; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Provides services to an individual before the individual is admitted to a hospital.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(5)">
        <section prefix="(i)">"Health care provider" means an individual who is licensed, certified, or otherwise authorized under the Health Occupations Article or this article to provide health or medical care in:</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">"Health care provider" includes any agent or employee of a hospital.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">"Health care provider" does not include an individual who is eligible to receive notification under the provisions of &#xA7; 18-213 of this title, including any law enforcement officer or any member of any fire department, ambulance company, or rescue squad.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(6)">"HIV" means the human immunodeficiency virus that causes acquired immune deficiency syndrome.</section>
      <section prefix="(7)">"Hospital" has the meaning stated in &#xA7; 19-301 of this article.</section>
      <section prefix="(8)">"Public safety worker" means:<section prefix="(i)">A career or volunteer member of a fire, rescue, or emergency medical services department, company, squad, or auxiliary;</section><section prefix="(ii)">A law enforcement officer;</section><section prefix="(iii)">The State Fire Marshal or a sworn member of the State Fire Marshal's office; or</section><section prefix="(iv)">A forensic scientist who works under the direction of a law enforcement agency.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Notwithstanding the provisions of &#xA7; 18-338.1 of this subtitle, the designated infectious disease/communicable disease officer of a hospital shall order a test for the presence of antibodies to the human immunodeficiency virus (HIV) under subsection (d) of this section when:<section prefix="(1)">There has been an exposure in a hospital between a patient and a health care provider, an exposure between a patient and a first responder, or an exposure between a patient and a public safety worker before admission of the patient to a hospital, that, in accordance with the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention recommendations, would warrant recommending or offering chemoprophylaxis treatment for the health care provider, first responder, or public safety worker;</section><section prefix="(2)"><section prefix="(i)">Informed consent, or substitute consent as required under &#xA7; 18-338.1(c) of this subtitle, of the patient to test a blood sample of the patient for the presence of HIV was sought and the patient was unavailable or unable to consent; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">Informed consent, or substitute consent as required under &#xA7; 18-338.1(c) of this subtitle, of the patient to test a blood sample already obtained from the patient for the presence of HIV was sought, the patient refused, and the patient was informed of the provisions of this subsection;</section></section><section prefix="(3)"><section prefix="(i)">In accordance with hospital procedures, the health care provider involved in the exposure has given prompt notice of the exposure to the designated hospital infectious disease/communicable disease officer where the exposure occurred; or</section><section prefix="(ii)"/></section><section prefix="(4)">The health care provider, first responder, or public safety worker involved in the exposure has given informed consent and has submitted a blood sample to be tested for the presence of HIV; and</section><section prefix="(5)">The designated hospital infectious disease/communicable disease officer has made a determination, in accordance with the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention recommendations, that the testing of blood samples or other body fluids of the patient for the presence of antibodies to the human immunodeficiency virus (HIV) would be helpful in managing the risk of disease and health outcome of the health care provider, first responder, or public safety worker.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">If there has been an exposure between a first responder and an individual or a public safety worker and an individual before the admission of the individual to a hospital:<section prefix="(1)">The first responder or public safety worker shall give notice to the first responder's or public safety worker's medical director in accordance with subsection (b)(3)(ii)1 of this section;</section><section prefix="(2)">The medical director shall act as an intermediary at all times between the first responder or public safety worker and the designated hospital infectious disease/communicable disease officer; and</section><section prefix="(3)">The medical director and the designated hospital infectious disease/communicable disease officer shall ensure that all communications and information related to the exposure of the first responder or public safety worker are confidential.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">If the requirements of subsections (b) and (c) of this section are satisfied, the designated hospital infectious disease/communicable disease officer shall order tests to be conducted for the presence of antibodies to the human immunodeficiency virus (HIV) using a test procedure approved by the Department on:<section prefix="(1)">Blood samples already obtained from the patient; or</section><section prefix="(2)">Blood samples or other body fluids collected for the purpose of HIV testing under this section.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">When the designated hospital infectious disease/communicable disease officer obtains the results of an HIV test conducted in accordance with the provisions of subsection (d) of this section, the designated hospital infectious disease/communicable disease officer shall attempt to directly notify the patient of the results of the HIV test and, to the extent possible, in a manner that will protect the confidentiality of the health care provider, the first responder, or the public safety worker and the patient.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">If the results of an HIV test conducted in accordance with the provisions of subsection (d) of this section are positive, the designated hospital infectious disease/communicable disease officer shall provide or arrange for the provision of appropriate counseling and treatment recommendations to the health care provider, first responder, or public safety worker and the patient.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Notwithstanding the provisions of Title 4, Subtitle 3 of this article, the medical records, including any physician order for an HIV test or the results of an HIV test conducted under this section, may not be documented in the medical record of the patient, health care provider, first responder, or public safety worker.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The hospital where the exposure occurred shall maintain a separate confidential record or incident report for all HIV tests conducted under this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Each hospital shall adopt procedures for the confidential HIV testing of blood samples or other body fluids used or collected for purposes of this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">Except as provided in paragraph (5) of this subsection, the medical records, including any physician order for an HIV test or the results of any HIV test conducted under this section, are:<section prefix="(i)">Confidential; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Not discoverable or admissible in evidence in any criminal, civil, or administrative action.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(5)">If the identity of the patient or any other information that could be readily associated with the identity of the patient is not disclosed, the results of an HIV test conducted on a patient for purposes of this section may be introduced into evidence in any criminal, civil, or administrative action including the adjudication of a workers' compensation claim.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(h)">The costs incurred in performing an HIV test on a patient in accordance with the provisions of this section shall be paid by the hospital.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">Each hospital shall develop written procedures to implement the provisions of this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(j)">A health care provider, first responder, public safety worker, or hospital or designee of a hospital acting in good faith to provide notification or maintain the confidentiality of the results of a test conducted under this section may not be held liable in any cause of action related to a breach of patient, health care provider, first responder, or public safety worker confidentiality.</section>
  </text>
</law>
