<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghg" order_by="ghg" level="1">Health - General</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghg-5-701</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated....</catch_line>
  <order_by>701</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Child" means an individual under the age of 18 years.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Child death review case reporting system" means a national, standardized, web-based reporting system for the confidential collection, analysis, aggregation, and reporting of child death data that is maintained and operated by a national center for child death review.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">"Data use agreement" means a contract between the Department and a national center for child death review that establishes the terms and conditions for the State and local child fatality review teams' participation in a child death review case reporting system.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"Health care provider" means:<section prefix="(1)">An individual licensed or certified under the Health Occupations Article to provide health care; or</section><section prefix="(2)">A facility that provides health care to individuals.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">"Local team" means the multidisciplinary and multiagency child fatality review team established for a county.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">"Meeting" includes meetings through telephone conferencing.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">"National center for child death review" means a public, private, nonprofit, or governmental organization or entity that is funded or otherwise recognized by the United States Department of Health and Human Services and is responsible for:<section prefix="(1)">Developing a child death review case reporting system;</section><section prefix="(2)">Training and serving as a liaison to State agencies participating in the system; and</section><section prefix="(3)">Disseminating national child death review data generated by the system.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(i)">"State Team" means the State Child Fatality Review Team.</section>
    <section prefix="(j)">"Unexpected child death" means a death of a child investigated by the office of the Chief Medical Examiner as required by &#xA7; 5-309 of this title.</section>
  </text>
</law>
