<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghg" order_by="ghg" level="1">Health - General</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghg-8-6C-04</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this section, "county" includes Baltimore City....</catch_line>
  <order_by>04</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, "county" includes Baltimore City.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A request for Partnership funding may be submitted to the Department by:<section prefix="(1)">The governing body of a county; or</section><section prefix="(2)">The governing body of more than one county.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A request for Partnership funding shall be made in accordance with a schedule and format determined by the Department, in consultation with the Task Force to Study Increasing the Availability of Substance Abuse Programs.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">In a request for Partnership funding, the applicant or applicants shall include:<section prefix="(1)">A description of the proposal;</section><section prefix="(2)">An indication of the eligible targeted population or populations that the proposal will serve;</section><section prefix="(3)">A description of the services to be provided under the proposed new or expanded program and an identification of the local providers able to provide those services;</section><section prefix="(4)">A plan to reach the targeted populations using relevant means of contact;</section><section prefix="(5)">Performance and outcome indicators to evaluate the program effectiveness, including a description of the expected schedule and methods for measuring performance and outcome; and</section><section prefix="(6)">A statement of the funds that the applicant intends to commit.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">In evaluating a request for Partnership funding, the Department, in consultation with the Task Force to Study Increasing the Availability of Substance Abuse Programs, shall consider:<section prefix="(1)">The performance and outcome indicators specified;</section><section prefix="(2)">The degree to which the proposal may reduce the need for other State or local public services or programs intended for the populations targeted by the proposal;</section><section prefix="(3)">The extent to which the proposal incorporates the use of excess or otherwise available medical-related facilities, including vacant hospital beds;</section><section prefix="(4)">How the proposal fits into a balanced approach to the State's variety of substance abuse needs and populations that serves different geographic areas of the State with Partnership funding; and</section><section prefix="(5)">The extent to which the proposal is part of or consistent with a regional strategy for substance abuse treatment programs affecting adjoining jurisdictions.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">After consulting with the Task Force to Study Increasing the Availability of Substance Abuse Programs, the Department shall award Partnership funding following the considerations in this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Except as provided in subparagraph (ii) of this paragraph, a county granted funding shall be responsible for one-half of the cost of the approved partnership.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The Department may award Partnership funding that results in a county being responsible for less than one-half of the cost of the approved partnership after considering:<section prefix="1.">The financial hardship of the participating county;</section><section prefix="2.">Prior contributions of funds for substance abuse treatment programs made by the participating county; or</section><section prefix="3.">Other relevant considerations deemed appropriate by the Department.</section></section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A participating county:<section prefix="(i)">May use Partnership funds only to supplement levels of spending by the participating county on drug treatment programs; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">May not use Partnership funds to supplant spending by the participating county on drug treatment programs.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
