<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="ghg" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="20-105" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghg-20-105</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Informal kinship care" means a living arrangement in which a relative of a child, who is not in the care, custody, or guardianship of the local department of social services, provides for the care and custody of the child due to a serious family hardship.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Relative" means an adult related to the child by blood or marriage within the fifth degree of consanguinity.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">"Serious family hardship" means:<section prefix="(i)">Death of a parent or legal guardian of the child;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Serious illness of a parent or legal guardian of the child;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Drug addiction of a parent or legal guardian of the child;</section><section prefix="(iv)">Incarceration of a parent or legal guardian of the child;</section><section prefix="(v)">Abandonment by a parent or legal guardian of the child; or</section><section prefix="(vi)">Assignment of a parent or legal guardian to active military duty.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A relative providing informal kinship care for a child may consent to health care on behalf of the child if:<section prefix="(1)">A court has not appointed a guardian for the child or awarded custody of the child to an individual other than the relative providing informal kinship care; and</section><section prefix="(2)">The relative verifies the informal kinship care relationship through a sworn affidavit that:<section prefix="(i)">Meets the requirements of this section; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Is filed with the Department of Human Resources, Social Services Administration.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The affidavit shall include:<section prefix="(1)">The name and date of birth of the child;</section><section prefix="(2)">The name and address of the child's parent or legal guardian;</section><section prefix="(3)">The name and address of the relative providing informal kinship care;</section><section prefix="(4)">The date the relative assumed informal kinship care;</section><section prefix="(5)">The nature of the serious family hardship and why it resulted in informal kinship care; and</section><section prefix="(6)">The kinship relation to the child of the relative providing informal kinship care.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The affidavit shall be in the following form:<section prefix="(1)">I, the undersigned, am over eighteen (18) years of age and competent to testify to the facts and matters set forth herein.</section><section prefix="(2)">_______________ (name of child), whose date of birth is _____________, is living with me because of the following serious family hardship (check each that is applicable):</section><section prefix="(3)">The name and last known address of the child's parent(s) or legal guardian is:</section><section prefix="(4)">My kinship relation to the child is </section><section prefix="(5)">My address is:</section><section prefix="(6)">I assumed informal kinship care of this child for 24 hours a day and 7 days a week on __________________ (day/month/year).</section><section prefix="(7)">The name and address of the school that the child attends is:</section><section prefix="(8)">I solemnly affirm under the penalties of perjury that the contents of the foregoing are true to the best of my knowledge, information, and belief.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">Affidavit forms that comply with subsection (d) of this section shall be made available free of charge at the offices of each county board of education and each local health department.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">If a change occurs in the care or in the serious family hardship of the child, the relative providing informal kinship care shall notify the Department of Human Resources, Social Services Administration in writing within 30 days after the change occurs.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">The relative providing informal kinship care shall file an affidavit annually with the Department of Human Resources, Social Services Administration for each year the child continues to live with the relative because of a serious family hardship.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">A copy of the affidavit shall be given to the health care provider that treats the child.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">The relative providing informal kinship care may apply on behalf of the child for all medical and public assistance entitlements for which the child may be eligible.</section>
    <section prefix="(j)">An affidavit under this section does not abrogate the right of the parent or guardian of a child to consent to health care on behalf of the child in a future health care decision.</section>
  </text>
</law>
