<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="ghg" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="19-3B-03" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghg-19-3B-03</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">After consultation with representatives of payors, health care practitioners, and ambulatory care facilities, the Secretary shall by regulation establish:<section prefix="(i)">Procedures to implement the provisions of this subtitle; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Standards to ensure quality of care and patient safety that shall include:</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The procedures for practitioner performance evaluation required under paragraph (1)(ii)1 of this subsection shall include a review of care provided to patients at the freestanding ambulatory care facility by members of the medical staff.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The review of care shall:<section prefix="(i)">Be undertaken for cases chosen at random and for cases with unexpected adverse outcomes;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Be based on objective review standards;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Include a review of the appropriateness of the plan of care for the patient, particularly any medical procedures performed on the patient, in relation to the patient's condition; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">Except as provided in paragraph (4) of this subsection, be conducted by at least two members of the medical staff who:</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">A review of the care provided by a member of the medical staff who is a solo practitioner shall be conducted by an external reviewer.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">A freestanding ambulatory care facility shall take into account the results of the practitioner performance evaluation process for a member of the medical staff in the reappointment process.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">If appropriate certification by Medicare is available, obtaining the certification shall be a condition of licensure for:<section prefix="(1)">An ambulatory surgical facility; and</section><section prefix="(2)">A kidney dialysis center.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Each freestanding ambulatory care facility shall provide assurances satisfactory to the Secretary that the freestanding ambulatory care facility does not discriminate against patients, including discrimination based on ability to pay for nonelective procedures.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Secretary may delegate to the Kidney Disease Commission the Secretary's authority under &#xA7; 19-3B-07 of this subtitle to inspect kidney dialysis centers.</section>
  </text>
</law>
