<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="ghg" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="20-116" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghg-20-116</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Biennial" means once every other year.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Clinical breast examination" means a breast examination performed by a health care professional for the purpose of detecting breast cancer.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">"Eligible individual" means an individual who is eligible to receive benefits under the Program in accordance with subsection (e) of this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">"Mammogram" means an X-ray examination of the breast using dedicated equipment, including X-ray tube, filter, compression device, screens, films, and cassettes, specifically for mammography that delivers an average radiation exposure of less than one rad mid-breast with two views for each breast.</section>
      <section prefix="(6)">"Mastectomy" means the surgical removal of all or part of a breast as a result of breast cancer.</section>
      <section prefix="(7)">"Program" means the Breast Cancer Program.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Department shall establish a Breast Cancer Program.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The purpose of the Program is to:<section prefix="(i)">Provide at least biennial screening mammograms and clinical breast examinations to low-income, underinsured and low-income, uninsured women aged 40 years to 49 years;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Provide annual screening mammograms and clinical breast examinations to low-income, underinsured and low-income, uninsured women aged 50 years and older; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Provide diagnosis and treatment for individuals who are identified by this Program as being in need.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Treatment provided to a Program participant who has undergone a mastectomy shall include:<section prefix="(1)">Reconstruction of the breast on which the mastectomy has been performed;</section><section prefix="(2)">Surgery and reconstruction of the other breast to produce a symmetrical appearance;</section><section prefix="(3)">Prostheses; and</section><section prefix="(4)">Any physical complications related to the mastectomy.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Department shall administer the Program through the local health departments using a grant program under which a local health department makes arrangements with health care facilities to provide screening mammograms and clinical breast examinations to eligible individuals.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">An individual is eligible for the Program if the individual:<section prefix="(1)">Has a family income that does not exceed 250% of the federal poverty level; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Does not have access to health insurance coverage that covers screening mammograms and clinical breast examinations for women aged 40 years and older.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">For each fiscal year, the Governor shall include an appropriation of general funds to the Program in an amount not less than the amount appropriated for breast cancer screening, diagnosis, and treatment in the State budget for fiscal year 1999, subject to the availability of State funds.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">The Department shall:<section prefix="(1)">Adopt regulations necessary to implement the Program; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Work with all interested parties to assure that breast cancer screening services are available to women at least 40 years old.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
