<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="ghg" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="13-1303" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghg-13-1303</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The University of Maryland School of Nursing and the Advisory Board shall ensure that the following geographic areas are served by the Program:<section prefix="(1)">Western Maryland;</section><section prefix="(2)">The Washington metropolitan area;</section><section prefix="(3)">The Baltimore metropolitan area;</section><section prefix="(4)">Southern/Central Maryland;</section><section prefix="(5)">The upper Eastern Shore; and</section><section prefix="(6)">The lower Eastern Shore.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The University of Maryland School of Nursing and the Advisory Board shall:<section prefix="(1)">Develop partnerships with local health departments, hospitals, schools, community associations, businesses, and other entities that can facilitate the provision of primary and preventive health care services through the Program;</section><section prefix="(2)">Solicit public and private grants and donations on behalf of the Program; and</section><section prefix="(3)">Develop a mechanism for receiving third party reimbursement.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The University of Maryland, Baltimore may establish a nonprofit corporation to accept any public and private grants or donations made to the Program.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">On or before September 1 of each year, the University of Maryland School of Nursing and the Advisory Board shall submit a report to the Governor and, in accordance with &#xA7; 2-1246 of the State Government Article, the General Assembly detailing the operation and management of the Program, including:<section prefix="(i)">The number of individuals served by the Program;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The type and number of health care services provided to individuals served by the Program;</section><section prefix="(iii)">The establishment and continuation of any public or private partnerships;</section><section prefix="(iv)">The funding received from public and private sources;</section><section prefix="(v)">Funds received through third party reimbursement;</section><section prefix="(vi)">The condition and maintenance expenses of vehicles used by the Program to deliver health care services;</section><section prefix="(vii)">The areas served by the Program;</section><section prefix="(viii)">The impact of the Program in the communities served; and</section><section prefix="(ix)">Any recommendations for enhancing or furthering the purposes of the Program.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Office of Legislative Audits shall audit the accounts and transactions of the Governor's Wellmobile Program in accordance with &#xA7;&#xA7; 2-1220 through 2-1227 of the State Government Article.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
