<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghg" order_by="ghg" level="1">Health - General</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghg-19-2302</section_number>
  <catch_line>An accreditation organization shall apply to the Secretary for approval....</catch_line>
  <order_by>2302</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">An accreditation organization shall apply to the Secretary for approval.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Prior to approval of an accreditation organization, the Secretary shall:<section prefix="(1)">Determine that the standards of the accreditation organization are equal to or more stringent than existing State requirements;</section><section prefix="(2)">Evaluate the survey or inspection process of the accreditation organization to ensure the integrity of the survey or inspection process; and</section><section prefix="(3)">Enter into a formal written agreement with the accreditation organization that includes requirements for:<section prefix="(i)">Notice of all surveys and inspections;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Sharing of complaints and other relevant information;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Participation of the Department in accreditation organization activities; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">Any other provision necessary to ensure the integrity of the accreditation and licensure process.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">When an approved accreditation organization has issued a final report finding a health care facility to be in substantial compliance with the accreditation organization's standards, the Department shall accept the report as evidence that the health care facility has met State licensure requirements and shall grant the health care facility deemed status.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A health care facility that fails to achieve substantial compliance with the standards of an approved accreditation organization may be subject to the provisions of &#xA7; 19-360 of this title.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">An approved accreditation organization shall send the Department any preliminary and final report of each inspection and survey at the time it is sent to the health care facility.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A final report of an approved accreditation organization shall be made immediately available to the public on request.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A preliminary or final report of an approved accreditation organization is not admissible in evidence in any civil action or proceeding.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The Department may inspect an accredited health care facility to:<section prefix="(1)">Determine compliance with any quality requirement;</section><section prefix="(2)">Follow up on any serious problem identified by an approved accreditation organization;</section><section prefix="(3)">Investigate a complaint; or</section><section prefix="(4)">Validate the findings of an approved accreditation organization.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The Department may participate in or observe a survey or inspection of a health care facility conducted by an approved accreditation organization.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">On a determination by the Secretary that an approved accreditation organization has failed to meet its obligations under this section, the Secretary may withdraw:<section prefix="(1)">The approval from the accreditation organization; and</section><section prefix="(2)">The deemed status given to a health care facility by the accreditation organization.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
