<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghg" order_by="ghg" level="1">Health - General</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghg-19-1409</section_number>
  <catch_line>There is an Oversight Committee on Quality of Care in Nursing Homes and Assisted Living Facilities....</catch_line>
  <order_by>1409</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">There is an Oversight Committee on Quality of Care in Nursing Homes and Assisted Living Facilities.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Oversight Committee shall consist of the following members:<section prefix="(1)">One member of the Senate Finance Committee, appointed by the President of the Senate;</section><section prefix="(2)">One member of the Senate Education, Health, and Environmental Affairs Committee, appointed by the President of the Senate;</section><section prefix="(3)">Two members of the House Health and Government Operations Committee, appointed by the Speaker of the House;</section><section prefix="(4)">The Secretary of the Department of Aging;</section><section prefix="(5)">The Secretary of the Department of Health and Mental Hygiene, or the Secretary's designee;</section><section prefix="(6)">One representative from the Department of Health and Mental Hygiene's Mental Hygiene Administration;</section><section prefix="(7)">The Secretary of the Department of Human Resources, or the Secretary's designee;</section><section prefix="(8)">Three representatives of area agencies on aging, one of which shall be a member of a local long-term care ombudsman program established under Title 10, Subtitle 9 of the Human Services Article, appointed by the Secretary of Aging;</section><section prefix="(9)">One representative from the Health Facilities Association of Maryland;</section><section prefix="(10)">One representative from the Mid-Atlantic LifeSpan;</section><section prefix="(11)">One representative of the Hospice Network of Maryland;</section><section prefix="(12)">One representative of the Maryland Hospital Association;</section><section prefix="(13)">One representative of the Service Employees International Union;</section><section prefix="(14)">One representative of the Maryland Chapter of AARP;</section><section prefix="(15)">One representative of United Seniors of Maryland;</section><section prefix="(16)">One representative of Voices for Quality Care;</section><section prefix="(17)">One representative of the Mental Health Association knowledgeable in elderly issues;</section><section prefix="(18)">One representative of the Greater Maryland Chapter of the Alzheimer's Association;</section><section prefix="(19)">Three representatives from the assisted living industry, of which one shall represent a program that cares for one to four residents, one shall represent a program that cares for five to nine residents, and one shall represent a program that cares for more than 10 residents; and</section><section prefix="(20)">Three consumer members appointed by the Governor, one of whom shall be a consumer living in an assisted living facility.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Secretary of Aging shall chair the Oversight Committee.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Oversight Committee shall evaluate the progress in improving nursing home care quality and assisted living facility quality statewide, including consideration of:<section prefix="(1)">Quality of care standards for nursing homes and assisted living facilities;</section><section prefix="(2)">Standards for the identification of the onset of dementia and Alzheimer's disease;</section><section prefix="(3)">Standards for the identification of conditions appropriate for hospice services;</section><section prefix="(4)">Staffing patterns and staffing standards;</section><section prefix="(5)">Policies and procedures for inspecting nursing homes and assisted living facilities, and responding to quality of care complaints;</section><section prefix="(6)">A comparison of Maryland standards, policies, and procedures to those in other states;</section><section prefix="(7)">The labor pool available to fill nursing and nursing aide jobs;</section><section prefix="(8)">State funding mechanisms for nursing homes and assisted living facilities, including the Medicaid Nursing Home Reimbursement System, and regulation of nursing homes; and</section><section prefix="(9)">The provision and quality of mental and behavioral health care services to meet the needs of nursing home and assisted living facility residents.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The Office of Health Care Quality in the Department of Health and Mental Hygiene shall submit a report to the Oversight Committee annually on the status of quality of care in nursing homes and assisted living facilities.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The Deputy Secretary of Health Care Financing, or the Deputy Secretary's designee, shall report annually to the Oversight Committee on the status of the Medicaid Nursing Home Reimbursement System, which shall include but not be limited to:<section prefix="(1)">Elements of the existing methodology that are no longer relevant;</section><section prefix="(2)">Elements of the existing methodology that can be revised;</section><section prefix="(3)">The appropriateness of redesigning the system given changing demographics of the target population; and</section><section prefix="(4)">General Fund and federal fund savings from a system redesign that may be redirected to nursing home staff development in the nursing cost center.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(g)">The Oversight Committee shall review the reports of the Office of Health Care Quality and the Deputy Secretary of Health Care Financing and develop recommendations to continue improvement in nursing home and assisted living facility care.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">The Oversight Committee shall report its findings and recommendations to the Governor and, subject to &#xA7; 2-1246 of the State Government Article, to the General Assembly on or before December 1 of each year.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">The Department of Aging, with assistance from the Department of Health and Mental Hygiene, the Department of Human Resources, and the Department of Legislative Services, shall provide staff support for the Oversight Committee.</section>
  </text>
</law>
