<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghg" order_by="" level="1">Health - General</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghg-21-1113</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>1113</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following terms have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Authorized prescriber" means a licensed dentist, licensed physician, licensed podiatrist, licensed veterinarian, certified nurse midwife to the extent permitted under &#xA7; 8-601 of the Health Occupations Article, certified nurse practitioner to the extent permitted under &#xA7; 8-508 of the Health Occupations Article, or other individual authorized by law to prescribe prescription or nonprescription drugs or devices.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Board" means a health occupation licensing board authorized to issue a permit, license, or certificate under the Health Occupations Article.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">
        <section prefix="(i)">"Controlled dangerous substance" means a drug, substance, or immediate precursor listed in Schedule I through Schedule V in Title 5 of the Criminal Law Article.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">"Controlled dangerous substance" does not include tobacco or a distilled spirit, wine, or malt beverage.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(5)">"Drug" means a prescription or nonprescription drug.</section>
      <section prefix="(6)">"Nonprescription drug" means a drug which may be sold without a prescription and which is labeled for consumer use in accordance with the requirements of the laws and regulations of this State and the federal government.</section>
      <section prefix="(7)">"Permit holder" means a holder of, or applicant for:<section prefix="(i)">A pharmacy permit, manufacturer's permit, or distributor's permit issued by the State Board of Pharmacy under Title 12 of the Health Occupations Article; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">A dispensing permit issued by a board under the authority of &#xA7; 12-102(c)(2) of the Health Occupations Article.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(8)">"Prescription drug" means a drug that under &#xA7; 21-220 of this title may be dispensed only on the prescription of a health practitioner who is authorized by law to prescribe the drug.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Department may issue an order of impoundment and immediately impound drugs or prescription records of a permit holder or an authorized prescriber if:<section prefix="(i)">A permit holder's permit or authorized prescriber's license has expired or has been revoked or suspended;</section><section prefix="(ii)">An application for a permit or license has been denied;</section><section prefix="(iii)">A board has:<section prefix="1.">Determined that the permit holder or authorized prescriber failed to comply with a board order, letter of surrender, or law regarding the disposition of drugs or prescription records; and</section><section prefix="2.">Requested that the Department impound the drugs or prescription records;</section></section><section prefix="(iv)">The drugs pose an imminent threat to the public health, safety, or welfare; or</section><section prefix="(v)">The confidentiality of the prescription records is in imminent danger of being compromised.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Department may not impound the drugs or prescription records of a permit holder or authorized prescriber who is in compliance with a board order or law specifically providing for the manner of the disposition of drugs or prescription records.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as otherwise provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, the Department shall:<section prefix="(i)">Attempt to serve written notice of an impoundment on the permit holder or authorized prescriber;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Provide the permit holder or authorized prescriber with an opportunity to avoid impoundment by allowing the permit holder or authorized prescriber to dispose of the drugs or prescription records in a manner acceptable to the Department;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Provide the permit holder or authorized prescriber with an opportunity prior to impoundment to review the nature, type, and amount of information upon which the Department issued the impoundment order; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">Provide the permit holder or authorized prescriber with an opportunity to avoid impoundment by providing the Department with information upon which the Department could reasonably conclude that the impoundment is not warranted.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If drugs pose an imminent threat to the public health, safety, or welfare, or if the confidentiality of prescription records is in imminent danger of being compromised, the Department may:<section prefix="(i)">Issue an impoundment order; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Immediately impound drugs or prescription records without prior notice to the permit holder or authorized prescriber.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">An order of impoundment constitutes a final order subject to judicial review under the State Administrative Procedure Act.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The Department shall provide the permit holder or authorized prescriber with a list of all drugs and prescription records impounded.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The Department may charge reasonable fees to recover the costs of the collection, storage, and disposition of drugs or prescription records.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">The Department shall adopt regulations governing the disposition of impounded drugs and prescription records.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">Prior to issuing an order of impoundment, the Department, with the approval of the Board of Pharmacy, shall develop regulations concerning:<section prefix="(1)">The nature, type, and amount of information upon which the Department may rely to issue an order of impoundment;</section><section prefix="(2)">The level of investigation the Department must pursue to verify the information upon which the order of impoundment was based under subsection (b)(1)(iv) or (v) or (c)(2) of this section; and</section><section prefix="(3)">The measures the Department must pursue to attempt service on the permit holder or authorized prescriber prior to impoundment under subsection (c) of this section.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(i)">Prior to destroying or transferring impounded drugs or prescription records, the Department shall publish a notice for 2 consecutive weeks in a daily newspaper that is circulated locally:<section prefix="(1)">Stating the date that the drugs or prescription records will be destroyed or transferred; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Designating a date, time, and location where the drugs or prescription records may be retrieved by the permit holder or authorized prescriber if certain conditions are met.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(j)">A board shall immediately notify the Division of Drug Control of the surrender, suspension, or revocation of a permit holder's permit or an authorized prescriber's license.</section>
  </text>
</law>
