<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghg" order_by="" level="1">Health - General</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghg-17-2A-02</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>02</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Secretary shall adopt regulations that set standards and requirements for forensic laboratories.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The regulations shall contain the standards and requirements that the Secretary considers necessary to assure the citizens of the State that forensic laboratories provide safe, reliable, and accurate services.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The regulations shall:<section prefix="(i)">Require the director of a forensic laboratory to establish and administer an ongoing quality assurance program using standards acceptable to the Secretary;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Require the director of a forensic laboratory to retain all case files for at least 10 years;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Establish qualifications for the personnel of  forensic laboratories;</section><section prefix="(iv)">Establish procedures for verifying the  background and education of the personnel of forensic  laboratories;</section><section prefix="(v)">Require the Secretary to charge fees that may  not exceed the actual direct and indirect costs to the Department  to carry out the provisions of this subtitle; and</section><section prefix="(vi)">Establish any additional standards that the Secretary considers necessary to assure that forensic laboratories provide accurate and reliable services.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A forensic laboratory that examines or  analyzes physical evidence shall demonstrate satisfactory  performance in an approved proficiency testing program   specifically related to the particular forensic analysis being  performed.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Secretary shall adopt regulations for the forensic proficiency testing program that:<section prefix="(i)">Define satisfactory proficiency testing performance; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Set standards and requirements that a forensic proficiency testing program shall meet.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Department shall review a  forensic laboratory's proficiency testing program.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">To assure compliance with the standards and requirements under this subtitle, the Secretary shall conduct:<section prefix="(1)">An inspection of each forensic laboratory for which a license to operate is sought; and</section><section prefix="(2)">An inspection of each forensic laboratory for which a license has been issued.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">To assure compliance with the standards and  requirements under this subtitle, the Secretary may conduct:<section prefix="(1)">A complaint investigation; and</section><section prefix="(2)">A validation survey of an accredited forensic  laboratory.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
