<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghg" order_by="" level="1">Health - General</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghg-7-1002</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>1002</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">"Qualified developmental disability professional" shall be defined by rule and regulation.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">It is the policy of this State that, in addition to any other rights, each individual who receives any services provided by the Administration or by a licensee has the following basic rights:<section prefix="(1)">The right to be treated with courtesy, respect, and full recognition of human dignity and individuality;</section><section prefix="(2)">The right to receive treatment, services, and habilitation in the most integrated setting that is available, adequate, appropriate, and in compliance with relevant laws and regulations;</section><section prefix="(3)">The right to be free from mental and physical abuse;</section><section prefix="(4)">The right to be free from chemical restraints, except for minimal restraints that a physician authorizes, in writing, for a clearly indicated medical need and makes a permanent part of the individual's record;</section><section prefix="(5)">The right to be free from physical restraints except for minimal restraints that are authorized in writing and made a permanent part of the record by a physician or qualified developmental disability professional and which are clearly indicated for the protection of the individual with developmental disability or others;</section><section prefix="(6)">The right to privacy;</section><section prefix="(7)">The right to worship as the individual chooses;</section><section prefix="(8)">The right to an accounting of any funds of the individual; and</section><section prefix="(9)">The right to be informed of all of the most integrated setting service options licensed through the Administration.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Secretary shall issue regulations to enforce the rights enumerated in subsection (b) of this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Each licensee shall:<section prefix="(1)">Post, conspicuously in a public place, the policy stated in this section;</section><section prefix="(2)">Give a copy of the policy:<section prefix="(i)">On admittance, to the individual;</section><section prefix="(ii)">To the guardian, next of kin, or sponsoring agency of the individual; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">To a representative payee of the individual;</section></section><section prefix="(3)">Keep a receipt for the copy that is signed by the person who received the copy; and</section><section prefix="(4)">Provide appropriate staff training to carry out the policy.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
