<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghg" order_by="" level="1">Health - General</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghg-13-1302</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>1302</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">There is a Governor's Wellmobile Program Advisory Board.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The purpose of the Advisory Board is to assist the University of Maryland School of Nursing in overseeing and raising funds for the Program.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Advisory Board consists of nine individuals, of whom:<section prefix="(1)">One shall be the Dean of the University of Maryland School of Nursing;</section><section prefix="(2)">One shall be a member of the House of Delegates appointed by the Speaker;</section><section prefix="(3)">One shall be a member of the Senate appointed by the President;</section><section prefix="(4)">Two shall have business expertise;</section><section prefix="(5)">Two shall have health expertise; and</section><section prefix="(6)">Two shall have media or marketing expertise.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Except for the ex officio and legislative members, the members of the Advisory Board shall be appointed by the Governor with the advice and consent of the Senate.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Dean of the University of Maryland School of Nursing shall serve as the chairman of the Advisory Board.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except for the ex officio and legislative members, the term of a member is 3 years.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Except for the ex officio and legislative members, the terms of members are staggered as required by the terms provided for members of the Board on October 1, 2000.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">At the end of a term, a member continues to serve until a successor is appointed.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">A member who is appointed after a term has begun serves only for the rest of the term and until a successor is appointed.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The Board shall meet at least four times each year, at the times and places that it determines.</section>
  </text>
</law>
