<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghg" order_by="" level="1">Health - General</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghg-19-3B-05</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>05</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">A license expires on the third anniversary of its effective date unless the license is renewed for a 3-year term as provided in this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Before the license expires, a license may be renewed for an additional 3-year term, if the applicant:<section prefix="(1)">Otherwise is entitled to the license;</section><section prefix="(2)">Pays to the Secretary the renewal fee set by the Secretary through regulation; and</section><section prefix="(3)">Submits to the Secretary:<section prefix="(i)">A renewal application on the form that the Secretary requires; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Satisfactory evidence of compliance with any requirement under this subtitle for license renewal.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Secretary shall renew the license if the applicant meets the requirements of this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Secretary shall set reasonable application and renewal fees not to exceed the administrative costs of the licensing program.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">For purposes of this subsection, administrative costs under paragraph (1) of this subsection do not include any costs of administering the Medicare certification program.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">A license does not entitle the licensee to an exemption from other provisions of law relating to:<section prefix="(1)">The review and approval of hospital rates and charges by the Health Services Cost Review Commission; or</section><section prefix="(2)">The review and approval of new services or facilities by the Maryland Health Care Commission.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
