<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghg" order_by="ghg" level="1">Health - General</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghg-21-324</section_number>
  <catch_line>The floors, walls, ceilings, sidewalks, furniture, receptacles, implements, and machinery of or in a...</catch_line>
  <order_by>324</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The floors, walls, ceilings, sidewalks, furniture, receptacles, implements, and machinery of or in any food establishment shall be kept in a clean and sanitary condition at all times.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The design and construction of existing equipment in food establishments shall be accepted by the Department, if the existing equipment:<section prefix="1.">Complied with the Department's standards that prevailed at the time of the installation;</section><section prefix="2.">Accomplishes its intended and required function in the establishment;</section><section prefix="3.">Is cleanable;</section><section prefix="4.">Is free of hazardous materials and toxic food contact surfaces; and</section><section prefix="5.">Is in good repair.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The Department shall establish guidelines for the replacement of failed existing equipment.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Any vehicle that is used to transport food or from which any food is sold shall be kept in a clean and sanitary condition at all times.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A condition that is unclean and unsanitary exists whenever any of the following occurs:<section prefix="(1)">Any food in the process of manufacture, preparation, packing, canning, freezing, storing, sale, distribution, or transportation is not protected as far as practicable from flies, filth, and any foreign or injurious contamination;</section><section prefix="(2)">Refuse, dirt, or waste products subject to decomposition and fermentation that are incident to the manufacture, preparation, packing, canning, freezing, storing, sale, distribution, or transportation of food are not removed daily, or at a frequency required by the Department;</section><section prefix="(3)">Any receptacle, chute, platform, rack, table, shelf, utensil, or machinery used in moving, handling, cutting, chopping, mixing, canning, freezing, or processing food is not kept clean;</section><section prefix="(4)">The clothing or body of any individual employed in the establishment, place, or vehicle is not kept as clean as the nature of the employment permits;</section><section prefix="(5)">The food establishment lacks an adequate supply of potable water; or</section><section prefix="(6)">The food establishment lacks an adequate sewage disposal facility.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
