<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghg" order_by="ghg" level="1">Health - General</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghg-21-330.1</section_number>
  <catch_line>This section does not:...</catch_line>
  <order_by>330.1</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">This section does not:<section prefix="(1)">Apply to a food establishment that is required to have a license under &#xA7; 21-305 of this subtitle; or</section><section prefix="(2)">Exempt a cottage food business from any applicable State or federal tax laws.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A cottage food business is not required to be licensed by the Department if the owner of the cottage food business complies with this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The owner of a cottage food business may sell only cottage food products that are:<section prefix="(1)">Stored on the premises of the cottage food business; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Prepackaged with a label that contains:<section prefix="(i)">The following information:<section prefix="1.">The name and address of the cottage food business;</section><section prefix="2.">The name of the cottage food product;</section><section prefix="3.">The ingredients of the cottage food product in descending order of the amount of each ingredient by weight;</section><section prefix="4.">The net weight or net volume of the cottage food product;</section><section prefix="5.">Allergen information as specified by federal labeling requirements; and</section><section prefix="6.">If any nutritional claim is made, nutritional information as specified by federal labeling requirements; and</section></section><section prefix="(ii)">The following statement printed in 10 point or larger type in a color that provides a clear contrast to the background of the label: "Made by a cottage food business that is not subject to Maryland's food safety regulations.".</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The owner of a cottage food business shall comply with all applicable county and municipal laws and ordinances regulating the preparation, processing, storage, and sale of cottage food products.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Department may investigate any complaint alleging that a cottage food business has violated this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">On receipt of a complaint, a representative of the Department, at a reasonable time, may enter and inspect the premises of a cottage food business to determine compliance with this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The owner of a cottage food business may not:<section prefix="(i)">Refuse to grant access to a representative who requests to enter and inspect the premises of the cottage food business under paragraph (2) of this subsection; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">Interfere with any inspection under paragraph (2) of this subsection.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">An investigation of a cottage food business conducted under this subsection may include sampling of a cottage food product to determine if the cottage food product is misbranded or adulterated.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The Department shall adopt regulations to carry out this section.</section>
  </text>
</law>
