<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="ghg" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="19-404" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghg-19-404</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Department shall adopt rules and regulations that set standards for the care, treatment, health, safety, welfare, and comfort of patients of home health agencies.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The rules and regulations shall provide for the licensing of home health agencies and annual license renewal, and shall establish standards that require as a minimum, that all home health agencies:<section prefix="(1)">Within 10 days of acceptance of a patient for skilled care, make and record all reasonable efforts to contact a physician to obtain the signed order required under item (2) of this subsection;</section><section prefix="(2)">That accept patients for skilled care do so only on the signed order of a physician obtained within 28 days after acceptance;</section><section prefix="(3)">Adopt procedures for the administration of drugs and biologicals;</section><section prefix="(4)">Maintain clinical records on all patients accepted for skilled care;</section><section prefix="(5)">Establish patient care policies and personnel policies;</section><section prefix="(6)">Have services available at least 8 hours a day, 5 days a week, and available on an emergency basis 24 hours a day, 7 days a week;</section><section prefix="(7)">Make service available to an individual in need within 24 hours of a referral when stipulated by a physician's order;</section><section prefix="(8)">Have a designated supervisor of patient care who is a full-time employee of the agency and is available at all times during operating hours and additionally as needed; and</section><section prefix="(9)">Have as the administrator of the agency a person who has at least 1 year of supervisory experience in hospital management, home health management, or public health program management and who is:<section prefix="(i)">A licensed physician;</section><section prefix="(ii)">A registered nurse; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">A college graduate with a bachelor's degree in a health-related field.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The rules and regulations may include provisions that:<section prefix="(1)">Deal with the establishment of home health agencies;</section><section prefix="(2)">Require each home health agency to have its policies established by a professional group that includes at least:<section prefix="(i)">1 physician;</section><section prefix="(ii)">1 registered nurse;</section><section prefix="(iii)">1 representative of another offered service; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">1 public member;</section></section><section prefix="(3)">Govern the services provided by the home health agencies;</section><section prefix="(4)">Require keeping clinical records of each patient, including the plan of treatment to be provided;</section><section prefix="(5)">Govern supervision of the services, as appropriate, by:<section prefix="(i)">A physician;</section><section prefix="(ii)">A registered nurse; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">Another health professional who is qualified sufficiently by advanced training to supervise the same kind of services in a hospital; and</section></section><section prefix="(6)">Require submission of an annual report which includes service utilization statistics.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The provisions of this section do not waive the requirement for a home health agency to obtain a certificate of need.</section>
  </text>
</law>
