<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="ghg" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="19-2002" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghg-19-2002</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, "Office" means the Office of Health Care Quality in the Department of Health and Mental Hygiene.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Office may inspect a nursing staff agency to verify compliance with this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">When the Office conducts an inspection, the Office shall verify that the nursing personnel referred by the nursing staff agency:<section prefix="(1)">If registered nurses or licensed practical nurses, are licensed by the Board; or</section><section prefix="(2)">If certified nursing assistants, are certified by the Board.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">When the Office conducts an inspection, the Office shall verify that the nursing staff agency has developed, documented, and implemented procedures for:<section prefix="(1)">Selecting and verifying the credentials of nursing personnel referred by the agency;</section><section prefix="(2)">Validating experience of nursing personnel prior to referral by the agency;</section><section prefix="(3)">Tracking and acting on serious or life-threatening complaints received by a client facility or the client facility's agent;</section><section prefix="(4)">Reporting of an action or condition under &#xA7; 19-2001(h) of this subtitle;</section><section prefix="(5)">Verifying that nursing personnel referred by the agency are of satisfactory health status and have received the necessary testing and immunization as required or requested by the client facility;</section><section prefix="(6)">Verifying I-9 status;</section><section prefix="(7)">Verifying, prior to initial referral of nursing personnel to a client facility by the agency, drug screening of nursing personnel referred by the agency if the client facility requires drug screening for facility employees;</section><section prefix="(8)">Verifying, when there is probable cause to perform a drug test or when a client facility requests a drug test, drug testing of nursing personnel referred by the agency;</section><section prefix="(9)">Verifying, prior to initial referral of nursing personnel to a client facility by the agency, criminal background checks of nursing personnel referred by the agency if the client facility requires criminal background checks for facility employees; and</section><section prefix="(10)">Verifying the references of nursing personnel referred by the agency.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">A nursing staff agency shall attest that the nursing staff agency is in compliance with the:<section prefix="(1)">Civil Rights Act of 1964;</section><section prefix="(2)">Rehabilitation Act of 1973;</section><section prefix="(3)">Americans with Disabilities Act of 1990; and</section><section prefix="(4)">Drug Free Workplace Act of 1988, if applicable.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The Office may inspect a nursing staff agency upon receiving a complaint, and may give notice of the inspection to the nursing staff agency.</section>
  </text>
</law>
