<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghg" order_by="" level="1">Health - General</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghg-13-1602</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>1602</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Advisory Council consists of the following 23 members:<section prefix="(1)">The Attorney General or the Attorney General's designee;</section><section prefix="(2)">One member of the Senate of Maryland, appointed by the President of the Senate of Maryland;</section><section prefix="(3)">One member of the House of Delegates, appointed by the Speaker of the House;</section><section prefix="(4)">The Secretary of Aging or the Secretary's designee;</section><section prefix="(5)">The Secretary of Health and Mental Hygiene or the Secretary's designee;</section><section prefix="(6)">The Secretary of Disabilities or the Secretary's designee; and</section><section prefix="(7)">17 members appointed by the Governor:<section prefix="(i)">One physician with experience in end-of-life care;</section><section prefix="(ii)">One nurse with experience in end-of-life care;</section><section prefix="(iii)">One pharmacist with experience in end-of-life care;</section><section prefix="(iv)">One physician with experience managing long-term care;</section><section prefix="(v)">One nurse with experience managing long-term care;</section><section prefix="(vi)">One representative of the health insurance industry;</section><section prefix="(vii)">One representative from a managed care organization;</section><section prefix="(viii)">One representative of the legal community;</section><section prefix="(ix)">One representative from the hospice care community;</section><section prefix="(x)">Two representatives from advocacy groups for end-of-life care;</section><section prefix="(xi)">Two representatives from religious groups;</section><section prefix="(xii)">Two representatives of the general public with experience with end-of-life or long-term care issues;</section><section prefix="(xiii)">One representative of the hospital industry; and</section><section prefix="(xiv)">One representative of the nursing home industry.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The term of a member appointed by the Governor is 4 years.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">At the end of a term, a member continues to serve until a successor is appointed and qualifies.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A member who is appointed after a term has begun serves only for the rest of the term and until a successor is appointed and qualifies.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">A member who serves two consecutive 4-year terms may not be reappointed for 4 years after the completion of those terms.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">If a vacancy occurs among the members appointed by the Governor, the Governor shall promptly appoint a successor.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
