<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghg" order_by="ghg" level="1">Health - General</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghg-18-202.1</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this section, "institution" includes:...</catch_line>
  <order_by>202.1</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, "institution" includes:<section prefix="(1)">A hospital;</section><section prefix="(2)">A nursing home;</section><section prefix="(3)">A hospice facility;</section><section prefix="(4)">A medical clinic in a correctional facility;</section><section prefix="(5)">An inpatient psychiatric facility; and</section><section prefix="(6)">An inpatient drug rehabilitation facility.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">When an institution has an individual in the care of the institution with a diagnosis of human immunodeficiency virus or acquired immunodeficiency syndrome according to the current definition published in the morbidity and mortality weekly report by the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, a clinical or infection control practitioner shall submit a report within 48 hours to the health officer for the county where the institution is located.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The report shall:<section prefix="(1)">Be on the form that the Secretary provides;</section><section prefix="(2)">Identify the disease;</section><section prefix="(3)">State the name, age, race, sex, and residence address of the individual with the disease;</section><section prefix="(4)">State the name of the administrative head of the institution; and</section><section prefix="(5)">State the address of the institution.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">All institution reports required under this section are:<section prefix="(i)">Confidential and subject to Title 4, Subtitle 1 of this article; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Not medical records under Title 4, Subtitle 3 of this article, but are subject to the confidentiality requirements of Title 4, Subtitle 1 of this article.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The reports and any proceedings, records, or files relating to the reports required under this section are not discoverable and are not admissible in evidence in any civil action.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">This subsection does not apply to a disclosure by the Secretary to another governmental agency performing its lawful duties in accordance with State or federal law where the Secretary determines the agency to whom the information is disclosed will maintain the confidentiality of the disclosure.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
