<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghg" order_by="ghg" level="1">Health - General</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghg-19-1904</section_number>
  <catch_line>As part of the application for a State criminal history records check to be conducted by the Departm...</catch_line>
  <order_by>1904</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">As part of the application for a State criminal history records check to be conducted by the Department, an eligible employee shall submit to the adult dependent care program:<section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in subsection (c) of this section, a complete set of legible fingerprints taken on forms specified by the Director of the Criminal Justice Information System Central Repository; and</section><section prefix="(2)">The disclosure statement required under &#xA7; 19-1905 of this subtitle.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The adult dependent care program shall submit the fingerprints, disclosure statement, and payment for the costs of the criminal history records check.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The requirement that a complete set of legible fingerprints taken on forms specified by the Director of the Criminal Justice Information System Central Repository be submitted as part of the application for a criminal history records check may be waived by the Department if:<section prefix="(1)">The eligible employee has attempted to have a complete set of fingerprints taken on at least two occasions;</section><section prefix="(2)">The taking of a complete set of legible fingerprints is not possible because of a physical or medical condition of the eligible employee's fingers or hands;</section><section prefix="(3)">The eligible employee submits documentation satisfactory to the Department of the requirements of this subsection; and</section><section prefix="(4)">The eligible employee submits the other information required for a criminal history records check to be conducted by the Department as part of the application process.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
