<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="ghg" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="5-708" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghg-5-708</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Meetings of the State Team and of local teams shall be closed to the public and not subject to Title 10, Subtitle 5 of the State Government Article when the State Team or local teams are discussing individual cases of child deaths.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Except as provided in subsection (c) of this section, meetings of the State Team and of local teams shall be open to the public and subject to Title 10, Subtitle 5 of the State Government Article when the State Team or local team is not discussing individual cases of child deaths.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">During a public meeting, information may not be disclosed that identifies:<section prefix="(i)">A deceased child;</section><section prefix="(ii)">A family member, guardian, or caretaker of a deceased child;</section><section prefix="(iii)">An alleged or suspected perpetrator of abuse or neglect upon a child; or</section><section prefix="(iv)">A child convicted of a crime or adjudicated as having committed a delinquent act that caused a death or near fatality.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">During a public meeting, information may not be disclosed regarding the involvement of any agency with:<section prefix="(i)">A deceased child;</section><section prefix="(ii)">A family member, guardian, or caretaker of a deceased child;</section><section prefix="(iii)">An alleged or suspected perpetrator of abuse or neglect upon a child; or</section><section prefix="(iv)">A child convicted of a crime or adjudicated as having committed a delinquent act that caused a death or near fatality.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">This section does not prohibit the State Team or a local team from requesting the attendance at a team meeting of a person who has information relevant to the team's exercise of its purpose and duties.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">Violation of this section is a misdemeanor and is punishable by a fine not exceeding $500 or imprisonment not exceeding 90 days or both.</section>
  </text>
</law>
