<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghg" order_by="" level="1">Health - General</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghg-15-303</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>303</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Department shall be responsible for enrolling program recipients in managed care organizations under the Maryland Children's Health Program established under &#xA7;&#xA7; 15-301 and 15-301.1 of this subtitle.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Department may contract with an entity to perform any part or all of its enrollment responsibilities under paragraph (1) of this subsection.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Department or its enrollment contractor, to the extent feasible in its marketing, outreach, and enrollment programs, shall hire individuals receiving assistance under the Family Investment Program established under Title 5, Subtitle 3 of the Human Services Article.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">To the extent allowed under federal law and regulations, the Secretary shall implement expedited eligibility for any individual who applies through the local health department for the Maryland Children's Health Program under &#xA7;&#xA7; 15-301 and 15-301.1 of this subtitle, including any individual with associated food stamp, cash assistance, or medical assistance cases.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Secretary shall designate organizations that may:<section prefix="(i)">Assist individuals in the application process; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Perform other outreach functions.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">In designating the organizations under paragraph (2) of this subsection, the Secretary shall ensure the inclusion of statewide and local organizations that provide services to children of all ages in each region of the State, and shall provide such organizations with:<section prefix="(i)">Forms that are necessary for parents, guardians, and other individuals to submit applications to the Maryland Children's Health Program on behalf of a child; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Information on how to assist parents, guardians, and other individuals in completing and filing such applications.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
