<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghg" order_by="" level="1">Health - General</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghg-5-606</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>606</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Prior to providing, withholding, or withdrawing treatment for which authorization has been obtained or will be sought under this subtitle, the attending physician and a second physician, one of whom shall have examined the patient within 2 hours before making the certification, shall certify in writing that the patient is incapable of making an informed decision regarding the treatment. The certification shall be based on a personal examination of the patient.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If a patient is unconscious, or unable to communicate by any means, the certification of a second physician is not required under paragraph (1) of this subsection.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">When authorization is sought for treatment of a mental illness, the second physician may not be otherwise currently involved in the treatment of the person assessed.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The cost of an assessment to certify incapacity under this subsection shall be considered for all purposes a cost of the patient's treatment.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A health care provider may not withhold or withdraw life-sustaining procedures on the basis of an advance directive where no agent has been appointed or on the basis of the authorization of a surrogate, unless:<section prefix="(1)">The patient's attending physician and a second physician have certified that the patient is in a terminal condition or has an end-stage condition; or</section><section prefix="(2)">Two physicians, one of whom is a neurologist, neurosurgeon, or other physician who has special expertise in the evaluation of cognitive functioning, certify that the patient is in a persistent vegetative state.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
