<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghg" order_by="ghg" level="1">Health - General</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghg-19-126</section_number>
  <catch_line>If the Commission receives an application for a certificate of need for a change in the bed capacity...</catch_line>
  <order_by>126</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">If the Commission receives an application for a certificate of need for a change in the bed capacity of a health care facility, as required under &#xA7; 19-120 of this subtitle, or for a health care project that would create a new health care service or abolish an existing health care service, the Commission shall give notice of the filing by publication in the Maryland Register and give the following notice to:<section prefix="(1)">Each member of the General Assembly in whose district the action is planned;</section><section prefix="(2)">Each member of the governing body for the county where the action is planned;</section><section prefix="(3)">The county executive, mayor, or chief executive officer, if any, in whose county or city the action is planned; and</section><section prefix="(4)">Any health care provider, third party payor, local planning agency, or any other person the Commission knows has an interest in the application.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Failure to give notice shall not adversely affect the application.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">All decisions of the Commission on an application for a certificate of need, except in emergency circumstances posing a threat to public health, shall be consistent with the State health plan and the standards for review established by the Commission.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The mere failure of the State health plan to address any particular project or health care service shall not alone be deemed to render the project inconsistent with the State health plan.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Unless the Commission finds that the facility or service for which the proposed expenditure is to be made is not needed or is not consistent with the State health plan, the Commission shall approve an application for a certificate of need required under &#xA7; 19-120(k) of this subtitle to the extent that the expenditure is to be made to:<section prefix="(i)">Eliminate or prevent an imminent safety hazard, as defined by federal, State, or local fire, building, or life safety codes or regulations;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Comply with State licensing standards; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">Comply with accreditation standards for reimbursement under Title XVIII of the Social Security Act or under the State Medical Assistance Program approved under Title XIX of the Social Security Act.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Commission alone shall have final nondelegable authority to act upon an application for a certificate of need, except as provided in this subsection.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A majority of the full authorized membership of the Commission shall be a quorum to act on an application for a certificate of need.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">After an application is filed, the staff of the Commission:<section prefix="(i)">Shall review the application for completeness within 10 working days of the filing of the application; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">May request further information from the applicant.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The Commission may delegate to a reviewer the responsibility for review of an application for a certificate of need, including:<section prefix="(i)">The holding of an evidentiary hearing if the Commission, in accordance with criteria it has adopted by regulation, considers an evidentiary hearing appropriate due to the magnitude of the impact the proposed project may have on the health care delivery system; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Preparation of a recommended decision for consideration by the full Commission.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(5)">The Commission shall designate a single Commissioner to act as a reviewer for the application and any competing applications.</section>
      <section prefix="(6)">The Commission shall delegate to its staff the responsibility for an initial review of an application, including, in the event that no written comments on an application are submitted by any interested party other than the staff of the Commission, the preparation of a recommended decision for consideration by the full Commission.</section>
      <section prefix="(7)">Any "interested party" may submit written comments on the application in accordance with procedural regulations adopted by the Commission.</section>
      <section prefix="(8)">The Commission shall define the term "interested party" to include, at a minimum:<section prefix="(i)">The staff of the Commission;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Any applicant who has submitted a competing application;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Any other person who can demonstrate that the person would be adversely affected by the decision of the Commission on the application; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">A local health planning agency for a jurisdiction or region in which the proposed facility or service will be located.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(9)">The reviewer shall review the application, any written comments on the application, and any other materials permitted by this section or by the Commission's regulations, and present a recommended decision on the application to the full Commission.</section>
      <section prefix="(10)">
        <section prefix="(i)">An applicant and any interested party may request the opportunity to present oral argument to the reviewer, in accordance with regulations adopted by the Commission, before the reviewer prepares a recommended decision on the application for consideration by the full Commission.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The reviewer may grant, deny, or impose limitations on an interested party's request to present oral argument to the reviewer.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(11)">Any interested party who has submitted written comments under paragraph (7) of this subsection may submit written exceptions to the proposed decision and make oral argument to the Commission, in accordance with regulations adopted by the Commission, before the Commission takes final action on the application.</section>
      <section prefix="(12)">The Commission shall, after determining that the recommended decision is complete, vote to approve, approve with conditions, or deny the application on the basis of the recommended decision, the record before the staff or the reviewer, and exceptions and arguments, if any, before the Commission.</section>
      <section prefix="(13)">The decision of the Commission shall be by a majority of the quorum present and voting.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">Where the State health plan identifies a need for additional hospital bed capacity in a region or subregion, in a comparative review of 2 or more applicants for hospital bed expansion projects, a certificate of need shall be granted to 1 or more applicants in that region or subregion that:<section prefix="(1)">Have satisfactorily met all applicable standards;</section><section prefix="(2)"><section prefix="(i)">Have within the preceding 10 years voluntarily delicensed the greater of 10 beds or 10 percent of total licensed bed capacity to the extent of the beds that are voluntarily delicensed; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">Have been previously granted a certificate of need which was not recertified by the Commission within the preceding 10 years; and</section></section><section prefix="(3)">The Commission finds at least comparable to all other applicants.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If any party or interested person requests an evidentiary hearing with respect to a certificate of need application for any health care facility other than an ambulatory surgical facility and the Commission, in accordance with criteria it has adopted by regulation, considers an evidentiary hearing appropriate due to the magnitude of the impact that the proposed project may have on the health care delivery system, the Commission or a committee of the Commission shall hold the hearing in accordance with the contested case procedures of the Administrative Procedure Act.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Except as provided in this section or in regulations adopted by the Commission to implement the provisions of this section, the review of an application for a certificate of need for an ambulatory surgical facility is not subject to the contested case procedures of Title 10, Subtitle 2 of the State Government Article.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">An application for a certificate of need shall be acted upon by the Commission no later than 150 days after the application was docketed.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If an evidentiary hearing is not requested, the Commission's decision on an application shall be made no later than 90 days after the application was docketed.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(h)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The applicant or any aggrieved party, as defined in &#xA7; 19-128(a) of this subtitle, may petition the Commission within 15 days for a reconsideration.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Commission shall decide whether or not it will reconsider its decision within 30 days of receipt of the petition for reconsideration.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Commission shall issue its reconsideration decision within 30 days of its decision on the petition.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(i)">If the Commission does not act on an application within the required period, the applicant may file with a court of competent jurisdiction within 60 days after expiration of the period a petition to require the Commission to act on the application.</section>
  </text>
</law>
