<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghg" order_by="" level="1">Health - General</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghg-13-1108</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>1108</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">After the Baseline Cancer Study has been completed and before soliciting applications for Local Public Health Cancer Grants, the Department, in consultation with local health departments, shall:<section prefix="(1)">Establish short-term and long-term cancer prevention, education, screening, and treatment goals for each county;</section><section prefix="(2)">Establish other requirements for each county that the Department determines to be necessary to meet the goals established under paragraph (1) of this subsection; and</section><section prefix="(3)">Provide for the distribution of Local Public Health Cancer Grants to eligible counties based on the formula established under subsection (b) of this section.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Subject to subsections (c) through (e) of this section and &#xA7;&#xA7; 13-1109 through 13-1113 of this subtitle, the Department shall distribute a Local Public Health Cancer Grant to each county that is equal to the sum of:<section prefix="(1)">A base amount of funding as determined by the Department for each county;</section><section prefix="(2)">The product of:<section prefix="(i)">One-half of the amount remaining from the allocation to the Local Public Health Component in the State budget after the base amount under item (1) of this subsection is distributed to each county; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">The number of individuals in the county who have any of the targeted cancers divided by the number of individuals in the State residing outside of Baltimore City who have any of the targeted cancers; and</section></section><section prefix="(3)">The product of:<section prefix="(i)">One-half of the amount remaining from the allocation to the Local Public Health Component in the State budget after the base amount under item (1) of this subsection is distributed to each county; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">The number of individuals in the county who died from any of the targeted cancers during the prior year divided by the number of individuals in the State residing outside of Baltimore City who died from any of the targeted cancers during the prior year.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in this subsection, Baltimore City is not eligible to receive money from the Department based on the formula established under subsection (b) of this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Each year, before calculating the amount of money that may be distributed to each county as a Local Public Health Cancer Grant under subsection (b) of this section, the Department shall calculate the amount of money that would have been distributed to each county if Baltimore City were included in the formula.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">For fiscal year 2007 or any subsequent fiscal year, if the amount of money that would have been distributed to Baltimore City using the formula established under subsection (b) of this section if Baltimore City were included in the formula exceeds 19%, the Department shall transfer the difference between that amount and 19% from the Local Public Health Component to the Statewide Academic Health Center Component.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Beginning in fiscal year 2004, the calculations required in subsection (b)(2)(ii) and (3)(ii) of this section of the numbers of individuals having any of the targeted cancers or who died from any of the targeted cancers shall be based on the most recent data averaged over a multiyear period as determined by the Department.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The allocation formula calculated in accordance with subsection (b) of this section for fiscal year 2004 shall remain in effect for the following 3 years and thereafter be recalculated every 4th year in accordance with the provisions of this section.</section>
  </text>
</law>
