<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="ghg" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="13-603" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghg-13-603</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">There is an Advisory Council for the program.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Advisory Council consists of 11 members appointed by the Secretary.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Of the 11 members:<section prefix="(i)">1 shall be a physician with expertise in childhood hearing loss;</section><section prefix="(ii)">3 shall be from the field of education:</section><section prefix="(iii)">1 shall be from the Maryland Department of Health and Mental Hygiene;</section><section prefix="(iv)">1 shall be a mental health professional with expertise in the area of deafness;</section><section prefix="(v)">2 shall be parents of hearing-impaired children;</section><section prefix="(vi)">1 shall be from the Maryland Association of the Deaf;</section><section prefix="(vii)">1 shall be an audiologist with expertise in childhood hearing loss; and</section><section prefix="(viii)">1 shall be from the Alexander Graham Bell Association of Maryland.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Advisory Council shall elect a chairperson from among its members.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Advisory Council shall meet at least 6 times a year at the times and places that it determines.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">A member of the Advisory Council:<section prefix="(1)">May not receive compensation; but</section><section prefix="(2)">Is entitled to reimbursement for expenses under the Standard State Travel Regulations, as provided in the State budget.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The Advisory Council shall:<section prefix="(1)">Advise the Department on the implementation of universal hearing screening of newborns and an early identification program and follow-up of hearing-impaired infants and infants who have a risk factor of developing a hearing impairment;</section><section prefix="(2)">Provide consultation to the Department in the development of the program;</section><section prefix="(3)">Make recommendations for operation of the program;</section><section prefix="(4)">Advise the Department:<section prefix="(i)">In setting standards for the program;</section><section prefix="(ii)">In monitoring and reviewing the program; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">In providing quality assurance for the program;</section></section><section prefix="(5)">Advise the Department on the development of protocols to assist hospitals in implementing universal hearing screening of newborns;</section><section prefix="(6)">Provide consultation to the Department in the establishment of an educational program for families, professionals, and the public that can be integrated with existing State and local education agency programs; and</section><section prefix="(7)">Review any materials the Department may distribute to the public concerning hearing-impaired newborns and infants.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(g)">In consultation with the Advisory Council, the Department shall develop guidelines for the operations of the Advisory Council.</section>
  </text>
</law>
