<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="ghg" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="19-3A-07" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghg-19-3A-07</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">There are two freestanding medical facility pilot projects that shall operate in two jurisdictions in the State.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Department shall issue a freestanding medical facility license to:<section prefix="(1)">One freestanding medical facility pilot project if:<section prefix="(i)">The freestanding medical facility pilot project is established by, and will operate administratively as part of, an acute care general hospital;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The acute care general hospital is part of a merged asset system with all of its existing Maryland acute care general hospitals located in a single jurisdiction;</section><section prefix="(iii)">There are not more than 5 acute care general hospitals in the jurisdiction;</section><section prefix="(iv)">One or more of the existing acute care general hospitals in the merged asset system has an emergency department volume of 75,000 or more visits for the 12 months ending June 30, 2004;</section><section prefix="(v)">The freestanding medical facility pilot project will operate in Montgomery County;</section><section prefix="(vi)">The capital expenditure to implement the freestanding medical facility pilot project otherwise meets the requirements of &#xA7; 19-120(k)(6)(viii) of this title; and</section><section prefix="(vii)">The freestanding medical facility pilot project meets the requirements under &#xA7; 19-3A-02(b) of this subtitle; and</section></section><section prefix="(2)">One freestanding medical facility pilot project if:<section prefix="(i)">The freestanding medical facility pilot project is established by, and will operate administratively as part of, an acute care general hospital located in Talbot County;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The freestanding medical facility pilot project will operate in Queen Anne's County;</section><section prefix="(iii)">The capital expenditure to implement the freestanding medical facility pilot project otherwise meets the requirements of &#xA7; 19-120(k)(6)(viii) of this title; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">The freestanding medical facility pilot project meets the requirements under &#xA7; 19-3A-02(b) of this subtitle.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A freestanding medical facility pilot project shall provide to the Maryland Health Care Commission information, as specified by the Commission, on the configuration, location, operation, and utilization, including patient-level utilization, of the pilot project.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A certificate of need is not required for a freestanding medical facility pilot project.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The provisions of &#xA7;&#xA7; 19-3A-01 through 19-3A-06 of this subtitle shall apply to a freestanding medical facility pilot project.</section>
  </text>
</law>
