<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghg" order_by="" level="1">Health - General</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghg-21-435</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>435</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">An individual who has a communicable disease or is a carrier of a communicable disease may not work, in any capacity that brings that individual into contact with the production, handling, storage, or transportation of milk products, containers, equipment, or utensils, at:<section prefix="(i)">A dairy farm;</section><section prefix="(ii)">A milk plant;</section><section prefix="(iii)">A receiving station; or</section><section prefix="(iv)">A transfer station.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A person who operates a dairy farm, transfer station, receiving station, or milk plant may not employ any individual:<section prefix="(i)">Who, if employed, would violate paragraph (1) of this subsection; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">Whom the employer reasonably believes would violate paragraph (1) of this subsection if employed.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Each holder of a permit for a receiving station, transfer station, or as a distributor, milk processor, or milk producer shall notify the Secretary immediately if:<section prefix="(1)">A communicable disease affects any individual on that person's dairy farm, distribution station, receiving station, transfer station, or milk plant; or</section><section prefix="(2)">That person suspects that any employee of that person has contracted a communicable disease or has become a carrier of a communicable disease.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">An individual who has an infected cut or lesion on a hand or arm may not handle any milk product, milk container, or milk equipment.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Secretary may make or require a reasonable medical and biological examination of an individual who is suspected of having any communicable disease.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">An examination under this subsection may include examination of the bodily discharges of the individual.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
