<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghg" order_by="" level="1">Health - General</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghg-13-104</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>104</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Advisory Council consists of 11 voting members and 5 nonvoting members.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Of the 11 voting members:<section prefix="(i)">1 shall be a member of the Senate appointed by the President of the Senate;</section><section prefix="(ii)">1 shall be a member of the House of Delegates appointed by the Speaker of the House;</section><section prefix="(iii)">4 shall be professional individuals in the field of hereditary or congenital disorders appointed by the Governor; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">5 shall be individuals appointed by the Governor, none of whom may be:<section prefix="1.">A health professional or spouse of a health professional; or</section><section prefix="2.">An individual or spouse of an individual involved in the administration or ownership of any health care institution or health insurance organization.</section></section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Except as provided in subparagraph (iv) of this paragraph, the Governor shall appoint 1 professional member from a list of qualified individuals submitted to the Governor by each of the following organizations:<section prefix="1.">The Monumental City Medical Society;</section><section prefix="2.">The Medical and Chirurgical Faculty of the State of Maryland;</section><section prefix="3.">The faculty of the University of Maryland School of Medicine; and</section><section prefix="4.">The faculties of the Johns Hopkins Medical Institutions.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The number of names on a list shall be 3.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">An organization shall submit its list:<section prefix="1.">At least 3 months before the expiration of the term of the professional member who represents the organization; and</section><section prefix="2.">If a vacancy is for a reason other than expiration of the term, at any time before the Governor makes the appointment, if the organization complies with the reasonable request of the Governor for the list.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(iv)">If a list is not submitted to the Governor as required under subparagraph (iii) of this paragraph, within 3 months after a request is made by the Governor, the Governor may appoint any professional individual who meets the requirements under subsection (b) of this section.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(4)">Of the 5 nonvoting members:<section prefix="(i)">1 shall be a representative of the State Health Planning and Development Agency, appointed by the Secretary; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">4 shall be representatives of the Department, appointed by the Secretary.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Each professional individual selected for the Advisory Council shall be knowledgeable in the diagnosis and treatment of hereditary and congenital disorders.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The term of a voting member is 4 years.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The terms of the voting members are staggered as required by the terms provided for voting members of the Advisory Council on July 1, 1982. The terms of those members end as follows:<section prefix="(i)">3 in 1983;</section><section prefix="(ii)">3 in 1984;</section><section prefix="(iii)">3 in 1985; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">2 in 1986.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">At the end of a term, a voting member continues to serve until a successor is appointed and qualifies.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">A voting member who is appointed after a term has begun serves only for the rest of the term and until a successor is appointed and qualifies.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">A voting member who serves 2 consecutive full 4-year terms may not be reappointed for 4 years after completion of those terms.</section>
      <section prefix="(6)">When a vacancy occurs, a successor shall be appointed promptly.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
