<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghg" order_by="ghg" level="1">Health - General</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghg-15-701</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this subtitle, "Fund" means the Health Care Coverage Fund....</catch_line>
  <order_by>701</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this subtitle, "Fund" means the Health Care Coverage Fund.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">There is a Health Care Coverage Fund.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The purpose of the Fund is to:<section prefix="(1)">Support health care coverage for individuals and families with low or moderate income; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Subject to subsection (i) of this section, support the provision of health care services in Prince George's County.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Department and the Maryland Health Care Commission shall administer the Fund.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Fund is a special, nonlapsing fund that is not subject to &#xA7; 7-302 of the State Finance and Procurement Article.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Treasurer shall hold the Fund separately, and the Comptroller shall account for the Fund.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The Fund consists of:<section prefix="(1)">Moneys transferred from the Maryland Health Insurance Plan Fund;</section><section prefix="(2)">Moneys collected from any assessment by the State Health Services Cost Review Commission on hospitals under &#xA7; 19-214(d) of this article;</section><section prefix="(3)">Any moneys made available from investment earnings; and</section><section prefix="(4)">Any other moneys from any other source accepted for the benefit of the Fund.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Fund shall be invested and reinvested in the same manner as other State funds.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Any investment earnings shall be credited to the Fund.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(h)">The Fund may be used only for expenses associated with:<section prefix="(1)">Expanding Medicaid eligibility for parents and caretaker relatives:<section prefix="(i)">Who have a dependent child living with them; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Whose annual household income is at or below 116% of the federal poverty guidelines;</section></section><section prefix="(2)">Expanding Medicaid eligibility and benefits for individuals:<section prefix="(i)">Who do not meet requirements, such as age, disability, or parent or caretaker relative of a dependent child, for a federal category of eligibility for Medicaid;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Whose annual household income is at or below 116% of the federal poverty guidelines; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Who are not enrolled in the federal Medicare program, as enacted by Title XVIII of the Social Security Act;</section></section><section prefix="(3)">Providing and administering health benefit plan premium subsidies under Title 15, Subtitle 12A of the Insurance Article; and</section><section prefix="(4)">Supporting the provision of health care services in Prince George's County in accordance with subsection (i) of this section.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(i)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Subject to paragraph (2) of this subsection, in fiscal year 2010, $12,000,000, and in fiscal years 2011 through 2013, up to $10,000,000 may be transferred annually from the Fund to the Department for the purpose of providing a special fund operating grant to an independent entity with authority over the facilities currently operated and health care services currently provided by Dimensions Healthcare System until the facilities and obligation to provide the services are transferred to a new owner or operator.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Department may not provide a special fund operating grant until a long-term, comprehensive solution to the control and operation of the facilities and provision of health care services currently operated and provided by Dimensions Healthcare System is reached through:<section prefix="(i)">An Act of the General Assembly; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">A memorandum of understanding between the State and Prince George's County.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The long-term, comprehensive solution under paragraph (2) of this subsection shall address issues related to health care needs in Prince George's County and the surrounding region, including:<section prefix="(i)">The transfer to a new owner or operator of the facilities currently operated and the obligation to provide the health care services currently provided by Dimensions Healthcare System;</section><section prefix="(ii)">A plan for the assets currently held by Prince George's County related to the facilities currently operated by Dimensions Healthcare System;</section><section prefix="(iii)">A mechanism to provide a steady revenue stream to help support ongoing operations of the facilities currently operated by Dimensions Healthcare System and to retire the long-term bond indebtedness and satisfy the unfunded pension liability of Dimensions Healthcare System; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">A mechanism to assure equitable and sustainable funding from Prince George's County and the State.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">Moneys transferred from the Maryland Health Insurance Plan Fund or collected from an assessment by the State Health Services Cost Review Commission on hospitals may not be used for the purpose of this subsection.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(j)">Expenditures from the Fund may be made only in accordance with the State budget.</section>
    <section prefix="(k)">Money from the Fund shall supplement and may not supplant funding for the Maryland Medical Assistance Program.</section>
    <section prefix="(l)">The Fund is subject to audit by the Office of Legislative Audits.</section>
  </text>
</law>
