<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghg" order_by="" level="1">Health - General</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghg-20-1401</section_number>
  <catch_line>// EFFECTIVE UNTIL JUNE 30, 2016 PER CHAPTER 3 OF 2012 //...</catch_line>
  <order_by>1401</order_by>
  <text>// EFFECTIVE UNTIL JUNE 30, 2016 PER CHAPTER 3 OF 2012 //<section prefix="(a)">In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated.</section><section prefix="(b)">"Area" means a contiguous geographic area that:<section prefix="(1)">Demonstrates measurable and documented health disparities and poor health outcomes; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Is small enough to allow for the incentives offered under this subtitle to have a significant impact on improving health outcomes and reducing health disparities, including racial, ethnic, and geographic health disparities.</section></section><section prefix="(c)">"Commission" means the Community Health Resources Commission.</section><section prefix="(d)">"Fund" means the Health Enterprise Zone Reserve Fund established under &#xA7; 20-1406 of this subtitle.</section><section prefix="(e)">"Health Enterprise Zone" means a contiguous geographic area that:<section prefix="(1)">Demonstrates measurable and documented health disparities and poor health outcomes;</section><section prefix="(2)">Is small enough to allow for the incentives offered under this subtitle to have a significant impact on improving health outcomes and reducing health disparities, including racial, ethnic, and geographic health disparities; and</section><section prefix="(3)">Is designated as a Health Enterprise Zone by the Commission and the Secretary in accordance with the provisions of this subtitle.</section></section><section prefix="(f)">"Health Enterprise Zone practitioner" means a health care practitioner who is licensed or certified under the Health Occupations Article and who provides:<section prefix="(1)">Primary care, including obstetrics, gynecological services, pediatric services, or geriatric services;</section><section prefix="(2)">Behavioral health services, including mental health or alcohol and substance abuse services; or</section><section prefix="(3)">Dental services.</section></section></text>
</law>
