<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghg" order_by="" level="1">Health - General</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghg-15-101</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>101</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this title the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(a-1)">"Dental managed care organization" means a pre-paid dental plan that receives fees to manage dental services.</section>
    <section prefix="(a-2)">"Dental services" means diagnostic, emergency, preventive, and therapeutic services for oral diseases.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Enrollee" means a program recipient who is enrolled in a managed care organization.</section>
    <section prefix="(b-1)">"Expedited eligibility" means a streamlined eligibility process, conducted by the local health departments, for medical assistance for children and pregnant women under which an eligibility determination is made promptly, but not later than 10 working days after the date of application.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Facility" means a hospital or nursing facility including an intermediate care facility, skilled nursing facility, comprehensive care facility, or extended care facility.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Historic provider" means a health care provider, as defined in &#xA7; 19-132 of this article, or a residential service agency licensed under Title 19, Subtitle 4A of this article, that, on or before June 30, 1995, had a demonstrated history of providing services to program recipients, as defined by the Department in regulations.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Historic provider", to the extent the provider meets the requirements in paragraph (1) of this subsection, shall include:<section prefix="(i)">A federal or State qualified community health center;</section><section prefix="(ii)">A provider with a program for the training of health care professionals, including an academic medical center;</section><section prefix="(iii)">A hospital outpatient program, physician, or advanced practice nurse that is a Maryland Access to Care (MAC) provider;</section><section prefix="(iv)">A local health department;</section><section prefix="(v)">A hospice, as defined in Title 19, Subtitle 9 of this article;</section><section prefix="(vi)">A pharmacy; and</section><section prefix="(vii)">Any other historic provider designated in accordance with regulations adopted by the Department.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d-1)">"Independent foster care adolescent" means an individual:<section prefix="(1)">Who is under 21 years of age; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Who, on the individual's 18th birthday, was in foster care under the responsibility of the State.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"Managed care organization" means:<section prefix="(1)">A certified health maintenance organization that is authorized to receive medical assistance prepaid capitation payments; or</section><section prefix="(2)">A corporation that:<section prefix="(i)">Is a managed care system that is authorized to receive medical assistance prepaid capitation payments;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Enrolls only program recipients or individuals or families served under the Maryland Children's Health Program; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Is subject to the requirements of &#xA7; 15-102.4 of this subtitle.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">"Ombudsman program" means a program that assists enrollees in resolving disputes with managed care organizations in a timely manner and that is responsible, at a minimum, for the following functions:<section prefix="(1)">Investigating disputes between enrollees and managed care organizations referred by the enrollee hotline;</section><section prefix="(2)">Reporting to the Department:<section prefix="(i)">The resolution of all disputes;</section><section prefix="(ii)">A managed care organization's failure to meet the Department's requirements; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Any other information specified by the Department;</section></section><section prefix="(3)">Educating enrollees about:<section prefix="(i)">The services provided by the enrollee's managed care organization; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">The enrollee's rights and responsibilities in receiving services from the managed care organization; and</section></section><section prefix="(4)">Advocating on behalf of the enrollee before the managed care organization, including assisting the enrollee in using the managed care organization's grievance process.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(g)">"Primary mental health services" means the clinical evaluation and assessment of services needed by an individual and the provision of services or referral for additional services as deemed medically appropriate by a primary care provider.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">"Program" means the Maryland Medical Assistance Program.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">"Program recipient" means an individual who receives benefits under the Program.</section>
    <section prefix="(j)">"Specialty mental health services" means any mental health services other than primary mental health services.</section>
  </text>
</law>
