<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghg" order_by="ghg" level="1">Health - General</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghg-18-215</section_number>
  <catch_line>In addition to any other penalty provided by law, a physician who fails to submit the report require...</catch_line>
  <order_by>215</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In addition to any other penalty provided by law, a physician who fails to submit the report required under &#xA7; 18-204 of this subtitle, on conviction, is subject to a fine not exceeding $10.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A person who violates any provision of &#xA7; 18-202 of this subtitle is guilty of a misdemeanor and on conviction is subject to a fine not exceeding $50.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">In addition to any other penalty provided by law, a physician who fails to submit the report required under &#xA7; 18-201 of this subtitle, on conviction, is subject to a fine not exceeding $100.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A person who violates any provision of &#xA7; 18-205 of this subtitle is guilty of a misdemeanor and on conviction is subject to a fine not exceeding $500.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">A health care provider or any other person, including an officer or employee of a governmental unit, who knowingly and willfully discloses personal identifying health information acquired for the purposes of HIV and AIDS reporting under &#xA7; 18-201.1, &#xA7; 18-202.1, &#xA7; 18-205, or &#xA7; 18-207 of this subtitle to any person who is not authorized to receive personal identifying health information under this subtitle or otherwise in violation of this subtitle is guilty of a misdemeanor and on conviction is subject to a fine not exceeding $1,000 for the first offense and not exceeding $5,000 for each subsequent conviction for a violation of any provision of this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A health care provider or any other person, including an officer or employee of a governmental unit, who knowingly and willfully requests or obtains information on HIV and AIDS developed under &#xA7; 18-201.1, &#xA7; 18-202.1, &#xA7; 18-205, or &#xA7; 18-207 of this subtitle under false pretenses or through deception, on conviction is subject to:<section prefix="(i)">A fine not exceeding $100,000, imprisonment for not more than 5 years, or both; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">If the offense is committed with intent to sell, transfer, or use individually identifiable health information for commercial advantage, personal gain, or malicious harm, a fine not exceeding $250,000, imprisonment for not more than 10 years, or both.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">This subsection does not apply to an officer or employee of a governmental unit that is conducting a criminal investigation.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">A health care provider or any other person who knowingly violates subsection (e) or (f) of this section is liable for actual damages.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">A physician, laboratory, or institution as defined in &#xA7; 18-202.1 of this subtitle that in good faith submits a report or otherwise discloses information in accordance with this subtitle is not liable in any action arising from the disclosure of the information.</section>
  </text>
</law>
