<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghg" order_by="" level="1">Health - General</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghg-8-404</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>404</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Department shall adopt regulations for establishing, operating, and certifying alcohol abuse and drug abuse treatment programs that include:<section prefix="(1)">Procedures for consulting with the Administration to set standards relating to alcohol abuse and drug abuse treatment care and rehabilitation services;</section><section prefix="(2)">Standards relating to environmental and safety requirements concerning physical plant, equipment, and structure;</section><section prefix="(3)">Standards relating to programmatic operations of alcohol and drug abuse treatment, care, and rehabilitation services; and</section><section prefix="(4)">Provisions for denials, suspensions, and revocations of certification.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Department may adopt regulations for certifying individuals providing alcohol abuse and drug abuse treatment.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">An applicant for certification shall submit an application to the Department on the form that the Department requires.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Department shall issue a certificate to an individual or organization providing alcohol abuse and drug abuse treatment, care, and rehabilitation services that meets the Department's certification requirements.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">Before the Department disapproves an application, the Department shall give the applicant an opportunity for a hearing.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">Except as otherwise provided in this subtitle, an individual or organization may not operate or attempt to operate an alcohol abuse and drug abuse treatment program in the State unless certified by the Department.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">An individual or organization who operates an alcohol abuse and drug abuse treatment program in violation of this title is guilty of a misdemeanor.</section>
  </text>
</law>
