<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghg" order_by="" level="1">Health - General</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghg-8-204</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>204</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Director is responsible for carrying out the powers, duties, and responsibilities of the Administration.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">In addition to the powers set forth elsewhere in this title, the Director may:<section prefix="(1)">Within the amounts made available by appropriation, gift, or grant, make any agreement or joint financial arrangement to do or have done anything necessary, desirable, or proper to carry out the purposes of this title; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Within the amounts made available by appropriation, employ a staff.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">In addition to the duties set forth elsewhere in this title, the Director shall:<section prefix="(1)">Adopt regulations to carry out the provisions of this title, including provisions setting reasonable fees for the issuance and renewal of certification for those programs certified to perform medication-assisted treatment;</section><section prefix="(2)">Every 3 years, conduct an assessment of the needs of the State for prevention, diagnosis, and treatment of drug misuse or alcohol misuse that identifies the financial and treatment needs of each jurisdiction and of each drug treatment program operated by the State;</section><section prefix="(3)">Submit each report that the Secretary, Governor, or General Assembly requests;</section><section prefix="(4)">Gather and disseminate statistics and other information on drug misuse and alcohol misuse and drug misuse and alcohol misuse services;</section><section prefix="(5)">Work cooperatively and coordinate with other State agencies and advisory bodies in carrying out the provisions of this title; and</section><section prefix="(6)">Do anything necessary or proper to carry out the scope of this title.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
