<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghg" order_by="ghg" level="1">Health - General</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghg-13-1003</section_number>
  <catch_line>There is a Surveillance and Evaluation Component in the Program....</catch_line>
  <order_by>1003</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">There is a Surveillance and Evaluation Component in the Program.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The purposes of the Surveillance and Evaluation Component are to:<section prefix="(1)">Collect, analyze, and monitor data relating to tobacco use and tobacco use prevention and cessation in the State;</section><section prefix="(2)">Measure and evaluate the results of the Program, including the results of each component of the Program;</section><section prefix="(3)">Conduct a Baseline Tobacco Study, as provided under subsections (c) through (e) of this section; and</section><section prefix="(4)">Conduct a Tobacco Study, as provided under &#xA7; 13-1004 of this subtitle.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">To initiate the Surveillance and Evaluation Component, the Department shall conduct a comprehensive statewide Baseline Tobacco Study as provided under this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Baseline Tobacco Study shall measure:<section prefix="(i)">The number and percentage of individuals under the age of 18 years who smoke or otherwise use tobacco products, both statewide and in each county;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The number and percentage of minority individuals under the age of 18 years who smoke or otherwise use tobacco products, both statewide and in each county;</section><section prefix="(iii)">The number and percentage of individuals who smoke or otherwise use tobacco products, both statewide and in each county;</section><section prefix="(iv)">The number and percentage of minority individuals who smoke or otherwise use tobacco products, both statewide and in each county;</section><section prefix="(v)">The number and percentage of pregnant women who smoke or otherwise use tobacco products, both statewide and in each county;</section><section prefix="(vi)">The number and percentage of households with individuals under the age of 18 years in which at least one household member who is at least 18 years old smokes tobacco products, both statewide and in each county;</section><section prefix="(vii)">The number and percentage of individuals who, within an established amount of time before the start of the Baseline Tobacco Study, started to smoke or otherwise use tobacco products;</section><section prefix="(viii)">The number and percentage of individuals who smoke or otherwise use tobacco on a regular basis and who, within an established amount of time before the start of the Baseline Tobacco Study, voluntarily stopped smoking or otherwise using tobacco products for a significant amount of time, as determined by the Department, both statewide and in each county; and</section><section prefix="(ix)">Any other factor that the Department determines to be important for measuring tobacco use or evaluating whether the Program meets its objectives.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In conducting the Baseline Tobacco Study, the Department may consider any data collected after March 1, 2000 through the administration of the Maryland Adolescent Survey or the Youth Tobacco Survey.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Maryland State Department of Education, county boards of education, and each school selected to participate in the Maryland Adolescent Survey or the Youth Tobacco Survey shall cooperate with the Department in administering the surveys.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Subject to subparagraph (ii) of this paragraph, the Maryland State Department of Education may not discontinue administration of the Maryland Adolescent Survey until after it has submitted a report to the Governor and, subject to &#xA7; 2-1246 of the State Government Article, the General Assembly that states the reason for discontinuing the survey.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">If the Maryland State Department of Education submits a report as provided under subparagraph (i) of this paragraph, it may discontinue the Maryland Adolescent Survey in the first school year that begins after the report has been submitted.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Subject to paragraphs (2) through (4) of this subsection, the Department shall contract with a higher education institution or private entity to conduct the Baseline Tobacco Study.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Department shall issue a request for proposal to select the entity that will conduct the Baseline Tobacco Study.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The request for proposal shall require that any methodology or model that is used by the entity to conduct the Baseline Tobacco Study, any data collected under the Study, and any electronic files, codes, and definitions relating to the Study be provided to the State for use in subsequent studies, regardless of whether the subsequent studies are conducted by the same entity.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The Department may contract with an entity to conduct the Baseline Tobacco Study and one or more biennial tobacco studies as required under &#xA7; 13-1004 of this subtitle.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The Department shall use the criteria established in subparagraph (ii) of this paragraph as a guide in administering the request for proposal process for the Baseline Tobacco Study.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The Department shall give preference to an entity that:<section prefix="1.">Is a Maryland-based vendor;</section><section prefix="2.">Has previous work experience relating to tobacco or health activities;</section><section prefix="3.">Has previous work experience relating to youth and adolescents;</section><section prefix="4.">Demonstrates a capability for innovative activities and use of state-of-the-art technologies;</section><section prefix="5.">Has demonstrated the ability to provide culturally-specific and effective services to targeted minority populations;</section><section prefix="6.">Has previous work experience with the public sector;</section><section prefix="7.">Demonstrates performance in the specific content area for at least 3 years;</section><section prefix="8.">Has previous work experience with rural or urban communities;</section><section prefix="9.">Will maximize the use of State funds through the use of preexisting materials, funding partnerships, and resource matching; and</section><section prefix="10.">Has no history of working for the tobacco industry.</section></section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">On or before January 1, 2001, the Department shall submit a report to the Governor and, subject to &#xA7; 2-1246 of the State Government Article, the General Assembly on the results of the Baseline Tobacco Study.</section>
  </text>
</law>
