<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghg" order_by="" level="1">Health - General</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghg-19-119</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>119</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Commission shall develop and adopt an institution-specific plan to guide possible capacity reduction.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The institution-specific plan shall address:<section prefix="(1)">Accurate bed count data for licensed beds and staffed and operated beds;</section><section prefix="(2)">Cost data associated with all hospital beds and associated services on a hospital-specific basis;</section><section prefix="(3)">Migration patterns and current and future projected population data;</section><section prefix="(4)">Accessibility and availability of beds;</section><section prefix="(5)">Quality of care;</section><section prefix="(6)">Current health care needs, as well as growth trends for such needs, for the area served by each hospital;</section><section prefix="(7)">Hospitals in high growth areas; and</section><section prefix="(8)">Utilization.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">In the development of the institution-specific plan the Commission shall give priority to the conversion of acute capacity to alternative uses where appropriate.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Commission shall use the institution-specific plan in reviewing certificate of need applications for conversion, expansion, consolidation, or introduction of hospital services in conjunction with the State health plan.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If there is a conflict between the State health plan and any rule or regulation adopted by the Commission in accordance with Title 10, Subtitle 1 of the State Government Article to implement an institution-specific plan that is developed for identifying any excess capacity in beds and services, the provisions of whichever plan that is most recently adopted shall control.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Immediately upon adoption of the institution-specific plan the Commission shall begin the process of incorporating the institution-specific plan into the State health plan and shall complete the incorporation within 12 months.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">A State health plan developed or adopted after the incorporation of the institution-specific plan into the State health plan shall include the criteria in subsection (b) of this section in addition to the criteria in &#xA7; 19-118 of this subtitle.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
