<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="ghg" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="19-333" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghg-19-333</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In Part V of this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Affiliate" means:<section prefix="(1)">Each partner of a partnership;</section><section prefix="(2)">Each officer, director, and stockholder who has direct or indirect ownership or control of 10 percent or more of the stock of a corporation; or</section><section prefix="(3)">Each individual who has direct or indirect ownership of 10 percent or more of a nursing home or community program.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Community program" means:<section prefix="(1)">A program which provides residential services and is an alcohol abuse and drug abuse treatment program as defined in &#xA7; 8-403(a) of this article;</section><section prefix="(2)">A program which provides residential services for individuals with a developmental disability as defined in &#xA7; 7-101(d) and (h) of this article;</section><section prefix="(3)">A private group home required to be licensed by the Secretary under &#xA7; 10-517 of this article;</section><section prefix="(4)">A private therapeutic group home for children and adolescents as defined under &#xA7; 10-920 of this article;</section><section prefix="(5)">A private residential treatment center for children and adolescents licensed under &#xA7; 19-307 of this subtitle;</section><section prefix="(6)">A private facility operating living units that house less than 4 persons per unit under &#xA7; 10-902 of this article;</section><section prefix="(7)">A program which provides day habilitation, vocational, or community supported living arrangements services required to be licensed under &#xA7; 7-903 of this article; or</section><section prefix="(8)">A private program that provides outpatient services as set forth in &#xA7; 10-902 of this article.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">"Individual" means a person who is a resident of a nursing home or a community residential program or a person enrolled in a day habilitation or vocational program.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"Nursing home" means a related institution that is classified as a nursing home.</section>
  </text>
</law>
