<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghg" order_by="ghg" level="1">Health - General</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghg-19-701</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated....</catch_line>
  <order_by>701</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Benefit package" means a set of health care services to be provided to a member of a health maintenance organization under a contract that entitles the member to the health care services, whether the services are provided:<section prefix="(1)">Directly by a health maintenance organization; or</section><section prefix="(2)">Through a contract or arrangement with another person.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Commissioner" means the State Insurance Commissioner.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">"Covered service" means a health care service included in the benefit package of the health maintenance organization and rendered to a member or subscriber of the health maintenance organization by:<section prefix="(1)">A provider under contract with the health maintenance organization, when the service is obtained in accordance with the terms of the benefit contract of the member or subscriber; or</section><section prefix="(2)">A noncontracting provider under &#xA7; 19-710.1 of this subtitle, when the service is:<section prefix="(i)">Obtained in accordance with the terms of the benefit contract of the member or subscriber;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Obtained pursuant to a verbal or written referral by:<section prefix="1.">The health maintenance organization of the member or subscriber; or</section><section prefix="2.">A provider under written contract with the health maintenance organization of the member or subscriber; or</section></section><section prefix="(iii)">Preauthorized or otherwise approved either verbally or in writing by:<section prefix="1.">The health maintenance organization of the member or subscriber; or</section><section prefix="2.">A provider under written contract with the health maintenance organization of the member or subscriber.</section></section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"Emergency services" means those health care services that are provided in a hospital emergency facility after the sudden onset of a medical condition that manifests itself by symptoms of sufficient severity, including severe pain, that the absence of immediate medical attention could reasonably be expected by a prudent layperson, who possesses an average knowledge of health and medicine, to result in:<section prefix="(1)">Placing the patient's health in serious jeopardy;</section><section prefix="(2)">Serious impairment to bodily functions; or</section><section prefix="(3)">Serious dysfunction of any bodily organ or part.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Health care services" means services, medical equipment, and supplies that are provided by a provider.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Health care services" includes:<section prefix="(i)">Ambulance services;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Appliances, drugs, medicines, and supplies;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Chiropractic care and services;</section><section prefix="(iv)">Convalescent institutional care;</section><section prefix="(v)">Dental care and services;</section><section prefix="(vi)">Extended care;</section><section prefix="(vii)">Family planning or infertility services;</section><section prefix="(viii)">Health education services;</section><section prefix="(ix)">Home health care or medical social services;</section><section prefix="(x)">Inpatient hospital services;</section><section prefix="(xi)">Laboratory, radiological, or other diagnostic services;</section><section prefix="(xii)">Medical care and services;</section><section prefix="(xiii)">Mental health services;</section><section prefix="(xiv)">Nursing care and services;</section><section prefix="(xv)">Nursing home care;</section><section prefix="(xvi)">Optical care and services;</section><section prefix="(xvii)">Optometric care and services;</section><section prefix="(xviii)">Osteopathic care and services;</section><section prefix="(xix)">Outpatient services;</section><section prefix="(xx)">Pharmaceutical services;</section><section prefix="(xxi)">Physical therapy care and services;</section><section prefix="(xxii)">Podiatric care and services;</section><section prefix="(xxiii)">Preventive medical services;</section><section prefix="(xxiv)">Psychological care and services;</section><section prefix="(xxv)">Rehabilitative services;</section><section prefix="(xxvi)">Surgical care and services;</section><section prefix="(xxvii)">Treatment for alcoholism or drug abuse; and</section><section prefix="(xxviii)">Any other care, service, or treatment of disease or injury, the correction of defects, or the maintenance of the physical and mental well-being of human beings.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">"Health maintenance organization" means any person, including a profit or nonprofit corporation organized under the laws of any state or country, that:<section prefix="(1)">Operates or proposes to operate in this State;</section><section prefix="(2)">Except as provided in &#xA7; 19-703(b) and (f) of this subtitle, provides or otherwise makes available to its members health care services that include at least physician, hospitalization, laboratory, X-ray, emergency, and preventive services, out-of-area coverage, and any other health care services that the Commissioner determines to be available generally on an insured or prepaid basis in the area serviced by the health maintenance organization, and, at the option of the health maintenance organization, may provide additional coverage;</section><section prefix="(3)">Except for any copayment or deductible arrangement, is compensated only on a predetermined periodic rate basis for providing to members the minimum services that are specified in item (2) of this subsection;</section><section prefix="(4)">Assures its subscribers and members, the Commissioner, and the Department that one clearly specified legal and administrative focal point or element of the health maintenance organization has the responsibility of providing the availability, accessibility, quality, and effective use of comprehensive health care services; and</section><section prefix="(5)">Primarily provides services of physicians:<section prefix="(i)">Directly through physicians who are either employees or partners of the health maintenance organization; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">Under arrangements with one or more groups of physicians, who are organized on a group practice or individual practice basis, under which each group:<section prefix="1.">Is compensated for its services primarily on the basis of an aggregate fixed sum or on a per capita basis; and</section><section prefix="2.">Is provided with an effective incentive to avoid unnecessary inpatient use, whether the individual physician members of the group are paid on a fee-for-service or other basis.</section></section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(h)">"Member" means a person who makes a contract or on whose behalf a contract is made with a health maintenance organization for health care services.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">"Provider" means any person, including a physician or hospital, who is licensed or otherwise authorized in this State to provide health care services.</section>
    <section prefix="(j)">"Subscriber" means a person who makes a contract with a health maintenance organization, either directly or through an insurer or marketing organization, under which the person or other designated persons are entitled to the health care services.</section>
  </text>
</law>
