<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghg" order_by="" level="1">Health - General</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghg-20-1405</section_number>
  <catch_line>// EFFECTIVE UNTIL JUNE 30, 2016 PER CHAPTER 3 OF 2012 //...</catch_line>
  <order_by>1405</order_by>
  <text>// EFFECTIVE UNTIL JUNE 30, 2016 PER CHAPTER 3 OF 2012 //<section prefix="(a)">Health Enterprise Zone practitioners that practice in a Health Enterprise Zone may receive:<section prefix="(1)">Tax credits against the State income tax as provided in &#xA7; 10-731 of the Tax - General Article;</section><section prefix="(2)">Loan repayment assistance, as provided for in the application for designation for the Health Enterprise Zone and approved by the Secretary and the Commission under this subtitle;</section><section prefix="(3)">Priority to enter the Maryland Patient Centered Medical Home Program, if the Health Enterprise Zone practitioner meets the standards developed by the Maryland Health Care Commission for entry into the Program; and</section><section prefix="(4)">Priority for the receipt of any State funding available for electronic health records, if feasible and if other standards for receipt of the funding are met.</section></section><section prefix="(b)">A nonprofit community-based organization or a local government agency that applies on behalf of an area for designation as a Health Enterprise Zone may receive grants, as determined by the Commission and the Secretary, to implement actions outlined in the organization's or agency's application to improve health outcomes and reduce health disparities in the Health Enterprise Zone.</section><section prefix="(c)"><section prefix="(1)">A Health Enterprise Zone practitioner may apply to the Secretary for a grant to defray the costs of capital or leasehold improvements to, or medical or dental equipment to be used in, a Health Enterprise Zone.</section><section prefix="(2)">To qualify for a grant under paragraph (1) of this subsection, a Health Enterprise Zone practitioner shall:<section prefix="(i)">Own or lease the health care facility; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Provide health care from that facility.</section></section><section prefix="(3)"><section prefix="(i)">A grant to defray the cost of medical or dental equipment may not exceed the lesser of $25,000 or 50% of the cost of the equipment.</section><section prefix="(ii)">Grants for capital or leasehold improvements shall be for the purposes of improving or expanding the delivery of health care in the Health Enterprise Zone.</section></section></section></text>
</law>
