<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="ghg" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="21-209" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghg-21-209</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In addition to any other ground that may be applicable under &#xA7; 21-207 or &#xA7; 21-208 of this subtitle, a confectionary food product is adulterated if:<section prefix="(1)">It contains any nonnutritive object, except as permitted by the rules and regulations adopted under subsection (b)(1) of this section;</section><section prefix="(2)">It contains any nonnutritive substance other than a safe substance:<section prefix="(i)">That is in or on the confectionery because of some practical functional purpose in the manufacture, packaging, or storing of the confectionery; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">The use of which does not promote deception of the consumer or otherwise result in any adulteration or misbranding in violation of this subtitle; or</section></section><section prefix="(3)">It contains any alcohol:<section prefix="(i)">In excess of 5 percent by volume; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">Derived from anything but flavoring extracts.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If, in the judgment of the Secretary, a nonnutritive object is of practical, functional value to a confectionary food product and its use is not injurious or hazardous to health, the Secretary may adopt a rule or regulation that permits an exception to subsection (a)(1) of this section, regarding nonnutritive objects.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">To avoid or resolve uncertainty, the Secretary may by rule or regulation:<section prefix="(i)">Interpret subsection (a)(2) of this section as that subsection applies to use of a particular nonnutritive substance; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Allow or prohibit the use of the particular nonnutritive substance.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A confectionery that is manufactured or sold that contains between one-half of one percent and 5 percent of alcohol per volume:<section prefix="(1)">May not be sold to individuals under 21 years of age;</section><section prefix="(2)">Shall state on the label that the sale of the product to individuals under 21 years of age is prohibited; and</section><section prefix="(3)">Shall state on the label that the product contains alcohol up to 5 percent per volume.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
