<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghg" order_by="" level="1">Health - General</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghg-10-101</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>101</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this title the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Administration" means the Mental Hygiene Administration.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Admission" means the process by which an individual is accepted as a resident in:<section prefix="(i)">An inpatient facility; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">A Veterans' Administration hospital in this State that provides care or treatment for individuals who have mental disorders.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Admission" includes the physical act of the individual entering the facility or Veterans' Administration hospital.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">"Director" means the Director of Mental Hygiene.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as otherwise provided in this title, "facility" means any public or private clinic, hospital, or other institution that provides or purports to provide treatment or other services for individuals who have mental disorders.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Facility" does not include a Veterans' Administration hospital.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Mental disorder" means a behavioral or emotional illness that results from a psychiatric or neurological disorder.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Mental disorder" includes a mental illness that so substantially impairs the mental or emotional functioning of an individual as to make care or treatment necessary or advisable for the welfare of the individual or for the safety of the person or property of another.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Mental disorder" does not include an intellectual disability.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">"State Advisory Council" means the State Advisory Council on Mental Hygiene.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">"State facility" means a facility that is owned or operated by the Department.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">"Treatment" means any professional care or attention that is given in a facility, private therapeutic group home for children and adolescents, or Veterans' Administration hospital to improve or to prevent the worsening of a mental disorder.</section>
  </text>
</law>
