<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghg" order_by="" level="1">Health - General</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghg-19-336</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>336</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">After the hearing under &#xA7; 19-335 of this subtitle, the court may appoint a receiver for the nursing home or community program or continue the appointment of the receiver made ex parte, if the court finds:<section prefix="(1)">A person is operating the nursing home or community program without a license for it;</section><section prefix="(2)">The nursing home or community program will be closed within 30 days and arrangements to relocate its residents have not been approved by the Secretary;</section><section prefix="(3)">The nursing home or community program or its residents have been abandoned; or</section><section prefix="(4)">A situation, physical condition, practice, or method of operation presents an imminent danger of death or serious mental or physical harm to the individuals.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The court may appoint as receiver any responsible individual other than:<section prefix="(1)">A State employee;</section><section prefix="(2)">An employee of a local government; or</section><section prefix="(3)">The owner or administrator of or other individual with a financial interest in the nursing home or community program or agent of any of those individuals.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Before the receiver takes charge of the nursing home or community program, the receiver shall file a bond with the court.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The bond:<section prefix="(i)">May not exceed the value of the nursing home or community program and its assets; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Shall run to this State for benefit of all persons interested in the faithful performance of the receiver including the individuals.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Unless the court directs otherwise, the receiver may pay the premium of the bond from the income of the nursing home or community program.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Secretary may petition the court to appoint a substitute for a receiver who:<section prefix="(1)">Dies;</section><section prefix="(2)">Has a disability;</section><section prefix="(3)">Has an adverse interest; or</section><section prefix="(4)">Does not make reasonable progress in carrying out the receivership.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
