<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghg" order_by="ghg" level="1">Health - General</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghg-10-624</section_number>
  <catch_line>A peace officer shall take an emergency evaluee to the nearest emergency facility if the peace offic...</catch_line>
  <order_by>624</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A peace officer shall take an emergency evaluee to the nearest emergency facility if the peace officer has a petition under Part IV of this subtitle that:<section prefix="(i)">Has been endorsed by a court within the last 5 days; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">Is signed and submitted by a physician, psychologist, clinical social worker, licensed clinical professional counselor, clinical nurse specialist in psychiatric and mental health nursing, psychiatric nurse practitioner, licensed clinical marriage and family therapist, health officer or designee of a health officer, or peace officer.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">After a peace officer takes the emergency evaluee to an emergency facility, the peace officer need not stay unless, because the emergency evaluee is violent, a physician asks the supervisor of the peace officer to have the peace officer stay.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A peace officer shall stay until the supervisor responds to the request for assistance. If the emergency evaluee is violent, the supervisor shall allow the peace officer to stay.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">If a physician asks that a peace officer stay, a physician shall examine the emergency evaluee as promptly as possible.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If the petition is executed properly, the emergency facility shall accept the emergency evaluee.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Within 6 hours after an emergency evaluee is brought to an emergency facility, a physician shall examine the emergency evaluee, to determine whether the emergency evaluee meets the requirements for involuntary admission.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Promptly after the examination, the emergency evaluee shall be released unless the emergency evaluee:<section prefix="(i)">Asks for voluntary admission; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">Meets the requirements for involuntary admission.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">An emergency evaluee may not be kept at an emergency facility for more than 30 hours.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
