<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghg" order_by="ghg" level="1">Health - General</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghg-8-403</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this section, "alcohol abuse and drug abuse treatment program":...</catch_line>
  <order_by>403</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, "alcohol abuse and drug abuse treatment program":<section prefix="(1)">Means any individual or organization that provides treatment, care, or rehabilitation for individuals who show the effects of drug abuse or alcohol abuse, and represents or advertises itself as an alcohol abuse or drug abuse treatment program; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Includes a program or facility that is owned or operated by this State or any of its political subdivisions.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Except as otherwise provided in this section, an alcohol abuse and drug abuse treatment program shall be certified by the Department before program services may be provided in this State.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">This section does not apply to:<section prefix="(1)">A health professional licensed under the Health Occupations Article who is treating patients within the scope of the professional's practice and who does not advertise the practice as an alcohol abuse or drug abuse program;</section><section prefix="(2)">Alcoholics Anonymous, Narcotics Anonymous, transitional housing programs, or other similar organizations, if the organization holds meetings or provides support services to help individuals who show the effects of drug abuse or alcohol abuse; or</section><section prefix="(3)">An employees' assistance program of a business entity.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Unless requested, the certification requirements of this section do not apply to a hospital as defined in &#xA7; 19-301 of this article accredited by the Joint Commission on Accreditation of Hospitals with a separately accredited alcohol and drug abuse program.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">An intermediate care facility, alcoholic (type C or D), shall be certified as an intermediate care alcohol abuse and drug abuse treatment facility.</section>
  </text>
</law>
