<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="ghg" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="19-735" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghg-19-735</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Any foreign health maintenance organization with a certificate of authority to operate a health maintenance organization in this State may become a domestic health maintenance organization of this State by complying with all of the requirements of the law relating to the formation and organization of a domestic health maintenance organization and by designating its principal place of business at a place in this State. On becoming a domestic health maintenance organization, the health maintenance organization shall be entitled to certificates and licenses to transact business in this State issued to domestic health maintenance organizations, and shall be given recognition in all respects as a health maintenance organization formed under the laws of this State as of the date of authorization as a health maintenance organization in its original domiciliary state, district, territory, commonwealth, or possession of the United States of America, and shall be subject to the authority and jurisdiction of this State.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The certificate of authority, insurance producers' appointments, rates, and other forms which the Commissioner allows which are in existence at the time any foreign health maintenance organization with a certificate of authority to operate a health maintenance organization in this State transfers its corporate domicile to this State or to any other state by merger, consolidation, or any other lawful method shall continue in full force and effect on transfer if the health maintenance organization at all times retains a certificate of authority in this State.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">All outstanding subscriber contracts of a transferring health maintenance organization shall remain in full force and effect and need not be endorsed as to the new name of the health maintenance organization or its new domiciliary and location unless so ordered by the Commissioner.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A transferring health maintenance organization may file new contract forms with the Commissioner on or before the effective date of the transfer, or may use any existing contract form previously filed with the Commissioner with appropriate endorsements if allowed by and under such conditions as approved by the Commissioner.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">A foreign health maintenance organization transferring its domicile to another state shall notify the Commissioner of the details of the proposed transfer, and shall file promptly any resulting amendments to corporate documents and other items on file with the Commissioner.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
