<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghg" order_by="ghg" level="1">Health - General</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghg-10-616</section_number>
  <catch_line>A certificate for involuntary admission of an individual under Part III of this subtitle shall:...</catch_line>
  <order_by>616</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A certificate for involuntary admission of an individual under Part III of this subtitle shall:<section prefix="(i)">Be based on the personal examination of the physician or psychologist who signs the certificate; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Be in the form that the Secretary adopts, by rule or regulation.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The rules and regulations shall require the form to include:<section prefix="(i)">A diagnosis of a mental disorder of the individual;</section><section prefix="(ii)">An opinion that the individual needs inpatient care or treatment; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">An opinion that admission to a facility or Veterans' Administration hospital is needed for the protection of the individual or another.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A certificate may not be used for admission if the examination on which the certificate is made was done:<section prefix="(1)">More than 1 week before the certificate is signed; or</section><section prefix="(2)">More than 30 days before the facility or the Veterans' Administration hospital receives the application for admission.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A certificate may not be used for an admission if the physician or psychologist who signed the certificate:<section prefix="(1)">Has a financial interest, through ownership or compensation, in a proprietary facility and admission to that proprietary facility is sought for the individual whose status is being certified; or</section><section prefix="(2)">Is related, by blood or marriage, to the individual or to the applicant.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
