<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghg" order_by="" level="1">Health - General</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghg-13-1004</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>1004</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Beginning in fiscal year 2007 and in every second year thereafter, the Department shall conduct a Tobacco Study which shall measure the same factors that are set forth in &#xA7; 13-1003(c) of this subtitle and use the same methodology or model that was used for the Baseline Tobacco Study.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">To carry out the evaluation and surveillance functions of this subtitle, the Department may conduct any other tobacco study measuring the factors set forth in &#xA7; 13-1003(c) of this subtitle and using a methodology or model that is consistent with but need not be identical to that used to conduct the Baseline Tobacco Study.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Subject to paragraphs (2) through (4) of this subsection, the Department shall contract with a higher education institution or private entity to conduct the Biennial Tobacco Study.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Department shall issue a request for proposal to select the entity that will conduct the Biennial Tobacco Study.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Department may contract with an entity to conduct one or more biennial tobacco studies.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The Department shall use the criteria established in &#xA7; 13-1003(e)(5) of this subtitle as a guide in administering the request for proposal process.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">On or before September 1 of each even-numbered fiscal year, beginning in fiscal year 2008, the Department shall submit a report to the Governor and, subject to &#xA7; 2-1246 of the State Government Article, the General Assembly on the results of the Biennial Tobacco Study.</section>
  </text>
</law>
