<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="ghg" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="15-102.4" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghg-15-102.4</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Each managed care organization shall be actuarially sound.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Except as otherwise provided in this section, the surplus that a managed care organization is required to have shall be paid in full.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">A managed care organization shall have an initial surplus that exceeds the liabilities of the managed care organization by at least $1,500,000.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In consultation with the Secretary, the Insurance Commissioner may adjust the initial surplus requirement for a managed care organization that is not licensed as a health maintenance organization. In determining whether to make an adjustment under this paragraph, the Commissioner shall consider:<section prefix="(i)">The proposed capitation level that would be received by the managed care organization under a contract with the Department under this subtitle;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The proposed range of benefits to be provided under a contract with the Department under this subtitle;</section><section prefix="(iii)">The existence of any commitment by the Secretary to designate funds over and above the proposed capitation where the designated funds:</section><section prefix="(iv)">The availability of the money held in trust by the Secretary to pay claims in case of impairment or insolvency of the managed care organization.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Notwithstanding subsection (a)(2)(ii) of this section, a managed care organization shall have an initial surplus that exceeds liabilities by at least $1,250,000. If a managed care organization has an initial surplus that is at least $1,250,000 but less than $1,500,000, prior to approval, the Department shall designate funds under paragraph (1)(iii) of this subsection sufficient to provide an initial surplus of at least $1,500,000.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Each managed care organization shall maintain a surplus that exceeds the liabilities of the managed care organization in the amount that is at least equal to the greater of $750,000 or 5 percent of the subscription charges earned during the prior calendar year as recorded in the annual report filed by the managed care organization with the Commissioner.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">No managed care organization shall be required to maintain a surplus in excess of a value of $3,000,000.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">For the protection of the managed care organization's enrollees and creditors, the applicant shall deposit and maintain in trust with the State Treasurer $100,000 in cash or government securities of the type described in &#xA7; 5-701(b) of the Insurance Article.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)"/>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Each managed care organization shall comply with risk based capital standards in accordance with regulations adopted by the Insurance Commissioner under &#xA7; 4-311 of the Insurance Article.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">If there is money held in trust under this section, on or before June 1 of each year, the Secretary shall submit to the General Assembly, in accordance with &#xA7; 2-1246 of the State Government Article, a report on:<section prefix="(1)">The number of managed care organizations for which the Secretary has designated money to be held in trust under this section; and</section><section prefix="(2)">The amount of money held in trust by the Secretary that has been paid out in cases of insolvency or impairment of managed care organizations.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
