<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghg" order_by="ghg" level="1">Health - General</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghg-7-507</section_number>
  <catch_line>Subject to the limitations in this section, a petition for the release of an individual who is held ...</catch_line>
  <order_by>507</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Subject to the limitations in this section, a petition for the release of an individual who is held under this subtitle from a State residential center may be filed, at any time, by:<section prefix="(1)">The individual; or</section><section prefix="(2)">Any person who has a legitimate interest in the welfare of the individual.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The petition shall be filed in a circuit court for the county:<section prefix="(1)">Where the individual resides or resided at the time of the admission; or</section><section prefix="(2)">Where the State residential center is located.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Administration shall be the respondent in a petition under this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The petition shall be in the form and contain the information that the Maryland Rules require.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">If the petitioner requests trial by jury, the trial shall be held with a jury as in a civil action at law.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The trier of fact shall determine:<section prefix="(1)">Whether the individual has an intellectual disability;</section><section prefix="(2)">Whether for adequate habilitation, the individual needs residential services; and</section><section prefix="(3)">Whether there is a less restrictive setting in which the needed services can be provided that is available to the individual or will be available to the individual within a reasonable time.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The court shall remand the individual to the custody of the State residential center, if the trier of fact determines that:<section prefix="(i)">The individual has an intellectual disability;</section><section prefix="(ii)">For adequate habilitation the individual needs residential services; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">There is no less restrictive setting in which those services needed can be provided and which is available to the individual or will be available to the individual within a reasonable time.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The court shall order that appropriate less restrictive services be offered to an individual, if the trier of fact determines that:<section prefix="(i)">The individual has an intellectual disability;</section><section prefix="(ii)">For adequate habilitation the individual needs residential services; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">There is a less restrictive setting in which the service can be provided, and which from evidence submitted by the Director is available or will be available to the individual within a reasonable time.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The individual shall be released from the State residential center, if the trier of fact determines that:<section prefix="(i)">The individual does not have an intellectual disability;</section><section prefix="(ii)">For adequate habilitation the individual does not need residential services; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">There is a less restrictive setting in which the needed services can be provided that is available to the individual or will be available to the individual within a reasonable time.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(h)">Any party may appeal from a decision on the petition as in any other civil case.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">Appropriate records of the proceeding under this section shall be made a permanent part of the individual's record.</section>
    <section prefix="(j)">
      <section prefix="(1)">After a determination on the merits of a petition under this section, a court may not hear a later petition for the individual within 1 year after that determination, unless:<section prefix="(i)">The petition is verified, and alleges an improvement in the condition of the individual with an intellectual disability after the determination; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">The court, after review of the verified petition, determines that the matter should be reopened.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If the matter is reopened, the petition shall be heard as provided in this section.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
