<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghg" order_by="" level="1">Health - General</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghg-19-114</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>114</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this Part II of this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Ambulatory surgical facility" means any center, service, office, facility, or office of one or more health care practitioners or a group practice, as defined in &#xA7; 1-301 of the Health Occupations Article, that:<section prefix="(i)">Has two or more operating rooms;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Operates primarily for the purpose of providing surgical services to patients who do not require overnight hospitalization; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Seeks reimbursement from payors as an ambulatory surgical facility.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">For purposes of this subtitle, the office of one or more health care practitioners or a group practice with two operating rooms may be exempt from the certificate of need requirements under this subtitle if the Commission finds, in its sole discretion, that:<section prefix="(i)">A second operating room is necessary to promote the efficiency, safety, and quality of the surgical services offered; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">The office meets the criteria for exemption from the certificate of need requirements as an ambulatory surgical facility in accordance with regulations adopted by the Commission.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Certificate of need" means a certification of public need issued by the Commission under this Part II of this subtitle for a health care project.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Health care facility" means:<section prefix="(i)">A hospital, as defined in &#xA7; 19-301 of this title;</section><section prefix="(ii)">A limited service hospital, as defined in &#xA7; 19-301 of this title;</section><section prefix="(iii)">A related institution, as defined in &#xA7; 19-301 of this title;</section><section prefix="(iv)">An ambulatory surgical facility;</section><section prefix="(v)">An inpatient facility that is organized primarily to help in the rehabilitation of disabled individuals, through an integrated program of medical and other services provided under competent professional supervision;</section><section prefix="(vi)">A home health agency, as defined in &#xA7; 19-401 of this title;</section><section prefix="(vii)">A hospice, as defined in &#xA7; 19-901 of this title;</section><section prefix="(viii)">A freestanding medical facility, as defined in &#xA7; 19-3A-01 of this title; and</section><section prefix="(ix)">Any other health institution, service, or program for which this Part II of this subtitle requires a certificate of need.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Health care facility" does not include:<section prefix="(i)">A hospital or related institution that is operated, or is listed and certified, by the First Church of Christ Scientist, Boston, Massachusetts;</section><section prefix="(ii)">For the purpose of providing an exemption from a certificate of need under &#xA7; 19-120 of this subtitle, a facility to provide comprehensive care constructed by a provider of continuing care, as defined in &#xA7; 10-401 of the Human Services Article, if:<section prefix="1.">Except as provided under &#xA7; 19-123 of this subtitle, the facility is for the exclusive use of the provider's subscribers who have executed continuing care agreements and paid entrance fees that are at least equal to the lowest entrance fee charged for an independent living unit or an assisted living unit before entering the continuing care community, regardless of the level of care needed by the subscribers at the time of admission;</section><section prefix="2.">The facility is located on the campus of the continuing care community; and</section><section prefix="3.">The number of comprehensive care nursing beds in the community does not exceed:</section></section><section prefix="(iii)">Except for a facility to provide kidney transplant services or programs, a kidney disease treatment facility, as defined by rule or regulation of the United States Department of Health and Human Services;</section><section prefix="(iv)">Except for kidney transplant services or programs, the kidney disease treatment stations and services provided by or on behalf of a hospital or related institution; or</section><section prefix="(v)">The office of one or more individuals licensed to practice dentistry under Title 4 of the Health Occupations Article, for the purposes of practicing dentistry.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"Health care practitioner" means any individual who is licensed, certified, or otherwise authorized under the Health Occupations Article to provide health care services.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">"Health service area" means an area of this State that the Governor designates as appropriate for planning and developing of health services.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">"Local health planning agency" means the health department of a jurisdiction or a body designated by the local health department to perform health planning functions.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">"State health plan" means the State health plan for facilities and services.</section>
  </text>
</law>
