<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghg" order_by="" level="1">Health - General</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghg-19-128</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>128</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section, "aggrieved party" means:<section prefix="(i)">An interested party who presented written comments on the application to the Commission and who would be adversely affected by the decision of the Commission on the project; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">The Secretary.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The grounds for appeal by the Secretary shall be that the decision is inconsistent with the State health plan or adopted standards.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A decision of the Commission shall be the final decision for purposes of judicial review.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A request for a reconsideration will stay the final decision of the Commission for purposes of judicial review until a decision is made on the reconsideration.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">An aggrieved party may not appeal a final decision of the Commission to the board of review but may take a direct judicial appeal within 30 days of the final decision of the Commission.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Commission is a necessary party to an appeal at all levels of the appeal.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">In the event of an adverse decision that affects its final decision, the Commission may apply within 30 days by writ of certiorari to the Court of Appeals for review where:<section prefix="(1)">Review is necessary to secure uniformity of decision, as where the same statute has been construed differently by 2 or more judges; or</section><section prefix="(2)">There are other special circumstances that render it desirable and in the public interest that the decision be reviewed.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
