<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="ghg" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="18-404" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghg-18-404</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Employee" means an individual employed full-time or part-time directly, through contract with another entity, or as an independent contractor, by a related institution.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Related institution" has the meaning provided under &#xA7; 19-301 of this article.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">"Medically contraindicated" means that a medical treatment is potentially detrimental to the health of the individual intended to be treated.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Subject to subsection (e) of this section, each related institution in the State shall immunize residents against the influenza virus and pneumococcal disease.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Subject to subsection (e) of this section, each related institution in the State shall immunize employees against the influenza virus.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Before an immunization under this section is administered, the related institution shall obtain written consent to administer the immunization from:<section prefix="(i)">The resident or employee receiving the immunization; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">The legal guardian of the resident receiving the immunization.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Each related institution shall conduct the immunizations required under subsection (b) of this section:<section prefix="(1)">In accordance with the recommendations established by the Advisory Committee on Immunization Process of the United States Centers for Disease Control and Prevention that are in effect at the time the related institution conducts the immunizations; and</section><section prefix="(2)">By December 1 of each year that the immunization is required.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A related institution that accepts an individual as a new resident or accepts an individual as a new employee after December 1 but before April 1 shall:<section prefix="(1)">Determine the individual's status for immunization as required under subsection (b) of this section; and</section><section prefix="(2)">If necessary, provide or arrange for an immunization as required under subsection (b) of this section.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">A resident or employee is not required to receive a vaccine under this section if:<section prefix="(1)">The vaccine is medically contraindicated for the resident or employee;</section><section prefix="(2)">The vaccine is against the resident's or employee's religious beliefs; or</section><section prefix="(3)">After being fully informed by the related institution of the health risks associated with not receiving a vaccine, the resident or employee refuses the vaccine.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Each related institution shall document the annual immunization against influenza virus and immunization against pneumococcal disease received by each resident in the resident's medical record.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">Each related institution shall document the annual immunization against influenza virus received by each employee in the employee's personnel file.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If a resident or employee refuses to be immunized as required under subsection (b) of this section, the related institution shall document the refusal and the reason for the refusal.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">Each related institution shall:<section prefix="(1)">Notify each prospective resident and each prospective employee of the immunization requirements of this section and request that the resident or employee agree to be immunized in accordance with subsection (b)(3) of this section; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Make available to all residents and employees of the related institution educational and informational materials relating to immunization against influenza virus and immunization against pneumococcal disease.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
