<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghg" order_by="ghg" level="1">Health - General</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghg-21-339</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this section, "repack crab meat" means to take or remove crab meat from any container or package,...</catch_line>
  <order_by>339</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, "repack crab meat" means to take or remove crab meat from any container or package, when the crab meat has been picked from a crab at another location, and place that crab meat in another container or package.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Each container of crab meat shall be marked plainly with the information required by this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Each container of crab meat shall be marked by:<section prefix="(i)">Embossing;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Imprinting;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Lithography; or</section><section prefix="(iv)">Subject to paragraph (2) of this subsection, any other method that the Department approves.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Unless approved by the Secretary, a container of crab meat may not be stamped with ink.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Each container of crab meat shall be marked with:<section prefix="(i)">A description of the product in the container;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Subject to the requirements of paragraph (2) of this subsection, the name and address of the picking plant or the distributor;</section><section prefix="(iii)">If a chemical is added to the crab meat, a statement to that effect;</section><section prefix="(iv)">The license number of the crab meat plant preceded by the State abbreviation applicable to the picking plant;</section><section prefix="(v)">The net weight of the contents of the container; and</section><section prefix="(vi)">Any other information that the Department requires.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If a container of crab meat is marked with the name of the distributor, the name of the distributor shall be:<section prefix="(i)">Preceded by the words "packed for" or "distributed by"; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">Followed by the word "distributor".</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">A person may not put any false or misleading statement on a container of crab meat.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A person may not repack crab meat or change crab meat containers or container lids with the intent to sell the crab meat except as provided by the Department.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">A person may not possess more than 12 empty crab meat containers or container lids unless the person:<section prefix="1.">Is a manufacturer of containers or lids;</section><section prefix="2.">Is a licensed crab meat packer and the containers or lids are the same as used by the packer in the ordinary course of business;</section><section prefix="3.">Has removed the crab meat from the containers and lids for consumption on the premises; or</section><section prefix="4.">Is in possession of the containers or lids as provided for by the Department.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">Possession of empty containers or crab meat container lids in violation of this section shall be presumptive evidence of intent to repack crab meat in violation of this Part VI of this subtitle.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">Possession of crab meat containers or crab meat container lids from which the crab meat has been consumed or cooked for consumption and which have been properly disposed of may not constitute presumptive evidence of intent to repack or change crab meat containers for sale.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, each container of crab meat sold in the State containing crab meat picked from a crab, packed, repacked, or processed outside of the United States shall be marked with the words "This product contains crab meat from (name of country of origin)".</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The marking required by paragraph (1) of this subsection shall be prominently displayed in letters not smaller than 12-point type on the principal display panel of the container so as to be easily read by the consumer.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
