<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="ghg" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="7-1101" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghg-7-1101</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Unless licensed by the Administration under this title, a person may not provide the following services to an individual with developmental disability or to a recipient of individual support services, as defined in &#xA7; 7-901 of this title:<section prefix="(i)">Day habilitation services;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Residential services;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Services coordination;</section><section prefix="(iv)">Vocational services;</section><section prefix="(v)">More than 1 family support service, as defined in &#xA7; 7-701 of this title;</section><section prefix="(vi)">More than 1 individual support service; and</section><section prefix="(vii)">More than 1 community supported living arrangements service, as defined in &#xA7; 7-709 of this title.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Administration, the Administration's designee, or an agency that receives public funds may not place an individual in a residential group home or other facility that is not operating in compliance with applicable State licensing laws.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A person who provides services in violation of this section is guilty of a misdemeanor and on conviction is subject to a fine not exceeding $10,000.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">An employee, officer, or director of a provider of services under this title or any other person who knowingly participates in a violation of this section is guilty of a misdemeanor and on conviction is subject to a fine not exceeding $5,000, or imprisonment not exceeding 1 year, or both.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">In addition to any other penalties specified in this section, an individual who is admitted or held against the individual's will by a person who is providing services without a license may recover civil damages from that person and from any other person who knowingly participates in the admission or detention.</section>
  </text>
</law>
