<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="ghg" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="17-2A-09" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghg-17-2A-09</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Secretary may deny a license to an applicant or suspend, revoke, or limit a license or the authority of a licensee to offer or perform tests that a license sets forth, if the forensic laboratory or its director or other personnel fail to meet the standards and requirements of this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If the Secretary finds that a forensic laboratory  licensed under this subtitle no longer meets the standards and  requirements of this subtitle, the Secretary may:<section prefix="(i)">Revoke the license of the forensic laboratory;  or</section><section prefix="(ii)">Suspend the license of the forensic  laboratory.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If a deficiency exists, the Secretary may:<section prefix="(i)">Impose a directed plan of correction;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Regularly inspect the forensic laboratory to  assure compliance with the directed plan of correction; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">Limit the testing authorized by the license.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">If the Secretary finds that a forensic laboratory  provided erroneous or questionable test results, the Secretary  may order the laboratory to provide written notification to:<section prefix="(1)">The person or agency that ordered the tests;</section><section prefix="(2)">The Office of the Public Defender or counsel of  record; and</section><section prefix="(3)">The State's Attorney.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A State's Attorney who receives notification from a  laboratory under subsection (c) of this section shall notify the  victim of the criminal act or the victim's representative of the  erroneous or questionable test results.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">A forensic laboratory that fails to comply with an order issued by the Secretary under subsection (c) of this section is subject to a civil penalty of up to $1,000 for each day of noncompliance after the deadline for compliance stated in the  Secretary's order, not to exceed a maximum penalty of $50,000.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">Except as otherwise provided in the Administrative Procedure Act, before the Secretary denies, suspends, or revokes a license, or imposes a civil penalty under this section, the Secretary shall give the applicant or licensee notice and an opportunity for a hearing.</section>
  </text>
</law>
