<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="ghg" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="4-226" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghg-4-226</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">A person may not fail or refuse to execute and deliver a certificate of birth, death, or fetal death required by this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A person may not willfully provide false information for entry or willfully enter false information on a certificate of birth, death, or fetal death.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A person may not fail to provide a Social Security number or willfully provide a false Social Security number to the clerk of court under &#xA7; 4-208(g) of this subtitle.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Except as authorized by this subtitle, a person may not willfully alter any certificate, certified copy of a certificate, or other certified statement that relates to a birth, death, fetal death, or marriage registered under this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A person may not willfully use or attempt to use, with the intention to deceive, any certificate of birth or certified copy of a record of birth knowing that the certificate or certified copy:<section prefix="(i)">Was issued on a record that is wholly or partly false; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">Relates to the birth of another individual.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A person may not willfully and knowingly provide a certificate of birth or a certified copy of a record of birth to another person with the intention that it be used by that person to deceive.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">Without authorization, a person may not produce, reproduce, or distribute a blank certificate or other form that the Secretary uses to register or certify facts that relate to a birth, death, fetal death, or marriage.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">A person may not willfully use or attempt to use a photocopy of a birth, death, fetal death, or marriage certificate for any fraudulent or deceptive purpose.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">A person who has access to the birth, death, or fetal death records in the custody of the Secretary or an agent of the Secretary may not willfully communicate to anyone known to the person to be unauthorized any fact recorded on any birth, death, or fetal death certificate.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">A person may not willfully transport or accept for transportation, dissection, or other disposition a body without a burial-transit permit, as provided in this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">A person may not willfully:<section prefix="(1)">Violate any provision of this subtitle;</section><section prefix="(2)">Neglect to perform any duty imposed by this subtitle; or</section><section prefix="(3)">Violate any rule or regulation adopted under this subtitle.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
