<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="ghg" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="13-2701" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghg-13-2701</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Behavioral health services" means mental health services or alcohol and substance abuse services.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Crisis services" means temporary services designed to address and stabilize a severe behavioral health problem and to avoid an emergency situation.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Crisis services" includes hotlines, in-home support, and residential crisis services.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">"Maryland Defense Force" means the military force established under &#xA7; 13-501 of the Public Safety Article.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"Maryland National Guard" means the Maryland Army National Guard and Maryland Air National Guard.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">"Service coordination" means a service designed to coordinate and provide assistance in obtaining access to behavioral health services.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">"Uniformed services" has the meaning stated in 10 U.S.C. &#xA7; 101.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">"Veteran" means a Maryland resident who served on active duty in the uniformed services of the United States, other than for training, and was discharged or released under conditions other than dishonorable.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">"Web-based resource program" means an interactive Web-based communication medium that:<section prefix="(1)">Allows individuals to access comprehensive information, advocacy, and other resources regarding public and private behavioral health services, crisis and emergency services, and early intervention and prevention programs; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Enables the public and private health care communities to work together to address the problems related to providing and obtaining access to behavioral health services.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
