<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghg" order_by="ghg" level="1">Health - General</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghg-15-901</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated....</catch_line>
  <order_by>901</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Independent home care provider" means an individual who:<section prefix="(1)">Provides home care services that are directly reimbursed by the State or a fiscal intermediary functioning on behalf of the State, and not by an agency or business that employs employees or refers independent contractors as home care providers, under:<section prefix="(i)">The Medicaid Waiver for Older Adults that is jointly administered by the Department and the Department of Aging as established under &#xA7; 15-132 of this title, or any successor program;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The Medicaid Personal Care Program under the State Medical Assistance Program, or any successor program;</section><section prefix="(iii)">The Living at Home Waiver Program under Subtitle 8 of this title, or any successor program; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">The In-Home Aide Service Program administered by the Department of Human Resources, or any successor program;</section></section><section prefix="(2)">Is not employed or referred by an agency or business that employs employees or refers independent contractors as home care providers;</section><section prefix="(3)">Contracts directly with a program participant for home care services; and</section><section prefix="(4)">Provides home care services to a program participant personally and does not subcontract with any other party to provide the services to a program participant.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Provider organization" means an organization that:<section prefix="(i)">Includes independent home care providers; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Has as one of its purposes the representation of independent home care providers in their relations with the State.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Provider organization" does not include an agency or business that employs employees or refers independent contractors as home care providers.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
