<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="ghg" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="18-303" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghg-18-303</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Secretary shall establish and promote a statewide public information campaign on diethylstilbestrol (DES).</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The public information campaign shall:<section prefix="(i)">Try to reach each individual who has been exposed to diethylstilbestrol and each offspring of those individuals, to encourage the individuals and offspring to seek medical care for the prevention or treatment of cancer that results from the exposure to diethylstilbestrol; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Include any other matter that the Secretary considers appropriate.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Secretary shall expand existing cancer screening programs to detect any cancer or other abnormal condition that results from exposure to diethylstilbestrol, including breast, cervical, testicular, or vaginal cancer or vaginal adenosis.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Secretary shall establish a program to train physicians, physician's assistants, and nurses in:<section prefix="(1)">Identifying individuals who have been exposed to diethylstilbestrol;</section><section prefix="(2)">Diagnosing and treating any cancer or other abnormal condition that results from the exposure; and</section><section prefix="(3)">Preventing exposure to diethylstilbestrol.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">To carry out this section, the Secretary:<section prefix="(1)">On request, shall receive the help of or information from any agency of this State or of a political subdivision; and</section><section prefix="(2)">May contract for any necessary services.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Secretary may set a sliding fee schedule for services provided under this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">This State shall reimburse a provider of screening and diagnosis under this section in the amount that the screening and diagnosis exceeds the total of the fee charged for the service and of all third party payments for the service.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
