<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="ghg" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="19-350" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghg-19-350</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This section applies only to:<section prefix="(i)">Related institutions as defined in &#xA7; 19-301 of this subtitle; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Hospitals as defined in &#xA7; 19-301 of this subtitle.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Nothing in this section shall apply to charges for services that are set pursuant to &#xA7; 16-201 of this article.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">On request of a patient made before or during treatment, a hospital shall provide to the patient a written estimate of the total charges for the hospital services, procedures, and supplies that reasonably are expected to be provided and billed to the patient by the hospital.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The written estimate shall state clearly that it is only an estimate and actual charges could vary.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">A hospital may restrict the availability of a written estimate to normal business office hours.</section>
        <section prefix="(iv)">This paragraph does not apply to emergency services.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Within 30 days after discharge of an individual from a hospital, the hospital shall give the individual a summary financial statement that clearly describes:<section prefix="(i)">The total charges incurred;</section><section prefix="(ii)">If readily ascertainable, a summary of the total charges under the major services categories, including:</section><section prefix="(iii)">If applicable, the name of the primary and secondary insurer to which a claim has been or will be filed on the individual's behalf;</section><section prefix="(iv)">That charges for services provided by a physician are not included in the total hospital charges and are billed separately; and</section><section prefix="(v)">The individual's right to request an itemized statement of the account within 1 year of receipt of the summary statement.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Within 30 days after an individual's request as provided under paragraph (2)(v) of this subsection, the hospital shall provide the individual a statement of the account that:<section prefix="(i)">Is itemized; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Describes briefly but clearly each item and the amount charged for it.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Unless a related institution contracts with its residents to provide care for an all-inclusive preestablished fee, on demand made within 90 days after service is provided to a resident, the related institution shall give the resident or representative of the resident a financial statement that:<section prefix="(i)">Is itemized;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Describes briefly but clearly each item and the amount charged for it; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Identifies the payor to whom a claim has been forwarded.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A related institution may not be required to give a resident more than 1 itemized statement in any 90-day period.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">On demand made within 30 days after payment of any charge for an individual, a hospital or related institution shall give the individual or representative of the individual a financial statement that:<section prefix="(i)">Is itemized; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Describes briefly but clearly each item and the amount charged for it.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A hospital or related institution is subject to a fine of $300 if it fails to:<section prefix="(i)">Comply with this subsection; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">Give the individual or representative a reasonable written explanation for any delay in complying with this subsection.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">A hospital or related institution may not demand or accept final payment or recover for money unless the hospital or related institution has given the financial statements required under this section.</section>
  </text>
</law>
