<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghg" order_by="ghg" level="1">Health - General</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghg-7-508</section_number>
  <catch_line>At the direction of the Secretary, an individual who has been admitted under this subtitle shall be ...</catch_line>
  <order_by>508</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">At the direction of the Secretary, an individual who has been admitted under this subtitle shall be released from a State residential center if:<section prefix="(1)">The individual is not an individual with an intellectual disability;</section><section prefix="(2)">The individual is an individual with an intellectual disability but does not need residential services; or</section><section prefix="(3)">There is an available, less restrictive kind of service that is consistent with the welfare and safety of the individual.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">At the direction of the Secretary, any individual who has been admitted under this subtitle may be released conditionally from a State residential center for individuals with an intellectual disability, if, in the judgment of the Secretary, the individual:<section prefix="(i)">Would be cared for properly by the individual or another person; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Would not endanger the individual or the person or property of another.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Secretary may set the conditions for release that the Secretary considers reasonable. The conditions may relate to:<section prefix="(i)">The duration of the release;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Treatment during release; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">Placement under supervised care in an approved setting.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">An individual with an intellectual disability released conditionally is considered to be held by the State residential center from which the individual was released.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Each determination of any release of an individual, whether full or conditional, including a summary of the reasons for the determination, shall be made a permanent part of the individual's record.</section>
  </text>
</law>
