<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghg" order_by="ghg" level="1">Health - General</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghg-19-1410</section_number>
  <catch_line>By January 1, 2001, a nursing home shall develop and implement a quality assurance program....</catch_line>
  <order_by>1410</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">By January 1, 2001, a nursing home shall develop and implement a quality assurance program.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">By September 1, 2000, each nursing home shall designate a qualified individual to coordinate and manage the nursing home's quality assurance program.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Each nursing home shall establish a quality assurance committee and shall include at least the following members:<section prefix="(i)">The nursing home administrator;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The director of nursing;</section><section prefix="(iii)">The medical director;</section><section prefix="(iv)">A social worker;</section><section prefix="(v)">A licensed dietitian; and</section><section prefix="(vi)">A geriatric nursing assistant.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The quality assurance committee shall:<section prefix="(i)">Meet at least monthly;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Maintain records of all quality assurance activities;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Keep records of committee meetings that shall be available to the Department during any on-site visit; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">Prepare monthly reports that shall be presented to the ombudsman, the resident's council, and the family council.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The quality assurance committee for a nursing home shall review and approve annually the quality assurance plan for the nursing home.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">Each nursing home shall establish a written quality assurance plan that:<section prefix="(i)">Includes procedures for concurrent review for all residents;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Provides criteria that routinely monitors nursing care including medication administration, prevention of decubitus ulcers, dehydration and malnutrition, nutritional status and weight loss or gain, accidents and injuries, unexpected deaths, changes in mental or psychological status, and any other data necessary to monitor quality of care;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Includes methods to identify and correct problems; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">Is readily available to nursing home residents and their families, guardians, or surrogate decision makers.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(6)">The quality assurance plan shall be submitted to the Department by January 1, 2001, and at the time of license renewal.</section>
      <section prefix="(7)">The nursing home administrator shall take appropriate remedial actions based on the recommendations of the nursing home's quality assurance committee.</section>
      <section prefix="(8)">The Secretary may not require the quality assurance committee to disclose the records and the reports prepared by the committee except as necessary to assure compliance with the requirements of this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(9)">If the Department determines that a nursing home is not implementing its quality assurance program effectively and that quality assurance activities are inadequate, the Department may impose appropriate sanctions on the nursing home to improve quality assurance including mandated employment of specified quality assurance personnel.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Each nursing home shall display on each floor of the nursing home a notice that explains the current ratio of licensed personnel to residents and unlicensed personnel to residents.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The notice shall be:<section prefix="(i)">Posted in a location that is visible and accessible to residents and their family or guardians and any potential consumers; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">On a form provided by the Department.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
