<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghg" order_by="" level="1">Health - General</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghg-18-207</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>207</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"HIV/AIDS case report" means an abstract of the medical record of a patient diagnosed with human immunodeficiency virus or acquired immunodeficiency syndrome which contains:<section prefix="(i)">Reasonably obtained patient demographic information, including name and risk factors;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Relevant information on the:<section prefix="1.">Initial diagnosis;</section><section prefix="2.">Treatment and referral; and</section><section prefix="3.">Clinical condition; and</section></section><section prefix="(iii)">Facility and other provider identification information.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Report" means:<section prefix="(i)">A laboratory examination report for HIV or CD 4+ count as required by &#xA7; 18-205 of this subtitle;</section><section prefix="(ii)">A report for HIV or AIDS as required by &#xA7; 18-201.1, &#xA7; 18-202,  or &#xA7; 18-202.1 of this subtitle; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">An HIV/AIDS case report.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">"Designated anonymous HIV test site" means an HIV counseling and testing site approved by the Department of Health and Mental Hygiene as a site where a patient may have an anonymous HIV test.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except for a designated anonymous HIV test site, a facility or office that orders a test for HIV and receives a test result that documents the presence of HIV as defined by the CDC laboratory criteria shall, upon the Secretary's request,  make available to the Secretary, or an agent of the Secretary, the information necessary to compile an HIV/AIDS case report.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A report or information assembled or obtained under this section:<section prefix="(i)">Is confidential and subject to Title 4, Subtitle 1 of this article; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Is not a medical record under Title 4, Subtitle 3 of this article, but is subject to the confidentiality requirements of Title 4, Subtitle 1 of this article.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">This subsection does not apply to a disclosure by the Secretary to another governmental agency performing its lawful duties pursuant to State or federal law where the Secretary determines that the agency to which the information is disclosed will maintain the confidentiality of the disclosure.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The report and any proceedings, records, or files relating to the reports required under this section are not discoverable and are not admissible in evidence in any civil action.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
