<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghg" order_by="" level="1">Health - General</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghg-18-109</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>109</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Authorized user" means:<section prefix="(i)">A child care facility;</section><section prefix="(ii)">A health care provider;</section><section prefix="(iii)">A health insurer;</section><section prefix="(iv)">A health maintenance organization;</section><section prefix="(v)">An institution of higher learning;</section><section prefix="(vi)">A local health department;</section><section prefix="(vii)">A long-term care facility;</section><section prefix="(viii)">A managed care organization;</section><section prefix="(ix)">A nonprofit health service plan;</section><section prefix="(x)">A patient;</section><section prefix="(xi)">A school;</section><section prefix="(xii)">A school-based health center;</section><section prefix="(xiii)">In the case of a minor child, a parent or guardian; and</section><section prefix="(xiv)">Any other user designated by the Secretary.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"ImmuNet" means a computerized information and reminder system to:<section prefix="(i)">Improve the timely and appropriate delivery of immunizations;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Provide a coordinated network for reminder notices when immunizations are due;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Provide and collect information to be shared by authorized users; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">Provide a quality indicator for the insurers' health care provider practices and public health purposes.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">"Refusal to permit" means the right of an individual or the parent or guardian of a minor to prevent disclosure to authorized users of individual identifiable information that was reported to ImmuNet.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">There is an ImmuNet program in the Department.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Subject to subsection (d) of this section, an authorized user may use the information in ImmuNet for the following purposes:<section prefix="(1)">To provide coordinated immunization services, including sending reminder notices to individuals who need immunizations;</section><section prefix="(2)">To obtain an individual immunization history;</section><section prefix="(3)">To identify geographic areas or population groups that are under-immunized;</section><section prefix="(4)">To compile aggregate data and distribute statistical reports on the status of immunizations in geographic areas and population groups;</section><section prefix="(5)">To assist in the management of State and local immunization programs;</section><section prefix="(6)">To monitor the safety of vaccines;</section><section prefix="(7)">To assess compliance with immunization requirements by monitoring admissions to schools, institutions of higher learning, and child care facilities; and</section><section prefix="(8)">For any other purpose that the Secretary deems necessary to prevent the spread of communicable diseases.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">An individual, or the parent or guardian of a minor child who has received an immunization, may refuse to permit disclosure of confidential information collected by ImmuNet, to an authorized user.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If the individual or the parent or guardian of a minor child does not want the release of the individual's or child's confidential information, the individual or the parent or guardian of a minor child shall complete a "refusal to permit" form, provided by the Department, to be returned to the Department.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Secretary shall distribute "refusal to permit" forms to each health care provider who gives immunizations.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The Department shall:<section prefix="(i)">Develop brochures about ImmuNet that:<section prefix="1.">Describe the benefits of ImmuNet for authorized users;</section><section prefix="2.">Describe privacy protections in ImmuNet;</section><section prefix="3.">Notify an individual of the right to refuse to permit disclosure to an authorized user;</section><section prefix="4.">Notify an individual that the individual may correct any inaccurate information;</section><section prefix="5.">Provide a list of addresses where an individual may obtain a form to request the correction or removal of inaccurate information from ImmuNet;</section><section prefix="6.">Explain the right of an individual who has received an immunization to have the individual's personal information kept confidential;</section><section prefix="7.">Describe the kind of information collected and retained by ImmuNet about an individual who receives an immunization;</section><section prefix="8.">Describe who has access to the information in ImmuNet; and</section><section prefix="9.">Describe how the information is used by ImmuNet; and</section></section><section prefix="(ii)">Distribute copies of the brochure to each health care provider who administers immunizations.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(5)">Prior to administering immunizations to a newborn child, each birth hospital or birthing center shall distribute the form and the brochure described in paragraphs (2) and (4) of this subsection to the parent of a newborn child.</section>
      <section prefix="(6)">A health care provider who administers an immunization, or the agent of the health care provider, shall:<section prefix="(i)">Provide the individual with a copy of the form and the brochure described in paragraphs (2) and (4) of this subsection; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Notify the individual or the parent or guardian of a minor of the right to refuse to disclose to ImmuNet.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">Subject to the provisions of subsection (d) of this section, information for ImmuNet may be obtained from:<section prefix="(1)">Any records owned or controlled by the Department, including Medicaid records, clinic records, and vital records;</section><section prefix="(2)">Any authorized user; and</section><section prefix="(3)">Any other source of information authorized by the Secretary for use.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">Authorized users may not use the information in ImmuNet:<section prefix="(1)">To release or disclose information in ImmuNet that an individual has refused to disclose;</section><section prefix="(2)">To solicit new patients or clients; or</section><section prefix="(3)">For any other purpose unless authorized by the Secretary.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A local health department may operate a local immunization system.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A local health department operating a local immunization system shall be subject to the provisions of subsections (c) through (f) of this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A local health department is required to submit information maintained in a local immunization system to ImmuNet in accordance with regulations adopted by the Secretary.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(h)">An authorized user who in good faith discloses or does not disclose information to ImmuNet is not liable in any cause of action arising from the disclosure or nondisclosure of that information.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">An authorized user, including an officer or employee of a governmental unit, who knowingly and willfully violates subsection (f) of this section is guilty of a misdemeanor and on conviction is subject to a fine not exceeding $1,000 for the first offense and not exceeding $5,000 for each subsequent offense.</section>
    <section prefix="(j)">If the confidentiality of records of Maryland citizens is protected, the Secretary may enter into collaborative agreements with other states for the purpose of sharing information about immunizations.</section>
    <section prefix="(k)">The Secretary shall adopt regulations to implement this section, including regulations specifying:<section prefix="(1)">The type and kind of information to be collected;</section><section prefix="(2)">Procedures for protecting the confidentiality of information in ImmuNet;</section><section prefix="(3)">The permissible use of information compiled by ImmuNet; and</section><section prefix="(4)">Standards for maintaining security and reliability of collected information in the system.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
