<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghg" order_by="" level="1">Health - General</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghg-17-2A-12</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>12</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Governor shall establish a Forensic Laboratory Advisory Committee to advise the Secretary on matters relating to the implementation of the provisions of this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Advisory Committee shall consist of the following 10 members:<section prefix="(1)">The Director of the Laboratories Administration in  the Department, or the Director's designee;</section><section prefix="(2)">The Director of the Office of Health Care Quality  in the Department, or the Director's designee; and</section><section prefix="(3)">The following members, appointed by the Governor:<section prefix="(i)">One from the American Society for Clinical  Laboratory Science;</section><section prefix="(ii)">One from the University of Maryland School of  Medicine, Department of Medical Research and Technology;</section><section prefix="(iii)">One from the American Association for  Laboratory Accreditation;</section><section prefix="(iv)">One from the American Academy of Forensic  Sciences;</section><section prefix="(v)">One from the American Society of Crime  Laboratory Directors/Laboratory Accreditation Board; and</section><section prefix="(vi)">Three directors of forensic laboratories in  the State, including:<section prefix="1.">One from a forensic laboratory operated  by the State;</section><section prefix="2.">One from a forensic laboratory operated  by a county; and</section><section prefix="3.">One from a forensic laboratory operated  by a municipal corporation.</section></section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The term of an appointed member is 3 years.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The terms of appointed members are staggered as  required by the terms provided for appointed members of the  Advisory Committee on October 1, 2007.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Governor shall designate the chair of the Advisory  Committee.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">A majority of the members serving on the Advisory  Committee represents a quorum to conduct business.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">A member of the Advisory Committee may not receive  compensation but is entitled to reimbursement for expenses under  the Standard State Travel Regulations, as provided in the State  budget.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">The Department shall provide staff for the Advisory Committee.</section>
  </text>
</law>
