<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghg" order_by="ghg" level="1">Health - General</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghg-24-601</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated....</catch_line>
  <order_by>601</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Facility" means:<section prefix="(1)">A public community mental health facility, addiction facility, or developmental disabilities facility that is wholly owned by and operated under the authority of a county or a municipal corporation, or both; or</section><section prefix="(2)">A nonprofit community mental health facility, addiction facility, or developmental disabilities facility that is wholly owned by and operated under the authority of a nonprofit organization.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Nonprofit organization" means:<section prefix="(1)">A bona fide religious organization, no part of the earnings of which inures to the benefit of any individual or is used for any purpose other than the maintenance and operation of the facility, the purchase of equipment to be used in the facility, or the expansion of the facility; or</section><section prefix="(2)">An organization:<section prefix="(i)">That is chartered as a nonprofit corporation and classified by the Internal Revenue Service as nonprofit; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">No part of the earnings of which inures to the benefit of any individual or is used for any purpose other than the maintenance and operation of the facility, the purchase of equipment to be used in the facility, or the expansion of the facility.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">"Wholly owned" includes leased, if:<section prefix="(1)"><section prefix="(i)">The lease is for a minimum term of 30 years following project completion; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">The lease agreement extends the right of purchase to the lessee; and</section></section><section prefix="(2)"><section prefix="(i)">The lessor consents to the recording, in the land records of the political subdivision in which the facility is located, of a notice of the State's right of recovery, as provided under &#xA7; 24-606 of this subtitle; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">The lease agreement is with the State for a State-owned building or State-owned property.</section></section></section>
  </text>
</law>
