<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghg" order_by="" level="1">Health - General</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghg-18-903</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>903</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In accordance with procedures to be adopted by the Department, the Secretary, in consultation with health care facilities, may require health care facilities to develop and implement contingency plans addressing:<section prefix="(i)">Staff training needs;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Stockpiling of equipment, medication, and supplies necessary to address a catastrophic health emergency;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Treatment and decontamination protocols;</section><section prefix="(iv)">The coordination of services with other public and private entities; and</section><section prefix="(v)">Any other area that the Secretary determines is necessary to assist in the early detection and treatment of an individual exposed to a deadly agent.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">To the extent feasible, the procedures to be adopted by the Department under paragraph (1) of this subsection shall be consistent with accreditation requirements of the Joint Commission on Accreditation of Healthcare Organizations.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">After consulting with the appropriate licensing board, the Secretary:<section prefix="(1)">Shall publish protocols to assist health care practitioners in developing plans to respond to a catastrophic health emergency; and</section><section prefix="(2)">May, if necessary, require health care practitioners to implement the plans developed under item (1) of this subsection.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Secretary shall coordinate with the health occupations boards to develop a process to license, certify, or credential both licensed health care practitioners and out-of-state health care practitioners who may be needed to respond to a catastrophic health emergency.</section>
  </text>
</law>
