<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghg" order_by="ghg" level="1">Health - General</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghg-4-212</section_number>
  <catch_line>This section does not apply to a fetal death....</catch_line>
  <order_by>212</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">This section does not apply to a fetal death.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A certificate of death regardless of age of decedent shall be filled out and signed by:<section prefix="(i)">The medical examiner, if the medical examiner takes charge of the body; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">If the medical examiner does not take charge of the body, the physician or nurse practitioner who last attended the deceased.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The medical examiner, physician, or nurse practitioner shall fill in only the following information on the certificate of death:<section prefix="(i)">The name of the deceased.</section><section prefix="(ii)">The cause of death and medical certification.</section><section prefix="(iii)">The date and hour of death.</section><section prefix="(iv)">The place where death occurred.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Any other information that is required on the certificate of death regardless of age of decedent shall be filled in:<section prefix="(i)">By the person who has charge of the body; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">If the State Anatomy Board has charge of the body, by the person who last had charge of the body before it was sent to the State Anatomy Board.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The medical certification shall be completed within 24 hours after receipt of the death certificate by the physician or nurse practitioner in charge of the patient's care for the illness or condition which resulted in death, except when inquiry is required by the medical examiner.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">In the absence or inability of the attending physician or nurse practitioner or with the attending physician's or nurse practitioner's approval, the certificate may be completed by:<section prefix="(i)">The attending physician's associate;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The chief medical officer or designee of the institution in which death occurred; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">The physician who performed an autopsy upon the decedent, provided the individual has access to the medical history of the case and death is due to natural causes.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(6)">The person completing the cause of death and medical certification shall attest to the accuracy by signature or by an approved electronic process.</section>
      <section prefix="(7)">The funeral director or person acting as the funeral director shall in all cases obtain the medical certification from the person responsible for its completion or obtain assurance that the medical certification has been provided to the Secretary by an approved electronic process.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Each individual concerned with carrying out this subtitle promptly shall notify the medical examiner if:<section prefix="(1)">The deceased was not under treatment by a physician or nurse practitioner during the terminal illness;</section><section prefix="(2)">The cause of death is unknown; or</section><section prefix="(3)">The individual considers any of the following conditions to be the cause of death or to have contributed to the death:<section prefix="(i)">An accident, including a fall with a fracture or other injury.</section><section prefix="(ii)">Homicide.</section><section prefix="(iii)">Suicide.</section><section prefix="(iv)">Other external manner of death.</section><section prefix="(v)">Alcoholism.</section><section prefix="(vi)">Criminal or suspected criminal abortion.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If, within 24 hours after taking charge of a body, the medical examiner has not determined the cause of death, the medical examiner shall enter "investigation pending" in the cause of death section of the death certificate.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">As soon as the medical examiner determines the cause of death, the medical examiner shall send to the Secretary a report of the cause of death, for entry on the certificate.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A physician or nurse practitioner who fills out a certificate of death shall give it or transmit it by approved electronic media, including facsimile, to the mortician within 24 hours after the death occurred.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A medical examiner who fills out a certificate of death shall give it or transmit it by approved electronic media, including facsimile, to the mortician within 24 hours after the medical examiner took charge of the body.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If a death occurs on a common carrier in the United States and the body is removed from the carrier in this State, the death shall be registered in this State, and the place where it is first removed shall be considered the place of death. When a death occurs on a common carrier while in international waters or air space or in a foreign country or its air space and the body is first removed from the carrier in this State, the death shall be registered in this State, but the certificate shall show the actual place of death insofar as can be determined.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The individual in charge or the owner of the common carrier or a designee shall file a certificate of death within 24 hours after the body is removed from the carrier.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">If the death occurred under any of the conditions or circumstances set forth in subsection (c) of this section, the medical examiner shall be notified.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">A mortician who obtains a certificate of death under this section shall file the certificate within 72 hours after the death.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as authorized under this subtitle, an individual who has a duty to fill out and sign a certificate of death may not execute more than one certificate for a death.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The attending physician, the nurse practitioner, or a medical examiner who takes charge of a body may file a replacement death certificate if a correction that the physician, the nurse practitioner, or medical examiner authorizes cannot be entered legibly on the original certificate.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
