<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghg" order_by="" level="1">Health - General</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghg-19-207</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>207</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In addition to the powers set forth elsewhere in this subtitle, the Commission may:<section prefix="(1)">Adopt rules and regulations to carry out the provisions of this subtitle;</section><section prefix="(2)">Create committees from among its members;</section><section prefix="(3)">Appoint advisory committees, which may include individuals and representatives of interested public or private organizations;</section><section prefix="(4)">Apply for and accept any funds, property, or services from any person or government agency;</section><section prefix="(5)">Make agreements with a grantor or payor of funds, property, or services, including an agreement to make any study, plan, demonstration, or project;</section><section prefix="(6)">Publish and give out any information that relates to the financial aspects of health care and is considered desirable in the public interest; and</section><section prefix="(7)">Subject to the limitations of this subtitle, exercise any other power that is reasonably necessary to carry out the purposes of this subtitle.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">In addition to the duties set forth elsewhere in this subtitle, the Commission shall:<section prefix="(1)">Adopt rules and regulations that relate to its meetings, minutes, and transactions;</section><section prefix="(2)">Keep minutes of each meeting;</section><section prefix="(3)">Prepare annually a budget proposal that includes the estimated income of the Commission and proposed expenses for its administration and operation;</section><section prefix="(4)">Within a reasonable time after the end of each facility's fiscal year or more often as the Commission determines, prepare from the information filed with the Commission any summary, compilation, or other supplementary report that will advance the purposes of this subtitle;</section><section prefix="(5)">Periodically participate in or do analyses and studies that relate to:<section prefix="(i)">Health care costs;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The financial status of any facility; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">Any other appropriate matter;</section></section><section prefix="(6)">On or before October 1 of each year, submit to the Governor, to the Secretary, and, subject to &#xA7; 2-1246 of the State Government Article, to the General Assembly an annual report on the operations and activities of the Commission during the preceding fiscal year, including:<section prefix="(i)">A copy of each summary, compilation, and supplementary report required by this subtitle;</section><section prefix="(ii)">An update on the status of the State's Medicare waiver;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Budget information regarding the Health Services Cost Review Commission Fund, including:<section prefix="1.">Any balance remaining in the Fund at the end of the previous fiscal year; and</section><section prefix="2.">The percentage of the total annual costs of the Commission that is represented by the balance remaining in the Fund at the end of the previous fiscal year;</section></section><section prefix="(iv)">A summary of the Commission's role in hospital quality of care activities, including information about the status of any pay for performance initiatives; and</section><section prefix="(v)">Any other fact, suggestion, or policy recommendation that the Commission considers necessary;</section></section><section prefix="(7)">Oversee and administer the Maryland Trauma Physician Services Fund in conjunction with the Maryland Health Care Commission; and</section><section prefix="(8)">In consultation with the Maryland Health Care Commission, annually publish each acute care hospital's severity-adjusted average charge per case for the 15 most common inpatient diagnosis-related groups.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Commission shall set deadlines for the filing of reports required under this subtitle.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Commission may adopt rules or regulations that impose penalties for failure to file a report as required.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The amount of any penalty under paragraph (2) of this subsection may not be included in the costs of a facility in regulating its rates.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Except for privileged medical information, the Commission shall make:<section prefix="(1)">Each report filed and each summary, compilation, and report required under this subtitle available for public inspection at the office of the Commission during regular business hours; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Each summary, compilation, and report available to any agency on request.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Commission may contract with a qualified, independent third party for any service necessary to carry out the powers and duties of the Commission.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Unless permission is granted specifically by the Commission, a third party hired by the Commission may not release, publish, or otherwise use any information to which the third party has access under its contract.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
