<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghg" order_by="" level="1">Health - General</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghg-21-308</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>308</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, "on-farm home processing facility" means a home or domestic kitchen located on an individual's farm that manufactures and processes foods for commercial sale.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">For any license issued for which the authority to conduct a program under this subtitle has been delegated to a county health department:<section prefix="(i)">A county governing body or the Mayor and City Council of Baltimore City may and the Anne Arundel County Council shall provide for a license fee schedule based on the anticipated cost of licensing, inspecting, and regulating food establishments and may provide for exemptions from the license fee schedule; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">All license fees shall be paid to the local health department or chief financial officer of the county governing body or Baltimore City.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Except in Anne Arundel County, Baltimore City, Montgomery County, and Prince George's County, a license fee under this subsection may not exceed $70 for a seasonal food processing operation that:<section prefix="(i)">Uses only food that is grown on the property of the licensee; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Is in operation for not more than a 3-month continuous period in the calendar year.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A seasonal food processing operation may obtain a food establishment license for a fee of $70 under paragraph (2) of this subsection only twice in a calendar year.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">An on-farm home processing facility may obtain an on-farm home processing plant license for a fee established in regulations.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">An on-farm home processing facility that obtains an on-farm home processing plant license may manufacture or process only foods provided for in regulations of the Department.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A license or permit is not required to deliver prepackaged foods to fill an order of a customer.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">For any other food establishment license, the Secretary shall establish a license fee in accordance with &#xA7; 2-104 of this article.</section>
  </text>
</law>
