<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="ghg" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="20-113" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghg-20-113</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Before a physician treats any patient for any form of breast cancer, the physician shall educate the patient of alternative methods of treatment that may be medically practicable.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Department of Health and Mental Hygiene shall:<section prefix="(1)">Provide a standardized written summary in layman's language that:<section prefix="(i)">Lists all effective methods of treatment for breast cancer that may be medically practicable including surgical, radiological, chemotherapeutic, and combinations of those treatments; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Describes the advantages, disadvantages, risks, and procedures associated with each method of treatment listed;</section></section><section prefix="(2)">Update the standardized written summary annually;</section><section prefix="(3)">Distribute the standardized written summary to each hospital, clinic, and physician's office and other facility that performs treatments of breast cancer.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A physician satisfies the requirements of subsection (a) of this section if:<section prefix="(1)">The physician provides a breast cancer patient with the standardized written summary described in subsection (b) of this section in language that the patient understands;</section><section prefix="(2)">The patient receives the standardized written summary within 5 days of the start of the treatment for breast cancer; and</section><section prefix="(3)">The patient signs a statement provided by the Department of Health and Mental Hygiene acknowledging the receipt of the standardized written summary.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">This section does not apply if the attending physician certifies that:<section prefix="(1)">Treatment for breast cancer occurred within 5 days of the physician informing the patient of the diagnosis; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Treatment within this period of time was necessary to save the life of the patient.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">A physician who violates any provision of subsection (a) of this section is subject to the provisions of &#xA7; 14-404(a)(27) of the Health Occupations Article.</section>
  </text>
</law>
