<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghg" order_by="ghg" level="1">Health - General</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghg-15-801</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated....</catch_line>
  <order_by>801</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Agency-provider model" means a method of providing community attendant services and supports for a consumer by a personal assistant who is:<section prefix="(1)">Employed by a provider agency; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Supervised and evaluated by the consumer.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Attendant services and supports" means any of the following services for a consumer, which are certified as necessary by a health care professional:<section prefix="(1)">Dressing;</section><section prefix="(2)">Preparing food and assisting with eating;</section><section prefix="(3)">Bathing and personal hygiene;</section><section prefix="(4)">Assisting with routine bodily functions, including bowel and urinary care;</section><section prefix="(5)">Moving into, out of, or turning in bed;</section><section prefix="(6)">Laundering and other clothing care; and</section><section prefix="(7)">Cleaning house and performing other services of daily care, including shopping and transportation, that the consumer and the Department request.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">"Community attendant services and supports" means attendant services and supports provided to a consumer:<section prefix="(1)">Under a plan of services that is:<section prefix="(i)">Based on an assessment of the consumer's functional need; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Approved by the consumer or the consumer's representative; and</section></section><section prefix="(2)">Under an agency-provider model or consumer-directed model.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"Consumer" means an eligible individual who receives community attendant services and supports.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">"Eligible individual" means an individual who is eligible for the Program under &#xA7; 15-803 of this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">"Functional need" means the need for attendant services and supports based on the abilities and limitations of the consumer, regardless of medical diagnosis or category of disability.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">"Personal assistant" means an individual who directly provides attendant services and supports.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">"Program" means the Living at Home Waiver Program.</section>
    <section prefix="(j)">"Representative" means a parent, family member, guardian, advocate, or authorized representative of an individual.</section>
  </text>
</law>
