<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghg" order_by="ghg" level="1">Health - General</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghg-22-202</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this section, "caustic or corrosive substance" means:...</catch_line>
  <order_by>202</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section, "caustic or corrosive substance" means:<section prefix="(i)">Hypochlorous acid, either free or combined, and any compound or mixture that contains hypochlorous acid in a concentration so as to yield 10 percent or more by weight of available chlorine;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Potassium hydroxide and any compound or mixture that contains, in a concentration of 10 percent or more, free or chemically unneutralized potassium hydroxide, including caustic potash and vienna paste;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Sodium hydroxide and any compound or mixture that contains, in a concentration of 10 percent or more, free or chemically unneutralized sodium hydroxide, including caustic soda and lye; or</section><section prefix="(iv)">Ammonia water and any compound or mixture that yields, in a concentration of 5 percent or more, free or chemically uncombined ammonia, including ammonium hydroxide and hartshorn.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">In this section, "caustic or corrosive substance" does not include:<section prefix="(i)">Calx chlorinata;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Bleaching powder; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">Chloride of lime.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A person may not sell, exchange, receive, hold, pack, or display or offer for sale or exchange any caustic or corrosive substance for household use unless the container of the caustic or corrosive substance meets the labeling requirements of subsection (c) of this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">In addition to any other requirement of law, the container of any caustic or corrosive substance shall bear a plainly written, conspicuous label that includes:<section prefix="(1)">The common name of the caustic or corrosive substance;</section><section prefix="(2)">The name and business address of the manufacturer, packer, seller, or distributor;</section><section prefix="(3)">Directions for treatment in case of accidental personal injury from the caustic or corrosive substance, except on shipping containers used for shipment by manufacturers or wholesalers for other than household use; and</section><section prefix="(4)">The word "Poison":<section prefix="(i)">Parallel with the main body of print on the label;</section><section prefix="(ii)">On a plain, clear background of a distinctly contrasting color; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Printed in uncondensed gothic capital letters of a size that is:<section prefix="1.">Not less than 24 point; or</section><section prefix="2.">If there is no other print that is 24 point or larger, not smaller than the largest type on the label.</section></section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A person who violates any provision of this section is guilty of a misdemeanor and on conviction is subject to a fine not exceeding $100.</section>
  </text>
</law>
