<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghg" order_by="" level="1">Health - General</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghg-10-1403</section_number>
  <catch_line>** CONTINGENCY - NOT IN EFFECT - CHAPTER 371 OF 2002 **...</catch_line>
  <order_by>1403</order_by>
  <text>** CONTINGENCY - NOT IN EFFECT - CHAPTER 371 OF 2002 **<section prefix="(a)">The Crisis Response System shall include:<section prefix="(1)">A crisis communication center in each jurisdiction or region to provide:<section prefix="(i)">A single point of entry to the Crisis Response System;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Coordination with the local core service agency, police, emergency medical service personnel, and mental health providers; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Services that may include:<section prefix="1.">A hotline for suicide prevention and crisis intervention;</section><section prefix="2.">A telephone service for mental health information, referral, and assistance;</section><section prefix="3.">Triage for initial assessment and referral;</section><section prefix="4.">Referral to treatment, family and peer support groups, and other services as needed;</section><section prefix="5.">Follow-up for up to 1 month;</section><section prefix="6.">Coordination of disaster mental health teams, critical incident stress management, and maintenance of an on-call system for these services;</section><section prefix="7.">A community crisis bed and hospital bed registry, including a daily tally of empty beds;</section><section prefix="8.">Transportation coordination, ensuring transportation of patients to urgent appointments or to emergency psychiatric facilities; and</section><section prefix="9.">Linkage to 911 emergency systems and other telephone systems providing public or social services;</section></section></section><section prefix="(2)">Emergency services including:<section prefix="(i)">Mobile crisis teams to provide assessments, crisis intervention, treatment, follow-up, and referral to urgent care, and to arrange appointments for individuals to obtain public mental health services;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Urgent care; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Emergency psychiatric services;</section></section><section prefix="(3)">Follow-up services including:<section prefix="(i)">Mobile treatment teams to provide outreach services on location;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Individualized family intervention teams; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Residential crisis services;</section></section><section prefix="(4)">Community awareness promotion and training programs; and</section><section prefix="(5)">An evaluation of outcomes of services through an annual survey by the Administration of consumers and family members who have received services from the Crisis Response System.</section></section><section prefix="(b)">The Crisis Response System services shall be implemented as determined by the core service agency serving each jurisdiction.</section><section prefix="(c)">An advance directive for mental health services under &#xA7; 5-602.1 of this article shall apply to the delivery of services under this subtitle.</section><section prefix="(d)">This subtitle may not be construed to affect petitions for emergency evaluations under &#xA7; 10-622 of this title.</section></text>
</law>
