<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghg" order_by="" level="1">Health - General</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghg-5-311</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>311</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Office of the Chief Medical Examiner shall keep complete records on each medical examiner's case.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The records shall be indexed properly and include:<section prefix="(i)">The name, if known, of the deceased;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The place where the body was found;</section><section prefix="(iii)">The date, cause, and manner of death; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">All other available information about the death.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The original report of the medical examiner who investigates a medical examiner's case and the findings and conclusions of any autopsy shall be attached to the record of the medical examiner's case.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Chief Medical Examiner or, if the Chief Medical Examiner is absent or cannot act, the Deputy Chief Medical Examiner or an assistant medical examiner, and each deputy medical examiner promptly shall deliver to the State's Attorney for the county where the body was found a copy of each record that relates to a death for which the medical examiner considers further investigation advisable. A State's Attorney may obtain from the office of a medical examiner a copy of any record or other information that the State's Attorney considers necessary.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this subsection, "record":<section prefix="(i)">Means the result of an external examination of or an autopsy on a body; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Does not include a statement of a witness or other individual.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A record of the Office of the Chief Medical Examiner or any deputy medical examiner, if made by the medical examiner or by anyone under the medical examiner's direct supervision or control, or a certified transcript of that record, is competent evidence in any court in this State of the matters and facts contained in it.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Office of the Chief Medical Examiner shall charge a reasonable fee for reports as specified in a schedule of fees defined in the regulations of the Office of the Chief Medical Examiner.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A deputy medical examiner may keep any fee collected by the deputy medical examiner.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
