<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghg" order_by="" level="1">Health - General</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghg-19-130</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>130</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Fund" means the Maryland Trauma Physician Services Fund.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Maryland Trauma Specialty Referral Centers" means:<section prefix="(i)">The Johns Hopkins Health System Burn Program;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The Eye Trauma Center at the Wilmer Eye Institute at The Johns Hopkins Hospital; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">The Curtis National Hand Center at Union Memorial Hospital.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">"Rehabilitation hospital" means a facility classified as a special rehabilitation hospital as described in &#xA7; 19-307 of this title that is affiliated with a trauma center by common ownership.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">
        <section prefix="(i)">"Trauma center" means a facility designated by the Maryland Institute for Emergency Medical Services Systems as:<section prefix="1.">The State primary adult resource center;</section><section prefix="2.">A Level I trauma center;</section><section prefix="3.">A Level II trauma center;</section><section prefix="4.">A Level III trauma center;</section><section prefix="5.">A pediatric trauma center; or</section><section prefix="6.">The Maryland Trauma Specialty Referral Centers.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">"Trauma center" includes an out-of-state pediatric trauma center that has entered into an agreement with the Maryland Institute for Emergency Medical Services Systems.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(6)">"Trauma physician" means a physician who provides care in a trauma center or in a rehabilitation hospital to trauma patients on the State trauma registry as defined by the Maryland Institute for Emergency Medical Services Systems.</section>
      <section prefix="(7)">"Uncompensated care" means care provided by a trauma physician to a trauma patient on the State trauma registry who:<section prefix="(i)">Has no health insurance, including Medicare Part B coverage;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Is not eligible for medical assistance coverage; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Has not paid the trauma physician for care provided by the trauma physician, after documented attempts by the trauma physician to collect payment.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">There is a Maryland Trauma Physician Services Fund.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The purpose of the Fund is to subsidize the documented costs:<section prefix="(i)">Of uncompensated care incurred by a trauma physician in providing trauma care to a trauma patient on the State trauma registry;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Of undercompensated care incurred by a trauma physician in providing trauma care to an enrollee of the Maryland Medical Assistance Program who is a trauma patient on the State trauma registry;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Incurred by a trauma center to maintain trauma physicians on-call as required by the Maryland Institute for Emergency Medical Services Systems; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">Incurred by the Commission and the Health Services Cost Review Commission to administer the Fund and audit reimbursement requests to assure appropriate payments are made from the Fund.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Commission and the Health Services Cost Review Commission shall administer the Fund.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The Fund is a special, nonlapsing fund that is not subject to &#xA7; 7-302 of the State Finance and Procurement Article.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">Interest on and other income from the Fund shall be separately accounted for and credited to the Fund, and are not subject to &#xA7; 6-226(a) of the State Finance and Procurement Article.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Fund consists of motor vehicle registration surcharges paid into the Fund in accordance with &#xA7; 13-954(b)(2) of the Transportation Article.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Disbursements from the Fund shall be made in accordance with a methodology established jointly by the Commission and the Health Services Cost Review Commission to calculate costs incurred by trauma physicians and trauma centers that are eligible to receive reimbursement under subsection (b) of this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Fund shall transfer to the Department of Health and Mental Hygiene an amount sufficient to fully cover the State's share of expenditures for the costs of undercompensated care incurred by a trauma physician in providing trauma care to an enrollee of the Maryland Medical Assistance Program who is a trauma patient on the State trauma registry.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The methodology developed under paragraph (1) of this subsection shall:<section prefix="(i)">Take into account:<section prefix="1.">The amount of uncompensated care provided by trauma physicians;</section><section prefix="2.">The amount of undercompensated care attributable to the treatment of Medicaid enrollees in trauma centers;</section><section prefix="3.">The cost of maintaining trauma physicians on-call;</section><section prefix="4.">The number of patients served by trauma physicians in trauma centers;</section><section prefix="5.">The number of Maryland residents served by trauma physicians in trauma centers; and</section><section prefix="6.">The extent to which trauma-related costs are otherwise subsidized by hospitals, the federal government, and other sources; and</section></section><section prefix="(ii)">Include an incentive to encourage hospitals to continue to subsidize trauma-related costs not otherwise included in hospital rates.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The methodology developed under paragraph (1) of this subsection shall use the following parameters to determine the amount of reimbursement made to trauma physicians and trauma centers from the Fund:<section prefix="(i)"><section prefix="1.">The cost incurred by a Level II trauma center to maintain trauma surgeons, orthopedic surgeons, and neurosurgeons on-call shall be reimbursed:</section><section prefix="2.">The cost incurred by a Level III trauma center to maintain trauma surgeons, orthopedic surgeons, neurosurgeons, and anesthesiologists on-call shall be reimbursed:</section><section prefix="3.">The cost incurred by a Level I trauma center or pediatric trauma center to maintain trauma surgeons, orthopedic surgeons, and neurosurgeons on-call when a post-graduate resident is attending in the trauma center shall be reimbursed:</section><section prefix="4.">The cost incurred by a Maryland Trauma Specialty Referral Center to maintain trauma surgeons on-call in the specialty of the Center when a post-graduate resident is attending in the Center shall be reimbursed:</section><section prefix="5."/></section><section prefix="(ii)">The cost of undercompensated care incurred by a trauma physician in providing trauma care to enrollees of the Maryland Medical Assistance Program who are trauma patients on the State trauma registry shall be reimbursed at a rate of up to 100% of the Medicare payment for the service, minus any amount paid by the Maryland Medical Assistance Program;</section><section prefix="(iii)">The cost of uncompensated care incurred by a trauma physician in providing trauma care to trauma patients on the State trauma registry shall be reimbursed at a rate of 100% of the Medicare payment for the service, minus any recoveries made by the trauma physician for the care;</section><section prefix="(iv)">The Commission, in consultation with the Health Services Cost Review Commission, may establish a payment rate for uncompensated care incurred by a trauma physician in providing trauma care to trauma patients on the State trauma registry that is above 100% of the Medicare payment for the service if:<section prefix="1.">The Commission determines that increasing the payment rate above 100% of the Medicare payment for the service will address an unmet need in the State trauma system; and</section><section prefix="2.">The Commission reports on its intention to increase the payment rate to the Senate Finance Committee and the House Health and Government Operations Committee, in accordance with &#xA7; 2-1246 of the State Government Article, at least 60 days before any adjustment to the rate; and</section></section><section prefix="(v)">The total reimbursement to emergency physicians from the Fund may not exceed $300,000 annually.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(5)">In order to receive reimbursement, a trauma physician in the case of costs of uncompensated care under subsection (b)(2)(i) of this section, or a trauma center in the case of on-call costs under subsection (b)(2)(iii) of this section, shall apply to the Fund on a form and in a manner approved by the Commission and the Health Services Cost Review Commission.</section>
      <section prefix="(6)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The Commission and the Health Services Cost Review Commission shall adopt regulations that specify the information that trauma physicians and trauma centers must submit to receive money from the Fund.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The information required shall include:<section prefix="1.">The name and federal tax identification number of the trauma physician rendering the service;</section><section prefix="2.">The date of the service;</section><section prefix="3.">Appropriate codes describing the service;</section><section prefix="4.">Any amount recovered for the service rendered;</section><section prefix="5.">The name of the trauma patient;</section><section prefix="6.">The patient's trauma registry number; and</section><section prefix="7.">Any other information the Commission and the Health Services Cost Review Commission consider necessary to disburse money from the Fund.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">It is the intent of the General Assembly that trauma physicians and trauma centers shall cooperate with the Commission and the Health Services Cost Review Commission by providing information required under this paragraph in a timely and complete manner.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection and notwithstanding any other provision of law, expenditures from the Fund for costs incurred in any fiscal year may not exceed revenues of the Fund.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The Commission, in consultation with the Health Services Cost Review Commission and the Maryland Institute for Emergency Medical Services Systems, shall develop a process for the award of grants to Level II and Level III trauma centers in the State to be used for equipment primarily used in the delivery of trauma care.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">
          <section prefix="1.">The Commission shall issue grants under this paragraph from any balance carried over to the Fund from prior fiscal years.</section>
          <section prefix="2.">The total amount of grants awarded under this paragraph in a fiscal year may not exceed 10% of the balance remaining in the Fund at the end of the fiscal year immediately prior to the fiscal year in which grants are awarded.</section>
        </section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">The process developed by the Commission for the award of grants under this paragraph shall include:<section prefix="1.">Grant applications and review and selection criteria for the award of grants;</section><section prefix="2.">Review by the Commission, if necessary, for any project that exceeds certificate of need thresholds; and</section><section prefix="3.">Any other procedure determined necessary by the Commission.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(iv)">Before awarding grants under this subsection in a fiscal year, the Commission shall report to the Senate Finance Committee and the House Health and Government Operations Committee, in accordance with &#xA7; 2-1246 of the State Government Article, on the process that the Commission has developed for awarding grants in that fiscal year.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">On or before November 1 of each year, the Commission and the Health Services Cost Review Commission shall report to the General Assembly, in accordance with &#xA7; 2-1246 of the State Government Article, on:<section prefix="(1)">The amount of money in the Fund on the last day of the previous fiscal year;</section><section prefix="(2)">The amount of money applied for by trauma physicians and trauma centers during the previous fiscal year;</section><section prefix="(3)">The amount of money distributed in the form of trauma physician and trauma center reimbursements during the previous fiscal year;</section><section prefix="(4)">Any recommendations for altering the manner in which trauma physicians and trauma centers are reimbursed from the Fund;</section><section prefix="(5)">The costs incurred in administering the Fund during the previous fiscal year; and</section><section prefix="(6)">The amount that each hospital that participates in the Maryland trauma system and that has a trauma center contributes toward the subsidization of trauma-related costs for its trauma center.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
