<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="ghg" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="20-115" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghg-20-115</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">"Center" means any facility that produces, develops, or interprets:</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">"Center" includes a hospital, outpatient department, medical laboratory, clinic, radiology practice, office of a health care provider, or other testing facility conducting mammography testing.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">"Center" does not include a facility of the federal Department of Veterans Affairs.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Mammogram" means a radiographic image produced through mammography.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">"Mammography testing" means the imaging of the breast with ionizing radiation.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">On or after July 1, 1992, a person may not perform mammography testing unless:<section prefix="(1)">The individual performing mammography testing is qualified under Title 14 of the Health Occupations Article; and</section><section prefix="(2)">The center where the mammography testing is performed:<section prefix="(i)">Is accredited or has applied for accreditation under the American College of Radiology Screening Mammography Accreditation Program; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Has obtained a certificate of approval from the federal Food and Drug Administration as specified in the federal Mammography Quality Standards Act of 1992.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Notwithstanding any other provision of this title, the penalty for a violation of this section may not exceed $1,000.</section>
  </text>
</law>
