<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghg" order_by="ghg" level="1">Health - General</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghg-15-605</section_number>
  <catch_line>The Board may approve Medbank of Maryland, Inc., or another licensed pharmacy, to be a repository....</catch_line>
  <order_by>605</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Board may approve Medbank of Maryland, Inc., or another licensed pharmacy, to be a repository.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Consistent with its approval by the Board, a repository shall:<section prefix="(1)">Accept only donated prescription drugs and medical supplies forwarded by designated drop-off sites;</section><section prefix="(2)">Inspect all donated prescription drugs and medical supplies;</section><section prefix="(3)">Accept for dispensing to needy individuals only those donated prescription drugs and medical supplies that meet the requirements of &#xA7; 15-603 of this subtitle;</section><section prefix="(4)">Dispose of donated prescription drugs and medical supplies not accepted for dispensing to needy individuals in accordance with State and federal law;</section><section prefix="(5)">Maintain a separate inventory of donated prescription drugs and medical supplies;</section><section prefix="(6)">Store donated prescription drugs and medical supplies in a secure location used exclusively for the Program;</section><section prefix="(7)">Maintain separate prescription files for patients receiving donated prescription drugs and medical supplies; and</section><section prefix="(8)">Obliterate from the labels of donated prescription drugs and medical supplies any information specific to the patient for whom the donated prescription drugs and medical supplies were originally dispensed.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A repository shall dispense donated prescription drugs and medical supplies only:<section prefix="(1)">To an individual who meets the requirements of &#xA7; 15-606 of this subtitle;</section><section prefix="(2)">On a new prescription, in the case of a prescription drug or medical supply that requires a prescription; and</section><section prefix="(3)">In accordance with State and federal laws pertaining to:<section prefix="(i)">Storage, distribution, and dispensing of prescription drugs; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Confidentiality of patient information.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A repository may:<section prefix="(1)">Charge a fee, not to exceed $10, for each prescription drug or medical supply dispensed; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Dispense a donated prescription drug or medical supply by mail, provided that the repository informs the patient that a delay may be entailed.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">A repository may not establish or maintain a waiting list for any prescription drug or medical supply dispensed by the Program.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">A pharmacy may accept prescription drugs and medical supplies taken to the pharmacy for disposal only if the pharmacy is approved by the Board as a repository for this purpose.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">The Program may not require a private entity to establish, operate, or fund a drop-off site or disposal program.</section>
  </text>
</law>
