<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="ghg" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="18-338" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghg-18-338</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Correctional institution" means a place of detention or correctional confinement operated by or for the State or a local government.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Correctional employee" means:<section prefix="(i)">A person who is employed by a correctional institution; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">A person who performs duties in a correctional institution by virtue of federal, State, or local government employment.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">"Court" means a district or circuit court of the State.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">"Exposure" means, as between a correctional employee and an inmate:<section prefix="(i)">Percutaneous contact with blood, semen, or blood contaminated fluids;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Mucocutaneous contact with blood, semen, or blood contaminated fluids;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Open wound, including dermatitis, exudative lesions, or chapped skin, contact with blood, semen, or blood contaminated fluids; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">Intact skin contact with large amounts of blood, semen, or blood contaminated fluids for a prolonged period.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(6)">"Health care provider" means:<section prefix="(i)">Any person, including a physician or hospital, who is licensed or otherwise authorized in this State to provide health care services and is under contract with or operated by the correctional facility; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">An employee's private physician.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">An inmate shall furnish to the correctional institution a blood sample or buccal (cheek) swab to be tested for the presence of human immunodeficiency virus (HIV) when:<section prefix="(1)">There has been an exposure involving the inmate;</section><section prefix="(2)">The exposure occurred in connection with the inmate's violation of institutional regulations;</section><section prefix="(3)">The inmate has been found guilty of the violation of institutional regulations described in paragraph (2) of this subsection;</section><section prefix="(4)">The correctional employee involved in the exposure has given written notice of the exposure to the managing official of the correctional institution, or the official's designee; and</section><section prefix="(5)">The exposure is confirmed by a health care provider.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The correctional institution shall collect the blood sample from the inmate, and shall have the sample tested for human immunodeficiency virus (HIV) by a test and test procedure approved by the Department.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If the inmate refuses to furnish to the correctional institution a blood sample or buccal (cheek) swab to be tested for the presence of human immunodeficiency virus (HIV) as required under subsection (b) of this section, a court may order the inmate to furnish the blood sample or buccal (cheek) swab if:<section prefix="(i)">The correctional employee involved in the exposure or the correctional employee's representative requests the testing in writing to the State's Attorney in the county where the exposure occurred; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">The court finds probable cause to believe that the exposure occurred.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Before ordering a test under paragraph (1) of this subsection and subject to the provisions of paragraph (6) of this subsection, the court shall hold a hearing at which the correctional employee or the correctional employee's representative and the inmate or the inmate's representative have the right to be present.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The correctional employee or the correctional employee's representative and the inmate or the inmate's representative shall be notified of:<section prefix="(i)">The date, time, and location of the hearing; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Their right to be present at the hearing.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">During the hearing, the court may admit into evidence only affidavits, counter-affidavits, and medical records that:<section prefix="(i)">Relate to the material facts of the case; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Support or rebut a finding of probable cause to issue a court order.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(5)">The written request of the correctional employee or the correctional employee's representative shall be:<section prefix="(i)">Filed by the State's Attorney with the court; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Sealed by the court.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(6)">Except for good cause, the court shall:<section prefix="(i)">Hold the hearing within 15 days after the State's Attorney's presentment to the court of the written request of the correctional employee or the correctional employee's representative; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Issue an order granting or denying the request within 3 days after the conclusion of the hearing.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The correctional employee shall be notified of the results of the test for the presence of human immunodeficiency virus (HIV) conducted under the provisions of this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The notification required under subsection (e) of this section shall:<section prefix="(1)">Be made within 48 hours of confirmation of the inmate's diagnosis;</section><section prefix="(2)">Include subsequent written confirmation of the possible exposure to human immunodeficiency virus (HIV); and</section><section prefix="(3)">To the extent possible, be made in a manner that will protect the confidentiality of the correctional employee and the inmate.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(g)">If the results of the blood sample test are positive for the presence of human immunodeficiency virus (HIV), then the correctional employee and the inmate shall be provided appropriate counseling.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">All correctional institutions shall develop written procedures to carry out the provisions of this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">A health care provider acting in good faith to provide notification in accordance with this section may not be held liable in any cause of action related to a breach of patient confidentiality.</section>
    <section prefix="(j)">A health care provider acting in good faith to provide notification in accordance with this section may not be held liable in any cause of action for:<section prefix="(1)">The failure to give the required notice, if the correctional employee fails to properly initiate the notification procedures developed by the correctional institution under subsection (h) of this section; or</section><section prefix="(2)">The failure of the managing official of the correctional institution within which the correctional employee is employed to subsequently notify the correctional employee of the possible exposure to human immunodeficiency virus (HIV).</section></section>
    <section prefix="(k)">A health care provider may not be held liable in any cause of action related to obtaining a blood sample or performing and interpreting an approved HIV test without the inmate's informed consent.</section>
  </text>
</law>
