<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghg" order_by="" level="1">Health - General</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghg-4-301</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>301</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Directory information" means information concerning the presence and general health condition of a patient who has been admitted to a health care facility or who is currently receiving emergency health care in a health care facility.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Directory information" does not include health care information developed primarily in connection with mental health services.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Disclose" or "disclosure" means the transmission or communication of information in a medical record, including an acknowledgment that a medical record on a particular patient or recipient exists.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">"Emergency" means a situation when, in the professional opinion of the health care provider, a clear and significant risk of death or imminent serious injury or harm to a patient or recipient exists.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"General health condition" means the health status of a patient described in terms of "critical", "poor", "fair", "good", "excellent", or terms denoting similar conditions.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">"Health care" means any care, treatment, or procedure by a health care provider:<section prefix="(1)">To diagnose, evaluate, rehabilitate, manage, treat, or maintain the physical or mental condition of a patient or recipient; or</section><section prefix="(2)">That affects the structure or any function of the human body.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Health care provider" means:<section prefix="(i)">A person who is licensed, certified, or otherwise authorized under the Health Occupations Article or &#xA7; 13-516 of the Education Article to provide health care in the ordinary course of business or practice of a profession or in an approved education or training program; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">A facility where health care is provided to patients or recipients, including a facility as defined in &#xA7; 10-101(e) of this article, a hospital as defined in &#xA7; 19-301 of this article, a related institution as defined in &#xA7; 19-301 of this article, a health maintenance organization as defined in &#xA7; 19-701(g) of this article, an outpatient clinic, and a medical laboratory.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Health care provider" includes the agents, employees, officers, and directors of a facility and the agents and employees of a health care provider.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(h)">"Health information exchange" means an infrastructure that provides organizational and technical capabilities for the exchange of protected health information electronically among entities not under common ownership.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Medical record" means any oral, written, or other transmission in any form or medium of information that:<section prefix="(i)">Is entered in the record of a patient or recipient;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Identifies or can readily be associated with the identity of a patient or recipient; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Relates to the health care of the patient or recipient.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Medical record" includes any:<section prefix="(i)">Documentation of disclosures of a medical record to any person who is not an employee, agent, or consultant of the health care provider;</section><section prefix="(ii)">File or record maintained under &#xA7; 12-403(b)(13) of the Health Occupations Article by a pharmacy of a prescription order for drugs, medicines, or devices that identifies or may be readily associated with the identity of a patient;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Documentation of an examination of a patient regardless of who:<section prefix="1.">Requested the examination; or</section><section prefix="2.">Is making payment for the examination; and</section></section><section prefix="(iv)">File or record received from another health care provider that:<section prefix="1.">Relates to the health care of a patient or recipient received from that health care provider; and</section><section prefix="2.">Identifies or can readily be associated with the identity of the patient or recipient.</section></section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(j)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Mental health services" means health care rendered to a recipient primarily in connection with the diagnosis, evaluation, treatment, case management, or rehabilitation of any mental disorder.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">For acute general hospital services, mental health services are considered to be the primarily rendered service only if service is provided pursuant to Title 10, Subtitle 6 or Title 12 of this article.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(k)">"Patient" means a person who receives health care and on whom a medical record is maintained.</section>
    <section prefix="(l)">"Person in interest" means:<section prefix="(1)">An adult on whom a health care provider maintains a medical record;</section><section prefix="(2)">A person authorized to consent to health care for an adult consistent with the authority granted;</section><section prefix="(3)">A duly appointed personal representative of a deceased person;</section><section prefix="(4)"><section prefix="(i)">A minor, if the medical record concerns treatment to which the minor has the right to consent and has consented under Title 20, Subtitle 1 of this article; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">A parent, guardian, custodian, or a representative of the minor designated by a court, in the discretion of the attending physician who provided the treatment to the minor, as provided in &#xA7; 20-102 or &#xA7; 20-104 of this article;</section></section><section prefix="(5)">If item (4) of this subsection does not apply to a minor:<section prefix="(i)">A parent of the minor, except if the parent's authority to consent to health care for the minor has been specifically limited by a court order or a valid separation agreement entered into by the parents of the minor; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">A person authorized to consent to health care for the minor consistent with the authority granted; or</section></section><section prefix="(6)">An attorney appointed in writing by a person listed in item (1), (2), (3), (4), or (5) of this subsection.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(m)">"Primary provider of mental health services" means the designated mental health services provider who:<section prefix="(1)">Has primary responsibility for the development of the mental health treatment plan for the recipient; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Is actively involved in providing that treatment.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(n)">"Protected health information" means all individually identifiable health information held or transmitted by a covered entity or its business associate protected under the U.S. Department of Health and Human Services Privacy Rule.</section>
    <section prefix="(o)">"Recipient" means a person who has applied for, for whom an application has been submitted, or who has received mental health services.</section>
  </text>
</law>
