<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="ghg" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="19-121" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghg-19-121</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, "health maintenance organization" means a health maintenance organization under Subtitle 7 of this title.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A health maintenance organization or a health care facility that either controls, directly or indirectly, or is controlled by a health maintenance organization shall have a certificate of need before the health maintenance organization or health care facility builds, develops, operates, purchases, or participates in building, developing, operating, or establishing:<section prefix="(i)">A hospital, as defined in &#xA7; 19-301 of this title, or an ambulatory surgical facility or center, as defined in &#xA7; 19-114(b) of this subtitle; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Any other health care project for which a certificate of need is required under &#xA7; 19-120 of this subtitle if that health care project is planned for or used by any nonsubscribers of that health maintenance organization.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Notwithstanding paragraph (1)(i) of this subsection, a health maintenance organization or a health care facility that either controls, directly or indirectly, or is controlled by a health maintenance organization is not required to obtain a certificate of need before purchasing an existing ambulatory surgical facility or center, as defined in &#xA7; 19-114(b) of this subtitle.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">An application for a certificate of need by a health maintenance organization or by a health care facility that either controls, directly or indirectly, or is controlled by, a health maintenance organization shall be approved if the Commission finds that the application:<section prefix="(1)">Documents that the project is necessary to meet the needs of enrolled members and reasonably anticipated new members for the services proposed to be provided by the applicant; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Is not inconsistent with those sections of the State health plan or those sections of the institution-specific plan that govern hospitals, as defined in &#xA7; 19-301 of this title, and ambulatory surgical facilities or centers, as defined in &#xA7; 19-114(b) of this subtitle, or health care projects for which a certificate of need is required under subsection (b)(1)(ii) of this section.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
