<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghg" order_by="" level="1">Health - General</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghg-4-309</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>309</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">If a health care provider knowingly refuses to disclose a medical record within a reasonable time but no more than 21 working days after the date a person in interest requests the disclosure, the health care provider is liable for actual damages.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A health care provider may not refuse to disclose a medical record on the request of a person in interest because of the failure of the person in interest to pay for health care rendered by the health care provider.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A health care provider or any other person is in violation of this subtitle if the health care provider or any other person:<section prefix="(1)">Requests or obtains a medical record under false pretenses or through deception; or</section><section prefix="(2)">Discloses a medical record in violation of this subtitle.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Except as otherwise provided in subsection (e) of this section, a health care provider or any other person, including an officer or employee of a governmental unit, who knowingly and willfully violates any provision of this subtitle is guilty of a misdemeanor and on conviction is subject to a fine not exceeding $1,000 for the first offense and not exceeding $5,000 for each subsequent conviction for a violation of any provision of this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A health care provider or any other person, including an officer or employee of a governmental unit, who knowingly and willfully requests or obtains a medical record under false pretenses or through deception or knowingly and willfully discloses a medical record in violation of this subtitle is guilty of a misdemeanor and on conviction is subject to the following penalties:<section prefix="(i)">A fine not exceeding $50,000, imprisonment for not more than 1 year, or both;</section><section prefix="(ii)">If the offense is committed under false pretenses, a fine not exceeding $100,000, imprisonment for not more than 5 years, or both; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">If the offense is committed with intent to sell, transfer, or use individually identifiable health information for commercial advantage, personal gain, or malicious harm, a fine not exceeding $250,000, imprisonment for not more than 10 years, or both.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">This subsection does not apply to an officer or employee of a governmental unit that is conducting a criminal investigation.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">A health care provider or any other person who knowingly violates any provision of this subtitle is liable for actual damages.</section>
  </text>
</law>
