<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghg" order_by="ghg" level="1">Health - General</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghg-10-925</section_number>
  <catch_line>On or before January 1, 1985, the Director shall prepare and submit a plan to the Governor, the Pres...</catch_line>
  <order_by>925</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">On or before January 1, 1985, the Director shall prepare and submit a plan to the Governor, the President of the Senate, and the Speaker of the House.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The plan shall include:<section prefix="(1)">The number of children and adolescents in need of placement in private therapeutic group homes;</section><section prefix="(2)">The number, type, and location of private therapeutic group homes that are needed in the community for the treatment of these children and adolescents;</section><section prefix="(3)">The resources and procedures that are necessary to establish the private therapeutic group homes;</section><section prefix="(4)">The feasibility of transferring any resources of a State facility to any private therapeutic group home;</section><section prefix="(5)">The summaries of the individual plans of treatment;</section><section prefix="(6)">The schedule for the relocation of children and adolescents where plans indicate that a less restrictive placement is appropriate;</section><section prefix="(7)">A plan for establishing, developing, and maintaining a system for monitoring community services; and</section><section prefix="(8)">An evaluation by the Secretary of the feasibility of obtaining reimbursement, under Title XIX of the Social Security Act, for services to be provided to children and adolescents with mental disorders.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Director shall:<section prefix="(1)">Implement &#xA7;&#xA7; 10-920 through 10-924 and 10-926 of this subtitle upon completion of the plan to be submitted under this section; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Review and revise periodically the plan submitted under this section.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
