<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghg" order_by="" level="1">Health - General</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghg-21-101</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>101</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this title the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Advertisement" means any representation that:<section prefix="(1)">Is intended or is likely to induce, directly or indirectly, any person to purchase any food, drug, device, or cosmetic; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Is published by any means other than labeling.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Color additive" means any material that:<section prefix="(i)">Is a dye, pigment, or other substance made by a process of synthesis or similar artifice, or extracted, isolated, or otherwise derived, with or without intermediate or final change of identity, from a vegetable, animal, mineral, or other source; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">When added or applied to a food, drug, or cosmetic, or to any part of the human body, is capable, alone or through reaction with any other substance, of imparting color, including black, white, or intermediate grays, to the food, drug, cosmetic, or body.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Color additive" does not include any material that is not a color additive under the federal act.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">"Consumer commodity" means any food, drug, device, or cosmetic that is not:<section prefix="(1)">Tobacco or a tobacco product;</section><section prefix="(2)">A commodity that is subject to packaging or labeling requirements imposed under the Federal Insecticide, Fungicide, and Rodenticide Act or the federal Animal Virus, Serum, Toxin, Antitoxin Act;</section><section prefix="(3)">A drug that is subject to the provisions of &#xA7; 353(b)(1) of the federal act;</section><section prefix="(4)">A beverage that is subject to or complies with packaging or labeling requirements imposed by the federal Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco and Firearms; or</section><section prefix="(5)">A seed or other commodity that is subject to the provisions of &#xA7;&#xA7; 9-206 through 9-213 of the Agriculture Article.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Cosmetic" means any substance, or any component of a substance, that is intended to be rubbed, poured, sprinkled, or sprayed on, introduced into, or otherwise applied to the human body for cleansing, beautifying, promoting attractiveness, or altering appearance.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Cosmetic" does not include soap.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">"Device" means any instrument, apparatus, or contrivance, or any part or accessory of an instrument, apparatus, or contrivance, that is intended:<section prefix="(1)">For use in the diagnosis, cure, mitigation, treatment, or prevention of human disease; or</section><section prefix="(2)">To affect the structure or any function of the human body for medical, surgical, or therapeutic purposes.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Drug" means any substance or component of a substance:<section prefix="(i)">That is recognized in an official compendium;</section><section prefix="(ii)">That is intended for use in the diagnosis, cure, mitigation, treatment, or prevention of disease in human beings; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">Except for food, that is intended to affect the structure or any function of the human body.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Drug" does not include a device.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(h)">"Federal act" means the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act as that act appears at 21 U.S.C. &#xA7; 301 et seq.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">"Food" means:<section prefix="(1)">Any substance that is used as food or drink for human beings or as a component of food or drink for human beings; or</section><section prefix="(2)">Chewing gum or any substance that is used as a component of chewing gum.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(j)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Food additive" means any substance:<section prefix="(i)">The intended use of which results or reasonably may be expected to result, directly or indirectly, in the substance becoming a component of food or otherwise affecting the characteristics of food, including any substance used to produce, manufacture, pack, process, prepare, treat, package, transport, or hold food, or any source of radiation that is intended for any of these uses; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">That is not recognized generally by qualified scientific experts as having been shown to be safe under the conditions of its intended use:<section prefix="1.">Through scientific procedures; or</section><section prefix="2.">Through either scientific procedures or experience based on common use, if the substance was used in a food before January 1, 1958.</section></section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Food additive" does not include a color additive.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(k)">"Label" means a display of written, printed, or graphic matter on the container, other than the package liner, of a substance.</section>
    <section prefix="(l)">"Labeling" means any label or other written or graphic material that:<section prefix="(1)">Is on a substance or its container or its wrapping; or</section><section prefix="(2)">Accompanies a substance.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(m)">"Official compendium" means the most recent revision of the United States Pharmacopoeia and National Formulary, the official Homeopathic Pharmacopoeia of the United States, or any of their current supplements.</section>
    <section prefix="(n)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Package" means any container or wrapping of a consumer commodity that is used for delivery or display to retail consumers.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Package" does not include any container or wrapping that is used only for:<section prefix="(i)">Transportation of a consumer commodity in bulk or quantity to a manufacturer, packer, processor, or wholesale or retail distributor; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">Shipment or delivery of a consumer commodity to a retail customer, if the container or wrapping bears no printed material that relates to a particular consumer commodity.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(o)">"Person" includes:<section prefix="(1)">An operator of a facility that is owned by a State or local unit of government; or</section><section prefix="(2)">A State or local unit of government if the State or local unit of government is the operator of the facility.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(p)">"Secretary" means for the purposes of Subtitles 1, 2, 3, 4, 8, and 11 of this title, the Secretary of Health and Mental Hygiene or the Secretary's designee.</section>
  </text>
</law>
