<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghg" order_by="" level="1">Health - General</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghg-19-4A-01</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>01</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Home health care" includes any of the following services:<section prefix="(1)">Audiology and speech pathology;</section><section prefix="(2)">Dietary and nutritional services;</section><section prefix="(3)">Drug services;</section><section prefix="(4)">Home health aid;</section><section prefix="(5)">Laboratory;</section><section prefix="(6)">Medical social services;</section><section prefix="(7)">Nursing;</section><section prefix="(8)">Occupational therapy;</section><section prefix="(9)">Physical therapy;</section><section prefix="(10)">Provision of invasive medical equipment; and</section><section prefix="(11)">Home medical equipment services.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Home medical equipment services" means the delivery, installation, maintenance, or replacement of, or instruction in the use of, medical equipment used by a sick or disabled individual to allow the individual to be maintained in a noninstitutional environment.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">"Medical equipment" means technologically sophisticated medical devices including:<section prefix="(1)">Oxygen and oxygen delivery systems;</section><section prefix="(2)">Ventilators;</section><section prefix="(3)">Respiratory disease management devices;</section><section prefix="(4)">Electronic and computer driven wheelchairs and seating systems;</section><section prefix="(5)">Apnea monitors;</section><section prefix="(6)">Transcutaneous electrical nerve stimulator (T.E.N.S.) units;</section><section prefix="(7)">Low air loss cutaneous pressure management devices;</section><section prefix="(8)">Sequential compression devices;</section><section prefix="(9)">Neonatal home phototherapy devices;</section><section prefix="(10)">Feeding pumps; and</section><section prefix="(11)">Other similar equipment as defined in regulations established by the Secretary.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Residential service agency" means any person that is engaged in a nongovernmental business of employing or contracting with individuals to provide home health care for compensation to an unrelated sick or disabled individual in the residence of that individual.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Residential service agency" includes any agency that employs or contracts with individuals directly for hire as home health care providers.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Residential service agency" does not include:<section prefix="(i)">A home health agency that is licensed under the provisions of Subtitle 4 of this title;</section><section prefix="(ii)">A person required to be licensed as a home health agency under the provisions of Subtitle 4 of this title;</section><section prefix="(iii)">A home-based hospice care program that is licensed under the provisions of Subtitle 9 of this title;</section><section prefix="(iv)">A hospital that is licensed under the provisions of Subtitle 3 of this title;</section><section prefix="(v)">A related institution that is licensed under the provisions of Subtitle 3 of this title;</section><section prefix="(vi)">Personal care providers under the Medical Assistance Personal Care Program;</section><section prefix="(vii)">Any person practicing a health occupation that the person is authorized to practice under the Health Occupations Article;</section><section prefix="(viii)">A nursing referral service agency that is licensed under Subtitle 4B of this title;</section><section prefix="(ix)">A group of persons licensed under the same title of the Health Occupations Article practicing as a business; or</section><section prefix="(x)">Residential rehabilitation services providers approved under regulations adopted by the State Mental Health Authority.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
