<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="ghg" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="21-253" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghg-21-253</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Under this section, there is a ground for action against a food, drug, device, or cosmetic if it is:<section prefix="(1)">Adulterated;</section><section prefix="(2)">So misbranded that it is dangerous or fraudulent;</section><section prefix="(3)">A food that violates any requirement imposed under &#xA7; 21-211 of this subtitle; or</section><section prefix="(4)">A drug that violates the provisions on new drugs under &#xA7; 21-223 of this subtitle.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">If the Secretary finds or has probable cause to believe that there is ground for action against a food, drug, device, or cosmetic, the Secretary shall attach to the article a tag or other appropriate marking that gives notice that the article is, or is suspected of being, adulterated, misbranded, or in violation of &#xA7; 21-211 or &#xA7; 21-223 of this subtitle and that the article has been detained. The tag or other marking also shall warn all persons not to remove or dispose of the article, by sale or otherwise, until permission for removal or disposal is given by the Secretary, an authorized agent of the Secretary, or a court.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">If, after an article has been marked as provided in subsection (b) of this section, the Secretary finds that there is not a ground for action against the article, the Secretary shall remove the marking and release the article.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Secretary may proceed further against any article as to which there is a ground for action by filing a petition for an order with the circuit court for the county in which the article is located. The petition may request any relief permitted by this subsection.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If the court finds that there is a valid ground for action against the article, the court may proceed by issuing an order:<section prefix="(i)">Of forfeiture for destruction; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">To have the article delivered to its claimant and have the violation corrected by proper labeling or processing.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">If the court issues an order of forfeiture for destruction, the article shall be destroyed under the supervision of the Secretary and the owner shall pay all court, storage, and destruction costs, and any other cost that is incurred through the enforcement of this subtitle against the article.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">If the court issues an order to have the article delivered to its claimant for correction of the violation, the order shall require that the claimant:<section prefix="(i)">Correct the violation under the supervision of a representative of the Secretary;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Pay all court and storage costs, the expense of supervision by the representative of the Secretary, and any other cost that is incurred through the enforcement of this subtitle against the article; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Post a bond that is conditioned on the obligation that the article be labeled or processed properly and that the expense of supervision by the representative of the Secretary be paid.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(5)">A bond that is posted under this subsection shall be discharged on a representation to the court by the Secretary that there no longer is a ground for action against the article and that the expense of supervision has been paid.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
