<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghg" order_by="" level="1">Health - General</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghg-24-701</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>701</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Adult day care center" means a nonresidential center that:<section prefix="(1)">Serves the elderly, medically handicapped adults, or victims of Alzheimer's disease and related disorders;</section><section prefix="(2)">Meets the definition in &#xA7; 14-201(b) or &#xA7; 14-301(b) of this article; and</section><section prefix="(3)">Is licensed by the Department.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Facility" means an adult day care center that is wholly owned by and operated under the authority of:<section prefix="(1)">A county or a municipal corporation; or</section><section prefix="(2)">A nonprofit organization.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">"Nonprofit organization" means:<section prefix="(1)">A bona fide religious organization, no part of the earnings of which inures to the benefit of any individual or is used for any purpose other than the maintenance and operation of the facility, the purchase of equipment to be used in the facility, or the expansion of the facility; or</section><section prefix="(2)">An organization:<section prefix="(i)">That is chartered as a nonprofit corporation and classified by the Internal Revenue Service as nonprofit; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">No part of the earnings of which inures to the benefit of any individual or is used for any purpose other than the maintenance and operation of the facility, the purchase of equipment to be used in the facility, or the expansion of the facility.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"Wholly owned" includes leased, if:<section prefix="(1)"><section prefix="(i)">The lease is for a minimum term of 30 years following project completion; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">The lease agreement extends the right of purchase to the lessee; and</section></section><section prefix="(2)">The lessor consents to the recording, in the land records of the county or Baltimore City in which the facility is located, of a notice of the State's right of recovery, as provided under &#xA7; 24-706 of this subtitle.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
