<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="ghg" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="18-337" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghg-18-337</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, "health care provider" means a physician, a physician's designee, or a designee of a health care facility licensed or otherwise authorized to provide health care services.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">If an individual informed of the individual's HIV positive status under &#xA7; 18-336 of this subtitle refuses to notify the individual's sexual and needle-sharing partners, the individual's physician may inform the local health officer and/or the individual's sexual and needle-sharing partners of:<section prefix="(1)">The individual's identity; and</section><section prefix="(2)">The circumstances giving rise to the notification.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">When the local health officer is notified, the health officer shall enforce the provisions of &#xA7;&#xA7; 18-208 through 18-213.1 of this title:<section prefix="(1)">Within a reasonable time; and</section><section prefix="(2)">To the extent feasible.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Each local health officer shall refer the infected individual and any known sexual or needle-sharing partners of the individual to appropriate services for the care, support, and treatment for HIV infected individuals.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">A physician acting in good faith to provide notification in accordance with this section may not be held liable in any cause of action related to a breach of patient confidentiality.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">A physician acting in good faith may not be held liable in any cause of action for choosing not to disclose information related to a positive test result for the presence of human immunodeficiency virus to an individual's sexual and needle-sharing partners.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">A hospital or any other health care provider acting in good faith pursuant to a physician's order to perform or interpret a test for the presence of HIV may not be held liable in any cause of action related to:<section prefix="(1)">A breach of patient confidentiality; or</section><section prefix="(2)">A physician's decision to disclose or not to disclose information related to a positive test result to a local health officer and/or an individual's sexual and needle-sharing partners.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
