<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghg" order_by="ghg" level="1">Health - General</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghg-10-1202.1</section_number>
  <catch_line>This section applies only to Howard County....</catch_line>
  <order_by>1202.1</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">This section applies only to Howard County.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The purpose of this section is to authorize the establishment of a quasi-public authority which may be activated by Howard County, if the county decides to designate a quasi-public authority as the core service agency to perform the duties imposed under this subtitle.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">This section has no effect on any other form of core service agency, whether it is a unit of Howard County government, a local health department, or a private, nonprofit corporation.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If activated as a quasi-public authority by an ordinance or resolution of the governing body of Howard County, there is established a quasi-public authority in Howard County.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The quasi-public authority shall:<section prefix="(i)">Serve as the core service agency for the jurisdiction; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Be a public body, corporate and politic.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The local ordinance activating the quasi-public authority shall include the following:<section prefix="(1)">The name of the quasi-public authority;</section><section prefix="(2)">The method of appointing individuals to the authority, including whether or not appointments require approval of the chief elected official of the jurisdiction and the legislative body of the jurisdiction;</section><section prefix="(3)">The number of members of the authority;</section><section prefix="(4)">The terms of members;</section><section prefix="(5)">The duties and powers of the authority in accordance with the provisions of this subtitle; and</section><section prefix="(6)">Specific terms governing the operation of the authority, including, but not limited to financial reporting, budgetary, and personnel requirements, provided that these specific terms may not add powers to the authority which are not included under this subtitle.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The quasi-public authority is exempt from taxation by the State and the county.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">Howard County shall send to the Secretary a copy of any ordinance or resolution activating a quasi-public authority which will serve as a core service agency.</section>
  </text>
</law>
