<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="ghg" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="10-518" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghg-10-518</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">To qualify for a license, an applicant shall satisfy the Secretary that the proposed private group home:<section prefix="(1)">Is needed;</section><section prefix="(2)">Is compatible with the nature and character of the area involved;</section><section prefix="(3)">Is near transportation facilities;</section><section prefix="(4)">Meets or, on completion, will meet the requirements of this subtitle and the rules and regulations that the Secretary adopts under this subtitle; and</section><section prefix="(5)">Meets or, on completion, will meet all general zoning requirements that apply to the site and that relate to:<section prefix="(i)">The height and size of any buildings that are involved;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The land that may be covered or occupied;</section><section prefix="(iii)">The size of yards that require open space;</section><section prefix="(iv)">The density of population; and</section><section prefix="(v)">The use of the land and buildings.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A small private group home:<section prefix="(i)">Is deemed conclusively a single-family dwelling; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Is permitted to locate in all residential zones.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A large private group home is deemed conclusively a multi-family dwelling and is permitted to locate in zones of similar density.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A private group home may not be subject to any special exception, conditional use permit, or procedure that differs from that required for a single-family dwelling or a multi-family dwelling of similar density in the same zone.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">A general zoning ordinance that conflicts with the provisions of this section is superseded by this section to the extent of the conflict.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
