<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="ghg" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="13-109" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghg-13-109</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Subject to the requirements of this section, the Department may adopt rules, regulations, and standards for the detection and management of hereditary and congenital disorders.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Before the Department adopts a rule, regulation, or standard, the Department shall consult:<section prefix="(i)">The public, especially communities and groups who particularly are affected by hereditary and congenital disorders programs;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Where appropriate, experts in the medical, psychological, ethical, social, and economic effects of programs for the detection and management of hereditary and congenital disorders; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">The Advisory Council.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Before the Department adopts a rule, regulation, or standard, the Department shall consider:<section prefix="(i)">The incidence of each hereditary or congenital disorder; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">The cost of detection and management of each hereditary or congenital disorder.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The rules, regulations, and standards of the Department shall require the Department and each person who conducts a hereditary and congenital disorders program to keep in code and treat as a confidential medical record all information that is gathered in the program and identifies an individual. However, this requirement does not prevent the disclosure of information if the individual or, if the individual is a minor or disabled person, a parent or guardian of the person:<section prefix="(i)">Is informed of the scope of information to be released and the purpose of the release; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Consents to the release.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The rules, regulations, and standards of the Department shall provide that, subject to the restrictions on disclosure of confidential information, information on the operation of a hereditary and congenital disorders program shall be open and freely available to the public.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The rules, regulations, and standards of the Department shall provide that procedures for a hereditary and congenital disorders program shall:<section prefix="(1)">Be accurate;</section><section prefix="(2)">Provide maximum information;</section><section prefix="(3)">Be set forth clearly; and</section><section prefix="(4)">Be reviewed regularly.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The rules, regulations, and standards of the Department shall:<section prefix="(1)">Require that, before an individual participates in a hereditary and congenital disorders program, the person who conducts the program shall inform the individual or, if the individual is a minor or disabled person, a parent or guardian of the person of the requirement that participation in the program be wholly voluntary and of any risk that is involved in participation;</section><section prefix="(2)">Prohibit the testing of an individual for a hereditary or congenital disorder unless the individual or, if the individual is a minor or disabled person, a parent or guardian of the person:<section prefix="(i)">Is informed fully of the purpose of the test and the nature and consequences of being affected by a hereditary or congenital disorder or being a carrier of a hereditary disorder;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Is given a reasonable opportunity to object; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Does not object to the test; and</section></section><section prefix="(3)">Require unambiguous diagnostic results to be made available through a physician or other source of health care to the individual or, if the individual is a minor or disabled person, to a parent or guardian of the person.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The rules, regulations, and standards of the Department shall provide that a hereditary and congenital disorders program may not:<section prefix="(1)">Require participation in the program;</section><section prefix="(2)">Require restriction of childbearing; or</section><section prefix="(3)">Be prerequisite for eligibility for any service or other program.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(g)">The rules, regulations, and standards of the Department shall provide that:<section prefix="(1)">Each participant in a hereditary and congenital disorders program shall be:<section prefix="(i)">Protected from undue physical or mental harm; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Informed of the nature, cost, benefits, and risks of any therapy or maintenance program available for an individual affected by a hereditary or congenital disorder; and</section></section><section prefix="(2)">Each participant in a screening program for a hereditary or congenital disorder shall have available counseling services that:<section prefix="(i)">Are nondirective;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Emphasize informing the individual; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Do not require restriction of childbearing.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(h)">Only the Department may adopt rules, regulations, and standards under this subtitle.</section>
  </text>
</law>
