<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghg" order_by="ghg" level="1">Health - General</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghg-20-214</section_number>
  <catch_line>A person may not be required to perform or participate in, or refer to any source for, any medical p...</catch_line>
  <order_by>214</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A person may not be required to perform or participate in, or refer to any source for, any medical procedure that results in artificial insemination, sterilization, or termination of pregnancy.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The refusal of a person to perform or participate in, or refer to a source for, these medical procedures may not be a basis for:<section prefix="(i)">Civil liability to another person; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">Disciplinary or other recriminatory action against the person.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A licensed hospital, hospital director, or hospital governing board may not be required:<section prefix="(i)">To permit, within the hospital, the performance of any medical procedure that results in artificial insemination, sterilization, or termination of pregnancy; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">To refer to any source for these medical procedures.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The refusal to permit or to refer to a source for these procedures may not be grounds for:<section prefix="(i)">Civil liability to another person; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">Disciplinary or other recriminatory action against the person by this State or any person.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The refusal of an individual to submit to or give consent for an abortion or sterilization may not be grounds for loss of any privileges or immunities to which the individual otherwise would be entitled.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Submitting to or granting consent for an abortion or sterilization may not be a condition precedent to the receipt of any public benefits.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Notwithstanding any other provision of this section, a health care provider, a licensed hospital, a hospital director, or a hospital governing board is not immune from civil damages, if available at law, or from disciplinary or other recriminatory action, if the failure to refer a patient to a source for any medical procedure that results in sterilization or termination of pregnancy would reasonably be determined as:<section prefix="(1)">The cause of death or serious physical injury or serious long-lasting injury to the patient; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Otherwise contrary to the standards of medical care.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
