<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghg" order_by="ghg" level="1">Health - General</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghg-17-205</section_number>
  <catch_line>A person shall hold a license issued by the Secretary before the person may:...</catch_line>
  <order_by>205</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">A person shall hold a license issued by the Secretary before the person may:<section prefix="(1)">Offer or perform medical laboratory tests or examinations in this State;</section><section prefix="(2)">Offer or perform medical laboratory tests or examinations on specimens acquired from health care providers in this State at a medical laboratory located outside this State; or</section><section prefix="(3)">Represent or service in this State a medical laboratory regardless of the laboratory's location.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Secretary shall issue a letter of exception to a laboratory that:<section prefix="(1)">Performs only limited medical laboratory tests or examinations; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Meets the exception requirements in regulations adopted by the Secretary pursuant to this subtitle.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">For the purposes of this section, "limited medical laboratory tests or examinations" means medical laboratory procedures as defined in regulations adopted by the Secretary pursuant to this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">If preliminary screening procedures are performed by an operator who is trained under &#xA7; 17-214(k) of this subtitle, an employer:<section prefix="(1)">Is not required to obtain a permit or to obtain a letter of exception from the Secretary under this section to perform testing; but</section><section prefix="(2)">Is required before performing preliminary screening procedures, as defined under &#xA7; 17-214(a) of this subtitle, to register with the Secretary in accordance with requirements adopted in regulations by the Department of Health and Mental Hygiene.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
