<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghg" order_by="ghg" level="1">Health - General</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghg-7-904</section_number>
  <catch_line>The Secretary shall adopt rules and regulations for the licensing of services for an individual with...</catch_line>
  <order_by>904</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Secretary shall adopt rules and regulations for the licensing of services for an individual with developmental disability or a recipient of individual support services.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The rules and regulations shall ensure that services to an individual with developmental disability or a recipient of individual support services are provided in accordance with the policy stated in Subtitle 1 of this title.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The rules and regulations shall require that:<section prefix="(i)">At least 75% of the governing body of a licensee shall be residents of the State or reside within a 100-mile radius of the administrative offices of the licensee, which shall be located in the State; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">No employee of a licensee or immediate family member of an employee of a licensee may serve as a voting member of the governing body of a licensee unless:<section prefix="1.">The employee receives services from the licensee; or</section><section prefix="2.">The Administration explicitly approves the composition of the governing body through an innovative program service plan in accordance with COMAR 10.22.02.09.F.</section></section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The requirements of paragraph (1)(i) of this subsection may be waived if a community-based advisory board or committee is established by the licensee and approved by the Department.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The rules and regulations shall also require that an applicant for a license under this section shall demonstrate to the Department the applicant's capability to provide for or arrange for the provision of all applicable services required by this chapter by submitting, at a minimum, the following documents to the Department:<section prefix="(1)">A business plan that clearly demonstrates the ability of the applicant to provide services in accordance with Maryland regulations and funding requirements;</section><section prefix="(2)">A summary of the applicant's demonstrated experience in the field of developmental disabilities, in accordance with standards developed by the Department;</section><section prefix="(3)">Prior licensing reports issued within the previous 10 years from any in-State or out-of-state entities associated with the applicant, including deficiency reports and compliance records on which the State may make reasoned decisions about the qualifications of the applicant; and</section><section prefix="(4)">A written quality assurance plan, approved by the Developmental Disabilities Administration, to address how the applicant will ensure the health and safety of the individuals served by the applicant and the quality of services provided to individuals by the applicant.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
