<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="ghg" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="18-204" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghg-18-204</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Cancer report" means a 1-time abstract of the medical record of a patient diagnosed or treated for cancer or a central nervous system tumor which contains:<section prefix="(i)">Reasonably obtained patient demographic information, including risk factors;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Relevant information on the:</section><section prefix="(iii)">Facility and other provider identification information.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">"Central nervous system tumor" means, irrespective of histologic type or behavior, a primary tumor in the following sites:</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">"Central nervous system tumor" includes a primary intracranial tumor.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(4)">"Freestanding ambulatory care facility" has the meaning stated in &#xA7; 19-3B-01 of this article.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Each hospital which has care of a patient with cancer or a central nervous system tumor, each freestanding laboratory, freestanding ambulatory care facility, or therapeutic radiological center which has care of or has diagnosed cancer or a central nervous system tumor for a nonhospitalized patient, and each physician who has care of or has diagnosed cancer or a central nervous system tumor for a nonhospitalized patient not otherwise reported shall:<section prefix="(i)"/><section prefix="(ii)">Effective July 1, 1993, submit a cancer report in a computerized file on a quarterly basis to the Secretary, or an agent of the Secretary, for all patients initially diagnosed, treated, or admitted to a facility for cancer or a central nervous system tumor during that calendar quarter.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">To assure compliance with this section, the Secretary, or an agent of the Secretary, may inspect upon reasonable notice a representative sample of the medical records of patients diagnosed, treated, or admitted for cancer or a central nervous system tumor at the facility.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Information obtained under this subsection shall be confidential and subject to Title 4, Subtitle 1 of this article.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">This subsection does not apply to a disclosure by the Secretary to another governmental agency performing its lawful duties pursuant to State or federal law where the Secretary determines that the agency to whom the information is disclosed will maintain the confidentiality of the disclosure.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">A cancer report is not a medical record under Title 4, Subtitle 3 of this article, but is subject to the confidentiality requirements of Title 4, Subtitle 1 of this article.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(4)">Each hospital, freestanding laboratory, freestanding ambulatory care facility, therapeutic radiological center, or physician who in good faith submits a cancer report to the Secretary is not liable in any cause of action arising from the submission of the report.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">The Secretary, after consultation with the Cancer Registry Advisory Committee, the Maryland Hospital Association, and representatives of freestanding laboratories and therapeutic radiological centers, shall adopt regulations to implement the requirements of this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(6)">The Secretary, in accordance with &#xA7; 2-1246 of the State Government Article, shall submit an annual report to the Governor and General Assembly on the activities of the cancer registry, including utilization of cancer registry data.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
