<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gho" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="7-306" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gho-7-306</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">An individual shall obtain an apprentice license from the Board before beginning an apprenticeship in this State.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">An applicant for a mortician apprentice license shall have a sponsor with a current mortician license.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">An applicant for a funeral director license shall have a sponsor with a current mortician or funeral director license.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">An applicant for an apprentice license shall pay to the Board a fee set by the Board.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Prior to an individual appearing before the Board for approval of an apprentice license, the individual must complete two-thirds of the academic credits for a mortuary science program at a school accredited by the American Board of Funeral Service or approved by the Board, with a 2.0 grade point average or higher that is verified with a certified copy of the college transcript.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The applicant shall appear before the Board with the applicant's sponsor. The sponsor shall hold a current valid mortician license in Maryland and shall be employed by the same funeral home that employs the apprentice.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The practical experience of an apprentice shall include:<section prefix="(i)">Participation in at least 20 funerals;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Except as provided in paragraph (4) of this subsection, assistance in the preparation of at least 20 dead human bodies for final disposition; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Completion of 1,000 working hours in a licensed funeral establishment under the direct supervision of a licensed mortician or funeral director.  Supervision may include instruction by other licensed morticians or funeral directors employed or supervised by the sponsor.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">For an apprentice funeral director, the practical experience under paragraph (3)(ii) of this subsection may not include embalming.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">On termination of the sponsor-apprentice relationship, both the sponsor and the apprentice shall independently notify the Board in writing of:<section prefix="(i)">The date of termination;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The name, date of death, and date of service for each decedent for whom a funeral service was conducted under paragraph (3)(i) of this subsection in which the apprentice participated; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">The name, date of death, and date of the preparation for disposition of each decedent for whom the apprentice assisted in accordance with paragraph (3)(ii) of this subsection.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(6)">Prior approval must be granted by the Board before a change of sponsorship occurs.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">While the license is effective, an apprentice license authorizes the licensee to assist a licensed mortician or funeral director in the practice of mortuary science or funeral direction only as part of a training program to become a licensed mortician or funeral director.</section>
  </text>
</law>
