<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gho" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="14-5A-13" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gho-14-5A-13</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">A license expires on a date set by the Board, unless the license is renewed for an additional term as provided in this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">At least 1 month before the license expires, the Board shall send to the licensee a renewal notice that states:<section prefix="(1)">The date on which the current license expires;</section><section prefix="(2)">The date by which the renewal application must be received by the Board for the renewal to be issued and mailed before the license expires; and</section><section prefix="(3)">The amount of the renewal fee.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Except as otherwise provided in this subtitle, before a license expires, the licensee periodically may renew it for an additional term, if the licensee:<section prefix="(1)">Pays to the Board a renewal fee set by the Board;</section><section prefix="(2)">Submits to the Board:<section prefix="(i)">A renewal application on the form that the Board requires; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Satisfactory evidence of compliance with any continuing education or competency requirements and other requirements set under this section for license renewal; and</section></section><section prefix="(3)">Meets any additional renewal requirements established by the Board.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In addition to any other qualifications and requirements established by the Board, the Board may establish continuing education or competency requirements as a condition to the renewal of licenses under this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Board may impose a civil penalty of up to $100 per continuing education credit in lieu of a sanction under &#xA7; 14-5A-17 of this subtitle, for a first offense, for the failure of a licensee to obtain the continuing education credits required by the Board.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Board shall renew the license of each licensee who meets the requirements of this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A license may not be renewed for a term longer than 2 years.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The Board shall reinstate the license of a respiratory care practitioner who has failed to renew the license for any reason if the respiratory care practitioner:<section prefix="(1)">Meets the renewal requirements of this section;</section><section prefix="(2)">Submits to the Board:<section prefix="(i)">A reinstatement application on the form that the Board requires; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Satisfactory evidence of compliance with any continuing education or competency requirements; and</section></section><section prefix="(3)">Meets any additional requirements established by the Board for reinstatement.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
