<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gho" order_by="gho" level="1">Health Occupations</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gho-19-101</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this title the following words have the meanings indicated....</catch_line>
  <order_by>101</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this title the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Board" means the State Board of Social Work Examiners.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Certified" means having demonstrated to the satisfaction of the Board that the individual has completed 2 years of supervised social work practice as defined in &#xA7; 19-302(d) or (e) of this title.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">"License" means, unless the context requires otherwise, one of four types of licenses issued by the Board authorizing an individual to practice:<section prefix="(1)">Associate social work;</section><section prefix="(2)">Graduate social work;</section><section prefix="(3)">Certified social work; or</section><section prefix="(4)">Certified social work-clinical.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"Licensed associate social worker" means an individual licensed by the Board to practice associate social work.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">"Licensed certified social worker" means an individual licensed by the Board to practice certified social work.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">"Licensed certified social worker-clinical" means an individual licensed by the Board to practice clinical social work.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">"Licensed graduate social worker" means an individual licensed by the Board to practice graduate social work.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">"Practice associate social work" means to practice social work:<section prefix="(1)">Under the supervision of a licensed certified social worker, licensed certified social worker-clinical, or licensed graduate social worker who meets the conditions specified in regulations; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Utilizing the education and training required under &#xA7; 19-302(b) of this title.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(j)">"Practice certified social work" means to practice social work utilizing the education, training, and experience required under &#xA7; 19-302(d) or (e) of this title.</section>
    <section prefix="(k)">"Practice clinical social work" means to practice social work utilizing the specialized education, training, and experience required under &#xA7; 19-302(e) of this title.</section>
    <section prefix="(l)">"Practice graduate social work" means to practice social work:<section prefix="(1)">Under the supervision of a licensed certified social worker, licensed certified social worker-clinical, or licensed graduate social worker who meets the conditions specified in regulations; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Utilizing the education and training required under &#xA7; 19-302(c) of this title.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(m)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Practice social work" means to apply the theories, knowledge, procedures, methods, or ethics derived from a formal educational program in social work to restore or enhance social functioning of individuals, couples, families, groups, organizations, or communities through:<section prefix="(i)">Assessment;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Formulating diagnostic impressions;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Planning;</section><section prefix="(iv)">Intervention;</section><section prefix="(v)">Evaluation of intervention plans;</section><section prefix="(vi)">Case management;</section><section prefix="(vii)">Information and referral;</section><section prefix="(viii)">Counseling that does not include diagnosis or treatment of mental disorders;</section><section prefix="(ix)">Advocacy;</section><section prefix="(x)">Consultation;</section><section prefix="(xi)">Education;</section><section prefix="(xii)">Research;</section><section prefix="(xiii)">Community organization; or</section><section prefix="(xiv)">Development, implementation, and administration of policies, programs, and activities.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">For an individual licensed as a graduate social worker, "practice social work" also includes:<section prefix="(i)">Supervision of other social workers if the graduate social worker meets the requirements set out in regulations; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Treatment of psychosocial conditions and mental disorders and the provision of psychotherapy under the direct supervision of a licensed certified social worker-clinical.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">For an individual licensed as a certified social worker, "practice social work" also includes:<section prefix="(i)">Supervision of other social workers; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Treatment of psychosocial conditions and mental disorders and the provision of psychotherapy under the direct supervision of a licensed certified social worker-clinical.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">For an individual licensed as a certified social worker-clinical, "practice social work" also includes:<section prefix="(i)">Supervision of other social workers;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Evaluation, diagnosis, and treatment of psychosocial conditions, mental and emotional conditions and impairments, and mental disorders as defined in &#xA7; 10-101(f) of the Health - General Article; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">The provision of psychotherapy.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(n)">"Psychotherapy" means a method for the treatment of mental disorders and behavioral disturbances in which a licensed health care practitioner enters into a professional contract with the patient and, through a therapeutic communication or interaction, attempts to:<section prefix="(1)">Alleviate emotional disturbances;</section><section prefix="(2)">Reverse or alter maladaptive patterns of behavior; or</section><section prefix="(3)">Encourage personality growth and development.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(o)">"Supervision" means a formalized professional relationship between a supervisor and a supervisee that:<section prefix="(1)">Provides evaluation and direction of the supervisee; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Promotes continued development of the supervisee's knowledge, skills, and abilities to provide social work services in an ethical and competent manner.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
