<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gho" order_by="gho" level="1">Health Occupations</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gho-19-308</section_number>
  <catch_line>A license expires on the date set by the Board, unless the license is renewed for an additional term...</catch_line>
  <order_by>308</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">A license expires on the date set by the Board, unless the license is renewed for an additional term as provided in this section. A license may not be renewed for a term longer than 2 years.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">At least 1 month before the license expires, the Board shall send to the licensee, by first-class mail to the last known address of the licensee, a renewal notice that states:<section prefix="(1)">The date on which the current license expires;</section><section prefix="(2)">The date by which the renewal application must be received by the Board for the renewal to be issued and mailed before the license expires; and</section><section prefix="(3)">The amount of the renewal fee.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Each licensee shall notify the Board of any change in the address of the licensee within 60 days after the change occurs.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Before the license expires, the licensee periodically may renew it for an additional 2-year term, if the licensee:<section prefix="(1)">Otherwise is entitled to be licensed;</section><section prefix="(2)">Pays to the Board the appropriate renewal fee specified by this subtitle; and</section><section prefix="(3)">Submits to the Board:<section prefix="(i)">A renewal application on the form that the Board requires; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Satisfactory evidence of compliance with any continuing education requirement set under this section for license renewal.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Board shall renew the license of and issue a renewal certificate to each licensee who meets the requirements of this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Board shall include the term of the renewal on each renewal certificate that the Board issues.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
