<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gho" order_by="" level="1">Health Occupations</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gho-7-303</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>303</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Board shall determine the qualifications necessary for an individual to lawfully engage in the practice of mortuary science or funeral direction and to operate a funeral establishment within this State.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Except as otherwise provided in this subtitle, to qualify for a mortician or funeral director license, an applicant shall be an individual who meets the requirements of this section.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Board shall examine all applications for licensure for the practice of mortuary science or funeral direction and shall issue the mortician or funeral director license to an individual who:<section prefix="(1)">Is judged to be of good moral character;</section><section prefix="(2)">Has completed not less than 1 year and not more than 2 years of licensed apprenticeship, unless the Board allowed extensions for additional 1-year terms;</section><section prefix="(3)">Except as otherwise provided in this section, has graduated with an associate of arts degree in mortuary science or its equivalent from a school accredited by the American Board of Funeral Service Education or approved by the Board, or has acquired at least an associate of arts degree and completed a course in mortuary science that is accredited by the American Board of Funeral Service Education or approved by the Board;</section><section prefix="(4)">For an individual applying for a license to practice as a mortician, passed the national board examination administered by the Conference of Funeral Service Examining Boards of the United States;</section><section prefix="(5)">For an individual applying for a license to practice as a funeral director, passed the arts and sciences State board examinations, administered by the Conference of Funeral Service Examining Boards of the United States;</section><section prefix="(6)">Except as provided in subsection (c) of this section, has passed a written examination on Maryland law and regulations governing the practice of mortuary science and a practical examination demonstrating competency in the preparation of dead human bodies for final disposition and sanitary science; and</section><section prefix="(7)">Has submitted an application to the Board on the required form and has paid a fee set by the Board.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">For an individual applying for a license to practice funeral direction, the practical examination qualification under subsection (b)(6) of this section may not include demonstrating competency in embalming.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Board shall advise each applicant that a license issued under subsection (b) of this section does not guarantee that the applicant will be allowed to practice in any other state.</section>
  </text>
</law>
