<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gho" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="13-101" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gho-13-101</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this title the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Board" means the State Board of Physical Therapy Examiners.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"License" means, unless the context requires otherwise, a license issued by the Board to practice:<section prefix="(1)">Physical therapy; or</section><section prefix="(2)">Limited physical therapy.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">"Licensed physical therapist" means, unless the context requires otherwise, a physical therapist who is licensed by the Board to practice physical therapy.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"Licensed physical therapist assistant" means, unless the context requires otherwise, a physical therapist assistant who is licensed by the Board to practice limited physical therapy.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">"Physical therapist" means an individual, licensed by the State Board of Physical Therapy Examiners, who practices physical therapy and who has passed the national physical therapy licensing examination administered or accepted by the Board.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">"Physical therapist assistant" means an individual who practices limited physical therapy and who has passed the national physical therapy licensing examination administered or accepted by the Board.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Practice limited physical therapy" means to implement therapeutic interventions for the purpose of:<section prefix="(i)">The prevention of disability in patients or clients; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">The physical rehabilitation of patients or clients with a congenital or acquired disability.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Practice limited physical therapy" includes, except as provided in paragraph (3) of this subsection:<section prefix="(i)">Taking and documenting measurements; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Administering therapeutic interventions that include therapeutic exercise, therapeutic massage, mechanical devices, or therapeutic agents that use the physical, chemical, or other properties of air, water, electricity, sound, or radiant energy.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Practice limited physical therapy" does not include:<section prefix="(i)">Interpreting measurements;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Planning treatment programs;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Taking X rays;</section><section prefix="(iv)">Using radioactive substances; or</section><section prefix="(v)">Using electricity for cauterization or surgery.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(i)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Practice physical therapy" means to design, implement, and modify therapeutic interventions for the purpose of:<section prefix="(i)">The prevention of disability in patients or clients; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">The physical rehabilitation of patients or clients with a congenital or acquired disability.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Practice physical therapy" includes:<section prefix="(i)">Performing an evaluation of the physical therapy needs of patients or clients;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Performing and interpreting tests and measurements of neuromuscular and musculoskeletal functions to aid treatment;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Planning treatment programs that are based on test findings; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">Except as provided in paragraph (3) of this subsection, administering therapeutic interventions that include therapeutic exercise, therapeutic massage, mechanical devices, or therapeutic agents that use the physical, chemical, or other properties of air, water, electricity, sound, or radiant energy.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Practice physical therapy" does not include:<section prefix="(i)">Taking X rays;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Using radioactive substances; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">Using electricity for cauterization or surgery.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(j)">"Restricted license" means a license issued by the Board under and as limited by &#xA7; 13-314 of this title to practice physical therapy.</section>
  </text>
</law>
