<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gho" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="11-404.2" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gho-11-404.2</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, "refer" means that a therapeutically certified optometrist:<section prefix="(1)">Informs the patient that the patient should see an ophthalmologist and give the ophthalmologist an opportunity to physically examine the patient; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Refrains from rendering further treatment for the specific condition that is the basis for the referral until the patient has been physically examined by an ophthalmologist.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A therapeutically certified optometrist may administer and prescribe topical therapeutic pharmaceutical agents limited to:<section prefix="(i)">Ocular antihistamines, decongestants, and combinations thereof;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Ocular antiallergy pharmaceutical agents;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Ocular antibiotics and combinations of ocular antibiotics, excluding specially formulated or fortified antibiotics;</section><section prefix="(iv)">Anti-inflammatory agents;</section><section prefix="(v)">Ocular lubricants and artificial tears;</section><section prefix="(vi)">Tropicamide;</section><section prefix="(vii)">Homatropine;</section><section prefix="(viii)">Nonprescription drugs that are commercially available; and</section><section prefix="(ix)">Primary open-angle glaucoma medications, in accordance with subsection (c) of this section.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Except as provided in paragraph (4) of this subsection, if a therapeutically certified optometrist administers or prescribes a topical therapeutic pharmaceutical agent listed in paragraph (1)(i) through (vii) of this subsection, and the patient does not have the expected response within 72 hours:<section prefix="(i)">The therapeutically certified optometrist shall consult with an ophthalmologist; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">The ophthalmologist may determine that the ophthalmologist needs to physically examine the patient.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Except as provided in paragraph (4) of this subsection, if a therapeutically certified optometrist administers or prescribes a topical therapeutic pharmaceutical agent under paragraph (2) of this subsection, the therapeutically certified optometrist shall communicate with the patient to determine the response of the patient to the therapeutic pharmaceutical agent as soon as practicable after 72 hours of the time the agent was administered or prescribed.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">A therapeutically certified optometrist may administer or prescribe topical steroids in accordance with a practice protocol established by the Board.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">A therapeutically certified optometrist may not administer or prescribe:<section prefix="(i)">Antiviral agents;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Antifungal agents;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Antimetabolite agents; or</section><section prefix="(iv)">Antiparasitic agents.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(6)">A therapeutically certified optometrist may dispense a topical therapeutic pharmaceutical agent listed in paragraph (1) of this subsection only if:<section prefix="(i)">No charge is imposed for the therapeutic pharmaceutical agent or for dispensing the agent; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">The amount dispensed does not exceed a 72-hour supply, except that if the minimum available quantity for dispensing is greater than a 72-hour supply, the minimum available quantity may be dispensed.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A therapeutically certified optometrist may administer and prescribe topical therapeutic pharmaceutical agents for glaucoma only:<section prefix="(i)">For patients with primary open-angle glaucoma;</section><section prefix="(ii)">After the optometrist refers the patient to an ophthalmologist; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">After the ophthalmologist and optometrist jointly and promptly develop a written individualized treatment plan that is signed by the ophthalmologist and optometrist and includes:</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">A treatment plan developed under this subsection may be modified only after both the optometrist and the ophthalmologist consult together and consent to the modification.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">Each modification shall be noted in the optometric record of the patient.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A therapeutically certified optometrist who treats a patient with primary open-angle glaucoma in accordance with this section:<section prefix="(i)">Shall refer the patient to an ophthalmologist at least once a year after the initial mandatory referral under paragraph (1) of this subsection;</section><section prefix="(ii)">May continue to render treatment under the joint treatment plan until the patient is examined by an ophthalmologist;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Shall consult with an ophthalmologist if:</section><section prefix="(iv)">May perform and evaluate visual field tests, nerve fiber layer photos, and optic disc photos. The tests or photos shall be provided to an ophthalmologist for review by the ophthalmologist.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in paragraphs (2) and (3) of this subsection, a therapeutically certified optometrist may not administer or prescribe any oral pharmaceutical agent for any purpose.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">A therapeutically certified optometrist may administer and prescribe oral tetracycline and its derivatives only for the diagnosis and treatment of meibomitis and seborrheic blepharitis.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">If a therapeutically certified optometrist administers or prescribes oral tetracycline or its derivatives to a patient in accordance with subparagraph (i) of this paragraph and the patient does not improve within 3 weeks of treatment, the optometrist shall refer the patient to an ophthalmologist.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A therapeutically certified optometrist may administer or prescribe nonprescription drugs that are commercially available.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, a therapeutically certified optometrist may not perform any procedure on the eyelid of a patient.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A therapeutically certified optometrist may epilate with forceps an eyelash from the eyelid, adnexa, or lacrimal system of a patient.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">A therapeutically certified optometrist may remove superficial foreign bodies from the human eye only if:<section prefix="(1)">The foreign body may be removed with a cotton-tipped applicator or blunt spatula; and</section><section prefix="(2)">The foreign body has not penetrated beyond the bowman's membrane of the cornea and is not within 2.5 millimeters of the visual axis.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, a therapeutically certified optometrist may not order laboratory tests for a patient.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A therapeutically certified optometrist may order a conjunctival culture.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(h)">A therapeutically certified optometrist may not provide any therapeutic treatment listed in this section for a child under the age of 1 year.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">Unless the standard of care requires an earlier referral, if a therapeutically certified optometrist diagnoses a corneal ulcer or infiltrate, and the patient does not have the expected response within 48 hours, the optometrist immediately shall refer the patient to an ophthalmologist.</section>
    <section prefix="(j)">A therapeutically certified optometrist shall be held to the same standard of care as an ophthalmologist who is licensed under Title 14 of this article and who is providing similar services.</section>
  </text>
</law>
