<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gho" order_by="" level="1">Health Occupations</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gho-14-5B-05</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>05</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">There is a Radiation Therapy, Radiography, Nuclear Medicine Technology Advisory, and Radiology Assistance Committee within the Board.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Committee consists of 10 members appointed by the Board.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Of the 10 members:<section prefix="(i)">One shall be a licensed physician who specializes in radiology;</section><section prefix="(ii)">One shall be a licensed physician who specializes in radiology and who supervises a radiologist assistant;</section><section prefix="(iii)">One shall be a licensed physician who specializes in nuclear medicine;</section><section prefix="(iv)">One shall be a licensed physician who specializes in radiation oncology;</section><section prefix="(v)">One shall be a radiation therapist;</section><section prefix="(vi)">One shall be a radiographer;</section><section prefix="(vii)">One shall be a radiologist assistant;</section><section prefix="(viii)">One shall be a nuclear medicine technologist;</section><section prefix="(ix)">One shall be a consumer member; and</section><section prefix="(x)">One shall be a member of the Board.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">From among its members, the Committee shall elect a chair once every 2 years.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The consumer member of the Committee:<section prefix="(1)">Shall be a member of the general public;</section><section prefix="(2)">May not be or ever have been a health care professional or in training to be a health care professional; and</section><section prefix="(3)">May not:<section prefix="(i)">Participate or ever have participated in a commercial or professional field related to radiation therapy, radiography, nuclear medicine technology, or radiology assistance;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Have a household member who participates in a commercial or professional field related to radiation therapy, radiography, nuclear medicine technology, or radiology assistance; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">Have had within 2 years before appointment a financial interest in a person regulated by the Board.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The term of a member is 3 years.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The terms of members are staggered as required by regulation.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">At the end of a term, a member continues to serve until a successor is appointed and qualifies.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">A member may not serve more than 2 consecutive full terms.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
