<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gho" order_by="" level="1">Health Occupations</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gho-7-101</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>101</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this title the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Apprentice" means an individual licensed by the Board who assists a licensed mortician or funeral director in the practice of mortuary science or funeral direction, under direct supervision of a licensed mortician or funeral director.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Apprentice sponsor" means a person who:<section prefix="(1)">Is a licensed mortician or funeral director practicing mortuary science as a licensed mortician or funeral director in Maryland at least 1 year immediately prior to accepting the applicant as an apprentice; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Provides direct supervision to an apprentice.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">"Board" means the Maryland State Board of Morticians and Funeral Directors.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Business of operating a crematory" means controlling or managing a crematory.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Business of operating a crematory" does not include:<section prefix="(i)">The practice of funeral direction or the practice of mortuary science; or</section><section prefix="(ii)"><section prefix="1.">Assistance in making decisions and filling out forms that are not directly related to cremation;</section><section prefix="2.">Obtaining vital statistics, signatures, and other information necessary to complete a death certificate;</section><section prefix="3.">Transportation of a body to the place of disposition; or</section><section prefix="4.">Any other services regarding the disposition of a body that are not directly related to cremation.</section></section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Corporation" means a mortuary science business whose articles of incorporation are in good standing with the Maryland State Department of Assessments and Taxation, or its successor, the initial business for which the license is issued must have been incorporated on or before June 1, 1945 and have "Incorporated", "Inc.", or "Corporation" in its name.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Corporation" does not include, for purposes of issuing a corporation license, a "professional association" (P.A.) or a "professional corporation" (P.C.).</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">"Courtesy card" means a license issued by the Board to licensed practitioners of mortuary science in other states, to make a removal of a dead human body in this State and to return the body to another state or country, to return dead bodies from another state or country to this State, to fill out the family history portion of the death certificate, and to sign the death certificate in the holder's capacity as a licensed practitioner of mortuary science.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">"Cremation" means the process of reducing human remains to bone fragments through intense heat and evaporation, including any mechanical or thermal process.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">"Crematory" means a building, portion of a building, or structure that houses the necessary appliances and facilities for cremation.</section>
    <section prefix="(j)">"Funeral director" means an individual who is licensed by the Board to practice all aspects of mortuary science except for embalming.</section>
    <section prefix="(k)">"Funeral establishment" means any building, structure, or premises from which the business of practicing mortuary science is conducted.</section>
    <section prefix="(l)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Human remains" means:<section prefix="(i)">The body of a deceased person; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">A part of a body or limb that has been removed from a living person.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Human remains" includes the body or part of a body or limb in any state of decomposition.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(m)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"License" means, unless the context requires otherwise, a license issued by the Board.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"License" includes, unless otherwise indicated:<section prefix="(i)">A mortician license;</section><section prefix="(ii)">An apprentice license;</section><section prefix="(iii)">A funeral director license;</section><section prefix="(iv)">A surviving spouse license;</section><section prefix="(v)">A corporation license;</section><section prefix="(vi)">A funeral establishment license; and</section><section prefix="(vii)">A courtesy card.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(n)">"Licensed apprentice" means, unless the context requires otherwise, an apprentice who is licensed by the Board to assist a licensed mortician or funeral director in the practice of mortuary science or funeral direction.</section>
    <section prefix="(o)">"Licensed funeral director" means, unless the context requires otherwise, a funeral director who is licensed by the Board to practice funeral direction.</section>
    <section prefix="(p)">"Licensed funeral establishment" means, unless the context requires otherwise, a funeral establishment that is licensed by the Board.</section>
    <section prefix="(q)">"Licensed mortician" means, unless the context requires otherwise, a mortician who is licensed by the Board under this title to practice mortuary science.</section>
    <section prefix="(r)">"Licensee" means an individual or entity licensed by the Board to practice mortuary science to the extent determined by the Board.</section>
    <section prefix="(s)">"Mortician" means an individual who practices mortuary science.</section>
    <section prefix="(t)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Practice funeral direction" means:<section prefix="(i)">To operate a funeral establishment;</section><section prefix="(ii)">For compensation, to prepare a dead human body for disposition; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">For compensation, to arrange for or make final disposition of a dead human body.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Practice funeral direction" does not include:<section prefix="(i)">For compensation, disinfecting or preserving a dead human body or any of its parts by arterial or cavity injection or any other type of preservation; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">The business of operating a crematory.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(u)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Practice mortuary science" means:<section prefix="(i)">To operate a funeral establishment;</section><section prefix="(ii)">For compensation, to prepare a dead human body for disposition; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">For compensation, to arrange for or make final disposition of a dead human body.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Practice mortuary science" includes:<section prefix="(i)">The practice of funeral direction; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Disinfecting or preserving a dead human body or any of its parts by arterial or cavity injection.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Practice mortuary science" does not include:<section prefix="(i)">The pickup, removal, or transportation of a dead human body, if the unlicensed individual is acting under the direction of a licensed mortician or funeral director; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">The business of operating a crematory.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(v)">"Pre-need contract" means an agreement between a consumer and a licensed funeral director, licensed mortician, or surviving spouse to provide any goods and services purchased prior to the time of death. Goods and services shall include:<section prefix="(1)">A service, including any form of preservation and disposition or cremation, that a mortician normally provides in the ordinary course of business; or</section><section prefix="(2)">Merchandise, including a casket, vault, or clothing, that a mortician normally provides in the ordinary course of business.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(w)">"Surviving spouse" means the legal widow or widower of a licensed funeral director or licensed mortician, whose license was in good standing at the time of death, and who at the time of death, wholly or partly owned and operated a mortuary science business.</section>
  </text>
</law>
