<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gho" order_by="" level="1">Health Occupations</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gho-12-6C-03</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>03</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">A wholesale distributor shall hold a permit issued by the  Board before the wholesale distributor engages in wholesale  distribution in the State.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A manufacturer engaged in wholesale distribution shall hold a wholesale distributor permit issued under this subtitle.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Notwithstanding paragraph (1) of this subsection, the information and qualification requirements for obtaining a permit under this subtitle, beyond that required by federal law, do not apply to:<section prefix="(i)">A manufacturer that distributes its own prescription drugs that are approved by the U.S. Food and Drug Administration; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">A manufacturer that distributes its own prescription devices that are approved or authorized by the U.S. Food and Drug Administration.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A manufacturer's exclusive distributor and a third-party  logistics provider shall hold a wholesale distributor permit issued  under this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A wholesale distributor permit shall be displayed  conspicuously in the place of business for which the permit is  issued.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">A wholesale distributor permit is not transferable.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">Subject to any other restriction provided by law, a  person may not purchase or obtain a prescription drug or  prescription device unless the prescription drug or prescription  device is  purchased or obtained from a person who holds a  wholesale distributor permit, a licensed pharmacist, or an  authorized prescriber.</section>
  </text>
</law>
