<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gho" order_by="" level="1">Health Occupations</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gho-2-304</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>304</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">An applicant who otherwise qualifies for a license is entitled to be examined as provided in this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">For the examination of applicants for a license to practice audiology or speech-language pathology, the Board may adopt appropriate examinations given by a professional body in the field of audiology or the field of speech-language pathology.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">An examination shall be in writing and consist of tests that require an applicant to demonstrate the minimum knowledge of services and subject matter related to the practice of audiology or speech-language pathology that will enable the applicant to practice audiology or speech-language pathology effectively.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Board may supplement any written examination given under this section with an oral examination.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Board shall notify each qualified applicant of the time and place of examination.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Board:<section prefix="(1)">Shall determine the subjects, scope, form, and passing scores for examinations given under this subtitle; or</section><section prefix="(2)">May adopt an examination given by a national body.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The Board may not limit the number of times an applicant may take an examination required under this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">An applicant who otherwise qualifies for a license to practice hearing aid dispensing is entitled to be examined as provided in this subsection.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The examination shall consist of a written part and a practical part as required by regulations by the Board.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
