<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gho" order_by="" level="1">Health Occupations</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gho-14-316</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>316</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Board shall provide for the term and renewal of licenses under this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The term of a license may not be more than 3 years.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A license expires at the end of its term, unless the license is renewed for a term as provided by the Board.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">At least 1 month before the license expires, the Board shall send to the licensee, by first-class mail to the last known address of the licensee:<section prefix="(1)">A renewal notice that states:<section prefix="(i)">The date on which the current license expires;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The date by which the renewal application must be received by the Board for the renewal to be issued and mailed before the license expires; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">The amount of the renewal fee; and</section></section><section prefix="(2)">A blank panel data sheet supplied by the Health Care Alternative Dispute Resolution Office.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Before the license expires, the licensee periodically may renew it for an additional term, if the licensee:<section prefix="(1)">Otherwise is entitled to be licensed;</section><section prefix="(2)">Pays to the Board a renewal fee set by the Board; and</section><section prefix="(3)">Submits to the Board:<section prefix="(i)">A renewal application on the form that the Board requires; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Satisfactory evidence of compliance with any continuing education requirements set under this section for license renewal.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In addition to any other qualifications and requirements established by the Board, the Board may establish continuing education requirements as a condition to the renewal of licenses under this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">In establishing these requirements, the Board shall evaluate existing methods, devices, and programs in use among the various medical specialties and other recognized medical groups.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Board may not establish or enforce these requirements if they would so reduce the number of physicians in a community as to jeopardize the availability of adequate medical care in that community.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The Board may impose a civil penalty of up to $100 per continuing medical education credit in lieu of a sanction under  &#xA7; 14-404 of this title, for a first offense, for the failure of a licensee to obtain the continuing medical education credits required by the Board.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The Board shall renew the license of each licensee who meets the requirements of this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Each licensee shall notify the secretary of the Board in writing of any change in the licensee's name or address within 60 days after the change.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If a licensee fails to notify the secretary of the Board within the time required under this section, the licensee is subject to an administrative penalty of $100.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
