<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gho" order_by="gho" level="1">Health Occupations</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gho-14-413</section_number>
  <catch_line>Every 6 months, each hospital and related institution shall file with the Board a report that:...</catch_line>
  <order_by>413</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Every 6 months, each hospital and related institution shall file with the Board a report that:<section prefix="(i)">Contains the name of each licensed physician who, during the 6 months preceding the report:<section prefix="1.">Is employed by the hospital or related institution;</section><section prefix="2.">Has privileges with the hospital or related institution; and</section><section prefix="3.">Has applied for privileges with the hospital or related institution; and</section></section><section prefix="(ii)">States whether, as to each licensed physician, during the 6 months preceding the report:<section prefix="1.">The hospital or related institution denied the application of a physician for staff privileges or limited, reduced, otherwise changed, or terminated the staff privileges of a physician, or the physician resigned whether or not under formal accusation, if the denial, limitation, reduction, change, termination, or resignation is for reasons that might be grounds for disciplinary action under &#xA7; 14-404 of this subtitle;</section><section prefix="2.">The hospital or related institution took any disciplinary action against a salaried, licensed physician without staff privileges, including termination of employment, suspension, or probation, for reasons that might be grounds for disciplinary action under &#xA7; 14-404 of this subtitle;</section><section prefix="3.">The hospital or related institution took any disciplinary action against an individual in a postgraduate medical training program, including removal from the training program, suspension, or probation for reasons that might be grounds for disciplinary action under &#xA7; 14-404 of this subtitle;</section><section prefix="4.">A licensed physician or an individual in a postgraduate training program voluntarily resigned from the staff, employ, or training program of the hospital or related institution for reasons that might be grounds for disciplinary action under &#xA7; 14-404 of this subtitle; or</section><section prefix="5.">The hospital or related institution placed any other restrictions or conditions on any of the licensed physicians as listed in items 1 through 4 of this subparagraph for any reasons that might be grounds for disciplinary action under &#xA7; 14-404 of this subtitle.</section></section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The hospital or related institution shall:<section prefix="(i)">Submit the report within 10 days of any action described in paragraph (1)(ii) of this subsection; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">State in the report the reasons for its action or the nature of the formal accusation pending when the physician resigned.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Board may extend the reporting time under this subsection for good cause shown.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The minutes or notes taken in the course of determining the denial, limitation, reduction, or termination of the staff privileges of any physician in a hospital or related institution are not subject to review or discovery by any person.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Each court shall report to the Board each conviction of or entry of a plea of guilty or nolo contendere by a physician for any crime involving moral turpitude.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The court shall submit the report within 10 days of the conviction or entry of the plea.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Board may enforce this section by subpoena.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Any person shall have the immunity from liability described under &#xA7; 5-715(d) of the Courts and Judicial Proceedings Article for giving any of the information required by this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">A report made under this section is not subject to subpoena or discovery in any civil action other than a proceeding arising out of a hearing and decision of the Board under this title.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Board may impose a civil penalty of up to $5,000 for failure to report under this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Board shall remit any penalty collected under this subsection into the General Fund of the State.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
