<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gho" order_by="gho" level="1">Health Occupations</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gho-7-4A-06</section_number>
  <catch_line>Subject to the provisions of this subtitle, a person may recover compensation from the Fund for an a...</catch_line>
  <order_by>06</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Subject to the provisions of this subtitle, a person may recover compensation from the Fund for an actual pre-need trust fund loss that occurred on or after January 1, 2010, and is based on an act or omission as described in subsection (b) of this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A claim for the loss shall:<section prefix="(1)">Be based on an act or omission that occurs in the provision of funeral pre-need services by:<section prefix="(i)">A licensed mortician;</section><section prefix="(ii)">A licensed funeral director;</section><section prefix="(iii)">A licensed apprentice mortician;</section><section prefix="(iv)">A licensed apprentice funeral director; or</section><section prefix="(v)">An unlicensed employee of a licensed funeral establishment;</section></section><section prefix="(2)">Involve a transaction that relates to pre-need funeral planning that occurred in the State; and</section><section prefix="(3)">Be based on an act or omission:<section prefix="(i)">In which pre-need money is obtained from a person by theft, embezzlement, false pretenses, or forgery; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">That constitutes fraud or misrepresentation.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The amount recovered for any claim against the Fund:<section prefix="(1)">May not exceed the actual monetary loss suffered; and</section><section prefix="(2)">May not include noneconomic, consequential, or punitive damages.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A funeral establishment shall include in each sales contract that is provided by the funeral establishment a written notice to the buyer that the buyer may file a claim with the Fund.</section>
  </text>
</law>
