<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gho" order_by="" level="1">Health Occupations</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gho-1-306</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>306</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Anatomic pathology services" means:<section prefix="(i)">Histopathology or surgical pathology;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Cytopathology;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Hematology;</section><section prefix="(iv)">Subcellular pathology and molecular pathology; or</section><section prefix="(v)">Blood-banking services performed by pathologists.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Clinical laboratory" means a facility that provides anatomic pathology services.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">
        <section prefix="(i)">"Cytopathology" means the microscopic examination of cells from fluids, aspirates, washings, brushings, or smears.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">"Cytopathology" includes the microscopic examination of cells in a Pap test examination performed by a physician or under the direct supervision of a physician.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(5)">"Hematology" means:<section prefix="(i)">The microscopic evaluation of bone marrow aspirates and biopsies performed by a physician or under the direct supervision of a physician; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">Review of a peripheral blood smear if a physician or technologist requests that a pathologist review a blood smear.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(6)">"Histopathology or surgical pathology" means gross and microscopic examination of organ tissue performed by a physician or under the direct supervision of a physician.</section>
      <section prefix="(7)">
        <section prefix="(i)">"Referring laboratory" means a clinical laboratory that sends a specimen to another clinical laboratory for histologic processing or anatomic pathology consultation.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">"Referring laboratory" does not include a laboratory of a physician's office or a group practice that collects a specimen and orders, but does not perform, anatomic pathology services for patients.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Nothing in this section may be construed to:<section prefix="(1)">Mandate the assignment of benefits for anatomic pathology services; or</section><section prefix="(2)">Prohibit a health care practitioner who performs or supervises anatomic pathology services and is a member of a group practice, as defined under &#xA7; 1-301 of this subtitle, from reassigning the right to bill for anatomic pathology services to the group practice if the billing complies with the requirements of subsection (c) of this section.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A clinical laboratory, a physician, or a group practice located in this State or in another state that provides anatomic pathology services for a patient in this State shall present, or cause to be presented, a claim, bill, or demand for payment for the services to:<section prefix="(1)">Subject to the limitations of &#xA7; 19-710(p) of the Health - General Article, the patient directly unless otherwise prohibited by law;</section><section prefix="(2)">A responsible insurer or other third-party payor;</section><section prefix="(3)">A hospital, public health clinic, or nonprofit health clinic ordering the services;</section><section prefix="(4)">A referring laboratory;</section><section prefix="(5)">On behalf of the patient, a governmental agency or its public or private agent, agency, or organization; or</section><section prefix="(6)">A health care practitioner who orders but does not supervise or perform an anatomic pathology service on a Pap test specimen, provided the health care practitioner is in compliance with subsection (e)(2) of this section.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Except as provided in subsection (e) of this section, a health care practitioner licensed under this article may not directly or indirectly charge, bill, or otherwise solicit payment for anatomic pathology services unless the services are performed:<section prefix="(1)">By the health care practitioner or under the direct supervision of the health care practitioner; and</section><section prefix="(2)">In accordance with the provisions for the preparation of biological products by service in the federal Public Health Service Act.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">This section does not prohibit:<section prefix="(1)">A referring laboratory from billing for anatomic pathology services or histologic processing if the referring laboratory must send a specimen to another clinical laboratory for histologic processing or anatomic pathology consultation; and</section><section prefix="(2)">A health care practitioner who takes a Pap test specimen from a patient and who orders but does not supervise or perform an anatomic pathology service on the specimen, from billing a patient or payor for the service, provided the health care practitioner complies with:<section prefix="(i)">The disclosure requirements of &#xA7; 14-404(a)(16) of this article; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">The ethics policies of the American Medical Association that relate to referring physician billing for laboratory services.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">A patient, insurer, third-party payor, hospital, public health clinic, or nonprofit health clinic is not required to reimburse a health care practitioner who violates the provisions of this section.</section>
  </text>
</law>
