<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gho" order_by="gho" level="1">Health Occupations</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gho-4-508</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this section, "Dental Hygiene Well-Being Committee" means the committee of the Maryland Dental Hy...</catch_line>
  <order_by>508</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, "Dental Hygiene Well-Being Committee" means the committee of the Maryland Dental Hygienists' Association that evaluates and provides assistance to any dental hygienist, dental radiation technologist, or dental assistant in need of treatment and rehabilitation for alcoholism, drug abuse, chemical dependency, or other physical, emotional, or mental condition.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Maryland Dental Hygienists' Association shall appoint the members of the Dental Hygiene Well-Being Committee.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Board shall fund the budget of the Dental Hygiene Well-Being Committee as provided in &#xA7; 4-207 of this title.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Legislative Auditor shall audit the accounts and transactions of the Dental Hygiene Well-Being Committee as provided in &#xA7; 2-1220 of the State Government Article.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as otherwise provided in this subsection, the proceedings, records, and files of the Dental Hygiene Well-Being Committee are not discoverable and are not admissible in evidence in any civil action arising out of matters that are being or have been reviewed and evaluated by the Dental Hygiene Well-Being Committee.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Paragraph (1) of this subsection does not apply to any record or document that is considered by the Dental Hygiene Well-Being Committee and that otherwise would be subject to discovery or introduction into evidence in a civil action.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">For purposes of this subsection, civil action does not include a proceeding before the Board or judicial review of a proceeding before the Board.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">A person who acts in good faith and within the scope of jurisdiction of a Dental Hygiene Well-Being Committee is not civilly liable for any action as a member of the Dental Hygiene Well-Being Committee or for giving information to, participating in, or contributing to the function of the Well-Being Committee.</section>
  </text>
</law>
