<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gho" order_by="gho" level="1">Health Occupations</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gho-14-306</section_number>
  <catch_line>To the extent permitted by the rules, regulations, and orders of the Board, an individual to whom du...</catch_line>
  <order_by>306</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">To the extent permitted by the rules, regulations, and orders of the Board, an individual to whom duties are delegated by a licensed physician may perform those duties without a license as provided in this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The individuals to whom duties may be delegated under this section include any individual authorized to practice any other health occupation regulated under this article or &#xA7; 13-516 of the Education Article.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Board shall adopt rules and regulations to delineate the scope of this section. Before it adopts any rule or regulation under this section, the Board shall invite and consider proposals from any individual or health group that could be affected by the rule or regulation.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If a duty that is to be delegated under this section is a part of the practice of a health occupation that is regulated under this article by another board, any rule or regulation concerning that duty shall be adopted jointly by the Board of Physicians and the board that regulates the other health occupation.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If the two boards cannot agree on a proposed rule or regulation, the proposal shall be submitted to the Secretary for a final decision.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">An individual may perform X-ray duties without a license only if the duties:<section prefix="(1)">Do not include:<section prefix="(i)">Computerized or noncomputerized tomography;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Fluoroscopy;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Invasive radiology;</section><section prefix="(iv)">Mammography;</section><section prefix="(v)">Nuclear medicine;</section><section prefix="(vi)">Radiation therapy; or</section><section prefix="(vii)">Xerography.</section></section><section prefix="(2)">Are limited to X-ray procedures of the:<section prefix="(i)">Chest, anterior-posterior and lateral;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Spine, anterior-posterior and lateral; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">Extremities, anterior-posterior and lateral, not including the head.</section></section><section prefix="(3)">Are performed:<section prefix="(i)">By an individual who is not employed primarily to perform X-ray duties;</section><section prefix="(ii)">In the medical office of the physician who delegates the duties; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">By an individual who, before October 1, 2002, has:<section prefix="1.">Taken a course consisting of at least 30 hours of training in performing X-ray procedures approved by the Maryland Radiological Society in consultation with the Maryland Society of Radiologic Technologists; and</section><section prefix="2.">Successfully passed an examination based on that course that has been approved by the Maryland Radiological Society in consultation with the Maryland Society of Radiologic Technologists.</section></section></section></section>
  </text>
</law>
