<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gho" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="12-6B-02" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gho-12-6B-02</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">To qualify for registration an applicant shall be an individual who:<section prefix="(1)">Is currently certified by a national pharmacy technician certification program and complies with subsection (b)(6) of this section; or</section><section prefix="(2)">Meets the requirements of this section.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The applicant shall:<section prefix="(1)">Be of good moral character;</section><section prefix="(2)">Be at least 17 years old;</section><section prefix="(3)"><section prefix="(i)"/><section prefix="(ii)">Meet the requirements in subsection (d) of this section;</section></section><section prefix="(4)">Have successfully passed an examination approved by the Board;</section><section prefix="(5)">Complete a pharmacy technician training program approved by the Board that:<section prefix="(i)">Includes 160 hours of work experience; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Is no longer than 6 months' duration; and</section></section><section prefix="(6)">Submit a request for a State criminal history records check.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Board may not approve an application until the State criminal history records check is completed.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">If an applicant does not meet the requirements of subsection (b)(3) through (5) of this section, the applicant qualifies for registration if:<section prefix="(1)">The applicant has worked in the pharmacy area of a pharmacy operated by the same pharmacy permit holder since January 1, 2006;</section><section prefix="(2)">The pharmacy permit holder for whom the applicant works attests in writing that the applicant has worked in the pharmacy area operated by the pharmacy permit holder continuously since January 1, 2006;</section><section prefix="(3)">A pharmacist who has supervised the applicant for at least 6 months attests in writing that the individual has performed competently; and</section><section prefix="(4)">The applicant otherwise meets the requirements of subsection (b) of this section.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">An individual, at least 16 years and 6 months old, may begin fulfilling the pharmacy technician registration requirements under this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Subject to the provisions of this subsection, the Board may waive any requirement of this subtitle for an individual who is registered as or has worked as a pharmacy technician in another state.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Board may grant a waiver under this subsection only if the applicant:<section prefix="(i)">Pays the application fee required under &#xA7; 12-6B-03 of this subtitle; and</section><section prefix="(ii)"/></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
