<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gho" order_by="gho" level="1">Health Occupations</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gho-17-309</section_number>
  <catch_line>The Board may adopt regulations to allow an individual to practice under supervision as a licensed g...</catch_line>
  <order_by>309</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Board may adopt regulations to allow an individual to practice under supervision as a licensed graduate alcohol and drug counselor, a licensed graduate marriage and family therapist, a licensed graduate professional counselor, or a licensed graduate professional art therapist.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">To qualify to practice as a licensed graduate alcohol and drug counselor, a licensed graduate marriage and family therapist, a licensed graduate professional counselor, or a licensed graduate professional art therapist, an individual shall be:<section prefix="(1)">Of good moral character; and</section><section prefix="(2)">At least 18 years old.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">An individual may practice graduate alcohol and drug counseling under supervision for a limited period of time if the individual has:<section prefix="(1)">A master's or doctoral degree in a health and human services counseling field that meets the educational requirements of &#xA7; 17-302 of this subtitle; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Passed the National Alcohol and Drug Counselor Examination approved by the Board.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">An individual may practice graduate marriage and family therapy under supervision for a limited period of time if the individual has:<section prefix="(1)">A master's or doctoral degree in a marriage and family field that meets the educational requirements of &#xA7; 17-303 of this subtitle; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Passed the National Marriage and Family Therapy Examination approved by the Board.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">An individual may practice graduate professional counseling under supervision for a limited period of time if the individual has:<section prefix="(1)">A master's or doctoral degree in a professional counseling field that meets the educational requirements of &#xA7; 17-304 of this subtitle; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Passed the National Professional Counselor Examination approved by the Board.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">An individual may practice graduate professional art therapy under supervision for a limited period of time if the individual has a master's or doctoral degree in art therapy that meets the educational requirements of &#xA7; 17-304.1 of this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">An individual may not practice without approval by the Board.</section>
  </text>
</law>
