<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gho" order_by="gho" level="1">Health Occupations</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gho-14-5D-01</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated....</catch_line>
  <order_by>01</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Alternate supervising physician" means one or more physicians designated by the supervising physician to provide supervision of an athletic trainer:<section prefix="(1)">During the absence of the supervising physician; and</section><section prefix="(2)">In accordance with the evaluation and treatment protocol on file with the Board.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Athlete" means an individual who participates in an athletic activity.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">"Athletic activity" means exercise, recreation, sport, competition, or game that:<section prefix="(1)">Requires physical strength, range of motion, flexibility, control, speed, stamina, or agility; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Is associated with a setting as defined under this section, an educational institution, or a professional, amateur, or recreational sports club or athletic organization.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"Athletic injury" means an injury that affects an athlete's participation or performance in an athletic activity.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">"Board" means the State Board of Physicians.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">"Committee" means the Athletic Trainer Advisory Committee established under &#xA7; 14-5D-04 of this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">"Educational institution" includes:<section prefix="(1)">The schools in the public elementary and secondary education system of the State;</section><section prefix="(2)">A noncollegiate educational institution governed under &#xA7; 2-206 of the Education Article; and</section><section prefix="(3)">An institution of higher education as defined in &#xA7; 10-101 of the Education Article.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(i)">"Evaluation and treatment protocol" means a document that is executed by a physician and an athletic trainer that meets the requirements of &#xA7; 14-5D-11 of this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(j)">"License" means a license issued by the Board to practice athletic training.</section>
    <section prefix="(k)">"Licensed athletic trainer" means an individual who is licensed by the Board to practice athletic training.</section>
    <section prefix="(l)">"Licensed health care practitioner" means an individual licensed, certified, or otherwise authorized to practice a health occupation under this article.</section>
    <section prefix="(m)">"National certifying board" means the National Athletic Trainers' Association Board of Certification, Inc., or its successor organization.</section>
    <section prefix="(n)">"Nonsupervising physician" means a physician licensed by the Board who is not the supervising physician of the licensed athletic trainer.</section>
    <section prefix="(o)">"Outside referral" means a request for treatment from a nonsupervising physician or licensed health care practitioner.</section>
    <section prefix="(p)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Practice athletic training" means application of the following principles and methods for managing athletic injuries for athletes in good overall health under the supervision of a licensed physician:<section prefix="(i)">Prevention;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Clinical evaluation and assessment;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Immediate care; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">Treatment, rehabilitation, and reconditioning.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Practice athletic training" includes:<section prefix="(i)">Organization and administration of an athletic training program; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Instruction to coaches, athletes, parents, medical personnel, and community members regarding the care and prevention of athletic injuries.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Practice athletic training" does not include:<section prefix="(i)">The practice of:<section prefix="1.">Chiropractic, including adjustments, manipulation, or high velocity mobilizations of the spine or extremities;</section><section prefix="2.">Massage therapy;</section><section prefix="3.">Medicine;</section><section prefix="4.">Occupational therapy;</section><section prefix="5.">Physical therapy; or</section><section prefix="6.">Podiatry;</section></section><section prefix="(ii)">The reconditioning of systemic neurologic injuries, conditions, or disease; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">Except for the conditioning of an athlete under the supervision of a treating physician, the treatment, rehabilitation, or reconditioning of nonathletic injuries or disease.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(q)">"Setting" means a:<section prefix="(1)">Location where an athletic activity, as defined in subsection (d) of this section, is being held;</section><section prefix="(2)">Health or fitness club;</section><section prefix="(3)">Clinic or hospital;</section><section prefix="(4)">Corporation; or</section><section prefix="(5)">Government agency.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(r)">"Supervising physician" means a physician who has been approved by the Board to supervise one or more athletic trainers.</section>
    <section prefix="(s)">"Supervision" means the responsibility of a physician to provide ongoing and immediately available instruction, in person, by telephone, or by other electronic means, that is adequate to ensure the safety and welfare of a patient and is appropriate to the setting.</section>
  </text>
</law>
