<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gho" order_by="gho" level="1">Health Occupations</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gho-2-314.1</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this section, "medical examination" means a physical examination of the ear of an individual by a...</catch_line>
  <order_by>314.1</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, "medical examination" means a physical examination of the ear of an individual by an otolaryngologist, otologist, or other physician.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Before an audiologist or a hearing aid dispenser sells a hearing aid to an individual, the audiologist or hearing aid dispenser shall determine whether the individual has had a medical examination within the 6 months before the hearing aid service is to be provided.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Unless an audiologist or a hearing aid dispenser determines that an individual has had a medical examination within the period set under paragraph (1) of this subsection, the audiologist or hearing aid dispenser:<section prefix="(i)">Shall give the individual a written recommendation that the individual obtain a medical examination; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Except as provided in subsection (c) of this section, may not sell a hearing aid to the individual until the individual provides to the audiologist or the hearing aid dispenser satisfactory written evidence that the individual has had a medical examination within the 6 months before the hearing aid is provided.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">An audiologist or a hearing aid dispenser may sell a hearing aid to an individual without complying with the requirements of subsection (b)(2)(ii) of this section only if the services are:<section prefix="(i)">Limited to replacement of a hearing aid; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">Provided to an individual who:<section prefix="1.">Is at least 18 years old; and</section><section prefix="2.">Before a hearing aid is provided, signs a written waiver of the medical examination that otherwise is required under subsection (b)(2)(ii) of this section.</section></section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Each audiologist or hearing aid dispenser shall keep a copy of each signed waiver.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
