<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gho" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="7-308.1" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gho-7-308.1</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">A personal representative of a deceased mortician's or funeral director's estate shall be licensed by the Board before continuing operation of the mortuary science business.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Board shall issue an executor license to an applicant if the applicant:<section prefix="(1)">Is the appointed personal representative of a deceased mortician's or funeral director's estate in accordance with the requirements established in Title 5 of the Estates and Trusts Article;</section><section prefix="(2)">Submits to the Board, within 30 days of the death of the licensed mortician or funeral director, written verification of the death of the licensee, written verification of appointment as a personal representative, and the application required by the Board; and</section><section prefix="(3)">Pays a fee set by the Board.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Nothing in this section shall prevent a personal representative from selling the mortuary science business that was operated and wholly or partly owned by the licensed funeral director or licensed mortician.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Except as provided in subsection (c) of this section, while an executor license is effective, it authorizes the licensee to:<section prefix="(1)">Continue operation of the mortuary science business that had been operated and wholly or partly owned by the deceased mortician or funeral director; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Assist with the planning and conducting of funeral services for that mortuary science business.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The Board may issue a license under this section only if:<section prefix="(1)">The business is operated under the direct supervision of a licensed mortician or funeral director; and</section><section prefix="(2)">The embalming services are provided by a licensed mortician.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">Notwithstanding the provisions of &#xA7; 7-314 of this subtitle, an executor license is valid for six months from the date of issuance and may not be renewed or reinstated after expiration.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">A personal representative who wishes to continue operation of a mortuary science business upon expiration of the executor license must qualify and be licensed as a mortician or a funeral director, or be the holder of a surviving spouse or corporation license.</section>
  </text>
</law>
