<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gho" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="4-304" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gho-4-304</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">To apply for a license, an applicant shall:<section prefix="(1)">Submit an application to the Board on the form that the Board requires; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Pay to the Board an application fee set by the Board.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">In addition to the other requirements of this section, an applicant for a limited license to practice dentistry shall submit to the Board a written request, from the hospital, sanatorium, dental school, or public health program to which the practice is to be limited, that the license be issued.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">To apply for a retired volunteer dentist's license, a volunteer dentist's license, or a temporary volunteer dentist's license to practice dentistry, an applicant:<section prefix="(1)">Shall submit an application to the Board on the form that the Board requires; and</section><section prefix="(2)">May not be required to pay an application fee.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">At least 30 days before the examination, an applicant for a general license to practice dental hygiene shall submit the application to the Board.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">In addition to the other requirements of this section, an applicant for a license to practice dental hygiene shall submit to the Board:<section prefix="(i)">Satisfactory evidence of graduation from a dental hygiene program accredited by the American Dental Association Commission on Dental Accreditation; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Any other credentials that the Board requires.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">To apply for a retired volunteer dental hygienist's license, a volunteer dental hygienist's license, or a temporary volunteer dental hygienist's license to practice dental hygiene, an applicant:<section prefix="(1)">Shall submit an application to the Board on the form that the Board requires; and</section><section prefix="(2)">May not be required to pay an application fee.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">To apply for a temporary dental clinic permit, an applicant:<section prefix="(1)">Shall submit an application on the form that the Board requires; and</section><section prefix="(2)">May not be required to pay an application fee.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
