<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gho" order_by="gho" level="1">Health Occupations</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gho-14-5B-01</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated....</catch_line>
  <order_by>01</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Board" means the State Board of Physicians.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Certification" means recognition of an individual who has satisfied certain standards required by a national certifying board.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">"Committee" means the Radiation Therapy, Radiography, Nuclear Medicine Technology, and Radiology Assistance Advisory Committee of the Board.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"Holder of a temporary license" means an individual who is granted a temporary license to practice radiation therapy, radiography, or nuclear medicine technology pending fulfillment of the requirements under &#xA7; 14-5B-09(c) of this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">"License" means a license issued by the Board to practice as a radiation therapist, radiographer, nuclear medicine technologist, or radiologist assistant.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">"Licensed nuclear medicine technologist" means a nuclear medicine technologist who is licensed by the Board to practice nuclear medicine technology.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">"Licensed radiation therapist" means a radiation therapist who is licensed by the Board to practice radiation therapy.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">"Licensed radiographer" means a radiographer who is licensed by the Board to practice radiography.</section>
    <section prefix="(j)">"Licensed radiologist assistant" means an individual who is licensed to practice radiology assistance under the supervision of a licensed physician who:<section prefix="(1)">Specializes in radiology; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Is certified by:<section prefix="(i)">The American Board of Radiology;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The American Osteopathic Board of Radiology;</section><section prefix="(iii)">The British Royal College of Radiology; or</section><section prefix="(iv)">The Canadian College of Physicians and Surgeons.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(k)">"Licensee" means an individual who is licensed by the Board to practice as a radiation therapist, a radiographer, a nuclear medicine technologist, or radiologist assistant.</section>
    <section prefix="(l)">"National certifying board" means:<section prefix="(1)">The American Registry of Radiologic Technologists;</section><section prefix="(2)">The Nuclear Medicine Technology Certifying Board; or</section><section prefix="(3)">Another certifying organization approved by the Board.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(m)">"Practice nuclear medicine technology" means to:<section prefix="(1)">Prepare and administer radiopharmaceuticals to human beings; or</section><section prefix="(2)">Conduct in vivo detection and measurement of radioactivity for medical purposes to assist in the diagnosis and treatment of disease or injury.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(n)">"Practice radiation therapy" means to perform tumor localization radiography and apply therapeutic doses of radiation for the treatment of disease or injury.</section>
    <section prefix="(o)">"Practice radiography" means to use ionizing radiation to:<section prefix="(1)">Demonstrate portions of the human body to assist in the diagnosis or localization of disease or injury; or</section><section prefix="(2)">Perform tumor localization radiography.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(p)">"Practice radiology assistance" means to practice medical radiation technology and to perform:<section prefix="(1)">Fluoroscopy and selected radiology procedures;</section><section prefix="(2)">Patient assessment; and</section><section prefix="(3)">Patient management.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(q)">"Supervision" means the responsibility of a licensed physician to exercise on-site or immediately available direction for licensees or holders of temporary licenses.</section>
  </text>
</law>
