<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gho" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="17-101" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gho-17-101</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this title the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Alcohol and drug counseling" means assisting an individual, family, or group through the client-counselor relationship:<section prefix="(1)">To develop understanding of intrapersonal and interpersonal substance abuse problems;</section><section prefix="(2)">To define goals relating to substance abuse;</section><section prefix="(3)">To make decisions relating to substance abuse;</section><section prefix="(4)">To plan a course of action reflecting the needs, interests, and abilities of the individual, family, or group relating to substance abuse; and</section><section prefix="(5)">To use informational and community substance abuse resources relating to personal, social, emotional, educational, and vocational development and adjustment.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Appraisal" means:<section prefix="(i)">Selecting, administering, scoring, and interpreting instruments designed to assess an individual's aptitudes, attitudes, abilities, achievements, interests, and personal characteristics; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Using nonstandardized methods and techniques for understanding human behavior in relation to coping with, adapting to, or changing life situations.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Appraisal" does not include instruments which require specialized psychological training for administration and interpretation unless the licensed counselor or therapist has completed the training required under &#xA7; 17-310 of this title.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">"Art therapy" means the integrated use of psychotherapeutic principles, art media, and the creative process to assist individuals, families, or groups in:<section prefix="(1)">Increasing awareness of self and others;</section><section prefix="(2)">Coping with symptoms, stress, and traumatic experiences;</section><section prefix="(3)">Enhancing cognitive abilities; and</section><section prefix="(4)">Identifying and assessing clients' needs in order to implement therapeutic intervention to meet developmental, behavioral, mental, and emotional needs.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"Board" means the State Board of Professional Counselors and Therapists.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">"Certificate" means a certificate issued by the Board to practice professional counseling.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">"Certified professional counselor" means a professional counselor who is certified by the Board.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">"Certified professional counselor-marriage and family therapist" means an individual who is certified by the Board to practice marriage and family therapy in the State.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Certified supervised counselor-alcohol and drug" means an individual who is certified by the Board to practice alcohol and drug counseling in the State pursuant to the limitations in &#xA7; 17-404 of this title.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Certified associate counselor-alcohol and drug" means an individual who is certified by the Board to practice alcohol and drug counseling in the State pursuant to the limitations in &#xA7; 17-403 of this title.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Certified professional counselor-alcohol and drug" means an individual who is certified by the Board to practice alcohol and drug counseling in the State.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(j)">"Counseling" means assisting an individual, family, or group through the client-counselor relationship:<section prefix="(1)">To develop understanding of intrapersonal and interpersonal problems;</section><section prefix="(2)">To define goals;</section><section prefix="(3)">To make decisions;</section><section prefix="(4)">To plan a course of action reflecting the needs, interests, and abilities of the individual, family, or group; and</section><section prefix="(5)">To use informational and community resources, as these procedures are related to personal, social, emotional, educational, and vocational development and adjustment.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(k)">"Fund" means the State Board of Professional Counselors and Therapists Fund.</section>
    <section prefix="(l)">"License" means, unless the context requires otherwise, one of six types of licenses issued by the Board authorizing an individual to practice:<section prefix="(1)">Clinical alcohol and drug counseling;</section><section prefix="(2)">Clinical marriage and family therapy;</section><section prefix="(3)">Clinical professional art therapy;</section><section prefix="(4)">Clinical professional counseling;</section><section prefix="(5)">Graduate alcohol and drug counseling;</section><section prefix="(6)">Graduate marriage and family therapy;</section><section prefix="(7)">Graduate professional art therapy; or</section><section prefix="(8)">Graduate professional counseling.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(m)">"Licensed graduate alcohol and drug counselor" means an individual approved by the Board to practice graduate alcohol and drug counseling.</section>
    <section prefix="(n)">"Licensed graduate marriage and family therapist" means an individual approved by the Board to practice graduate marriage and family therapy.</section>
    <section prefix="(o)">"Licensed graduate professional art therapist" means an individual approved by the Board to practice graduate professional art therapy.</section>
    <section prefix="(p)">"Licensed graduate professional counselor" means an individual approved by the Board to practice graduate professional counseling.</section>
    <section prefix="(q)">"Marriage and family therapy" means applying marriage and family systems theory, principles, methods, therapeutic techniques, and research in:<section prefix="(1)">Resolving emotional conflict and modifying perception and behavior in the context of marriage and family life; and</section><section prefix="(2)">The identification and assessment of client needs and the implementation of therapeutic intervention.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(r)">"Practice alcohol and drug counseling" means to engage professionally and for compensation in alcohol and drug counseling activities while representing oneself to be a certified professional counselor-alcohol and drug, a certified supervised counselor-alcohol and drug, or a certified associate counselor- alcohol and drug.</section>
    <section prefix="(s)">"Practice clinical alcohol and drug counseling" means to engage professionally and for compensation in alcohol and drug counseling and appraisal activities by providing services involving the application of counseling principles and methods in the diagnosis, prevention, treatment, and amelioration of psychological problems and emotional or mental conditions of individuals or groups.</section>
    <section prefix="(t)">"Practice clinical marriage and family therapy" means to engage professionally and for compensation in marriage and family therapy and appraisal activities by providing services involving the application of therapy principles and methods in the diagnosis, prevention, treatment, and amelioration of psychological problems and emotional or mental conditions of individuals or groups.</section>
    <section prefix="(u)">"Practice clinical professional art therapy" means to engage professionally and for compensation in art therapy and appraisal activities by providing services involving the application of art therapy principles and methods in the diagnosis, prevention, treatment, and amelioration of psychological problems and emotional or mental conditions of individuals or groups.</section>
    <section prefix="(v)">"Practice clinical professional counseling" means to engage professionally and for compensation in counseling and appraisal activities by providing services involving the application of counseling principles and methods in the diagnosis, prevention, treatment, and amelioration of psychological problems and emotional or mental conditions of individuals or groups.</section>
    <section prefix="(w)">"Practice graduate alcohol and drug counseling" means to practice clinical alcohol and drug counseling:<section prefix="(1)">Under the supervision of a licensed clinical alcohol and drug counselor or another health care provider licensed under this article, as approved by the Board; and</section><section prefix="(2)">While fulfilling the requirements for supervised experience under &#xA7; 17-302 of this title.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(x)">"Practice graduate marriage and family therapy" means to practice clinical marriage and family therapy:<section prefix="(1)">Under the supervision of a licensed clinical marriage and family therapist or another health care provider licensed under this article, as approved by the Board; and</section><section prefix="(2)">While fulfilling the requirements for supervised experience under &#xA7; 17-303 of this title.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(y)">"Practice graduate professional art therapy" means to practice clinical professional art therapy:<section prefix="(1)">Under the supervision of a licensed clinical professional art therapist or another health care provider licensed under this article, as approved by the Board; and</section><section prefix="(2)">While fulfilling the requirements for supervised experience under &#xA7; 17-304.1 of this title.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(z)">"Practice graduate professional counseling" means to practice clinical professional counseling:<section prefix="(1)">Under the supervision of a licensed clinical professional counselor or another health care provider licensed under this article, as approved by the Board; and</section><section prefix="(2)">While fulfilling the requirements for supervised experience under &#xA7; 17-304 of this title.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(aa)">"Practice marriage and family therapy" means to engage professionally and for compensation in marriage and family therapy activities while representing oneself to be a certified professional counselor-marriage and family therapist.</section>
    <section prefix="(bb)">"Practice professional counseling" means to engage professionally and for compensation in counseling and appraisal activities while representing oneself to be a certified professional counselor.</section>
  </text>
</law>
