<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gho" order_by="gho" level="1">Health Occupations</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gho-4-310</section_number>
  <catch_line>The Board shall place the holder of a general license to practice dentistry or a general license to ...</catch_line>
  <order_by>310</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Board shall place the holder of a general license to practice dentistry or a general license to practice dental hygiene on inactive status and issue an inactive status registration certificate to the licensee, if the licensee:<section prefix="(i)">Submits to the Board an application for inactive status on the form required by the Board; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Pays to the Board the inactive status application fee set by the Board.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A licensee on inactive status may not practice dentistry or dental hygiene in this State.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The form provided by the Board for inactive status application or renewal shall require the individual to state:<section prefix="(1)">Name;</section><section prefix="(2)">Inactive status registration number, if any;</section><section prefix="(3)">Degree;</section><section prefix="(4)">School that awarded the degree;</section><section prefix="(5)">Year of graduation;</section><section prefix="(6)">Home address;</section><section prefix="(7)">Principal office address;</section><section prefix="(8)">Principal office telephone number; and</section><section prefix="(9)">Whether or not the individual is in regular practice outside this State.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Board shall waive the examination requirements of &#xA7;&#xA7; 4-302 and 4-305 of this subtitle for:<section prefix="(1)">A dentist on inactive status who applies for a general license to practice dentistry, if the dentist has practiced dentistry regularly in any other state within 3 years of applying for the license; or</section><section prefix="(2)">A dental hygienist on inactive status who applies for a general license to practice dental hygiene, if the dental hygienist has practiced dental hygiene regularly in any other state within 3 years of applying for the license.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
