<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gho" order_by="" level="1">Health Occupations</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gho-8-309</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>309</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">If an individual has been licensed by the Board to practice registered nursing or licensed practical nursing in this State in accordance with the requirements of this subtitle, the individual may be subsequently licensed as a registered nurse or as a licensed practical nurse on inactive status.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Board shall place a licensee on inactive status and record the inactive status in the Board's database and on the Board's website if the licensee:<section prefix="(1)"><section prefix="(i)">Has not satisfactorily completed 1,000 hours of active nursing practice within the 5-year period immediately preceding the date of anticipated renewal; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">Chooses inactive status;</section></section><section prefix="(2)">Completes the annual application for inactive status; and</section><section prefix="(3)">Pays the fee established by the Board.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A licensee on inactive status may not practice nursing in this State, but:<section prefix="(1)">A registered nurse on inactive status may use the title "Registered Nurse", or the abbreviation "RN"; and</section><section prefix="(2)">A practical nurse on inactive status may use the title "Licensed Practical Nurse", or the abbreviation "LPN".</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">If a licensee on inactive status applies for a license to practice nursing and meets the renewal requirements of &#xA7; 8-312 of this subtitle, the Board shall:<section prefix="(1)">Remove the licensee from inactive status;</section><section prefix="(2)">Void the licensee's inactive status registration certificate; and</section><section prefix="(3)">Renew the licensee's license to practice nursing in this State.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
