<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gho" order_by="" level="1">Health Occupations</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gho-12-205</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>205</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In addition to the powers set forth elsewhere in this title, the Board may adopt:<section prefix="(1)">Rules and bylaws that are necessary to do its business;</section><section prefix="(2)">Rules and regulations to carry out the provisions of this title;</section><section prefix="(3)">Rules and regulations that are necessary to protect the public health, safety, and welfare and that establish standards for practicing pharmacy and operating pharmacies, including rules and regulations that govern:<section prefix="(i)">Methods of advertising and promotion; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Standards for filling and refilling prescriptions; and</section></section><section prefix="(4)">A code of conduct that specifies which behaviors are either required or prohibited in the practice of pharmacy.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">In addition to the duties set forth elsewhere in this title, the Board shall:<section prefix="(1)">Keep a record that includes:<section prefix="(i)">The name and place of the business or the home address of each licensed pharmacist and each registered pharmacy technician;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The facts concerning the issuance of that pharmacist's license; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">The facts concerning the issuance of that pharmacy technician's registration;</section></section><section prefix="(2)">Prepare and deliver to the Governor, the Secretary, and the Maryland Pharmacists Association an annual report that:<section prefix="(i)">Summarizes the condition of pharmacy in this State; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Includes a record of the proceedings of the Board; and</section></section><section prefix="(3)">Disclose any information contained in a record to any health occupations regulatory board or agency of this State or another state if the health occupations regulatory board or agency of this State or another state requests the information in writing.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">In addition to the duties set forth elsewhere in this title, the Board may initiate such programs and projects as deemed necessary to inform or protect the public.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Board shall adopt standards for approving examinations under &#xA7; 12-6B-02(b)(4) of this title.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Board shall approve any examination that meets the standards adopted under paragraph (1) of this subsection including:<section prefix="(i)">Employer based pharmacy technician examinations;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Nationally recognized pharmacy technician examinations; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Examinations for certification as a pharmacy technician.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
