<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gho" order_by="gho" level="1">Health Occupations</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gho-14-505</section_number>
  <catch_line>A licensed physician or registered nurse who is primarily responsible for the treatment of an indivi...</catch_line>
  <order_by>505</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A licensed physician or registered nurse who is primarily responsible for the treatment of an individual for a burn injury described in paragraph (2) of this subsection shall as soon as practicable notify the county fire chief or administrator, or designee, or, if neither office exists, the State Fire Marshal or designee. If treatment occurs at a hospital, the treating physician or designee shall be responsible for giving the notice required by this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The provisions of paragraph (1) of this subsection apply to a burn injury:<section prefix="(i)">Causing 2nd or 3rd degree burns to 5 percent or more of the patient's body;</section><section prefix="(ii)">To the upper respiratory tract or laryngeal edema caused by inhaling super-heated air;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Which causes death; or</section><section prefix="(iv)">Which is likely to cause death.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The provisions of paragraph (1) of this subsection do not apply to a sunburn.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Notice under this section shall include:<section prefix="(1)">The name and address of the patient, if known;</section><section prefix="(2)">A description of the burn injury;</section><section prefix="(3)">The reported cause of the burn injury, if given;</section><section prefix="(4)">The patient's prognosis; and</section><section prefix="(5)">Any other fact concerning the burn injury which might assist in detecting arson.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">If an investigation is conducted after notification is given under subsection (a) of this section, the investigating agency shall report its findings on an incident reporting system report and send it to the State Fire Marshal's office for retention.</section>
  </text>
</law>
