<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gho" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="8-6A-13" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gho-8-6A-13</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Board shall appoint an advisory committee consisting of at least 15 members appointed by the Board.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Of the 15 committee members:<section prefix="(1)">Six shall be nursing assistants:<section prefix="(i)">One shall be an acute care nursing assistant;</section><section prefix="(ii)">One shall be a home care nursing assistant;</section><section prefix="(iii)">One shall be a long-term care nursing assistant;</section><section prefix="(iv)">One shall be an adult medical day care nursing assistant;</section><section prefix="(v)">At least one of the nursing assistant members shall be a member of a union; and</section><section prefix="(vi)">One shall be an independent contractor;</section></section><section prefix="(2)">Three shall be registered nurses:<section prefix="(i)">One shall be an acute care registered nurse;</section><section prefix="(ii)">One shall be a home care registered nurse; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">One shall be a long-term care registered nurse;</section></section><section prefix="(3)">One shall be an administrator from a licensed health care facility;</section><section prefix="(4)">One shall be a licensed practical nurse;</section><section prefix="(5)">One shall be an individual who teaches a nursing assistant course;</section><section prefix="(6)">One shall be a consumer member who has received care, or has a family member who has received care from a nursing assistant;</section><section prefix="(7)">One shall be a representative of the Department; and</section><section prefix="(8)">One shall be a certified medication technician.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Board shall appoint an alternate for each of the three nursing assistant members in the event that the nursing assistant member is unable to discharge the duties of the committee.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">An advisory committee member shall serve a term of 4 years.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The advisory committee shall meet at least once a month.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The advisory committee shall:<section prefix="(1)">Evaluate training programs and make recommendations for approval by the Board;</section><section prefix="(2)">Develop and recommend regulations to enforce the provisions of this subtitle;</section><section prefix="(3)">Evaluate candidates as required and recommend action to the Board;</section><section prefix="(4)">Review investigations of complaints against nursing assistants or medication technicians and make recommendations to the Board for disciplinary action;</section><section prefix="(5)">Keep a record of its proceedings; and</section><section prefix="(6)">Submit an annual report to the Board.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
