<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gho" order_by="gho" level="1">Health Occupations</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gho-8-701</section_number>
  <catch_line>Except as otherwise provided in this title, a person may not practice, attempt to practice, or offer...</catch_line>
  <order_by>701</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Except as otherwise provided in this title, a person may not practice, attempt to practice, or offer to practice registered nursing, registered nursing as an advanced practice nurse, or licensed practical nursing in this State unless licensed by the Board to practice registered nursing, registered nursing as an advanced practice nurse, or licensed practical nursing, respectively.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Except as otherwise provided in this title, a person may not practice, attempt to practice, or offer to practice electrology in this State unless licensed by the Board to practice electrology.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as otherwise provided in this title, a person may not practice, attempt to practice, or offer to practice as a certified nursing assistant unless certified by the Board as a certified nursing assistant.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Except as otherwise provided in this title, a person may not practice, attempt to practice, or offer to practice as a certified nursing assistant in a specific category unless certified by the Board as a certified nursing assistant in that category.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Except as otherwise provided in this title, a person may not practice, attempt to practice, or offer to practice as a certified medication technician in this State unless certified by the Board to practice as a certified medication technician.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">Except as otherwise provided in this title, a person may not practice, attempt to practice, or offer to practice as a certified medicine aide unless certified by the Board to practice as a certified medicine aide.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">A person may not require a licensee to perform an act that is beyond the licensee's knowledge and skills.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">A person may not direct a licensee to delegate a nursing task to a nurse when the person reasonably believes:<section prefix="(1)">The nurse lacks the knowledge and skills to perform the nursing task; or</section><section prefix="(2)">The patient's condition does not allow delegation of the nursing task.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
