<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gho" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="11-309" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gho-11-309</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In addition to any other qualifications and requirements established by the Board, the Board shall establish continuing education requirements as a condition to the renewal of licenses and certificates under this title.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The continuing education required by the Board shall be in courses approved by the Board.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Board may not require a nontherapeutically certified optometrist to attend more than 50 hours in any licensing period.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Board shall require a therapeutically certified optometrist to attend at least 50 hours of continuing education in a licensing period.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">
        <section prefix="(i)">In each licensing period, a therapeutically certified optometrist shall attend 30 hours of continuing education on the use and management of therapeutic pharmaceutical agents.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The 30 hours of continuing education required under subparagraph (i) of this paragraph shall be counted toward the total number of required hours of continuing education in a licensing period.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">At the time a licensee applies for license renewal, the licensee shall submit to the Board, on a form provided by the Board, a certification that the licensee has attended the required courses.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Board may refuse to renew the license of a licensee who has failed:<section prefix="(1)">To attend the required courses; or</section><section prefix="(2)">To submit certification of attendance at the required courses.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The Board may waive the continuing education requirements in cases of illness or other undue hardship on the licensee.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The Board may use any funds allocated to it for continuing education as State funds to match federal funds for providing continuing education.</section>
  </text>
</law>
