<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gho" order_by="gho" level="1">Health Occupations</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gho-14-308</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this section the following terms have the meanings indicated....</catch_line>
  <order_by>308</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following terms have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Fifth pathway program" means a program that the Board approves in its regulations for a student who:<section prefix="(i)">Has studied medicine at a foreign medical school;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Was a United States citizen when the student enrolled in the foreign medical school; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Has completed all of the formal requirements for graduation from the foreign medical school, except for any social service or postgraduate requirements.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Foreign medical school" means a medical school located outside of the United States, its territories or possessions, Puerto Rico, or Canada.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">An applicant for a license is exempt from the educational requirements of &#xA7; 14-307 of this subtitle, if the applicant:<section prefix="(1)">Has studied medicine at a foreign medical school;</section><section prefix="(2)">Is certified by the Educational Commission for Foreign Medical Graduates or by its successor as approved by the Board;</section><section prefix="(3)">Passes a qualifying examination for foreign medical school graduates required by the Board;</section><section prefix="(4)">Meets any other qualifications for foreign medical school graduates that the Board establishes in its regulation for licensing of applicants;</section><section prefix="(5)">Submits acceptable evidence to the Board of the requirements set in the Board's regulations; and</section><section prefix="(6)">Meets one of the following requirements:<section prefix="(i)">The applicant graduated from any foreign medical school and submits evidence acceptable to the Board of successful completion of 2 years of training in a postgraduate medical education program accredited by an accrediting organization recognized by the Board; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">The applicant successfully completed a fifth pathway program and submits evidence acceptable to the Board that the applicant:<section prefix="1.">Has a document issued by the foreign medical school certifying that the applicant completed all of the formal requirements of that school for the study of medicine, except for the postgraduate or social service components as required by the foreign country or its medical school;</section><section prefix="2.">Has successfully completed a fifth pathway program; and</section><section prefix="3.">Has successfully completed 2 years of training in a postgraduate medical education program following completion of a Board approved fifth pathway program.</section></section></section></section>
  </text>
</law>
