<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gho" order_by="" level="1">Health Occupations</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gho-2-310.3</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>310.3</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Subject to the provisions of this section, the Board shall issue a limited license to assist in the practice of speech-language pathology to an applicant who:<section prefix="(1)">Except for the clinical observation hours and supervised clinical assisting experience hours requirement, meets the license requirements under &#xA7; 2-302.3 of this subtitle;</section><section prefix="(2)">Demonstrates to the satisfaction of the Board that for the term of the limited license the applicant will practice only under the supervision of an individual described under subsection (b)(2) of this section;</section><section prefix="(3)">Submits an application to the Board on the form that the Board requires; and</section><section prefix="(4)">Pays to the Board an application fee set by the Board.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The purpose of a limited license to assist in the practice of speech-language pathology is to permit an individual to practice as a speech-language pathology assistant while completing the licensing requirements of this title.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">While it is effective, a limited license to assist in the practice of speech-language pathology authorizes the licensee to assist in the practice of speech-language pathology under the direct supervision of:<section prefix="(i)">A fully licensed speech-language pathologist; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">If the individual is employed in a setting in which licensure is not required as provided under &#xA7; 2-301(b)(1)(i) of this subtitle, an individual who holds national certification in speech-language pathology from a professional organization as provided for in  the regulations adopted by the Board.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A limited license to assist in the practice of speech-language pathology expires on the first anniversary of its effective date.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Board may renew a limited license to assist in the practice of speech-language pathology once for an additional 1-year term, if the holder:<section prefix="(1)">Otherwise meets the requirements of this section;</section><section prefix="(2)">Submits a renewal application to the Board on the form that the Board requires; and</section><section prefix="(3)">Pays to the Board a limited license renewal fee set by the Board.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">If a limited licensee fails to receive a full license within 2 years, the individual shall wait a minimum of 1 year before the individual may apply for another license.</section>
  </text>
</law>
