<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gho" order_by="" level="1">Health Occupations</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gho-14-411.1</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>411.1</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, "health maintenance organization" has the meaning stated in &#xA7; 19-701 of the Health - General Article.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Board shall create and maintain a public individual profile on each licensee that includes the following information:<section prefix="(1)">A description of any disciplinary action taken by the Board against  the licensee within the most recent 10-year period that includes a copy of the public  order;</section><section prefix="(2)">A description in summary form of any final disciplinary action  taken by a licensing board in any other state or jurisdiction against the licensee within  the most recent 10-year period;</section><section prefix="(3)">The number of medical malpractice final court judgments and arbitration awards against the licensee within the most recent 10-year period for which all appeals have been exhausted as reported to the Board;</section><section prefix="(4)">A description of a conviction or entry of a plea of guilty or  nolo contendere by the licensee for a crime involving moral turpitude reported to the  Board under &#xA7; 14-413(b) of this subtitle; and</section><section prefix="(5)">Medical education and practice information about the  licensee including:<section prefix="(i)">The name of any medical school that the licensee attended  and the date on which the licensee graduated from the school;</section><section prefix="(ii)">A description of any internship and residency training;</section><section prefix="(iii)">A description of any specialty board certification by a  recognized board of the American Board of Medical Specialties or the American  Osteopathic Association;</section><section prefix="(iv)">The name of any hospital where the licensee has medical  privileges as reported to the Board under &#xA7; 14-413 of this subtitle;</section><section prefix="(v)">The location of the licensee's primary practice setting; and</section><section prefix="(vi)">Whether the licensee participates in the Maryland Medical  Assistance Program.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">In addition to the requirements of subsection (b) of this section, the Board  shall:<section prefix="(1)">Provide appropriate and accessible Internet links from the Board's  Internet site:<section prefix="(i)">To the extent available, to the appropriate portion of the  Internet site of each health maintenance organization licensed in this State which will  allow the public to ascertain the names of the physicians affiliated with the health  maintenance organization; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">To the appropriate portion of the Internet site of the  American Medical Association;</section></section><section prefix="(2)">Include a statement on each licensee's profile of information to be  taken into consideration by a consumer when viewing a licensee's profile, including  factors to consider when evaluating a licensee's malpractice data; and</section><section prefix="(3)">Provide on the Board's Internet site:<section prefix="(i)">Notification that a person may contact the  Board by telephone, electronic mail, or written request to find out  whether the number of medical malpractice settlements involving  a particular licensee totals three or more with a settlement   amount of $150,000 or greater within the most recent 5-year period  as reported to the Board; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">A telephone number, electronic mail address,  and physical address through which a person may contact the Board  to request the information required to be provided under item (i) of  this item.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Board:<section prefix="(1)">On receipt of a written request for a licensee's profile from any  person, shall forward a written copy of the profile to the person;</section><section prefix="(2)">Shall maintain a website that serves as a single point of entry  where all physician profile information is available to the public on the Internet; and</section><section prefix="(3)">On receipt of a verbal, electronic, or written  request in accordance with subsection (c)(3) of this section, shall  provide the information within 2 business days of the request.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The Board shall provide a mechanism for the notification and prompt correction of any factual inaccuracies in a licensee's profile.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The Board shall include information relating to a final disciplinary action taken by the Board against a licensee in the licensee's profile within 10 days after the action becomes final.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">This section does not limit the Board's authority to disclose information as required under &#xA7; 14-411 of this subtitle.</section>
  </text>
</law>
