<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gho" order_by="gho" level="1">Health Occupations</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gho-1A-307</section_number>
  <catch_line>The Board shall place a licensee on inactive status if the licensee submits to the Board:...</catch_line>
  <order_by>307</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Board shall place a licensee on inactive status if the licensee submits to the Board:<section prefix="(i)">An application for inactive status on the form required by the Board; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">The inactive status fee set by the Board.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Board may not place a licensee on inactive status for more than 6 years.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Board shall reactivate a license to an individual who is on inactive status if the individual complies with the renewal requirements that exist at the time the individual changes from inactive to active status.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Board may reinstate the license of a former licensee who has failed to renew the license for any reason if the former licensee:<section prefix="(1)">Meets the continuing education requirements of &#xA7; 1A-306 of this subtitle for each year that the license has lapsed;</section><section prefix="(2)">Applies for reinstatement more than 30 days after the license renewal deadline;</section><section prefix="(3)">Submits to the Board an application for reinstatement on the form required by the Board; and</section><section prefix="(4)">Pays to the Board a reinstatement fee and a renewal fee set by the Board.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Board may not assess the reinstatement fee required under subsection (c) of this section on an individual who has been on inactive status for more than 6 years if the individual can provide documentation of maintaining an active license in another state.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">An individual who has been previously licensed by the Board shall obtain a license only by means of license renewal or reinstatement as provided in this article and in regulations adopted by the Board.</section>
  </text>
</law>
