<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gho" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="10-303" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gho-10-303</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Board shall waive the education and experience requirements of &#xA7; 10-302(d) of this subtitle for an applicant for an occupational therapist license:<section prefix="(i)">Who applied for a license before July 1, 1979;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Whose principal residence is in this State;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Who presents to the Board satisfactory evidence that the applicant practiced occupational therapy in this State for at least 2 years before July 1, 1979; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">Who has a baccalaureate degree in a health science from an accredited college or university.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Except for an applicant who was licensed as an occupational therapy assistant under subsection (b) of this section, the Board shall waive the education requirements of &#xA7; 10-302(d) of this subtitle for an applicant for an occupational therapist license who has:<section prefix="(i)">Practiced limited occupational therapy for at least 4 years either as a licensed occupational therapy assistant or as an occupational therapy assistant certified by the American Occupational Therapy Association; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Had at least 6 months full-time supervised field work experience.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Board shall waive the requirements of &#xA7; 10-302(e) of this subtitle for an applicant for an occupational therapy assistant license:<section prefix="(1)">Who applied for a license before July 1, 1979;</section><section prefix="(2)">Whose principal residence is in this State;</section><section prefix="(3)">Who presents to the Board satisfactory evidence that the applicant has practiced limited occupational therapy in this State for at least 2 years before July 1, 1979; and</section><section prefix="(4)">Who has a high school diploma or has completed successfully a high school equivalency examination or program.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
