<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gho" order_by="gho" level="1">Health Occupations</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gho-19-304</section_number>
  <catch_line>An approved applicant is entitled to be examined for licensure as provided in this section....</catch_line>
  <order_by>304</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">An approved applicant is entitled to be examined for licensure as provided in this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Board shall ensure that a Board-approved examination for each category of license is made available for an applicant to take at least twice a year, at the times and places that the Board determines.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Board shall notify each approved applicant of the procedures for taking the examination.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Board shall approve the subjects, scope, form, and passing score for each type of examination given under this subtitle.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The examinations given under this subtitle shall strive to be free of cultural bias.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Board, by regulation, may limit:<section prefix="(i)">The number of times an applicant may be reexamined after failing an examination required under this subtitle; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">The interval between reexaminations.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If an applicant is permitted to be reexamined under paragraph (1) of this subsection, the applicant shall pay a fee to the examining body approved by the Board.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">Notwithstanding the provisions of &#xA7; 19-302 of this subtitle, an applicant for a certified social worker license or a certified social worker-clinical license who was enrolled in a doctoral program on October 1, 1992 and has remained continuously enrolled in a doctoral program and who otherwise qualifies for the applicable license is entitled to be examined for that license as provided in this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">The examination shall be prepared to measure the competence of the applicant to engage in the pertinent practice of social work.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">In the preparation, administration, and grading of an examination, the Board may employ, cooperate, or contract with an organization or consultant.</section>
  </text>
</law>
