<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gho" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="12-309" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gho-12-309</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Except as permitted in subsections (b) and (c) of this section, the Board may not renew the license and issue a certificate of renewal to any pharmacist until the pharmacist presents evidence of having completed 30 hours of approved continuing pharmaceutical education within the preceding 2 years.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Board may renew the license and issue a certificate of renewal to a pharmacist who presents acceptable evidence that the pharmacist was unable to comply with subsection (a) of this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Board may renew the license and issue a certificate of renewal for the first renewal period following the issuance of the original license without requiring a pharmacist to complete any continuing pharmaceutical education, if the pharmacist obtains a license within 1 year of the completion of the pharmacist's pharmaceutical education.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Board shall evaluate and approve programs of continuing pharmaceutical education submitted to the Board by the person who intends to offer the program.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">Each program of continuing pharmaceutical education shall consist of at least 1 continuing education unit, which is 1 hour of participation in an organized continuing educational experience, including postgraduate studies, institutes, seminars, lectures, conferences, workshops, correspondence courses, cassette programs, programmed learning courses, audiovisual programs, and any other form of presentation that is approved by the Board.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">Any aspect of the practice of pharmacy may be the subject of a program of continuing pharmaceutical education, including pharmaceutics (compounding), pharmacology, pharmaceutical chemistry, biochemistry, physiology, microbiology, pharmacy administration, and professional practice management.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">Each program of continuing pharmaceutical education submitted to the Board of Pharmacy for approval shall:<section prefix="(1)">Have a definite stated objective;</section><section prefix="(2)">Be presented in an organized manner by a qualified instructor or resource person; and</section><section prefix="(3)">Include a method of program evaluation that is suitable to the type of program being presented.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(h)">Each person who offers a program of continuing pharmaceutical education shall:<section prefix="(1)">Provide a means for registration by the participants;</section><section prefix="(2)">Maintain a record of participation for at least 3 years; and</section><section prefix="(3)">Furnish each participant with adequate documentation of satisfactory completion of the program, including:<section prefix="(i)">The name of the participant;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The name of the sponsor;</section><section prefix="(iii)">The type of program completed;</section><section prefix="(iv)">The number of continuing education hours or units completed; and</section><section prefix="(v)">The date of completion.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(i)">For purposes of evaluation, members of the Board may attend and participate in any continuing pharmaceutical education program approved for credit.</section>
    <section prefix="(j)">A pharmacist who completes a program of continuing pharmaceutical education that is not previously approved by the Board may request the Board, in writing, to approve the program for credit.</section>
    <section prefix="(k)">The Board shall adopt regulations that are necessary to carry out the purposes of this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(l)">Any continuing education program that is currently approved by the American Council on Pharmaceutical Education automatically qualifies for continuing education credit.</section>
  </text>
</law>
