<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gho" order_by="" level="1">Health Occupations</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gho-11-202</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>202</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Board consists of 7 members.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Of the 7 members:<section prefix="(i)">Five shall be licensed optometrists; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Two shall be consumer members.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Governor shall appoint the optometrist members, with the advice of the Secretary, from a list submitted to the Secretary by the Maryland Optometric Association.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The number of names on the list shall be three times the number of vacancies.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">For each optometrist vacancy, the Maryland Optometric Association shall:<section prefix="(i)">Notify all licensed optometrists in the State of the vacancy to solicit nominations to fill the vacancy; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Conduct a balloting process where every licensed optometrist is eligible to vote to select the names of the licensed optometrists that will be submitted to the Governor.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(6)">The Governor shall appoint the consumer members with the advice of the Secretary and the advice and consent of the Senate.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">For at least 5 years before appointment, each optometrist member of the Board shall have:<section prefix="(1)">Resided in this State; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Practiced optometry actively and continuously in this State.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The consumer members of the Board:<section prefix="(1)">Shall be a member of the general public;</section><section prefix="(2)">May not be or ever have been an optometrist or in training to become an optometrist;</section><section prefix="(3)">May not have a household member who is an optometrist or in training to become an optometrist;</section><section prefix="(4)">May not participate or ever have participated in a commercial or professional field related to optometry;</section><section prefix="(5)">May not have a household member who participates in a commercial or professional field related to optometry; and</section><section prefix="(6)">May not have had within 2 years before appointment a substantial financial interest in a person regulated by the Board.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">While a member of the Board, a consumer member may not have a substantial financial interest in a person regulated by the Board.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">Before taking office, each appointee to the Board shall take the oath required by Article I, &#xA7; 9 of the Maryland Constitution.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The term of a member is 4 years.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The terms of members are staggered as required by the terms provided for members of the Board on July 1, 1982.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">At the end of a term, a member continues to serve until a successor is appointed and qualifies.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">A member who is appointed after a term has begun serves only for the rest of the term and until a successor is appointed and qualifies.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">To the extent practicable, the Governor shall fill any vacancy on the Board within 60 days of the date of the vacancy.</section>
      <section prefix="(6)">A member may not serve more than 2 consecutive full terms.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Governor may remove a member for incompetence or misconduct.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Upon the recommendation of the Secretary, the Governor may remove a member whom the Secretary finds to have been absent from 2 successive Board meetings without adequate reason.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
