<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gho" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="12-318" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gho-12-318</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, "pharmacy review committee" means an advisory committee appointed by the Board from a pool of Board approved pharmacists to aid the Board in licensing and disciplinary matters.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A pharmacy review committee shall:<section prefix="(1)">Evaluate and seek to improve the quality of pharmaceutical care provided by providers of pharmaceutical care;</section><section prefix="(2)">Evaluate the need for and the level of performance of pharmaceutical care provided by providers of pharmaceutical care;</section><section prefix="(3)">Evaluate the qualifications, competence, and performance of providers of pharmaceutical care; or</section><section prefix="(4)">Evaluate and act on matters that relate to the discipline of any provider of pharmaceutical care.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This subsection does not apply to:<section prefix="(i)">A civil action brought by a party to the proceedings of the pharmacy review committee who claims to be aggrieved by the decision of the pharmacy review committee; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">Any record or document that is considered by the pharmacy review committee and that otherwise would be subject to discovery and introduction into evidence in a civil trial.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The proceedings, records, and files of a pharmacy review committee are not discoverable and are not admissible in evidence in any civil action arising out of matters that are being reviewed and evaluated by the pharmacy review committee.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A person who acts in good faith and within the scope of jurisdiction of a pharmacy review committee is not civilly liable for any action as a member of the pharmacy review committee or for giving information to, participating in, or contributing to the function of the pharmacy review committee.</section>
  </text>
</law>
