<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gho" order_by="gho" level="1">Health Occupations</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gho-17-303</section_number>
  <catch_line>To qualify for a license to practice clinical marriage and family therapy, an applicant shall be an ...</catch_line>
  <order_by>303</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">To qualify for a license to practice clinical marriage and family therapy, an applicant shall be an individual who meets the requirements of this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The applicant shall be of good moral character.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The applicant shall be at least 18 years old.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in &#xA7; 17-306 of this subtitle, the applicant shall hold a master's or doctoral degree in a marriage and family field from an accredited educational institution that is approved by the Board or have completed a program of studies judged by the Board to be substantially equivalent in subject matter and extent of training as required under this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">In the case of an applicant holding a doctoral degree, the applicant shall have completed a minimum of 90 graduate credit hours in training in marriage and family therapy approved by the Board that includes instruction in the following specialized areas:<section prefix="(i)">Analysis of family systems;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Family therapy, theory, and techniques;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Couples therapy, theory, and techniques;</section><section prefix="(iv)">Gender and ethnicity in marriage and family therapy; and</section><section prefix="(v)">Sexual issues in marriage and family therapy.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">In the case of an applicant holding only a master's degree, the applicant shall have completed a minimum of 60 graduate credit hours in training in marriage and family therapy approved by the Board that includes instruction in the specialized areas set forth in paragraph (2) of this subsection.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The applicant shall have completed not less than 2 years with a minimum of 2,000 hours of supervised experience in marriage and family therapy approved by the Board, 2 years of which shall have been completed after the award of the master's or doctoral degree or its substantial equivalent.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The applicant shall provide documentation to the Board evidencing the completion of 60 hours of graduate course work completed at an accredited college or university approved by the Board, that included training in:<section prefix="(1)">Personality development;</section><section prefix="(2)">Diagnosis and treatment of mental and emotional disorders;</section><section prefix="(3)">Psychopathology;</section><section prefix="(4)">Family therapy; and</section><section prefix="(5)">Psychotherapy.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(g)">The applicant shall provide documentation evidencing the completion of 2 years of postgraduate supervised clinical experience as required by the Board.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">Except as otherwise provided in this title, the applicant shall pass an examination approved by the Board.</section>
  </text>
</law>
