<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gho" order_by="gho" level="1">Health Occupations</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gho-21-304</section_number>
  <catch_line>An applicant who otherwise qualifies for licensure is entitled to be examined as provided in this se...</catch_line>
  <order_by>304</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">An applicant who otherwise qualifies for licensure is entitled to be examined as provided in this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">An applicant qualifies to take the examination if the applicant:<section prefix="(1)"><section prefix="(i)">Has graduated from an accredited college or university with a baccalaureate degree in environmental science or environmental health; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Has obtained 12 months of experience in an environmental health specialist-in-training program approved by the Board;</section></section><section prefix="(2)"><section prefix="(i)">Has graduated from an accredited college or university with a baccalaureate degree in the physical, biological, or environmental sciences including:<section prefix="1.">A minimum of 60 semester credit hours or the equivalent quarter credit hours of physical, biological, and environmental sciences acceptable to the Board which includes at least one laboratory course in two of the following fields:</section><section prefix="2.">A course in mathematics; and</section></section><section prefix="(ii)">Has obtained 12 months of experience in an environmental health specialist-in-training program approved by the Board;</section></section><section prefix="(3)"><section prefix="(i)">Has graduated from an accredited college or university with a baccalaureate degree that includes:<section prefix="1.">30 semester credit hours or the equivalent quarter credit hours in the physical, biological, and environmental sciences acceptable to the Board, which includes at least one laboratory course in two of the following fields:</section><section prefix="2.">A course in mathematics; and</section></section><section prefix="(ii)">Has obtained 24 months of experience in an environmental health specialist-in-training program approved by the Board; or</section></section><section prefix="(4)">Has graduated from an accredited college or university with a master's degree in public or environmental health science that includes:<section prefix="(i)">30 semester credit hours or 45 quarter credit hours of physical, biological, or environmental sciences acceptable to the Board, which includes at least one laboratory course in two of the following fields:<section prefix="1.">Chemistry;</section><section prefix="2.">Physics; and</section><section prefix="3.">Biology;</section></section><section prefix="(ii)">A course in mathematics; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">3 months of internship approved by the Board if not previously completed.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This subsection does not alter the requirement that an applicant demonstrate completion of a baccalaureate or master's degree to qualify for examination.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Board may waive any of the specific course requirements for an applicant to qualify for examination in subsection (b) of this section if the Board determines that an applicant:<section prefix="(i)">Has obtained an equivalent number of credit hours in a course relevant to practice as an environmental health specialist; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">Has work experience that is an acceptable substitute for a course required in subsection (b) of this section.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Board may waive the experience requirement in subsection (b)(3)(ii) of this section if the Board determines that an applicant:<section prefix="(i)">Has obtained at least 12 months of experience in an environmental health specialist-in-training program; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Has the written support of the applicant's employer.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The examination shall include a written examination in the physical, biological, and environmental sciences that relates to practices and principles of environmental health.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The Board shall give examinations to applicants at least once a year, at the times and places that the Board determines.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The Board shall notify each qualified applicant of the time and place of examination.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as otherwise provided in this subtitle, the Board shall determine the subjects, scope, form, and passing score for examinations given under this subtitle.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Board shall use professional examinations prepared by recognized examination agencies.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Examination papers shall identify the applicant only by a number assigned by the Board secretary.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(h)">Examination papers shall be filed with the Board secretary and kept at least 1 year.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">
      <section prefix="(1)">An applicant who fails an examination may retake the examination as provided in the rules and regulations adopted by the Board.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">An applicant for reexamination shall:<section prefix="(i)">Submit to the Board an application on the form the Board requires; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Pay to the Board a reexamination fee set by the Board.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(j)">Unless authorized by the Board, the consumer members of the Board may not participate in any activity related to examinations under this subtitle.</section>
  </text>
</law>
