<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gho" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="14-504" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gho-14-504</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">This section does not apply to a dentist performing acupuncture in connection with the practice of dentistry if the dentist is licensed or otherwise authorized to practice dentistry under Title 4 of this article.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Unless licensed under Title 1A of this article, a physician shall be registered by the Board before the physician may perform acupuncture in this State.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Board shall register to perform acupuncture any physician who meets the following requirements:<section prefix="(1)"><section prefix="(i)">Successful completion of at least 200 hours of training in a program of study in acupuncture, including any examinations required under the program, approved for category 1 continuing medical education credit by an institution accredited or recognized by the Accreditation Council on Continuing Medical Education; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">Successful completion of a course of study approved by the Board which includes at least 200 hours of instruction in:</section></section><section prefix="(2)">Ability to communicate in the English language;</section><section prefix="(3)">Payment of application and registration fees; and</section><section prefix="(4)">Other reasonable conditions determined by the Board.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A physician who is registered under this section may perform acupuncture on or off the premises of the physician's office.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">A physician who performs acupuncture may advertise only as permitted by the rules and regulations of the Board.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The Board may adopt rules and regulations to carry out the provisions of this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">Subject to the hearing provisions of &#xA7; 14-405 of this title, the Board, on the affirmative vote of a majority of its quorum, may reprimand or place a physician who performs acupuncture on probation or suspend or revoke the registration of a physician for:<section prefix="(1)">Any conduct prohibited under the provisions of this section or prohibited under any regulation adopted pursuant to the provisions of this section;</section><section prefix="(2)">Except in an emergency life-threatening situation where it is not feasible or practicable, failing to comply with the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention's guidelines on universal precautions; or</section><section prefix="(3)">Failing to display the notice required under subsection (h) of this section.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(h)">If a physician who performs acupuncture is engaged in the private practice of acupuncture in this State, the physician who performs acupuncture shall display the notice developed under &#xA7; 1-207 of this article conspicuously in each office where the physician is engaged in practice.</section>
  </text>
</law>
