<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gho" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="3-502" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gho-3-502</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Unless authorized to practice chiropractic under this title, a person may not represent to the public by title, by description of services, methods, or procedures, or otherwise, that the person is authorized to practice chiropractic in this State.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Unless authorized to practice under this title, a person may not use the title "chiropractor", or "D.C.", or any other term or title with the intent to represent that the person practices chiropractic.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">An individual who is not a licensed massage therapist or registered as a massage practitioner under this title may not advertise or claim by title, abbreviation, sign, card, or any other representation that the individual practices massage, massage therapy, myotherapy, or any synonym or derivation of these terms.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Unless authorized to practice under this title, a person may not use the title "massage therapist", "MT", "licensed massage therapist", "LMT", "massage practitioner", "MP", "registered massage practitioner", "RMP", or any other term or title with the intent to represent that the person practices massage therapy.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">An individual who is a registered massage practitioner under this title or a business entity that employs registered massage practitioners under this title may not advertise to the public that the individual or business entity provides health-related therapeutic massage services.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In Charles County and Washington County, an individual may not perform a massage or offer to perform a massage on another person for compensation unless the individual who performs the massage or offers to perform a massage is a  licensed massage therapist or registered massage practitioner.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A law enforcement officer in Charles County or Washington County may demand proof of licensure or registration.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
