<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gho" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="1-204" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gho-1-204</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.<section prefix="(1)">"Health occupation" means nurses, cytotechnologists, hospital pharmacists, occupational therapists, physical therapists, radiation technologists, and respiratory therapists who are licensed or certified under this article or by the Department.</section><section prefix="(2)">"Hospital or related institution" means a hospital or related institution, as defined in &#xA7; 19-301 of the Health - General Article.</section><section prefix="(3)">"Area of shortage" means those health occupations for which the average statewide employment vacancy rate at hospitals or related institutions exceeds 7 percent.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Each year, the Secretary shall:<section prefix="(1)">Survey hospitals and related institutions for areas of shortage; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Project for each of the subsequent 5 years:<section prefix="(i)">Average statewide employment vacancy rates expected in areas of shortage; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">The number of students expected to graduate from programs leading to licensure or certification in those areas of shortage based on information provided by appropriate State education officials.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Each board or commission established under this article shall provide the Secretary with any information the Secretary may require to conduct the activities under subsection (b) of this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Each year, the Secretary shall report to the General Assembly, in accordance with &#xA7; 2-1246 of the State Government Article, the Governor, and the Maryland Higher Education Commission on the number and types of areas of shortage and the projected statewide employment vacancy rates in hospitals and related institutions.</section>
  </text>
</law>
