<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gho" order_by="gho" level="1">Health Occupations</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gho-7-205</section_number>
  <catch_line>In addition to the powers and duties set forth elsewhere in this title, the Board has the following ...</catch_line>
  <order_by>205</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In addition to the powers and duties set forth elsewhere in this title, the Board has the following powers and duties:<section prefix="(1)">To adopt bylaws, rules, and regulations to carry out the provisions of this title;</section><section prefix="(2)">To adopt a seal;</section><section prefix="(3)">To establish procedures for licensing apprentices;</section><section prefix="(4)">To keep a list of all individuals currently licensed by the Board;</section><section prefix="(5)">To investigate any alleged violation of this title;</section><section prefix="(6)">To enforce this title;</section><section prefix="(7)">To adopt rules and regulations regarding false and misleading advertising and misrepresentation;</section><section prefix="(8)">To inspect licensed funeral establishments;</section><section prefix="(9)">On receipt of a written and signed complaint, including a referral from the Commissioner of Labor and Industry, to conduct an unannounced inspection of the funeral establishment to determine compliance at that funeral establishment with the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention's guidelines on universal precautions;</section><section prefix="(10)">To establish standards for the practice of mortuary science; and</section><section prefix="(11)">To establish standards for sanitation and waste disposal in connection with the practice of mortuary science.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Board may conduct an audit of a licensee that:<section prefix="(1)">Receives pre-need funds;</section><section prefix="(2)">Places pre-need funds in a trust; or</section><section prefix="(3)">Enters into a pre-need contract.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">In conjunction with the Office of Cemetery Oversight, the Board shall:<section prefix="(1)">Establish a process for regulating crematories that provides for:<section prefix="(i)">Registration or licensure and renewal;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Applications, including certification of ownership and identification of individuals who will perform cremation;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Registration or licensure fees;</section><section prefix="(iv)">Inspections and oversight;</section><section prefix="(v)">Grounds for discipline and penalties; and</section><section prefix="(vi)">Complaints and hearings; and</section></section><section prefix="(2)">Adopt regulations that are identical to regulations adopted by the Director of the Office of Cemetery Oversight to:<section prefix="(i)">Implement item (1) of this subsection; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Ensure public health and safety.</section></section></section>
  </text>
</law>
