<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gho" order_by="" level="1">Health Occupations</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gho-17-513</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>513</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">An action may be maintained in the name of the State or the Board to enjoin:<section prefix="(1)">The unauthorized practice of alcohol and drug counseling and clinical alcohol and drug counseling, marriage and family therapy and clinical marriage and family therapy, professional counseling and clinical professional counseling, or clinical professional art therapy; or</section><section prefix="(2)">Conduct that is a ground for disciplinary action under &#xA7; 17-509 of this subtitle.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">An action under this section may be brought by:<section prefix="(1)">The Board, in its own name;</section><section prefix="(2)">The Attorney General, in the name of the State; or</section><section prefix="(3)">A State's Attorney, in the name of the State.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">An action under this section shall be brought in the county where the defendant:<section prefix="(1)">Resides; or</section><section prefix="(2)">Engages in the acts sought to be enjoined.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Proof of actual damages or that any person will sustain any damages if an injunction is not granted is not required for an action under this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">An action under this section is in addition to and not instead of criminal prosecution for the unauthorized practice of alcohol and drug counseling and clinical alcohol and drug counseling, marriage and family therapy and clinical marriage and family therapy, professional counseling and clinical professional counseling, or clinical professional art therapy, under &#xA7; 17-301, &#xA7; 17-601, &#xA7; 17-602, or &#xA7; 17-603 of this title or disciplinary action under &#xA7; 17-509 of this subtitle.</section>
  </text>
</law>
