<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gho" order_by="" level="1">Health Occupations</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gho-8-302</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>302</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Except as otherwise provided in this title, to qualify for a license or certification, an applicant shall be an individual who submits to a criminal history records check in accordance with &#xA7; 8-303 of this subtitle and meets the requirements of this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">An applicant for certification as an advanced practice nurse shall:<section prefix="(i)">Be a registered nurse;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Complete an education program approved by the Board;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Submit to the Board:<section prefix="1.">A completed application for certification as a nurse practitioner, nurse anesthetist, nurse midwife, nurse psychotherapist, or clinical nurse specialist for each area in which certification is sought;</section><section prefix="2.">Documentation of an active license in good standing as a registered nurse in the State;</section><section prefix="3.">Documentation that the applicant has graduated from an accredited program for advanced practice nursing for nurse practitioners, nurse anesthetists, nurse midwives, nurse psychotherapists, or clinical nurse specialists; and</section><section prefix="4.">Documentation of certification as a nurse practitioner, nurse anesthetist, nurse midwife, nurse psychotherapist, or clinical nurse specialist by a nationally recognized certifying body approved by the Board; and</section></section><section prefix="(iv)">Meet any other requirements that the Board sets.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">An individual certified as a nurse practitioner by a national certifying body prior to October 1, 2010 who is certified by the Board and in good standing shall be deemed to meet the education requirements under subsection (b)(1)(iii)3 of this section.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">An individual certified as a nurse anesthetist, nurse midwife, nurse psychotherapist, or clinical nurse specialist who is certified by the Board and in good standing prior to October 1, 2012, shall be deemed to meet the education requirements under subsection (b)(1)(iii)3 of this section.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">In addition to the requirements for renewal of a license under &#xA7; 8-312 of this subtitle, the Board may establish continuing education or competency requirements for the renewal of a certificate under this subsection.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Subject to the provisions of this subsection, the Board may waive any requirement of this subsection for an applicant who is licensed or certified to practice as a nurse practitioner, nurse anesthetist, nurse midwife, nurse psychotherapist, or clinical nurse specialist in any other state or country.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The Board may grant a waiver under this paragraph only if the applicant:<section prefix="1.">Pays the application fee required by the Board under &#xA7; 8-304 of this subtitle;</section><section prefix="2.">Became licensed or certified in the other state or country under requirements substantially equivalent to the certification requirements of this title; and</section><section prefix="3.">Meets any other qualifications established by the Board.</section></section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(5)">
        <section prefix="(i)">A certified nurse practitioner may not practice in the State unless the nurse practitioner has an approved attestation that:<section prefix="1.">The nurse practitioner has an agreement for collaboration and consulting with a physician licensed under Title 14 of this article and will refer to and consult with physicians and other health care providers as needed; and</section><section prefix="2.">The nurse practitioner will practice in accordance with the standards of practice of the American Academy of Nurse Practitioners or any other national certifying body recognized by the Board.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The Board shall:<section prefix="1.">Maintain an approved attestation; and</section><section prefix="2.">Make the approved attestation available to the State Board of Physicians on the request of the State Board of Physicians.</section></section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(6)">Unless authorized to practice as a nurse practitioner under this title, a person may not:<section prefix="(i)">Represent to the public by title or by description of services, methods, or procedures, or otherwise, that the person is authorized to practice as a nurse practitioner in this State;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Use as a title or describe the services the person provides by use of the words "nurse practitioner" or "certified registered nurse practitioner"; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">Use the abbreviation "N.P.", "C.R.N.P.", or any other words, letters, or symbols with the intent to represent that the person practices as a nurse practitioner.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(7)">Unless authorized to practice as a nurse anesthetist under this title, a person may not:<section prefix="(i)">Practice nurse anesthesia unless certified by the Board in accordance with this section; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">Use the title "certified nurse anesthetist", "nurse anesthetist", or any other words, letters, or symbols with the intent to represent that the person practices as a nurse anesthetist.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(8)">Unless authorized to practice as a nurse midwife under this title, a person may not:<section prefix="(i)">Practice nurse midwifery unless certified by the Board in accordance with this section; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">Use the title "certified nurse midwife", "nurse midwife", or any other words, letters, or symbols with the intent to represent that the person practices as a nurse midwife.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(9)">Unless authorized to practice as a nurse psychotherapist under this title, a person may not:<section prefix="(i)">Practice as a nurse psychotherapist unless certified by the Board in accordance with this section; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">Use the title "advanced practice nurse", "certified nurse psychotherapist", "registered nurse/psychiatric mental health", "nurse psychotherapist", or any other words, letters, or symbols with the intent to represent that the person practices as a nurse psychotherapist.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(10)">Unless authorized to practice as a clinical nurse specialist under this title, a person may not:<section prefix="(i)">Practice as a clinical nurse specialist unless certified by the Board in accordance with this section; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">Use the title "certified clinical nurse specialist", "clinical nurse specialist", "clinical registered nurse specialist", "clinical nurse specialist graduate", or any other words, letters, or symbols with the intent to represent that the person practices as a clinical nurse specialist.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">An applicant for a license to practice registered nursing shall complete satisfactorily and meet all requirements for a diploma or degree from:<section prefix="(1)">A registered nursing education program approved by the Board; or</section><section prefix="(2)">An education program in registered nursing in any other state or country that the Board finds substantially equivalent to the program in this State.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">An applicant for a license to practice licensed practical nursing shall:<section prefix="(1)">Meet all requirements for a high school diploma or its equivalent; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Complete satisfactorily and meet all requirements for a diploma from:<section prefix="(i)">A licensed practical nursing education program or its equivalent approved by the Board; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">An education program in licensed practical nursing in any other state or country that the Board finds substantially equivalent to the program in this State.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">Except as otherwise provided in this title, the applicant shall pass an examination developed by the National Council of State Boards of Nursing and administered at a testing site approved by the National Council.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as otherwise provided in this subsection, the Board shall require as part of its examination or licensing procedures that an applicant for a license to practice registered nursing or licensed practical nursing demonstrate an oral competency in the English language.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Acceptable proof of proficiency in the oral communication of the English language under this section includes:<section prefix="(i)">After at least 3 years of enrollment, graduation from a recognized English-speaking undergraduate school;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Graduation from a recognized English-speaking professional school; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">Completion of at least 5 years of practicing nursing in another state or English-speaking territory of the United States.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">By regulation, the Board shall develop a procedure for testing individuals who because of their speech impairment are unable to complete satisfactorily a Board approved standardized test of oral competency.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">If any disciplinary charge or action that involves a problem with the oral communication of the English language is brought against a licensee under this title, the Board shall require the licensee to take and pass a Board approved standardized test of oral competency.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">The Board may not require that an applicant for a license to practice registered nursing or licensed practical nursing who was previously licensed in any other state to practice registered nursing or licensed practical nursing to demonstrate an oral competency in the English language as part of its examination or licensing procedures if the other state has a similar oral competency component as part of its examination or licensing procedures.</section>
      <section prefix="(6)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The Board may issue a temporary license to any applicant for a license to practice registered nursing or licensed practical nursing who was previously licensed in any other state to practice registered nursing or licensed practical nursing and who, except for the oral competency in the English language component, is otherwise qualified for a license.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">A temporary license issued under this subsection is valid only until the date when the next test to demonstrate oral competency in the English language is given.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">An applicant for a license or certification under this section shall be of good moral character.</section>
  </text>
</law>
