<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gho" order_by="" level="1">Health Occupations</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gho-17-406</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>406</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Approved alcohol and drug supervisor" means:<section prefix="(i)">A certified professional counselor-alcohol and drug;</section><section prefix="(ii)">A licensed clinical alcohol and drug counselor; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">A health care provider licensed or certified under this article with documented expertise in alcohol and drug counseling, as approved by the Board.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Under the supervision of an approved alcohol and drug supervisor" means engaging in an ongoing process that includes direct, on-site, face-to-face, individual or group meetings with an approved alcohol and drug supervisor focused on quality of delivery of alcohol and drug counseling services and improvement of counseling skills for a minimum of 1 documented hour for each 40-hour workweek but not less than 2 documented hours per month for less than a 40-hour workweek.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">An individual may practice clinical alcohol and drug counseling without a license for a limited period of time, as determined by the Board, if the individual is working as a trainee under the supervision of an approved alcohol and drug supervisor while fulfilling the experiential or course of study requirements under &#xA7; 17-302 of this title or &#xA7; 17-403 or &#xA7; 17-404 of this subtitle.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">An individual may practice alcohol and drug counseling without certification for a limited period of time, as determined by the Board, if the individual is working as a trainee under the supervision of an approved alcohol and drug supervisor while fulfilling the experiential or course of study requirements under &#xA7; 17-302 of this title or &#xA7; 17-403 or &#xA7; 17-404 of this subtitle.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
