<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gho" order_by="gho" level="1">Health Occupations</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gho-8-206</section_number>
  <catch_line>There is a Board of Nursing Fund....</catch_line>
  <order_by>206</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">There is a Board of Nursing Fund.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Board may set reasonable fees for the issuance and renewal of licenses and its other services.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The fees charged shall be set so as to produce funds to approximate the cost of maintaining the Board as provided in subsection (e) of this section.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Board shall publish in its rules and regulations the fees that it sets.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Board shall pay all fees collected under the provisions of this title to the Comptroller of the State.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Comptroller shall distribute the fees received from the Board to the Board of Nursing Fund.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Board of Nursing Fund shall be used exclusively to cover the actual documented direct and indirect costs of fulfilling the statutory and regulatory duties of the Board as provided by the provisions of this title.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The Board of Nursing Fund is a continuing, nonlapsing fund, not subject to &#xA7; 7-302 of the State Finance and Procurement Article.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">Any unspent portions of the Board of Nursing Fund may not be transferred or revert to the General Fund of the State, but shall remain in the Board of Nursing Fund to be used for the purposes specified in this title.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">No other State money may be used to support the Board of Nursing Fund.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Chairman of the Board or the designee of the Chairman shall administer the Board of Nursing Fund.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Moneys in the Board of Nursing Fund may be expended only for any lawful purpose authorized by the provisions of this title.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">The Legislative Auditor shall audit the accounts and transactions of the Board of Nursing Fund as provided in &#xA7; 2-1220 of the State Government Article.</section>
  </text>
</law>
