<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gho" order_by="" level="1">Health Occupations</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gho-7-309</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>309</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Except as otherwise provided by law, a corporation may not operate a mortuary science business and the Board may not issue a license to or list any corporation as licensed to operate a mortuary science business.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Board may renew only the license of a corporation that:<section prefix="(1)">On June 1, 1945, held a license issued by this State;</section><section prefix="(2)">Has been renewed continuously since that date;</section><section prefix="(3)">Submits an application on a form required by the Board; and</section><section prefix="(4)">Pays a fee set by the Board.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Each application for renewal made by a corporation shall state the name and address of each officer and director of the corporation.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">While a corporation license is effective, it authorizes a corporation to operate a mortuary science business only if any practice of mortuary science that is conducted for the corporation is practiced by a licensed individual.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">A corporation may not operate a branch funeral establishment unless the branch funeral establishment was in operation on or before October 1, 1964.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">If a corporation is sold, declares bankruptcy, or ceases to operate, written notice must be submitted to:<section prefix="(1)">The Board, within 2 weeks of the occurrence, detailing the changes and the arrangements for carrying out the pre-need contracts and disbursement of the money held in escrow; and</section><section prefix="(2)">The holders of pre-need contracts advising them of their options under Maryland law.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
