<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gho" order_by="" level="1">Health Occupations</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gho-8-202</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>202</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Board consists of 13 members.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Of the 13 Board members:<section prefix="(i)">8 shall be registered nurses;</section><section prefix="(ii)">3 shall be licensed practical nurses; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">2 shall be consumers.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Of the 8 registered nurse members:<section prefix="(i)">1 shall be certified in an advanced practice nursing specialty that rotates with each vacancy among the following specialties:<section prefix="1.">Nurse anesthetist;</section><section prefix="2.">Nurse practitioner;</section><section prefix="3.">Nurse midwife; and</section><section prefix="4.">Nurse psychotherapist;</section></section><section prefix="(ii)">1 shall be a baccalaureate nursing educator with, at least, a master's degree in nursing or education;</section><section prefix="(iii)">1 shall be an associate degree nursing educator with, at least, a master's degree in nursing or education;</section><section prefix="(iv)">1 shall be a practical nursing educator with, at least, a bachelor of science degree in nursing or education;</section><section prefix="(v)">1 shall be a nurse administrator with, at least, a master's degree in nursing administration, business administration, business management, education, or public health;</section><section prefix="(vi)">1 shall be a nurse clinician with at least a master's degree in nursing or public health;</section><section prefix="(vii)">1 shall be a currently practicing nurse, who has practiced acute care for at least 5 years, with a bachelor of science degree in nursing; and</section><section prefix="(viii)">1 shall be a currently practicing nurse who has practiced as a delegating nurse in a supervised group living setting, as defined in COMAR 10.27.11.02(20), for at least 5 years.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">Of the 3 licensed practical nurse members, at least 1 shall practice in a long-term care nursing facility.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Governor shall appoint:<section prefix="(i)">The registered nurse member certified in an advanced practice nursing specialty, with the advice of the Secretary, from a list of qualified individuals jointly developed in accordance with the requirements of subsection (a)(3)(i) of this section and submitted to the Secretary and the Governor by the:<section prefix="1.">Maryland Association of Nurse Anesthetists, Inc.;</section><section prefix="2.">Nurse Practitioners Association of Maryland, Inc.;</section><section prefix="3.">Maryland Coalition of Nurse Practitioners, Inc.;</section><section prefix="4.">Maryland Chapter, American College of Nurse-Midwives; and</section><section prefix="5.">Psychiatric Advance Practice Nurses of Maryland; and</section></section><section prefix="(ii)">The other registered nurse members, with the advice of the Secretary, from:<section prefix="1.">A list of qualified individuals submitted to the Secretary and the Governor by:</section><section prefix="2.">A valid petition submitted to the Secretary and the Governor by a registered nurse with an active license under this title.</section></section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Governor shall appoint the licensed practical nurse members, with the advice of the Secretary, from:<section prefix="(i)">A list of qualified individuals submitted to the Secretary and the Governor by:<section prefix="1.">The Maryland Licensed Practical Nurse Association, Inc.; or</section><section prefix="2.">Any other professional nursing organization representing at least 25 licensed practical nurses; or</section></section><section prefix="(ii)">A valid petition submitted to the Secretary and the Governor by a licensed practical nurse with an active license under this title.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A list submitted to the Secretary and the Governor under this subsection shall be 5 times the number of vacancies.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">A petition submitted to the Secretary and Governor under this subsection shall have at least 25 signatures of support from nurses with active licenses in the State.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">The Board shall provide notice of a vacancy on the Board to:<section prefix="(i)">All nurses with an active license in the State; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">All appropriate professional nursing organizations.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(6)">The Governor may request an additional list of 5 nominees for each vacancy from the appropriate professional nursing organizations.</section>
      <section prefix="(7)">The Governor shall make the appointment for each vacancy from the lists or petitions submitted under this subsection.</section>
      <section prefix="(8)">The Governor shall appoint the consumer members with the advice of the Secretary and the advice and consent of the Senate.</section>
      <section prefix="(9)">To the extent practicable, the members appointed to the Board shall reasonably reflect the geographic, racial, ethnic, cultural, and gender diversity of the State.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Each member of the Board shall be:<section prefix="(1)">A citizen of the United States; and</section><section prefix="(2)">A resident of this State.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A registered nurse member of the Board shall:<section prefix="(i)">Have graduated from an approved school of nursing or its equivalent; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Have at least 5 years of experience in nursing administration, education, or practice, which includes at least the 3 years immediately before the appointment.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A member of the Board who is a registered nurse certified in an advanced practice nursing specialty shall:<section prefix="(i)">Hold a current license to practice registered nursing in this State;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Hold a current certification in an advanced practice nursing specialty in this State; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Have at least 5 years of experience in an advanced practice nursing education or practice, including at least the 3 years immediately before the appointment.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">A licensed practical nurse member of the Board shall have at least 5 years of experience in the practice of licensed practical nursing, which includes at least the 3 years immediately before the appointment.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">Each consumer member of the Board:<section prefix="(1)">Shall be a member of the general public;</section><section prefix="(2)">May not be or ever have been a registered nurse or licensed practical nurse or in training to become a registered nurse or licensed practical nurse;</section><section prefix="(3)">May not have a household member who is a registered nurse or licensed practical nurse or in training to become a registered nurse or licensed practical nurse;</section><section prefix="(4)">May not participate or ever have participated in a commercial or professional field related to registered nursing or licensed practical nursing;</section><section prefix="(5)">May not have a household member who participates in a commercial or professional field related to registered nursing or licensed practical nursing; or</section><section prefix="(6)">May not have had within 2 years before appointment a substantial financial interest in a person who is regulated by the Board.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(g)">While a member of the Board, a consumer member may not have a substantial financial interest in a person regulated by the Board.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">Before taking office, each appointee to the Board shall take the oath required by Article I, &#xA7; 9 of the Maryland Constitution.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The term of a member is 4 years, except that the initial term of 1 of the consumer members is 2 years.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The terms of the members are staggered as required by the terms provided for members of the Board on July 1, 1981.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">At the end of a term, a member continues to serve until a successor is appointed and qualifies.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">A member who is appointed after a term has begun may serve an additional 2 consecutive full terms.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">A member may not serve more than 2 consecutive full terms.</section>
      <section prefix="(6)">To the extent practicable, the Governor shall fill any vacancy on the Board within 60 days of the date of the vacancy.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(j)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Governor may remove a member for incompetence, misconduct, neglect of a duty required by law, unprofessional conduct, or dishonorable conduct.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Upon the recommendation of the Secretary, the Governor may remove a member whom the Secretary finds to have been absent from 2 successive Board meetings without adequate reason.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
