<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gho" order_by="gho" level="1">Health Occupations</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gho-13-319</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this section, "physical therapist rehabilitation committee" means a committee that:...</catch_line>
  <order_by>319</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, "physical therapist rehabilitation committee" means a committee that:<section prefix="(1)">Is defined in subsection (b) of this section; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Performs any of the functions listed in subsection (c) of this section.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">For purposes of this section, a physical therapist rehabilitation committee is a committee of the American Physical Therapy Association of Maryland, Inc. that:<section prefix="(1)">Is recognized by the Board; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Is composed of physical therapists.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">For purposes of this section, a physical therapist rehabilitation committee evaluates and provides assistance to any physical therapist and physical therapist assistant in need of treatment and rehabilitation for alcoholism, drug abuse, chemical dependency, or other physical, emotional, or mental condition.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as otherwise provided in this section, the proceedings, records, and files of the physical therapist rehabilitation committee are not discoverable and are not admissible in evidence in any civil action arising out of matters that are being or have been reviewed and evaluated by the physical therapist rehabilitation committee.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Paragraph (1) of this subsection does not apply to any record or document that is considered by the physical therapist rehabilitation committee and that otherwise would be subject to discovery and introduction into evidence in a civil trial.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">For the purposes of this subsection, civil action does not include a proceeding before the Board or judicial review of a proceeding before the Board.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">A person who acts in good faith and within the scope of jurisdiction of a physical therapist rehabilitation committee is not civilly liable for any action as a member of the physical therapist rehabilitation committee or for giving information to, participating in, or contributing to the function of the physical therapist rehabilitation committee.</section>
  </text>
</law>
