<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gho" order_by="" level="1">Health Occupations</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gho-7-602</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>602</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">A mortuary transport service shall be issued a permit by the Board before the mortuary transport service may remove and transport human remains in this State.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">To apply for a permit, a mortuary transport service shall submit to the Board:<section prefix="(i)">An application on the form that the Board requires;</section><section prefix="(ii)">An application fee set by the Board; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Evidence that the mortuary transport service is bonded and carries liability insurance that covers each registered transporter employed by the mortuary transport service.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">An application for a permit shall be signed by an individual who is the owner or a co-owner of the mortuary transport service to be issued a permit.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">To qualify for a permit, a mortuary transport service shall satisfy the Board that the mortuary transport service:<section prefix="(1)">Has complied with all applicable State and local laws;</section><section prefix="(2)">Will be owned and operated in accordance with this subtitle; and</section><section prefix="(3)">While the mortuary transport service removes and transports human remains, will be held responsible for the treatment of the human remains.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A permit holder shall use vehicles that have passed an inspection by an inspector designated by the Board while the permit holder removes and transports human remains.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A permit holder shall employ only registered transporters to remove and transport human remains.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">A permit issued under this subtitle shall expire on the date set by the Board.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">A permit may not be renewed for a term longer than 2 years.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A permit holder may renew a permit for additional terms, if the permit holder:<section prefix="(i)">Submits to the Board:<section prefix="1.">An application on the form that the Board requires; and</section><section prefix="2.">An application fee set by the Board; and</section></section><section prefix="(ii)">Complies with any other renewal requirements established by the Board.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">Signs and advertisements for a mortuary transport service shall display the name of the mortuary transport service as it appears on the permit.</section>
  </text>
</law>
