<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gho" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="8-6B-14" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gho-8-6B-14</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">A license expires on a date set by the Board, unless the license is renewed for an additional term as provided in this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">On or before December 31, 2012, a license may not be renewed for a term longer than 1 year.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Beginning on January 1, 2013, a license may not be renewed for a term longer than 2 years.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">At least 3 months before a license expires, the Board shall send a renewal notice to the licensee, by:<section prefix="(i)">First-class mail to the last known mailing address of the licensee; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">Electronic means to the last known electronic address of the licensee.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A renewal notice shall state:<section prefix="(i)">The date on which the current license expires;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The date by which the renewal application must be received by the Board for the renewal to be issued and mailed before the license expires; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">The amount of the renewal fee.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Except as otherwise provided in this subtitle, before a license expires, the licensee periodically may renew it for an additional term, if the licensee:<section prefix="(1)">Otherwise is entitled to be licensed;</section><section prefix="(2)">Pays to the Board a renewal fee set by the Board; and</section><section prefix="(3)">Submits to the Board:<section prefix="(i)">A renewal application on the form that the Board requires; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Satisfactory evidence of compliance with any continuing education requirement set under this subtitle for license renewal.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">In addition to any other qualifications and requirements established by the Board, the Board may establish continuing education or competency requirements as a condition to the renewal of licenses under this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">Subject to subsection (k) of this section, the Board shall renew the license of each licensee who meets the requirements of this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">If a licensee fails to provide satisfactory evidence of compliance with any continuing education requirements set under this subtitle for license renewal, the Board shall place the licensee on inactive status.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Board shall place a licensee on inactive status, if the licensee submits to the Board:<section prefix="(i)">An application for inactive status on the form required by the Board; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">The inactive status fee set by the Board.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Board shall reactivate the license of an individual who is on inactive status, if the individual:<section prefix="(i)">Complies with any continuing education requirement established by the Board for this purpose;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Pays to the Board a reactivation fee set by the Board; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Is otherwise entitled to be licensed.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">If the individual has been on inactive status for 5 years or more, before the Board may reactivate the license, the individual must pass an examination approved by the Board.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(i)">The Board, in accordance with its rules and regulations, shall reinstate the license of an individual who has failed to renew the license for any reason if the individual:<section prefix="(1)">Is otherwise entitled to be licensed;</section><section prefix="(2)">Complies with any continuing education requirement established by the Board for this purpose;</section><section prefix="(3)">Pays to the Board a reinstatement fee set by the Board; and</section><section prefix="(4)">Applies to the Board for reinstatement of the license within 5 years after the license expires.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(j)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Board may not reinstate the license of an electrologist or an electrology instructor who fails to apply for reinstatement of the license within 5 years after the license expires.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The electrologist or electrology instructor may become licensed by meeting the current requirements for obtaining a new license under this subtitle.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(k)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Beginning January 2011, the Board shall begin a process requiring criminal history records checks on selected annual renewal applicants as determined by regulations adopted by the Board in accordance with &#xA7; 8-303 of this title.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">An additional criminal history records check shall be performed every 12 years thereafter.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">On receipt of the criminal history record information of a licensee forwarded to the Board in accordance with &#xA7; 8-303 of this title, in determining whether to renew a license, the Board shall consider:<section prefix="(i)">The age at which the crime was committed;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The circumstances surrounding the crime;</section><section prefix="(iii)">The length of time that has passed since the crime;</section><section prefix="(iv)">Subsequent work history;</section><section prefix="(v)">Employment and character references; and</section><section prefix="(vi)">Other evidence that demonstrates that the licensee does not pose a threat to the public health or safety.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Board may not renew a license if the criminal history record information required under &#xA7; 8-303 of this title has not been received.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
