<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gho" order_by="gho" level="1">Health Occupations</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gho-8-204</section_number>
  <catch_line>Except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, a majority of the full authorized membership...</catch_line>
  <order_by>204</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, a majority of the full authorized membership of the Board that includes at least one officer is a quorum.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">In addition to the requirements of paragraph (1) of this subsection, on a matter concerning licensing or disciplining of an individual, a quorum shall include:<section prefix="(i)">At least three registered nurse members if a registered nurse or an applicant for a license as a registered nurse is involved; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">At least two licensed practical nurse members if a licensed practical nurse or an applicant for a license as a licensed practical nurse is involved.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">In addition to the other meeting requirements of this title, the Board shall meet:<section prefix="(1)">At the request of the Secretary; or</section><section prefix="(2)">If necessary to transact its business.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">In accordance with the State budget, each member of the Board is entitled to:<section prefix="(1)">Compensation, at a rate determined by the Board, for each day on which the member is engaged in the duties of the member's office; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Reimbursement for expenses under the Standard State Travel Regulations.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Board may:<section prefix="(1)">Employ a staff in accordance with the State budget;</section><section prefix="(2)">Define the duties of its staff; and</section><section prefix="(3)">Employ an executive director who shall be a registered nurse with a minimum of a master's degree in nursing or the equivalent, in the judgment of the Board, in professional education and administrative experience.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
