<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gho" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="11-307.1" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gho-11-307.1</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">An applicant for a limited license shall submit to the Board:<section prefix="(1)">An application on the form the Board requires; and</section><section prefix="(2)">A written confirmation of participation from the institution in which the applicant intends to participate in a postgraduate teaching, research, or training program.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Board may waive the examination requirements of this subtitle and issue a limited license to practice optometry to an individual who:<section prefix="(1)">Is qualified for a postgraduate teaching, research, or training position;</section><section prefix="(2)">Is applying to participate in a postgraduate teaching, research, or training program approved by the Board under this subsection;</section><section prefix="(3)">Is eligible to sit for the Maryland licensure examination;</section><section prefix="(4)">Is licensed, at the time of application, to practice optometry in another state; and</section><section prefix="(5)">Pays the fee set by the Board.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A limited license authorizes the licensee for 1 year to practice optometry only:<section prefix="(1)">At the institution that has been approved by the Board and is designated on the individual's license;</section><section prefix="(2)">At other institutions that are affiliated with the designated institution; and</section><section prefix="(3)">On the patients of the designated institution or its affiliates.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Board may renew a limited license once for an additional 1-year term if the holder:<section prefix="(1)">Otherwise meets the requirements of this section;</section><section prefix="(2)">Submits a renewal application to the Board on the form that the Board requires; and</section><section prefix="(3)">Pays to the Board the limited license renewal fee set by the Board.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
