<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gho" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="16-307" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gho-16-307</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Except as provided for a limited license in &#xA7; 16-317 of this subtitle, a license expires on the date set by the Board, unless the license is renewed for an additional term as provided in this section. A license may not be renewed for a term longer than 2 years.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">At least 1 month before a license expires, the Board shall send to the licensee, by first-class mail to the last known address of the licensee, a renewal notice that states:<section prefix="(1)">The date on which the current license expires;</section><section prefix="(2)">The date by which the renewal application must be received by the Board for the renewal to be issued and mailed before the license expires; and</section><section prefix="(3)">The amount of the renewal fee.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Before the license expires, a licensee periodically may renew it for an additional 2-year term, if the licensee:<section prefix="(1)">Otherwise is entitled to be licensed;</section><section prefix="(2)">Pays to the Board a renewal fee set by the Board; and</section><section prefix="(3)">Submits to the Board:<section prefix="(i)">A renewal application on the form that the Board requires; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Satisfactory evidence of compliance with any continuing education requirements set under this subtitle for license renewal.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Board may establish continuing education requirements as a condition to the renewal of licenses under this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The Board shall renew the license of each licensee who meets the requirements of this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A podiatrist has a grace period of 30 days after the podiatrist's license expires in which to renew the license retroactively, if the podiatrist:<section prefix="(i)">Otherwise is entitled to have the license renewed; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Pays to the Board the renewal fee and any late fee set by the Board.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">After the grace period of 30 days:<section prefix="(i)">The expired license lapses into a nonrenewal status; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">The Board may require the licensee to meet the requirements of &#xA7; 16-308 to be reinstated.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
