<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gho" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="16-302" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gho-16-302</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">To qualify for a license, an applicant shall be an individual who meets the requirements of this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The applicant shall be of good moral character.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The applicant shall be at least 18 years old.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The applicant shall be a graduate of a school or college of podiatry that is accredited by the Council on Education of the American Podiatric Medical Association and approved by the Board.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">Except as otherwise provided in this title, the applicant shall pass an examination given by the Board under this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The Board may require an applicant to complete a postgraduate podiatric residency program in:<section prefix="(1)">A health care facility licensed or approved by the Department;</section><section prefix="(2)">A program approved by the Council on Education of the American Podiatric Medical Association or its successor; or</section><section prefix="(3)">A program approved by the Board.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Board shall require as part of its examination or licensing procedures that an applicant for a license to practice podiatry demonstrate an oral competency in the English language.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Graduation from a recognized English-speaking undergraduate school after at least 3 years of enrollment, or from a recognized English-speaking professional school is acceptable as proof of proficiency in the oral communication of the English language under this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">By regulation, the Board shall develop a procedure for testing individuals who because of their speech impairment are unable to complete satisfactorily a Board approved standardized test of oral competency.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">If any disciplinary charges or action that involves a problem with the oral communication of the English language are brought against a licensee under this title, the Board shall require the licensee to take and pass a Board approved standardized test of oral competency.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
