<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gho" order_by="gho" level="1">Health Occupations</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gho-4-503</section_number>
  <catch_line>A licensed dentist may not advertise:...</catch_line>
  <order_by>503</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">A licensed dentist may not advertise:<section prefix="(1)">To guarantee any dental work;</section><section prefix="(2)">Making an undifferentiated claim to do dental work painlessly;</section><section prefix="(3)">To do dental work in a superior manner; or</section><section prefix="(4)">Falsely or in a manner that tends to deceive or mislead the public.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A licensed dentist may not:<section prefix="(i)">Use the designation "Dental Surgeon" on a sign that bears the name of the licensee; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">Include a specialty designation in a card, letterhead, sign, telephone directory listing, or other printed matter that bears the name of the licensee, unless:<section prefix="1.">The licensee is identified by the Board as a specialist in the designated field under &#xA7; 4-504 of this subtitle; and</section><section prefix="2.">The language used to refer to the specialty is approved by the Board.</section></section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A licensed dentist may use the designations "Dr.", "dentist", "D.D.S.", or "D.M.D." on a sign that bears the licensee's name.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A person who is not a licensed dentist may not solicit or advertise to the general public in any manner that the person alters, constructs, duplicates, repairs, or supplies a dental appliance.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A licensed dentist may use a trade name in connection with the practice of dentistry provided that:<section prefix="(1)">The use of the trade name is not deceptive or misleading;</section><section prefix="(2)">The advertisement in which the trade name appears includes the name of the licensed dentist or the name of the business entity providing the dental services being advertised as long as the advertisement includes the name of a licensed dentist;</section><section prefix="(3)">The name of the licensed dentist providing dental services shall appear on the billing invoices, and on the receipts if any are given to patients; and</section><section prefix="(4)">Treatment records are maintained that clearly identify the licensed dentist who has performed the dental service for any patient.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
