<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gho" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="12-6C-06" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gho-12-6C-06</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">A wholesale distributor permit expires on May 31 after its effective date, unless the wholesale distributor permit is renewed for an additional 2-year term as provided in this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in paragraph (2) of this  subsection, at least 1 month before a wholesale distributor permit  expires, the Board shall send to the wholesale distributor permit   holder a renewal notice by first-class mail to the last known  address of the permit holder.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If requested by a wholesale distributor permit  holder, the Board shall send to the permit holder, at least two  times within the month before a wholesale distributor permit  expires, a renewal notice by electronic means to the last known  electronic address of the permit holder.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">If a renewal notice sent by electronic means under  paragraph (2) of this subsection is returned to the Board as  undeliverable, the Board shall send to the wholesale distributor  permit holder a renewal notice by first-class mail to the last  known address of the permit holder.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">A renewal notice sent under this subsection shall  state:<section prefix="(i)">The date on which the current wholesale  distributor permit expires;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The date by which the renewal application must  be received by the Board for the renewal to be issued and mailed  before the current wholesale distributor permit expires; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">The amount of the renewal fee.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(5)">Before a wholesale distributor permit expires, a  wholesale distributor permit holder periodically may renew it for  an additional 2-year term, if the wholesale distributor permit  holder:<section prefix="(i)">Otherwise is entitled to a wholesale  distributor permit;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Pays to the Board a renewal fee set by the  Board; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Submits to the Board a renewal application on  the form that the Board requires.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(6)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The renewal application form shall set forth  the information that the wholesale distributor provided under &#xA7;  12-6C-05 of this subtitle.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">Within 30 days after receiving the form, the  wholesale distributor shall identify and state under oath to the  Board all changes or corrections to the information that was  provided under &#xA7; 12-6C-05 of this subtitle.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(7)">The Board shall renew the wholesale distributor  permit of a wholesale distributor permit holder who meets the  requirements of this subtitle and any regulations adopted under  this subtitle.</section>
      <section prefix="(8)">The Board may deny, suspend, or revoke the permit  of a wholesale distributor if the Board determines that the  wholesale distributor no longer qualifies for a permit.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
