<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gho" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="8-303" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gho-8-303</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, "Central Repository" means the Criminal Justice Information System Central Repository of the Department of Public Safety and Correctional Services.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">As part of an application to the Central Repository for a State and national criminal history records check, an applicant shall submit to the Central Repository:<section prefix="(1)">Two complete sets of legible fingerprints taken on forms approved by the Director of the Central Repository and the Director of the Federal Bureau of Investigation;</section><section prefix="(2)">The fee authorized under &#xA7; 10-221(b)(7) of the Criminal Procedure Article for access to State criminal history records; and</section><section prefix="(3)">The processing fee required by the Federal Bureau of Investigation for a national criminal history records check.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">In accordance with &#xA7;&#xA7; 10-201 through 10-228 of the Criminal Procedure Article, the Central Repository shall forward to the Board and to the applicant the criminal history record information of the applicant.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">If an applicant has made two or more unsuccessful attempts at securing legible fingerprints, the Board may accept an alternate method of criminal history records check as permitted by the Director of the Central Repository and the Director of the Federal Bureau of Investigation.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">Information obtained from the Central Repository under this section shall be:<section prefix="(1)">Confidential and may not be redisseminated; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Used only for the licensing purpose authorized by this title.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The subject of a criminal history records check under this section may contest the contents of the printed statement issued by the Central Repository as provided in &#xA7; 10-223 of the Criminal Procedure Article.</section>
  </text>
</law>
