<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gho" order_by="gho" level="1">Health Occupations</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gho-15-205</section_number>
  <catch_line>In addition to the powers set forth elsewhere in this title, the Committee, on its initiative or on ...</catch_line>
  <order_by>205</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In addition to the powers set forth elsewhere in this title, the Committee, on its initiative or on the Board's request, may:<section prefix="(1)">Recommend to the Board regulations for carrying out the provisions of this title;</section><section prefix="(2)">Recommend to the Board approval, modification, or disapproval of an application for licensure or a delegation agreement;</section><section prefix="(3)">Report to the Board any conduct of a supervising physician or a physician assistant that may be cause for disciplinary action under this title or under &#xA7; 14-404 of this article; and</section><section prefix="(4)">Report to the Board any alleged unauthorized practice of a physician assistant.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In addition to the duties set forth elsewhere in this title, the Board shall adopt regulations to carry out the provisions of this title.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Board shall:<section prefix="(i)">Consider all recommendations of the Committee; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Provide a written explanation of the Board's reasons for rejecting or modifying the Committee's recommendations.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Board may:<section prefix="(i)">Investigate any alleged unauthorized practice of a physician assistant;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Investigate any conduct that may be cause for disciplinary action under this title; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">On receipt of a written and signed complaint, including a referral from the Commissioner of Labor and Industry, conduct an unannounced inspection of the office of a physician assistant, other than an office of a physician assistant in a hospital, related institution, freestanding medical facility, or freestanding birthing center, to determine compliance at that office with the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention's guidelines on universal precautions.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">If the entry is necessary to carry out a duty under this subtitle, including an investigation or determination of compliance as provided under paragraph (3) of this subsection and an audit to determine compliance with the Board's requirements with respect to physician assistant practice, the Executive Director of the Board or other duly authorized agent or investigator may enter at any reasonable hour a place of business of a licensed physician or a licensed physician assistant or public premises.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">
        <section prefix="(i)">A person may not deny or interfere with an entry under this subsection.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">A person who violates any provision of this subsection is guilty of a misdemeanor and on conviction is subject to a fine not exceeding $100.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
