<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gho" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="15-302.2" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gho-15-302.2</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">A primary supervising physician may not delegate prescribing, dispensing, and administering of controlled dangerous substances, prescription drugs, or medical devices unless the primary supervising physician and physician assistant include in the delegation agreement:<section prefix="(1)">A notice of intent to delegate prescribing of controlled dangerous substances, prescription drugs, or medical devices;</section><section prefix="(2)">An attestation that all prescribing activities of the physician assistant will comply with applicable federal and State regulations;</section><section prefix="(3)">An attestation that all medical charts or records will contain a notation of any prescriptions written by a physician assistant in accordance with this section;</section><section prefix="(4)">An attestation that all prescriptions written under this section will include the physician assistant's name and the supervising physician's name, business address, and business telephone number legibly written or printed;</section><section prefix="(5)">An attestation that the physician assistant has:<section prefix="(i)">Passed the physician assistant national certification exam administered by the National Commission on the Certification of Physician Assistants within the previous 2 years; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">Successfully completed 8 category 1 hours of pharmacology education within the previous 2 years; and</section></section><section prefix="(6)">An attestation that the physician assistant has:<section prefix="(i)">A bachelor's degree or its equivalent; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">Successfully completed 2 years of work experience as a physician assistant.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A primary supervising physician may not delegate the prescribing of substances that are identified as Schedule I controlled dangerous substances under &#xA7; 5-402 of the Criminal Law Article.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A primary supervising physician may delegate the prescribing of substances that are identified as Schedules II through V controlled dangerous substances under &#xA7; 5-402 of the Criminal Law Article, including legend drugs as defined under &#xA7; 503(b) of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A primary supervising physician may not delegate the prescribing of controlled dangerous substances to a physician assistant unless the physician assistant has a valid:<section prefix="(i)">State controlled dangerous substance registration; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Federal Drug Enforcement Agency (DEA) registration.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A physician assistant personally may dispense a starter dosage or dispense drug samples of any drug the physician assistant is authorized to prescribe to a patient of the physician assistant if:<section prefix="(1)">The starter dosage or drug sample complies with the labeling requirements of &#xA7; 12-505 of this article;</section><section prefix="(2)">No charge is made for the starter dosage; and</section><section prefix="(3)">The physician assistant enters an appropriate record in the patient's medical record.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A physician assistant who personally dispenses a drug sample or starter dosage in the course of treating a patient as authorized under subsection (c) of this section shall comply with the requirements under Titles 12 and 14 of this article and applicable federal law and regulations.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">Before a physician assistant may renew a license for an additional 2-year term under &#xA7; 15-307 of this subtitle, the physician assistant shall submit evidence to the Board of successful completion of 8 category 1 hours of pharmacology education within the previous 2 years.</section>
  </text>
</law>
