<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gho" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="8-703" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gho-8-703</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Unless authorized to practice registered nursing under this title, a person may not represent to the public by title, by description of services, methods, or procedures, or otherwise, that the person is authorized to practice registered nursing in this State.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Unless authorized to practice licensed practical nursing under this title, a person may not represent to the public by title, by description of services, methods, or procedures, or otherwise, that the person is authorized to practice licensed practical nursing in this State.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Unless authorized to provide patient care as a certified nursing assistant or medication assistant under this title, a person may not represent to the public by title, by description of services, methods, or procedures, or otherwise, that the person is authorized to provide care as a certified nursing assistant or medication assistant in this State.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">Unless authorized to provide patient care in a specific category of certified nursing assistant, a person may not represent to the public by title, by description of services, methods, or procedures, or otherwise, that the person is authorized to provide care as a certified nursing assistant in a specific category in this State.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">Unless authorized to administer medication as a medication technician under this title, a person may not represent to the public by title, by description of services, methods, or procedures, or otherwise, that the person is authorized to administer medication as a certified medication technician in this State.</section>
      <section prefix="(6)">Unless authorized to administer medication as a medicine aide under this title, a person may not represent to the public by title, by description of services, methods, or procedures, or otherwise, that the person is authorized to administer medication as a certified medicine aide in this State.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Unless authorized to practice registered nursing or licensed practical nursing under this title, a person may not use the word "nurse" to describe the profession of the person.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Unless authorized to practice registered nursing under this title, a person may not use the words or terms "registered nurse", the abbreviation "R.N.", or any other title, symbol, abbreviation, sign, card, device, or other representation with the intent to represent that the person practices registered nursing.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Unless authorized to practice licensed practical nursing under this title, a person may not use the words or terms "licensed practical nurse", the abbreviation "L.P.N.", or any other title, symbol, abbreviation, sign, card, device, or other representation with the intent to represent that the person practices licensed practical nursing.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">Unless authorized to practice as a nursing graduate under this title, a person may not use the words "nursing graduate", the abbreviation "NG", or any other title, symbol, abbreviation, sign, card, device, or other representation with the intent to represent that the person practices as a nursing graduate.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">Unless authorized to practice as a certified nursing assistant under this title, a person may not use the words or terms "nursing assistant" or "certified nursing assistant", the abbreviation "CNA", or any other title, symbol, abbreviation, sign, card, device, or other representation with the intent to represent that the person practices as a certified nursing assistant.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">Unless authorized to practice as a certified medication technician under this title, a person may not use the words or terms "medication technician" or "certified medication technician", the abbreviation "MT", or any other title, symbol, abbreviation, sign, card, device, or other representation with the intent to represent that the person practices as a certified medication technician.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">Unless authorized to practice as a certified medicine aide under this title, a person may not use the words or terms "medicine aide" or "certified medicine aide" or any other title, symbol, abbreviation, sign, card, device, or other representation with the intent to represent that the person practices as a certified medicine aide.</section>
  </text>
</law>
