<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gho" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="12-101" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gho-12-101</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this title the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Authorized prescriber" means any licensed dentist, licensed physician, licensed podiatrist, licensed veterinarian, certified nurse midwife to the extent permitted in &#xA7; 8-601 of this article, certified nurse practitioner to the extent permitted in &#xA7; 8-508 of this article, or other individual authorized by law to prescribe prescription or nonprescription drugs or devices.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Board" means the State Board of Pharmacy.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Compounding" means the preparation, mixing, assembling, packaging, or labeling of a drug or device:<section prefix="(i)">As the result of a practitioner's prescription drug order or initiative based on the practitioner/patient/pharmacist relationship in the course of professional practice; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">For the purpose of, or incident to, research, teaching, or chemical analysis and not for the sale or dispensing of the drug or device.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Compounding" includes the preparation of drugs or devices in anticipation of a prescription drug order based on routine, regularly observed prescribing patterns.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Delegated pharmacy act" means an activity that constitutes the practice of pharmacy delegated by a licensed pharmacist under this title and regulations adopted by the Board.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Delegated pharmacy act" does not include:<section prefix="(i)">An act within the parameters of a therapy management contract as provided under Subtitle 6A of this title;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The administration of an influenza vaccination in accordance with &#xA7; 12-508 of this title;</section><section prefix="(iii)">The delegation of a pharmacy act by a registered pharmacy technician, pharmacy student, or pharmacy technician trainee;</section><section prefix="(iv)">A pharmacy activity performed by a pharmacy student in accordance with &#xA7; 12-301(b) of this title;</section><section prefix="(v)">A pharmacy activity performed by an applicant for a license to practice pharmacy in accordance with regulations adopted by the Board; or</section><section prefix="(vi)">The performance of other functions prohibited in regulations adopted by the Board.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Device" means a device used in the diagnosis, treatment, or prevention of disease.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Device" does not include any:<section prefix="(i)">Surgical or dental instrument;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Physical therapy equipment;</section><section prefix="(iii)">X-ray apparatus; or</section><section prefix="(iv)">Component part or accessory of any of these items.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">"Direct supervision" means that a licensed pharmacist is physically available on-site to supervise the performance of delegated pharmacy acts.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">"Dispense" or "dispensing" means the procedure which results in the receipt of a prescription or nonprescription drug or device by a patient or the patient's agent and which entails the:<section prefix="(1)">Interpretation of an authorized prescriber's prescription for a drug or device;</section><section prefix="(2)">Selection and labeling of the drug or device prescribed pursuant to that prescription; and</section><section prefix="(3)">Measuring and packaging of the prescribed drug or device in accordance with State and federal laws.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(i)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Distribute" means the process resulting in the provision of a prescription or nonprescription drug or device to a separate, intervening individual, licensed and practicing under this article, prior to administration of the provided drug or device to the patient pursuant to a prescription issued by an authorized prescriber.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Distribute" does not include the operations of a person who holds a permit issued under &#xA7; 12-6C-03 of this title.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(j)">"License" means, unless the context requires otherwise, a license issued to a pharmacist by the Board to practice pharmacy.</section>
    <section prefix="(k)">"Licensed pharmacist" means, unless the context requires otherwise, a pharmacist who is licensed by the Board to practice pharmacy.</section>
    <section prefix="(l)">"Nonprescription drug" means a drug which may be sold without a prescription and which is labeled for use by the consumer in accordance with the requirements of the laws and regulations of this State and the federal government.</section>
    <section prefix="(m)">"Nonresident pharmacy" means a pharmacy located outside this State that, in the normal course of business, as determined by the Board, ships, mails, or delivers drugs or devices to a person in this State pursuant to a prescription.</section>
    <section prefix="(n)">"Pharmaceutical care" means the provision of a patient's drug regimen for the purpose of achieving definite outcomes related to the cure or prevention of a disease, elimination or reduction of a patient's symptoms, or arresting or slowing of a disease process by identifying, resolving, or preventing actual or potential drug therapy problems and which may include patient counseling and providing information to licensed and certified health care providers.</section>
    <section prefix="(o)">"Pharmacist" means an individual who practices pharmacy regardless of the location where the activities of practice are performed.</section>
    <section prefix="(p)">"Pharmacy" means an establishment in which prescription or nonprescription drugs or devices are compounded, dispensed, or distributed.</section>
    <section prefix="(q)">"Pharmacy permit" means a permit issued by the Board to establish and operate a pharmacy.</section>
    <section prefix="(r)">"Pharmacy student" means an individual who is enrolled as a student in a school or college of pharmacy approved by the Board or accredited by the Accreditation Council for Pharmacy Education.</section>
    <section prefix="(s)">"Pharmacy technician trainee" means an individual engaged in a Board approved pharmacy technician training program.</section>
    <section prefix="(t)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Practice pharmacy" means to engage in any of the following activities:<section prefix="(i)">Providing pharmaceutical care;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Compounding, dispensing, or distributing prescription drugs or devices;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Compounding or dispensing nonprescription drugs or devices;</section><section prefix="(iv)">Monitoring prescriptions for prescription and nonprescription drugs or devices;</section><section prefix="(v)">Providing information, explanation, or recommendations to patients and health care practitioners about the safe and effective use of prescription or nonprescription drugs or devices;</section><section prefix="(vi)">Identifying and appraising problems concerning the use or monitoring of therapy with drugs or devices;</section><section prefix="(vii)">Acting within the parameters of a therapy management contract, as provided under Subtitle 6A of this title;</section><section prefix="(viii)">Administering an influenza vaccination, a vaccination for pneumococcal pneumonia or herpes zoster, or any vaccination that has been determined by the Board, with the agreement of the Board of Physicians and the Board of Nursing, to be in the best health interests of the community in accordance with &#xA7; 12-508 of this title;</section><section prefix="(ix)">Delegating a pharmacy act to a registered pharmacy technician, pharmacy student, or an individual engaged in a Board approved pharmacy technician training program;</section><section prefix="(x)">Supervising a delegated pharmacy act performed by a registered pharmacy technician, pharmacy student, or an individual engaged in a Board approved pharmacy technician training program; or</section><section prefix="(xi)">Providing drug therapy management in accordance with &#xA7; 19-713.6 of the Health - General Article.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Practice pharmacy" does not include the operations of a person who holds a permit issued under &#xA7; 12-6C-03 of this title.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(u)">"Registered pharmacy technician" means an individual who is registered with the Board to perform delegated pharmacy acts.</section>
    <section prefix="(v)">"Registration" means, unless the context requires otherwise, a registration issued by the Board to perform delegated pharmacy acts under the supervision of a licensed pharmacist.</section>
    <section prefix="(w)">"Supervision" means reviewing the work, guiding and directing the activities, and monitoring the performance of an individual.</section>
  </text>
</law>
