<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gho" order_by="gho" level="1">Health Occupations</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gho-8-312</section_number>
  <catch_line>On or before December 31, 2012, a license expires on the 28th day of the birth month of the licensee...</catch_line>
  <order_by>312</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">On or before December 31, 2012, a license expires on the 28th day of the birth month of the licensee, unless the license is renewed for a 1-year term as provided in this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">On or after January 1, 2013, a license expires on the date set by the Board and may not be renewed for a term longer than 2 years.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">At least 3 months before a license expires, the Board shall send to the licensee a renewal notice by:<section prefix="(i)">First-class mail to the last known mailing address of the licensee; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">Electronic means to the last known electronic address of the licensee.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If a licensee is required to have a criminal history records check before a license may be renewed, the Board shall send the licensee the documents necessary for initiating the criminal history records check in conjunction with the renewal notice required under paragraph (1) of this subsection.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Before a license expires, the licensee periodically may renew it for an additional term, if the licensee:<section prefix="(1)">Otherwise is entitled to be licensed;</section><section prefix="(2)">Pays to the Board:<section prefix="(i)">A renewal fee set by the Board; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">A renewal fee that is set by the Board if the licensee certifies to the Board that the licensee provides professional services only as a volunteer; and</section></section><section prefix="(3)">Submits to the Board by paper application or electronic means:<section prefix="(i)">A renewal application on the form that the Board requires; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Satisfactory evidence of completion of:<section prefix="1.">1,000 hours of active nursing practice within the 5-year period immediately preceding the date of renewal;</section><section prefix="2.">A course of instruction, commonly known as a refresher course, approved by the Board; or</section><section prefix="3.">A preceptorship program provided by an employer and approved by the Board.</section></section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Board may grant a 30-day extension, beyond a license's expiration date, to a licensee so that the licensee may renew the license before it expires.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Board may grant two 90-day extensions beyond a license's expiration date pending receipt of criminal history record information.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Each licensee shall notify the Board in writing of any change in the name or address of the licensee within 60 days after the change occurred.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If a licensee fails to notify the Board within the time required under this subsection, subject to the hearing provisions of &#xA7; 8-317 of this subtitle, the Board may impose an administrative penalty of $100.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Subject to subsection (g) of this section, the Board shall renew the license of each licensee who meets the requirements of this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A volunteer's license issued under subsection (c)(2)(ii) of this section shall be clearly designated as a volunteer's license.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Beginning July 2009, the Board shall begin a process requiring criminal history records checks in accordance with &#xA7; 8-303 of this subtitle on:<section prefix="1.">Selected annual renewal applicants as determined by regulations adopted by the Board; and</section><section prefix="2.">Each former licensee who files for reinstatement under &#xA7; 8-313 of this subtitle after failing to renew the license for a period of 1 year or more.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">An additional criminal history records check shall be performed every 12 years thereafter.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">On receipt of the criminal history record information of a licensee forwarded to the Board in accordance with &#xA7; 8-303 of this subtitle, in determining whether to renew a license, the Board shall consider:<section prefix="(i)">The age at which the crime was committed;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The circumstances surrounding the crime;</section><section prefix="(iii)">The length of time that has passed since the crime;</section><section prefix="(iv)">Subsequent work history;</section><section prefix="(v)">Employment and character references; and</section><section prefix="(vi)">Other evidence that demonstrates whether the licensee poses a threat to the public health or safety.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Board may not renew a license if the criminal history record information required under &#xA7; 8-303 of this subtitle has not been received.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
