<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gho" order_by="" level="1">Health Occupations</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gho-4-101</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>101</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this title the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Board" means the State Board of Dental Examiners.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Dental appliance" means any:<section prefix="(1)">Oral prosthesis;</section><section prefix="(2)">Orthodontic appliance;</section><section prefix="(3)">Regulatory appliance;</section><section prefix="(4)">Supportive appliance; or</section><section prefix="(5)">Other intraoral appliance or restoration.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">"Dental hygienist" means an individual, other than a dentist, who practices dental hygiene.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"Dental laboratory" means any commercial laboratory or workroom in which a person engages in dental laboratory work.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">"Dental laboratory work" means making, repairing, or altering a dental appliance extraorally.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">"Dentist" means an individual who practices dentistry.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"License" means, unless the context requires otherwise, a license issued by the Board to:<section prefix="(i)">Practice dentistry; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">Practice dental hygiene.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"License" includes, unless the context requires otherwise:<section prefix="(i)">A general license to practice dentistry;</section><section prefix="(ii)">A limited license to practice dentistry;</section><section prefix="(iii)">A teacher's license to practice dentistry;</section><section prefix="(iv)">A general license to practice dental hygiene;</section><section prefix="(v)">A teacher's license to practice dental hygiene;</section><section prefix="(vi)">A retired volunteer dentist's license to practice dentistry;</section><section prefix="(vii)">A retired volunteer dental hygienist's license to practice dental hygiene;</section><section prefix="(viii)">A volunteer dentist's license to practice dentistry;</section><section prefix="(ix)">A volunteer dental hygienist's license to practice dental hygiene;</section><section prefix="(x)">A temporary volunteer dentist's license to practice dentistry; and</section><section prefix="(xi)">A temporary dental hygienist's license to practice dental hygiene.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(i)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Licensed dental hygienist" means, unless the context requires otherwise, a dental hygienist who is licensed by the Board to practice dental hygiene.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Licensed dental hygienist" includes, unless the context requires otherwise, a holder of:<section prefix="(i)">A general license to practice dental hygiene;</section><section prefix="(ii)">A teacher's license to practice dental hygiene;</section><section prefix="(iii)">A retired volunteer dental hygienist's license to practice dental hygiene;</section><section prefix="(iv)">A volunteer dental hygienist's license to practice dental hygiene; or</section><section prefix="(v)">A temporary volunteer dental hygienist's license to practice dental hygiene.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(j)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Licensed dentist" means, unless the context requires otherwise, a dentist who is licensed by the Board to practice dentistry.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Licensed dentist" includes, unless the context requires otherwise, a holder of:<section prefix="(i)">A general license to practice dentistry;</section><section prefix="(ii)">A limited license to practice dentistry;</section><section prefix="(iii)">A teacher's license to practice dentistry;</section><section prefix="(iv)">A retired volunteer dentist's license to practice dentistry;</section><section prefix="(v)">A volunteer dentist's license to practice dentistry; or</section><section prefix="(vi)">A temporary volunteer dentist's license to practice dentistry.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(k)">"Practice dental hygiene" means to:<section prefix="(1)">Perform a preliminary dental examination;</section><section prefix="(2)">Perform a complete prophylaxis, including the removal of any deposit, accretion, or stain from the surface of a tooth or a restoration;</section><section prefix="(3)">Polish a tooth or a restoration;</section><section prefix="(4)">Chart cavities, restorations, missing teeth, periodontal conditions, and other features observed during preliminary examination, prophylaxis, or polishing;</section><section prefix="(5)">Apply a medicinal agent to a tooth for a prophylactic purpose;</section><section prefix="(6)">Take a dental X ray;</section><section prefix="(7)">Perform a manual curettage in conjunction with scaling and root planing;</section><section prefix="(8)">Administer local anesthesia in accordance with &#xA7; 4-206.1 or &#xA7; 4-206.3 of this title; or</section><section prefix="(9)">Perform any other intraoral function that the Board authorizes by a rule or regulation adopted under &#xA7; 4-206 of this title.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(l)">"Practice dentistry" means to:<section prefix="(1)">Be a manager, a proprietor, or a conductor of or an operator in any place in which a dental service or dental operation is performed intraorally;</section><section prefix="(2)">Perform or attempt to perform any intraoral dental service or intraoral dental operation;</section><section prefix="(3)">Diagnose, treat, or attempt to diagnose or treat any disease, injury, malocclusion, or malposition of a tooth, gum, or jaw, or structures associated with a tooth, gum, or jaw if the service, operation, or procedure is included in the curricula of an accredited dental school or in an approved dental residency program of an accredited hospital or teaching institution;</section><section prefix="(4)">Perform or offer to perform dental laboratory work;</section><section prefix="(5)">Place or adjust a dental appliance in a human mouth; or</section><section prefix="(6)">Administer anesthesia for the purposes of dentistry and not as a medical specialty.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(m)">Except as provided in &#xA7; 4-308(f)(2) of this title, "supervision" means supervision of a dental hygienist by a dentist, where the dentist may or may not be present when the dental hygienist performs the dental hygiene procedures but is available on the premises.</section>
    <section prefix="(n)">"Temporary dental clinic permit" means, unless the context requires otherwise, a temporary permit issued by the Board to a bona fide charitable organization to provide dental services to the poor, elderly, or disabled at a dental clinic.</section>
    <section prefix="(o)">"Third party" means any person who collects premiums, assumes financial risks, pays claims, or provides administrative services relating to any:<section prefix="(1)">Insurance policy;</section><section prefix="(2)">Insurance contract;</section><section prefix="(3)">Health prepayment contract;</section><section prefix="(4)">Health care plan; or</section><section prefix="(5)">Nonprofit health service plan contract.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
