<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gho" order_by="gho" level="1">Health Occupations</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gho-1-212</section_number>
  <catch_line>Each health occupation board authorized to issue a license or certificate under this article shall a...</catch_line>
  <order_by>212</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Each health occupation board authorized to issue a license or certificate under this article shall adopt regulations that:<section prefix="(1)">Prohibit sexual misconduct; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Provide for the discipline of a licensee or certificate holder found to be guilty of sexual misconduct.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">For the purposes of the regulations adopted in accordance with subsection (a) of this section, "sexual misconduct" shall be construed to include, at a minimum, behavior where a health care provider:<section prefix="(1)">Has engaged in sexual behavior with a client or patient in the context of a professional evaluation, treatment, procedure, or other service to the client or patient, regardless of the setting in which professional service is provided;</section><section prefix="(2)">Has engaged in sexual behavior with a client or patient under the pretense of diagnostic or therapeutic intent or benefit; or</section><section prefix="(3)">Has engaged in any sexual behavior that would be considered unethical or unprofessional according to the code of ethics, professional standards of conduct, or regulations of the appropriate health occupation board under this article.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Subject to the provisions of the law governing contested cases, if an applicant, licensee, or certificate holder violates a regulation adopted under subsection (a) of this section a board may:<section prefix="(1)">Deny a license or certificate to the applicant;</section><section prefix="(2)">Reprimand the licensee or certificate holder;</section><section prefix="(3)">Place the licensee or certificate holder on probation; or</section><section prefix="(4)">Suspend or revoke the license or certificate.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">This section does not negate any other disciplinary action under a health occupation board's statutory or regulatory provisions.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Each year, each health occupation board shall submit a statistical report to the Secretary, indicating the number of complaints of sexual misconduct received and the resolution of each complaint. The report shall cover the period beginning October 1 and ending the following September 30 and shall be submitted by the board not later than the November 15 following the reporting period.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Secretary shall compile the information received from the health occupation boards and submit an annual report to the General Assembly, in accordance with &#xA7; 2-1246 of the State Government Article, not later than December 31 of each year.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
