<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gho" order_by="" level="1">Health Occupations</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gho-3-101</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>101</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this title the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Board" means the State Board of Chiropractic and Massage Therapy Examiners.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Chiropractor" means an individual who practices chiropractic.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">"License" means, unless the context requires otherwise, a license issued by the Board:<section prefix="(1)">To practice chiropractic; or</section><section prefix="(2)">To practice chiropractic with the right to practice physical therapy.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"Licensed chiropractor" means, unless the context requires otherwise, a chiropractor who is licensed by the Board to practice chiropractic or to practice chiropractic with the right to practice physical therapy.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Practice chiropractic" means to use a drugless system of health care based on the principle that interference with the transmission of nerve impulses may cause disease.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Practice chiropractic" includes the diagnosing and locating of misaligned or displaced vertebrae and, through the manual manipulation and adjustment of the spine and other skeletal structures, treating disorders of the human body.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Except as otherwise provided in this title, "practice chiropractic" does not include the use of drugs or surgery, or the practice of osteopathy, obstetrics, or any other branch of medicine.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The definition of "practice chiropractic" does not prohibit a chiropractor from selecting diet and hygiene measures for an individual.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">"Practice physical therapy" has the meaning stated in &#xA7; 13-101 of this article.</section>
  </text>
</law>
