<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gho" order_by="gho" level="1">Health Occupations</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gho-11-404.3</section_number>
  <catch_line>The Maryland Optometric Association and the Maryland Society of Eye Physicians and Surgeons shall re...</catch_line>
  <order_by>404.3</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Maryland Optometric Association and the Maryland Society of Eye Physicians and Surgeons shall recommend to the Secretary quality assurance guidelines for therapeutically certified optometrists and optometric care.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">After considering the recommendations of the Maryland Optometric Association and the Maryland Society of Eye Physicians and Surgeons, the Secretary shall adopt regulations that establish:<section prefix="(i)">Standards of quality for therapeutically certified optometrists and optometric care;</section><section prefix="(ii)">An ongoing quality assurance program that includes the monitoring and study of the joint management of primary open-angle glaucoma patients under &#xA7; 11-404.2(c) of this subtitle;</section><section prefix="(iii)">A program to evaluate the cost of optometric care; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">A plan to monitor complaint investigation.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The regulations shall require the Board to:<section prefix="(i)">Conduct a continuing study and investigation of therapeutically certified optometrists to ensure the quality of care they provide; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Report to the Secretary, as the Secretary requires, on the results of the Board's study and investigation.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Board's study and investigation shall include:<section prefix="(i)">A peer review program; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">A review of patient optometric records that includes the collection and evaluation of data on the drugs being prescribed and administered and the appropriateness of treatment by therapeutically certified optometrists.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
