<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gho" order_by="gho" level="1">Health Occupations</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gho-12-6A-01</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated....</catch_line>
  <order_by>01</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Group model health maintenance organization" has the meaning stated in &#xA7; 19-713.6 of the Health - General Article.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Health maintenance organization" has the meaning stated in &#xA7; 19-701(g) of the Health - General Article.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Institutional facility" means a facility other than a nursing home whose primary purpose is to provide a physical environment for patients to obtain inpatient or emergency care.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Institutional facility" does not include an urgent care facility that is not part of a facility.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"Licensed physician" means an individual who is licensed to practice medicine under Title 14 of this article.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">"Physician-pharmacist agreement" means an agreement between a licensed physician and a licensed pharmacist that is disease-state specific and specifies the protocols that may be used.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">"Protocol" means a course of treatment predetermined by the licensed physician and licensed pharmacist according to generally accepted medical practice for the proper completion of a particular therapeutic or diagnostic intervention.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Therapy management contract" means a voluntary, written arrangement that is disease-state specific signed by each party to the arrangement between:<section prefix="(i)">One licensed pharmacist and the licensed pharmacist's designated alternate licensed pharmacists;</section><section prefix="(ii)">One licensed physician and alternate designated licensed physicians involved directly in patient care; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">One patient receiving care from a licensed physician and a licensed pharmacist pursuant to a physician-pharmacist agreement and protocol under this subtitle.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A therapy management contract shall be related to treatment using drug therapy, laboratory tests, or medical devices, under defined conditions or limitations for the purpose of improving patient outcomes.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
