<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gho" order_by="gho" level="1">Health Occupations</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gho-10-206</section_number>
  <catch_line>There is a State Board of Occupational Therapy Practice Fund....</catch_line>
  <order_by>206</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">There is a State Board of Occupational Therapy Practice Fund.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Board may set reasonable fees for the issuance and renewal of licenses and its other services.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The fees charged shall be set so as to approximate the cost of maintaining the Board.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Funds to cover the compensation and expenses of the Board members shall be generated by fees set under this section.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Board shall pay all funds collected under this title to the Comptroller of the State.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Comptroller shall distribute the fees to the State Board of Occupational Therapy Practice Fund.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Fund shall be used to cover the actual documented direct and indirect costs of fulfilling the statutory and regulatory duties of the Board as provided by the provisions of this article.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Fund is a continuing, nonlapsing fund, not subject to &#xA7; 7-302 of the State Finance and Procurement Article.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Any unspent portions of the Fund may not be transferred or revert to the General Fund of the State, but shall remain in the Fund to be used for the purposes specified in this article.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">No other State money may be used to support the Fund.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A designee of the Board shall administer the Fund.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Moneys in the Fund may be expended only for any lawful purpose authorized under the provisions of this article.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The Legislative Auditor shall audit the accounts and transactions of the Fund as provided in &#xA7; 2-1220 of the State Government Article.</section>
  </text>
</law>
