<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gho" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="1A-316" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gho-1A-316</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">An acupuncturist licensed by the Board may provide supervision to as many individuals performing auricular detoxification as permitted by Board regulations, if each individual:<section prefix="(1)">Is:<section prefix="(i)">An alcohol, substance abuse, or chemical dependency counselor who is:</section><section prefix="(ii)">A nurse licensed to practice under Title 8, Subtitle 3 of this article;</section><section prefix="(iii)">A psychologist licensed to practice under Title 18, Subtitle 3 of this article who works directly with the alcohol- or drug-addicted clients of a chemical dependency program in the counseling or treatment of those clients; or</section><section prefix="(iv)">A licensed certified social worker-clinical licensed to practice under Title 19, Subtitle 3 of this article who works directly with the alcohol- or drug-addicted clients of a chemical dependency program in the counseling or treatment of those clients;</section></section><section prefix="(2)">Provides documentation to the Board of the successful completion of a training program in acupuncture for the treatment of alcoholism, substance abuse, or chemical dependency that:<section prefix="(i)">Is approved by the Board; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Meets or exceeds the standards of the National Acupuncture Detoxification Association;</section></section><section prefix="(3)">Does not represent to the public, by description of services, methods, or procedures, or otherwise, that the individual is authorized to practice acupuncture in this State;</section><section prefix="(4)">Agrees to be subject to the Board for any violation of &#xA7; 1A-309 of this subtitle; and</section><section prefix="(5)">Performs auricular detoxification only:<section prefix="(i)">Within the context of a clinical substance abuse program;</section><section prefix="(ii)">In hospitals, prisons, outpatient clinics, or other settings approved by the Board; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Under the supervision of an acupuncturist licensed by the State.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Board shall adopt regulations to carry out the provisions of this section, including regulations that cover:<section prefix="(1)">The qualifications, training, and monitoring of individuals who perform auricular detoxification under the supervision of an acupuncturist licensed by the Board;</section><section prefix="(2)">The number of individuals performing auricular detoxification to which an acupuncturist licensed by the Board may provide supervision; and</section><section prefix="(3)">The requirements for the approval of a clinical substance abuse program or a setting where an individual may perform auricular detoxification under the supervision of an acupuncturist licensed by the Board.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as otherwise provided in this section, an individual may not practice, attempt to practice, or offer to practice auricular detoxification in this State.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">An acupuncturist who is licensed by the Board is responsible for assuring the Board that the individual performing auricular detoxification under the supervision of the acupuncturist complies with all applicable laws, regulations, and standards of practice.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">If the individual performing auricular detoxification under this section violates any applicable laws, regulations, or standards of practice, the Board may discipline:<section prefix="(i)">The individual performing auricular detoxification; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">The supervising acupuncturist licensed by the Board for unprofessional conduct under &#xA7; 1A-309 of this subtitle.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
