<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gho" order_by="gho" level="1">Health Occupations</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gho-9-312.1</section_number>
  <catch_line>If an individual has been licensed by the Board to practice as a nursing home administrator in the S...</catch_line>
  <order_by>312.1</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">If an individual has been licensed by the Board to practice as a nursing home administrator in the State in accordance with the requirements of this subtitle, the individual may be licensed subsequently as a nursing home administrator on inactive status, retaining the licensee's original license number.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Board shall place a licensee on inactive status if the licensee submits to the Board:<section prefix="(i)">An application for inactive status on the form required by the Board; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">The inactive status fee set by the Board.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A licensee's inactive status expires on the second anniversary of its effective date, unless the licensee renews the inactive status for a 2-year term as provided in this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Board shall provide a licensee who has complied with the requirements of paragraph (1) of this subsection with written notification of:<section prefix="(i)">The date that the licensee's inactive status becomes effective;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The date that the licensee's 2-year term of inactive status expires; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">The consequences of:<section prefix="1.">Not renewing inactive status before expiration of the 2-year term of inactive status; and</section><section prefix="2.">Not resuming active status within the 5-year period of inactive status, beginning on the first day of inactive status.</section></section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A licensee on inactive status may not practice as a nursing home administrator in the State.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Board shall issue a license to a licensee who is on inactive status if the licensee:<section prefix="(1)">Completes an application form for reactivation of a license before expiration of the 2-year term of inactive status on the form required by the Board;</section><section prefix="(2)">Complies with the renewal requirements in effect at the time the licensee seeks to reactivate the license;</section><section prefix="(3)">Meets the continuing education requirements set by the Board;</section><section prefix="(4)">Has not practiced as a nursing home administrator in the State while on inactive status;</section><section prefix="(5)">Pays all appropriate fees set by the Board;</section><section prefix="(6)">Has been on inactive status for less than 5 years; and</section><section prefix="(7)">Is otherwise entitled to be licensed.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">Before the Board may reactivate the license of an individual who has been on inactive status for 5 years or more, the individual shall:<section prefix="(1)">Submit a new application;</section><section prefix="(2)">Pay all appropriate fees set by the Board;</section><section prefix="(3)">Complete a Board approved 1-month administrator refresher program; and</section><section prefix="(4)">Pass the State's standards examination.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">A nursing home administrator whose inactive license expires before the nursing home administrator returns to active licensure shall meet the reinstatement requirements of &#xA7; 9-312 of this subtitle.</section>
  </text>
</law>
