<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gho" order_by="gho" level="1">Health Occupations</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gho-21-202</section_number>
  <catch_line>The Board consists of 9 members appointed by the Governor with the advice of the Secretary, and with...</catch_line>
  <order_by>202</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Board consists of 9 members appointed by the Governor with the advice of the Secretary, and with the advice and consent of the Senate.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Of the 9 Board members:<section prefix="(i)">7 shall be licensed environmental health specialists appointed as follows:<section prefix="1.">1 shall be employed by private industry;</section><section prefix="2.">1 shall be employed by the Department of the Environment;</section><section prefix="3.">1 shall be employed by the Department;</section><section prefix="4.">1 shall be employed by a local health department and be employed under the State Personnel Management System;</section><section prefix="5.">1 shall be employed by a local government and not be employed under the State Personnel Management System; and</section><section prefix="6.">2 shall be appointed at large; and</section></section><section prefix="(ii)">2 shall be consumer members.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">All Board members shall be residents of the State.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The members appointed at large shall reasonably reflect the geographic diversity of the State.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The consumer members of the Board:<section prefix="(i)">Shall be members of the general public;</section><section prefix="(ii)">May not be licensed environmental health specialists;</section><section prefix="(iii)">May not have a household member who is a licensed environmental health specialist;</section><section prefix="(iv)">May not participate or ever have participated in a related commercial or professional field;</section><section prefix="(v)">May not have a household member who participates in a related commercial or professional field; and</section><section prefix="(vi)">May not have had within 2 years before appointment a substantial financial interest in a person regulated by the Board.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">While a member of the Board, a consumer member may not have a substantial financial interest in a person regulated by the Board.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Before taking office, each appointee to the Board shall take the oath required by Article I, &#xA7; 9 of the Maryland Constitution.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The term of a member is 4 years.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The terms of members are staggered as required by the terms provided for members of the Board on July 1, 2012.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">At the end of a term, a member continues to serve until a successor is appointed and qualifies.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">A member who is appointed after a term has begun serves only for the rest of the term and until a successor is appointed and qualifies.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">A member may not serve more than 2 consecutive terms.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">For each vacancy of a licensed environmental health specialist member, the Board shall:<section prefix="(1)">Solicit nominations by notifying all licensed environmental health specialists of the vacancy; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Submit to the Secretary a list of at least three candidates for each vacancy.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(g)">On the recommendation of the Secretary, the Governor may remove a member for incompetence, misconduct, neglect of duty, or other sufficient cause.</section>
  </text>
</law>
