<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gho" order_by="" level="1">Health Occupations</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gho-8-6B-08</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>08</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">To qualify for a license, an applicant shall be an individual who submits to a criminal history records check in accordance with &#xA7; 8-303 of this title and meets the requirements of this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The applicant shall be of good moral character.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The applicant shall be at least 18 years old.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Except as otherwise provided in this subtitle, an applicant shall be a high school graduate or have completed equivalent education and have completed satisfactorily:<section prefix="(1)">An electrology education program, taught by a licensed electrology instructor, that includes at least 600 hours of instruction, and has been approved by the Board; or</section><section prefix="(2)">An electrology education program in any other state that the Board determines is substantially equivalent to that required by item (1) of this subsection.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as otherwise provided in this subtitle, each applicant shall pass:<section prefix="(i)">An examination approved by the Board; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">A clinical examination approved by the Board.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Applicants are responsible for scheduling the examinations required under paragraph (1) of this subsection.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">In addition to the other requirements of this section, an applicant for an electrology instructor license shall:<section prefix="(1)">Be a licensed electrologist;</section><section prefix="(2)">Have practiced electrology actively for at least 5 years immediately before the application;</section><section prefix="(3)">Pass an examination approved by the Board; and</section><section prefix="(4)">Meet any other requirements set forth in regulations adopted by the Board under &#xA7; 8-6B-03 of this subtitle.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
