<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gho" order_by="gho" level="1">Health Occupations</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gho-7-308</section_number>
  <catch_line>Subject to the provisions of this section, the Board shall issue a surviving spouse license to an ap...</catch_line>
  <order_by>308</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Subject to the provisions of this section, the Board shall issue a surviving spouse license to an applicant if the applicant:<section prefix="(1)">Is the surviving spouse of a licensed mortician or licensed funeral director whose license was in good standing at the time of death and who at the time of death was operating and wholly or partly owned a mortuary science business;</section><section prefix="(2)">Is not a licensed mortician or licensed funeral director;</section><section prefix="(3)">Submits to the Board, within 30 days of the death of the licensed mortician or funeral director, written verification of the death of the licensee and the application required by the Board; and</section><section prefix="(4)">Pays a fee set by the Board.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Within 6 months of the issuance of the surviving spouse license, the applicant must take the written Maryland State law examination administered by the Board under &#xA7; 7-304(b), (c), (d)(1), (e), and (f) of this subtitle.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The license becomes null and void if the surviving spouse fails the Maryland State law examination twice.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">An applicant may retake the law examination as often as necessary to fulfill the requirement of this subsection.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Nothing in this section shall prevent a surviving spouse from selling the mortuary science business that was operated and wholly or partly owned by the licensed funeral director or licensed mortician.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Except as provided in subsection (c) of this section, while a surviving spouse license is effective, it authorizes the licensee to:<section prefix="(1)">Continue the operation of the mortuary science business that had been operated and wholly or partly owned by the spouse of the licensee; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Assist with the planning and conducting of funeral services for that mortuary science business.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The Board may issue a license under this section only if:<section prefix="(1)">The business is operated under the direct supervision of a licensed mortician or funeral director; and</section><section prefix="(2)">The embalming is done by a licensed mortician.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
