<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gho" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="7-4A-03" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gho-7-4A-03</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">There is a Family Security Trust Fund.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Board shall:<section prefix="(1)">Administer the Fund; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Over a reasonable period of time, build the Fund to a level of $1,000,000 and thereafter maintain the Fund at that level.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Fund is a special, nonlapsing fund that is not subject to &#xA7; 7-302 of the State Finance and Procurement Article.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Board shall deposit all money collected to the credit of the Fund with the State Treasurer for placement into a special account.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The State Treasurer may invest or reinvest money in the Fund in the same manner as money in the State Retirement and Pension System.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The investment earnings shall be:</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">If the level of the Fund exceeds $1,000,000, the State Treasurer shall pay the investment earnings of the Fund into the General Fund of the State.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The Fund is not liable for any other expenses or obligations of the Board.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Accounting and financial reports related to the Fund shall be publicly available in a timely manner.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Legislative Auditor shall audit the accounts and transactions of the Fund as provided in &#xA7; 2-1220 of the State Government Article.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Board may retain the services of appropriate experts or service providers to advise about, or administer, the Fund.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The costs of the services described in paragraph (1) of this subsection shall be paid out of the Fund.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(h)">The Board shall adopt regulations for the administration and claims procedures of the Fund.</section>
  </text>
</law>
