<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gho" order_by="" level="1">Health Occupations</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gho-4-403</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>403</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The work authorization required by &#xA7; 4-402 of this subtitle for dental laboratory work shall:<section prefix="(1)">Be on the form that the Board requires;</section><section prefix="(2)">Be signed by a licensed dentist who requests the work; and</section><section prefix="(3)">Contain the information required by this section.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The work authorization shall be prepared in duplicate and contain:<section prefix="(1)">The name and address of the dental laboratory to do the work;</section><section prefix="(2)">Identification of the patient by name or number;</section><section prefix="(3)">The date on which the work authorization form was completed;</section><section prefix="(4)">A description of the work to be done, including diagrams if necessary;</section><section prefix="(5)">A specification of the type of dental materials to be used; and</section><section prefix="(6)">The name and license number of the dentist who requests the work.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A dental laboratory named in a work authorization may subcontract dental laboratory work, if that dental laboratory:<section prefix="(1)">Completes in duplicate the subcontracted work authorization form that the Board requires; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Complies with the record keeping requirements of &#xA7; 4-404 of this subtitle.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Board shall publish:<section prefix="(1)">An approved standard work authorization form; and</section><section prefix="(2)">An approved standard subcontracted work authorization form that is of a color different from the standard work authorization form.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">A dental laboratory in this State may do dental laboratory work on the request of a dentist licensed and practicing in any other state or a foreign country if the request:<section prefix="(1)">Is on the form that the Board requires or a reasonably equivalent form; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Otherwise meets the requirements of this subtitle.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
