<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gho" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="3-5A-01" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gho-3-5A-01</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Board" means the State Board of Chiropractic and Massage Therapy Examiners.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Health care facility" has the meaning stated in &#xA7; 19-114(d) of the Health - General Article.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">"License" means, unless the context requires otherwise, a license issued by the Board to practice massage therapy.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"Licensed massage therapist" means an individual who is licensed by the Board to practice massage therapy.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Massage therapy" means the use of manual techniques on soft tissues of the human body including effleurage (stroking), petrissage (kneading), tapotement (tapping), stretching, compression, vibration, and friction, with or without the aid of heat limited to hot packs and heating pads, cold water, or nonlegend topical applications, for the purpose of improving circulation, enhancing muscle relaxation, relieving muscular pain, reducing stress, or promoting health and well-being.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Massage therapy" does not include:<section prefix="(i)">The diagnosis or treatment of illness, disease, or injury;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The adjustment, manipulation, or mobilization of any of the articulations of the osseous structures of the body or spine; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">Except as provided in paragraph (3) of this subsection, the laying on of hands, consisting of pressure or movement on a fully clothed individual, to specifically affect the electromagnetic energy or energetic field of the human body.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Massage therapy" includes the laying on of hands, consisting of pressure or movement on a fully clothed individual, to specifically affect the electromagnetic energy or energetic field of the human body if this practice includes use of the manual techniques set forth in paragraph (1) of this subsection.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">In paragraph (2)(iii) of this subsection, "fully clothed" does not require the wearing of footwear.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">The provisions of paragraph (2) of this subsection do not preclude the application of the modalities described in paragraph (1) of this subsection to an individual who has an injury.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">"Practice massage therapy" means to engage professionally and for compensation in massage therapy.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">"Practice non-therapeutic massage" means to engage professionally and for compensation in massage therapy in a setting that is not a health care facility.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">"Registered massage practitioner" means an individual who is registered by the Board to practice non-therapeutic massage.</section>
    <section prefix="(j)">"Registration" means, unless the context requires otherwise, a registration issued by the Board to practice non-therapeutic massage.</section>
  </text>
</law>
