<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gho" order_by="gho" level="1">Health Occupations</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gho-14-101</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this title the following words have the meanings indicated....</catch_line>
  <order_by>101</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this title the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Board" means the State Board of Physicians.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Civil action" includes a health care malpractice claim under Title 3, Subtitle 2A of the Courts Article.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Cosmetic surgical procedure" means the use of surgical services to reshape the structure of a human body in order to change the appearance of an individual.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Cosmetic surgical procedure" does not include:<section prefix="(i)">A procedure done under local anesthesia or mild sedation; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">Liposuction that removes less than 1,000 cubic centimeters of aspirate.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"Faculty" means the Medical and Chirurgical Faculty of the State of Maryland.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">"Hospital" has the meaning stated in &#xA7; 19-301 of the Health - General Article.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">"License" means, unless the context requires otherwise, a license issued by the Board to practice medicine.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">"Licensed physician" means, unless the context requires otherwise, a physician, including a doctor of osteopathy, who is licensed by the Board to practice medicine.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">"Licensee" means an individual to whom a license is issued, including an individual practicing medicine within or as a professional corporation or professional association.</section>
    <section prefix="(j)">"Mild sedation" means a drug-induced state during which:<section prefix="(1)">A patient is able to respond to verbal commands;</section><section prefix="(2)">A patient's ventilatory and cardiovascular functions are not affected; and</section><section prefix="(3)">A patient's cognitive function and coordination may be impaired.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(k)">"Perform acupuncture" means to stimulate a certain point or points on or near the surface of the human body by the insertion of needles to prevent or modify the perception of pain or to normalize physiological functions, including pain control, for the treatment of ailments or conditions of the body.</section>
    <section prefix="(l)">"Physician" means an individual who practices medicine.</section>
    <section prefix="(m)">"Physician Rehabilitation Program" means the program of the Board or the nonprofit entity with which the Board contracts under &#xA7; 14-401(g) of this title that evaluates and provides assistance to impaired physicians and other health professionals regulated by the Board who are directed by the Board to receive treatment and rehabilitation for alcoholism, chemical dependency, or other physical, emotional, or mental conditions.</section>
    <section prefix="(n)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Practice medicine" means to engage, with or without compensation, in medical:<section prefix="(i)">Diagnosis;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Healing;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Treatment; or</section><section prefix="(iv)">Surgery.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Practice medicine" includes doing, undertaking, professing to do, and attempting any of the following:<section prefix="(i)">Diagnosing, healing, treating, preventing, prescribing for, or removing any physical, mental, or emotional ailment or supposed ailment of an individual:<section prefix="1.">By physical, mental, emotional, or other process that is exercised or invoked by the practitioner, the patient, or both; or</section><section prefix="2.">By appliance, test, drug, operation, or treatment;</section></section><section prefix="(ii)">Ending of a human pregnancy; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Performing acupuncture as provided under &#xA7; 14-504 of this title.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Practice medicine" does not include:<section prefix="(i)">Selling any nonprescription drug or medicine;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Practicing as an optician; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">Performing a massage or other manipulation by hand, but by no other means.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(o)">"Related institution" has the meaning stated in &#xA7; 19-301 of the Health - General Article.</section>
  </text>
</law>
