<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gho" order_by="gho" level="1">Health Occupations</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gho-8-208</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this section the following words have the meanings indicated....</catch_line>
  <order_by>208</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Applicant" means an individual who has submitted an application to the Board to be licensed as a registered nurse, licensed practical nurse, or electrologist or to be certified as a nursing assistant or medication technician in this State.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Program" means the rehabilitation program.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">There is a Rehabilitation Committee in the Board.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Board may create 1 or more rehabilitation committees.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Committee shall consist of 6 members.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Of the 6 Committee members:<section prefix="(i)">3 shall be licensed registered nurses, who have demonstrated expertise in the field of chemical dependency or psychiatric nursing;</section><section prefix="(ii)">1 shall be a registered nurse, who has demonstrated expertise in the area of pain management;</section><section prefix="(iii)">1 shall be a licensed practical nurse; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">1 shall be a consumer member, who is knowledgeable in the field of chemical dependency.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Board shall determine the term of a member of the Committee.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">At the end of a term, a member continues to serve until a successor is appointed and qualifies.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A Committee member who is appointed after a term has begun serves only for the rest of the term and until a successor is appointed and qualifies.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The Board may remove a Committee member for incompetence or misconduct.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Committee shall elect a chairperson and a vice-chairperson.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The manner of election of officers shall be as the Committee determines.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">A majority of the members then serving on the Committee Board is a quorum.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">The Committee shall determine the times and places of its meetings.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">Each member of the Committee is entitled to:<section prefix="(1)">Compensation in accordance with the State budget; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Reimbursement for expenses under the Standard State Travel Regulations, as provided in the State budget.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(i)">The Board may employ a staff to carry out the activities of the Committee in accordance with the State budget.</section>
    <section prefix="(j)">In addition to the powers set forth elsewhere in this subtitle, the Committee may:<section prefix="(1)">Evaluate those nurses, nursing assistants, medication technicians, electrologists, or applicants who request participation in the program according to the guidelines prescribed by the Board and consider the recommendations for admission into the program;</section><section prefix="(2)">Review and designate those treatment facilities and services to which nurses, nursing assistants, medication technicians, electrologists, or applicants in the program may be referred;</section><section prefix="(3)">Receive and review information concerning a nurse, nursing assistant, medication technician, electrologist, or applicant participating in the program;</section><section prefix="(4)">Consider in the case of each nurse, nursing assistant, medication technician, electrologist, or applicant participating in a program whether the nurse, nursing assistant, medication technician, electrologist, or applicant may with safety continue or resume the practice of nursing or delegated nursing functions or electrology; and</section><section prefix="(5)">Have meetings as necessary to consider the requests of nurses, nursing assistants, medication technicians, electrologists, or applicants to participate in the program, and consider reports regarding nurses, nursing assistants, medication technicians, electrologists, or applicants participating in the program.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(k)">In addition to the duties set forth elsewhere in this subtitle, the Committee shall:<section prefix="(1)">Prepare reports to be submitted to the Board; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Set forth in writing for each nurse, nursing assistant, medication technician, electrologist, or applicant participating in the program a rehabilitation program established for that nurse, nursing assistant, medication technician, electrologist, or applicant, including the requirements for supervision and surveillance.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(l)">The Committee shall inform each nurse, nursing assistant, medication technician, electrologist, or applicant who requests participation in the program of:<section prefix="(1)">The procedures followed in the program;</section><section prefix="(2)">The rights and responsibilities of the nurse, nursing assistant, medication technician, electrologist, or applicant in the program; and</section><section prefix="(3)">The possible results of noncompliance with the program.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(m)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Each nurse, nursing assistant, medication technician, electrologist, or applicant who requests to participate in the program shall agree to cooperate with the individual rehabilitation program designed by the Committee.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Any failure to comply with the provisions of a rehabilitation program may result in termination of the nurse's, nursing assistant's, medication technician's, electrologist's, or applicant's participation in the program.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Committee shall report the name and license number of a nurse or electrologist, the name and certificate number of a nursing assistant or medication technician, or the name of an applicant who is expelled from the program for failure to comply with the conditions of the program.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The program shall transfer to the Board all the records of any nurse, nursing assistant, medication technician, electrologist, or applicant expelled from the program.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The Board may initiate disciplinary action based on the failure of the nurse, nursing assistant, medication technician, electrologist, or applicant to comply with the conditions of the program in accordance with the provisions of &#xA7;&#xA7; 8-316 and 8-317 or &#xA7;&#xA7; 8-6B-18 and 8-6B-19 of this title.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(n)">After the Committee has determined that a nurse, nursing assistant, medication technician, electrologist, or applicant has been rehabilitated, the Committee shall purge and destroy all records concerning a nurse's, nursing assistant's, medication technician's, electrologist's, or applicant's participation in the program.</section>
    <section prefix="(o)">All Board and Committee records of a proceeding concerning the rehabilitation of a nurse, nursing assistant, medication technician, electrologist, or applicant in the program are confidential and are not subject to discovery or subpoena in any civil or criminal action.</section>
    <section prefix="(p)">The Board shall provide for the representation of any person making reports to the Committee or the Board under this section in any action for defamation directly resulting from reports or information given to the Committee or the Board regarding a nurse's, nursing assistant's, medication technician's, electrologist's, or applicant's participation in the program.</section>
    <section prefix="(q)">Beginning July 1, 1990, and on a regular basis thereafter, the Board shall require reports from the Committee. The reports shall include:<section prefix="(1)">Information concerning the number of cases accepted, denied, or terminated with compliance or noncompliance; and</section><section prefix="(2)">A cost analysis of the program.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
