<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gho" order_by="gho" level="1">Health Occupations</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gho-12-302</section_number>
  <catch_line>To qualify for a license, an applicant shall be an individual who meets the requirements of this sec...</catch_line>
  <order_by>302</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">To qualify for a license, an applicant shall be an individual who meets the requirements of this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The applicant shall be of good moral character.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The applicant shall be at least 18 years old.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The applicant shall:<section prefix="(1)">Be a graduate of a school or college of pharmacy that is approved by the Board or accredited by the American Council on Pharmaceutical Education; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Have completed the professional experience program that the Board requires.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">Except as otherwise provided in this title, the applicant shall pass an examination given by the Board under this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this subsection, "foreign school or college of pharmacy" means a school or college of pharmacy that is not located in any state in the United States.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Board may waive the requirements of subsection (d)(1) of this section for an applicant who is a graduate of a foreign school or college of pharmacy, provided that the applicant passes an examination approved by the Board in addition to the examinations otherwise given by the Board under this subtitle.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Board shall require, as part of its examination or licensing procedures, an applicant for a license to practice pharmacy to demonstrate an oral competency in the English language by passing a Board approved standardized test of oral competency.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Board shall adopt regulations that establish a procedure for testing an individual who because of the individual's speech or hearing impairment is unable to complete satisfactorily a Board approved standardized test of oral competency.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">If any disciplinary charge or action that relates to a problem with the oral communication of the English language is brought against a licensee under this title, the Board shall require the licensee to pass a Board approved standardized test of oral competency.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The Board may not require an applicant for a license to practice pharmacy, who was previously licensed in another state to practice pharmacy, to demonstrate an oral competency in the English language, if the other state's examination and licensing procedures at the time the applicant was licensed in the other state included an oral competency component similar to the oral competency component in this State's examination and licensing procedures.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
