<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gho" order_by="" level="1">Health Occupations</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gho-14-5C-01</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>01</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Board" means the State Board of Physicians.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Committee" means the Polysomnography Professional Standards Committee established under &#xA7; 14-5C-05 of this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">"License" means a license issued by the Board.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"Licensed polysomnographic technologist" means a polysomnographic technologist who is licensed by the Board under this subtitle to practice polysomnography under the supervision of a licensed physician.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Practice polysomnography" means:<section prefix="(i)">Monitoring and recording physiologic data during sleep, including sleep-related respiratory disturbances under the supervision of a licensed physician; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">Using data collected under item (i) of this paragraph for the purposes of assisting a licensed physician in the diagnosis and treatment of sleep and wake disorders.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Practice polysomnography" includes:<section prefix="(i)">Providing polysomnography services that are safe, aseptic, preventive, and restorative;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Diagnosing and treating individuals who suffer from sleep disorders as a result of developmental defects, the aging process, physical injury, disease, or actual or anticipated somatic dysfunction;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Observing and monitoring physical signs and symptoms, general behavior, and general physical response to polysomnographic evaluation and determining whether initiation, modification, or discontinuation of a treatment regimen is warranted;</section><section prefix="(iv)">Using evaluation techniques that include limited cardiopulmonary function assessments, the need and effectiveness of therapeutic modalities and procedures, and the assessment and evaluation of the need for extended care; and</section><section prefix="(v)">Applying the use of techniques, equipment, and procedures involved in the evaluation of polysomnography, including:<section prefix="1.">Continuous positive airway pressure or bi-level positive airway pressure titration on spontaneously breathing patients;</section><section prefix="2.">Supplemental low flow oxygen therapy during polysomnogram;</section><section prefix="3.">Capnography during polysomnogram;</section><section prefix="4.">Cardiopulmonary resuscitation;</section><section prefix="5.">Pulse oximetry;</section><section prefix="6.">PH probe placement and monitoring;</section><section prefix="7.">Esophageal pressure;</section><section prefix="8.">Sleep staging including surface electroencephalography, surface electrooculography, and surface submental electromyography;</section><section prefix="9.">Surface electromyography of arms and legs;</section><section prefix="10.">Electrocardiography;</section><section prefix="11.">Respiratory effort including thoracic and abdominal;</section><section prefix="12.">Plethysmography blood flow;</section><section prefix="13.">Snore monitoring;</section><section prefix="14.">Audio or video monitoring;</section><section prefix="15.">Implementation of a written or verbal order from a licensed physician that requires the practice of polysomnography;</section><section prefix="16.">Monitoring the effects a nasal device, used to treat sleep apnea, has on sleep patterns provided that the device does not extend into the trachea; and</section><section prefix="17.">Monitoring the effects an oral device, used to treat sleep apnea, has on sleep patterns, provided that:</section></section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">"Student" means an individual who, in accordance with section 14-5C-09(c) of this subtitle, is:<section prefix="(1)">Enrolled in an accredited educational program in order to qualify for a license under this title; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Performing polysomnography services within the accredited program under the supervision of a licensed physician and without compensation.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(h)">"Registered polysomnographic technologist" means a polysomnographic technologist who is registered by the Board of Registered Polysomnographic Technicians.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">"Supervision" means general or direct supervision of a licensed polysomnographic technologist by a licensed physician.</section>
  </text>
</law>
