<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gho" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="12-505" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gho-12-505</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Except for a drug or device dispensed to an inpatient in a hospital or related institution, each container of a drug or device dispensed shall be labeled in accordance with this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">In addition to any other information required by law, the label shall include:<section prefix="(1)">The date the prescription is filled; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Unless otherwise required by the prescriber:<section prefix="(i)">An expiration date of the drugs or devices which shall be the lesser of:</section><section prefix="(ii)">Any appropriate special handling instructions regarding proper storage of the drugs or devices; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Subject to the provisions of subsection (c) of this section, the name and strength of the drugs or devices.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, the label shall indicate the same name for the drug or device as that used by the authorized prescriber.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If, under &#xA7; 12-504 of this subtitle, the pharmacist substitutes a drug or device product for that named by the authorized prescriber, the label shall indicate both the name of the drug or device product and the name of the manufacturer or distributor of the drug or device dispensed.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in this subsection, if an authorized prescriber dispenses a drug or device, the prescriber shall label each container of the drug or device.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">In addition to any other information required by law, the authorized prescriber shall include on the label:<section prefix="(i)">The name and strength of the drug or device;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The date the prescription is dispensed;</section><section prefix="(iii)">An expiration date of the drug or device which shall be the lesser of:</section><section prefix="(iv)">Any appropriate special handling instructions regarding proper storage of the drug or device.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The labeling requirements of this subsection do not apply if the authorized prescriber dispenses the drug or device:<section prefix="(i)">To an inpatient in a hospital or related institution;</section><section prefix="(ii)">In an emergency situation; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">As a sample drug or device dispensed in the regular course of the authorized prescriber's practice.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">So long as any of the original contents remain in the container, a person may not alter, deface, or remove any label required by this section.</section>
  </text>
</law>
