<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gho" order_by="" level="1">Health Occupations</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gho-8-301</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>301</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Except as otherwise provided in this title, an individual shall be licensed by the Board before the individual may practice registered nursing in this State.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Except as otherwise provided in this title, an individual shall be licensed by the Board before the individual may practice licensed practical nursing in this State.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">This section does not apply to:<section prefix="(1)">A student enrolled in an approved education program while practicing registered nursing or licensed practical nursing in that program;</section><section prefix="(2)">An individual employed by the federal government to practice registered nursing or licensed practical nursing while practicing within the scope of that employment, if the individual is authorized by any state to practice registered nursing or licensed practical nursing;</section><section prefix="(3)">An individual permitted to practice registered nursing or licensed practical nursing under rules and regulations adopted by the Board, if the individual:<section prefix="(i)">Otherwise has qualified to practice registered nursing or licensed practical nursing in any other state or country and is in this State temporarily; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">Has an application for a license pending before the Board:<section prefix="1.">But has not taken the examination required under this title;</section><section prefix="2.">Has taken an examination under this title, but the results of the examination are not yet known; or</section><section prefix="3.">Has taken and passed an examination under this title, but is waiting for the completion of the criminal history records check;</section></section></section><section prefix="(4)">An individual who provides gratuitous care for friends, domestic partners, or family members; or</section><section prefix="(5)">An individual who responds to a disaster situation in this State to practice registered nursing or licensed practical nursing, if:<section prefix="(i)">The individual has an active unencumbered license to practice registered nursing or licensed practical nursing in another state and the individual is assigned by:<section prefix="1.">The American Red Cross; or</section><section prefix="2.">A member of the Maryland Emergency Management Assistance Compact under &#xA7; 14-803 of the Public Safety Article;</section></section><section prefix="(ii)">The Governor has declared a State of Emergency by Executive Order or proclamation in accordance with &#xA7; 3-401 of the State Government Article; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">The individual reports to the designated staging area in accordance with &#xA7; 14-803(2)(b)(5)(iv) of the Public Safety Article.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A registered nurse or licensed practical nurse in a party state to the Nurse Multistate Licensure Compact shall hold a license in only one party state at a time, that is issued by the home state in accordance with Subtitle 7A of this title.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">A registered nurse who has been granted multistate licensing privileges by a party state to the Nurse Multistate Licensure Compact set forth in Subtitle 7A of this title may practice registered nursing in the State.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">A licensed practical nurse who has been granted multistate licensing privileges by a party state to the Nurse Multistate Licensure Compact set forth in Subtitle 7A of this title may practice practical nursing in the State.</section>
  </text>
</law>
