<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gho" order_by="gho" level="1">Health Occupations</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gho-4-302</section_number>
  <catch_line>Except as otherwise provided in this title, to qualify for a license, an applicant shall be an indiv...</catch_line>
  <order_by>302</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Except as otherwise provided in this title, to qualify for a license, an applicant shall be an individual who meets the requirements of this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The applicant shall be of good moral character.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">To qualify for a license to practice dentistry, the applicant shall be at least 18 years old.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Unless waived by the Board under &#xA7;&#xA7; 4-303 and 4-303.1 of this subtitle, to qualify for a license to practice dentistry, the applicant shall hold a degree of Doctor of Dental Surgery, Doctor of Dental Medicine, or the equivalent, from a college or university that is:<section prefix="(1)">Authorized by any state or any province of Canada to grant the degree; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Recognized by the Board as requiring adequate preprofessional collegiate training and as maintaining an acceptable course of dental instruction.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">To qualify for a license to practice dental hygiene, the applicant shall be a graduate of a school for dental hygienists that:<section prefix="(1)">Requires at least 2 years of education in an institution of higher education;</section><section prefix="(2)">Is accredited by the American Dental Association Commission on Dental Accreditation; and</section><section prefix="(3)">Is approved by the Board.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Unless the examination requirement is waived under &#xA7; 4-306 or &#xA7; 4-310 of this subtitle, and except as provided in &#xA7; 4-303.1 of this subtitle, to qualify for a general license to practice dentistry or a general license to practice dental hygiene, the applicant shall pass an examination given by the Board under this subtitle.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">An examination is not required for a teacher's license to practice dentistry, a limited license to practice dentistry, or a teacher's license to practice dental hygiene.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">In addition to the requirements of subsections (a), (b), (c), and (d) of this section, to qualify for a teacher's license to practice dentistry, the applicant shall:<section prefix="(1)">Be licensed to practice dentistry in any other state;</section><section prefix="(2)">Have been active in the dental profession for at least 5 years;</section><section prefix="(3)">Be a full-time or part-time faculty member at a college or university where the applicant teaches a subject required by the dental school of that college or university; and</section><section prefix="(4)">If the applicant is engaged in a teaching area that is designated as a specialty by the American Dental Association, meet the requirements established by the American Dental Association for that specialty.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(h)">In addition to the requirements of subsections (a), (b), and (e) of this section, to qualify for a teacher's license to practice dental hygiene, the applicant shall:<section prefix="(1)">Be licensed to practice dental hygiene in any other state;</section><section prefix="(2)">Have been active as a dental hygienist for at least 5 years before applying for the teacher's license to practice dental hygiene; and</section><section prefix="(3)">Be a full-time or part-time faculty member at a dental school where the applicant teaches a subject required by that school.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(i)">In addition to the requirements of subsections (a), (b), (c), and (d) of this section, to qualify for a retired volunteer dentist's license to practice dentistry, the applicant shall:<section prefix="(1)">Have had a general license to practice dentistry issued under this title within the last 2 years;</section><section prefix="(2)">Complete the continuing education requirements that the Board establishes for a general license; and</section><section prefix="(3)">Provide dental services as required under &#xA7; 4-308(c) of this subtitle.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(j)">In addition to the requirements of subsections (a), (b), and (e) of this section, to qualify for a retired dental hygienist's license to practice dental hygiene, the applicant shall:<section prefix="(1)">Have had a general license to practice dental hygiene under this title within the last 2 years;</section><section prefix="(2)">Complete the continuing education requirements that the Board establishes for a general license; and</section><section prefix="(3)">Provide dental hygiene services as required under &#xA7; 4-308(g) of this subtitle.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(k)">In addition to the requirements of subsections (a), (b), (c), and (d) of this section, to qualify for a volunteer dentist's license to practice dentistry, the applicant shall:<section prefix="(1)">Satisfy the requirements of &#xA7; 4-306(b)(1) and (d)(2) of this subtitle;</section><section prefix="(2)">Hold an active license to practice dentistry in another state or in the District of Columbia;</section><section prefix="(3)">Complete the continuing education requirements that the Board establishes for a general license;</section><section prefix="(4)">Provide dental services exclusively in the manner described in &#xA7; 4-308(c) of this subtitle; and</section><section prefix="(5)">Immediately upon ceasing to provide services exclusively in the manner described in &#xA7; 4-308(c), surrender the volunteer license to the Board.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(l)">In addition to the requirements of subsections (a), (b), (c), and (e) of this section, to qualify for a volunteer dental hygienist's license to practice dental hygiene, an applicant shall:<section prefix="(1)">Satisfy the requirements of &#xA7; 4-306(b)(2) and (e)(2) of this subtitle;</section><section prefix="(2)">Hold an active license to practice dental hygiene in another state or in the District of Columbia;</section><section prefix="(3)">Complete the continuing education requirements that the Board establishes for a general license;</section><section prefix="(4)">Provide dental hygiene services exclusively in the manner described in &#xA7; 4-308(g) of this subtitle; and</section><section prefix="(5)">Immediately upon ceasing to provide services exclusively in the manner described in &#xA7; 4-308(g), surrender the volunteer license to the Board.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(m)">To qualify for a limited license to practice dentistry, the applicant shall meet the requirements set forth in subsections (a), (b), (c), and (d) of this section.</section>
  </text>
</law>
