<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gho" order_by="gho" level="1">Health Occupations</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gho-5-101</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated....</catch_line>
  <order_by>101</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Board" means the State Board of Dietetic Practice.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Certified nutrition specialist" means an individual certified by the Certification Board for Nutrition Specialists, the accrediting body of the American College of Nutrition.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">"Dietitian-nutritionist" means, unless the context requires otherwise, an individual who is licensed by the Board to practice dietetics.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"License" means, unless the context requires otherwise, a license issued by the Board to practice dietetics.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Medical device" means a health care product used in the diagnosis, treatment, or prevention of disease.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Medical device" does not mean:<section prefix="(i)">A drug;</section><section prefix="(ii)">A surgical or dental instrument;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Physical therapy equipment;</section><section prefix="(iv)">X-ray apparatus; or</section><section prefix="(v)">A component part or accessory of any of the items listed in this paragraph.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">"Medical nutrition" means the nutritional advice or counsel provided to an individual by a licensee in their professional capacity that is designed for an individual to alleviate a specific physiological complaint, condition, or symptom.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Practice dietetics" means to apply the principles derived from integrating knowledge of food, biochemistry, physiology, management science, behavioral science, and social science to human nutrition.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Practice dietetics" includes:<section prefix="(i)">Assessing individual and community food practices and nutritional status using anthropometric, biochemical, clinical, dietary, and demographic data, for clinical, research, and program planning purposes;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Developing, establishing, and evaluating nutritional care plans that establish priorities, goals, and objectives for meeting nutrient needs for individuals or groups;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Nutrition counseling and education as a part of preventive or restorative health care throughout the life cycle;</section><section prefix="(iv)">Determining, applying, and evaluating standards for food and nutrition services; and</section><section prefix="(v)">Applying scientific research to the role of food in the maintenance of health and the treatment of disease.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(i)">"Registered dietitian" means an individual registered with the Commission on Dietetic Registration, the accrediting body of the American Dietetic Association.</section>
    <section prefix="(j)">"Supervision" means the management of an individual who aids in the practice of dietetics by a licensed dietitian-nutritionist who may or may not be on the premises.</section>
  </text>
</law>
