<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gho" order_by="" level="1">Health Occupations</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gho-18-101</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>101</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this title the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Board" means the State Board of Examiners of Psychologists.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Doctoral degree in psychology" means:<section prefix="(i)">A degree received from a program that at the time the degree was awarded:<section prefix="1.">Is accredited by the American Psychological Association or the Canadian Psychological Association; or</section><section prefix="2.">Is listed in the designated doctoral programs in psychology published by the Council for the National Register of Health Service Providers in Psychology; or</section></section><section prefix="(ii)">A doctoral degree in psychology that the Council for the National Register of Health Service Providers in Psychology determines meets its criteria for a doctoral degree in psychology, if the degree was received from a doctoral program in psychology that:<section prefix="1.">Is located outside the United States and Canada;</section><section prefix="2.">Is currently accredited or designated in accordance with paragraph (1)(i) of this subsection, but was not accredited or designated at the time the degree was awarded;</section><section prefix="3.">Was completed prior to 1981 for United States programs;</section><section prefix="4.">Was completed prior to 1988 for Canadian programs; or</section><section prefix="5.">Is no longer in existence.</section></section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">A determination by the Council under paragraph (1)(ii) of this subsection that a doctoral degree in psychology meets its criteria shall be considered by the Board as prima facie evidence that the degree meets those criteria.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">In determining whether the degree in psychology meets the criteria described in paragraph (1)(ii) of this subsection and subparagraph (i) of this paragraph, the Board may consider the completion of postdoctoral course work in psychology, not to exceed 9 semester hours.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">"License" means, unless the context requires otherwise, a license issued by the Board to practice psychology.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"Licensed psychologist" means, unless the context requires otherwise, a psychologist who is licensed by the Board to practice psychology.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Practice psychology" means to provide to any person:<section prefix="(i)">Any service for compensation involving the application of psychological principles, psychological methods, or psychological procedures for understanding, predicting, or influencing behavior, including the principles that relate to learning, perception, motivation, emotions, organizational relationships, and interpersonal relationships;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Any service for compensation involving the application of psychological methods or psychological procedures for interviewing, counseling, psychotherapy, behavior modification, or hypnosis; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">Any service for compensation involving the application of psychological methods or psychological procedures for constructing, administering, or interpreting tests of mental abilities, neuropsychological functioning, aptitudes, interests, attitudes, personality characteristics, emotions, or motivations.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Practice psychology" includes:<section prefix="(i)">The application of psychological principles and psychological methods in the diagnosis, prevention, treatment, and amelioration of psychological problems, emotional conditions, or mental conditions of individuals or groups;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The use of psychological methods to assist an individual in acquiring greater human effectiveness or to modify feelings, conditions, attitudes, or behavior that is emotionally, intellectually, or socially ineffectual or maladjusted; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">The use of biofeedback instruments that do not pierce or cut the skin to measure physical and mental functioning.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">In this subsection, "psychological methods", "psychological principles", and "psychological procedures" include the body of information that can be derived from a graduate program in psychology, and other education or training recognized by the Board as prerequisites for a license under this title, and that does not amount to the practice of medicine.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">"Psychologist" means an individual who practices psychology.</section>
  </text>
</law>
