<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gho" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="5-308" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gho-5-308</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Unless the license is renewed for an additional term as provided in this section, a license expires on the date set by the Board.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A license may not be renewed for a term longer than 2 years.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">At least 1 month before the license expires, the Board shall send to the licensee, by first-class mail to the last known address of the licensee, a renewal notice that states:<section prefix="(1)">The date on which the current license expires;</section><section prefix="(2)">The date by which the Board must receive the renewal application for the renewal to be issued and mailed before the license expires; and</section><section prefix="(3)">The amount of the renewal fee.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Before the license expires, the licensee may renew it for an additional 2-year term, if the licensee:<section prefix="(1)">Otherwise is entitled to be licensed;</section><section prefix="(2)">Pays to the Board a renewal fee set by the Board; and</section><section prefix="(3)">Submits to the Board:<section prefix="(i)">A renewal application on the form that the Board requires; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Satisfactory evidence of compliance with the continuing education requirements for license renewal set by the Board under this section.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">In addition to any other qualifications and requirements established by the Board, the Board shall establish continuing education requirements as a condition to the renewal of licenses under this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The Board shall renew the license of each licensee who meets the requirements of this section.</section>
  </text>
</law>
