<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gho" order_by="" level="1">Health Occupations</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gho-10-101</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>101</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this title the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"ACOTE" means the Accreditation Council for Occupational Therapy Education.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Aide" means any individual who:<section prefix="(1)">Is not licensed by the Board to perform occupational therapy or limited occupational therapy; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Provides supportive services to the occupational therapist or occupational therapy assistant under direct supervision.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">"Board" means the State Board of Occupational Therapy Practice.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"Direct supervision" means supervision provided on a face-to-face basis by a supervising therapist when delegated client-related tasks are performed.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">"License" means, unless the context requires otherwise, a license issued by the Board to practice:<section prefix="(1)">Occupational therapy; or</section><section prefix="(2)">Limited occupational therapy.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(g)">"Licensed occupational therapist" means, unless the context requires otherwise, an occupational therapist who is licensed by the Board to practice occupational therapy.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">"Licensed occupational therapy assistant" means, unless the context requires otherwise, an occupational therapy assistant who is licensed by the Board to practice limited occupational therapy.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Limited occupational therapy" means participation, while under the periodic supervision of a licensed occupational therapist, in:<section prefix="(i)">An initial screening and evaluation that applies the principles and procedures of occupational therapy; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">A treatment program that applies the principles and procedures of occupational therapy.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Limited occupational therapy" does not include:<section prefix="(i)">Initiation and interpretation of evaluation data; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Initiation of a treatment program before the client has been evaluated and a licensed occupational therapist has rendered a treatment plan.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(j)">"NBCOT" means the National Board for Certification in Occupational Therapy.</section>
    <section prefix="(k)">"Occupational therapist" means an individual who practices occupational therapy.</section>
    <section prefix="(l)">"Occupational therapy" means the therapeutic use of purposeful and meaningful goal-directed activities to evaluate, consult, and treat individuals who:<section prefix="(1)">Have a disease or disorder, impairment, activity limitation, or participation restriction that interferes with their ability to function independently in daily life roles; or</section><section prefix="(2)">Benefit from the prevention of impairments and activity limitations.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(m)">"Occupational therapy assistant" means an individual who practices limited occupational therapy.</section>
    <section prefix="(n)">"Occupational therapy practice" or "limited occupational therapy practice" means to carry out a treatment program that applies the principles and procedures of occupational therapy.</section>
    <section prefix="(o)">"Occupational therapy principles" include:<section prefix="(1)">The use of therapeutic activities that promote independence in daily life roles;</section><section prefix="(2)">Remediation or restoration of performance abilities that are limited due to impairment in biological, physiological, psychological, or neurological processes;</section><section prefix="(3)">In order to enhance performance, the adaption of task, process, or the environment, or the teaching of compensatory techniques;</section><section prefix="(4)">Methods and techniques for preventing disability that facilitate the development or safe application of performance skills;</section><section prefix="(5)">Health promotion strategies and practices that enhance performance abilities; and</section><section prefix="(6)">Education, instruction, and research in the practice of occupational therapy.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(p)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Occupational therapy procedures" include:<section prefix="(i)">Developing, improving, sustaining, or restoring skills in activities of daily living, work, or productive activities, including:<section prefix="1.">Instrumental activities of daily activity; and</section><section prefix="2.">Play and leisure activities;</section></section><section prefix="(ii)">Developing, remediating, or restoring sensorimotor, perceptual, cognitive, or psychological components of performance;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Designing, fabricating, applying, or training in the use of assistive technology, splinting, or orthotic devices, including training in the use of prosthetic devices;</section><section prefix="(iv)">Adapting environments and processes, including the application of ergonomic principles to enhance performance and safety in daily life roles;</section><section prefix="(v)">Applying physical agent modalities as adjuncts to or in preparation for purposeful activity with appropriate training, as specified by the Board in regulations;</section><section prefix="(vi)">Promoting safe, functional mobility in daily life tasks;</section><section prefix="(vii)">Providing intervention in collaboration with the client, the client's family, the client's caregiver, or others;</section><section prefix="(viii)">Educating the client, the client's family, the client's caregiver, or others in carrying out appropriate nonskilled interventions; and</section><section prefix="(ix)">Consulting with groups, programs, organizations, and communities to provide population-based services.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Occupational therapy procedures" do not include the adjustment or manipulation of any of the osseous structures of the body or spine.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(q)">"On-site supervision" means supervision in which a supervisor is immediately available on a face-to-face basis when client procedures are performed or as otherwise necessary.</section>
    <section prefix="(r)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Periodic supervision" means supervision by a licensed occupational therapist on a face-to-face basis, occurring the earlier of at least:<section prefix="(i)">Once every 10 therapy visits; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">Once every 30 calendar days.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Periodic supervision" includes:<section prefix="(i)">Chart review; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Meetings to discuss client treatment plans, client response, or observation of treatment.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(s)">"Supervision" means aid, direction, and instruction provided by an occupational therapist to adequately ensure the safety and welfare of clients during the course of occupational therapy.</section>
    <section prefix="(t)">"Temporary license" means a license issued by the Board under and as limited by &#xA7; 10-313 of this title to practice:<section prefix="(1)">Occupational therapy; or</section><section prefix="(2)">Limited occupational therapy.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
