<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gho" order_by="gho" level="1">Health Occupations</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gho-2-310.1</section_number>
  <catch_line>Subject to the provisions of this section, the Board shall issue a limited license to practice heari...</catch_line>
  <order_by>310.1</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Subject to the provisions of this section, the Board shall issue a limited license to practice hearing aid dispensing to an individual who is waiting to take a licensing examination under this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Board may issue a limited license to practice hearing aid dispensing only to an individual who:<section prefix="(1)">Except for completing the requirements under &#xA7; 2-302.1(c) of this subtitle, otherwise qualifies for a license;</section><section prefix="(2)">Submits to the Board an application on the form that the Board provides;</section><section prefix="(3)">Satisfies the Board that the individual will practice hearing aid dispensing only within the scope allowed under subsection (c) of this section; and</section><section prefix="(4)">Pays to the Board the application fee set by the Board.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">While a limited license to practice hearing aid dispensing is in effect, it authorizes the holder to practice hearing aid dispensing only while being trained under the supervision of a licensed hearing aid dispenser or a licensed audiologist.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A limited license to practice hearing aid dispensing expires on the first anniversary of its effective date.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">Subject to the provisions of this subsection, the Board may renew once for an additional 1-year term the limited license to practice hearing aid dispensing to an individual who:<section prefix="(1)"><section prefix="(i)">Takes but fails to pass the examination; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">Does not take the examination for a reason that the Board finds adequate to excuse the failure to take the examination;</section></section><section prefix="(2)">Submits to the Board a renewal application on the form that the Board provides; and</section><section prefix="(3)">Pays to the Board the renewal fee set by the Board.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The total amount of time during which an individual may practice hearing aid dispensing under a limited license or licenses may not be more than 2 years.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">If a limited licensee fails to receive a full license within 2 years after the initial limited license was issued, the individual shall wait a minimum of 1 year before the individual may apply for another license.</section>
  </text>
</law>
