<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gho" order_by="" level="1">Health Occupations</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gho-10-319</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>319</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, "impaired occupational therapist professionals committee" means a committee that:<section prefix="(1)">Is defined in subsection (b) of this section; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Performs any of the functions listed in subsection (d) of this section.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">For purposes of this section, an impaired occupational therapist professionals committee is a committee of the Board or a committee of the Maryland Occupational Therapy Association that:<section prefix="(1)">Is recognized by the Board; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Includes but is not limited to occupational therapists.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">An impaired occupational therapist professionals committee of the Board or recognized by the Board may function:<section prefix="(1)">Solely for the Board; or</section><section prefix="(2)">Jointly with an impaired professionals committee representing another board or boards.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">For purposes of this section, an impaired occupational therapist professionals committee evaluates and provides assistance to any occupational therapist or occupational therapy assistant in need of treatment and rehabilitation for alcoholism, drug abuse, chemical dependency, or other physical, emotional, or mental condition.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as otherwise provided in this subsection, the proceedings, records, and files of the impaired occupational therapist professionals committee are not discoverable and are not admissible in evidence in any civil action arising out of matters that are being or have been reviewed and evaluated by the impaired occupational therapist professionals committee.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Paragraph (1) of this subsection does not apply to any record or document that is considered by the impaired occupational therapist professionals committee and that otherwise would be subject to discovery or introduction into evidence in a civil action.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">For purposes of this subsection, civil action does not include a proceeding before the Board or judicial review of a proceeding before the Board.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">A person who acts in good faith and within the scope of jurisdiction of an impaired occupational therapist professionals committee is not civilly liable for any action as a member of the impaired occupational therapist professionals committee or for giving information to, participating in, or contributing to the function of the impaired occupational therapist professionals committee.</section>
  </text>
</law>
