<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gho" order_by="gho" level="1">Health Occupations</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gho-17-304</section_number>
  <catch_line>Except as provided in &#xA7; 17-307 of this subtitle, to qualify for a license to practice clinical prof...</catch_line>
  <order_by>304</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Except as provided in &#xA7; 17-307 of this subtitle, to qualify for a license to practice clinical professional counseling, an applicant shall be an individual who meets the requirements of this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The applicant shall be of good moral character.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The applicant shall be at least 18 years old.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The applicant shall hold a master's or doctoral degree in a professional counseling field from an accredited educational institution that is approved by the Board.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">In the case of an applicant holding a doctoral degree, the applicant shall have completed:<section prefix="(i)">A minimum of 90 graduate credit hours in counselor training approved by the Board, including instruction in:<section prefix="1.">Counseling theory and ethics;</section><section prefix="2.">Counseling techniques;</section><section prefix="3.">Human growth and development and maladaptive behaviors;</section><section prefix="4.">Group dynamics, processing, and counseling;</section><section prefix="5.">Social and cultural foundations;</section><section prefix="6.">Lifestyle and career development;</section><section prefix="7.">Appraisal of individuals;</section><section prefix="8.">Research and evaluation;</section><section prefix="9.">Participation in a supervised practicum in professional counseling;</section><section prefix="10.">Marriage and family therapy; and</section><section prefix="11.">Alcohol and drug counseling; and</section></section><section prefix="(ii)">Not less than 2 years of supervised experience in counseling approved by the Board, 1 year of which shall have been completed after the award of the doctoral degree.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">In the case of an applicant holding only a master's degree, the applicant shall have completed:<section prefix="(i)">A minimum of 60 graduate credit hours in counselor training in the areas set forth in paragraph (2) of this subsection; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Not less than 3 years, with a minimum of 3,000 hours, of supervised experience in counseling approved by the Board, 2 years of which shall have been completed after the award of the master's degree.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The applicant shall provide documentation to the Board evidencing the completion of 60 hours of graduate course work in the applicant's respective area of practice from an accredited college or university program approved by the Board, including training in:<section prefix="(1)">Personality development;</section><section prefix="(2)">Diagnosis and treatment of mental and emotional disorders;</section><section prefix="(3)">Psychopathology; and</section><section prefix="(4)">Psychotherapy.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The applicant shall provide documentation evidencing the completion of 2 years of postgraduate supervised experience as required by the Board.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">Except as otherwise provided in this title, the applicant shall pass an examination approved by the Board.</section>
  </text>
</law>
