<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gho" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="8-6A-07" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gho-8-6A-07</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Subject to subsection (g) of this section, the Board shall certify any applicant who meets the requirements of this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Board shall:<section prefix="(i)">Issue each new certified nursing assistant or medication technician a certificate number and registration certificate that indicates the initial certificate was issued by the Board; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Electronically record each certificate in the Board's database and on the Board's website.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Each certificate shall include:<section prefix="(i)">Any expiration date;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The type of certificate; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Any specific category of nursing assistant.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">An individual who has met the requirements for a certified nursing assistant shall be certified with the title of "certified nursing assistant".</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">An individual who routinely performs nursing tasks delegated by a registered nurse or licensed practical nurse for compensation and has also completed a Board-approved course in medication administration shall be certified with the title of "certified medicine aide".</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">An individual who has met the requirements for a certified medication technician shall be certified with the title of "certified medication technician".</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The Board may issue a registration certificate to replace a lost, destroyed, or mutilated certificate, if the certificate holder pays the certificate replacement fee set by the Board.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Board may issue a temporary practice certificate to an applicant who:<section prefix="(i)">Has met the appropriate certification requirements of this subtitle to the satisfaction of the Board;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Does not have a criminal record and has not been the subject of a health professional disciplinary action in this State or another jurisdiction; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Does not have a criminal charge or a health professional disciplinary action pending in this State or another jurisdiction.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Unless the Board suspends or revokes a temporary practice certificate, the temporary practice certificate expires 90 days after issuance.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A temporary practice certificate may be extended up to an additional 90 days if the applicant is awaiting the completion of criminal history record information.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(h)">A medication technician graduate may practice for no more than 90 days from the date of completion of a medication technician training program without certification by the Board.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">
      <section prefix="(1)">On receipt of the criminal history record information of an applicant for certification as a certified nursing assistant forwarded to the Board in accordance with &#xA7; 8-303 of this title, in determining whether to grant a certificate, the Board shall consider:<section prefix="(i)">The age at which the crime was committed;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The circumstances surrounding the crime;</section><section prefix="(iii)">The length of time that has passed since the crime;</section><section prefix="(iv)">Subsequent work history;</section><section prefix="(v)">Employment and character references; and</section><section prefix="(vi)">Other evidence that demonstrates whether the applicant poses a threat to the public health or safety.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Board may not issue a certificate if the criminal history record information required under &#xA7; 8-303 of this title has not been received.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
