<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gho" order_by="" level="1">Health Occupations</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gho-15-103</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>103</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, "alternative health care system" has the meaning stated in &#xA7; 1-401 of this article.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">An employer of a physician assistant shall report to the Board, on the form prescribed by the Board, any termination of employment of the physician assistant if the cause of termination is related to a quality of care issue.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Except as otherwise provided under subsections (b) and (d) of this section, a hospital, a related institution, an alternative health care system, or an employer of a physician assistant shall report to the Board any limitation, reduction, or other change of the terms of employment of the physician assistant or any termination of employment of the physician assistant for any reason that might be grounds for disciplinary action under &#xA7; 15-314 of this title.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A hospital, related institution, alternative health system, or employer that has reason to know that a physician assistant has committed an action or has a condition that might be grounds for reprimand or probation of the physician assistant or suspension or revocation of the license of the physician assistant under &#xA7; 15-314 of this title because the physician assistant is alcohol- or drug-impaired is not required to report to the Board if:<section prefix="(1)">The hospital, related institution, alternative health system, or employer knows that the physician assistant is:<section prefix="(i)">In an alcohol or drug treatment program that is accredited by the Joint Commission on Accreditation of Healthcare Organizations or is certified by the Department; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">Under the care of a health care practitioner who is competent and capable of dealing with alcoholism and drug abuse;</section></section><section prefix="(2)">The hospital, related institution, alternative health system, or employer is able to verify that the physician assistant remains in the treatment program until discharge; and</section><section prefix="(3)">The action or condition of the physician assistant has not caused injury to any person while the physician assistant is practicing as a licensed physician assistant.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If the physician assistant enters, or is considering entering, an alcohol or drug treatment program that is accredited by the Joint Commission on Accreditation of Healthcare Organizations or that is certified by the Department, the physician assistant shall notify the hospital, related institution, alternative health system, or employer of the physician assistant's decision to enter the treatment program.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If the physician assistant fails to provide the notice required under paragraph (1) of this subsection, and the hospital, related institution, alternative health system, or employer learns that the physician assistant has entered a treatment program, the hospital, related institution, alternative health system, or employer shall report to the Board that the physician assistant has entered a treatment program and has failed to provide the required notice.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">If the physician assistant is found to be noncompliant with the treatment program's policies and procedures while in the treatment program, the treatment program shall notify the hospital, related institution, alternative health system, or employer of the physician assistant's noncompliance.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">On receipt of the notification required under paragraph (3) of this subsection, the hospital, related institution, alternative health system, or employer of the physician assistant shall report the physician assistant's noncompliance to the Board.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">A person is not required under this section to make any report that would be in violation of any federal or State law, rule, or regulation concerning the confidentiality of alcohol- and drug-abuse patient records.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">The hospital, related institution, alternative health system, or employer shall submit the report within 10 days of any action described in this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">A report under this section is not subject to subpoena or discovery in any civil action other than a proceeding arising out of a hearing and decision of the Board under this title.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Board may impose a civil penalty of up to $1,000 for failure to report under this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Board shall pay any fees collected under this subsection into the General Fund of the State.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(j)">An employer shall make the report required under this section to the Board within 5 days after the date of termination of employment.</section>
    <section prefix="(k)">The Board shall adopt regulations to implement the provisions of this section.</section>
  </text>
</law>
