<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gho" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="8-6A-05" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gho-8-6A-05</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Board shall adopt regulations establishing:<section prefix="(1)">Categories of certified nursing assistants, including geriatric nursing assistants, home health aides, school health aides, dialysis technicians, individuals working in developmental disabilities administration facilities, and medicine aides;</section><section prefix="(2)">Qualifications for each category of certified nursing assistant;</section><section prefix="(3)">Qualifications for certified medication technicians; and</section><section prefix="(4)">Standards for qualification of applicants for certification, including the applicant's criminal history, work record, and prohibitions against behavior which may be potentially harmful to patients.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">To qualify for certification as a nursing assistant, a nursing assistant in a specific category, or a medication technician, an applicant shall meet the requirements set by the Board.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">An applicant for a certificate shall:<section prefix="(i)">Submit an application to the Board on the form that the Board requires;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Provide evidence, as required by the Board, of successful completion of:</section><section prefix="(iii)">Pay to the Board an application fee set by the Board;</section><section prefix="(iv)">Be of good moral character;</section><section prefix="(v)">Be at least 16 years old to apply for certification as a nursing assistant; and</section><section prefix="(vi)">Be at least 18 years old to apply for certification as a medication technician.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Subject to paragraph (1) of this subsection, an applicant for certification as a certified nursing assistant shall submit to the Board:<section prefix="(i)">A criminal history records check in accordance with &#xA7; 8-303 of this title and &#xA7; 8-6A-08(k) of this subtitle; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">On the form required by the Board, written, verified evidence that the requirement of item (i) of this paragraph is being met or has been met.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">An applicant for certification as a certified medicine aide, in addition to the requirements under subsection (c)(1) of this section, shall submit an additional application to that effect to the Board on the form that the Board requires.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">An applicant for a certificate may not:<section prefix="(i)">Have committed any act or omission that would be grounds for discipline or denial of certification under this subtitle; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Have a record of abuse, negligence, misappropriation of a resident's property, or any disciplinary action taken or pending in any other state or territory of the United States against the certification of the nursing assistant or medication technician in the state or territory.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
