<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gho" order_by="gho" level="1">Health Occupations</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gho-8-315</section_number>
  <catch_line>The Board may issue a temporary license to any applicant who:...</catch_line>
  <order_by>315</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Board may issue a temporary license to any applicant who:<section prefix="(1)">Submits to a criminal history records check in accordance with &#xA7; 8-303 of this subtitle;</section><section prefix="(2)"><section prefix="(i)">Is licensed by any other state; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">Has taken and passed an examination under this title, but is waiting for the completion of the criminal history records check;</section></section><section prefix="(3)">Submits to the Board:<section prefix="(i)">An application on the form required by the Board;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Written, verified evidence that the requirement of item (1) of this subsection is being met; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Any other document required by the Board; and</section></section><section prefix="(4)">Pays the fee required by the Board.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A temporary license issued to an individual who is authorized to practice registered nursing in another state or who has taken and passed an examination under this title authorizes the holder to practice registered nursing in this State while the temporary license is effective.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A temporary license issued to an individual who is authorized to practice licensed practical nursing in another state or who has taken and passed an examination under this title authorizes the holder to practice licensed practical nursing in this State while the temporary license is effective.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Board may issue a temporary practice letter to a certified nurse practitioner or certified nurse-midwife who:<section prefix="(i)">Has been issued a temporary license under this subsection; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Is authorized to practice as a registered nurse.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A temporary practice letter issued to an individual who is authorized to practice as a certified nurse practitioner in another state authorizes the holder to practice as a certified nurse practitioner in this State while the temporary practice letter is effective.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in this subtitle, a temporary license and temporary practice letter may not be renewed.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Unless the Board suspends or revokes a temporary license or temporary practice letter, each temporary license or temporary practice letter expires 90 days after the date of issue.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A temporary license may be extended up to an additional 90 days if the applicant is awaiting the completion of criminal history record information.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">A temporary license or temporary practice letter may be extended every 90 days, provided that the total length of renewal does not exceed 12 months from the date the original temporary license or temporary practice letter was issued, if the applicant does not meet the practice requirement as provided for in regulation.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The Board shall revoke a temporary license or temporary certificate if the criminal history record information forwarded to the Board in accordance with &#xA7; 8-303 of this subtitle reveals that the applicant, certificate holder, or licensee has been convicted or pled guilty or nolo contendere to a felony or to a crime involving moral turpitude, whether or not any appeal or other proceeding is pending to have the conviction or plea set aside.</section>
  </text>
</law>
