<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gho" order_by="" level="1">Health Occupations</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gho-15-307</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>307</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Unless a license is renewed for an additional term as provided in this section, the license expires on the date set by the Board.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A license may not be renewed for a term longer than 2 years.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">At least 1 month before a license expires, the Board shall send to the licensee, by first-class mail to the last known address of the licensee, a renewal notice that states:<section prefix="(1)">The date on which the current license expires;</section><section prefix="(2)">The date by which the Board must receive the renewal application for the renewal to be issued and mailed before the license expires; and</section><section prefix="(3)">The amount of the renewal fee.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Before a license expires, the licensee periodically may renew it for an additional 2-year term, if the licensee:<section prefix="(1)">Is otherwise entitled to be issued a license;</section><section prefix="(2)">Pays to the Board the renewal fee, set by the Board;</section><section prefix="(3)">Submits to the Board:<section prefix="(i)">A renewal application on the form that the Board requires; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Satisfactory evidence of compliance with the continuing education requirements for license renewal set by the Board under this section; and</section></section><section prefix="(4)">Meets any additional requirements set by the Board for renewal of a license.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">In addition to any other qualifications and requirements established by the Board, the Board shall establish continuing education requirements as a condition for the renewal of licenses under this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The Board shall renew the license of each licensee who meets the requirements of this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">For the failure of a licensee to obtain continuing medical education credits as required by the Board, the Board may impose a civil penalty not to exceed $100 for each medical education credit not obtained by the licensee.</section>
  </text>
</law>
