<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gho" order_by="gho" level="1">Health Occupations</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gho-21-309</section_number>
  <catch_line>A license expires on the date specified on the license, unless it is renewed for a 2-year term as pr...</catch_line>
  <order_by>309</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">A license expires on the date specified on the license, unless it is renewed for a 2-year term as provided in this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">At least 1 month before the license expires, the Board shall send to the licensee, by first-class mail or electronic means to the last known address or electronic mail address of the licensee, a renewal notice that states:<section prefix="(1)">The date on which the current license expires;</section><section prefix="(2)">The date by which the renewal application must be received by the Board for the renewal to be issued and mailed before the license expires;</section><section prefix="(3)">The amount of the renewal fee; and</section><section prefix="(4)">The hours of approved training required for renewal of licensure.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Before the license expires, the licensee may renew it for an additional 2-year term, if the licensee:<section prefix="(1)">Otherwise is entitled to be licensed;</section><section prefix="(2)">Pays to the Board the renewal fee set by the Board;</section><section prefix="(3)">Submits to the Board a renewal application on the form that the Board requires; and</section><section prefix="(4)">Submits to the Board proof that during the previous 2-year period, the licensee has acquired 20 hours of approved training in environmental health or other equivalent education as approved by the Board.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The renewal license shall bear the same serial number assigned to the licensee at the time of the original registration or licensure.</section>
  </text>
</law>
