<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gho" order_by="" level="1">Health Occupations</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gho-2-301</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>301</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as otherwise provided in this title, an individual shall be licensed by the Board before the individual may practice audiology, hearing aid dispensing, or speech-language pathology, or assist in the practice of speech-language pathology in this State.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">On or after October 1, 2007, an individual hired by a Maryland local public school system, State-approved nonpublic school for handicapped children, or chartered educational institution of the State to practice speech-language pathology or assist in the practice of speech-language pathology, shall be licensed by the Board.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This section does not apply:<section prefix="(i)">To an individual employed by any agency of the federal government performing the duties of that employment;</section><section prefix="(ii)">To an individual continuously employed to practice audiology since June 30, 1988 by a county public school system, a State approved nonpublic school for handicapped children, a chartered institution of the State, or the State Department of Education while performing the duties of that employment;</section><section prefix="(iii)">To an individual employed by a Maryland local public school system, State approved nonpublic school for handicapped children, or chartered educational institution of the  State or the State Department of Education to practice speech-language pathology continuously since on or before September 30, 2007, while performing the duties of that employment;</section><section prefix="(iv)">To a student or trainee in audiology or speech-language pathology while pursuing a supervised course of study at an accredited university or college or a recognized training center while the student is obtaining clinical practicum hours; or</section><section prefix="(v)">To a volunteer while working in free speech and hearing screening programs.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Board may allow an audiologist, hearing aid dispenser, speech-language pathologist, or speech-language pathology assistant licensed in another state to practice audiology, hearing aid dispensing, or speech-language pathology, or assist in the practice of speech-language pathology in this State without a license if the audiologist, hearing aid dispenser, speech-language pathologist, or speech-language pathology assistant has a completed application for a license pending before the Board.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
