<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gho" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="4-303" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gho-4-303</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Subject to the provisions of this section, the Board may waive the education requirements of &#xA7; 4-302 of this subtitle for an applicant for a limited license who does not hold a degree of Doctor of Dental Surgery, Doctor of Dental Medicine, or the equivalent from a college or university that is authorized by any state or any province of Canada to grant the degree and is recognized by the Board under &#xA7; 4-302(d)(2) of this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Board may grant a waiver under this section only if the applicant:<section prefix="(1)">Completes at least 2 years of formal general clinical training in a college or university that is authorized by any state or any province of Canada to grant the degree of Doctor of Dental Surgery, Doctor of Dental Medicine, or the equivalent and is recognized by the Board under &#xA7; 4-302(d)(2) of this subtitle; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Meets any other requirements that the Board establishes for a waiver of the education requirements of &#xA7; 4-302 of this subtitle.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Notwithstanding the provisions of subsection (b) of this section and &#xA7; 4-302(g) of this subtitle, the Board may grant a waiver for a teacher's license if it finds that:<section prefix="(i)">The applicant holds a degree of Doctor of Dental Surgery, Doctor of Dental Medicine, or an equivalent degree from a school, college, or faculty of dentistry;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The applicant demonstrates that the applicant has had at least 5 years of clinical dental experience;</section><section prefix="(iii)">The applicant is found to be of good moral character and professionally competent;</section><section prefix="(iv)">The Dean of the University of Maryland Dental School requests the waiver and circumstances exist that justify the granting of a waiver; and</section><section prefix="(v)">The applicant is appointed to a full-time or part-time faculty position at the University of Maryland Dental School.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A teacher's license granted pursuant to a waiver under paragraph (1) of this subsection:<section prefix="(i)">Authorizes the licensee to practice dentistry to the same extent as other faculty members who hold general licenses to practice dentistry, provided that the licensee only practices dentistry at established teaching sites and faculty programs of the University of Maryland Dental School; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Shall be surrendered immediately to the Board when the licensee ceases to hold an appointment as a full-time or part-time faculty member of the University of Maryland Dental School.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
