<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gho" order_by="gho" level="1">Health Occupations</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gho-1A-101</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this title the following words have the meanings indicated....</catch_line>
  <order_by>101</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this title the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Acupuncture" means a form of health care, based on a theory of energetic physiology, that describes the interrelationship of the body organs or functions with an associated point or combination of points.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Auricular detoxification" means an acupuncture technique involving the needling of the external auricle of the human ear for the purpose of assisting a person who is undergoing detoxification to remove addictive substances from the body and restoring health.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">"Board" means the State Acupuncture Board.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"License" means, unless the context requires otherwise, a license issued by the Board to practice acupuncture.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Practice acupuncture" means the use of oriental medical therapies for the purpose of normalizing energetic physiological functions including pain control, and for the promotion, maintenance, and restoration of health.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Practice acupuncture" includes:<section prefix="(i)">Stimulation of points of the body by the insertion of acupuncture needles;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The application of moxibustion; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Manual, mechanical, thermal, or electrical therapies only when performed in accordance with the principles of oriental acupuncture medical theories.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">"Supervision" means:<section prefix="(1)">A formalized professional relationship between a licensed acupuncturist and an individual performing auricular detoxification that provides evaluation and direction of the individual to adequately ensure the safety and welfare of clients during the course of treatment; and</section><section prefix="(2)">As defined by the Board in regulations:<section prefix="(i)">Periodic direct supervision where the licensed acupuncturist is present or on-site during treatment; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">General supervision where the licensed acupuncturist is neither present nor on-site during treatment.</section></section></section>
  </text>
</law>
