<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gho" order_by="" level="1">Health Occupations</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gho-14-503</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>503</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">A physician may not represent to the public that the physician is certified by a public or private board, including a multidisciplinary board, or that the physician is board certified unless:<section prefix="(1)">The physician discloses the full name of the board from which the physician is certified and the name of the specialty or subspecialty in which the physician is certified; and</section><section prefix="(2)">The certifying board meets one of the following requirements:<section prefix="(i)">The certifying board is:<section prefix="1.">A member of the American Board of Medical Specialties; or</section><section prefix="2.">An American Osteopathic Association certifying board;</section></section><section prefix="(ii)">The certifying board has been approved by the Board; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">The certifying board requires that, in order to be certified, the physician:<section prefix="1.">Complete a postgraduate training program that:</section><section prefix="2.">Be certified by the member board of the American Board of Medical Specialties or the American Osteopathic Association in the training field.</section></section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Board may approve a certifying board under subsection (a)(2)(ii) of this section only if the certifying board requires that, in order to be certified, the physician:<section prefix="(1)">Complete a postgraduate training program that:<section prefix="(i)">Provides complete training in the specialty or subspecialty being certified; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Is accredited by the Accreditation Council for Graduate Medical Education or the American Osteopathic Association; and</section></section><section prefix="(2)">Be certified by the American Board of Medical Specialties or American Osteopathic Association in the same training field.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A physician may advertise only as permitted by the rules and regulations of the Board and subject to subsection (a) of this section.</section>
  </text>
</law>
