<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gho" order_by="" level="1">Health Occupations</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gho-8-508</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>508</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Nurse practitioner" means a registered nurse who is:<section prefix="(i)">Certified as a nurse practitioner; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Authorized to prescribe drugs under regulations adopted by the State Board of Nursing.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Starter dosage" means an amount of drug sufficient to begin therapy:<section prefix="(i)">Of short duration of 72 hours or less; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">Prior to obtaining a larger quantity of the drug to complete therapy.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">"Personally prepare and dispense" means that a nurse practitioner:<section prefix="(i)">Is physically present on the premises where the prescription is filled; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Performs a final check of the prescription before it is provided to the patient.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A nurse practitioner may personally prepare and dispense a starter dosage of any drug the nurse practitioner is authorized to prescribe to a patient of the nurse practitioner if:<section prefix="(1)">The starter dosage complies with the labeling requirements of &#xA7; 12-505 of this article;</section><section prefix="(2)">No charge is made for the starter dosage; and</section><section prefix="(3)">The nurse practitioner enters an appropriate record in the patient's medical record.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">In accordance with the provisions of subsection (d) of this section, a nurse practitioner may personally prepare and dispense any drug that a nurse practitioner may prescribe to the extent permitted by law in the course of treating a patient at:<section prefix="(1)">A medical facility or clinic that specializes in the treatment of medical cases reimbursable through workers' compensation insurance;</section><section prefix="(2)">A medical facility or clinic that is operated on a nonprofit basis;</section><section prefix="(3)">A health center that operates on a campus of an institution of higher education;</section><section prefix="(4)">A public health facility, a medical facility under contract with a State or local health department, or a facility funded with public funds; or</section><section prefix="(5)">A nonprofit hospital or a nonprofit hospital outpatient facility as authorized under the policies established by the hospital.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A nurse practitioner who personally prepares and dispenses a drug in the course of treating a patient as authorized under subsection (c) of this section shall:<section prefix="(1)">Comply with the labeling requirements of &#xA7; 12-505 of this article;</section><section prefix="(2)">Record the dispensing of the prescription drug on the patient's chart;</section><section prefix="(3)">Allow the Division of Drug Control to enter and inspect the nurse practitioner's office at all reasonable hours; and</section><section prefix="(4)">Except for starter dosages or samples dispensed without charge, provide the patient with a written prescription, maintain prescription files, and maintain a separate file for Schedule II prescriptions for a period of at least 5 years.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
