<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gho" order_by="gho" level="1">Health Occupations</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gho-5-302</section_number>
  <catch_line>To qualify for a license, an applicant shall be an individual who meets the requirements of this sec...</catch_line>
  <order_by>302</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">To qualify for a license, an applicant shall be an individual who meets the requirements of this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The applicant must be of good moral character.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The applicant must be at least 18 years old.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The applicant for licensure as a dietitian-nutritionist shall:<section prefix="(1)"><section prefix="(i)"><section prefix="1.">Have satisfactorily completed academic requirements for the field of dietetics as approved by the Board; and</section><section prefix="2.">Have received a baccalaureate degree from a college or university accredited by an educational accrediting association recognized by the Council on Higher Education and Accreditation; or</section></section><section prefix="(ii)">Have received a master's or doctoral degree from a college or university accredited by an educational accrediting association recognized by the Council on Higher Education and Accreditation in nutritional sciences (with emphasis in human nutrition), food and nutrition, dietetics, human nutrition, community nutrition, public health nutrition, or equivalent training approved by the Board;</section></section><section prefix="(2)">Have satisfactorily completed a program of supervised clinical experience approved by the Board; and</section><section prefix="(3)"><section prefix="(i)">Submit to the Board proof of certification by the Certification Board for Nutritional Specialists; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">Submit to the Board proof of registration with the Commission on Dietetic Registration of the American Dietetic Association.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">Except as otherwise provided in this subtitle, the applicant must pass an examination approved by the Board under this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The applicant shall meet any other qualifications or requirements that the Board establishes for license applicants.</section>
  </text>
</law>
