<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gho" order_by="gho" level="1">Health Occupations</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gho-8-317</section_number>
  <catch_line>Except as otherwise provided in the Administrative Procedure Act and in subsection (g) of this secti...</catch_line>
  <order_by>317</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Except as otherwise provided in the Administrative Procedure Act and in subsection (g) of this section, before the Board takes any action under &#xA7; 8-312 or &#xA7; 8-316 of this subtitle or &#xA7; 8-404 or &#xA7; 8-6A-10 of this title, it shall give the person against whom the action is contemplated an opportunity for a hearing before the Board.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Board shall give notice and hold the hearing in accordance with the Administrative Procedure Act.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The hearing notice to be given to the person shall be sent by certified mail, return receipt requested, bearing a postmark from the United States Postal Service, to the last known address of the person at least 30 days before the hearing.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The person may be represented at the hearing by counsel.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">If after due notice the individual against whom the action is contemplated fails or refuses to appear, nevertheless the Board may hear and determine the matter.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Over the signature of the president, the executive director, or the deputy director as authorized by the executive director of the Board, the Board may issue subpoenas and administer oaths in connection with any investigation under this title and any hearings or proceedings before it.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If a person, without lawful excuse, disobeys a subpoena from the Board or an order by the Board to take an oath, testify, or answer questions, on petition of the Board a court of competent jurisdiction may compel compliance with the subpoena and hold the individual in contempt of court.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">The Board may immediately suspend the license of a registered nurse or licensed practical nurse who is expelled from the rehabilitation program under &#xA7; 8-208 of this title for noncompliance with the nurse's agreement if:<section prefix="(1)">Prior to suspending the license, the Board provides the nurse with an opportunity to show cause by written communication or nontestimonial presentation as to why the suspension should not occur; and</section><section prefix="(2)">The Board provides the nurse with an opportunity for a hearing, which:<section prefix="(i)">Shall occur within 30 days of written request by the nurse; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Shall impose on the licensee the burden of proving by a preponderance of the evidence that the licensee is not addicted to drugs or alcohol.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(h)">
      <section prefix="(1)">After the Board conducts an investigation under this title, the Board may issue an advisory letter to the licensee or certificate holder.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Board may disclose an advisory letter issued under this subsection to the public.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The issuance of an advisory letter under this subsection may not:<section prefix="(i)">Be considered a disciplinary action under &#xA7;&#xA7; 8-316 and 8-6A-10 of this title; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Be reported to any licensing entity, employer, or insurance company as a disciplinary action.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
