<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gho" order_by="" level="1">Health Occupations</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gho-14-207</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>207</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">There is a Board of Physicians Fund.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Board may set reasonable fees for the issuance and renewal of licenses and its other services.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The fees charged shall be set so as to approximate the cost of maintaining the Board.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Funds to cover the compensation and expenses of the Board members shall be generated by fees set under this section.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Board shall pay all fees collected under the provisions of this title to the Comptroller of the State.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">If the Governor does not include in the State budget at least $750,000 for the operation of the Health Personnel Shortage Incentive Grant Program under &#xA7; 18-803 of the Education Article and the Maryland Loan Assistance Repayment Program for Physicians under Title 18, Subtitle 28 of the Education Article, as administered by the Maryland Higher Education Commission, the Comptroller shall distribute:<section prefix="1.">Except as provided in subparagraph (ii) of this paragraph, 12 percent of the fees received from the Board to the Office of Student Financial Assistance to be used as follows:</section><section prefix="2.">The balance of the fees to the Board of Physicians Fund.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">For fiscal 2008, if the Governor does not include in the State budget the funds specified under subparagraph (i) of this paragraph, the Comptroller shall distribute 14 percent of the fees received from the Board to the Office of Student Financial Assistance to be used as provided under subparagraph (i) of this paragraph.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">If the Governor includes in the State budget at least $750,000 for the operation of the Health Personnel Shortage Incentive Grant Program under &#xA7; 18-803 of the Education Article and the Maryland Loan Assistance Repayment Program for Physicians of the Education Article, as administered by the Maryland Higher Education Commission, the Comptroller shall distribute the fees to the Board of Physicians Fund.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Fund shall be used exclusively to cover the actual documented direct and indirect costs of fulfilling the statutory and regulatory duties of the Board as provided by the provisions of this title.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The Fund is a continuing, nonlapsing fund, not subject to &#xA7; 7-302 of the State Finance and Procurement Article.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">Any unspent portions of the Fund may not be transferred or revert to the General Fund of the State, but shall remain in the Fund to be used for the purposes specified in this title.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Interest or other income earned on the investment of moneys in the Fund shall be paid into the Fund.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">No other State money may be used to support the Fund.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In addition to the requirements of subsection (d) of this section, the Board shall fund the budget of the Physician Rehabilitation Program with fees set, collected, and distributed to the Fund under this title.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">After review and approval by the Board of a budget submitted by the Physician Rehabilitation Program, the Board may allocate moneys from the Fund to the Physician Rehabilitation Program.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The chair of the Board or the designee of the chair shall administer the Fund.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Moneys in the Fund may be expended only for any lawful purpose authorized by the provisions of this title.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">The Legislative Auditor shall audit the accounts and transactions of the Fund as provided in &#xA7; 2-1220 of the State Government Article.</section>
  </text>
</law>
