<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gho" order_by="" level="1">Health Occupations</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gho-4-306</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>306</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"ADEX" means the American Board of Dental Examiners, Inc., or its successor organization.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">"ADLEX" means the American Dental Licensing Examination designed and developed by ADEX, or its successor examination.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">"ADLEX" includes a written component and a clinical component.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(4)">
        <section prefix="(i)">"ADHLEX" means the American Dental Hygiene Licensing Examination designed and developed by ADEX, or its successor examination.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">"ADHLEX" includes a written component and a clinical component.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A dentist licensed in any other state shall be issued a license in this State if the applicant:<section prefix="(i)"><section prefix="1.">Has passed the ADLEX; and</section><section prefix="2.">Has passed the Maryland Dental Jurisprudence Examination given by the Board or its designee; or</section></section><section prefix="(ii)"><section prefix="1.">For the 5 preceding years, has been actively engaged in practicing dentistry for at least 850 hours on average per year;</section><section prefix="2.">Has passed an examination with a clinical component as a requirement for licensure in another state;</section><section prefix="3.">Has passed a comprehensive written examination on applied clinical diagnosis and treatment planning administered by ADEX; and</section><section prefix="4.">Has passed the Maryland Dental Jurisprudence Examination given by the Board or its designee.</section></section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A dental hygienist licensed in any other state shall be issued a license in this State if the applicant:<section prefix="(i)"><section prefix="1.">Has passed the ADHLEX; and</section><section prefix="2.">Has passed the Maryland Dental Hygiene Jurisprudence Examination given by the Board or its designee; or</section></section><section prefix="(ii)"><section prefix="1.">For the 3 preceding years, has been actively engaged in practicing dental hygiene for at least 150 hours on average per year;</section><section prefix="2.">Has passed an examination with a clinical component as a requirement for licensure in another state;</section><section prefix="3.">Has passed a comprehensive written examination on applied clinical diagnosis and treatment planning administered by ADEX; and</section><section prefix="4.">Has passed the Maryland Dental Hygiene Jurisprudence Examination given by the Board or its designee.</section></section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Board may adopt regulations for the content and administration of examinations and any other regulations necessary to provide for the licensure of individuals who apply for a license to practice dentistry under subsection (b)(1) of this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Board may adopt regulations for the content and administration of examinations and any other regulations necessary to provide for the licensure of individuals who apply for a license to practice dental hygiene under subsection (b)(2) of this section.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">An applicant for a general license to practice dentistry under this section shall:<section prefix="(1)">Pay the application fee required by &#xA7; 4-304 of this subtitle; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Provide adequate evidence that the applicant:<section prefix="(i)">Meets the qualifications otherwise required by this title for a general license to practice dentistry;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Holds a license to practice dentistry in another state;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Has satisfied the examination requirements provided in subsection (b)(1) of this section;</section><section prefix="(iv)">	Is not being investigated by a disciplinary authority of another state, does not have charges pending against the applicant's license, and has not been disciplined by a disciplinary or licensing authority of any other state or country, or been convicted or disciplined by a court of any state or country for an act that would be grounds for disciplinary action under &#xA7; 4-315 of this subtitle; and</section><section prefix="(v)">	Has not previously failed an examination for licensure as a dentist in this State.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">An applicant for a general license to practice dental hygiene under this section shall:<section prefix="(1)">Pay the application fee required by &#xA7; 4-304 of this subtitle; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Provide adequate evidence that the applicant:<section prefix="(i)">Meets the qualifications otherwise required by this title for a general license to practice dental hygiene;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Holds a license to practice dental hygiene in another state;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Has satisfied the examination requirements provided in subsection (b)(2) of this section;</section><section prefix="(iv)">	Is not being investigated by a disciplinary authority of another state, does not have charges pending against the applicant's license, and has not been disciplined by a disciplinary or licensing authority of any other state or country, or been convicted or disciplined by a court of any state or country for an act that would be grounds for disciplinary action under &#xA7; 4-315 of this subtitle; and</section><section prefix="(v)">	Has not previously failed an examination for licensure as a dental hygienist in this State.</section></section></section>
  </text>
</law>
