<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gho" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="3-316.1" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gho-3-316.1</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">An action may be maintained in the name of this State or the Board to enjoin:<section prefix="(1)">The unauthorized practice of chiropractic or massage therapy; or</section><section prefix="(2)">Conduct that is a ground for disciplinary action under &#xA7; 3-313 of this subtitle or &#xA7; 3-5A-11 of this title.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">An action under this section may be brought by:<section prefix="(1)">The Board, in its own name;</section><section prefix="(2)">The Attorney General, in the name of this State; or</section><section prefix="(3)">A State's Attorney, in the name of this State.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">An action under this section shall be brought in the county where the defendant:<section prefix="(1)">Resides; or</section><section prefix="(2)">Engages in the acts sought to be enjoined.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, an action under this section may not be brought against an individual who is authorized to practice a health occupation under this article.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">An action under this section may be brought against an individual who is authorized to practice chiropractic or massage therapy under this title.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">Proof of actual damage or that any person will sustain any damage if an injunction is not granted is not required for an action under this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">An action under this section is in addition to and not instead of criminal prosecution for:<section prefix="(1)">The unauthorized practice of chiropractic under &#xA7; 3-501 of this title or disciplinary action under &#xA7; 3-313 of this subtitle; or</section><section prefix="(2)">The unauthorized practice of massage therapy under &#xA7; 3-501 of this title or disciplinary action under &#xA7; 3-5A-11 of this title.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
