<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gho" order_by="gho" level="1">Health Occupations</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gho-12-6C-01</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this subtitle the following words have the meanings  indicated....</catch_line>
  <order_by>01</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this subtitle the following words have the meanings  indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Authenticate" means to affirmatively verify, before any  wholesale distribution of a prescription drug occurs, that each  transaction listed on the pedigree for the prescription drug has  occurred.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Authorized distributor of record" means a wholesale  distributor with whom a manufacturer has established an ongoing  relationship to distribute the manufacturer's prescription drug.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">"Co-licensed partner" means a person in a relationship in  which two or more persons have the right to engage in the  manufacturing or marketing of a prescription drug, consistent with  the U.S. Food and Drug Administration's implementation of the  federal Prescription Drug Marketing Act.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"Co-licensed product" means a product of co-licensed  partners.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">"Designated representative" means an individual who:<section prefix="(1)">Is designated by a wholesale distributor;</section><section prefix="(2)">Serves as the primary contact of the wholesale  distributor with the Board; and</section><section prefix="(3)">Is actively involved in and aware of the daily  operation of the wholesale distributor.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(g)">"Drop shipment" means the sale of a prescription drug:<section prefix="(1)">To a wholesale distributor by:<section prefix="(i)">The manufacturer of the prescription drug; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">The manufacturer's co-licensed partner, third  party logistics provider, or manufacturer's exclusive distributor;  and</section></section><section prefix="(2)">Through which:<section prefix="(i)">The wholesale distributor or a pharmacy  warehouse takes title to but not physical possession of the  prescription drug;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The wholesale distributor invoices the  pharmacy, pharmacy warehouse, or other person authorized by law  to dispense or administer the prescription drug to a patient; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">The pharmacy, pharmacy warehouse, or other  authorized person receives delivery of the prescription drug  directly from:<section prefix="1.">The manufacturer; or</section><section prefix="2.">The manufacturer's third party logistics  provider or the manufacturer's exclusive distributor.</section></section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(h)">"Facility" means a facility of a wholesale distributor  where prescription drugs are stored, handled, repackaged, or  offered for sale.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">"Intracompany sales" means a:<section prefix="(1)">Transaction or transfer of prescription drugs  between a division, subsidiary, parent, or affiliated or related  company under common ownership and control of a corporate  entity; or</section><section prefix="(2)">Transaction or transfer of a co-licensed product between co-licensed partners.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(j)">"Manufacturer" means a person licensed or approved by  the U.S. Food and Drug Administration to engage in the  manufacture of prescription drugs or prescription devices,  consistent with the definition of "manufacturer" under the U.S.  Food and Drug Administration's regulations and guidelines  implementing the Prescription Drug Marketing Act.</section>
    <section prefix="(k)">"Manufacturer's exclusive distributor" means a person  who:<section prefix="(1)">Contracts with a manufacturer to provide or  coordinate warehousing, distribution, or other services on behalf  of the manufacturer; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Takes title to the manufacturer's prescription  drug, but does not have general responsibility to direct the sale or  disposition of the manufacturer's prescription drug.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(l)">"Normal distribution channel" means a chain of custody  for a prescription drug that, directly or by drop shipment, goes:<section prefix="(1)">From:<section prefix="(i)">A manufacturer of the prescription drug; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">The manufacturer's co-licensed partner, third  party logistics provider, or manufacturer's exclusive distributor;  and</section></section><section prefix="(2)">To:<section prefix="(i)">A pharmacy or other designated person  authorized by law to dispense or administer the prescription drug  to a patient;</section><section prefix="(ii)">A wholesale distributor to a pharmacy or  other designated person authorized by law to dispense or  administer the prescription drug to a patient;</section><section prefix="(iii)">A wholesale distributor to a pharmacy  warehouse to the pharmacy warehouse's intracompany pharmacy or  other designated person authorized by law to dispense or  administer the prescription drug to a patient;</section><section prefix="(iv)">A pharmacy warehouse to the pharmacy  warehouse's intracompany pharmacy or other designated person  authorized by law to dispense or administer the prescription drug  to a patient; or</section><section prefix="(v)">An authorized distributor of record to  another authorized distributor of record solely for distribution  to an office-based health care practitioner authorized by law to  dispense or administer the prescription drug to a patient.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(m)">"Ongoing relationship" means a relationship that exists  between a wholesale distributor, including any affiliated group of  the wholesale distributor, as defined in &#xA7; 1504 of the Internal  Revenue Code, and a manufacturer when the wholesale distributor:<section prefix="(1)">Has a written agreement currently in effect with  the manufacturer evidencing the ongoing relationship; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Is listed on the manufacturer's current list of  authorized distributors of record.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(n)">"Pedigree" means a document or electronic file  containing information that records each wholesale distribution  of a prescription drug.</section>
    <section prefix="(o)">"Pharmacy warehouse" means a physical location for  storage of prescription drugs that:<section prefix="(1)">Serves as a central warehouse; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Performs intracompany sales or transfers of the  prescription drugs to a group of pharmacies that are under common  ownership and control with the pharmacy warehouse.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(p)">"Prescription device" means any device required by federal law or regulation to be dispensed only by a prescription.</section>
    <section prefix="(q)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Prescription drug" means any drug required by federal law or regulation to be dispensed only by a prescription.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Prescription drug" includes:<section prefix="(i)">A biological product; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Finished dosage forms and bulk drug substances subject to &#xA7; 503(b) of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Prescription drug" does not include blood and blood components intended for transfusion or biological products that are also medical devices.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(r)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Repackage" means to repackage or otherwise  change the container, wrapper, or labeling of a prescription drug  to further the distribution of the prescription drug.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Repackage" does not include changes to a  container, wrapper, or labeling of a prescription drug completed  by the pharmacist responsible for dispensing the prescription drug  to a patient.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(s)">"Repackager" means a person who repackages  prescription drugs.</section>
    <section prefix="(t)">"Third party logistics provider" means a person who:<section prefix="(1)">Contracts with a manufacturer to provide or  coordinate warehousing, distribution, or other services on behalf  of the manufacturer; but</section><section prefix="(2)">Does not take title to the prescription drug or have  general responsibility to direct the prescription drug's sale or  disposition.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(u)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Wholesale distribution" means the distribution of prescription drugs or prescription devices to persons other than a consumer or patient.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Wholesale distribution" does not include:<section prefix="(i)">Intracompany sales;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The sale, purchase, distribution, trade, or transfer of a prescription drug or an offer to sell, purchase, distribute, trade, or transfer a prescription drug for emergency medical reasons;</section><section prefix="(iii)">The sale, purchase, distribution, trade, or transfer of a prescription drug or prescription device by the Department for public health purposes;</section><section prefix="(iv)">The distribution of samples of a prescription drug by a manufacturer's representative;</section><section prefix="(v)">Prescription drug returns conducted by a hospital, health care entity, or charitable institution in accordance with 21 C.F.R. &#xA7; 203.23;</section><section prefix="(vi)">The sale of minimal quantities of prescription drugs by retail pharmacies to licensed health care practitioners for office use;</section><section prefix="(vii)">The sale, purchase, or trade of a prescription drug, an offer to sell, purchase, or trade a prescription drug, or the dispensing of a prescription drug in accordance with a prescription;</section><section prefix="(viii)">The sale, transfer, merger, or consolidation of all or part of the business of a pharmacy to or with another pharmacy, whether accomplished as a purchase and sale of stock or business assets;</section><section prefix="(ix)">The sale, purchase, distribution, trade, or transfer of a prescription drug from one authorized distributor of record to one additional authorized distributor of record if:<section prefix="1.">The manufacturer has stated in writing to the receiving authorized distributor of record that the manufacturer is unable to supply the prescription drug; and</section><section prefix="2.">The supplying authorized distributor of record states in writing that the prescription drug being supplied had until that time been exclusively in the normal distribution channel;</section></section><section prefix="(x)">The delivery of, or offer to deliver, a prescription drug by a common carrier solely in the common carrier's usual course of business of transporting prescription drugs, if the common carrier does not store, warehouse, or take legal ownership of the prescription drug; or</section><section prefix="(xi)">The sale or transfer from a retail pharmacy or pharmacy warehouse of expired, damaged, returned, or recalled prescription drugs to the original manufacturer or to a third party returns processor.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(v)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Wholesale distributor" means a person that is  engaged in the wholesale distribution of prescription drugs or  prescription devices.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Wholesale distributor" includes:<section prefix="(i)">A manufacturer;</section><section prefix="(ii)">A repackager;</section><section prefix="(iii)">An own-label distributor;</section><section prefix="(iv)">A private-label distributor;</section><section prefix="(v)">A jobber;</section><section prefix="(vi)">A broker;</section><section prefix="(vii)">A warehouse, including a manufacturer's or  distributor's warehouse;</section><section prefix="(viii)">A manufacturer's exclusive distributor or an  authorized distributor of record;</section><section prefix="(ix)">A drug wholesaler or distributor;</section><section prefix="(x)">An independent wholesale drug trader;</section><section prefix="(xi)">A third party logistics provider;</section><section prefix="(xii)">A retail pharmacy that conducts wholesale  distribution, if the wholesale distribution business accounts for  more than 5% of the retail pharmacy's annual sales; and</section><section prefix="(xiii)">A pharmacy warehouse that conducts  wholesale distribution.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(w)">"Wholesale distributor permit" means a permit issued by  the Board under this subtitle to distribute prescription drugs or  prescription devices into, out of, or within the State as a wholesale  distributor.</section>
  </text>
</law>
