<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gho" order_by="gho" level="1">Health Occupations</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gho-17-205</section_number>
  <catch_line>In addition to the powers set forth elsewhere in this title, the Board may adopt rules and regulatio...</catch_line>
  <order_by>205</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In addition to the powers set forth elsewhere in this title, the Board may adopt rules and regulations to carry out the provisions of this title.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">In addition to the duties set forth elsewhere in this title, the Board shall:<section prefix="(1)">Maintain a registry of all counselors or therapists currently licensed or certified by the Board and all individuals currently working as trainees in accordance with &#xA7; 17-406(b) of this title;</section><section prefix="(2)">Submit an annual report to the Governor and the Secretary;</section><section prefix="(3)">Adopt a code of ethics that the Board considers to be appropriate and applicable to the counselors or therapists currently certified or licensed by the Board and the individuals currently working as trainees in accordance with &#xA7; 17-406(b) of this title;</section><section prefix="(4)">Establish continuing education requirements for the counselors or therapists currently certified or licensed by the Board;</section><section prefix="(5)">Adopt an official seal; and</section><section prefix="(6)">Create committees as it deems appropriate to advise the Board on special issues.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Board may take action against a marriage and family therapist only if:<section prefix="(i)">Before taking action against the marriage and family therapist, the Board discusses the proposed action with a Board member who is a licensed clinical marriage and family therapist; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">A Board member who is a licensed clinical marriage and family therapist votes, either in the affirmative or in the negative, on the proposed action.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Board may take action against an alcohol and drug counselor only if:<section prefix="(i)">Before taking action against the alcohol and drug counselor, the Board discusses the proposed action with a Board member who is a licensed clinical alcohol and drug counselor; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">A Board member who is a licensed clinical alcohol and drug counselor votes, either in the affirmative or in the negative, on the proposed action.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Board shall investigate all complaints filed against licensed counselors and therapists if, at the time of the violation, the licensed counselor or therapist has also registered and qualified for psychology associate status by virtue of holding a master's degree under Title 18 (Maryland Psychologists Act) of this article.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The Board shall notify the Board of Examiners of Psychologists of the complaint in writing within 60 days of receipt of the complaint if an investigation of the supervising licensed psychologists is warranted.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">The Board shall initiate disciplinary action against any licensed counselor or therapist who also registers as a psychology associate and violates any portion of this statute.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Board shall establish or select examinations that the Board considers appropriate to determine the ability of an applicant to be licensed or certified by the Board.</section>
  </text>
</law>
