<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gho" order_by="" level="1">Health Occupations</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gho-15-101</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>101</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this title the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Alternate supervising physician" means one or more physicians designated by the primary supervising physician to provide supervision of a physician assistant in accordance with the delegation agreement on file with the Board.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Ambulatory surgical facility" means a facility:<section prefix="(1)">Accredited by:<section prefix="(i)">The American Association for Accreditation of Ambulatory Surgical Facilities;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The Accreditation Association for Ambulatory Health Care; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">The Joint Commission on Accreditation of Healthcare Organizations; or</section></section><section prefix="(2)">Certified to participate in the Medicare program, as enacted by Title XVIII of the Social Security Act.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">"Board" means the State Board of Physicians, established under &#xA7; 14-201 of this article.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"Committee" means the Physician Assistant Advisory Committee.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">"Controlled dangerous substances" has the meaning stated in &#xA7; 5-101 of the Criminal Law Article.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">"Correctional facility" includes a State or local correctional facility.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">"Delegated medical acts" means activities that constitute the practice of medicine delegated by a physician under Title 14 of this article.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">"Delegation agreement" means a document that is executed by a primary supervising physician and a physician assistant containing the requirements of &#xA7; 15-302 of this title.</section>
    <section prefix="(j)">"Dispense" means to dispense drug samples or starter dosages.</section>
    <section prefix="(k)">"Drug sample" means a unit of a prescription drug that is intended to promote the sale of the drug and is not intended for sale.</section>
    <section prefix="(l)">"Hospital" means:<section prefix="(1)">A hospital as defined under &#xA7; 19-301 of the Health - General Article;</section><section prefix="(2)">A comprehensive care facility that:<section prefix="(i)">Meets the requirements of a hospital-based skilled nursing facility under federal law; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Offers acute care in the same building; and</section></section><section prefix="(3)">An emergency room that is physically connected to a hospital or a freestanding medical facility that is licensed under Title 19, Subtitle 3A of the Health - General Article.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(m)">"License" means a license issued by the Board to a physician assistant under this title.</section>
    <section prefix="(n)">"National certifying examination" means the Physician Assistant National Certifying Examination administered by the National Commission on Certification of Physician Assistants or its successor.</section>
    <section prefix="(o)">"Physician assistant" means an individual who is licensed under this title to practice medicine with physician supervision.</section>
    <section prefix="(p)">"Practice as a physician assistant" means the performance of medical acts that are:<section prefix="(1)">Delegated by a supervising physician to a physician assistant;</section><section prefix="(2)">Within the supervising physician's scope of practice; and</section><section prefix="(3)">Appropriate to the physician assistant's education, training, and experience.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(q)">"Prescriptive authority" means the authority delegated by a primary or alternate supervising physician to a physician assistant to:<section prefix="(1)">Prescribe and administer controlled dangerous substances, prescription drugs, medical devices, and the oral, written, or electronic ordering of medications; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Dispense as provided under &#xA7; 15-302.2(b), (c), and (d) of this title.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(r)">"Primary supervising physician" means a physician who:<section prefix="(1)">Completes a delegation agreement that meets the requirements under &#xA7;&#xA7; 15-301(d) and (e) and 15-302 of this title and files a copy with the Board;</section><section prefix="(2)">Acts as the physician responsible to ensure that a physician assistant practices medicine in accordance with this title and the regulations adopted under this title;</section><section prefix="(3)">Ensures that a physician assistant practices within the scope of practice of the primary supervising physician or any designated alternate supervising physician; and</section><section prefix="(4)">Ensures that a list of alternate supervising physicians is maintained at the practice setting.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(s)">"Public health facility" means a site where clinical public health services are rendered under the auspices of the Department, a local health department in a county, or the Baltimore City Health Department.</section>
    <section prefix="(t)">"Starter dosage" means an amount of a drug sufficient to begin therapy:<section prefix="(1)">Of short duration of 72 hours or less; or</section><section prefix="(2)">Prior to obtaining a larger quantity of the drug to complete therapy.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(u)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Supervision" means the responsibility of a physician to exercise on-site supervision or immediately available direction for physician assistants performing delegated medical acts.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Supervision" includes physician oversight of and acceptance of direct responsibility for the patient services and care rendered by a physician assistant, including continuous availability to the physician assistant in person, through written instructions, or by electronic means and by designation of one or more alternate supervising physicians.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
