<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gho" order_by="gho" level="1">Health Occupations</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gho-2-305</section_number>
  <catch_line>The Board may waive any of the qualifications required for a license to practice audiology under thi...</catch_line>
  <order_by>305</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Board may waive any of the qualifications required for a license to practice audiology under this title for an individual who:<section prefix="(1)">Is of good moral character;</section><section prefix="(2)">Pays the application fee required by the Board under &#xA7; 2-303 of this subtitle; and</section><section prefix="(3)"><section prefix="(i)">Holds or has held a national certification in audiology from an organization if the organization is recognized by the Board and the qualifications for certification meet the practice requirements established by the regulations adopted by the Board;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Holds a current license to practice audiology in another state if the Board determines that the state has requirements for licensure that are at least equivalent to the requirements of this State and meet the practice requirements established under regulations adopted by the Board; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">On or before September 30, 2007, holds a current license to practice audiology in this or another state or practices audiology under the authority and supervision of an agency of the federal government or a board, agency, or department of this State or another state if:<section prefix="1.">The individual holds a master's degree in audiology from an accredited educational program;</section><section prefix="2.">The Board determines that the requirements for practice are at least equivalent to the requirements of this Board; and</section><section prefix="3.">The individual meets other requirements established by regulations adopted by the Board that may not include a requirement for a doctoral degree in audiology.</section></section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Board may waive any of the qualifications required for a license to practice speech-language pathology or to assist in the practice of speech-language pathology under this title for an individual who:<section prefix="(1)">Is of good moral character;</section><section prefix="(2)">Pays the application fee required by the Board under &#xA7; 2-303 of this subtitle; and</section><section prefix="(3)"><section prefix="(i)">Holds or has held a national certification in speech-language pathology or as an assistant of speech-language pathology from an organization if the organization is recognized by the Board and the qualifications for certification meet the practice requirements established by the regulations adopted by the Board; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">Holds a current license to practice speech-language pathology or to assist in the practice of speech-language pathology in another state that the Board determines has requirements for licensure and practice that are at least equivalent to the requirements established under regulations adopted by the Board.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Board may waive any examination requirement of this subtitle for an applicant for a license to practice audiology or speech-language pathology who:<section prefix="(1)">Pays the application fee required by the Board under &#xA7; 2-303 of this subtitle; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Provides adequate evidence that the applicant:<section prefix="(i)">Meets the qualifications otherwise required by this title; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Became licensed in the other state after meeting, in that or any other state, requirements that are at least equivalent to the licensing requirements of this State.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Board shall waive the examination requirements of this subtitle for an applicant for a license to practice hearing aid dispensing who is licensed to practice hearing aid dispensing in another state.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Board may grant a waiver under this subsection only if the applicant:<section prefix="(i)">Pays the application fee required under &#xA7; 2-303 of this subtitle; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Provides adequate evidence that the applicant:<section prefix="1.">Meets the qualifications otherwise required by this title;</section><section prefix="2.">Became licensed in the other state after meeting, in that or any other state, requirements that are at least equivalent to the licensing requirements of this State; and</section><section prefix="3.">Meets the practice requirements established by the regulations adopted by the Board.</section></section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Board may grant a waiver under this subsection if an applicant holds current national board certification as a hearing instrument specialist and meets the practice requirements established by regulations adopted by the Board.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
