<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gho" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="20-310" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gho-20-310</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A certificate expires on a date set by the Board, unless the certificate is renewed for an additional term as provided in this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A certificate may not be renewed for a term longer than 2 years.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">At least 1 month before the certificate expires, the Board shall send to the certified program administrator or certified residential child and youth care practitioner, by first-class mail to the last known address of the certified program administrator or certified residential child and youth care practitioner, a renewal notice that states:<section prefix="(1)">The date on which the current certificate expires;</section><section prefix="(2)">The date by which the renewal application must be received by the Board for the renewal to be issued and mailed before the certificate expires; and</section><section prefix="(3)">The amount of the renewal fee.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Before the certificate expires, the certified program administrator or certified residential child and youth care practitioner periodically may renew it for an additional 2-year term, if the certified program administrator or certified residential child and youth care practitioner:<section prefix="(1)">Otherwise is entitled to obtain a certificate;</section><section prefix="(2)">Pays to the Board a renewal fee set by the Board; and</section><section prefix="(3)">Submits to the Board:<section prefix="(i)">A renewal application on the form that the Board requires; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Satisfactory evidence of compliance with any continuing education and other qualifications and requirements set under this section for certificate renewal.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">In addition to any other qualifications and requirements established in consultation with the Children's Cabinet, the Board may set continuing education requirements as a condition for the renewal of certificates under this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The Board shall renew the certificate of each certified program administrator or certified residential child and youth care practitioner who meets the requirements of this section.</section>
  </text>
</law>
