<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gho" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="20-302.1" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gho-20-302.1</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">To qualify for a certificate as a residential child and youth care practitioner, an applicant shall be an individual who meets the requirements of this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The applicant shall be of good moral character.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The applicant shall have completed a State and national criminal history records check.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The applicant shall be:<section prefix="(1)">At least 21 years old; or</section><section prefix="(2)">At least 18 years old and have earned at least an associate's or bachelor's degree from an accredited college or university.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The applicant shall have:<section prefix="(1)">A high school diploma or equivalent and have successfully completed an approved training program;</section><section prefix="(2)">At least 2 years experience in the human service field and sponsorship from a certified program administrator; or</section><section prefix="(3)">An associate's or bachelor's degree from an accredited college or university.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, the applicant shall have successfully completed a training program approved under &#xA7; 20-302.2 of this subtitle.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">An applicant who has an associate's or bachelor's degree from an accredited college or university may be waived from the training program requirement, if the applicant passes an examination and meets other requirements established by the Board under this subtitle.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The Board shall establish requirements and procedures for waiving the training program requirement for an applicant under subparagraph (i) of this paragraph.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">The applicant shall pass an examination given by the Board under this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">The Board shall waive the education, experience, training, and examination requirements of this section for an applicant who:<section prefix="(1)">Applies for certification on or before October 1, 2015; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Presents to the Board satisfactory evidence that the applicant worked as a residential child and youth care practitioner in the State for at least 2 years before October 1, 2015.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
