<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gho" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="11-101" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gho-11-101</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this title the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Board" means the State Board of Examiners in Optometry.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Diagnostically certified optometrist" means a licensed optometrist who is certified by the Board to administer topical ocular diagnostic pharmaceutical agents to the extent permitted under &#xA7; 11-404 of this title.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">"License" means, unless the context requires otherwise, a license issued by the Board to practice optometry.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"Licensed optometrist" means, unless the context requires otherwise, an optometrist who is licensed by the Board to practice optometry.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">"Optometrist" means an individual who practices optometry.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Practice optometry" means:<section prefix="(i)">Subject to &#xA7;&#xA7; 11-404 and 11-404.2 of this title, to use any means known in the science of optics or eye care, except surgery:</section><section prefix="(ii)">To give advice or direction on the fitness or adaptation of eyeglasses or lenses to any individual for the correction or relief of a condition for which eyeglasses or lenses are worn; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">To use or permit the use of any instrument, test card, test type, test eyeglasses, test lenses, or other device to aid in choosing eyeglasses or lenses for an individual to wear.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Subject to &#xA7;&#xA7; 11-404 and 11-404.2 of this title, "practice optometry" includes:<section prefix="(i)">The administration of topical ocular diagnostic pharmaceutical agents;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The administration and prescription of therapeutic pharmaceutical agents; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">The removal of superficial foreign bodies from the cornea and conjunctiva.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(h)">"Therapeutically certified optometrist" means a licensed optometrist who is certified by the Board to practice optometry to the extent permitted under &#xA7; 11-404.2 of this title.</section>
  </text>
</law>
