<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gho" order_by="gho" level="1">Health Occupations</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gho-4-307</section_number>
  <catch_line>The Board shall issue the appropriate license to any applicant who meets the requirements of this ti...</catch_line>
  <order_by>307</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Board shall issue the appropriate license to any applicant who meets the requirements of this title for that license.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Board shall include on each license that the Board issues:<section prefix="(i)">The name of the licensee;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The date the license was issued;</section><section prefix="(iii)">A serial number;</section><section prefix="(iv)">The signatures of the president and secretary of the Board; and</section><section prefix="(v)">The seal of the Board.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">On a limited license to practice dentistry, the Board also shall include:<section prefix="(i)">The date the license expires, for a license that expires on the first anniversary of its effective date; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">The name of the institution or public health program at which the licensee is authorized to practice dentistry.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">On a teacher's license to practice dentistry, the Board also shall include the name of the college or university at which the licensee is a full-time or part-time faculty member.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">On a teacher's license to practice dental hygiene, the Board also shall include the name of the dental school at which the licensee is a full-time or part-time faculty member.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Board shall issue a license to replace a lost or destroyed license if the licensee pays a fee set by the Board that approximates the actual cost of replacing the license.</section>
  </text>
</law>
