<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gho" order_by="gho" level="1">Health Occupations</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gho-1-208</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this section the following words have the meanings indicated....</catch_line>
  <order_by>208</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Except as otherwise provided in this paragraph, "health care practitioner" means a physician or any other person licensed or certified under this article and reimbursed by a third party payor.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">Subject to the provisions of subparagraph (iii) of this paragraph, "health care practitioner" does not include a physician or other person licensed or certified under this article who is compensated by a health maintenance organization on a salaried or capitated basis.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">The exclusion provided under subparagraph (ii) of this paragraph only applies when the physician or other licensed or certified person is rendering care to a member or subscriber of the health maintenance organization on a salaried or capitated system basis.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Third party payor" means any person that administers or provides reimbursement for health care benefits on an expense incurred basis including:<section prefix="(i)">A health maintenance organization issued a certificate of authority in accordance with Title 19, Subtitle 7 of the Health - General Article;</section><section prefix="(ii)">A health insurer or nonprofit health service plan authorized to offer health insurance policies or contracts in this State in accordance with the Insurance Article; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">A third party administrator registered under the Insurance Article.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">"Uniform claims form" means the claim or billing form for reimbursement of services rendered by a health care practitioner adopted by the Insurance Commissioner under &#xA7; 15-1003 of the Insurance Article.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">When submitting a claim or bill for reimbursement to a third party payor, a health care practitioner shall use the uniform claims form.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The uniform claims form submitted under this section:<section prefix="(1)">Shall be properly completed; and</section><section prefix="(2)">May be submitted by electronic transfer.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Secretary may impose a penalty not to exceed $100 on any health care practitioner that violates the provisions of this section.</section>
  </text>
</law>
