<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gho" order_by="" level="1">Health Occupations</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gho-14-411</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>411</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, "record" means the proceedings, records, or files of the Board.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Except as otherwise expressly provided in this section and &#xA7; 14-411.1 of this subtitle, the Board or any of its investigatory bodies may not disclose any information contained in a record.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Nothing in this section shall be construed to prevent or limit the disclosure of:<section prefix="(1)">General licensure, certification, or registration information maintained by the Board, if the request for release complies with the criteria of &#xA7; 10-617(h) of the State Government Article;</section><section prefix="(2)">Profile information collected and disseminated under &#xA7; 14-411.1 of this subtitle; or</section><section prefix="(3)">Personal and other identifying information of a licensee, as required by the National Practitioner Data Bank for participation in the proactive disclosure service.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Board shall disclose any information contained in a record to:<section prefix="(1)">A committee of a hospital, health maintenance organization, or related institution if:<section prefix="(i)">The committee of a medical hospital staff concerned with physician discipline or other committee of a hospital, health maintenance organization, or related institution requests the information in writing;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The Board has issued an order as to a licensed physician on whom the information is requested; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">The Board determines that the information requested is necessary for an investigation or action of the committee as to a medical privilege of a licensed physician; or</section></section><section prefix="(2)">The Secretary, the Office of Health Care Quality in the Department, or the Health Services Cost Review Commission for the purpose of investigating quality or utilization of care in any entity regulated by the Office of Health Care Quality or the Health Services Cost Review Commission.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">On or before January 1, 2013, the Board, the Secretary, the Maryland Health Care Commission, and the Health Services Cost Review Commission jointly shall adopt regulations for the efficient and secure transfer, under subsection (d)(2) of this section, of any information in a record that may indicate that an investigation of an entity regulated by the Office of Health Care Quality, the Maryland Health Care Commission, or the Health Services Cost Review Commission may be appropriate.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">Subsection (d)(2) of this section may not be construed to alter the authority of the Secretary under &#xA7; 1-203(a) of this article or &#xA7; 2-106(c) of the Health - General Article.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Board shall notify all hospitals, health maintenance organizations, or other health care facilities where a physician or an allied health professional regulated by the Board has privileges, has a provider contract with a health maintenance organization, or is employed of a complaint or report filed against that physician, if:<section prefix="(i)">The Board determines, in its discretion, that the hospital, health maintenance organization, or health care facility should be informed about the report or complaint;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The nature of the complaint suggests a reasonable possibility of an imminent threat to patient safety; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">The complaint or report was as a result of a claim filed in the Health Care Alternative Dispute Resolution Office and a certificate of a qualified expert is filed in accordance with &#xA7; 3-2A-04(b)(1) of the Courts Article.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Board shall disclose any information pertaining to a physician's competency to practice medicine contained in record to a committee of a hospital, health maintenance organization, or other health care facility if:<section prefix="(i)">The committee is concerned with physician discipline and requests the information in writing; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">The Board has received a complaint or report pursuant to paragraph (1)(i) and (ii) of this subsection on the licensed physician on whom the information is requested.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Board shall, after formal action is taken pursuant to &#xA7; 14-406 of this subtitle, notify those hospitals, health maintenance organizations, or health care facilities where the physician has privileges, has a provider contract with a health maintenance organization, or is employed of its formal action within 10 days after the action is taken and shall provide the hospital, health maintenance organization, or health care facility with periodic reports as to enforcement or monitoring of a formal disciplinary order against a physician within 10 days after receipt of those reports.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(h)">On the request of a person who has made a complaint to the Board regarding a physician, the Board shall provide the person with information on the status of the complaint.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">Following the filing of charges or notice of initial denial of license application, the Board shall disclose the filing to the public.</section>
    <section prefix="(j)">The Board may disclose any information contained in a record to a licensing or disciplinary authority of another state if:<section prefix="(1)">The licensing or disciplinary authority of another state that regulates licensed physicians in that state requests the information in writing; and</section><section prefix="(2)">The disclosure of any information is limited to the pendency of an allegation of a ground for disciplinary or other action by the Board until:<section prefix="(i)">The Board has passed an order under &#xA7; 14-406 of this subtitle; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">A licensed physician on whom the information is requested authorizes a disclosure as to the facts of an allegation or the results of an investigation before the Board.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(k)">The Board may disclose any information contained in a record to a person if:<section prefix="(1)">A licensed physician on whom any information is requested authorizes the person to receive the disclosure;</section><section prefix="(2)">The person requests the information in writing; and</section><section prefix="(3)">The authorization for the disclosure is in writing.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(l)">The Board may disclose any information contained in a record to the State Medical Assistance Compliance Administration, the Secretary of the U.S. Department of Health and Human Services or the Secretary's designee, or any health occupational regulatory board if:<section prefix="(1)"><section prefix="(i)">The State Medical Assistance Compliance Administration or any health occupational regulatory board requests the information in writing; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">The Secretary of the U.S. Department of Health and Human Services or the Secretary's designee is entitled to receive the information or have access to the information under 42 U.S.C. &#xA7; 1396r-2;</section></section><section prefix="(2)"><section prefix="(i)">The Board has issued an order under &#xA7; 14-406 of this subtitle; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">An allegation is pending before the Board; and</section></section><section prefix="(3)">The Board determines that the requested information is necessary for the proper conduct of the business of that administration or board.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(m)">If the Board determines that the information contained in a record concerns possible criminal activity, the Board shall disclose the information to a law enforcement or prosecutorial official.</section>
    <section prefix="(n)">The Board may permit inspection of records for which inspection otherwise is not authorized by a person who is engaged in a research project if:<section prefix="(1)">The researcher submits to the executive director and the Board approves a written request that:<section prefix="(i)">Describes the purpose of the research project;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Describes the intent, if any, to publish the findings;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Describes the nature of the requested personal records;</section><section prefix="(iv)">Describes the safeguards that the researcher would take to protect the identity of the persons in interest; and</section><section prefix="(v)">States that persons in interest will not be contacted unless the executive director approves and monitors the contact;</section></section><section prefix="(2)">The executive director is satisfied that the proposed safeguards will prevent the disclosure of the identity of persons in interest; and</section><section prefix="(3)">The researcher makes an agreement with the executive director that:<section prefix="(i)">Defines the scope of the research project;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Sets out the safeguards for protecting the identity of the persons in interest; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">States that a breach of any condition of the agreement is a breach of contract.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(o)">On the request of a person who has testified in a Board or Office of Administrative Hearings proceeding, the Board shall provide to the person who testified a copy of the portion of the transcript of that person's testimony.</section>
    <section prefix="(p)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Board may publish a summary of any allegations of grounds for disciplinary or other action.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A summary may not identify:<section prefix="(i)">Any person who makes an allegation to the Board or any of its investigatory bodies;</section><section prefix="(ii)">A licensed physician about whom an allegation is made; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">A witness in an investigation or a proceeding before the Board or any of its investigatory bodies.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(q)">The Board shall disclose information in a record upon the request of the Governor, Secretary, or Legislative Auditor, in accordance with &#xA7; 2-1223(a) of the State Government Article. However, the Governor, Secretary, or Auditor, or any of their employees may not disclose personally identifiable information from any of these records which are otherwise confidential by law.</section>
    <section prefix="(r)">This section does not apply to:<section prefix="(1)">Any disclosure of a record by the Board to any of its investigatory bodies; or</section><section prefix="(2)">A licensee, certificate holder, or registration holder who has been charged under this title or a party to a proceeding before the Board who claims to be aggrieved by the decision of the Board.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(s)">If any information contained in any medical or hospital document or any other exhibit is otherwise open for disclosure under law, the use of that document or exhibit in any record of the Board or any of its investigatory bodies does not prevent its disclosure in any other proceeding.</section>
  </text>
</law>
