<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gho" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="14-321" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gho-14-321</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Practice osteopathy" means to treat a disease or ailment of the human body by manipulation.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Restricted license" means a license issued by the Board to practice osteopathy.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Board shall issue a restricted license only to an applicant who:<section prefix="(1)">Was licensed to practice osteopathy in this State or in another state on June 30, 1980;</section><section prefix="(2)">Is licensed to practice osteopathy in this State or in another state on the date that the application for a restricted license is submitted to the Board;</section><section prefix="(3)">Submits an application to the Board on the form that the Board requires;</section><section prefix="(4)">Pays to the Board the restricted license fee set by the Board; and</section><section prefix="(5)">Meets any other requirement set by the Board.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A restricted license authorizes the license holder to practice osteopathy while the restricted license is effective.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The term and renewal of a restricted license shall be as provided for a license under &#xA7; 14-316 of this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Subject to the requirements of the Administrative Procedure Act, the Board on the affirmative vote of a majority of its quorum, may reprimand a restricted license holder, may place any restricted license holder on probation, or suspend or revoke a restricted license for any of the grounds for Board action under &#xA7; 14-404 of this title.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Board may only dismiss a case against a restricted license holder on the affirmative vote of a majority of its quorum.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
