<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gho" order_by="" level="1">Health Occupations</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gho-14-5E-01</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>01</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Board" means the State Board of Physicians.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Committee" means the Perfusion Advisory Committee established under &#xA7; 14-5E-05 of this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">"License" means a license issued by the Board to practice perfusion.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"Licensed perfusionist" means a perfusionist who is licensed by the Board under this subtitle to practice perfusion.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Practice perfusion" means to perform the functions necessary for the support, treatment, measurement, or supplementation of the cardiovascular, circulatory, or respiratory systems, or other organs to ensure the safe management of physiologic functions by monitoring and analyzing the parameters of the systems under an order and the supervision of a licensed physician.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Practice perfusion" includes:<section prefix="(i)">Cardiopulmonary bypass for adult, pediatric, and neonatal patients;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Extracorporeal circulatory support for renal, neurological, hepatic, and vascular surgery;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Extracorporeal resuscitation;</section><section prefix="(iv)">Extracorporeal circulation for long-term support of failing respiratory or cardiac function;</section><section prefix="(v)">Extracorporeal membrane oxygenation;</section><section prefix="(vi)">Extracorporeal carbon dioxide removal;</section><section prefix="(vii)">Myocardial protection;</section><section prefix="(viii)">Perfusion-assisted direct coronary artery bypass;</section><section prefix="(ix)">Hemofiltration and hemodialysis;</section><section prefix="(x)">Anticoagulation and hemostasis monitoring, analysis, and intervention;</section><section prefix="(xi)">Thermal regulation;</section><section prefix="(xii)">Blood gas and blood chemistry monitoring, analysis, and intervention;</section><section prefix="(xiii)">Physiological monitoring, analysis, and intervention;</section><section prefix="(xiv)">Administration of blood components and pharmaceuticals;</section><section prefix="(xv)">Administration of anesthetic agents through a heart lung machine at the direction of an anesthesiologist;</section><section prefix="(xvi)">Ventricular assist device and mechanical circulatory support management;</section><section prefix="(xvii)">Intra-aortic balloon counterpulsation;</section><section prefix="(xviii)">Temporary pacemaker management;</section><section prefix="(xix)">Periodic flow augmentation therapy;</section><section prefix="(xx)">Autotransfusion;</section><section prefix="(xxi)">Platelet gel production, autologous hemocyte tissue matrix production;</section><section prefix="(xxii)">Nondifferentiated progenitor cell harvest bone marrow aspirate concentrate;</section><section prefix="(xxiii)">Acute normovolemic hemodilution;</section><section prefix="(xxiv)">Isolated limb or organ delivery of chemotherapeutics, progenitor cells, gene therapy vectors, and other items;</section><section prefix="(xxv)">Organ procurement and preservation;</section><section prefix="(xxvi)">Thermogenic lavage;</section><section prefix="(xxvii)">Electrophysiological analysis;</section><section prefix="(xxviii)">Therapeutic hyperthermia;</section><section prefix="(xxix)">Intravascular membrane oxygenation; and</section><section prefix="(xxx)">Renal perfusion.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">"Student" means an individual who, in accordance with &#xA7; 14-5E-09(c) of this subtitle, is:<section prefix="(1)">Enrolled in an accredited educational program to qualify for a license under this subtitle; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Performing perfusion services within the accredited program under the supervision of a licensed perfusionist and without compensation.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(h)">"Supervision" means the responsibility of a licensed physician to exercise on site or immediately available direction for a licensed perfusionist to ensure the safety and welfare of patients during the course of perfusion.</section>
  </text>
</law>
