<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gho" order_by="gho" level="1">Health Occupations</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gho-20-101</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this title the following words have the meanings indicated....</catch_line>
  <order_by>101</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this title the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Agency" means:<section prefix="(i)">The Developmental Disabilities Administration in the Department;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The Department;</section><section prefix="(iii)">The Department of Human Resources;</section><section prefix="(iv)">The Department of Juvenile Services; and</section><section prefix="(v)">The Mental Hygiene Administration in the Department.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Agency" includes the State Superintendent of Schools.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Board" means the State Board for Certification of Residential Child Care Program Professionals.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">"Certificate" means, unless the context requires otherwise, a certificate issued by the Board to practice as a program administrator or as a residential child and youth care practitioner.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"Certified program administrator" means, unless the context requires otherwise, an individual who is certified by the Board to practice as a program administrator.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">"Certified residential child and youth care practitioner" means, unless the context requires otherwise, an individual who is certified by the Board to practice as a residential child and youth care practitioner.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">"Program administrator" means the individual responsible for the day-to-day management and operation of a residential child care program and for assuring the care, treatment, safety, and protection of the children in the residential child care program.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Residential child and youth care practitioner" means an individual assigned to perform direct responsibilities related to activities of daily living, self-help, and socialization skills in a residential child care program under the direction of a certified program administrator.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Residential child and youth care practitioner" does not include an individual assigned to perform direct responsibilities related to activities of daily living, self-help, and socialization skills in a residential child care program licensed by the Developmental Disabilities Administration.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(i)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Residential child care program" means an entity that provides for children 24-hour per day care within a structured set of services and activities that are designed to achieve specific objectives relative to the needs of the children served and that include the provision of food, clothing, shelter, education, social services, health, mental health, recreation, or any combination of these services and activities.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Residential child care program" includes a program:<section prefix="(i)">Licensed by:<section prefix="1.">The Department of Health and Mental Hygiene;</section><section prefix="2.">The Department of Human Resources; or</section><section prefix="3.">The Department of Juvenile Services; and</section></section><section prefix="(ii)">That is subject to the licensing regulations of the Governor's Office for Children governing the operations of residential child care programs.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
