<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gho" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="14-307" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gho-14-307</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">To qualify for a license, an applicant shall be an individual who meets the requirements of this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The applicant shall be of good moral character.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The applicant shall be at least 18 years old.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Except as provided in &#xA7; 14-308 of this subtitle, the applicant shall:<section prefix="(1)"><section prefix="(i)">Have a degree of doctor of medicine from a medical school that is accredited by an accrediting organization that the Board recognizes in its regulations; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Submit evidence acceptable to the Board of successful completion of 1 year of training in a postgraduate medical training program that is accredited by an accrediting organization that the Board recognizes in its regulations; or</section></section><section prefix="(2)"><section prefix="(i)">Have a degree of doctor of osteopathy from a school of osteopathy in the United States, its territories or possessions, Puerto Rico, or Canada that has standards for graduation equivalent to those established by the American Osteopathic Association; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Submit evidence acceptable to the Board of successful completion of 1 year of training in a postgraduate medical training program accredited by an accrediting organization that the Board recognizes in its regulations.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">Except as otherwise provided in this title, the applicant shall pass an examination required by the Board under this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The applicant shall meet any other qualifications that the Board establishes in its regulations for license applicants.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">An applicant who has failed the examination or any part of the examination 3 or more times shall submit evidence of having completed 1 year of additional clinical training in an approved postgraduate training program following the latest failure.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Board shall require as part of its examination or licensing procedures that an applicant for a license to practice medicine demonstrate an oral competency in the English language.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Graduation from a recognized English-speaking undergraduate school or high school, including General Education Development (GED), after at least 3 years of enrollment, or from a recognized English-speaking professional school is acceptable as proof of proficiency in the oral communication of the English language under this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">By regulation, the Board shall develop a procedure for testing individuals who because of their speech impairment are unable to complete satisfactorily a Board approved standardized test of oral competency.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">If any disciplinary charges or action that involves a problem with the oral communication of the English language are brought against a licensee under this title, the Board shall require the licensee to take and pass a Board approved standardized test of oral competency.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
