<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gho" order_by="" level="1">Health Occupations</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gho-15-302</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>302</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">A physician may delegate medical acts to a physician assistant only after:<section prefix="(1)">A delegation agreement has been executed and filed with the Board; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Any advanced duties have been authorized as required under subsection (c) of this section.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The delegation agreement shall contain:<section prefix="(1)">A description of the qualifications of the primary supervising physician and physician assistant;</section><section prefix="(2)">A description of the settings in which the physician assistant will practice;</section><section prefix="(3)">A description of the continuous physician supervision mechanisms that are reasonable and appropriate to the practice setting;</section><section prefix="(4)">A description of the delegated medical acts that are within the primary or alternate supervising physician's scope of practice and require specialized education or training that is consistent with accepted medical practice;</section><section prefix="(5)">An attestation that all medical acts to be delegated to the physician assistant are within the scope of practice of the primary or alternate supervising physician and appropriate to the physician assistant's education, training, and level of competence;</section><section prefix="(6)">An attestation of continuous supervision of the physician assistant by the primary supervising physician through the mechanisms described in the delegation agreement;</section><section prefix="(7)">An attestation by the primary supervising physician of the physician's acceptance of responsibility for any care given by the physician assistant;</section><section prefix="(8)">A description prepared by the primary supervising physician of the process by which the physician assistant's practice is reviewed appropriate to the practice setting and consistent with current standards of acceptable medical practice;</section><section prefix="(9)">An attestation by the primary supervising physician that the physician will respond in a timely manner when contacted by the physician assistant;</section><section prefix="(10)">The following statement: "The primary supervising physician and the physician assistant attest that:<section prefix="(i)">They will establish a plan for the types of cases that require a physician plan of care or require that the patient initially or periodically be seen by the supervising physician; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">The patient will be provided access to the supervising physician on request"; and</section></section><section prefix="(11)">Any other information deemed necessary by the Board to carry out the provisions of this subtitle.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Board may not require prior approval of a delegation agreement that includes advanced duties, if an advanced duty will be performed in a hospital or ambulatory surgical facility, provided that:<section prefix="(i)">A physician, with credentials that have been reviewed by the hospital or ambulatory surgical facility as a condition of employment, as an independent contractor, or as a member of the medical staff, supervises the physician assistant;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The physician assistant has credentials that have been reviewed by the hospital or ambulatory surgical facility as a condition of employment, as an independent contractor, or as a member of the medical staff; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Each advanced duty to be delegated to the physician assistant is reviewed and approved within a process approved by the governing body of the health care facility before the physician assistant performs the advanced duties.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">In any setting that does not meet the requirements of paragraph (1) of this subsection, a primary supervising physician shall obtain the Board's approval of a delegation agreement that includes advanced duties, before the physician assistant performs the advanced duties.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Notwithstanding paragraph (1) of this subsection, a primary supervising physician shall obtain the Board's approval of a delegation agreement before the physician assistant may administer, monitor, or maintain general anesthesia or neuroaxial anesthesia, including spinal and epidural techniques, under the agreement.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">For a delegation agreement containing advanced duties that require Board approval, the Committee shall review the delegation agreement and recommend to the Board that the delegation agreement be approved, rejected, or modified to ensure conformance with the requirements of this title.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The Committee may conduct a personal interview of the primary supervising physician and the physician assistant.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">On review of the Committee's recommendation regarding a primary supervising physician's request to delegate advanced duties as described in a delegation agreement, the Board:<section prefix="(i)">May approve the delegation agreement; or</section><section prefix="(ii)"><section prefix="1.">If the physician assistant does not meet the applicable education, training, and experience requirements to perform the specified delegated acts, may modify or disapprove the delegation agreement; and</section><section prefix="2.">If the Board takes an action under item 1 of this item:</section></section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">To the extent practicable, the Board shall approve a delegation agreement or take other action authorized under this subsection within 90 days after receiving a completed delegation agreement including any information from the physician assistant and primary supervising physician necessary to approve or take action.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">If the Board determines that a primary or alternate supervising physician or physician assistant is practicing in a manner inconsistent with the requirements of this title or Title 14 of this article, the Board on its own initiative or on the recommendation of the Committee may demand modification of the practice, withdraw the approval of the delegation agreement, or take other disciplinary action under &#xA7; 14-404 or &#xA7; 15-314 of this article.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">A primary supervising physician may not delegate medical acts under a delegation agreement to more than four physician assistants at any one time, except in a hospital or in the following nonhospital settings:<section prefix="(1)">A correctional facility;</section><section prefix="(2)">A detention center; or</section><section prefix="(3)">A public health facility.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(i)">A person may not coerce another person to enter into a delegation agreement under this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(j)">A physician may supervise a physician assistant:<section prefix="(1)">As a primary supervising physician in accordance with a delegation agreement approved by the Board under this subtitle; or</section><section prefix="(2)">As an alternate supervising physician if:<section prefix="(i)">The alternate supervising physician supervises in accordance with a delegation agreement filed with the Board;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The alternate supervising physician supervises no more than four physician assistants at any one time, except in a hospital, correctional facility, detention center, or public health facility;</section><section prefix="(iii)">The alternate supervising physician's period of supervision, in the absence of the primary supervising physician, does not exceed:<section prefix="1.">The period of time specified in the delegation agreement; and</section><section prefix="2.">A period of 45 consecutive days at any one time; and</section></section><section prefix="(iv)">The physician assistant performs only those medical acts that:<section prefix="1.">Have been delegated under the delegation agreement filed with the Board; and</section><section prefix="2.">Are within the scope of practice of the primary supervising physician and alternate supervising physician.</section></section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(k)">In the event of a sudden departure, incapacity, or death of a primary supervising physician, a designated alternate supervising physician may assume the role of the primary supervising physician by submitting a new delegation agreement to the Board within 15 days.</section>
    <section prefix="(l)">Individual members of the Board are not civilly liable for actions regarding the approval, modification, or disapproval of a delegation agreement described in this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(m)">A physician assistant may practice in accordance with a delegation agreement filed with the Board under this subtitle.</section>
  </text>
</law>
