<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gho" order_by="" level="1">Health Occupations</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gho-1A-202</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>202</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Board consists of seven members appointed by the Governor.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Of the seven members:<section prefix="(i)">Five shall be licensed acupuncturists appointed from a list submitted as provided in subsection (c) of this section; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Two shall be consumer members.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Each acupuncturist member shall:<section prefix="(1)">Be a resident of the State; and</section><section prefix="(2)">For at least 5 years immediately before appointment have been engaged in the practice of acupuncture in the State.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">For each vacancy of an acupuncture member, the Board shall compile a list of names to be submitted to the Governor in the following manner:<section prefix="(1)">The Board shall notify all licensed acupuncturists in the State of the vacancy to solicit nominations to fill the vacancy;</section><section prefix="(2)">Each professional association of acupuncturists in the State shall nominate at least one person for every two vacancies that exist; and</section><section prefix="(3)">Each educational institution that provides acupuncture training in the State shall nominate at least one person for every two vacancies that exist.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The consumer members:<section prefix="(1)">Shall be members of the general public;</section><section prefix="(2)">May not be or ever have been an acupuncturist or in training to become an acupuncturist;</section><section prefix="(3)">May not have a household member who is an acupuncturist or in training to become an acupuncturist;</section><section prefix="(4)">May not participate or ever have participated in a commercial or professional field related to acupuncture;</section><section prefix="(5)">May not have a household member who participates in a commercial or professional field related to acupuncture; and</section><section prefix="(6)">May not have had within 2 years before appointment a substantial financial interest in a person regulated by the Board.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">While a member of the Board, the consumer member may not have a substantial financial interest in a person regulated by the Board.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">Before taking office, each appointee to the Board shall take the oath required by Article I, &#xA7; 9 of the Maryland Constitution.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The term of a member is 4 years.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The terms of members are staggered as required by the terms provided for members of the Board on July 1, 1994.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">At the end of a term, a member continues to serve until a successor is appointed and qualifies.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">A member may not serve more than two consecutive full terms.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">A member who is appointed after a term has begun serves only for the rest of the term and until a successor is appointed and qualifies.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(h)">The Governor may remove a member for incompetence or misconduct.</section>
  </text>
</law>
