<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gho" order_by="" level="1">Health Occupations</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gho-14-414</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>414</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Every 6 months, each alternative health system as defined in &#xA7; 1-401 of this article shall file with the Board a report that:<section prefix="(i)">Contains the name of each licensed physician who, during the 6 months preceding the report:<section prefix="1.">Is employed by the alternative health system;</section><section prefix="2.">Is under contract with the alternative health system; and</section><section prefix="3.">Has completed a formal application process to become under contract with the alternative health system; and</section></section><section prefix="(ii)">States whether, as to each licensed physician, during the 6 months preceding the report:<section prefix="1.">The alternative health system denied the formal application of a physician to contract with the alternative health system or limited, reduced, otherwise changed, or terminated the contract of a physician, or the physician resigned whether or not under formal accusation, if the denial, limitation, reduction, change, termination, or resignation is for reasons that might be grounds for disciplinary action under &#xA7; 14-404 of this subtitle; or</section><section prefix="2.">The alternative health system placed any other restrictions or conditions on any licensed physician for any reasons that might be grounds for disciplinary action under &#xA7; 14-404 of this subtitle.</section></section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The alternative health system shall:<section prefix="(i)">Submit the report within 10 days of any action described in paragraph (1)(ii) of this subsection; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">State in the report the reasons for its action or the nature of the formal accusation pending when the physician resigned.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Board may extend the reporting time under this subsection for good cause shown.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The minutes or notes taken in the course of determining the denial, limitation, reduction, or termination of the employment contract of any physician in an alternative health system are not subject to review or discovery by any person.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Each court shall report to the Board each conviction of or entry of a plea of guilty or nolo contendere by a physician for any crime involving moral turpitude.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The court shall submit the report within 10 days of the conviction or entry of the plea.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Board may enforce this section by subpoena.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Any person shall have the immunity from liability described under &#xA7; 5-715(d) of the Courts and Judicial Proceedings Article for giving any of the information required by this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">A report made under this section is not subject to subpoena or discovery in any civil action other than a proceeding arising out of a hearing and decision of the Board under this title.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">Failure to report pursuant to the requirements of this section shall result in imposition of a civil penalty of up to $5,000 by a circuit court of this State.</section>
  </text>
</law>
