<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gho" order_by="" level="1">Health Occupations</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gho-21-101</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>101</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this title the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Board" means the State Board of Environmental Health Specialists.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Environmental health specialist" means an individual who practices as an environmental health specialist.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">"Environmental health specialist-in-training" means an individual who meets the educational qualifications required under this title but has not yet completed the environmental health specialist-in-training program required under &#xA7; 21-305 of this title.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"Environmental health specialist-in-training program" means a program of training and experience under the supervision of a licensed environmental health specialist or other individual acceptable to the Board.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">"Hours of approved training" means the value given to participation in continuing education or experience as approved by the Board.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">"License" means, unless the context requires otherwise, a license issued by the Board to practice as an environmental health specialist.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">"Licensed environmental health specialist" means an individual licensed by the Board to practice as an environmental health specialist.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">"Practice as an environmental health specialist" means, as a major component of employment, to apply academic principles, methods and procedures of the environmental, physical, biological, and health sciences to the inspections and investigations necessary to collect and analyze data and to make decisions necessary to secure compliance with federal, State, and local health and environmental laws and regulations specifically relating to control of the public health aspects of the environment including:<section prefix="(1)">The manufacture, preparation, handling, distribution, or sale of food and milk;</section><section prefix="(2)">Water supply and treatment;</section><section prefix="(3)">Wastewater treatment and disposal;</section><section prefix="(4)">Solid waste management and disposal;</section><section prefix="(5)">Vector control;</section><section prefix="(6)">Insect and rodent control;</section><section prefix="(7)">Air quality;</section><section prefix="(8)">Noise control;</section><section prefix="(9)">Product safety;</section><section prefix="(10)">Recreational sanitation; and</section><section prefix="(11)">Institutional and residential sanitation.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
