<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gho" order_by="" level="1">Health Occupations</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gho-8-6A-08</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>08</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">A certificate expires on the 28th day of the birth month of the nursing assistant or medication technician, unless the certificate is renewed for a 2-year term as provided in this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">At least 3 months before a certificate expires, the Board shall send a renewal notice to the nursing assistant or medication technician by:<section prefix="(i)">First-class mail to the last known mailing address of the nursing assistant or medication technician; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">Electronic means to the last known electronic address of the certificate holder.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A renewal notice shall state:<section prefix="(i)">The date on which the current certificate expires;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The date by which the renewal application must be received by the Board for the renewal to be issued and mailed before the certificate expires; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">The amount of the renewal fee.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">If a nursing assistant or medication technician is required to have a criminal history records check before a certificate may be renewed, the Board shall send the nursing assistant or medication technician the documents necessary for initiating the criminal history records check in conjunction with the renewal notice required under paragraph (1) of this subsection.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Before a certificate expires, a nursing assistant periodically may renew it for an additional term, if the certificate holder:<section prefix="(1)">Otherwise is entitled to be certified;</section><section prefix="(2)">Submits to the Board a renewal application on the form that the Board requires;</section><section prefix="(3)">Pays to the Board a renewal fee set by the Board; and</section><section prefix="(4)">Provides satisfactory evidence of completion of:<section prefix="(i)">16 hours of active nursing assistant practice within the 2-year period immediately preceding the date of renewal; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">An approved nursing assistant training program.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">In addition to the requirements in subsection (c)(1), (2), and (3) of this section, a certified medicine aide shall:<section prefix="(1)">Provide satisfactory evidence of completion of 100 hours of practice as a certified medicine aide in the 2-year period preceding the date of renewal; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Successfully complete a Board-approved medicine aide continuing education program.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">Before a certificate expires, a medication technician periodically may renew it for an additional term, if the certificate holder:<section prefix="(1)">Otherwise is entitled to be certified;</section><section prefix="(2)">Submits to the Board a renewal application on the form that the Board requires;</section><section prefix="(3)">Pays to the Board a renewal fee set by the Board;</section><section prefix="(4)">Every 2 years, provides satisfactory evidence of completion of a Board-approved clinical refresher course; and</section><section prefix="(5)">Provides satisfactory evidence of completion of 100 hours of practice as a certified medication technician within the 2-year period preceding the date of renewal.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Board may grant a 30-day extension, beyond a certificate's expiration date, to a certificate holder so that the certificate holder may renew the certificate before it expires.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Board may grant two 90-day extensions beyond a certificate's expiration date pending receipt of criminal history record information.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">The Board shall reinstate the certificate of a former certificate holder who has failed to renew the certificate for any reason if the former certificate holder meets the applicable renewal requirements of subsections (c) through (e) and (k)(1)(i)2 of this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">Subject to subsection (i) of this section, the Board shall renew the certificate of each nursing assistant or medication technician who meets the requirements of this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Within 60 days after a change has occurred, each certificate holder shall notify the Board in writing of any change in a name or address.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If the certificate holder fails to notify the Board within the time required under this subsection, the Board may impose an administrative penalty of $25 on the certificate holder.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(j)">The Board shall pay any penalty collected under this subsection to the General Fund of the State.</section>
    <section prefix="(k)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The Board shall require criminal history records checks in accordance with &#xA7; 8-303 of this title on:<section prefix="1.">Selected applicants for certification as a certified nursing assistant who renew their certificates every 2 years as determined by regulations adopted by the Board; and</section><section prefix="2.">Each former certified nursing assistant who files for reinstatement under subsection (g) of this section after failing to renew the certificate for a period of 1 year or more.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">An additional criminal history records check shall be performed every 12 years thereafter.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">On receipt of the criminal history record information of a certificate holder forwarded to the Board in accordance with &#xA7; 8-303 of this title, in determining whether to renew the certificate, the Board shall consider:<section prefix="(i)">The age at which the crime was committed;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The circumstances surrounding the crime;</section><section prefix="(iii)">The length of time that has passed since the crime;</section><section prefix="(iv)">Subsequent work history;</section><section prefix="(v)">Employment and character references; and</section><section prefix="(vi)">Other evidence that demonstrates whether the certificate holder poses a threat to the public health or safety.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Board may not renew a certificate if the criminal history record information required under &#xA7; 8-303 of this title has not been received.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
