<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gho" order_by="gho" level="1">Health Occupations</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gho-2-101</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this title the following words have the meanings indicated....</catch_line>
  <order_by>101</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this title the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Audiologist" means an individual who practices audiology.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Board" means the State Board of Examiners for Audiologists, Hearing Aid Dispensers, and Speech-Language Pathologists.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">"Direct supervision" means on-site and personal oversight by an individual licensed under this title who assumes responsibility for another individual's conduct whether it is consistent or fails to be consistent with professional standards and the provisions of this title.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"Hearing aid" means any FDA approved instrument or device that is designed for or represented as being capable of improving or correcting impaired human hearing.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">"Hearing aid dispenser" means an individual who practices hearing aid dispensing.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">"Hearing aid dispenser supervisor" means a licensed hearing aid dispenser or licensed audiologist who supervises a limited licensee who is studying hearing aid dispensing for the purpose of becoming eligible to sit for the licensure examination.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Hearing aid dispensing" means performing, conducting, and interpreting hearing assessment procedures to determine the type and extent of hearing loss for the purpose of:<section prefix="(i)">Fitting suitable hearing instruments;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Selecting suitable hearing instruments;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Programming a hearing aid by selecting and determining the frequency response, compression, output, gain, or other parameters of the hearing aid for initial wear by an  individual or any required alterations throughout the use of the hearing aid;</section><section prefix="(iv)">Making ear molds or ear impressions; and</section><section prefix="(v)">Providing appropriate counseling.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Hearing aid dispensing" includes:<section prefix="(i)">An act pertaining to the selling, renting, leasing, or delivering of a hearing instrument; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Providing maintenance or repair services for a hearing aid.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(i)">"Hearing aid establishment" means an establishment that offers, advertises, or performs hearing aid dispensing.</section>
    <section prefix="(j)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"License" means, unless the context requires otherwise, a license issued by the Board to practice audiology, hearing aid dispensing, or speech-language pathology, or to assist in the practice of speech-language pathology.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"License" includes, unless the context requires otherwise, a limited license.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(k)">"Licensed audiologist" means, unless the context requires otherwise, an audiologist who is licensed by the Board to practice audiology.</section>
    <section prefix="(l)">"Licensed hearing aid dispenser" means, unless the context requires otherwise, a hearing aid dispenser who is licensed by the Board to practice hearing aid dispensing.</section>
    <section prefix="(m)">"Licensed speech-language pathologist" means, unless the context requires otherwise, a speech-language pathologist who is licensed by the Board to practice speech-language pathology.</section>
    <section prefix="(n)">"Licensed speech-language pathology assistant" means, unless the context requires otherwise, a speech-language pathology assistant who is licensed by the Board to assist a  licensed speech-language pathologist in the practice of speech-language pathology.</section>
    <section prefix="(o)">"Limited license" means a license issued by the Board to practice audiology, hearing aid dispensing, or speech-language pathology, or to assist in the practice of speech-language pathology as limited by &#xA7;&#xA7; 2-310 through 2-310.3 of this title.</section>
    <section prefix="(p)">"Oral competency" means the demonstration of general English-speaking proficiency by receiving a passing score on a standardized test that the Board has approved by regulation.</section>
    <section prefix="(q)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Practice audiology" means to apply the principles, methods, and procedures of measurement, prediction, evaluation, testing, counseling, consultation, and instruction that relate to the development and disorders of hearing, vestibular functions, and related language and speech disorders, to prevent or modify the disorders or assist individuals in hearing and auditory and related skills for communication.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Practice audiology" includes the fitting or selling of hearing aids.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(r)">"Practice speech-language pathology" means to apply the principles, methods, and procedures of measurement, prediction, evaluation, testing, counseling, consultation, and instruction that relate to the development and disorders of speech, voice, swallowing, and related language and hearing disorders, to prevent or modify the disorders or to assist individuals in cognition-language and communication skills.</section>
    <section prefix="(s)">"Speech-language pathologist" means an individual who practices speech-language pathology.</section>
    <section prefix="(t)">"Speech-language pathology assistant" means an individual who:<section prefix="(1)">Meets the minimum qualifications established by the Board that shall be less stringent than those established by this title to license speech-language pathologists;</section><section prefix="(2)">Does not work independently;</section><section prefix="(3)">Works under the direct supervision of a speech-language pathologist licensed under this title.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(u)">"Telehealth" means the use of telecommunications and information technologies for the exchange of information from one site to another for the provision of health care to an individual from a provider through hardwire or Internet connection.</section>
  </text>
</law>
