<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gho" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="14-401" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gho-14-401</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Board shall perform any necessary preliminary investigation before the Board refers to an investigatory body an allegation of grounds for disciplinary or other action brought to its attention.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">If an allegation of grounds for disciplinary or other action is made by a patient or a family member of a patient based on &#xA7; 14-404(a)(22) of this subtitle and a full investigation results from that allegation, the full investigation shall include an offer of an interview with the patient or a family member of the patient who was present on or about the time that the incident that gave rise to the allegation occurred.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as otherwise provided in this subsection, after performing any necessary preliminary investigation of an allegation of grounds for disciplinary or other action, the Board may:<section prefix="(i)">Refer the allegation for further investigation to the entity that has contracted with the Board under subsection (e) of this section;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Take any appropriate and immediate action as necessary; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">Come to an agreement for corrective action with a licensee pursuant to paragraph (4) of this subsection.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">After performing any necessary preliminary investigation of an allegation of grounds for disciplinary or other action, the Board shall refer any allegation based on &#xA7; 14-404(a)(22) of this subtitle to the entity or entities that have contracted with the Board under subsection (e) of this section for further investigation and physician peer review within the involved medical specialty or specialties.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">If, after performing any necessary preliminary investigation, the Board determines that an allegation involving fees for professional or ancillary services does not constitute grounds for disciplinary or other action, the Board shall offer the complainant and the licensee an opportunity to mediate the dispute.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Except as provided in subparagraph (ii) of this paragraph, if an allegation is based on &#xA7; 14-404(a)(40) of this subtitle, the Board:</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The Board may not enter into an agreement for corrective action with a licensee if patient safety is an issue.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">The Board shall subsequently evaluate the licensee and shall:</section>
        <section prefix="(iv)">An agreement for corrective action under this paragraph may not be made public or considered a disciplinary action under this title.</section>
        <section prefix="(v)">The Board shall provide a summary of the corrective action agreements in the executive director's report of Board activities.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">County medical societies shall refer to the Board all complaints that set forth allegations of grounds for disciplinary action under &#xA7; 14-404 of this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">In accordance with subsection (f) of this section, the Board shall enter into a written contract with an entity or individual for confidential physician peer review of allegations based on &#xA7; 14-404(a)(22) of this subtitle.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The Board shall obtain two peer review  reports for each allegation it refers for peer review.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A peer reviewer shall:<section prefix="(i)">Be Board certified;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Have special qualifications to judge the matter at hand;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Have received a specified amount of medical experience and training;</section><section prefix="(iv)">Have no formal actions against the  peer reviewer's own license;</section><section prefix="(v)">Receive training in peer review;</section><section prefix="(vi)">Have a standard format for peer review reports; and</section><section prefix="(vii)">To the extent practicable, be licensed and  engaged in the practice of medicine in the  State.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Board may consult with  the appropriate specialty health care provider societies in the  State to obtain a list of physicians qualified to provide peer review  services.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">For purposes of peer review, the Board may use sole  source procurement under &#xA7; 13-107 of the State Finance and  Procurement Article.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">The hearing of charges may not be stayed or  challenged because of the selection of peer reviewers under this  subsection before the filing of charges.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The entity or individual peer  reviewer with which the Board contracts under subsection (e) of this section shall have 90 days for completion of peer review.<section prefix="(2)">The entity or individual peer  reviewer may apply to the Board for an extension of up to 30 days to the time limit imposed under paragraph (1) of this subsection.</section><section prefix="(3)">If an extension is not granted, and 90 days have elapsed, the Board may contract with any other entity or individual who meets  the requirements of subsection (e)(2) of this section for the services of peer review.</section><section prefix="(4)">If an extension has been granted, and 120 days have elapsed, the Board may contract with any other entity or individual who meets  the requirements of subsection (e)(2) of this section for the services of peer review.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in paragraph (2) of this  subsection, on or before January 1, 2008, the Board shall issue a  request for proposals and enter into a written contract with a  nonprofit entity to provide rehabilitation services for physicians  or other allied health professionals directed by the Board to  receive rehabilitation services.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If the Board does not receive a responsive proposal  under paragraph (1) of this subsection or is not able to contract   with a nonprofit entity, the Board shall provide directly  rehabilitation services for physicians.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(h)">
      <section prefix="(1)">To facilitate the investigation and prosecution of disciplinary matters and the mediation of fee disputes coming before it, the Board may contract with an entity or entities for the purchase of investigatory, mediation, and related services.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Services that may be contracted for under this subsection include the services of:<section prefix="(i)">Investigators;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Attorneys;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Accountants;</section><section prefix="(iv)">Expert witnesses;</section><section prefix="(v)">Consultants; and</section><section prefix="(vi)">Mediators.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(i)">The Board may issue subpoenas and administer oaths in connection with any investigation under this section and any hearing or proceeding before it.</section>
    <section prefix="(j)">Those individuals not licensed under this title but covered under &#xA7; 14-413(a)(1)(ii)3 and 4 of this subtitle are subject to the hearing provisions of &#xA7; 14-405 of this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(k)">
      <section prefix="(1)">It is the intent of this section that the disposition of every complaint against a licensee that sets forth allegations of grounds for disciplinary action filed with the Board shall be completed as expeditiously as possible and, in any event, within 18 months after the complaint was received by the Board.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If the Board is unable to complete the disposition of a complaint within 1 year, the Board shall include in the record of that complaint a detailed explanation of the reason for the delay.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
