<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gho" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="14-5B-09" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gho-14-5B-09</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">To qualify for a license, an applicant shall be an individual who meets the requirements of this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Except as provided in subsection (c) of this section, the applicant shall:<section prefix="(1)">Be of good moral character;</section><section prefix="(2)">Be at least 18 years old;</section><section prefix="(3)">Demonstrate oral and written competency in English as required by the Board; and</section><section prefix="(4)">Meet any educational, training, or examination requirements established by the Board, including:<section prefix="(i)">Graduation from an appropriate educational program as determined by the Board; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Certification.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">To qualify for a license to practice as a radiologist assistant, an applicant shall:<section prefix="(1)">Be issued a general license to perform medical radiation technology;</section><section prefix="(2)">Complete an advanced academic program with a nationally recognized radiology curriculum that results in a baccalaureate degree, post baccalaureate certificate, or graduate degree and incorporates a radiologist-directed clinical preceptorship;</section><section prefix="(3)">Be certified in advanced cardiac life support; and</section><section prefix="(4)">Be certified as a radiologist assistant by the American Registry of Radiologic Technologists.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except for a license to practice radiology assistance, the Board may issue a temporary license to an applicant who:<section prefix="(i)">Except for the certification requirement, has met all of the requirements for licensure in this section; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Is scheduled to take a national certifying examination within 3 months after graduation from an appropriate educational program.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Board shall adopt regulations governing the issuance of temporary licenses to applicants in accordance with this subsection.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">Except for requirements adopted by the Board for license renewal under &#xA7; 14-5B-12 of this subtitle, nothing in this subtitle may be construed to require an individual who is certified by the Board as a radiation oncology/therapy technologist, medical radiation technologist, or nuclear medicine technologist as of October 1, 2008, to meet additional education, training, or examination requirements.</section>
  </text>
</law>
