<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gho" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="14-202" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gho-14-202</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Board shall consist of 21 members appointed by the Governor with the advice of the Secretary and the advice and consent of the Senate.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Of the 21 members:<section prefix="(i)">11 shall be practicing licensed physicians, at least one of whom shall be a doctor of osteopathy, appointed as provided in subsections (d) and (e) of this section;</section><section prefix="(ii)">1 shall be a practicing licensed physician appointed at the Governor's discretion;</section><section prefix="(iii)">1 shall be a representative of the Department nominated by the Secretary;</section><section prefix="(iv)">1 shall be a certified physician assistant appointed at the Governor's discretion as provided in subsections (f) and (g) of this section;</section><section prefix="(v)">1 shall be a practicing licensed physician with a full-time faculty appointment appointed to serve as a representative of an academic medical institution in this State appointed from a list containing:</section><section prefix="(vi)">5 shall be consumer members; and</section><section prefix="(vii)">1 shall be a public member knowledgeable in risk management or quality assurance matters appointed from a list submitted by the Maryland Hospital Association.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Each consumer or public member of the Board:<section prefix="(i)">Shall be a member of the general public;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Shall be a resident of the State for at least 5 years;</section><section prefix="(iii)">May not be or ever have been a physician or in training to become a physician;</section><section prefix="(iv)">May not have a household member who is a physician or in training to become a physician;</section><section prefix="(v)">May not have a household member who participates in a commercial or professional field related to medicine; and</section><section prefix="(vi)">May not have had within 2 years before appointment a substantial financial interest in a person regulated by the Board.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A consumer member of the Board may not have a substantial personal, business, professional, or pecuniary connection with a medical field or with an institution of medical education or a health care facility.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">While serving as a member of the Board, each consumer member and the public member shall continue to meet the requirements of subsection (b) of this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">For each vacancy of a practicing licensed physician appointed in accordance with subsection (a)(2)(i) of this section, the Board shall:<section prefix="(i)">Notify all practicing licensed physicians and professional organizations representing at least 25 licensed physicians in the State of the vacancy;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Provide information regarding the selection process as provided under subsection (a)(2)(i) of this section;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Solicit nominations for the vacancy; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">Forward to the Governor:</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Board shall meet the requirements of paragraph (1) of this subsection within:<section prefix="(i)">4 months prior to an upcoming vacancy on the Board; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">2 months after a vacancy exists on the Board.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">For each vacancy of a practicing licensed physician appointed in accordance with subsection (a)(2)(i) of this section, the Governor:<section prefix="(1)">May:<section prefix="(i)">Reappoint a member who has not served for more than 2 consecutive full terms; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">Appoint a practicing licensed physician in accordance with subsection (a)(2)(i) of this section from lists submitted by the Board as provided in subsection (d)(1)(iv) of this section; and</section></section><section prefix="(2)">May not reappoint or appoint a practicing licensed physician from a particular medical specialty if there are two current members serving on the Board from the same medical specialty.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">For the vacancy of a certified physician assistant appointed in accordance with subsection (a)(2)(iv) of this section, the Board shall:<section prefix="(i)">Notify all practicing certified physician assistants and professional organizations representing at least 25 certified physician assistants in the State of the vacancy;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Provide information regarding the selection process as provided under subsection (a)(2)(iv) of this section;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Solicit nominations for the vacancy; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">Forward to the Governor:</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Board shall meet the requirements of paragraph (1) of this subsection within:<section prefix="(i)">4 months prior to an upcoming vacancy on the Board; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">2 months after a vacancy exists on the Board.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">For each vacancy of a certified physician assistant appointed in accordance with subsection (a)(2)(iv) of this section, the Governor may:<section prefix="(1)">Reappoint a member who has not served for more than two consecutive full terms; or</section><section prefix="(2)">Appoint a certified physician assistant in accordance with subsection (a)(2)(iv) of this section from lists submitted by the Board as provided in subsection (f)(1)(iv) of this section.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(h)">Before taking office, each appointee to the Board shall take the oath required by Article I, &#xA7; 9 of the Maryland Constitution.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The term of a member is 4 years.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The terms of members are staggered as required by the terms provided for members of the Board on August 1, 2003.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">At the end of a term, a member continues to serve until a successor is appointed and qualifies.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">A member may not serve more than 2 consecutive full terms.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(j)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If a vacancy occurs as to a member, the Governor shall appoint a new member to serve only for the rest of the term and until a successor is appointed and qualifies.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">To the extent practicable, the Governor shall fill any vacancy on the Board within 60 days of the date of the vacancy.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(k)">
      <section prefix="(1)">On the recommendation of the Board, the Secretary may remove any member of the Board for neglect of duty, misconduct, malfeasance, or misfeasance in office.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Upon the recommendation of the Secretary, the Governor may remove a member whom the Secretary finds to have been absent from 2 successive Board meetings without adequate reason.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Governor may remove a member for incompetence or misconduct.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
