<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gho" order_by="" level="1">Health Occupations</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gho-20-301</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>301</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as otherwise provided in this subsection, on or after October 1, 2007, an individual shall receive a certificate from the Board before the individual may be a program administrator in this State.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Except as provided in subparagraph (ii) of this paragraph, if a program administrator leaves or is removed from a position as program administrator by death or for any other unexpected cause, the owner of a residential child care program or other appropriate program authority shall immediately designate a certified program administrator to serve in that capacity.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">
          <section prefix="1.">In the event a certified program administrator is not available, the owner or other appropriate program authority may appoint a noncertified person to serve in the capacity of acting program administrator for a period not to exceed 180 days.</section>
          <section prefix="2.">The owner or other appropriate program authority shall immediately notify the Board of the appointment and forward the credentials of the person appointed to the Board for evaluation to assure that the person appointed is experienced, trained, and competent.</section>
          <section prefix="3.">The 180-day period begins on the date that the program administrator leaves or is removed from the position as a program administrator.</section>
          <section prefix="4.">The Board may extend the 180-day period for a further period of not more than 30 days.</section>
        </section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, on or before October 1, 2015, an individual shall receive a certificate from the Board before the individual may be a residential child and youth care practitioner in this State.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">This subsection does not apply to:<section prefix="(i)">An employee of the Maryland School for the Blind who is a residential child and youth care practitioner and holds a current paraprofessional certificate; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">For up to 180 days, an individual participating in a Board-approved training program.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
