<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gho" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="14-5A-01" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gho-14-5A-01</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Board" means the State Board of Physicians.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Committee" means the Respiratory Care Professional Standards Committee established under &#xA7; 14-5A-05 of this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">"License" means a license issued by the Board to practice respiratory care.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"Licensed respiratory care practitioner" means a respiratory care practitioner who is licensed by the Board to practice respiratory care.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">"Licensee" means a licensed respiratory care practitioner.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">"National certifying board" means the National Board for Respiratory Care or a certifying organization that has certification requirements equivalent to the National Board for Respiratory Care and that has been approved by the Board.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Practice respiratory care" means to evaluate, care for, and treat, including the diagnostic evaluation of, individuals who have deficiencies and abnormalities that affect the pulmonary system and associated aspects of the cardiopulmonary and other systems under the supervision of and in collaboration with a physician.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Practice respiratory care" includes:<section prefix="(i)">Providing direct and indirect respiratory care services that are safe, aseptic, preventive, and restorative;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Practicing the principles, techniques, and theories derived from cardiopulmonary medicine;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Evaluating and treating individuals whose cardiopulmonary functions have been threatened or impaired by developmental defects, the aging process, physical injury, disease, or actual or anticipated dysfunction of the cardiopulmonary system;</section><section prefix="(iv)">Observing and monitoring physical signs and symptoms, general behavior, and general physical response to respiratory care procedures and determining if initiation, modification, or discontinuation of a treatment regimen is warranted;</section><section prefix="(v)">Transcribing and implementing written or oral orders regarding the practice of respiratory care;</section><section prefix="(vi)">Using evaluation techniques that include cardiopulmonary function assessments, gas exchange, the need and effectiveness of therapeutic modalities and procedures, and the assessment and evaluation of the need for extended care and home care procedures, therapy, and equipment; and</section><section prefix="(vii)">Applying the use of techniques, equipment, and procedures involved in the administration of respiratory care, including:</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(i)">"Supervision" means the responsibility of a physician to exercise on-site or immediately available direction for a licensed respiratory care practitioner performing delegated medical acts.</section>
  </text>
</law>
