<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gho" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="2-302" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gho-2-302</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">To qualify for a license to practice audiology, an applicant shall be an individual who meets the requirements of this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The applicant shall be of good moral character.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The applicant shall:<section prefix="(1)">On or before September 30, 2007:<section prefix="(i)">Hold a master's or doctoral degree in audiology from an accredited educational institution which incorporates the academic course work and the minimum hours of supervised clinical training required by the regulations adopted by the Board; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Have completed the period of supervised postgraduate professional practice in audiology as specified by the regulations adopted by the Board;</section></section><section prefix="(2)">On or after October 1, 2007, hold a doctoral degree in audiology from an accredited educational institution which incorporates the academic course work and the minimum hours of supervised clinical training required by the regulations adopted by the Board; or</section><section prefix="(3)">Qualify for a license under &#xA7; 2-305 of this subtitle.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Except as otherwise provided in this title, the applicant shall:<section prefix="(1)">Pass an examination in audiology required by the regulations adopted by the Board; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Complete training consistent with the standards established by:<section prefix="(i)">The Accreditation Commission for Audiology Education; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">The Counsel of Academic Accreditation.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The applicant shall demonstrate oral competency.</section>
  </text>
</law>
