<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gho" order_by="gho" level="1">Health Occupations</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gho-9-302</section_number>
  <catch_line>To qualify for a license, an applicant shall be an individual who meets the requirements of this sec...</catch_line>
  <order_by>302</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">To qualify for a license, an applicant shall be an individual who meets the requirements of this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The applicant shall be of good moral character.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The applicant shall be at least 21 years old.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The applicant shall:<section prefix="(i)"><section prefix="1.">Have a baccalaureate or master's degree in health care administration from an accredited college or university; or</section><section prefix="2."/></section><section prefix="(ii)"><section prefix="1.">Have completed an administrator-in-training program approved by the Board; or</section><section prefix="2.">Have completed 1 year of full-time nursing home administration in a nursing home.</section></section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The requirements of paragraph (1) of this subsection do not apply to an individual who:<section prefix="(i)">Was in possession of a valid license on December 15, 1988; or</section><section prefix="(ii)"><section prefix="1.">Had applied for a license by December 15, 1988; and</section><section prefix="2.">Met all of the other requirements for licensure.</section></section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The Board may waive any education requirement of subsection (d) of this section for an individual who was licensed and practiced as a nursing home administrator for at least 3 years in another state.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Notwithstanding the provisions of subsection (d)(1)(i)1 or 2A of this section, the Board may not require an applicant to have a baccalaureate degree if the applicant:<section prefix="(i)">Is a registered nurse who:<section prefix="1.">Has an associate in arts degree in nursing; or</section><section prefix="2.">Is a diplomate nurse;</section></section><section prefix="(ii)">Has been working as a nursing home director of nursing for a period of at least 5 years, with at least 3 years experience at the same facility, prior to the date the applicant submits an application to the Board for a license;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Has completed at least 6 months of full-time nursing home administration in a training program approved by the Board; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">Has satisfactorily completed a minimum of 100 hours in a course of study in health care administration, or equivalent, approved by the Board.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Whenever federal law requires that an applicant for a license to practice as a nursing home administrator must have a baccalaureate degree in health care administration or in a field other than health care administration the provisions of this section shall cease to be effective.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">Except as otherwise provided in this title, the applicant shall pass an examination given by the Board under this subtitle.</section>
  </text>
</law>
