<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gho" order_by="" level="1">Health Occupations</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gho-8-6B-05</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>05</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">There is an Electrology Practice Committee within the Board.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Committee consists of five members appointed by the Board.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Of the five Committee members:<section prefix="(i)">Four shall be licensed electrologists or licensed electrology instructors; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">One shall be a consumer member.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Each member of the Committee shall be a citizen of the United States and a resident of the State.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Each electrologist member of the Committee shall have practiced electrology actively in the State for at least 5 years immediately before appointment.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The consumer member of the Committee:<section prefix="(1)">Shall be a member of the general public;</section><section prefix="(2)">May not be or ever have been:<section prefix="(i)">An electrologist;</section><section prefix="(ii)">A health care professional; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">In training to be an electrologist or a health care professional;</section></section><section prefix="(3)">May not have a household member who is an electrologist, a health care professional, in training to be an electrologist, or in training to be a health care professional; and</section><section prefix="(4)">May not:<section prefix="(i)">Participate or ever have participated in a commercial or professional field related to electrology;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Have a household member who participates in a commercial or professional field related to electrology; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">Have, or have had within 2 years before appointment, a substantial financial interest in a person regulated by the Board.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The term of a member is 4 years.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The terms of the members are staggered as required by the provisions for members of the Committee on July 1, 2003.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">At the end of a term, a member continues to serve until a successor is appointed and qualifies.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">A member who is appointed after a term has begun serves only for the rest of the term and until a successor is appointed and qualifies.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">A member may not serve more than two consecutive full terms.</section>
      <section prefix="(6)">To the extent practicable, the Board shall fill any vacancy on the Committee within 60 days of the date of the vacancy.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">A majority of the full authorized membership of the Committee is a quorum.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">In addition to any other meeting requirements of this title, the Committee  shall meet:<section prefix="(1)">At the request of the executive director of the Board; or</section><section prefix="(2)">As necessary to conduct Board business.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(i)">In accordance with the State budget, each member of the Committee  is entitled to:<section prefix="(1)">Compensation, at a rate determined by the Board, for each day, or part of a day, on which the member is engaged in the duties of the Committee; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Reimbursement for expenses under the Standard State Travel Regulations.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(j)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Board may remove a member for incompetence or misconduct.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Board may remove a member who is absent from two successive Committee meetings without adequate reason.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
