<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gho" order_by="gho" level="1">Health Occupations</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gho-14-5C-09</section_number>
  <catch_line>To qualify for a license, an applicant shall be an individual who meets the requirements of this sec...</catch_line>
  <order_by>09</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">To qualify for a license, an applicant shall be an individual who meets the requirements of this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The applicant shall:<section prefix="(1)">Be of good moral character; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Be at least 18 years old.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">An applicant for a polysomnographic technologist license shall:<section prefix="(1)">Have passed the national certifying examination given by the Board of Registered Polysomnographic Technologists or another examination approved by the Board;</section><section prefix="(2)">Submit to the Board proof of certification as a registered polysomnographic technologist or other national certification approved by the Board;</section><section prefix="(3)"><section prefix="(i)"><section prefix="1.">Have graduated from a polysomnographic educational program that is accredited by the Commission on Accreditation of Allied Health Education Programs; or</section><section prefix="2."/></section><section prefix="(ii)"><section prefix="1.">Have graduated from a respiratory care educational program that is accredited by the Commission on Accreditation of Allied Health Education Programs; and</section><section prefix="2.">Have completed the Committee on Accreditation for Respiratory Care's curriculum for a polysomnography certificate that is accredited by the Commission on Accreditation of Allied Health Education Programs; or</section></section><section prefix="(iii)"><section prefix="1.">Have graduated from an electroneuro-diagnostic educational program that is accredited by the Commission on Accreditation of Allied Health Education Programs; and</section><section prefix="2.">Have completed additional units, modules, and courses of instruction focused on polysomnographic technology that are accredited by the Commission on Accreditation of Allied Health Education Programs; and</section></section></section><section prefix="(4)">Meet any other educational or clinical requirements established by the Committee and approved by the Board.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
