<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gho" order_by="" level="1">Health Occupations</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gho-1-608</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>608</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Secretary shall monitor the timeliness of complaint resolution for each health occupations board.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">On or before October 1, 2012, the Secretary shall establish goals for the timeliness of complaint resolution for all of the boards, a group of boards, or a specific board, including:<section prefix="(i)">After a complaint is filed with a board, a goal for the length of time a board has to complete an investigation and determine whether to bring charges;</section><section prefix="(ii)">After a board makes a decision to charge, a goal for the length of time a board has to issue charges;</section><section prefix="(iii)">After a board issues charges, a goal for the length of time a board has to schedule a hearing; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">After the date of an opinion from the Office of Administrative Hearings, or the final day of any hearing, a goal for the length of time a board has to issue a final decision.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">When determining the time frames for complaint resolution, the Secretary shall consider:<section prefix="(i)">The administrative and fiscal constraints of each health occupations board; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">The recommendations from the Task Force on Discipline of Health Care Professionals and Improved Patient Care.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The goals established by the Secretary in accordance with this section are nonbinding and failure to meet the goals may not be used as grounds for any hearing or appeal of any board action.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">On or before October 1, 2012, the Secretary of Health and Mental Hygiene shall, in accordance with &#xA7; 2-1246 of the State Government Article, report to the Senate Education, Health, and Environmental Affairs Committee and the House Health and Government Operations Committee on the goals for the timeliness of complaint resolution established under this section.</section>
  </text>
</law>
