<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gho" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="12-6C-05.1" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gho-12-6C-05.1</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this subsection, "Central Repository" means the Criminal Justice Information System Central Repository of the Department of Public Safety and Correctional Services.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">This subsection applies to applicants located in the State.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">As part of an application to the Central Repository for a State and national criminal history records check, the designated representative and the immediate supervisor of the designated representative of an applicant shall submit to the Central Repository:<section prefix="(i)">Two complete sets of legible fingerprints taken on forms approved by the director of the Central Repository and the Director of the Federal Bureau of Investigation;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The fee authorized under &#xA7; 10-221(b)(7) of the Criminal Procedure Article for access to State criminal history records; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">The processing fee required by the Federal Bureau of Investigation for a national criminal history records check.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">In accordance with &#xA7;&#xA7; 10-201 through 10-228 of the Criminal Procedure Article, the Central Repository shall forward the criminal history records information of the designated representative and the immediate supervisor of the designated representative of an applicant to the Board and the applicant.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">The Board shall ensure that information obtained from the Central Repository under this subsection:<section prefix="(i)">Is kept confidential;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Is not redisseminated; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Is used only for the permitting purpose authorized by this subtitle.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(6)">The subject of a criminal history records check under this subsection may contest the contents of the printed statement issued by the Central Repository as provided in &#xA7; 10-223 of the Criminal Procedure Article.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This subsection applies to applicants located outside the State.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The designated representative and the immediate supervisor of the designated representative of an applicant shall submit to a criminal history records check by the applicant's state of residence, in accordance with the laws of the applicant's state of residence.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The criminal history records check shall consist of:<section prefix="(i)">A state criminal history records check for the applicant's state of residence; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">A national criminal history records check.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The designated representative and the immediate supervisor of the designated representative of an applicant shall request the appropriate entity in the applicant's state of residence to forward the results of the criminal history records check to the Board and the applicant.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">The Board shall ensure that information obtained under this subsection:<section prefix="(i)">Is kept confidential;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Is not redisseminated; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Is used only for the permitting purpose authorized by this subtitle.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
