<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gho" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="4-308" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gho-4-308</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">A general license to practice dentistry issued under this title authorizes the licensee to practice dentistry while the license is effective.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">While it is effective, a limited license to practice dentistry issued under this title authorizes the licensee to practice dentistry, including as an intern or a resident:<section prefix="(1)">Only for the institution or public health program named on the license; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Only on patients of the institution or public health program named on the license.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">While it is effective, a retired volunteer dentist's license or a volunteer dentist's license to practice dentistry issued under this title authorizes the licensee to practice dentistry:<section prefix="(1)">Only in a dental office, dental clinic, ambulatory care facility, or hospital;</section><section prefix="(2)">Only for an entity providing medical care to the poor, elderly, or disabled that is operated by:<section prefix="(i)">The State or a local government;</section><section prefix="(ii)">A bona fide charitable organization; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">Any other entity authorized under regulations adopted by the Board;</section></section><section prefix="(3)">If the dentist signs a written statement agreeing to donate at least 100 hours of dental services without compensation in a facility that satisfies the requirements of items (1) and (2) of this subsection;</section><section prefix="(4)">If the dentist provides documentation as required by the Board which evidences that the licensee is covered by malpractice insurance; and</section><section prefix="(5)">If the dentist does not otherwise practice dentistry for profit in Maryland.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">While it is effective, a temporary volunteer dentist's license issued under this title authorizes the licensee to practice dentistry:<section prefix="(i)">Only in a temporary dental clinic providing medical care to the poor, elderly, or disabled that is operated by:</section><section prefix="(ii)">If:</section><section prefix="(iii)">If the dentist has fulfilled any requirements of the Board relating to knowledge of the regulations adopted by the Board and the laws concerning the practice of dentistry in the State;</section><section prefix="(iv)">If the dentist provides a notarized affidavit to the Board agreeing to donate dental services without compensation for a temporary dental clinic that satisfies the requirements of subsection (i) of this section;</section><section prefix="(v)">If the dentist provides documentation as required by the Board that evidences that the dentist is covered by malpractice insurance;</section><section prefix="(vi)">If the dentist does not otherwise practice dentistry for profit in the State; and</section><section prefix="(vii)">If the dentist provides verification of current cardiopulmonary resuscitation certification.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A dentist who holds a temporary volunteer dentist's license may not administer, maintain, or monitor general anesthesia or sedation.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A dentist who holds a temporary volunteer dentist's license may only provide services authorized under the Maryland Dentistry Act and the regulations adopted by the Board.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">A dentist who holds a temporary volunteer dentist's license or the temporary dental clinic in which the dentist is providing services shall provide a form to a patient at the conclusion of treatment that contains:<section prefix="(i)">A summary of the services that were provided to the patient by the dentist and, if applicable, the dental hygienist; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Instructions for any recommended follow-up dental care.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(5)">The Board may deny a temporary volunteer dentist's license on the grounds provided under &#xA7; 4-315 of this subtitle.</section>
      <section prefix="(6)">A temporary volunteer dentist's license issued to a dentist under this title shall be issued for the duration of the temporary dental clinic only and may not be renewed.</section>
      <section prefix="(7)">The Board may issue a temporary volunteer dentist's license to a dentist who previously held a temporary volunteer dentist's license if the dentist applies for a new license and satisfies the requirements of this subtitle.</section>
      <section prefix="(8)">The Board may not require continuing education as a condition for the issuance of a temporary volunteer dentist's license.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">While it is effective, a teacher's license to practice dentistry issued under this title authorizes the licensee to practice dentistry at only the following institutions:<section prefix="(1)">The institution named on the license; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Other affiliated institutions as appropriate because of the specialized nature of the services to be performed.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in subsection (k) of this section, while it is effective, a general license to practice dental hygiene issued under this title authorizes the licensee to practice dental hygiene:<section prefix="(i)">Under the supervision of a licensed dentist who is:</section><section prefix="(ii)">Only in a:</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The Board may waive, on a case by case basis only, the supervision requirements of this subsection for:</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">A waiver is not required to practice dental hygiene under general supervision in accordance with subsection (k) of this section.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Board may grant a waiver under paragraph (2) of this subsection if:<section prefix="(i)">The facility requesting the waiver has submitted a written application;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The facility requesting the waiver has submitted a medical emergency plan of action at the time of application; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">The Board finds that:</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The Board, upon written request or its own motion, may conduct a public informational meeting on any waiver application.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The Board shall maintain records of all waiver applications and the criteria and basis for its action on each application.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">The Board shall have the power to inspect or review any facility, location, person, or entity applying for, covered by, or acting under a waiver.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(5)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Except as provided under subparagraph (ii) of this paragraph, the Board shall accept or deny a waiver under paragraph (2) of this subsection within 60 calendar days of the receipt of the application for the waiver or it shall be deemed to have been accepted.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">If extraordinary circumstances exist, the Board shall accept or deny a waiver under paragraph (2) of this subsection within 90 calendar days of the receipt of the application for the waiver or it shall be deemed to have been accepted.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(6)">Any changes in the procedures or personnel of a facility with a waiver granted under this subsection shall be reported to the Board within 15 business days after the change.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">While it is effective, a retired volunteer dental hygienist's license or a volunteer dental hygienist's license to practice dental hygiene issued under this title authorizes the licensee to practice dental hygiene:<section prefix="(1)">Only in a dental office, dental clinic, ambulatory care facility, or hospital;</section><section prefix="(2)">Only for an entity providing medical care to the poor, elderly, or handicapped that is operated by:<section prefix="(i)">The State or a local government;</section><section prefix="(ii)">A bona fide charitable organization; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">Any other entity authorized under regulations adopted by the Board;</section></section><section prefix="(3)">If the dental hygienist signs a written statement agreeing to donate at least 100 hours of dental hygiene services without compensation in a facility that satisfies the requirements of items (1) and (2) of this subsection;</section><section prefix="(4)">If the dental hygienist provides documentation as required by the Board which evidences that the licensee is covered by malpractice insurance; and</section><section prefix="(5)">If the dental hygienist does not otherwise practice dental hygiene for profit in Maryland.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(h)">
      <section prefix="(1)">While it is effective, a temporary volunteer dental hygienist's license issued under this title authorizes the licensee to practice dental hygiene:<section prefix="(i)">Only in a temporary dental clinic providing medical care to the poor, elderly, or disabled that is operated by:</section><section prefix="(ii)">If the dental hygienist holds a general license to practice dental hygiene in another state that permits clinical practice and the dental hygienist is not subject to clinical restrictions;</section><section prefix="(iii)">In addition to holding a general license to practice dental hygiene, if the dental hygienist:</section><section prefix="(iv)">If the dental hygienist has fulfilled any requirements of the Board related to knowledge of the laws and regulations governing the practice of dental hygiene in the State;</section><section prefix="(v)">If the dental hygienist provides a notarized affidavit to the Board agreeing to donate dental hygiene services without compensation for a temporary dental clinic that satisfies the requirements of subsection (i) of this section;</section><section prefix="(vi)">If the dental hygienist provides documentation as required by the Board evidencing that the dental hygienist is covered by malpractice insurance;</section><section prefix="(vii)">If the dental hygienist does not otherwise practice dental hygiene for profit in the State; and</section><section prefix="(viii)">If the dental hygienist provides verification of current cardiopulmonary resuscitation certification.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A dental hygienist who holds a temporary volunteer dental hygienist's license may only provide services authorized under the Maryland Dentistry Act and the regulations adopted by the Board.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A dental hygienist who holds a temporary volunteer dental hygienist's license may not:<section prefix="(i)">Administer local anesthesia; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">Administer, maintain, or monitor nitrous oxide oxygen.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">While it is effective, a temporary volunteer dental hygienist's license issued under this title authorizes the licensee to practice dental hygiene under the general supervision of a dentist who:<section prefix="(i)">Is on the premises;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Examines the patient at any time during the treatment; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Is available for personal consultation while the services are being performed.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(5)">A dental hygienist may perform an assessment of dental needs and provide dental hygiene services prior to an examination by a supervising dentist.</section>
      <section prefix="(6)">This subsection may not be construed to:<section prefix="(i)">Require a preliminary dental examination or treatment by a dental hygienist; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">Prohibit a supervising dentist from either examining a patient or providing treatment to a patient prior to treatment by a dental hygienist.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(7)">The Board may deny a temporary volunteer license to practice dental hygiene on the grounds provided under &#xA7; 4-315 of this subtitle.</section>
      <section prefix="(8)">A temporary volunteer dental hygienist's license issued to a dental hygienist under this section shall be issued for the duration of the temporary dental clinic only and may not be renewed.</section>
      <section prefix="(9)">The Board may issue a temporary volunteer dental hygienist's license to a dental hygienist who previously held a temporary volunteer dental hygienist's license if the dental hygienist applies for a new license and satisfies the requirements of this subtitle.</section>
      <section prefix="(10)">The Board may not require continuing education as a condition for the issuance of a temporary volunteer dental hygienist's license.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(i)">
      <section prefix="(1)">While it is effective, a temporary dental clinic permit issued to a bona fide charitable organization under this title authorizes the permit holder to utilize holders of a temporary volunteer dentist's license or a temporary volunteer dental hygienist's license to provide dental services to the poor, elderly, or disabled at a temporary dental clinic that is operated by the bona fide charitable organization.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Board shall issue a temporary dental clinic permit to a bona fide charitable organization that meets the requirements of this subsection.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A temporary dental clinic permit issued to a bona fide charitable organization under this title shall be issued for the duration of the dental clinic only and may not be renewed.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The Board may issue a temporary dental clinic permit to a bona fide charitable organization that previously held a temporary dental clinic permit if the bona fide charitable organization applies for a new permit and satisfies the requirements of this subtitle.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">A bona fide charitable organization that conducts a temporary dental clinic under this title may not be construed to be practicing dentistry as defined in &#xA7; 4-101 of this title.</section>
      <section prefix="(6)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The State, a local government, or a local health department that provides dental services to the poor, elderly, or disabled:</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">A holder of an out-of-state license to practice dentistry or dental hygiene who would like to provide dental services sponsored by the State, a local government, or a local health department shall obtain a temporary volunteer dentist's license or temporary volunteer dental hygienist's license as provided in this title before providing the dental services.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(7)">A holder of a temporary dental clinic permit shall have:<section prefix="(i)">A medical emergency plan;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Adequate equipment, including portable equipment where appropriate, and appropriate armamentarium available for the appropriate delivery of dental services; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Adequate safeguards to protect the health and safety of patients.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(8)">The Board may:<section prefix="(i)">Enter and inspect a temporary dental clinic in order to carry out a duty under this title; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Conduct an investigation of a temporary dental clinic or a holder of a temporary volunteer dentist's license or a temporary volunteer dental hygienist's license providing dental services at the temporary dental clinic.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(j)">While it is effective, a teacher's license to practice dental hygiene issued under this title authorizes the licensee to:<section prefix="(1)">Teach dental hygiene only at the institution named on the license; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Practice dental hygiene under the general supervision of a licensed dentist with the institution named on the license.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(k)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)">In this subsection the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">"Contractual employee" means a dental hygienist who has an annual contract to practice dental hygiene an average of at least 8 hours per week in a facility specified under paragraph (3)(i) of this subsection.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">"Facility" includes a program operated within a facility that is specified under paragraph (3)(i) of this subsection.</section>
        <section prefix="(iv)">"Federally qualified health center" has the meaning stated in 42 U.S.C. &#xA7; 254b(a).</section>
        <section prefix="(v)">"Federally qualified health center look-alike" has the meaning stated in 42 U.S.C. &#xA7; 1396d(l)(2)(B).</section>
        <section prefix="(vi)">"General supervision" means supervision of a dental hygienist by a dentist, where the dentist may or may not be present when the dental hygienist performs the dental hygiene procedures.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">While effective, a general license to practice dental hygiene issued under this title authorizes the licensee to practice dental hygiene and apply sealants or fluoride agents such as professional topical fluoride treatments, mouth rinse, or varnish:</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">This subsection may not be construed to:</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">While it is effective, a general license to practice dental hygiene issued under this title authorizes the licensee to practice dental hygiene under general supervision in:</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">Before a facility may allow a dental hygienist authorized to practice dental hygiene under general supervision in accordance with this subsection to practice in the facility, the facility shall report to the Board:</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(4)">A facility in which a dental hygienist is authorized to practice under the general supervision of a licensed dentist in accordance with this subsection shall ensure that:<section prefix="(i)">The supervising dentist for the facility:</section><section prefix="(ii)">Each dental hygienist authorized to practice under the general supervision of a licensed dentist in accordance with this subsection:</section><section prefix="(iii)">The facility has:</section><section prefix="(iv)">A recall patient who has been examined by a dental hygienist practicing under the general supervision of a licensed dentist will be scheduled for an oral examination every 6 months, or as otherwise recommended by the supervising dentist;</section><section prefix="(v)">A dental hygienist practicing under the general supervision of a licensed dentist ascertains before treating a recall patient that there has been no change in the patient's medical history;</section><section prefix="(vi)">A dental hygienist consults with the supervising dentist, the patient's dentist, or a treating physician before proceeding with treatment if there is a change in the patient's medical history;</section><section prefix="(vii)">Adequate facilities and equipment are available for the delivery of dental hygiene services other than fluoride rinse programs; and</section><section prefix="(viii)">The facility reports to the Board any changes in the status of the facility's general supervision, any supervising dentist, or any dental hygienist within 30 days after the change.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(l)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this subsection, "private dental office" means a dental office owned and operated by:<section prefix="(i)">A licensed dentist; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">A professional corporation, partnership, limited liability company, or limited liability partnership owned and controlled by a licensed dentist.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">While it is effective, a general license to practice dental hygiene issued under this title authorizes the licensee to practice dental hygiene under the general supervision of a licensed dentist in a private dental office.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A private dental office in which a dental hygienist is authorized to practice under the general supervision of a licensed dentist shall ensure that:<section prefix="(i)">The supervising dentist holds an active license to practice dentistry in this State;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The dental hygienist holds an active license to practice dental hygiene in this State;</section><section prefix="(iii)">The dental hygienist has at least 1,500 hours of dental hygiene clinical practice in direct patient care; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">There is a written agreement between the supervising dentist and the dental hygienist practicing under general supervision that clearly sets forth the terms and conditions under which the dental hygienist may practice, including a statement that the dental hygienist may provide dental hygiene services without the supervising dentist on the premises.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">A dental hygienist may perform authorized dental hygiene services without the supervising dentist on the premises only if:<section prefix="(i)">After the supervising dentist examines and evaluates a patient, the prescribed and authorized treatment to be provided by the dental hygienist is written in the patient's records;</section><section prefix="(ii)"/><section prefix="(iii)">Prior to an appointment, the patient or the custodial parent or legal guardian of a minor or incompetent adult shall:</section><section prefix="(iv)">Written emergency procedures are in place and the dental hygienist is trained to implement the emergency procedures;</section><section prefix="(v)">A designated licensed dentist is available for consultation with the dental hygienist; and</section><section prefix="(vi)">The number of unsupervised clinical hours worked by a supervised dental hygienist in any given 3-month period is less than 60 percent of the dental hygienist's total hours worked during that 3-month period.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(5)">A supervising dentist may not employ more than two dental hygienists to work under the dentist's general supervision at any given time.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
