<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gho" order_by="gho" level="1">Health Occupations</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gho-12-507</section_number>
  <catch_line>A pharmacist who provides prescription services to medical assistance recipients shall offer to disc...</catch_line>
  <order_by>507</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">A pharmacist who provides prescription services to medical assistance recipients shall offer to discuss with each medical assistance recipient or caregiver who presents a prescription order for outpatient drugs any matter which, in the exercise of the pharmacist's professional judgment, the pharmacist deems significant, which may include the following:<section prefix="(1)">The name and description of the medication;</section><section prefix="(2)">The route, dosage form, dosage, route of administration, and duration of drug therapy;</section><section prefix="(3)">Special directions and precautions for preparation, administration, and use by the patient;</section><section prefix="(4)">Common severe side or adverse effects or interactions and therapeutic contraindications that may be encountered, including their avoidance, and the action required if they occur;</section><section prefix="(5)">Techniques for self-monitoring drug therapy;</section><section prefix="(6)">Proper storage;</section><section prefix="(7)">Prescription refill information; and</section><section prefix="(8)">Action to be taken in the event of a missed dose.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The offer to discuss may be made in the manner determined by the professional judgment of the pharmacist, which shall include either:<section prefix="(1)">A face-to-face communication with the pharmacist; or</section><section prefix="(2)">At least 2 of the following:<section prefix="(i)">A sign posted so it can be seen by patients;</section><section prefix="(ii)">A notation affixed to or written on the bag in which the prescription is to be dispensed;</section><section prefix="(iii)">A notation contained on the prescription container; or</section><section prefix="(iv)">Communication by telephone.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Nothing in this section shall be construed as requiring a pharmacist to provide consultation if the medical assistance recipient or caregiver refuses the consultation.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A pharmacist must make a reasonable effort to obtain, record, and maintain, at the individual pharmacy, at least the following information regarding a medical assistance recipient:<section prefix="(1)">Name, address, telephone number, date of birth or age, and gender;</section><section prefix="(2)">Individual history when significant, including disease state or states, known allergies and drug reactions, and a comprehensive list of medications and relevant devices; and</section><section prefix="(3)">Pharmacist comments relevant to the individual's drug therapy which may be recorded either manually or electronically in the patient's profile.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">This section shall apply only to medical assistance recipients presenting prescriptions for covered outpatient drugs.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The requirements of this section do not apply to refill prescriptions.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">The Secretary, after consultation with the Maryland Pharmacists Association and the Maryland Association of Chain Drug Stores, shall adopt regulations in accordance with pharmacy practices in Maryland to implement the provisions of this section.</section>
  </text>
</law>
