<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gho" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="1-101" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gho-1-101</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this article the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Board of Review" means the Board of Review of the Department.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"County" means a county of this State and, unless expressly provided otherwise, Baltimore City.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">"Department" means the Department of Health and Mental Hygiene.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"Household member" means someone who is:<section prefix="(1)">The individual's:<section prefix="(i)">Spouse;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Son;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Daughter;</section><section prefix="(iv)">Ward; or</section><section prefix="(v)">Parent; or</section></section><section prefix="(2)">The individual's relative:<section prefix="(i)">Who shares the individual's legal residence; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">Whose financial affairs are under the legal or actual control of the individual.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">"Includes" or "including" means includes or including by way of illustration and not by way of limitation.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">"Oral competency" means general English-speaking proficiency as evidenced by achievement of a passing score obtained on a Board approved standardized test.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">"Person" means an individual, receiver, trustee, guardian, personal representative, fiduciary, or representative of any kind and any partnership, firm, association, corporation, or other entity.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">"Physician" means, except in Title 14 of this article, an individual who is authorized by a law of this State to practice medicine in this State.</section>
    <section prefix="(j)">"Secretary" means the Secretary of Health and Mental Hygiene.</section>
    <section prefix="(k)">"State" means:<section prefix="(1)">A state, possession, or territory of the United States;</section><section prefix="(2)">The District of Columbia; or</section><section prefix="(3)">The Commonwealth of Puerto Rico.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(l)">"Substantial financial interest" means:<section prefix="(1)">An asset with a fair market value of $1,000 or more; or</section><section prefix="(2)">A source of income of $500 or more in a calendar year.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
