<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gho" order_by="gho" level="1">Health Occupations</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gho-16-317</section_number>
  <catch_line>The Board may issue a limited license for training to an applicant who:...</catch_line>
  <order_by>317</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Board may issue a limited license for training to an applicant who:<section prefix="(1)">Meets all the requirements of this title for a license to practice podiatry, except the National Board of Podiatric Medical Examiners - Part III examination;</section><section prefix="(2)">Has an appointment for postgraduate clinical training in podiatry or as a podiatric instructor in:<section prefix="(i)">A health care facility licensed or approved by the Department;</section><section prefix="(ii)">A program approved by the Council on Education of the American Podiatry Association;</section><section prefix="(iii)">A program approved by the Board; or</section><section prefix="(iv)">A program affiliated with the Council of Podiatric Medical Education;</section></section><section prefix="(3)">Submits an application to the Board on the form that the Board requires; and</section><section prefix="(4)">Pays to the Board the application fee set by the Board.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Board shall include on any limited license that the Board issues:<section prefix="(1)">The name of the health care facility or program to which the individual holds an appointment; and</section><section prefix="(2)">The expiration date of the limited license.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A limited license temporarily authorizes the licensee to practice podiatry, while the license is effective, only on:<section prefix="(1)">Patients of the health care facility or program named on the license; or</section><section prefix="(2)">Patients of a health care facility or program that is:<section prefix="(i)">Affiliated for training purposes with the health care facility or program named on the limited license; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Approved by the Board.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A limited license may be issued for a term of 1 year and may be renewed annually.</section>
  </text>
</law>
