<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gho" order_by="gho" level="1">Health Occupations</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gho-7-304</section_number>
  <catch_line>An applicant who otherwise qualifies for a mortician or funeral director license is entitled to be e...</catch_line>
  <order_by>304</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">An applicant who otherwise qualifies for a mortician or funeral director license is entitled to be examined as provided in this section if the applicant:<section prefix="(1)">Holds an apprentice license; or</section><section prefix="(2)">Has completed the apprenticeship requirements of this title.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Board shall give examinations to applicants twice each year, at the times and places that the Board determines.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Board shall notify each qualified applicant of the time and place of examination.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The written part of the examination shall include:<section prefix="(i)">The general and local laws of this State on the practice of mortuary science; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">The laws and regulations on infectious diseases.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">In the practical part of the examination:<section prefix="(i)">The Board shall provide a dead human body; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Except as provided in paragraph (3) of this subsection, in the presence of at least one third of the licensed members of the Board, each applicant shall demonstrate the applicant's knowledge and skill in the preparation of dead human remains for final disposition.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">For individuals applying for a license to practice funeral direction, a practical examination under paragraph (2) of this subsection may not include demonstrating competency in embalming.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">An applicant shall pay to the Board an examination fee set by the Board.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The payment of one examination fee entitles an applicant to take the examination twice.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">If an applicant fails the examination twice, the applicant may retake the examination if the applicant pays the appropriate fee.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">In addition to the written and practical examinations administered by the Board, an applicant must take and pass the national examination administered by the Conference of Funeral Service Examining Boards of the United States.</section>
  </text>
</law>
