<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gho" order_by="" level="1">Health Occupations</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gho-17-507</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>507</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Any individual who is licensed under Subtitle 3 of this title or certified under Subtitle 4 of this title may not charge a client or receive remuneration for counseling or therapy services unless:<section prefix="(1)">Before the performance of those services, the client is furnished a copy of a professional disclosure statement; or</section><section prefix="(2)"><section prefix="(i)">This professional disclosure statement is displayed in a conspicuous location at the place where the services are performed; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">A copy of the statement is provided to the client on request.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The professional disclosure statement shall contain:<section prefix="(1)">The name, title, business address, and business telephone number of the licensee or certificate holder performing the services;</section><section prefix="(2)">The formal professional education of the licensee or certificate holder, including the institutions attended and the degrees received from them;</section><section prefix="(3)">The areas of specialization of the licensee or certificate holder and the services provided;</section><section prefix="(4)">In the case of an individual licensed under Subtitle 3 of this title or certified under Subtitle 4 of this title who is engaged in a private individual practice, partnership, or group practice, the individual's fee schedule listed by type of service or hourly rate;</section><section prefix="(5)">At the bottom of the first page of the disclosure statement, the words, "This information is required by the Board of Professional Counselors and Therapists, which regulates all licensed and certified counselors and therapists."; and</section><section prefix="(6)">Immediately beneath the statement required by item (5) of this subsection, the name, address, and telephone number of the Board.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
