<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gho" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="4-202" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gho-4-202</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Board consists of 16 members.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Of the 16 Board members:<section prefix="(i)">9 shall be licensed dentists;</section><section prefix="(ii)">4 shall be licensed dental hygienists; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">3 shall be consumer members.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Subject to subsection (b)(1) of this section, the Governor shall appoint the dentist Board members, with the advice of the Secretary, from a list of names submitted to the Governor by the Board.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The number of names on the list for one vacancy shall be at least four names, for two vacancies at least three names for each vacancy, and for three or more vacancies at least two names for each vacancy.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(4)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Subject to subsection (b)(2) of this section, the Governor shall appoint the dental hygienist Board members, with the advice of the Secretary, from a list of names submitted to the Governor by the Board.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The number of names on the list shall be four times the number of vacancies.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(5)">The Governor shall appoint the consumer members with the advice of the Secretary and the advice and consent of the Senate.</section>
      <section prefix="(6)">To the extent practicable, the members appointed to the Board shall reasonably reflect the geographic, racial, ethnic, cultural, and gender diversity of the State.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">For each licensed dentist vacancy, the Board shall:<section prefix="(i)">Send by electronic mail or regular mail a solicitation for nominations to fill the vacancy to:</section><section prefix="(ii)">Conduct a balloting process by which each dentist licensed by the State is eligible to vote to select the names of the licensed dentists to be submitted to the Governor.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">For each licensed dental hygienist vacancy, the Board shall:<section prefix="(i)">Send by electronic mail or regular mail a solicitation for nominations to fill the vacancy to:</section><section prefix="(ii)">Conduct a balloting process by which each dental hygienist licensed by the State is eligible to vote to select the names of the licensed dental hygienists to be submitted to the Governor.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Board shall develop guidelines for the solicitation of nominations and balloting process that to the extent possible will result in the overall composition of the Board reasonably reflecting the geographic, racial, ethnic, and gender diversity of the State.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Each dentist Board member:<section prefix="(1)">Shall be an individual of recognized ability and honor;</section><section prefix="(2)">Shall be a practicing holder of a general license to practice dentistry who has practiced dentistry actively in this State for at least 5 years immediately before appointment;</section><section prefix="(3)">Shall be a resident of this State; and</section><section prefix="(4)">In the case of a Board member belonging to an association whose members are regulated by the Board, may not be:<section prefix="(i)">An officer of the association;</section><section prefix="(ii)">A member of the association's governing board or committee;</section><section prefix="(iii)">A member of the association's house of delegates; or</section><section prefix="(iv)">A voting member of a committee of the association that contributes to the establishment of governmental, regulatory, or legislative policy objectives of the association.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Each dental hygienist Board member:<section prefix="(1)">Shall be a practicing holder of a general license to practice dental hygiene who has practiced dental hygiene actively in this State for at least 3 years immediately before appointment;</section><section prefix="(2)">Shall be a resident of this State;</section><section prefix="(3)">In the case of a Board member belonging to an association whose members are regulated by the Board, may not be:<section prefix="(i)">An officer of the association;</section><section prefix="(ii)">A member of the association's governing board or committee;</section><section prefix="(iii)">A member of the association's house of delegates; or</section><section prefix="(iv)">A voting member of a committee of the association that contributes to the establishment of governmental, regulatory, or legislative policy objectives of the association.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">Each consumer member of the Board:<section prefix="(1)">Shall be a member of the general public;</section><section prefix="(2)">May not be or ever have been a dentist or dental hygienist or in training to become a dentist or dental hygienist;</section><section prefix="(3)">May not have a household member who is a dentist or dental hygienist or in training to become a dentist or dental hygienist;</section><section prefix="(4)">May not participate or ever have participated in a commercial or professional field related to dentistry;</section><section prefix="(5)">May not have a household member who participates in a commercial or professional field related to dentistry; and</section><section prefix="(6)">May not have had within 2 years before appointment a substantial financial interest in a person regulated by the Board.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">While a member of the Board, a consumer member may not have a substantial financial interest in a person regulated by the Board.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">Before taking office, each appointee to the Board shall take the oath required by Article I, &#xA7; 9 of the Maryland Constitution.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The term of a member is 4 years.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The terms of the members are staggered as required by the terms provided for members of the Board on October 1, 2006.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">At the end of a term, a member continues to serve until a successor is appointed and qualifies.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">A member who is appointed after a term has begun serves only for the rest of the term and until a successor is appointed and qualifies.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">A member may not be appointed for more than 2 consecutive full terms.</section>
      <section prefix="(6)">To the extent practicable, the Governor shall fill any vacancy on the Board within 60 days of the date of the vacancy.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(i)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Governor may remove a member for incompetence, misconduct, continued neglect of duties imposed by this subtitle, unprofessional conduct, or dishonorable conduct.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Governor shall remove a member whom the Governor finds to have been absent from 2 successive Board meetings without adequate reason.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
