<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gho" order_by="gho" level="1">Health Occupations</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gho-14-502</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this section, "the Maryland Institute for Emergency Medical Services Systems" means the State age...</catch_line>
  <order_by>502</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, "the Maryland Institute for Emergency Medical Services Systems" means the State agency described in &#xA7; 13-503 of the Education Article.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">This section applies to:<section prefix="(1)">The Faculty;</section><section prefix="(2)">A component medical society of the Faculty;</section><section prefix="(3)">A committee of the Faculty or of a component medical society of the Faculty;</section><section prefix="(4)">A committee appointed by or established in the Maryland Institute for Emergency Medical Services Systems;</section><section prefix="(5)">A hospital, related institution, or other health care facility staff committee;</section><section prefix="(6)">A hospital, related institution, or other health care facility credentials committee or its equivalent;</section><section prefix="(7)">The chief executive officer of a hospital, related institution, or other health care facility;</section><section prefix="(8)">The dean of any medical school in this State;</section><section prefix="(9)">A member of the Board;</section><section prefix="(10)">A casualty insurer writing medical professional liability insurance in this State;</section><section prefix="(11)">A utilization committee of:<section prefix="(i)">A nonprofit health service plan; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">A health insurer doing business in this State;</section></section><section prefix="(12)">The chief executive officer of an alternative health system;</section><section prefix="(13)">The medical director of an alternative health system;</section><section prefix="(14)">A medical review committee appointed by or established in an alternative health system; and</section><section prefix="(15)">A physician.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A person described in subsection (b) of this section shall have the immunity from liability described under &#xA7; 5-638 of the Courts and Judicial Proceedings Article for giving information to any hospital, hospital medical staff, related institution, or other health care facility, alternative health system, professional society, medical school, or professional licensing board.</section>
  </text>
</law>
