<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gho" order_by="" level="1">Health Occupations</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gho-8-308</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>308</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Subject to subsection (c) of this section, the Board shall license any applicant who meets the requirements for a license as:<section prefix="(1)">A registered nurse under this title; or</section><section prefix="(2)">A licensed practical nurse under this title.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Board shall:<section prefix="(i)">Issue each new licensee a license number and registration certificate that indicates that the initial license was issued by the Board; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Electronically record each license in the Board's database and on the Board's website.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Each license shall include:<section prefix="(i)">Any expiration date;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The type of license; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Any certification.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">On receipt of the criminal history record information of an applicant for licensure or certification forwarded to the Board in accordance with &#xA7; 8-303 of this subtitle, in determining whether to grant a license or a certificate, the Board shall consider:<section prefix="(i)">The age at which the crime was committed;</section><section prefix="(ii)">The circumstances surrounding the crime;</section><section prefix="(iii)">The length of time that has passed since the crime;</section><section prefix="(iv)">Subsequent work history;</section><section prefix="(v)">Employment and character references; and</section><section prefix="(vi)">Other evidence that demonstrates whether the applicant poses a threat to the public health or safety.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Except as provided in subparagraph (ii) of this paragraph, the Board may not issue a license or a certificate if the criminal history record information required under &#xA7; 8-303 of this subtitle has not been received.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The Board may grant a 90-day extension of a temporary license pending receipt of criminal history record information.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
