<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="gho" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="2-308" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gho-2-308</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Except as provided for a limited license in &#xA7;&#xA7; 2-310 through 2-310.3 of this subtitle, a license expires on the date set by the Board, unless the license is renewed for an additional term as provided in this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">At least 2 months before the license expires, the Board shall contact the licensee at the last known address provided by the licensee and advise the licensee of:<section prefix="(1)">The date on which the current license expires;</section><section prefix="(2)">The date by which the renewal application must be received by the Board for the renewal to be issued and mailed before the license expires; and</section><section prefix="(3)">The amount of the renewal fee.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Before the license expires, the licensee periodically may renew it for an additional term, if the licensee:<section prefix="(1)">Otherwise is entitled to be licensed;</section><section prefix="(2)">Pays to the Board a renewal fee set by the Board; and</section><section prefix="(3)">Submits to the Board:<section prefix="(i)">A renewal application on the form that the Board requires;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Evidence of compliance with any continuing education requirement set under this section for license renewal; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Evidence that each audiometer in use has been calibrated within 12 months before the date the license is renewed.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">In addition to any other qualifications and requirements established by the Board, the Board, by rule or regulation, shall establish continuing education requirements as a condition to the renewal of licenses under this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The Board shall renew the license of each licensee who meets the requirements of this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">A licensee has a grace period of 30 days after a license expires in which to renew it retroactively, if the licensee:<section prefix="(1)">Otherwise is entitled to have the license renewed; and</section><section prefix="(2)">Pays to the Board the renewal fee and any late fee set by the Board.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
