<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gho" order_by="gho" level="1">Health Occupations</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gho-17-401</section_number>
  <catch_line>This subsection only applies to individuals certified by the Board as a certified professional couns...</catch_line>
  <order_by>401</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This subsection only applies to individuals certified by the Board as a certified professional counselor or certified professional counselor-marriage and family therapist on or before September 30, 2008.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">An individual shall be certified as a professional counselor by the Board before the individual may:<section prefix="1.">Use the title "certified professional counselor";</section><section prefix="2.">Use the initials "C.P.C." after the name of the individual; or</section><section prefix="3.">Represent to the public that the individual is certified as a professional counselor.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">A certificate to practice professional counseling issued by the Board authorizes the certificate holder to practice professional counseling while the certificate is effective.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">An individual shall be certified as a professional counselor-marriage and family therapist by the Board before the individual may:<section prefix="1.">Use the title "certified professional counselor-marriage and family therapist";</section><section prefix="2.">Use the initials "C.P.C.-M.F.T." after the name of the individual; or</section><section prefix="3.">Represent to the public that the individual is certified as a certified professional counselor-marriage and family therapist.</section></section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">A certificate to practice marriage and family therapy issued by the Board authorizes the certificate holder to practice marriage and family therapy while the certificate is effective.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">An individual shall be certified as a certified professional counselor-alcohol and drug by the Board before the individual may:<section prefix="(i)">Use the title "certified professional counselor-alcohol and drug";</section><section prefix="(ii)">Use the initials "C.P.C.-A.D." after the name of the individual; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">Represent to the public that the individual is certified as a certified professional counselor-alcohol and drug.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">An individual shall be certified as a certified associate counselor-alcohol and drug by the Board before the individual may:<section prefix="(i)">Use the title "certified associate counselor-alcohol and drug";</section><section prefix="(ii)">Use the initials "C.A.C.-A.D." after the name of the individual; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">Represent to the public that the individual is certified as a certified associate counselor-alcohol and drug.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">An individual shall be certified as a certified supervised counselor-alcohol and drug by the Board before the individual may:<section prefix="(i)">Use the title "certified supervised counselor-alcohol and drug";</section><section prefix="(ii)">Use the initials "C.S.C.-A.D." after the name of the individual; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">Represent to the public that the individual is certified as a certified supervised counselor-alcohol and drug.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">A certificate to practice alcohol and drug counseling issued by the Board authorizes the certificate holder to practice alcohol and drug counseling while the certificate is effective.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
