<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gho" order_by="gho" level="1">Health Occupations</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gho-16-202</section_number>
  <catch_line>The Board consists of 7 members....</catch_line>
  <order_by>202</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Board consists of 7 members.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Of the 7 Board members:<section prefix="(i)">5 shall be licensed podiatrists; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">2 shall be consumer members.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Governor shall appoint the podiatrist members, with the advice of the Secretary, from a list of names submitted by the Maryland Podiatric Medical Association. The number of names on the list shall be twice the number of vacancies.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The Governor shall appoint the consumer members with the advice of the Secretary and the advice and consent of the Senate.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The list submitted by the Maryland Podiatric Medical Association shall consist of names of nominees chosen by a majority of its members present at a meeting called for that purpose.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">At least 2 weeks before the meeting required by paragraph (1) of this subsection, the Secretary of the Association shall mail to its members, at the addresses that appear on the records of the Association, notice stating the time, place, and purpose of the meeting.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Each podiatrist member of the Board shall be:<section prefix="(1)">A licensed practicing podiatrist of recognized ability and integrity;</section><section prefix="(2)">A resident of this State who has practiced actively in this State for at least 5 years immediately before appointment; and</section><section prefix="(3)">A licensed podiatrist with peer review experience.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Each consumer member of the Board:<section prefix="(1)">Shall be a member of the general public;</section><section prefix="(2)">May not be or ever have been a podiatrist or in training to become a podiatrist;</section><section prefix="(3)">May not have a household member who is a podiatrist or in training to become a podiatrist;</section><section prefix="(4)">May not participate or ever have participated in a commercial or professional field related to podiatry;</section><section prefix="(5)">May not have a household member who participates in a commercial or professional field related to podiatry; and</section><section prefix="(6)">May not have had within 2 years before appointment a substantial financial interest in a person regulated by the Board.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">While a member of the Board, a consumer member may not have a substantial financial interest in a person regulated by the Board.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">Before taking office, each appointee to the Board shall take the oath required by Article I, &#xA7; 9 of the Maryland Constitution.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The term of a member is 4 years.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The terms of the members are staggered as required by the terms provided for members of the Board on July 1, 1981.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">At the end of a term, a member continues to serve until a successor is appointed and qualifies.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">A member who is appointed after a term has begun serves only for the rest of the term and until a successor is appointed and qualifies.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">A member may not serve more than 2 consecutive full terms.</section>
      <section prefix="(6)">To the extent practicable, the Governor shall fill any vacancy on the Board within 60 days of the date of the vacancy.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(h)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Governor shall remove a member for continued neglect of duty, incompetence, or unprofessional or dishonorable conduct.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Governor shall remove a member whom the Governor finds to have been absent from 2 successive Board meetings without adequate reason.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
