<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gho" order_by="gho" level="1">Health Occupations</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gho-15-301</section_number>
  <catch_line>Nothing in this title may be construed to authorize a physician assistant to practice independent of...</catch_line>
  <order_by>301</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Nothing in this title may be construed to authorize a physician assistant to practice independent of a primary or alternate supervising physician.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A license issued to a physician assistant shall limit the physician assistant's scope of practice to medical acts:<section prefix="(1)">Delegated by the primary or alternate supervising physician;</section><section prefix="(2)">Appropriate to the education, training, and experience of the physician assistant;</section><section prefix="(3)">Customary to the practice of the primary or alternate supervising physician; and</section><section prefix="(4)">Consistent with the delegation agreement filed with the Board.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Patient services that may be provided by a physician assistant include:<section prefix="(1)"><section prefix="(i)">Taking complete, detailed, and accurate patient histories; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">Reviewing patient records to develop comprehensive medical status reports;</section></section><section prefix="(2)">Performing physical examinations and recording all pertinent patient data;</section><section prefix="(3)">Interpreting and evaluating patient data as authorized by the primary or alternate supervising physician for the purpose of determining management and treatment of patients;</section><section prefix="(4)">Initiating requests for or performing diagnostic procedures as indicated by pertinent data and as authorized by the supervising physician;</section><section prefix="(5)">Providing instructions and guidance regarding medical care matters to patients;</section><section prefix="(6)">Assisting the primary or alternate supervising physician in the delivery of services to patients who require medical care in the home and in health care institutions, including:<section prefix="(i)">Recording patient progress notes;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Issuing diagnostic orders; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Transcribing or executing specific orders at the direction of the primary or alternate supervising physician; and</section></section><section prefix="(7)">Exercising prescriptive authority under a delegation agreement and in accordance with &#xA7; 15-302.2 of this subtitle.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as otherwise provided in this title, an individual shall be licensed by the Board before the individual may practice as a physician assistant.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Except as otherwise provided in this title, a physician may not supervise a physician assistant in the performance of delegated medical acts without filing a completed delegation agreement with the Board.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Except as otherwise provided in this title or in a medical emergency, a physician assistant may not perform any medical act for which:<section prefix="(i)">The individual has not been licensed; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">The medical acts have not been delegated by a primary or alternate supervising physician.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">A physician assistant is the agent of the primary or alternate supervising physician in the performance of all practice-related activities, including the oral, written, or electronic ordering of diagnostic, therapeutic, and other medical services.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">Except as provided in subsection (g) of this section, the following individuals may practice as a physician assistant without a license:<section prefix="(1)">A physician assistant student enrolled in a physician assistant educational program that is accredited by the Accreditation Review Commission on Education for the Physician Assistant or its successor and approved by the Board; or</section><section prefix="(2)">A physician assistant employed in the service of the federal government while performing duties incident to that employment.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(g)">A physician may not delegate prescriptive authority to a physician assistant student in a training program that is accredited by the Accreditation Review Commission on Education for the Physician Assistant or its successor.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If a medical act that is to be delegated under this section is a part of the practice of a health occupation that is regulated under this article by another board, any rule or regulation concerning that medical act shall be adopted jointly by the State Board of Physicians and the board that regulates the other health occupation.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If the two boards cannot agree on a proposed rule or regulation, the proposal shall be submitted to the Secretary for a final decision.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
