<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="gho" order_by="gho" level="1">Health Occupations</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>gho-7-314</section_number>
  <catch_line>A license issued under this title expires on the date set by the Board, unless the license is renewe...</catch_line>
  <order_by>314</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">A license issued under this title expires on the date set by the Board, unless the license is renewed for an additional term as provided in this section. A license may not be renewed for a term longer than 2 years.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">At least 1 month before a license expires, the Board shall send to the licensee, by first-class mail to the last known address of the licensee, a renewal notice that states:<section prefix="(1)">The date on which the current license expires;</section><section prefix="(2)">The date by which the renewal application must be received by the Board for the renewal to be issued and mailed before the license expires; and</section><section prefix="(3)">The amount of the renewal fee.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Except as otherwise provided in this section, before a license expires, the licensee periodically may renew it for additional terms, if the licensee:<section prefix="(1)">Has met the qualifications for licensure and is not under a suspension or revocation order of the Board;</section><section prefix="(2)">Except as otherwise provided under this title, pays to the Board a renewal fee set by the Board;</section><section prefix="(3)">Submits to the Board a renewal application on the form that it requires;</section><section prefix="(4)">Submits to the Board satisfactory evidence of compliance with any continuing education requirements the Board may adopt by regulation; and</section><section prefix="(5)">For a funeral establishment license, provides proof of any payment to the Board required in accordance with &#xA7; 7-4A-05(b) of this title.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Board shall renew the license of and issue a renewal certificate to each licensee who meets the requirements of this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The secretary of the Board may issue a renewal certificate during the interim between meetings of the Board.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Before an apprentice license expires, the licensee may renew it for an additional 1-year term only if the licensee:<section prefix="(i)">Submits to the Board a renewal application on the form that the Board requires;</section><section prefix="(ii)">Continues to participate in a training program; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">Pays to the Board a renewal fee set by the Board.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">An apprentice license may be renewed only two times.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">Before a courtesy card expires, the licensee may renew it for additional terms if the licensee:<section prefix="(1)">Submits to the Board a renewal application on the form that the Board requires;</section><section prefix="(2)">Submits documentation to the Board that the out-of-state license is in good standing; and</section><section prefix="(3)">Pays to the Board a renewal fee set by the Board.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(g)">If, when the license of an individual otherwise would expire, the licensee is on active duty as a member of the armed forces but not on a career basis, the license is renewed automatically for a 1-year term without application or payment of a fee.</section>
  </text>
</law>
