<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghs" order_by="" level="1">Housing and Community Development</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghs-4-926</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>926</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Accessory housing" means a dwelling with complete and independent sleeping, cooking, and living facilities that is:<section prefix="(i)">within, attached to, or on the same parcel as a single-family, owner-occupied dwelling; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">subordinate to but under the same ownership as the single-family, owner-occupied dwelling.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Shared housing" means a single-family, owner-occupied dwelling adapted for common and shared living use by the owner-occupant and another family of limited income.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">"Sheltered housing" means a single-family, owner-occupied dwelling that:<section prefix="(i)">accommodates the owner-occupant; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">provides sleeping and living facilities, meals, and assistance with daily activities for a rental fee to not more than 15 elderly individuals or individuals with disabilities.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">There is an Accessory, Shared, and Sheltered Housing Program.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Department shall operate the Accessory, Shared, and Sheltered Housing Program and make loans for rehabilitation costs for accessory, shared, and sheltered housing from the Special Loan Programs Fund under this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The terms for accessory, shared, and sheltered housing loans shall satisfy the requirements of &#xA7; 4-916(b) of this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">To qualify for an accessory housing loan, an applicant shall:<section prefix="(1)">own the property for which the loan is made and agree to live in the property after the rehabilitation is completed; and</section><section prefix="(2)"><section prefix="(i)">agree to use the loan proceeds to implement a rehabilitation project to provide an accessory dwelling for a family of limited income for a fixed minimum term that the Department determines; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">be a family of limited income when the loan is made and agree to use the loan proceeds to provide an accessory dwelling for a fixed minimum term that the Department determines.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">To qualify for a shared housing loan, an applicant shall:<section prefix="(1)">be a family of limited income;</section><section prefix="(2)">own the property for which the loan is made and agree to live in the property after the rehabilitation is completed; and</section><section prefix="(3)">agree to use the loan proceeds to implement a rehabilitation project to provide shared housing or an accessory dwelling for a family of limited income.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(g)">To qualify for a sheltered housing loan, an applicant shall:<section prefix="(1)">own the property for which the loan is made and agree to live in the property after the rehabilitation is completed;</section><section prefix="(2)">agree to provide shelter, meals, and assistance with daily activities to not more than 15 elderly individuals or individuals with disabilities who qualify as families of limited income; and</section><section prefix="(3)">demonstrate that the property will be certified by the appropriate governmental unit to provide sheltered care to elderly individuals or individuals with disabilities.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
