<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghs" order_by="" level="1">Housing and Community Development</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghs-7-204</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>204</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The owner shall offer the right of first purchase by written notice to:<section prefix="(i)">each political subdivision in which the assisted project is located;</section><section prefix="(ii)">each local public housing authority;</section><section prefix="(iii)">each group that represents tenants at the assisted project and has registered with the Secretary;</section><section prefix="(iv)">each low-income housing developer that has registered with the Secretary and is exempt from taxation under &#xA7; 501(a) of the Internal Revenue Code; and</section><section prefix="(v)">any other person that has experience in the ownership or operation of low-income housing projects, is unrelated to the owner, and has registered with the Secretary.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The owner shall deliver the offer:<section prefix="(i)">with or after the notice of intent; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">to a person registered with the Secretary within 10 days after the Secretary gives the owner the title and mailing address of the person.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The owner shall deliver a copy of the offer to the Department.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The owner's offer shall include:<section prefix="(1)">the terms of the offer, including:<section prefix="(i)">the date of the offer;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the purchase price, as determined under &#xA7; 7-205(b) of this subtitle;</section><section prefix="(iii)">a date for settlement, which must be 1 year or more after the later of:<section prefix="1.">the date of the owner's offer; and</section><section prefix="2.">the date of the notice of intent;</section></section><section prefix="(iv)">a provision stating that:<section prefix="1.">the buyer's obligation is contingent on the buyer's obtaining financing; and</section><section prefix="2.">the contingency will not expire before the settlement;</section></section><section prefix="(v)">a requirement that the first $10,000 of any deposit by the purchaser be nonrefundable, except as provided in &#xA7; 7-205(c)(1)(iii) of this subtitle; and</section><section prefix="(vi)">other terms determined under &#xA7; 7-205(b) of this subtitle; and</section></section><section prefix="(2)">a summary of the procedures and timing to exercise the right of first purchase, as specified in this subtitle and in any departmental regulations.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The date of the owner's offer is the date on which it is delivered to the last political subdivision to which it must be delivered.</section>
  </text>
</law>
