<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="ghs" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="4-923" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghs-4-923</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The purpose of a rehabilitation project is:<section prefix="(1)">to bring a building to a decent, safe, and sanitary condition in accordance with applicable codes and standards, including those for construction, health, safety, fire, and occupancy;</section><section prefix="(2)">to maintain the building in that condition;</section><section prefix="(3)">to make the building more useful and attractive;</section><section prefix="(4)">to conform the building to the appropriate minimum livability code;</section><section prefix="(5)">to acquire a building containing more than four dwelling units for the purposes set forth in items (1) through (4) of this subsection;</section><section prefix="(6)">to provide, under applicable special loan programs:<section prefix="(i)">lead paint abatement;</section><section prefix="(ii)">indoor plumbing; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">shared, accessory, or sheltered housing;</section></section><section prefix="(7)">in the case of a loan to an elderly household or a disabled homeowner, to modify or improve a dwelling to make it more accessible or functional for the occupants, if the building is, or after improvements will be, structurally sound and free of health and safety hazards; or</section><section prefix="(8)">to provide, under applicable special loan pilot programs, radon abatement or asbestos abatement.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The applicable codes and standards under subsection (a)(1) of this section are:<section prefix="(i)">those in force in the political subdivision where the building is located; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">those that the Department sets by regulation for that political subdivision solely for purposes of this subtitle, if the political subdivision lacks codes and standards that the Secretary considers sufficient to promote the objectives of this subtitle.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">With the approval of the local enforcement authority, the Secretary may allow exceptions to a code or standard to preserve the historic or architectural value of a building undergoing rehabilitation under this subtitle.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
