<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghs" order_by="" level="1">Housing and Community Development</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghs-3-202</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>202</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The General Assembly finds that:<section prefix="(i)">the flow of private investment capital into adequate housing can be stimulated by a system insuring qualified lending institutions against losses resulting from nonpayment of money owed under the terms of a note, bond, or other evidence of indebtedness; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">the insurance can help State and local activity to finance housing and rehabilitation.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The General Assembly also finds that adequate housing can and should be provided by private capital under our free enterprise system and in accordance with sound investment practices.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The General Assembly finds as a subject of concern that:<section prefix="(i)">many residents of the State are living in substandard housing; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">there is a shortage of housing at reasonable costs for various income levels.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The General Assembly finds that it is in the public interest to promote energy conservation projects and solar energy projects by providing insurance for:<section prefix="(1)">loans made by qualified lending institutions; and</section><section prefix="(2)">bonds or notes issued to finance the projects.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The General Assembly finds that the sale of pooled mortgages or securities backed by mortgages to private or public investors, including public and private pension funds, is in the public interest and could increase the investment capital available to make mortgage loans to acquire, construct, and rehabilitate housing.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this subsection, "distressed area" has the meaning stated in &#xA7; 4-201 of this article.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The General Assembly finds that it is in the public interest to encourage the financing of, and otherwise to support, the planning, acquisition, development, construction, reconstruction, rehabilitation, repair, renovation, and other improvement of:<section prefix="(i)">public purpose projects in distressed areas in the State; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">infrastructure projects.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The General Assembly finds that the flow of public and private capital to support the activities specified in this section will be encouraged and expanded by:<section prefix="(1)">insuring:<section prefix="(i)">loans made by qualified lending institutions;</section><section prefix="(ii)">bonds or notes issued by qualified issuers; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">obligations backed by mortgages; and</section></section><section prefix="(2)">providing other credit enhancements.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
