<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghs" order_by="" level="1">Housing and Community Development</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghs-4-914</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>914</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">If the Department certifies a political subdivision as capable of administering a local rehabilitation program, the political subdivision may originate and administer Program loans under regulations of the Department.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">By regulation, the Department shall establish standards for determining the capability of a political subdivision to administer a local rehabilitation program.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The standards shall include provisions on:<section prefix="(i)">the size, training, and experience of the professional staff that would administer the Program; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">the capability of the professional staff to:<section prefix="1.">determine rehabilitation needs;</section><section prefix="2.">establish rehabilitation programs;</section><section prefix="3.">evaluate applications for Program loans; and</section><section prefix="4.">monitor Program loans and the rehabilitation work done with them.</section></section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">If the Department determines that a political subdivision cannot or does not want to administer a local rehabilitation program, the Department may originate and administer Program loans from the allocation or suballocation to that political subdivision.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Department may:<section prefix="(1)">help train employees of political subdivisions to administer local rehabilitation programs under the standards that the Department sets; and</section><section prefix="(2)">provide political subdivisions advice and technical assistance on the administration of their local rehabilitation programs, including loan packaging, contractor and bid selection, zoning, marketing, engineering, and related services.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
