<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghs" order_by="ghs" level="1">Housing and Community Development</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghs-12-101</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this Division II the following words have the meanings indicated....</catch_line>
  <order_by>101</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this Division II the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Area of operation" means the geographical area within which an authority is empowered to act.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Authority" means a public corporation created as a housing authority under this Division II.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">"Bond" includes a note, an interim certificate, a debenture, and any other obligation issued by an authority under this Division II.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"Chief elected official" means:<section prefix="(1)">the individual who exercises the office of the chief publicly elected executive official of the political subdivision; or</section><section prefix="(2)">in a political subdivision without a chief publicly elected executive official, the highest executive body.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">"Code authority" means an authority activated on or after July 1, 1990.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">"County" means a county of the State or Baltimore City.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">"Custodian of records" means:<section prefix="(1)">the clerk of the political subdivision;</section><section prefix="(2)">the officer charged with the duties customarily imposed on a clerk; or</section><section prefix="(3)">the political subdivision's designee to be the custodian of records for this Division II.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(i)">"Economically depressed or physically deteriorated area" means an area in which most housing is harmful to safety, health, and morals because of:<section prefix="(1)">dilapidation;</section><section prefix="(2)">overcrowding;</section><section prefix="(3)">faulty arrangement or design; or</section><section prefix="(4)">lack of ventilation, light, or sanitary facilities.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(j)">"Extraordinary majority" means two-thirds or more of the authorized number of members of the legislative body or the board of commissioners of an authority, as applicable.</section>
    <section prefix="(k)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Housing project" means a work or undertaking to:<section prefix="(i)">demolish, clear, or remove buildings from an economically depressed or physically deteriorated area; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">provide decent, safe, and sanitary housing for persons of eligible income and, to the extent authorized by &#xA7; 12-503(a)(4) of this title, for other persons.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Housing project" includes:<section prefix="(i)">work connected to planning, constructing, reconstructing, altering, or repairing improvements, acquiring property, or demolishing structures;</section><section prefix="(ii)">adapting an economically depressed or physically deteriorated area to public purposes, including parks and other recreational or community purposes; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">acquiring buildings, land, equipment, facilities, and other real or personal property for necessary, convenient, or desirable:<section prefix="1.">appurtenances;</section><section prefix="2.">streets;</section><section prefix="3.">sewers;</section><section prefix="4.">water service;</section><section prefix="5.">parks;</section><section prefix="6.">site preparation;</section><section prefix="7.">gardening; and</section><section prefix="8.">administrative, community, health, recreational, educational, welfare, or other purposes.</section></section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(l)">"Legislative body" means the council, commissioners, or other legislative body of a political subdivision.</section>
    <section prefix="(m)">"Military personnel" includes all civilian and military employees of the military and naval forces of the United States and their families and other dependents who are living with them.</section>
    <section prefix="(n)">"Obligee" includes:<section prefix="(1)">a bondholder and a trustee for a bondholder;</section><section prefix="(2)">a lessor that leases to the authority property used in connection with a housing project, and an assignee of all or part of the lessor's interest; and</section><section prefix="(3)">the State or federal government when it is a party to a contract with an authority.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(o)">"Person" means an individual, a receiver, a trustee, a guardian, a personal representative, a fiduciary, a representative of any kind, a partnership, a firm, an association, a corporation, a public corporation, or any other entity.</section>
    <section prefix="(p)">"Person of eligible income" means an individual or family that qualifies under &#xA7; 12-106 of this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(q)">"Political subdivision" means a county or municipal corporation of the State.</section>
    <section prefix="(r)">"Pre-existing authority" means an authority that was activated before July 1, 1990.</section>
    <section prefix="(s)">"Real property" includes:<section prefix="(1)">land;</section><section prefix="(2)">improvements and fixtures on the land;</section><section prefix="(3)">property of any nature appurtenant to or used in connection with the land; and</section><section prefix="(4)">each legal or equitable estate, interest, and right in the land, including:<section prefix="(i)">terms for years and liens by way of judgment, mortgage, or otherwise; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">the indebtedness secured by those liens.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(t)">"State public body" means any political subdivision, commission, district, authority, or unit of the State.</section>
  </text>
</law>
