<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghs" order_by="ghs" level="1">Housing and Community Development</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghs-6-206</section_number>
  <catch_line>The Department shall:...</catch_line>
  <order_by>206</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Department shall:<section prefix="(1)">review each application and may request more information from the sponsor;</section><section prefix="(2)">accept public input on each application;</section><section prefix="(3)">submit each application to appropriate State units and appropriate members of the Smart Growth Subcabinet;</section><section prefix="(4)">consider any recommendation a State unit or member of the Smart Growth Subcabinet makes;</section><section prefix="(5)">consider geographic balance when reviewing applications; and</section><section prefix="(6)">give priority in awarding financial assistance to applicants that are likely to repay the financial assistance to a community development financial institution or to the Community Legacy Financial Assistance Fund.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Department may not approve an application unless the political subdivision in which the proposed project is located approves the application by resolution.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If an application affects a sustainable community entirely within a municipal corporation, the approval must come from the municipal corporation rather than the surrounding county.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">If an application affects a sustainable community within more than one political subdivision, each political subdivision must approve it by resolution.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Secretary shall award financial assistance to a sponsor or a sponsor's designee:<section prefix="(1)">in the amount and of the type that the Secretary determines; and</section><section prefix="(2)">under the terms of a community legacy agreement.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
