<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="ghs" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="7-220" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghs-7-220</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">After notice and public hearing, a political subdivision may find that, because of a protected action, a low-income and moderate-income rental housing emergency exists in all or part of its jurisdiction.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The political subdivision shall make findings as to:<section prefix="(i)">the nature and incidence of protected actions;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the resulting hardship to and displacement of tenants; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">the scarcity of low-income and moderate-income rental housing.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, on finding that there is an emergency under this section, a political subdivision may enact a law, ordinance, or regulation to:<section prefix="(i)">grant to a designated household a right to an extended lease for a period in addition to that granted under &#xA7; 7-214 of this subtitle; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">extend any other provision of this subtitle concerning extended leases.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A political subdivision may not require that:<section prefix="(i)">more than 20% of assisted units in an assisted project be set aside for extended leases for designated households; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">the term of an extended lease for any household made a designated household by the political subdivision exceed 3 years.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The political subdivision may require that the notice required under &#xA7; 7-216(a)(3) of this subtitle be modified to disclose the effects of any actions taken under this section.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Within 10 days after enacting a law, ordinance, or regulation in accordance with this section, a political subdivision shall send a copy to the Secretary of State and the Secretary of Housing and Community Development.</section>
  </text>
</law>
