<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="ghs" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="4-201" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghs-4-201</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Commercial building" means any building that:<section prefix="(1)">is used primarily to carry on a business whether or not for profit;</section><section prefix="(2)">is not a residential building; and</section><section prefix="(3)">is not used primarily to manufacture or produce raw materials, products, or agricultural commodities.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Commercial energy audit" means:<section prefix="(1)">an energy audit performed for purposes of Title VII of the National Energy Conservation Policy Act, 42 U.S.C. &#xA7;&#xA7; 6201 through 6422; or</section><section prefix="(2)">an onsite inspection of a commercial building that includes a determination of, and provides information on:<section prefix="(i)">the type, quantity, and rate of energy consumption of the building;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the maintenance and operation procedures to reduce the energy consumption of the building; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">the cost of implementing an appropriate energy conservation project, a solar energy project, or both, and the savings in energy costs likely to result from the project.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">"Community development project" means a project that qualifies under &#xA7; 4-217 of this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Development costs" means the costs that the Department considers reasonable and necessary to carry out:<section prefix="(i)">a community development project;</section><section prefix="(ii)">an energy conservation project;</section><section prefix="(iii)">a home improvement project;</section><section prefix="(iv)">an infrastructure project;</section><section prefix="(v)">a public purpose project;</section><section prefix="(vi)">a solar energy project; or</section><section prefix="(vii)">a special housing facility.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Development costs" includes:<section prefix="(i)">the costs of:</section><section prefix="(ii)">expenses incurred in connection with initial occupancy or operation of the project;</section><section prefix="(iii)">an allocable portion of the administrative and operating expenses of the Department;</section><section prefix="(iv)">the cost of financing the project, including interest on bonds and notes issued to finance the project from the date issued to the date the Department determines that the project is substantially occupied or substantially in operation; and</section><section prefix="(v)">the cost of other items, including indemnity and surety bonds, premiums on insurance, fees, relocation costs, and charges and expenses of trustees, depositories, and paying agents for bonds and notes issued.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">"Director" means the Director of the Administration.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">"Energy conservation project" means a project that qualifies under &#xA7; 4-218 of this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">"Family of limited income" means a family or individual whose income does not exceed the upper income limits established by the Secretary under &#xA7; 4-212 of this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">"Home improvement project" means a project that qualifies under &#xA7; 4-219 of this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(j)">"Infrastructure project" means a project that qualifies under &#xA7; 4-220 of this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(k)">"Limited dividend corporation" means a corporation that:<section prefix="(1)">qualifies as a limited dividend corporation under the Moderate-Income Rental Program of the National Housing Act, Title 12, Chapter 13 of the United States Code; and</section><section prefix="(2)">is operated only to further a community development project.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(l)">"Local development agency" means the governmental unit of a political subdivision that the chief executive officer of the political subdivision designates to carry out community development under this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(m)">"Local development entity" means a corporation or foundation, no part of the net earnings of which inures to the benefit of a private shareholder or individual, that is organized and operated primarily to foster, encourage, and assist community development in the State.</section>
    <section prefix="(n)">"Local obligation" means a bond, note, or other obligation of a political subdivision or a governmental unit of a political subdivision.</section>
    <section prefix="(o)">"Public purpose project" means a project that qualifies under &#xA7; 4-221 of this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(p)">"Residential building" means a single family or multifamily structure that is used primarily for human dwelling and that has a system for heating, cooling, or both.</section>
    <section prefix="(q)">"Residential energy audit" means:<section prefix="(1)">an inspection or energy audit of a residential building or a dwelling unit in a residential building performed for purposes of Title II or Title VII of the National Energy Conservation Policy Act, Title 42, Chapter 91 of the United States Code; or</section><section prefix="(2)">an onsite inspection of a residential building or a dwelling unit in a residential building that includes a determination of and provides information on:<section prefix="(i)">the type, quantity, and rate of energy consumption of the building or dwelling unit;</section><section prefix="(ii)">maintenance and operating procedures to reduce the energy consumption of the residential building or dwelling unit; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">the cost of implementing an appropriate energy conservation project, solar energy project, or both, and the savings in energy costs that are likely to result from the project.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(r)">"Residential mortgage loan" means a loan, including a temporary loan or advance, that is secured by a mortgage of real property in the State that is:<section prefix="(1)">improved by a residential building; or</section><section prefix="(2)">unimproved, if the loan proceeds are to be used to construct a residential building.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(s)">"Solar energy project" means a project that qualifies under &#xA7; 4-222 of this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(t)">"Special housing facility" means a project or undertaking for the refinancing, acquisition, rehabilitation, improvement, renovation, or construction of a building that:<section prefix="(1)">will be occupied in substantial part by families of limited income;</section><section prefix="(2)">will provide common, shared, or independent living, dining, kitchen, sanitary, and sleeping facilities;</section><section prefix="(3)">may include supportive services or supervisory live-in personnel for individuals with specialized housing needs;</section><section prefix="(4)">may include nonresidential facilities to serve individuals with special needs who need not be residents of the project or undertaking; and</section><section prefix="(5)">is not subject to &#xA7; 4-213(b) of this subtitle.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
