<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghs" order_by="" level="1">Housing and Community Development</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghs-4-505</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>505</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, "Fund" means the Special Loan Programs Fund.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">There is a Special Loan Programs Fund.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">As provided in the State budget and subject to subsection (d) of this section, the Department shall use the Fund to:<section prefix="(1)">operate, pay expenses of, and make loans under the Group Home Financing Program;</section><section prefix="(2)">operate, pay expenses of, and make grants and loans under the Lead Hazard Reduction Grant Program and the Lead Hazard Reduction Loan Program;</section><section prefix="(3)">operate, pay expenses of, and make loans under the Maryland Housing Rehabilitation Program, including reserves for anticipated future losses directly related to the Maryland Housing Rehabilitation Program;</section><section prefix="(4)">make loans under the Regular Rehabilitation Program; and</section><section prefix="(5)">make loans under the special loan programs.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">During the first 6 months of each fiscal year the Department shall reserve at least 25% of the appropriation for the Fund to make loans to rehabilitate buildings with four or fewer dwelling units.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Department annually shall allocate money in the Fund to the Lead Hazard Reduction Grant Program and the Lead Hazard Reduction Loan Program.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If the number of eligible applications under the Lead Hazard Reduction Grant Program or the Lead Hazard Reduction Loan Program is insufficient to commit all money allocated to that Program within 6 months after the allocation, the Department may reallocate the uncommitted money to other programs of the Fund.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The Fund shall be administered in accordance with this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Fund consists of:<section prefix="(i)">money appropriated by the State for special loan programs, including:<section prefix="1.">the Special Rehabilitation Program under &#xA7; 4-906(b) of this title;</section><section prefix="2.">the Regular Rehabilitation Program under &#xA7; 4-906(b) of this title;</section><section prefix="3.">the Group Home Financing Program under &#xA7; 4-602 of this title; and</section><section prefix="4.">the Lead Hazard Reduction Grant Program under &#xA7; 4-708 of this title and the Lead Hazard Reduction Loan Program under &#xA7; 4-709 of this title;</section></section><section prefix="(ii)">repayments of principal and payments of interest on loans made under these programs;</section><section prefix="(iii)">repayments of grants from the Fund;</section><section prefix="(iv)">repayments of principal and payments of interest on loans from the Fund;</section><section prefix="(v)">money transferred to the Fund in accordance with &#xA7;&#xA7; 4-502(e), 4-503(d), and 4-504(f) of this subtitle and &#xA7;&#xA7; 3-203(i) and 6-310(g) of this article; and</section><section prefix="(vi)">investment earnings of the Fund.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The State, under &#xA7; 4-501(c) of this subtitle, may appropriate to the Fund money received as repayment of principal or payment of interest on a loan made by the Maryland Housing Rehabilitation Program.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(h)">Subject to &#xA7; 7-209 of the State Finance and Procurement Article and except as otherwise provided in the State budget, after the first 8 months of a fiscal year, the Department may transfer unencumbered money in the Fund to any other fund established under this title.</section>
  </text>
</law>
