<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghs" order_by="" level="1">Housing and Community Development</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghs-7-101</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>101</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this title the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Assisted household" means one or more individuals who occupy a rental unit in an assisted project.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Assisted project" means a property that qualifies under &#xA7; 7-105 of this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">"Assisted unit" means a dwelling unit that is in an assisted project and is subject to regulatory requirements regarding:<section prefix="(1)">the rent the owner may charge; or</section><section prefix="(2)">the maximum annual income of the household occupying the unit.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"Designated household" means a household that qualifies under &#xA7;  7-213 of this title.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">"Notice of intent" means a notice of intent to take a protected action in accordance with Subtitle 2 of this title.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">"Owner" means a person who holds legal title to an assisted project or any mortgagee in possession, receiver, trustee, or other person that may take a protected action.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">"Owner's offer" means the written offer made by the owner to parties having a right of first purchase under &#xA7; 7-204 of this title.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Project-based &#xA7; 8 rental assistance" means federal rental assistance under &#xA7; 8 of the United States Housing Act of 1937, 42 U.S.C. &#xA7; 1437f, to the owner or lender of a housing project under a new construction program, a substantial rehabilitation program, a loan management assistance program, or a property disposition program.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Project-based &#xA7; 8 rental assistance" does not include rental assistance made directly to a tenant under existing certificate or voucher programs.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(j)">"Protected action" means a sale, conveyance, transfer, prepayment, termination, failure to renew, or expiration under &#xA7; 7-102(a) of this title.</section>
    <section prefix="(k)">"Relocation expenses" means costs incurred to:<section prefix="(1)">hire contractors, labor, vehicles, or equipment to transport personal property;</section><section prefix="(2)">pack and unpack personal property;</section><section prefix="(3)">disconnect and reconnect utilities, such as water, telephone, gas, or electric, and to perform related services;</section><section prefix="(4)">disconnect and install personal property;</section><section prefix="(5)">insure personal property to be moved;</section><section prefix="(6)">pay rental application fees and make security deposits; and</section><section prefix="(7)">pay other costs that the Secretary determines are reasonable.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(l)">"Tenant protection assistance" means payments to, and extensions of leases for, the occupant or former occupant of an assisted unit in connection with a protected action as required under &#xA7; 7-212 of this title.</section>
  </text>
</law>
