<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghs" order_by="" level="1">Housing and Community Development</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghs-15-109</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>109</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Baltimore Authority may recognize and engage in collective bargaining with the exclusive bargaining representatives of all appropriate employee bargaining units, including units consisting of:<section prefix="(i)">maintenance, housekeeping, and technical personnel;</section><section prefix="(ii)">administrative and clerical personnel; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">supervisory personnel.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The power under paragraph (1) of this section includes the power of the Baltimore Authority to:<section prefix="(i)">deal with and, through an exclusive bargaining representative, address grievances and settle disputes;</section><section prefix="(ii)">meet and bargain in good faith with an exclusive bargaining representative about wages, hours, working conditions, and other terms and conditions of employment to form a binding labor agreement; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">draft and execute labor agreements that last not more than 3 consecutive fiscal years.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A bargaining unit under paragraph (1) of this subsection may not include:<section prefix="(i)">confidential employees;</section><section prefix="(ii)">contractual employees employed for less than 5 consecutive years;</section><section prefix="(iii)">probationary employees;</section><section prefix="(iv)">attorneys in the general counsel's office;</section><section prefix="(v)">supervisors, as defined in 29 U.S.C. &#xA7; 152(11); or</section><section prefix="(vi)">employees whose main responsibility is to manage or direct independently the assets and affairs of the Baltimore Authority.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Baltimore Authority may engage in binding third-party arbitration of:<section prefix="(1)">disputes over a term or condition of employment; and</section><section prefix="(2)">grievances that relate to the interpretation or application of a written collective bargaining agreement, employment regulation, or work rule.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Baltimore Authority may exercise any power that is necessary and appropriate to establish and implement a system of collective bargaining with its employees.</section>
  </text>
</law>
