<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="ghs" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="4-235" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghs-4-235</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Mortgage loan" includes a loan to:<section prefix="(i)">finance or refinance the purchase of stock or membership in a cooperative ownership housing corporation; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">rehabilitate units in a cooperative ownership housing corporation.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Reverse equity mortgage loan" includes a loan that uses the equity in a home as collateral.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Administration may make, participate in making, and undertake a commitment for a residential mortgage loan to a family of limited income:<section prefix="(1)">for a family that has a disabled family member who will reside in the dwelling;</section><section prefix="(2)">for an emergency housing need as determined by the Secretary;</section><section prefix="(3)">for settlement and down payment costs; or</section><section prefix="(4)">that is made in conjunction with a loan funded with State appropriated funds if the State appropriated funded loan comprises at least 20% of the total amount loaned.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In accordance with &#xA7; 4-213 of this subtitle, the Administration may make, participate in making, purchase, and undertake a commitment for:<section prefix="(i)">a mortgage loan or other financial assistance secured by a mortgage lien for a community development project or public purpose project; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">a reverse equity mortgage loan secured by a mortgage lien that is for housing related expenses of an elderly household that qualifies as a family of limited income.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Financial assistance to purchase a dwelling unit in a community development project or public purpose project under paragraph (1)(i) of this subsection may include a temporary loan or advance and a permanent direct mortgage loan to a family of limited income, if otherwise required by law.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Housing related expenses under paragraph (1)(ii) of this subsection include personal expenses that enable the owner to continue to occupy the owner's home.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A commitment, mortgage, bond, or secured note shall contain terms and conditions necessary to secure repayment of its loan, the interest on it, and other charges in connection with the loan.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Except as provided in subparagraph (ii) of this paragraph, a mortgage loan for a community development project or a public purpose project and a reverse equity mortgage loan may bear interest at a rate or rates that the Administration finds will make the project economically feasible.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The Administration may not increase the interest rate originally charged on a permanent direct mortgage loan to a family for the purchase of a dwelling unit in a community development project or a public purpose project.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Subject to any agreement with noteholders or bondholders, the Administration may consent to the modification of the interest rate, time of payment of any installment of principal or interest, security, or any other term, of a mortgage, mortgage loan, reverse equity mortgage loan, mortgage loan commitment, or reverse equity mortgage loan commitment, contract, or agreement to which the Administration is a party.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">In connection with property on which it holds a mortgage loan or reverse equity mortgage loan:<section prefix="(1)">the Administration may:<section prefix="(i)">foreclose on the property or begin an action to protect or enforce a right that is conferred on the Administration by law, a mortgage contract, or other agreement;</section><section prefix="(ii)">bid for and purchase the property at a foreclosure or other sale; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">acquire or take possession of the property; and</section></section><section prefix="(2)">in a manner to protect the interests of the Administration, the Administration may:<section prefix="(i)">complete, administer, and pay the principal of and interest on an obligation incurred in connection with the property;</section><section prefix="(ii)">dispose of the property; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">otherwise deal with the property.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This subsection does not apply to a lien held in connection with a public purpose project.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Administration may not lend money on the security of property unless the lien on the property is superior to all other liens, except for:<section prefix="(i)">liens for taxes owed to the State or a political subdivision; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">earlier mortgage liens.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">The Administration may:<section prefix="(1)">sell any mortgage or other obligation that it holds, at public or private sale, with or without public bidding; and</section><section prefix="(2)">retain the servicing rights and charge servicing fees for any mortgage or other obligation the Administration sells.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(h)">The Administration may purchase securities backed by mortgages to provide financial assistance to community development projects and public purpose projects and to finance residential mortgage loans with the proceeds of the securities or with investment earnings on the securities.</section>
  </text>
</law>
