<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghs" order_by="ghs" level="1">Housing and Community Development</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghs-6-310</section_number>
  <catch_line>There is a Neighborhood Business Development Fund....</catch_line>
  <order_by>310</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">There is a Neighborhood Business Development Fund.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Department shall use the Fund to:<section prefix="(1)">operate and pay expenses of the Program; and</section><section prefix="(2)">provide financial assistance to small businesses, nonprofit organizations, and microenterprises.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Department shall administer the Fund.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The State Treasurer shall hold and the Comptroller shall account for the Fund.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Fund is a continuing, nonlapsing special fund that is not subject to &#xA7; 7-302 of the State Finance and Procurement Article.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The Fund consists of:<section prefix="(1)">money appropriated in the State budget for the Program;</section><section prefix="(2)">any repayment or prepayment of financial assistance under this subtitle or under the State Action Loans for Targeted Areas Program under former Article 83B, Title 4, Subtitle 6, of the Code;</section><section prefix="(3)">money transferred to the Fund from any other fund as provided in this article;</section><section prefix="(4)">money received from the sale, assignment, or other disposition of Program loans;</section><section prefix="(5)">other money received by the Program under this subtitle or from the Community Development Administration under Subtitle 2 of this title; and</section><section prefix="(6)">investment earnings of the Fund.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The Fund shall be invested in the same way as other State money.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">With the approval of the Legislative Policy Committee and, subject to &#xA7; 7-209 of the State Finance and Procurement Article, after the first 8 months of a fiscal year, the Department may transfer unencumbered money in the Fund to any other fund established under this title.</section>
  </text>
</law>
