<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="ghs" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="4-1801" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghs-4-1801</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Affordable" means that housing costs do not exceed 30% of a household's income.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Area median income" means the median household income for the area adjusted for household size as published and annually updated by the United States Department of Housing and Urban Development.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">"Development costs" means costs related to acquisition, site clearance and preparation, relocation, construction, renovation, financing, refinancing, engineering, or architectural plans.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"Fund"  means the Workforce Housing Fund.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">"Household of low or moderate income" means a household that a qualifying local government determines cannot afford a sales price or rent sufficient to induce private enterprise in the area of the qualifying local government to develop enough adequate and safe housing without the assistance of a program.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">"Housing costs" means:<section prefix="(1)">rent for a rental housing unit; or</section><section prefix="(2)">mortgage principal and interest, real property taxes, and insurance for a housing unit that is for sale.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(h)">"Net proceeds of transfer" means all amounts paid to the original buyer or obligations of the original buyer assumed by a purchaser of a workforce housing unit minus:<section prefix="(1)">reasonable costs paid by the original buyer;</section><section prefix="(2)">the combined amount of Program funds and qualifying local government matching funds used to develop the workforce housing unit; and</section><section prefix="(3)">other liens as permitted by regulation by the Department.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(i)">"Priority funding area" has the meaning stated in &#xA7; 5-7B-02 of the State Finance and Procurement Article.</section>
    <section prefix="(j)">"Program" means the Workforce Housing Grant Program.</section>
    <section prefix="(k)">"Qualifying local government" means a county or municipal corporation that qualifies for participation in the Program under &#xA7; 4-1803 of this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(l)">"Workforce housing" means:<section prefix="(1)">rental housing that is affordable for a household with an aggregate annual income between 50% and 100% of the area median income; or</section><section prefix="(2)">homeownership housing that:<section prefix="(i)">except as provided in item (ii) of this item, is affordable to a household with an aggregate annual income between 60% and 120% of the area median income; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">in target areas that are recognized by the Secretary for purposes of administering the Maryland Mortgage Program, is affordable to a household with an aggregate annual income between 60% and 150% of the area median income.</section></section></section>
  </text>
</law>
