<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="ghs" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="17-101" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghs-17-101</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this title the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Continuing care facility" means a facility in which shelter and medical and nursing services or other health related services are made available:<section prefix="(1)">to an individual who is 60 years old or older and not related by blood or marriage to the provider;</section><section prefix="(2)">for the life of the individual or for a period exceeding 1 year; and</section><section prefix="(3)">under a written agreement that requires a transfer of assets or an entrance fee, notwithstanding periodic charges.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Housing project" means a work or undertaking to provide decent, safe, and sanitary urban or rural apartments, or other housing for the persons of eligible income who live in the area of the housing.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Housing project" includes buildings, land, equipment, facilities, and other real or personal property that is planned, acquired, owned, used, developed, reconstructed, rehabilitated, or improved to provide:<section prefix="(i)">the housing; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">the necessary, convenient, or desirable:</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">"Person of eligible income" means an individual or a family that:<section prefix="(1)">lives in the area of operation of the Prince George's Authority that undertakes a housing project; and</section><section prefix="(2)">as determined by the Prince George's Authority, lacks sufficient income without financial assistance to live in decent, safe, and sanitary housing without overcrowding.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"Prince George's Authority" means the Housing Authority of Prince George's County.</section>
  </text>
</law>
