<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghs" order_by="" level="1">Housing and Community Development</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghs-16-317</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>317</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, "strike" means the action of an employee, in concert with others, to:<section prefix="(1)">refuse to report to work;</section><section prefix="(2)">stop or slow down work; or</section><section prefix="(3)">abstain wholly or partly from the full, faithful, and proper performance of duties when the object is to induce, influence, or coerce a change in the terms, conditions, rights, or privileges of employment.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A Montgomery Commission employee, a group of Montgomery Commission employees, or an employee organization may not engage in, induce, initiate, or ratify a strike by Montgomery Commission employees.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">If a strike occurs, on request of the Montgomery Commission, a court of competent jurisdiction may enjoin the strike.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">An employee may not receive compensation from the Montgomery Commission while the employee is engaged in a strike.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If an employee engages in, induces, initiates, or ratifies a strike, the Montgomery Commission may take appropriate disciplinary action against the employee, including suspension or discharge.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The labor relations administrator shall hold a hearing on the disciplinary action at which the Montgomery Commission, the employee, and any interested employee organization may present evidence and argument.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If the labor relations administrator finds after a hearing that an employee organization certified as an exclusive representative assisted, authorized, or initiated a strike involving the refusal of Montgomery Commission employees to report for work, the labor relations administrator shall revoke the certification of the employee organization.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">An employee organization decertified under paragraph (1) of this paragraph may not be recertified for 2 years after the end of the strike.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">If the labor relations administrator finds after a hearing that an employee organization certified as an exclusive representative assisted, authorized, or initiated any other kind of strike, the labor relations administrator may revoke the certification of the employee organization for up to 1 year from the end of the strike.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
