<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghs" order_by="ghs" level="1">Housing and Community Development</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghs-12-312</section_number>
  <catch_line>When a code authority becomes authorized to do business and exercise its powers, the political subdi...</catch_line>
  <order_by>312</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">When a code authority becomes authorized to do business and exercise its powers, the political subdivision:<section prefix="(i)">immediately shall estimate the amount of money necessary for the administrative expenses and overhead of the code authority during the first year thereafter; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">shall appropriate that amount to the code authority out of money in the political subdivision's treasury not appropriated to some other purpose.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The political subdivision shall pay the money appropriated to the code authority as a donation.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Subject to paragraph (2) of this subsection, the political subdivision shall appropriate to the code authority money needed to comply with any requirement imposed on it by its articles of organization, if enough money for the code authority to comply is not available from State, federal, or other sources.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A political subdivision is not required to provide any money for a code authority to satisfy a judgment, liability, debt, or other financial obligation to a third party.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A political subdivision located wholly or partly in the area of operation of a code authority may lend, donate, or agree to lend or donate money to the code authority.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The code authority, when it has the money available, shall reimburse the political subdivision for all loans made to it by the political subdivision.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
