<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghs" order_by="ghs" level="1">Housing and Community Development</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghs-12-206</section_number>
  <catch_line>A pre-existing authority may be governed by articles of organization if:...</catch_line>
  <order_by>206</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A pre-existing authority may be governed by articles of organization if:<section prefix="(i)">the pre-existing authority meets the requirements of subsection (b) or (c) of this section;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the custodian of records files with the Secretary of State the documents required under subsection (d) of this section; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">the Secretary of State issues a certificate of approval in accordance with subsection (e) of this section.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Articles of organization shall comply with &#xA7; 12-205(b) through (d) of this subtitle.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Before a pre-existing authority may adopt articles of organization under this subsection, the articles of organization must be:<section prefix="(1)">recommended in writing by the chief elected official;</section><section prefix="(2)">approved by an extraordinary majority of the board of commissioners of the authority; and</section><section prefix="(3)">adopted by an extraordinary majority of the legislative body.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Before a pre-existing authority may adopt articles of organization under this subsection:<section prefix="(1)">the custodian of records shall provide documentation to the Secretary of State that within 5 years before the date the documentation is submitted:<section prefix="(i)">the political subdivision, within each of any 3 fiscal years within the 5-year period, has provided financial assistance to the authority from local tax revenues or bond sale proceeds in an amount equal to the greater of:<section prefix="1.">the product of $1 times the number of residents of the political subdivision as published annually by the Department of Health and Mental Hygiene or as otherwise available; and</section><section prefix="2.">the product of $100 times the total number of housing units owned or managed by the authority; and</section></section><section prefix="(ii)">the authority, at the request and with the financial support of the political subdivision, is operating one or more housing projects for which the federal government provided no more than half of the development and operating costs; and</section></section><section prefix="(2)">the articles of organization must be:<section prefix="(i)">recommended in writing by the chief elected official;</section><section prefix="(ii)">approved by a resolution of the board of commissioners of the authority; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">adopted by a resolution or ordinance of the legislative body.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The custodian of records shall file with the Secretary of State:<section prefix="(1)">a copy of the documentation described in subsection (c)(1) of this section, if applicable;</section><section prefix="(2)">the articles of organization and the applicable recommending, approving, and adopting instruments described in subsection (b) or (c)(2) of this section;</section><section prefix="(3)">certification by the custodian of records that the articles of organization have been recommended and adopted by the political subdivision in accordance with the applicable requirements of subsection (b)(1) and (3) or subsection (c)(2)(i) and (iii) of this section; and</section><section prefix="(4)">certification by the secretary of the pre-existing authority that the articles of organization have been approved by the board of commissioners of the authority in accordance with the applicable requirements of subsection (b)(2) or subsection (c)(2)(ii) of this section.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If the Secretary of State finds that the requirements of subsection (b) or (c) and subsection (d) of this section have been satisfied, the Secretary of State shall endorse the articles as "approved" and issue a certificate of approval attached to the endorsed articles.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">When the certificate of approval is issued, the articles of organization as filed are considered to have been adopted.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
