<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghs" order_by="" level="1">Housing and Community Development</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghs-4-806</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>806</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Department shall:<section prefix="(1)">manage the Program in a manner that:<section prefix="(i)">serves all areas of the State; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">does not create or aggravate low-income concentrations that adversely affect communities;</section></section><section prefix="(2)">periodically set upper limits on adjusted annual income;</section><section prefix="(3)">use federal or State programs that complement or facilitate carrying out the Program; and</section><section prefix="(4)">adopt regulations to carry out the Program.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Department shall adopt policies to ensure that each loan made under the Program is made only to:<section prefix="(1)">a household that:<section prefix="(i)">when the loan is made, has an adjusted annual income at or below the applicable upper limit that the Secretary sets under &#xA7; 4-807 of this subtitle; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">cannot qualify for conventional or other available departmental financing to enable the owner to continue to occupy the home, or to acquire, acquire and rehabilitate with or without demolition or lot consolidation, or refinance a home;</section></section><section prefix="(2)">a developer that the Department reasonably believes can build or rehabilitate housing that a household of limited income can afford; and</section><section prefix="(3)">an owner-occupant of a residential building with not more than four units if each unit other than the owner's will be occupied by a household of limited income.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">For each type of loan described in &#xA7; 4-804 of this subtitle, the Department periodically shall set:<section prefix="(i)">appropriate terms, including deferred payments on principal and interest; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">a preferred interest rate that may be as low as 0.0% or as high as is reasonable in light of the incomes of the proposed occupants.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">In setting these terms and interest rates, the Department shall take into account rates available in the conventional private housing market and the adjusted annual income and assets of prospective borrowers.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
