<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghs" order_by="" level="1">Housing and Community Development</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghs-12-705</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>705</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In addition to all other rights that a contract may confer on an obligee of an authority, subject only to binding contractual restrictions, the obligee may:<section prefix="(1)">by a writ of mandamus or a proceeding at law or in equity, compel the authority and the authority's commissioners, officers, agents, or employees to perform each term, provision, and covenant contained in a contract of the authority with or for the benefit of the obligee;</section><section prefix="(2)">require the carrying out of any covenant or agreement of the authority and the fulfillment of all duties imposed on the authority by this Division II; and</section><section prefix="(3)">by a proceeding in equity, enjoin any unlawful act or thing or the violation of any right of the obligee.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">By resolution, trust indenture, mortgage, lease, or other contract, an authority may confer the right to take action under subsection (c) of this section if a default, as defined in the resolution or instrument, occurs.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The right may be conferred on an obligee that:<section prefix="(i)">holds or represents a specified amount in bonds or notes; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">holds a mortgage, deed of trust, security instrument, or lease.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">An obligee that has the right under subsection (b) of this section to take action under this subsection may, by a proceeding in a court of competent jurisdiction:<section prefix="(i)">have possession of all or part of a housing project surrendered to any such obligee;</section><section prefix="(ii)">require the authority and its commissioners to account as if the authority and its commissioners were trustees of an express trust; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">have a receiver appointed for all or part of a housing project and its rents and profits.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If a receiver is appointed, the receiver may:<section prefix="(i)">enter and take possession of the housing project or any part of the housing project;</section><section prefix="(ii)">operate and maintain it; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">collect and receive all fees, rents, revenues, or other charges thereafter arising from it.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The receiver shall keep the money in a separate account or accounts and apply the money in accordance with the obligations of the authority as the court directs.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
