<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="ghs" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="9-204" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghs-9-204</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Subject to the requirements of this title, the organizational documents of the Fund shall govern the operation of the Board, including quorum and voting requirements.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Board has all powers arising from the documents and procedures creating and organizing the Fund as an independent legal entity.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Board shall:<section prefix="(1)">operate the Fund;</section><section prefix="(2)">keep proper records of the Board's accounts;</section><section prefix="(3)">establish standards and guidelines for:<section prefix="(i)">the terms and conditions of community reinvestment assistance and other Fund reinvestments; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">allocating community reinvestment assistance and other Fund investments;</section></section><section prefix="(4)">apportion among Fund transactions the operating costs of the Fund; and</section><section prefix="(5)">within the first 90 days of each fiscal year, make an annual report of Fund activities to the Governor and, subject to &#xA7; 2-1246 of the State Government Article, to the General Assembly.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Board shall appoint a loan committee to review and make determinations on specific requests or categories of requests for community reinvestment assistance to community reinvestment projects.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The loan committee may review and make recommendations to the Board on other matters as the Board determines, including eligibility guidelines and financing policies for community reinvestment projects.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The loan committee consists of:<section prefix="(i)">the Secretary of Housing and Community Development and the Secretary of Business and Economic Development or their designees as nonvoting members; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">the voting members that the Board appoints or their designees.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
