<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghs" order_by="ghs" level="1">Housing and Community Development</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghs-12-207</section_number>
  <catch_line>Articles of amendment or restatement of articles of organization of an authority must be:...</catch_line>
  <order_by>207</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Articles of amendment or restatement of articles of organization of an authority must be:<section prefix="(1)">recommended in writing by the chief elected official;</section><section prefix="(2)">if required by subsection (d) of this section, approved by a resolution of the board of commissioners of the authority; and</section><section prefix="(3)">adopted by a resolution or ordinance of the legislative body.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">An amendment or restatement of articles of organization shall comply with &#xA7; 12-205(b) through (d) of this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A political subdivision may not amend the articles of organization to change the number of commissioners of an authority or the length of terms of commissioners stated in the initial articles of organization.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A political subdivision may not amend the articles of organization of a pre-existing authority without the approval of the board of commissioners of the pre-existing authority.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The custodian of records shall file with the Secretary of State:<section prefix="(1)">a copy of the articles of amendment or restatement, the recommending and adopting instruments required by subsection (a)(1) and (3) of this section, and any approving instrument required by subsection (a)(2) of this section;</section><section prefix="(2)">the certification of the custodian of records that the articles of amendment or restatement have been recommended and adopted by the political subdivision in accordance with the requirements of subsection (a)(1) and (3) of this section; and</section><section prefix="(3)">if required by subsection (a)(2) of this section, the certification of the secretary of the authority that the articles of amendment or restatement have been approved by the board of commissioners of the authority in accordance with the requirements of subsection (a)(2) of this section.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If the Secretary of State finds that the requirements of subsections (a) and (e) of this section have been met, the Secretary of State shall endorse the articles of amendment or restatement as "approved" and issue an attached certificate of approval.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">On issuance of the certificate of approval, the articles of amendment or restatement as filed are considered to have been adopted.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
