<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghs" order_by="" level="1">Housing and Community Development</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghs-4-245</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>245</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Administration may:<section prefix="(i)">borrow money and issue bonds or notes; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">use the proceeds or the earnings from the investment of the proceeds to provide money to:<section prefix="1.">make, purchase, or participate in making mortgage loans or other loans;</section><section prefix="2.">purchase securities backed by mortgage loans or other loans;</section><section prefix="3.">purchase local obligations;</section><section prefix="4.">meet any development cost; or</section><section prefix="5.">achieve any other purpose of the Administration.</section></section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Bonds or notes may be issued only if:<section prefix="(i)">the Director, or a person that the Secretary designates, determines that the issuance is necessary to achieve one or more purposes of the Administration; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">the Secretary approves the determination.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Without any other proceeding, action, or approval, the determination is effective when approved by the Secretary and is conclusive.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">For bonds or notes of any issue, the Administration has absolute discretion to determine:<section prefix="(1)">the date, amount, and manner of issue, including private sale;</section><section prefix="(2)">the date of maturity, which:<section prefix="(i)">for a bond, may not be more than 50 years after the bond is issued; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">for a note, including renewals, may not be more than 5 years after the note is originally issued;</section></section><section prefix="(3)">the price to be paid, whether above, at, or below par, the interest rate to be paid, and the dates of payment;</section><section prefix="(4)">the form, denomination, and manner of execution, which may be by facsimile;</section><section prefix="(5)">the place of payment, which may be any bank or trust company in or out of the State;</section><section prefix="(6)">whether they are redeemable before maturity and, if so, the terms, conditions, and prices of the redemption; and</section><section prefix="(7)">any other matter relating to the form, terms, conditions, security, issuance, sale, delivery, replacement, and indemnification in connection with replacement or payment.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A bond or note issued under this section is a negotiable instrument under State law notwithstanding any other provision of the Code or any recital in the bond or note.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The manual or facsimile signature of an officer or employee of the Administration that appears on a bond, note, or coupon is valid even if the individual leaves office or employment before delivery of the bond, note, or coupon.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The Administration may:<section prefix="(1)">issue its bonds or notes in coupon or registered form or both; and</section><section prefix="(2)">provide for:<section prefix="(i)">registration of coupon bonds or notes as to principal only or as to both principal and interest;</section><section prefix="(ii)">reconversion into coupon form of bonds or notes registered as to both principal and interest; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">interchange of coupon and registered bonds or notes.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">A bond or note issued under this section is exempt from &#xA7;&#xA7; 8-206, 8-208, and 8-213 through 8-221 of the State Finance and Procurement Article.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">The Administration may issue a bond or note without:<section prefix="(1)">the consent of another governmental unit of the State; or</section><section prefix="(2)">a proceeding, or the occurrence of a condition, other than those that this section expressly requires.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(h)">The Secretary and any other person executing a bond or note under this section are not personally liable or accountable because the bond or note is issued.</section>
  </text>
</law>
