<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghs" order_by="ghs" level="1">Housing and Community Development</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghs-13-107</section_number>
  <catch_line>Except as provided in paragraph (3) of this subsection, the Annapolis Authority shall publish notice...</catch_line>
  <order_by>107</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in paragraph (3) of this subsection, the Annapolis Authority shall publish notice of each of its meetings in at least two newspapers of general circulation in the City of Annapolis at least 7 days before the meeting.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The notice shall contain:<section prefix="(i)">the date, time, and place of the meeting; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">a summary of the subject matter to be considered at the meeting.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Chair of the Annapolis Authority may waive the notice required under paragraph (1) of this subsection for an emergency meeting if:<section prefix="(i)">notice cannot reasonably be given; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">minutes of the emergency meeting will be included in the minutes of the next open meeting of the Annapolis Authority.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The Annapolis Authority may add an item to the agenda for the meeting after publication of the notice if the item is necessary to the business of the Annapolis Authority and could not reasonably have been placed on the agenda when the notice was published.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Annapolis Authority may meet in closed session or adjourn an open session and reconvene in a closed session only to:<section prefix="(i)">discuss the appointment, employment, assignment, promotion, discipline, demotion, removal, or resignation of appointees, employees, or officials over whom the Annapolis Authority has jurisdiction;</section><section prefix="(ii)">consider the acquisition of real property for a public purpose and matters directly related to the acquisition;</section><section prefix="(iii)">consult with counsel;</section><section prefix="(iv)">consult with staff, consultants, or other individuals about pending or potential litigation;</section><section prefix="(v)">comply with a specific constitutional, statutory, or judicially imposed requirement that prevents public disclosures about a particular proceeding or matter; or</section><section prefix="(vi)">satisfy an exceptional reason, if at least two-thirds of the Commissioners present vote to find that the reason is so compelling that it overrides the general public policy in favor of open sessions.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Annapolis Authority meeting in closed session under this section may not discuss or act on any matter not specified under paragraph (1) of this subsection.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
