<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="ghs" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="4-927" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghs-4-927</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">There is an Indoor Plumbing Program.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Department shall:<section prefix="(1)">operate the Indoor Plumbing Program; and</section><section prefix="(2)">make loans for rehabilitation projects that provide for adequate indoor plumbing from the Special Loan Programs Fund under this subtitle.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The terms for indoor plumbing loans shall meet the requirements of &#xA7;&#xA7; 4-917 through 4-919 of this subtitle.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Department may forgive all or part of a deferred payment loan, if:<section prefix="(i)">the loan is made to a family of limited income that owns and occupies the dwelling and whose income is within a lower income range established under &#xA7; 4-916(b) of this subtitle; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">the Secretary determines that the family of limited income does not have enough income to repay the principal amount of the loan.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">To qualify for an indoor plumbing loan, an applicant shall:<section prefix="(1)">own a building that is otherwise structurally sound, or for which the applicant provides a commitment from a lender to finance improvements needed to make the building structurally sound, and that:<section prefix="(i)">has no or incomplete indoor plumbing or a failing septic system; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">needs indoor plumbing pipes, equipment, wells, septic tanks or other on-site sewer system, or a connection to a community water or sewer system;</section></section><section prefix="(2)">live in the building and be a family of limited income, or rent at least two-thirds of the dwellings in the building to families of limited income; and</section><section prefix="(3)">submit to the Department a proposal for installing an adequate indoor plumbing system for water supply and sewage disposal, including any needed septic system, well, or connection to a community sewer or water system that meets the requirements of the Department of the Environment and every other governmental unit that has jurisdiction over the system.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
