<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="ghs" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="4-504" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghs-4-504</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, "Fund" means the Rental Housing Programs Fund.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">There is a Rental Housing Programs Fund.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Department shall use the Fund to:<section prefix="(i)">operate, make loans, and pay expenses of the Maryland Housing Rehabilitation Program, including reserves for anticipated future losses directly related to the Maryland Housing Rehabilitation Program, as provided in the State budget; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">operate, make loans, and pay expenses of the Rental Housing Production Program.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Administration shall use the Fund to operate, make loans, and pay expenses of the Elderly Rental Housing Program.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The Administration may use the Fund to make deferred payment loans to approved applicants to enable the applicants to acquire, construct, or rehabilitate elderly rental housing projects or to convert existing rental housing to elderly rental housing projects.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">Deferred payment loans may be subordinate to other financing.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Administration shall administer the Fund.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Fund consists of:<section prefix="(i)">money appropriated by the State for rental housing programs, including the Elderly Rental Housing Program under &#xA7; 4-402 of this title, the Multifamily Rehabilitation Program under &#xA7; 4-906(b) of this title, the Nonprofit Rehabilitation Program under &#xA7; 4-929 of this title, and the Rental Housing Production Program under &#xA7; 4-1502 of this title;</section><section prefix="(ii)">repayments and prepayments of loans made under the programs set forth in item (i) of this paragraph;</section><section prefix="(iii)">money appropriated under &#xA7; 4-501(c) of this subtitle;</section><section prefix="(iv)">money transferred to the Fund in accordance with &#xA7;&#xA7; 4-502(e), 4-503(d), and 4-505(h) of this subtitle and &#xA7;&#xA7; 3-203(i) and 6-310(g) of this article; and</section><section prefix="(v)">investment earnings of the Fund.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The State, under &#xA7; 4-501(c) of this subtitle, may appropriate to the Fund money received as repayment of principal or payment of interest on a loan made by the Maryland Housing Rehabilitation Program.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">When the Department issues a binding commitment to make a loan, the Department shall withdraw from the Fund an amount equal to the commitment.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Subject to &#xA7; 7-209 of the State Finance and Procurement Article and except as otherwise provided in the State budget, after the first 8 months of a fiscal year the Department may transfer unencumbered money in the Fund to any other fund established under this title.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
