<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghs" order_by="ghs" level="1">Housing and Community Development</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghs-4-1405</section_number>
  <catch_line>The Department may administer the programs by providing monthly housing assistance payments to or on...</catch_line>
  <order_by>1405</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Department may administer the programs by providing monthly housing assistance payments to or on behalf of eligible households directly or through political subdivisions, their local housing agencies or departments, or nonprofit organizations.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">In establishing the programs, the Department shall consult with, as appropriate:<section prefix="(1)">the Department of Human Resources;</section><section prefix="(2)">the Department of Disabilities; or</section><section prefix="(3)">any other unit of State or local government.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Secretary shall establish criteria for the programs, including:<section prefix="(1)">income limits for eligibility of households;</section><section prefix="(2)">time frames for assistance;</section><section prefix="(3)">monthly assistance amounts;</section><section prefix="(4)">standards for eligible dwelling units, including types of units, inspection standards, and rent limits;</section><section prefix="(5)">eligible uses of assistance payments which may include security deposits, utilities, and other housing related expenses; and</section><section prefix="(6)">any other criteria the Secretary considers appropriate.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">In establishing the program criteria, the Secretary may consider factors that include:<section prefix="(1)">household size and expected average income;</section><section prefix="(2)">regional variations throughout the State;</section><section prefix="(3)">typical housing costs and expenses;</section><section prefix="(4)">relevant standards and definitions established for State and federal housing programs;</section><section prefix="(5)">housing needs of eligible households and the expected duration of the housing needs; and</section><section prefix="(6)">equitable distribution of funds statewide.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The Secretary may establish different criteria for different programs.</section>
  </text>
</law>
