<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghs" order_by="ghs" level="1">Housing and Community Development</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghs-4-213</section_number>
  <catch_line>In accordance with regulations that the Secretary adopts, an agreement that the Administration makes...</catch_line>
  <order_by>213</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In accordance with regulations that the Secretary adopts, an agreement that the Administration makes to carry out its functions and responsibilities under &#xA7;&#xA7; 4-211, 4-214, and 4-225 through 4-235 of this subtitle shall be approved by:<section prefix="(1)">the Secretary; and</section><section prefix="(2)">the Board of Public Works, if its approval is required by law.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Administration shall get approval of the land use for a community development project by resolution of the appropriate governing body of the locality in which the development is located before:<section prefix="(1)"><section prefix="(i)">acquiring, owning, or holding land that is not open, mainly open, or undeveloped, personal property, or mixed property;</section><section prefix="(ii)">clearing, improving, constructing, or rehabilitating the property; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">transferring, leasing, mortgaging, or otherwise disposing of the property; or</section></section><section prefix="(2)">building housing on any land.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A project that the Administration finances is subject to applicable zoning and building codes.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This subsection applies notwithstanding any other provision of this subtitle or other State law.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">In exercising its functions and responsibilities, the Administration may sell or lease for a term not exceeding 99 years all or part of the real, mixed, or personal property constituting a community development project.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A sale or lease under this section may be made:<section prefix="(i)">without public bidding or public sale; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">on terms and conditions that make housing in that development economically feasible for families of limited income.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">A sale or lease under this section shall conform with a plan for community development that the Secretary approves at a public hearing held after notice is published in at least one newspaper of general circulation in the political subdivision in which the development is located.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">The plan for community development presented at the hearing shall be in accordance with regulations that the Secretary adopts, requiring:<section prefix="(i)">a description of the property;</section><section prefix="(ii)">a statement of the identity of the proposed purchaser or lessee and the proposed use or reuse of the property;</section><section prefix="(iii)">the price or rental to be paid by the purchaser or lessee; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">the conditions of the sale or lease that ensure that the community development purposes of this subtitle will be carried out.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">In carrying out this subtitle, the Administration shall comply with local laws applicable to the community development project.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In carrying out this subtitle, the Administration shall:<section prefix="(i)">work closely, consult, and cooperate with local elected officials;</section><section prefix="(ii)">give primary consideration to local needs and desires;</section><section prefix="(iii)">foster local initiative and participation in community development activities; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">consider local and regional goals and policies as expressed in urban renewal, community renewal, and local comprehensive land use plans and regional plans.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Wherever possible, the Administration shall carry out community development projects together with and through the use of:<section prefix="(i)">private enterprise;</section><section prefix="(ii)">limited dividend corporations;</section><section prefix="(iii)">local development agencies; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">local development entities.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
