<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="ghs" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="4-917" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghs-4-917</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">A Program loan:<section prefix="(1)">may not be made if the Department determines that comparable private financing is available to the prospective borrower; and</section><section prefix="(2)">may not exceed an amount the Secretary establishes by regulation.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided under paragraphs (2), (3), and (4) of this subsection, a Program loan of more than $5,000 shall be secured wholly or partly by a recorded mortgage or deed of trust on real property.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A Program loan to a political subdivision may be secured by a recorded mortgage, deed of trust on real property, or other security device acceptable to the Department.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A Program loan to a trust described in 42 U.S.C. &#xA7; 1396p(d)(4) may be secured by a recorded mortgage, deed of trust on real property, or other security device acceptable to the Department.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Subject to subparagraph (ii) of this paragraph, a Program loan to a member of a cooperative housing corporation may be secured by a perfected security interest in the member's cooperative interest.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">Before a Program loan is secured by a perfected security interest in the member's cooperative interest, the Department shall enter into an agreement with the cooperative housing corporation that establishes the rights and obligations of the Department and the cooperative housing corporation with respect to the secured cooperative interest.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Program loans shall be made to:<section prefix="(1)">families of limited income owning and occupying the building to be rehabilitated; or</section><section prefix="(2)">sponsors or nonprofit sponsors.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Department may require that Program loans be insured.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">A Program loan may cover:<section prefix="(1)">costs of a rehabilitation project, including implementation costs such as appraisal, architectural, and engineering fees; and</section><section prefix="(2)">closing costs of the Program loan.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The Department may modify the interest rate, the time or amount of payment, or any other term of a Program loan that is in default to facilitate repayment of the Program loan and achieve the purposes of the Program.</section>
  </text>
</law>
