<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="ghs" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="4-221" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghs-4-221</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">A project or undertaking, including the real, personal, and mixed property involved, qualifies as a public purpose project if it is planned, acquired, owned, developed, constructed, reconstructed, rehabilitated, repaired, renovated, or improved with the financial assistance of the Administration or the assistance of federal low-income housing credits authorized by the Internal Revenue Code, and it is:<section prefix="(1)">eligible wholly or partly for federal low-income housing credits; or</section><section prefix="(2)">located in a distressed area designated under subsection (e) of this section.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Except as provided in subsection (c) of this section, a public purpose project:<section prefix="(1)">shall provide in substantial part for existing or new housing; and</section><section prefix="(2)">may include:<section prefix="(i)">any improvements, such as streets, roads, sewer lines, and water lines; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">public or private commercial, educational, cultural, recreational, community, or civic facilities.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A public purpose project may include a greater proportion of public or private facilities if the Secretary determines that to do so would promote sound community development.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">All or part of the housing portion of a public purpose project shall be occupied by families of limited income.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">At the request of a political subdivision, the Secretary may designate a distressed area of the political subdivision after considering factors including:<section prefix="(1)">the availability, cost, and condition of housing and neighborhood facilities, including the age and number of abandoned and substandard structures;</section><section prefix="(2)">the incomes of residents relative to State or area-wide regional median incomes, including the number of individuals who are welfare recipients, unemployed, or living in poverty;</section><section prefix="(3)">the need to finance housing or public or private facilities to upgrade the social and economic conditions of the distressed area;</section><section prefix="(4)">the plans and financial commitment of the political subdivision to undertake improvements in the distressed area; and</section><section prefix="(5)">other standards and criteria that the Secretary considers relevant, including standards established for other State or federal programs.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
