<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghs" order_by="ghs" level="1">Housing and Community Development</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghs-6-204</section_number>
  <catch_line>A sponsor may file one or more applications in accordance with the schedules that the Department est...</catch_line>
  <order_by>204</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">A sponsor may file one or more applications in accordance with the schedules that the Department establishes.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">An application shall set forth:<section prefix="(1)">a description of one or more sustainable communities where the sponsor proposes to develop a sustainable community plan or to carry out a community legacy project using the standards listed in &#xA7; 6-205 of this subtitle;</section><section prefix="(2)">a detailed description of the proposed sustainable community plan or proposed community legacy project;</section><section prefix="(3)">the amount and type of financial assistance sought;</section><section prefix="(4)">the ability of the sponsor to carry out the proposed sustainable community plan or community legacy project;</section><section prefix="(5)">the strength and quality of partnerships created among the federal government, the State government, political subdivisions, community development organizations, and other private organizations to develop the sustainable community plan or carry out the community legacy project, including:<section prefix="(i)">financial support;</section><section prefix="(ii)">dedication of staff and resources; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">commitment to and development of local smart growth policies;</section></section><section prefix="(6)">proposed benchmarks for evaluating whether the proposed sustainable community plan or community legacy project results in a desired outcome for a proposed sustainable community, such as:<section prefix="(i)">stabilizing it;</section><section prefix="(ii)">reversing its social, economic, or physical decline; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">encouraging growth in it; and</section></section><section prefix="(7)">the process used to seek and receive public input on the proposed sustainable community plan or community legacy project, including the nature and extent of public support or opposition.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Smart Growth Subcabinet, on the recommendation of the Secretary, may designate an area as a sustainable community.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If the Smart Growth Subcabinet has not acted within 90 days of a recommendation from the Secretary, the Secretary may designate an area as a sustainable community without the approval of the Smart Growth Subcabinet.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
