<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="ghs" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="6-208" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghs-6-208</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Subject to this section, the Department has the powers necessary or desirable to implement the Program.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Department may determine the terms and conditions for financial assistance awarded under &#xA7; 6-206(c) of this subtitle.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Financial assistance may be secured by a mortgage, lien, or security interest that is superior to or subordinate to other mortgages, liens, or security interests.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Department may establish time limits for the use of financial assistance.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Department may enforce the terms and conditions of the financial assistance given under this subtitle.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Notwithstanding any other law, if a loan or grant is secured by a first or subordinate mortgage or other lien, the Department may:<section prefix="(i)">begin an action to protect or enforce any right given by law, a contract, or other agreement;</section><section prefix="(ii)">foreclose on property;</section><section prefix="(iii)">purchase property at any foreclosure or other sale, or acquire or take possession of the property through conveyance in lieu of foreclosure or otherwise, and convey property after acquiring it;</section><section prefix="(iv)">settle or compromise any debt or obligation owed to the Department;</section><section prefix="(v)">pay the principal of and interest on any obligation incurred in connection with the property, and dispose of or otherwise deal with the property to protect the interests of the Program; or</section><section prefix="(vi)">release or sell any mortgage, obligation, or property that the Department holds at public or private sale, with or without public bidding.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Department may contract with any person, including a private property manager, mortgage servicer, architect, engineer, or other property consultant, or with any governmental unit, for property or services necessary to operate the Program or to implement community legacy projects.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Department may make agreements with other governmental units to establish partnerships to carry out the Program.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Department may contract for and accept any grant, contribution, or loan of money, property, or other aid from the federal government and may do all things consistent with this subtitle to qualify for the aid or participate in or administer a federal program.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">In connection with loans that it makes, the Department may:<section prefix="(1)">require and obtain appraisals, credit information, and other pertinent information; and</section><section prefix="(2)">charge interest.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">When it is consistent with the best interests of the State to do so, the Department may consent to the modification of any provision of any loan or other financial assistance.</section>
  </text>
</law>
