<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghs" order_by="" level="1">Housing and Community Development</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghs-4-801</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>801</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Adjusted annual income" means gross income from all sources with adjustments, as determined by the Department, made for unusual or temporary income items and long-term unusual expenses such as medical, rehabilitation, or special education expenses.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Adjusted annual income" includes:<section prefix="(i)">wages;</section><section prefix="(ii)">investment income;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Social Security payments;</section><section prefix="(iv)">retirement payments;</section><section prefix="(v)">disability payments; and</section><section prefix="(vi)">unemployment insurance payments.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Fund" means the Homeownership Programs Fund under Subtitle 5 of this title.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">"Household of limited income" means one or more individuals whose aggregate adjusted annual income does not exceed the upper income limits that the Secretary sets under &#xA7; 4-807 of this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"Lot consolidation" means the acquisition of real property adjacent to and in connection with a residence financed by the Program to include the real property as part of the residence.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">"Median annual family income" means the median annual family income for the State, county, or area, whichever is greatest, as shown in the latest Census Bureau Report of the United States Department of Commerce.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">"Preferred interest rate" means an interest rate that the Department sets under &#xA7; 4-806(c) of this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">"Program" means the Maryland Home Financing Program.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">"Region" means an area of the State that the Department establishes comprising one or more counties.</section>
    <section prefix="(j)">"Short-term loan" means a loan that, under the loan documents, is expected to be taken out by other financing within 7 years.</section>
  </text>
</law>
