<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghs" order_by="ghs" level="1">Housing and Community Development</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghs-4-1607</section_number>
  <catch_line>The legislative body of a covered county that issues bonds under this subtitle shall determine:...</catch_line>
  <order_by>1607</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The legislative body of a covered county that issues bonds under this subtitle shall determine:<section prefix="(1)">the time or times when interest is to be paid on the bonds;</section><section prefix="(2)">the time or times when the bonds are to be executed, issued, and delivered;</section><section prefix="(3)">the form, denomination, and tenor of the bonds;</section><section prefix="(4)">the time or times when the principal of the bonds is to be paid, which may not be more than 40 years after the bonds are issued; and</section><section prefix="(5)">the place or places where the bonds are to be paid.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The bonds may be secured by:<section prefix="(1)">a pledge of mortgages or notes secured by deeds of trust on any type of interest in real or other property, including the real property or other interests held by stock cooperatives or condominiums and their unit owners;</section><section prefix="(2)">servicing agreements;</section><section prefix="(3)">condemnation proceeds;</section><section prefix="(4)">private, governmental, or other mortgage insurance proceeds;</section><section prefix="(5)">casualty or special hazard insurance proceeds; or</section><section prefix="(6)">any other security that the legislative body of the covered county finds appropriate.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The bonds may provide that, at the option of the covered county, the bonds or any one of them may be called for redemption before maturity, at a price and under the terms and conditions that the legislative body of the covered county fixed before issuing the bonds.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The following are exempt at all times from taxation of every kind and nature whatsoever by the State or a county:<section prefix="(1)">the principal of a bond;</section><section prefix="(2)">the transfer of, interest payable on, or income derived from a bond; and</section><section prefix="(3)">profit made by the sale or transfer of a bond.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">A bond issued under this subtitle is a negotiable instrument.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">A covered county may:<section prefix="(1)">issue its bonds in coupon form; or</section><section prefix="(2)">provide for registration of the bonds as to principal alone or principal and interest.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The bonds shall be signed by a commissioner or other chief executive officer of the covered county.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The seal of the covered county shall be affixed to the bond and attested to by the clerk or the officer exercising the functions of a clerk.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">An officer's signature or countersignature that appears on bonds or coupons is valid even if the officer leaves office before delivery of the bonds.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
