<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghs" order_by="" level="1">Housing and Community Development</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghs-4-1208</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>1208</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">A political subdivision or housing authority may participate in the Program and do all things necessary or convenient to its participation, including:<section prefix="(1)">developing, acquiring, improving, owning, operating, and managing rental housing;</section><section prefix="(2)">borrowing money; and</section><section prefix="(3)">mortgaging, pledging, and granting a security interest in real or personal property related to a particular partnership project.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Department may not require a political subdivision or housing authority to repay money made available under the Program, unless the political subdivision or housing authority:<section prefix="(1)">sells the partnership project; or</section><section prefix="(2)">fails to operate the partnership project for the benefit of households of lower income in accordance with agreements between the Department and the political subdivision or housing authority.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Department shall secure the obligations of the political subdivision, housing authority, or private sector entity by using a mortgage, deed of trust, or other security device that the Department accepts on the property or on revenues derived from the property.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">To allow for more affordable rents, a political subdivision or housing authority may contribute local money, including locally administered federal money or federal rental assistance.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The contributions of political subdivisions or housing authorities under &#xA7; 4-1207(a)(2)(iii) of this subtitle may include the costs of:<section prefix="(i)">necessary studies, surveys, tests, plans, and specifications;</section><section prefix="(ii)">architectural, design, engineering, and other special services;</section><section prefix="(iii)">site preparation;</section><section prefix="(iv)">indemnity and surety bonds and premiums on title and hazard insurance; and</section><section prefix="(v)">other costs of development.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">To participate in the Program and to receive loans, a political subdivision or housing authority may not be required to pledge its full faith and credit.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">For rental housing financed from the Fund and owned or managed by a housing authority, this subtitle supersedes:<section prefix="(1)">&#xA7;&#xA7; 12-401, 12-402, and 12-405 of this article; and</section><section prefix="(2)">all other restrictions on tenant income under Division II of this article.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
