<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghs" order_by="ghs" level="1">Housing and Community Development</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghs-15-108</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this section, "Baltimore Authority police officer" means a member of the Housing Authority of Bal...</catch_line>
  <order_by>108</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, "Baltimore Authority police officer" means a member of the Housing Authority of Baltimore City Police Force who, when acting in an official capacity, may make arrests.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">There is a Housing Authority of Baltimore City Police Force.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Executive Director of the Baltimore Authority or the Director's designee shall appoint the Baltimore Authority police officers.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A Baltimore Authority police officer has all of the powers of a law enforcement officer in the State.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A Baltimore Authority police officer may exercise these powers on property that is owned, leased, operated by, or under the control of the Baltimore Authority.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A Baltimore Authority police officer may exercise these powers elsewhere only if:<section prefix="(i)">doing so is necessary to facilitate the orderly flow of traffic to or from property that is owned, leased, operated by, or under the control of the Baltimore Authority; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">the officer is:<section prefix="1.">ordered to do so by the Mayor of Baltimore City;</section><section prefix="2.">asked or authorized to do so by the Police Commissioner of Baltimore City; or</section><section prefix="3.">engaged in fresh pursuit of a suspected offender.</section></section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Baltimore Authority shall adopt standards, qualifications, and prerequisites of character, training, education, human and public relations, experience, and performance for Baltimore Authority police officers.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">To the extent feasible, the standards shall be similar to those adopted for the Baltimore City Police Department.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This section does not:<section prefix="(i)">treat a Baltimore Authority police officer as a member of the Baltimore City Police Department; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">affect the salary, benefits, or retirement program of an employee of the Baltimore Authority.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The list of powers in this section does not imply that the exercise of powers by the Baltimore Authority before July 1, 1991, was unauthorized.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
