<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghs" order_by="" level="1">Housing and Community Development</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghs-4-1501</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>1501</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Development costs" means costs incurred to construct or rehabilitate a project.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Development costs" includes the costs of:<section prefix="(i)">necessary studies, surveys, plans, or specifications;</section><section prefix="(ii)">architectural, engineering, or other specialized services;</section><section prefix="(iii)">the acquisition of land or improvements;</section><section prefix="(iv)">site preparation or development;</section><section prefix="(v)">construction, reconstruction, rehabilitation, ancillary demolition, lot consolidation, or improvement;</section><section prefix="(vi)">acquisition of necessary machinery, equipment, or furnishings;</section><section prefix="(vii)">the initial occupancy expenses of the project;</section><section prefix="(viii)">indemnity bonds, surety bonds, or insurance premiums; and</section><section prefix="(ix)">other fees or relocation expenses.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Family of lower income" means a family or individual whose income:<section prefix="(1)">does not exceed the upper income limits that the Secretary establishes under &#xA7; 4-1505 of this subtitle; and</section><section prefix="(2)">is lower than the income limits established for families of limited income as provided in &#xA7; 4-212 of this title.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">"Fund" means the Rental Housing Programs Fund under Subtitle 5 of this title.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"Office or other commercial space conversion" means the conversion to rental housing of a building that:<section prefix="(1)">is in a sustainable community as defined in &#xA7; 6-301 of this article;</section><section prefix="(2)">was built more than 30 years before an application is submitted to the Department to finance the conversion;</section><section prefix="(3)">consists of at least two floors at or above ground level; and</section><section prefix="(4)">was last used as office or other commercial space.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Operating costs" means a cost that a sponsor of a completed project incurs that is necessary to maintain or operate a project.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Operating costs" includes payments of principal and interest on a loan to cover development costs.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">"Program" means the Rental Housing Production Program.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">"Program loan" means a loan that the Department makes under this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">"Project" means a rental housing production project that meets the qualifications under &#xA7; 4-1504 of this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(j)">"Sponsor" means the Department, a political subdivision, or a person that applies for a Program loan.</section>
  </text>
</law>
