<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghs" order_by="" level="1">Housing and Community Development</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghs-4-708</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>708</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">There is a Lead Hazard Reduction Grant Program.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Department may make a grant solely to finance a lead hazard reduction activity that:<section prefix="(1)">is a program that tests innovative or unproven methods of lead hazard reduction; or</section><section prefix="(2)">is in a residential property in an area designated by the Department to have a concentration of:<section prefix="(i)">families of limited income; and</section><section prefix="(ii)"><section prefix="1.">residential property constructed before 1950; or</section><section prefix="2.">children diagnosed with elevated blood lead, which is a quantity of lead in their blood, expressed in micrograms per deciliter (&#xB5;g/dl), that exceeds a specified threshold level.</section></section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Department may establish standards to determine the eligibility of a lead hazard reduction activity for a grant under the Grant Program.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The standards may call for consideration of:<section prefix="(i)">the extent to which the lead hazard reduction activity benefits families of limited income;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the need and circumstances of the owner-occupants or tenants of the residential property in which the proposed lead hazard reduction activity will be undertaken; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">whether the grant finances research into innovative or unproven methods for lead hazard reduction.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">In determining whether to make a grant under the Grant Program, the Department shall require that the owner of the residential property or child care center submit evidence that the owner cannot undertake lead hazard reduction activity without a grant.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The Department may require that all or part of a grant under the Grant Program be repaid when conditions specified by the Department occur.</section>
  </text>
</law>
