<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="ghs" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="4-1004" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghs-4-1004</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">To be eligible for a grant under this subtitle, a neighborhood corporation or umbrella corporation shall:<section prefix="(1)">submit a timely application in the form that the Secretary prescribes;</section><section prefix="(2)">create a board of directors composed of:<section prefix="(i)">a member of the General Assembly;</section><section prefix="(ii)">neighborhood residents;</section><section prefix="(iii)">representatives of local financial institutions; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">representatives of local political subdivisions, if not inconsistent with local law;</section></section><section prefix="(3)">be authorized to establish and administer a revolving loan fund by lending money at flexible rates and terms to neighborhood homeowners who cannot obtain mortgage financing on reasonable terms through normal lending channels to preserve or revitalize neighborhoods and encourage homeownership; and</section><section prefix="(4)">be authorized to establish and administer, in cooperation with appropriate officials of the political subdivision, a housing program to bring neighborhood dwellings to acceptable levels of health and safety.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Secretary or the Secretary's designee shall be a voting member of each neighborhood corporation receiving grants from the Department.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">An application for a grant under subsection (a)(1) of this section shall contain:<section prefix="(1)">a description of the boundaries of the area that the neighborhood corporation or Program serves;</section><section prefix="(2)">certification that the applicant is registered with the Neighborhood Reinvestment Corporation;</section><section prefix="(3)">certification of incorporation under State law;</section><section prefix="(4)">certification of receipt of a ruling from the Internal Revenue Service that the applicant is exempt from federal income taxation;</section><section prefix="(5)">certification that the portion of the applicant's annual operating budget that will not be covered by the grant sought has been provided exclusively from political subdivisions or private sources; and</section><section prefix="(6)">any other information that the Secretary requires.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
