<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghs" order_by="ghs" level="1">Housing and Community Development</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghs-6-305</section_number>
  <catch_line>A small business, nonprofit organization, or microenterprise may apply for financial assistance unde...</catch_line>
  <order_by>305</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A small business, nonprofit organization, or microenterprise may apply for financial assistance under the Business Development Program.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Department shall review each application.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">An applicant may qualify for financial assistance for a project in a sustainable community if the application demonstrates that:<section prefix="(1)">except for a microenterprise project, the project has significant commitments for financing from other private and nonstate public sources that are sufficient to complete the project with the money from the Fund;</section><section prefix="(2)">the financial assistance from the Fund is the minimum amount necessary to make the project financially feasible;</section><section prefix="(3)">the project is ready to proceed when it receives financial assistance from the Business Development Program; and</section><section prefix="(4)">the political subdivision has adopted a resolution, or its authorized designee has delivered a letter to the Business Development Program, that expresses support for the project.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Financial assistance under the Business Development Program may be provided to a small business, nonprofit organization, or microenterprise as:<section prefix="(1)">a grant;</section><section prefix="(2)">a loan;</section><section prefix="(3)">a reduction in the principal obligation of or interest rate on a loan or portion of a loan;</section><section prefix="(4)">a prepayment of interest on a subordinate or superior loan or portion of a loan;</section><section prefix="(5)">an assurance;</section><section prefix="(6)">a guarantee; or</section><section prefix="(7)">any other form of credit enhancement.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
