<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghs" order_by="ghs" level="1">Housing and Community Development</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghs-16-306</section_number>
  <catch_line>The labor relations administrator shall hold an election for an exclusive representative after:...</catch_line>
  <order_by>306</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The labor relations administrator shall hold an election for an exclusive representative after:<section prefix="(1)">an employee organization shows by petition that at least 30% of the eligible employees in a bargaining unit support representation by an exclusive representative for collective bargaining; or</section><section prefix="(2)">an employee or an employee organization shows by petition that at least 30% of the eligible employees in a bargaining unit no longer support the current exclusive representative.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Elections may not be held:<section prefix="(i)">within 1 year after the date of an election under this subtitle; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, during the term of a collective bargaining agreement.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">During the term of a collective bargaining agreement, a petition for an election may be filed only in November of the fiscal year in which the agreement expires.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">At least 30 days before an election under subsection (a) of this section, the labor relations administrator shall get from the Montgomery Commission and provide to the employee organization a list of the name, home address, and telephone number of each employee in the bargaining unit.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Providing a list under this subsection by the Montgomery Commission, the labor relations administrator, or any Montgomery Commission officials, employees, or other agents does not violate &#xA7; 10-617(e) of the State Government Article or any State or local law.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">An election shall be held by secret ballot.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The ballot shall contain:<section prefix="(1)">the name of each employee organization that submits a valid petition for an election;</section><section prefix="(2)">the name of any other employee organization supported by a petition signed by at least 10% of the eligible employees in the bargaining unit; and</section><section prefix="(3)">an option for no representation.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If a petition described in subsection (a)(1) is submitted at the same time that a petition described in subsection (a)(2) is submitted, one election shall be held to determine which employee organization, if any, shall be the exclusive representative.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The ballot shall contain:<section prefix="(i)">the name of the current certified employee organization;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the name of the petitioning employee organization; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">a provision for "no representation".</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">If none of the choices on the ballot receives a majority of the votes, the labor relations administrator shall hold a runoff election between the two choices receiving the most votes.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">
      <section prefix="(1)">After the election, the labor relations administrator shall certify the employee organization with the most votes as the exclusive representative.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If the petitioning employee organization is certified as a result of an election carried out under subsection (f) of this section, that employee organization shall be treated as a successor in interest and party to any collective bargaining agreement to which the previous employee organization was a party.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(i)">The Montgomery Commission and the employee organization shall share the costs of the election procedures equally.</section>
  </text>
</law>
