<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghs" order_by="ghs" level="1">Housing and Community Development</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghs-2-116</section_number>
  <catch_line>This section does not apply to a governmental unit in the Department to the extent that the governme...</catch_line>
  <order_by>116</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">This section does not apply to a governmental unit in the Department to the extent that the governmental unit is authorized by law to employ its own legal adviser or counsel.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Attorney General is the legal adviser to the Department.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Attorney General shall assign to the Department the number of assistant Attorneys General authorized by law for the Department and its governmental units.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">An assistant Attorney General shall be a lawyer of the State in good standing.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">An assistant Attorney General is entitled to the compensation provided in the State budget.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Attorney General shall designate one of the assistant Attorneys General as counsel to the Department and may not reassign the counsel without consulting the Secretary.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The counsel to the Department has no duty other than to:<section prefix="(i)">give the legal aid, advice, and counsel that the Secretary and the other officials of the Department require; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">supervise the other assistant Attorneys General assigned to the Department.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The counsel shall perform the duties specified in paragraph (2) of this subsection subject to the control and discretion of the Attorney General.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The counsel and the other assistant Attorneys General in the Department shall perform those duties that the Attorney General assigns.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Attorney General may require an assistant Attorney General to perform, subject to the Attorney General's control and discretion, any duty for the Department required of the Attorney General by law.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
