<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghs" order_by="ghs" level="1">Housing and Community Development</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghs-12-105</section_number>
  <catch_line>An authority of a municipal corporation or Baltimore City may:...</catch_line>
  <order_by>105</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">An authority of a municipal corporation or Baltimore City may:<section prefix="(1)">operate within its territorial boundaries; and</section><section prefix="(2)">without regard to location:<section prefix="(i)">administer rent subsidy payments and housing assistance programs for both eligible landlords and tenants;</section><section prefix="(ii)">own or manage housing projects in operation before January 1, 1990; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">develop, own, or operate a housing project at the request of and within the territorial boundaries of another political subdivision.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Anywhere in its county an authority of a county may:<section prefix="(i)">administer rent subsidy payments and housing assistance programs for both eligible landlords and tenants; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">own or manage housing projects in operation before:<section prefix="1.">January 1, 1990, if the authority is of Baltimore City; or</section><section prefix="2.">January 1, 1991, if the authority is of another county.</section></section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Subject to paragraph (3) of this subsection, an authority of a county may conduct its other operations within the county.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">An authority of a county other than Baltimore City may not conduct its other operations within a municipal corporation unless the governing body of the municipal corporation consents by resolution to its inclusion in the authority's area of operation.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">An authority created under &#xA7; 12-208 of this title may conduct its operations in the area prescribed under its articles of organization.</section>
  </text>
</law>
