<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghs" order_by="ghs" level="1">Housing and Community Development</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghs-6-209</section_number>
  <catch_line>The purposes of a neighborhood intervention project are to provide financial assistance for:...</catch_line>
  <order_by>209</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The purposes of a neighborhood intervention project are to provide financial assistance for:<section prefix="(1)">buying properties that need rehabilitation and redeveloping the properties through rehabilitation, demolition, reconstruction, or re-use; or</section><section prefix="(2)">demolishing property improvements and preparing property for revitalization, redevelopment, or re-use.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">To be eligible for financial assistance for a neighborhood intervention project, an applicant shall be:<section prefix="(1)">a political subdivision; or</section><section prefix="(2)">a community development finance institution.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">To be eligible for financial assistance, the applicant must provide evidence at the time of application that:<section prefix="(1)">the applicant has a legal interest in the property through:<section prefix="(i)">ownership of the property;</section><section prefix="(ii)">a contract, option, or other legal right to acquire the property; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">the right to demolish the improvements on the property;</section></section><section prefix="(2)">the applicant intends to revitalize, redevelop, sell, or re-use the property as part of a redevelopment strategy for the property or a redevelopment plan;</section><section prefix="(3)">the applicant has complied with the requirements of &#xA7;&#xA7; 5A-325 and 5A-326 of the State Finance and Procurement Article and &#xA7; 13-1112(b) of the Financial Institutions Article;</section><section prefix="(4)">the financial assistance from the Program is the least amount necessary to complete the project; and</section><section prefix="(5)">the project meets any other condition that the Department may require under this subtitle.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Unless waived by the Secretary, a neighborhood intervention project shall meet the additional following requirements:<section prefix="(1)">the project shall be located in a sustainable community and be a part of a sustainable community plan in accordance with &#xA7;&#xA7; 6-204(b)(1) and 6-205 of this subtitle; and</section><section prefix="(2)">for a project under subsection (a)(2) of this section, the applicant shall agree to repay the financial assistance to the Community Legacy Financial Assistance Fund, up to the amount the applicant receives from:<section prefix="(i)">the net proceeds of the sale of the property on which the demolition took place; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">any payment to the applicant relating to the property, including any payment for the costs of demolishing the improvements on the property.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Secretary may not allocate annually more than 15% of the Community Legacy Financial Assistance Fund to neighborhood intervention projects.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Secretary may not award more than $500,000 for any neighborhood intervention project.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The restrictions in paragraphs (1) and (2) of this subsection do not apply to projects approved by the Secretary in the case of an emergency or when the project requires urgent approval if the project is funded from the reserve established under &#xA7; 6-211(h) of this subtitle.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
