<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghs" order_by="" level="1">Housing and Community Development</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghs-4-502</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>502</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, "Fund" means the Homeownership Programs Fund.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">There is a Homeownership Programs Fund.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">As provided in the State budget, the Department shall use the Fund to:<section prefix="(1)">pay expenses of the Maryland Home Financing Program, including reserves for anticipated future losses directly related to the Maryland Home Financing Program;</section><section prefix="(2)">make loans under the Maryland Home Financing Program; and</section><section prefix="(3)">make loans and pay expenses of the Down Payment and Settlement Expense Loan Program.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Fund consists of:<section prefix="(1)">money appropriated by the State for homeownership programs, including the Maryland Home Financing Program under Subtitle 8 of this title and the Down Payment and Settlement Expense Loan Program under Subtitle 3 of this title;</section><section prefix="(2)">money from the sale of the State's general obligation bonds;</section><section prefix="(3)">repayments or prepayments of principal and payments of interest on loans made under the Maryland Home Financing Program, the Homeowners' Emergency Mortgage Assistance Program, the Reverse Equity Program, or the Down Payment and Settlement Expense Loan Program, formerly the Settlement Expense Loan Program;</section><section prefix="(4)">money transferred to the Fund in accordance with &#xA7;&#xA7; 4-503(d), 4-504(f), and 4-505(h) of this subtitle and &#xA7;&#xA7; 3-203(i) and 6-310(g) of this article; and</section><section prefix="(5)">investment earnings of the Fund.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">Subject to &#xA7; 7-209 of the State Finance and Procurement Article and except as otherwise provided in the State budget, after the first 8 months of a fiscal year, the Department may transfer unencumbered money in the Fund to any other fund established under this title.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">Money received as repayment of principal or payment of interest on a loan made under the Maryland Home Financing Program that is not appropriated in the State budget may be credited to the Annuity Bond Fund and used to pay the principal of or interest on money borrowed by the State and appropriated to the Maryland Home Financing Program.</section>
  </text>
</law>
