<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghs" order_by="" level="1">Housing and Community Development</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghs-6-308.1</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>308.1</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">If the Department determines that an entity is capable of administering a microenterprise loan program, the entity may originate and administer loans to microenterprises in accordance with standards the Department adopts by regulation.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Department shall adopt regulations to establish standards for determining the eligibility of an entity to administer a microenterprise loan program.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The standards shall include provisions on:<section prefix="(i)">the size, training, and experience of the professional staff that would administer the program; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">the capability of the professional staff to:<section prefix="1.">determine financial capacity of a borrower;</section><section prefix="2.">originate a loan; and</section><section prefix="3.">evaluate applications for program loans.</section></section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Department may:<section prefix="(1)">help train employees of an approved entity to administer a microenterprise loan program in accordance with standards that the Department adopts;</section><section prefix="(2)">charge and collect from a borrower:<section prefix="(i)">reasonable origination, application, and processing fees; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">other charges, fees, or reimbursements incidental to microenterprise loans;</section></section><section prefix="(3)">include the fees and charges listed in item (2) of this subsection in the loan amount;</section><section prefix="(4)">pay an approved entity a reasonable origination, application, and processing fee for each loan to a microenterprise that is originated by the approved entity;</section><section prefix="(5)">directly fund a loan to a microenterprise that is originated by an approved entity; and</section><section prefix="(6)">provide financial assistance to an approved entity for the purpose of the approved entity making a loan to a microenterprise in accordance with this subtitle.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
