<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghs" order_by="ghs" level="1">Housing and Community Development</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghs-12-502</section_number>
  <catch_line>In addition to any powers set forth elsewhere, an authority has the powers set forth in this section...</catch_line>
  <order_by>502</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In addition to any powers set forth elsewhere, an authority has the powers set forth in this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">An authority may:<section prefix="(1)">sue and be sued;</section><section prefix="(2)">have and alter a seal at pleasure;</section><section prefix="(3)">have perpetual existence;</section><section prefix="(4)">make contracts and other instruments necessary or convenient to the exercise of the authority's powers;</section><section prefix="(5)">make, amend, and repeal bylaws, rules, and regulations not inconsistent with this Division II; and</section><section prefix="(6)">carry out the purposes of the authority.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">An authority may also:<section prefix="(1)">prepare, carry out, acquire, own, lease, and operate housing projects in its area of operation;</section><section prefix="(2)">provide for the construction, reconstruction, improvement, alteration, or repair of a housing project;</section><section prefix="(3)">provide directly or arrange or contract for a person or governmental unit to furnish facilities or services, including drug rehabilitation, elderly or child day care, and other social services for or in connection with:<section prefix="(i)">a housing project; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">the residents of a housing project; and</section></section><section prefix="(4)">notwithstanding any other law, require in a contract in connection with a housing project that the contractor and any subcontractors comply with:<section prefix="(i)">requirements about minimum wages and maximum hours of labor; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">any conditions that the State or federal government attaches to financial aid for the housing project.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">An authority may also:<section prefix="(1)">make rent subsidy payments to or on behalf of persons of eligible income;</section><section prefix="(2)">rent out houses, accommodations, lands, buildings, structures, or facilities in a housing project;</section><section prefix="(3)">subject to the limitations contained in this Division II, establish and revise the rents or charges;</section><section prefix="(4)">own, hold, and improve real and personal property;</section><section prefix="(5)">purchase, lease, obtain options on, or acquire by gift, grant, bequest, devise, or otherwise any real or personal property;</section><section prefix="(6)">sell, lease, exchange, transfer, assign, pledge, or dispose of any real or personal property;</section><section prefix="(7)">insure or provide for the insurance of real or personal property or operations of the authority against any risks or hazards; and</section><section prefix="(8)">get from the State or federal government insurance or guarantees of payment of debts secured by mortgages on property in any of its housing projects, whether or not the debts are incurred by the authority.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">When an authority has money that is held in a reserve or sinking fund or is not needed for immediate disbursement, the authority may invest the money in property or securities in which savings banks may invest.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">An authority may purchase its bonds at not more than their principal amount and accrued interest, all bonds so purchased to be canceled.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">An authority may also:<section prefix="(1)">investigate living and housing conditions in its area of operation and ways to improve those conditions;</section><section prefix="(2)">determine where:<section prefix="(i)">economically depressed or physically deteriorated areas exist; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">there is a shortage of decent, safe, and sanitary housing for persons of eligible income;</section></section><section prefix="(3)">make studies and recommendations on clearing, replanning, and reconstructing economically depressed or physically deteriorated areas and providing housing for persons of eligible income;</section><section prefix="(4)">cooperate with the State or a political subdivision to solve the problems set forth in this subsection; and</section><section prefix="(5)">conduct research, studies, and experiments on housing issues.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(g)">Acting through one or more of its commissioners or designees, an authority may also:<section prefix="(1)">examine, investigate, hear testimony, and take evidence at public or private hearings on any matter material to its duties;</section><section prefix="(2)">make findings and recommendations about any property where conditions pose a danger to the public health, morals, safety, or welfare; and</section><section prefix="(3)">make those findings and recommendations available to appropriate governmental units, including those that in its area of operation have the duty to:<section prefix="(i)">abate or require the correction of nuisances or like conditions; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">demolish unsafe or unsanitary structures.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(h)">An authority may also establish and control not-for-profit entities, including corporations and limited liability companies, that may own, operate, and take steps necessary or convenient to develop or otherwise undertake housing projects in the authority's area of operation.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In the manner provided under Title 12 of the Real Property Article or any other applicable statutory law, an authority may also acquire by eminent domain real property that the authority considers necessary for its purposes under this Division II, if:<section prefix="(i)">the authority adopts a resolution declaring that the acquisition of the real property is necessary for those purposes; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">the legislative body and the chief elected official approve.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Subject to subparagraph (ii) of this paragraph, property devoted to a public use may similarly be acquired by eminent domain.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">Real property that belongs to the State or a political subdivision may not be acquired without the consent of the State or the political subdivision.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(j)">An authority may also:<section prefix="(1)">borrow money and accept grants and other financial assistance from the political subdivision, the State, and the federal government and accept grants from nongovernmental sources for a housing project in its area of operation;</section><section prefix="(2)">take over, lease, or manage a housing project or undertaking constructed, financed, or owned by the political subdivision, the State, or the federal government; and</section><section prefix="(3)">comply with conditions and enter into mortgages, trust indentures, leases, and agreements as may be necessary or desirable.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
