<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="ghs" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="4-901" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghs-4-901</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Cooperative housing corporation" has the meaning stated in &#xA7; 5-6B-01 of the Corporations and Associations Article.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Cooperative interest" has the meaning stated in &#xA7; 5-6B-01 of the Corporations and Associations Article.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Family of limited income" means a family or individual whose income does not exceed the limits that the Secretary establishes under &#xA7; 4-915 of this subtitle.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Family of limited income" includes a trust described in 42 U.S.C. &#xA7; 1396p(d)(4), or a trust established for the benefit of an individual with a disability by an individual other than the beneficiary and that is funded with assets that were never owned or controlled by the beneficiary, if:<section prefix="(i)">the income of the trust does not exceed the upper income limits established by the Secretary under &#xA7; 4-915 of this subtitle; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">the beneficiary of the trust is an individual who resides in the residential building owned by the trust.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"Local rehabilitation program" means a rehabilitation program that uses Program loans and is administered by a political subdivision.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">"Member" has the meaning stated in &#xA7; 5-6B-01 of the Corporations and Associations Article.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">"Minimum livability code" means a regulation, statute, or ordinance that establishes minimum property maintenance standards that the State or a political subdivision adopts under &#xA7; 12-203 of the Public Safety Article.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">"Nonprofit sponsor" means:<section prefix="(1)">a nonprofit organization;</section><section prefix="(2)">a political subdivision; or</section><section prefix="(3)">a limited partnership formed to undertake a rehabilitation project that is eligible wholly or partly for federal programs or incentives, including low-income housing tax credits, if:<section prefix="(i)">each general partner is a nonprofit organization or a political subdivision; or</section><section prefix="(ii)"/></section></section>
    <section prefix="(i)">"Program" means the Maryland Housing Rehabilitation Program.</section>
    <section prefix="(j)">"Program loan" means a loan under the Maryland Housing Rehabilitation Program or a special loan program.</section>
    <section prefix="(k)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Rehabilitation project" means a project to repair, reconstruct, renovate, redevelop, improve, modify, or add to a building for a purpose listed in &#xA7; 4-923 of this subtitle.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Rehabilitation project" includes providing utility submetering for dwellings in a residential rental building.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(l)">"Special loan program" means:<section prefix="(1)">the Accessory, Shared, and Sheltered Housing Program;</section><section prefix="(2)">the Indoor Plumbing Program;</section><section prefix="(3)">the Lead Paint Abatement Program;</section><section prefix="(4)">the Migratory Worker Housing Program; or</section><section prefix="(5)">the Radon and Asbestos Abatement Pilot Program.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(m)">"Sponsor" means an owner who receives a loan to rehabilitate a building for residential rental purposes or nonresidential purposes.</section>
  </text>
</law>
