<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghs" order_by="" level="1">Housing and Community Development</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghs-6-104</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>104</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The General Assembly finds that the State must have sustainable communities in order to:<section prefix="(i)">preserve and protect the State's natural resources; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">achieve the State's economic growth, resource protection, and planning policy in &#xA7; 5-7A-01 of the State Finance and Procurement Article.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The General Assembly finds that sustainable communities are places where public and private investments and partnerships achieve:<section prefix="(i)">development of a healthy local economy;</section><section prefix="(ii)">protection and appreciation of historic and cultural resources;</section><section prefix="(iii)">a mix of land uses;</section><section prefix="(iv)">affordable and sustainable housing and job options; and</section><section prefix="(v)">growth and development practices that protect the environment and conserve air, water, and energy resources, encourage walkability and recreational opportunities, and, where available, create access to transit.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">It is the intent of the General Assembly that the community legacy and neighborhood business development programs:<section prefix="(1)">be used to create, enhance, support, and revitalize sustainable communities across the State; and</section><section prefix="(2)">be coordinated with other State programs, such as the Sustainable Communities Tax Credit Program established under Title 5A, Subtitle 3 of the State Finance and Procurement Article, in order to maximize the State's investment in sustainable communities.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
