<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghs" order_by="" level="1">Housing and Community Development</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghs-4-217</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>217</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">A project, undertaking, or a part of a project or undertaking, including the real, personal, and mixed property involved, qualifies as a community development project if it is planned, acquired, owned, developed, constructed, reconstructed, rehabilitated, repaired, renovated, or improved to promote sound community development.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A community development project shall provide for:<section prefix="(1)">new or existing housing:<section prefix="(i)">that is or will be occupied in substantial part by families of limited income; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">at least 20% of which is or will be occupied by families of limited income, if the project is financed with bonds, notes, or other evidences of indebtedness issued by the Administration, the income from which being includable in the holder's gross income under the Internal Revenue Code as determined by the Administration at the time of issue;</section></section><section prefix="(2)">any improvements, such as streets, roads, sewer lines, and water lines that are needed to support the housing; and</section><section prefix="(3)">the public or private commercial, educational, cultural, recreational, community, or civic facilities that are needed to support the housing.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A community development project may include public or private commercial, educational, cultural, recreational, community, or civic facilities that are not needed to support the housing, if:<section prefix="(1)">they are less than a substantial part of the project; or</section><section prefix="(2)">the Secretary finds that they will promote sound community development.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Administration shall administer community development projects that:<section prefix="(i)">are in sustainable communities approved under &#xA7; 6-305 of this article; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">provide employees with financial assistance in the form of grants to buy homes near their workplaces.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A community development project administered under this subsection is not subject to the provisions of subsection (b)(1) of this section that require part of the housing to be occupied by families of limited income.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The community development projects administered under this subsection shall be known as the "Live Near Your Work" program.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The Secretary shall adopt regulations to implement the "Live Near Your Work" program established under this subsection.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">
        <section prefix="(i)">In fiscal year 2007 and fiscal year 2008, the Governor may include in the State budget $250,000 for the "Live Near Your Work" program established under this subsection.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">In fiscal year 2009 and every fiscal year thereafter, the Governor may include in the State budget no less than $250,000 and no more than $500,000 for the "Live Near Your Work" program established under this subsection.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
