<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="ghs" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="6-201" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghs-6-201</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Application" means an application to the Secretary that includes a request to:<section prefix="(1)">designate an area as a sustainable community;</section><section prefix="(2)">approve a sustainable community plan; or</section><section prefix="(3)">approve a community legacy project.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Community development financial institution" has the meaning stated in 12 U.S.C. &#xA7; 4702.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">"Community development organization" means an entity that meets the qualifications of &#xA7; 6-203 of this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"Community legacy agreement" means an agreement between the Department and a sponsor to develop a sustainable community plan or to implement one or more community legacy projects in a designated sustainable community.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">"Community legacy project" includes projects to:<section prefix="(1)">create, improve, or preserve housing opportunities by acquiring, constructing, rehabilitating, or improving new or existing residential properties;</section><section prefix="(2)">demolish buildings or improvements strategically to enhance the use of land;</section><section prefix="(3)">create, improve, or preserve commercial or mixed-use development, including an appropriate combination of properties related to business, housing, open-space, and institutional uses;</section><section prefix="(4)">develop public infrastructure that is incidental to the implementation of a community legacy project, such as streets, parking, public utilities, landscaping, lighting, and improvements to pedestrian and bicycle circulation;</section><section prefix="(5)">encourage and develop cooperative ownership or control of open space;</section><section prefix="(6)">develop or create strategies designed to increase investment in existing communities, including outreach activities to attract business, capital, residents, and visitors and the development and maintenance of resources directly related to the development of a sustainable community plan or the implementation of a community legacy project;</section><section prefix="(7)">engage in landbanking or otherwise acquire or improve vacant buildings or unimproved land;</section><section prefix="(8)">provide financial assistance for neighborhood intervention projects; or</section><section prefix="(9)">develop other plans or implement other projects as the Department considers necessary to further the purposes of this subtitle.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(g)">"Financial assistance" includes:<section prefix="(1)">a grant;</section><section prefix="(2)">a loan;</section><section prefix="(3)">a reduction in the principal obligation of or rate of interest payable on a loan or portion of a loan;</section><section prefix="(4)">a prepayment of interest on a subordinate or superior loan or portion of a loan;</section><section prefix="(5)">an assurance;</section><section prefix="(6)">a guarantee; or</section><section prefix="(7)">any other form of credit enhancement.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(h)">"Landbanking" means acquiring or holding improved and unimproved property:<section prefix="(1)">in anticipation of future development of the property; or</section><section prefix="(2)">to keep the future use of the property and improvements affordable.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(i)">"Priority funding area" means an area designated as a priority funding area under &#xA7; 5-7B-02 of the State Finance and Procurement Article.</section>
    <section prefix="(j)">"Program" means the Community Legacy Program established by this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(k)">"Smart Growth Subcabinet" means the subcabinet established under &#xA7; 9-1406 of the State Government Article.</section>
    <section prefix="(l)">"Sustainable community" means the part of a priority funding area that:<section prefix="(1)">as determined by the Smart Growth Subcabinet, satisfies the requirements of &#xA7; 6-205 of this subtitle;</section><section prefix="(2)">has been designated as a BRAC Revitalization and Incentive Zone under Title 5, Subtitle 13 of the Economic Development Article; or</section><section prefix="(3)">has been designated a transit-oriented development under &#xA7; 7-101 of the Transportation Article.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(m)">"Sustainable community plan" means a plan consisting of one or more community legacy projects or other revitalization projects to prevent or reverse the decline of or disinvestment in a sustainable community through improvements in residential, commercial, or other public or private properties.</section>
  </text>
</law>
