<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="ghs" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="4-1811" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghs-4-1811</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Rental units developed under this subtitle shall remain affordable as workforce housing for a period of at least 25 years.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">If an original buyer of a homeownership workforce housing unit developed through the Program transfers title to the unit at any time, the original buyer shall pay to the Department 100% of the combined amount of Program funds and qualifying local government matching funds used to develop the unit.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">If an original buyer of a homeownership workforce housing unit developed through the Program transfers title to the unit:<section prefix="(1)">within 5 years of the date of purchase, the original buyer shall pay the lesser of 20% of the net proceeds of transfer to the Department or a 5% annual return on the Program funds provided for the unit;</section><section prefix="(2)">during the period that is more than 5 years but less than 15 years from the date of purchase, the original  buyer shall pay  to the Department the lesser of a percentage of the net proceeds of transfer that begins at 20% and declines by 2% for each subsequent year of ownership or a 5% annual return on the Program funds provided for the unit; and</section><section prefix="(3)">during the period that is 15 years or more from the date of purchase, the original buyer is not required to pay  any portion of the net proceeds of transfer to the Department.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Department shall distribute to the qualifying local government:<section prefix="(1)">of the funds paid by the original buyer to the Department under subsection (b) of this section, an amount equal to the matching funds provided by the qualifying local government for the homeownership workforce housing unit; and</section><section prefix="(2)">of the funds paid by the original buyer to the Department under subsection (c) of this section, a proportionate share based on the amount of matching funds provided by the qualifying local government for the homeownership workforce housing unit.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The Department and the qualifying local governments shall use the funds received under this section to develop workforce housing under the Program.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The contract of sale to the original  buyer shall disclose all the requirements for repayment to the Department under this section in the event of a transfer of title, including the combined amount of Program funds and qualifying local government matching funds.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The amounts owed to the Department in the event of a transfer of title of a homeownership workforce housing unit under this section shall be secured by a recorded lien on the homeownership workforce housing unit.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The lien created under this subsection may be a subordinate lien.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Department may charge a fee for servicing a lien created under this subsection.	</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
