<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghs" order_by="ghs" level="1">Housing and Community Development</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghs-4-1608</section_number>
  <catch_line>The bonds shall be sold at public or private sale on the terms that the legislative body of the cove...</catch_line>
  <order_by>1608</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The bonds shall be sold at public or private sale on the terms that the legislative body of the covered county sets.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The bonds are not subject to Article 31, &#xA7;&#xA7; 9, 10, and 11 of the Code.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The bonds and the interest on them shall be limited obligations of the covered county.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The principal and interest on the bonds shall be payable only from:<section prefix="(i)">the revenue derived from:<section prefix="1.">interest;</section><section prefix="2.">mortgage insurance;</section><section prefix="3.">casualty or special hazard insurance or other insurance proceeds; or</section><section prefix="4.">condemnation proceeds;</section></section><section prefix="(ii)">other revenue derived from mortgage loans or property securing the loans; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">other payments or revenues derived from or relating to the making of the loans.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The bonds or coupons issued under this subtitle:<section prefix="(i)">are not an indebtedness or a charge against the general credit or taxing powers of the issuing county within the meaning of a constitution, county code provision, or statutory limit; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">are not and do not give rise to a monetary liability of the issuing county.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">On the advice of counsel, the face of each bond may plainly state that the bond was issued under this subtitle and is not an indebtedness to which the faith and credit of the county is pledged.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Money received from bonds issued under this subtitle shall be applied solely:<section prefix="(1)">to make money available through mortgage lending institutions only for residential mortgage loans to families of low or moderate income;</section><section prefix="(2)">to establish reserves;</section><section prefix="(3)">to pay the necessary expenses of financing; or</section><section prefix="(4)">to advance the payment of interest on the bonds during the first 3 years after the date of the bonds.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
