<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="ghs" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="3-206" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghs-3-206</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In offering insurance and other forms of credit enhancement, the Department shall adopt eligibility standards that are reasonable to aid in:<section prefix="(1)">financing the purchase, construction, or rehabilitation of:<section prefix="(i)">housing projects;</section><section prefix="(ii)">special housing facility projects, consisting of the acquisition, rehabilitation, improvement, renovation, construction, financing, or refinancing of a building that:</section><section prefix="(iii)">rehabilitation projects, as defined in &#xA7; 4-901 of this article;</section><section prefix="(iv)">energy conservation projects;</section><section prefix="(v)">solar energy projects;</section><section prefix="(vi)">public purpose projects; or</section><section prefix="(vii)">infrastructure projects; and</section></section><section prefix="(2)">the sale or other transfer of an obligation that is:<section prefix="(i)">denoted as a bond, note, collateralized obligation, grantor trust, conduit, or other form of security or obligation; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">backed directly or indirectly by a mortgage or a payment derived from a mortgage.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The standards adopted under subsection (a) of this section shall ensure that a lender benefiting from insurance or other credit enhancement provided by the Department is responsible and able to service the loan.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A determination by the Secretary is conclusive if it relates to the eligibility of a project, facility, or undertaking for:<section prefix="(1)">insurance or other credit enhancement; or</section><section prefix="(2)">other action taken by the Department, in its own name or in the name of the Fund, under this subtitle.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
