<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="ghs" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="4-507" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghs-4-507</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, "Fund" means the Housing Counseling and Foreclosure Mediation Fund.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">There is a Housing Counseling and Foreclosure Mediation Fund.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The purposes of the Fund are to:<section prefix="(1)">support nonprofit and government housing counselors and other nonprofit entities with providing:<section prefix="(i)">legal assistance to homeowners or occupants who are trying to avoid foreclosure or manage foreclosure proceedings; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">homebuyer education, housing advice, or financial counseling for homeowners and prospective homeowners;</section></section><section prefix="(2)">support the establishment and operation of nonprofit housing counseling entities;</section><section prefix="(3)">support efforts by the Department and the Department of Labor, Licensing, and Regulation to:<section prefix="(i)">contact and provide advice and assistance to homeowners or occupants facing financial difficulty or foreclosure; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">provide advice and assistance to prospective homeowners; and</section></section><section prefix="(4)">assist in funding the costs of foreclosure mediations provided by the Office of Administrative Hearings under &#xA7; 7-105.1 of the Real Property Article.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Department shall administer the Fund.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Fund is a special, nonlapsing fund that is not subject to &#xA7; 7-302 of the State Finance and Procurement Article.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The State Treasurer shall hold the Fund separately, and the Comptroller shall account for the Fund.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The Fund consists of:<section prefix="(1)">revenue distributed to the Fund under &#xA7; 7-105.1 of the Real Property Article;</section><section prefix="(2)">investment earnings of the Fund;</section><section prefix="(3)">money appropriated in the State budget to the Fund; and</section><section prefix="(4)">any other money from any other source accepted for the benefit of the Fund.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(g)">The Fund may be used only for the purposes described in subsection (c) of this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The State Treasurer shall invest the money of the Fund in the same manner as other State money may be invested.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Any investment earnings of the Fund shall be paid into the Fund.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(i)">Expenditures from the Fund may be made only in accordance with the State budget.</section>
  </text>
</law>
