<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghs" order_by="ghs" level="1">Housing and Community Development</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghs-1-101</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this Division I of this article the following words have the meanings indicated....</catch_line>
  <order_by>101</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this Division I of this article the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Community assistance" means activities designed to enhance the physical, social, or economic environment of a community to improve the health, safety, or socio-economic welfare of its citizens.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Community assistance" includes the promotion of activities specified in paragraph (1) of this subsection through the concentration and coordination in communities in the State of federal, State, regional, and local public and private resources.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"County" means a county of the State or Baltimore City.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">"Department" means the Department of Housing and Community Development.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Financial assistance" means any form of assurance, guarantee, grant, payment, or other assistance.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Financial assistance" includes a loan, loan guarantee, or reduction in the principal obligations of or rate of interest payable on a loan or portion of a loan.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">"Governmental unit" means an agency, authority, board, commission, council, office, or other unit or instrumentality of the government of the State or of a political subdivision of the State.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">"Nonprofit organization" means a corporation, foundation, or other legal entity, no part of the net earnings of which inures to the benefit of a private shareholder or individual holding an interest in the entity.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">"Person" means an individual, receiver, trustee, guardian, personal representative, fiduciary, representative of any kind, partnership, firm, association, corporation, or other entity.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">"Political subdivision" means a county or municipal corporation of the State.</section>
    <section prefix="(j)">"Secretary" means the Secretary of Housing and Community Development.</section>
  </text>
</law>
