<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="ghs" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="4-701" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghs-4-701</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this subtitle the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Child care center" has the meaning stated in &#xA7; 5-570(c) of the Family Law Article.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">"Family of limited income" means a family that meets the qualifications under &#xA7; 4-707 of this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">"Fund" means the Special Loan Programs Fund under Subtitle 5 of this title.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"Grant Program" means the Lead Hazard Reduction Grant Program.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Lead hazard reduction activity" means measures to reduce or eliminate lead-based paint hazards in accordance with State or federal standards.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Lead hazard reduction activity" includes:<section prefix="(i)">removing lead-based paint and lead-contaminated dust, containing or encapsulating lead-based paint, and replacing or removing surfaces or fixtures painted with lead-based paint;</section><section prefix="(ii)">meeting the risk reduction standards under &#xA7; 6-815 of the Environment Article or the modified risk reduction standards under &#xA7; 6-817 of the Environment Article;</section><section prefix="(iii)">temporarily reducing human exposure or probable exposure to lead-based paint hazards, including specialized cleaning, repairing, maintaining, painting, temporarily containing, and ongoing monitoring of lead-based paint hazards or potential hazards;</section><section prefix="(iv)">associated testing, preparing, cleaning, protecting workers, disposing, and post-lead hazard reduction clearance testing; and</section><section prefix="(v)">testing an innovative or unproven method of lead hazard reduction.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">"Loan Program" means the Lead Hazard Reduction Loan Program.</section>
  </text>
</law>
