<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghs" order_by="ghs" level="1">Housing and Community Development</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghs-12-702</section_number>
  <catch_line>Bonds of an authority are issued for an essential public and governmental purpose....</catch_line>
  <order_by>702</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Bonds of an authority are issued for an essential public and governmental purpose.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Neither a commissioner of an authority nor a person who executes the bond for an authority is personally liable on the bonds.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Neither the State nor a political subdivision is liable on the bonds.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The bonds of an authority:<section prefix="(1)">are not a debt of the State or a political subdivision and shall state so on their face;</section><section prefix="(2)">are payable only out of money or property of the authority; and</section><section prefix="(3)">are not an indebtedness for purposes of a constitutional or statutory debt limitation or restriction.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Bonds issued under this Division II and their transfer and the income from them, including any profit made on their sale, shall be free from taxation of every kind by the State and by all political subdivisions.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">Bonds issued by an authority are negotiable for the purposes of the Maryland Uniform Commercial Code, subject to the registration provisions of the Code.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Bonds issued by an authority are securities in which money may be invested by:<section prefix="(i)">public officers and governmental units of the State or its political subdivisions;</section><section prefix="(ii)">banks, trust companies, savings and loan associations, investment companies, and others carrying on a banking business;</section><section prefix="(iii)">insurance companies, insurance associations, and others carrying on an insurance business;</section><section prefix="(iv)">personal representatives, guardians, trustees, and other fiduciaries; and</section><section prefix="(v)">all other persons.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Money that may be invested in the bonds includes capital that an investor owns or controls.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">Bonds issued by an authority are securities that may be deposited with or received by any State or municipal officer, governmental unit, or political subdivision of the State for any purpose for which the deposit of bonds of the State is authorized by law.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This subsection:<section prefix="(i)">is intended only for any public approval requirement of the Internal Revenue Code relating to the issuance of tax-exempt obligations; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">does not determine whether an authority is a governmental unit of the State or of a political subdivision.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Subject to paragraph (1) of this subsection, an authority authorized under a resolution or ordinance of a political subdivision derives its authorization from the resolution or enactment rather than directly from State law.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
