<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghs" order_by="ghs" level="1">Housing and Community Development</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghs-4-307</section_number>
  <catch_line>Proceeds of a Program loan shall be used only to make a down payment or pay settlement expenses for ...</catch_line>
  <order_by>307</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Proceeds of a Program loan shall be used only to make a down payment or pay settlement expenses for an eligible homebuyer to purchase a personal residence.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A Program loan shall be secured by a mortgage lien that:<section prefix="(1)">may be subordinate to other mortgage liens; and</section><section prefix="(2)">may include terms, including deferred payment of principal and interest, that the Department considers necessary to make housing purchases affordable to eligible homebuyers.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">In reviewing an application for a Program loan, the Department shall:<section prefix="(1)">consider the eligible homebuyer's financial resources, including savings available to make a down payment or pay settlement expenses, in relation to:<section prefix="(i)">the purchase price of the home; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">the down payment requirements of the lender; and</section></section><section prefix="(2)">give high priority to eligible homebuyers of low income within the income limits established under &#xA7; 4-304(b)(3) of this subtitle.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Notwithstanding any other law, the Department may require that Program loans become due and payable on the later sale or transfer of the property, but the Department may allow an eligible homebuyer who purchases the property to assume the Program loan.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">If a borrower defaults, the Department may modify the interest rate, the time or amount of payment, or any other term of a Program loan to facilitate repayment of the Program loan and to achieve the purpose of the Program.</section>
  </text>
</law>
