<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghs" order_by="" level="1">Housing and Community Development</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghs-4-304</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>304</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Department may:<section prefix="(1)">charge an application fee or other fee to a Program loan applicant or lender;</section><section prefix="(2)">purchase or make commitments to purchase Program loans made by mortgage lenders;</section><section prefix="(3)">make contracts with third parties to make or service mortgage Program loans made for the Department;</section><section prefix="(4)">acquire any property that secures a Program loan under this subtitle by gift, purchase, foreclosure, or otherwise, and sell or otherwise dispose of the property or an interest in the property;</section><section prefix="(5)">delegate to a political subdivision any administrative or operational element of the Program not assigned to the Department under subsection (b) of this section;</section><section prefix="(6)">take any other action necessary or convenient to operate the Program; and</section><section prefix="(7)">require a political subdivision that administers its own down payment and settlement expense loan program to inform the Department of the political subdivision's homebuyer education requirements.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Department shall:<section prefix="(1)">administer the Program;</section><section prefix="(2)">attach to a Program loan the terms needed to carry out the Program;</section><section prefix="(3)">establish eligibility standards for Program loans, considering State, regional, and county housing costs, median incomes, and household sizes;</section><section prefix="(4)">establish guidelines to determine what parts of the down payment and settlement expenses may be covered by the Program loan; and</section><section prefix="(5)">adopt regulations to carry out the Program.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The sale or purchase of property that the Department acquires or disposes of under this section need not be approved or executed by the Board of Public Works or the Department of General Services.</section>
  </text>
</law>
