<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="ghs" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="16-204" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghs-16-204</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">On determining to issue bonds, the Montgomery Commission shall provide to the County Executive information about the bonds and the housing projects benefitting from the bond proceeds.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The information shall include:<section prefix="(i)">the terms and conditions of the bonds;</section><section prefix="(ii)">an estimate of the bond interest rate and the basis for the estimate;</section><section prefix="(iii)">the estimated timing and other provisions about the advertising and sale of the bonds;</section><section prefix="(iv)">a description of the proposed housing project, with detailed estimates of construction and related costs to make it ready to rent or sell;</section><section prefix="(v)">detailed estimates of operating costs and debt service;</section><section prefix="(vi)">schedules of reserves for depreciation and major maintenance;</section><section prefix="(vii)">separate schedules that show how, after allowance for vacancies, revenues are expected to cover:</section><section prefix="(viii)">separate schedules that:</section><section prefix="(ix)">a description of the terms and conditions for construction of the housing project, including any safeguards against construction default and the conditions under which construction financing is to be provided by the Montgomery Commission; and</section><section prefix="(x)">a description of the accounting system for recording and controlling expenditures of bond funds, debt service, operating costs, reserves, and revenues.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Each housing project shall be established as an independent accounting entity for revenues, expenditures, debt service, and reserves.</section>
  </text>
</law>
