<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghs" order_by="" level="1">Housing and Community Development</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghs-13-104</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>104</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Annapolis Authority consists of seven Commissioners appointed by the Mayor of Annapolis and approved by the Annapolis City Council.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Of the seven Commissioners:<section prefix="(i)">one shall be a tenant of an Annapolis Authority property other than an Annapolis Authority property for seniors; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">one shall be a tenant of an Annapolis Authority property for seniors.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The term of a Commissioner is 5 years.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The terms of Commissioners are staggered as required by the terms provided for Commissioners on October 1, 2006.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">At the end of a term, a Commissioner continues to serve until a successor is appointed and qualifies.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">A Commissioner who is appointed after a term has begun serves only for the rest of the term and until a successor is appointed and qualifies.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, a Commissioner while in office and for 2 years after leaving office may not be employed by the Annapolis Authority for compensation on a permanent or temporary full-time, part-time, contractual, or other basis.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Subject to approval by the Mayor of Annapolis and by the United States Department of Housing and Urban Development, the prohibition contained in paragraph (1) of this subsection may be waived for good cause shown.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
