<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghs" order_by="ghs" level="1">Housing and Community Development</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghs-4-1403</section_number>
  <catch_line>The Department shall administer the Rental Allowance Program to assist low-income households that ar...</catch_line>
  <order_by>1403</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Department shall administer the Rental Allowance Program to assist low-income households that are homeless or at risk of being homeless by providing housing assistance payments to or on behalf of eligible households.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Secretary shall establish:<section prefix="(1)">income limits for eligibility of low-income households not exceeding 30% of the State or area median income, whichever is higher; and</section><section prefix="(2)">minimum standards for eligible dwelling units.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Secretary shall establish the amount of payments made through the Rental Allowance Program, taking into account factors identified in &#xA7; 4-1405(d) of this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Eligible uses of payments may include rent, security deposits, utilities, and other housing-related expenses.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The Department may administer the Rental Allowance Program by providing monthly housing assistance payments to or on behalf of eligible households directly or through political subdivisions, their local housing agencies or departments, or nonprofit organizations.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">Funds appropriated to serve low-income households through the Rental Allowance Program may not be used for other programs authorized under this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">The Department may adopt regulations to carry out the Rental Allowance Program, including time frames for assistance and other criteria the Secretary considers appropriate.</section>
  </text>
</law>
