<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="ghs" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="17-107" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghs-17-107</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In addition to the powers listed elsewhere in this Division II, the Prince George's Authority may:<section prefix="(1)">exercise all or any part of those powers to provide housing, housing rehabilitation, housing projects, integrally related commercial structures, and their financing for county residents;</section><section prefix="(2)">exercise other functions and responsibilities required by the county, including community development; and</section><section prefix="(3)">acquire and spend public money for any purpose authorized under this Division II, if the exercise of all powers of the Prince George's Authority is in accordance with Prince George's County law or a contract or contracts with Prince George's County.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">As required by Prince George's County, the Prince George's Authority annually shall issue a financial report for the previous fiscal year based on a certified audit.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Prince George's County by local law may require the Prince George's Authority to comply with budgetary, financial, personnel, and ethics procedures of the county.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">With the approval of the Prince George's County governing body, the Prince George's Authority within its area of operation also may:<section prefix="(1)">make construction loans and long-term mortgage loans to any person to produce housing under this title;</section><section prefix="(2)">buy and insure mortgages secured by such housing; and</section><section prefix="(3)">make or buy mortgage loans to help first-time homebuyers to buy existing homes, if:<section prefix="(i)">the first-time homebuyers:</section><section prefix="(ii)">the Prince George's Authority determines that income from the assistance program will cover the costs of the program.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">With the approval of the Prince George's County governing body, the Prince George's Authority within its area of operation may finance housing, housing rehabilitation, a housing project, or a continuing care facility authorized by this title by issuing and selling the bonds of any type.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Bonds that may be issued under this subsection include those on which the principal and interest are payable:<section prefix="(i)">only from the income and revenues of the housing project or continuing care facility that is financed with the proceeds of the bonds or with both those proceeds and a federal grant;</section><section prefix="(ii)">only from the income and revenues of designated housing projects whether or not they were financed wholly or partly with the proceeds of the bonds; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">from its revenues generally.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A bond under this subsection may be secured by pledge of any revenue or a mortgage of a housing project, projects, or other property of the Prince George's Authority.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">Bonds of the Prince George's Authority may be sold at public or private sale in the manner and on the terms that are authorized by resolution of the Prince George's Authority.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">This section does not preempt or supersede the regulatory authority of a State governmental unit under State law.</section>
  </text>
</law>
