<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghs" order_by="" level="1">Housing and Community Development</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghs-4-228</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>228</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">To finance infrastructure projects, the Administration may:<section prefix="(1)">make, purchase, and participate in making loans;</section><section prefix="(2)">purchase local obligations issued to finance such projects; and</section><section prefix="(3)">provide any other form of financial assistance other than grants.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">All transactions under subsection (a) of this section shall be evidenced by instruments containing the terms and conditions necessary to secure payment of all obligations and charges due to the Administration.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Subject to an agreement with holders of its bonds, notes, or other obligations, the Administration may consent that a loan, local obligation, commitment, instrument, or agreement that the Administration holds or to which it is a party may be modified as to:<section prefix="(1)">interest rate;</section><section prefix="(2)">time of payment of any installment of principal or interest;</section><section prefix="(3)">security; or</section><section prefix="(4)">any other term.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In connection with any security that it receives or owns, including a local obligation, the Administration may:<section prefix="(i)">sue to protect or enforce its rights under any law or agreement; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">acquire or take possession of the security.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If the Administration begins such an action, it may:<section prefix="(i)">administer the security;</section><section prefix="(ii)">pay the principal and interest on any obligation incurred in connection with the security;</section><section prefix="(iii)">dispose of the security; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">otherwise deal with the security so as to protect the Administration's interests.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The Administration may sell a loan, agreement, local obligation, or other obligation that it holds at public or private sale with or without public bidding.</section>
  </text>
</law>
