<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghu" order_by="ghu" level="1">Human Services</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghu-8-505</section_number>
  <catch_line>A local management board shall apply for money from the Fund in accordance with procedures establish...</catch_line>
  <order_by>505</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">A local management board shall apply for money from the Fund in accordance with procedures established by the Children's Cabinet.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">In connection with an application for money under subsection (a) of this section, a local management board shall develop and submit a community partnership agreement that:<section prefix="(1)">reflects coordination with:<section prefix="(i)">the State's 3-year plan for children, youth, and families; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">any local government plan for services for children, youth, and families, including the local substance abuse plan developed in accordance with Title 8, Subtitle 10 of the Health - General Article; and</section></section><section prefix="(2)">addresses the priorities and strategies of the county for meeting the identified needs of children and families as articulated in the local management board's 5-year strategic plan regarding:<section prefix="(i)">youth development;</section><section prefix="(ii)">prevention services;</section><section prefix="(iii)">crisis and early intervention;</section><section prefix="(iv)">services for children at risk of out-of-home placement or returning from out-of-home placement; and</section><section prefix="(v)">out-of-home placement and treatment.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Children's Cabinet may disburse money to a local management board subject to the terms, conditions, performance measures, or outcome evaluations that the Children's Cabinet considers necessary.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The local management board shall use the money to implement:<section prefix="(1)">a local interagency services delivery system for children, youth, and families in accordance with the community partnership agreement; and</section><section prefix="(2)">any terms, conditions, and performance measures that the Children's Cabinet requires.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
