<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghu" order_by="" level="1">Human Services</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghu-10-501</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>501</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this part the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Capital equipment" means essential fixed equipment and furnishings with an expected useful life of at least 15 years.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Cost" means all expenses incident to the construction, acquisition, conversion, renovation, or improvement of a project.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Cost" includes:<section prefix="(i)">the cost to acquire any interest in real or personal property in connection with a project;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the cost of financial, technical, professional, engineering, and legal services in connection with a project whether the expenses are incurred before or after any bond, note, or other evidence of indebtedness or obligation is issued by the State to finance the project;</section><section prefix="(iii)">the cost of development of a senior citizen activities center master plan; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">the cost of plans, specifications, surveys, estimates of costs and revenues, feasibility or practicability reports, machinery, equipment, and administrative expenses, and other expenses that are necessary and incident to the financing authorized for the project.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">"Grant" means a grant from the State under the Program.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"Improvement" means construction, replacement, extension, or betterment of a project or real property.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">"Master plan" means a comprehensive plan for a local government's projected need for funds for senior citizen activities centers over 15 years.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">"Program" means the Senior Citizen Activities Centers Capital Improvement Grants Program.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">"Project" means a proposed or existing senior citizen activities center that:<section prefix="(1)">receives or has received a grant for work that is eligible under this part;</section><section prefix="(2)">is operated under the authority of a unit of local government; and</section><section prefix="(3)">is:<section prefix="(i)">wholly owned by the unit of local government; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">leased by a unit of local government if:<section prefix="1.">the lease is for a minimum term of 15 years after completion of the project or gives the lessee the right of purchase; and</section><section prefix="2.">the lessor consents to the recording of a notice of the right of recovery under &#xA7; 10-506 of this subtitle in the land records of the county in which the facility is located.</section></section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(i)">"Senior citizen activities center" means a community or neighborhood facility in which a broad spectrum of services are organized and provided to individuals at least 60 years old or their spouses, including health, social, nutritional, educational, and recreational services.</section>
  </text>
</law>
