<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghu" order_by="" level="1">Human Services</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghu-10-410</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>410</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">A provider may collect deposits from prospective subscribers if:<section prefix="(1)">the Department has approved the provider's feasibility study; and</section><section prefix="(2)">funds collected are maintained in an escrow account.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Each deposit agreement shall comply with the requirements of subsection (c) or (d) of this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">If a deposit agreement is used for a deposit on a unit for which the provider has not received written approval to withdraw deposits, the deposit agreement shall:<section prefix="(1)">state that all deposits and entrance fees will be held in escrow until:<section prefix="(i)">an initial certificate of registration for the unit is issued;</section><section prefix="(ii)">construction is completed;</section><section prefix="(iii)">a certificate of occupancy, or its equivalent, is issued by the local jurisdiction; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">the provider has the appropriate licenses or certificates from the Department of Health and Mental Hygiene, the Maryland Health Care Commission, and the Department;</section></section><section prefix="(2)">describe the disposition of any interest earned on deposits and entrance fees;</section><section prefix="(3)">state the amount of any processing fee and whether it will be refunded if the deposit agreement is canceled; and</section><section prefix="(4)">describe the disposition of the deposit if the deposit agreement is canceled before the continuing care agreement is executed.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">If a deposit agreement is used for a deposit on a unit for which the provider has received written approval to withdraw deposits, the deposit agreement shall:<section prefix="(1)">state that the provider may use all deposits and entrance fees at any time; or</section><section prefix="(2)">describe any applicable limitations on the use of deposits and entrance fees.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
