<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghu" order_by="ghu" level="1">Human Services</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghu-9-240.1</section_number>
  <catch_line>The Secretary shall establish a Program to attempt to provide a volunteer mentor for each child in t...</catch_line>
  <order_by>240.1</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Secretary shall establish a Program to attempt to provide a volunteer mentor for each child in the State who has spent at least 30 days in a committed placement.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Program shall be called "Maryland Rising".</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The purpose of the Program is to provide individualized attention to a child:<section prefix="(1)">to decrease the child's delinquent or violent behavior in the community; and</section><section prefix="(2)">to increase the child's potential for becoming a productive, successful member of the community.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">To carry out the purpose of the Program, the Department shall develop a statewide network of State agencies, community agencies, citizen action groups, social services providers, volunteer organizations, college student groups, and other groups who will recruit volunteer mentors for the Program.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A mentor shall have frequent contact with the child and may provide the following services to the child:<section prefix="(i)">informal counseling;</section><section prefix="(ii)">tutoring;</section><section prefix="(iii)">assisting the child with life skills training;</section><section prefix="(iv)">working with the child's family or guardian;</section><section prefix="(v)">interacting with the child's school or employer, if necessary; and</section><section prefix="(vi)">other individualized support services that help the child avoid negative behaviors and become a successful, productive member of the community.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Department may adopt regulations to implement this section.</section>
  </text>
</law>
