<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="ghu" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="8-703.1" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghu-8-703.1</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Licensing agency" means:<section prefix="(i)">the Department of Human Resources; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">the Department of Juvenile Services.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Statement of need" means an official certification of public need for the location and establishment of a residential child care program in a county issued by a licensing agency under this section.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The licensing agencies shall adopt regulations governing the issuance of statements of need.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">In developing the regulations required under subsection (b) of this section, a licensing agency shall:<section prefix="(1)">consider the specialized mental, physical, and behavioral health and developmental needs of children in the county or region affected by the statement of need; and</section><section prefix="(2)">consult with stakeholders in the county or region affected by the statement of need, including:<section prefix="(i)">State and local child-serving agencies;</section><section prefix="(ii)">providers of residential and community-based services for children; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">children, parents, and foster parents.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">An application may not be submitted to the office and a license may not be granted by a licensing agency for a residential child care program until a licensing agency issues a statement of need for a residential child care program in a county.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">In addition to the statement of need required under subsection (d) of this section, a statement of need is required before:<section prefix="(1)">an existing or previously licensed residential child care program is relocated to another site;</section><section prefix="(2)">the physical site of a residential child care program is expanded; or</section><section prefix="(3)">the number of placements in a residential child care program is increased.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(f)">A licensing agency shall publish notice of the issuance of a statement of need in the Maryland Register.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">A licensing agency may not delegate its authority to issue a statement of need.</section>
  </text>
</law>
