<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="ghu" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="5-603" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghu-5-603</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">In this section the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Delinquent tenant" means a tenant of public housing who is 30 or more days delinquent in paying the tenant's full monthly rent to a public housing authority.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Public housing" means a dwelling unit owned, leased, or managed by a public housing authority.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">"Public housing authority" means a public corporation created under Division II of the Housing and Community Development Article or the public corporation's designee.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">If a recipient of temporary cash assistance is a delinquent tenant, the Administration, at the request of the public housing authority, shall:<section prefix="(1)">deduct the amount of the tenant's rent from the tenant's monthly assistance payments each month;</section><section prefix="(2)">pay the amount deducted from the tenant's monthly assistance payments to the public housing authority or the public housing authority's authorized agent; and</section><section prefix="(3)">forward the remaining amount of the monthly assistance payments to the tenant.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If a court establishes an escrow account under &#xA7; 8-211 of the Real Property Article or a parallel provision of public local law for a tenancy covered under subsection (b) of this section, the public housing authority shall notify the Administration of the court action.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">On notice under paragraph (1) of this subsection or on certification by an attorney of record representing the delinquent tenant in the court action that an order has been issued to establish an escrow account, the Administration shall pay rent to the court as long as the order is in effect.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Any notice under paragraphs (1) and (2) of this subsection shall include a list of all addresses covered by the court action.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The public housing authority shall notify the Administration when the court action has been resolved.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
