<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghu" order_by="" level="1">Human Services</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghu-8-101</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>101</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this title the following words have the meanings indicated.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">"Agencies of the Children's Cabinet" includes:<section prefix="(1)">the Department of Budget and Management;</section><section prefix="(2)">the Department of Disabilities;</section><section prefix="(3)">the Department of Health and Mental Hygiene;</section><section prefix="(4)">the Department of Human Resources;</section><section prefix="(5)">the Department of Juvenile Services; and</section><section prefix="(6)">the State Department of Education.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Child in need of out-of-state placement" means a child who is recommended by a public agency for out-of-home placement outside of the State.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Child in need of out-of-state placement" does not include a child:<section prefix="(i)">placed in foster care, as defined in &#xA7; 5-501 of the Family Law Article; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">who is in a hospital for 30 continuous days or less.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">"Child with intensive needs" means a child who has behavioral, educational, developmental, or mental health needs that cannot be met through available public agency resources because:<section prefix="(1)">the child's needs exceed the resources of a single public agency; or</section><section prefix="(2)">there is no legally mandated funding source to meet the child's needs.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">"Core service agency" means the designated county or multicounty authority that is responsible for planning, managing, and monitoring publicly funded mental health services as provided under Title 10, Subtitle 12 of the Health - General Article.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">"Council" means the State Coordinating Council for Children.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">"Evidence-based" means meeting the criteria for an evidence-based early childhood home visiting service delivery model as defined by the federal Department of Health and Human Services.</section>
    <section prefix="(h)">"Executive Director" means the Executive Director of the Governor's Office for Children.</section>
    <section prefix="(i)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Family" means an eligible child's natural, adoptive, or foster parents.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Family" includes:<section prefix="(i)">a guardian;</section><section prefix="(ii)">a person acting as a parent of a child; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">a relative or stepparent with whom a child lives.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(j)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Home visiting program" means a program or initiative that:<section prefix="(i)">contains home visiting as a primary service delivery strategy;</section><section prefix="(ii)">offers services on a voluntary basis to pregnant women, expectant fathers, and parents and caregivers of children from birth to kindergarten entry; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">targets participant outcomes that may include:<section prefix="1.">improved maternal and child health;</section><section prefix="2.">prevention of child injuries, child abuse or maltreatment, and reduction of emergency department visits;</section><section prefix="3.">improvements in school readiness and achievement;</section><section prefix="4.">reduction in crime or domestic violence;</section><section prefix="5.">improvements in family economic self-sufficiency;</section><section prefix="6.">improvements in the coordination of and referrals to other community resources and supports; or</section><section prefix="7.">improvements in parenting skills related to child development.</section></section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Home visiting program" includes those program models identified in the Home Visiting Evidence of Effectiveness project of the federal Department of Health and Human Services.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">"Home visiting program" does not include:<section prefix="(i)">programs with few or infrequent visits;</section><section prefix="(ii)">programs in which home visiting is supplemental to other services; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">in-home services delivered through provisions of an individualized family service plan or an individualized education program under Part C or Part B of the federal Individuals with Disabilities Education Act.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(k)">"Hospital" has the meaning stated in &#xA7; 19-301 of the Health - General Article.</section>
    <section prefix="(l)">"Local management board" means an entity established or designated by a county under Subtitle 3 of this title to ensure the implementation of a local, interagency service delivery system for children, youth, and families.</section>
    <section prefix="(m)">"Office" means the Governor's Office for Children.</section>
    <section prefix="(n)">"Promising" means a home visiting program or practice that:<section prefix="(1)">does not yet meet the standard for evidence-based practices; and</section><section prefix="(2)">meets the criteria of a promising approach as defined by the federal Department of Health and Human Services.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(o)">"Public agency" means a State or local government unit or a quasi-governmental entity.</section>
    <section prefix="(p)">
      <section prefix="(1)">"Residential child care program" means an entity that provides 24-hour per day care for children within a structured set of services and activities that are designed to achieve specific objectives relative to the needs of the children served and that include the provision of food, clothing, shelter, education, social services, health, mental health, recreation, or any combination of these services and activities.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">"Residential child care program" includes a program:<section prefix="(i)">licensed by:<section prefix="1.">the Department of Health and Mental Hygiene;</section><section prefix="2.">the Department of Human Resources; or</section><section prefix="3.">the Department of Juvenile Services; and</section></section><section prefix="(ii)">that is subject to the licensing regulations of the members of the Children's Cabinet governing the operations of residential child care programs.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
