<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghu" order_by="ghu" level="1">Human Services</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghu-9-235</section_number>
  <catch_line>Except as provided in subsection (b) of this section, a person shall be licensed by the Department a...</catch_line>
  <order_by>235</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Except as provided in subsection (b) of this section, a person shall be licensed by the Department as a child care home before the person may exercise care, custody, or control over a child who is alleged to be or is adjudicated delinquent or in need of supervision.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">This section does not apply to:<section prefix="(1)">a parent of the child;</section><section prefix="(2)">an individual related to the child by blood or marriage within 4 degrees of consanguinity under the civil law rule;</section><section prefix="(3)">a guardian of the child;</section><section prefix="(4)">a person who exercises temporary custody or control over the child at the request of a parent or guardian of the child and who is not required otherwise to be licensed;</section><section prefix="(5)">a person who has the care, custody, or control of the child through placement by a parent or grandparent of the child in contemplation of adoption, if the requirements of &#xA7; 5-507(b)(2) and (c) of the Family Law Article are met;</section><section prefix="(6)">an institution that has a child care institution license under this subtitle or &#xA7; 5-509 of the Family Law Article;</section><section prefix="(7)">an institution operated by a unit of the State or a political subdivision; or</section><section prefix="(8)">a foster care provider with whom the child is placed by:<section prefix="(i)">a licensed child placement agency;</section><section prefix="(ii)">a local department of social services;</section><section prefix="(iii)">the Secretary of Health and Mental Hygiene;</section><section prefix="(iv)">the Department; or</section><section prefix="(v)">a court of competent jurisdiction.</section></section></section>
  </text>
</law>
