<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghu" order_by="ghu" level="1">Human Services</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghu-10-497</section_number>
  <catch_line>The Secretary may impose a civil money penalty against a provider for an action or inaction that vio...</catch_line>
  <order_by>497</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Secretary may impose a civil money penalty against a provider for an action or inaction that violates this subtitle or any regulation adopted by the Department under this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Before imposing a civil money penalty under subsection (a) of this section, the Department shall issue a notice of violation to the provider.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The notice shall state:<section prefix="(i)">when the provider must submit a plan of correction that is acceptable to the Department;</section><section prefix="(ii)">when each identified violation must be substantially corrected, which may not be less than 30 days; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">that failure to submit an acceptable plan of correction as required under item (i) of this paragraph or to correct an identified violation may result in an order imposing a civil money penalty under subsection (d) of this section.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">If at the expiration of the time set forth in the notice required under subsection (b) of this section the Department determines a violation has not been corrected, the Secretary may:<section prefix="(1)">extend the time in which the violation must be corrected; or</section><section prefix="(2)">impose a civil money penalty under subsection (d) of this section.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Secretary may impose a civil money penalty not exceeding $5,000 for each violation.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">In setting the amount of a civil money penalty under this section, the Secretary shall consider the following factors:<section prefix="(i)">the number, nature, and seriousness of the violations;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the degree of risk to the health, life, or physical or financial safety of the subscribers caused by the violations;</section><section prefix="(iii)">the efforts made by the provider to correct the violations;</section><section prefix="(iv)">whether the amount of the proposed civil money penalty will jeopardize the financial ability of the provider to continue operating; and</section><section prefix="(v)">other factors as justice may require.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">If a civil money penalty is imposed under this section, the Department shall issue an order stating:<section prefix="(i)">the basis on which the order is made;</section><section prefix="(ii)">each regulation or statute violated;</section><section prefix="(iii)">each civil money penalty imposed and the total amount of the civil money penalty imposed; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">the manner in which the amount of the civil money penalty was calculated.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The Department shall provide written notice to a provider of the imposition of a civil money penalty.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The notice shall be served on the provider by certified mail and shall include the order and a statement on how to file an administrative appeal.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(5)">If a civil money penalty is imposed under this section, the provider has the right to appeal from the order in accordance with Title 10, Subtitle 2 of the State Government Article.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A provider shall pay a civil money penalty to the Department within 10 days after the provider receives a final order imposing the civil money penalty.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">An order imposing a civil money penalty is final when the provider has exhausted all opportunities to contest the civil penalty in accordance with Title 10, Subtitle 2 of the State Government Article.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">If a provider does not comply with this section, the Department may file a civil action to recover the penalty.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The Department shall deposit all civil money penalties collected under this section into the General Fund.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
