<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="ghu" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="10-209" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghu-10-209</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Secretary shall develop congregate housing services programs for seniors in conjunction with:<section prefix="(i)">public or private for profit or nonprofit corporations; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">State or federal units.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Congregate housing services shall include congregate meals, housekeeping, and personal services.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">An individual is eligible for congregate housing services if the individual is at least 62 years old and has temporary or periodic difficulty with one or more essential activities of daily living, such as feeding, bathing, grooming, dressing, or transferring.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The spouse of an individual described in paragraph (1) of this subsection is eligible for congregate housing services if the spouse is at least 55 years old and has temporary or periodic difficulty with one or more essential activities of daily living, such as feeding, bathing, grooming, dressing, or transferring.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Secretary shall:<section prefix="(1)">make maximum use of rent and other subsidies available from federal and State sources;</section><section prefix="(2)">provide for subsidies necessary from State general funds to assist low-income seniors to reside in congregate housing as an alternative to more costly institutional care that is not required;</section><section prefix="(3)">find sponsors or managers for congregate housing services programs;</section><section prefix="(4)">assist developers in formulating design concepts and meeting program needs; and</section><section prefix="(5)">when necessary, provide subsidies for congregate meals, housekeeping, and personal services in congregate housing services programs and develop eligibility requirements for the subsidies.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Secretary shall adopt regulations to:<section prefix="(1)">govern the certification and operation of congregate housing services programs; and</section><section prefix="(2)">provide for investigations of criminal records of congregate housing services providers and employees under subsection (e) of this section.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The Secretary is authorized to conduct federal and State criminal background investigations of providers of congregate housing services programs and their employees.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A congregate housing services program must be certified by the Secretary.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Secretary shall review the compliance of congregate housing services programs with the regulations governing their certification and operation.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Before the Secretary may certify or renew the certification of a provider of congregate housing services for seniors with Alzheimer's disease and related disorders, the provider shall have an in-service education program that includes instruction on dementia and the techniques necessary to manage patients with physical, intellectual, and behavioral manifestations of dementia.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
