<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghu" order_by="" level="1">Human Services</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghu-10-412</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>412</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">A provider may not provide continuing care until the Department issues an initial certificate of registration.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">An application for an initial certificate of registration shall be filed in a form satisfactory to the Department.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">An application shall include at least the following information:<section prefix="(1)">for a project other than a conversion, verification that continuing care agreements have been executed with subscribers for at least 65% of the independent living units and at least 10% of the total entrance fee for each contracted unit has been collected;</section><section prefix="(2)">for a conversion project, verification that at least 80% of the accommodations in the project that are not licensed as assisted living or comprehensive care beds are occupied or reserved in accordance with:<section prefix="(i)">leases;</section><section prefix="(ii)">continuing care agreements executed with subscribers who have paid a deposit that:<section prefix="1.">equals at least 10% of the total entrance fee; and</section><section prefix="2.">has been deposited by the provider under an escrow agreement approved by the Department; or</section></section><section prefix="(iii)">other appropriate contractual arrangements;</section></section><section prefix="(3)">verification that the provider has received a written commitment for permanent long-term financing; and</section><section prefix="(4)">if construction financing is required, verification that the provider has applied for the financing.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If requested by the permanent financing lender, the Department may issue a letter stating that the requirements of subsection (c)(1) of this section have been met.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If requested by the construction lender, the Department may issue a letter stating that:<section prefix="(i)">the requirements of subsection (c)(1) and (3) of this section have been met; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">the initial certificate of registration will be issued on the closing of the construction loan.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Department shall issue an initial certificate of registration to a provider if the Department determines that:<section prefix="(i)">the provider has a preliminary certificate of registration;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the provider has submitted the required documents;</section><section prefix="(iii)">the form and substance of all advertisements, advertising campaigns, and other promotional materials submitted are not deceptive, misleading, or likely to mislead;</section><section prefix="(iv)">for a project other than a conversion, continuing care agreements have been executed with subscribers for at least 65% of the independent living units and at least 10% of the entrance fee has been paid as a deposit for each contracted unit;</section><section prefix="(v)">for a conversion project, at least 80% of the accommodations in the project that are not licensed as assisted living or comprehensive care beds are occupied or reserved in accordance with:<section prefix="1.">leases;</section><section prefix="2.">continuing care agreements executed with subscribers who have paid a deposit that:</section><section prefix="3.">other appropriate contractual arrangements;</section></section><section prefix="(vi)">if construction financing is required, closing on the financing has occurred; and</section><section prefix="(vii)">the provider has a commitment for permanent long-term financing.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Department may issue the initial certificate of registration for a period not exceeding 18 months.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">A deposit held in escrow may not be used until:<section prefix="(1)">an initial certificate of registration has been issued;</section><section prefix="(2)">construction is completed;</section><section prefix="(3)">the provider has a certificate of occupancy or the equivalent from the appropriate local jurisdiction; and</section><section prefix="(4)">the provider has the appropriate licenses or certificates from the Department of Health and Mental Hygiene or the Department.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(g)">If an initial certificate of registration is not issued within 24 months after the issuance of a preliminary certificate of registration, or a longer time allowed by the Department for good cause shown, the provider shall refund all deposits and stop offering continuing care under that application.</section>
  </text>
</law>
