<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghu" order_by="" level="1">Human Services</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghu-9-221</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>221</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">To carry out the objectives of this title, the following State units shall cooperate fully with the Department:<section prefix="(1)">the State Department of Education;</section><section prefix="(2)">the Department of General Services;</section><section prefix="(3)">the Department of Health and Mental Hygiene;</section><section prefix="(4)">the Department of Human Resources;</section><section prefix="(5)">the Department of Labor, Licensing, and Regulation;</section><section prefix="(6)">the Department of Public Safety and Correctional Services; and</section><section prefix="(7)">each other agency needed to accomplish these objectives.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Department shall cooperate with the Juvenile Justice Monitoring Unit of the Office of the Attorney General established under Title 6, Subtitle 4 of the State Government Article by:<section prefix="(i)">providing the Unit with access to all facilities, reports, and records relating to a child on request;</section><section prefix="(ii)">allowing the juvenile justice monitors to conduct interviews with staff, children, and any other individuals on request; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">submitting corrective action plans and incident reports to the Unit in response to findings and recommendations made by the juvenile justice monitors regarding a facility.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The Department shall respond to requests for information from a juvenile justice monitor concerning a facility within 30 days after the date of the request.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">If the Department does not respond to a request for information, the monitor may conduct a reasonable investigation relating to the original request for information.</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Department shall cooperate with the State Department of Education to establish educational programs as required under Title 22, Subtitle 3 of the Education Article.</section>
  </text>
</law>
