<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghu" order_by="" level="1">Human Services</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghu-4-205</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>205</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Administration shall be the central coordinating and directing agency of all social service activities in the State, including:<section prefix="(i)">child welfare services; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">any other social service activities financed wholly or partly by the Administration.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">For the purposes of these duties, child welfare services provided to a minor may continue after the minor's eighteenth birthday but not beyond the minor's twenty-first birthday.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Administration shall supervise, direct, and control the activities of the local departments that it finances wholly or partly.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Administration shall supervise all public and private institutions that have care, custody, or control of abused, abandoned, dependent, or neglected children, except:<section prefix="(1)">institutions under the authority of the Department of Juvenile Services; and</section><section prefix="(2)">agencies, persons, or institutions designated by the Department of Juvenile Services under &#xA7; 9-217 of this article.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Administration may visit any State-aided institution, organization, or agency engaged in social service or welfare activities and inspect thoroughly its management, buildings, and equipment.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Visits and inspections under paragraph (1) of this subsection shall be made:<section prefix="(i)">at reasonably convenient hours; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">with reasonable regard to the established discipline, regulations, and customs of the institution, organization, or agency.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">As desirable or necessary for the purpose of this title, the Administration may designate existing agencies or organizations in the State as the Administration's agents.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">Before the start of each regular session of the General Assembly, the Administration shall submit a report of its activities to the Governor.</section>
  </text>
</law>
