<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="ghu" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="11-301" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghu-11-301</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">There is a Board of Directors of the Corporation.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Board consists of:<section prefix="(i)">nine voting members appointed by the Governor with the advice and consent of the Senate; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">the executive director, who is a nonvoting ex officio member.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Voting members shall be residents of the State and shall represent the different geographical regions of the State.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Five voting members shall be lawyers admitted to the Bar in the State and four voting members shall be nonlawyers.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A voting member of the Board is not an officer or employee of the State.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The term of office of a voting member is 3 years.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">At the end of a term a voting member continues to serve until a successor is appointed and qualifies.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The terms of voting members are staggered as required by the terms provided for members of the Board on October 1, 2007.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">If a vacancy occurs during the term of a voting member, the Governor shall fill the vacancy.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">A voting member who is appointed after a term has begun serves only for the rest of the term and until a successor is appointed and qualifies.</section>
      <section prefix="(6)">A voting member may not be reappointed for more than 2 consecutive terms immediately following the member's initial term.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A voting member may be removed by a vote of seven members.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A voting member may only be removed for:<section prefix="(i)">malfeasance in office;</section><section prefix="(ii)">persistent neglect of or inability to discharge duties; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">offenses involving moral turpitude.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
