<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghu" order_by="ghu" level="1">Human Services</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghu-11-402</section_number>
  <catch_line>There is a Maryland Legal Services Corporation Fund....</catch_line>
  <order_by>402</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">There is a Maryland Legal Services Corporation Fund.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Administrative Office of the Courts shall administer the Fund.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Fund is a special, nonlapsing fund that is not subject to &#xA7; 7-302 of the State Finance and Procurement Article.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Fund consists of:<section prefix="(1)">money deposited to the Fund from the surcharge assessed in civil cases under &#xA7;&#xA7; 7-202 and 7-301 of the Courts Article;</section><section prefix="(2)">money appropriated to the Fund under &#xA7; 11-401 of this subtitle;</section><section prefix="(3)">interest on attorney trust accounts paid to the Fund under &#xA7; 10-303 of the Business Occupations and Professions Article; and</section><section prefix="(4)">investment earnings of the Fund.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The Corporation shall use the Fund to provide funding for civil legal services to indigents under this title.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">The Treasurer shall:<section prefix="(1)">invest and reinvest the Fund in the same manner as other State funds; and</section><section prefix="(2)">credit any investment earnings to the Fund and may not charge interest against the Fund if the average daily net cash balance for the month is less than zero.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(g)">Expenditures from the Fund shall be made in accordance with an appropriation requested by the Judicial Branch of the State government under &#xA7; 7-108 of the State Finance and Procurement Article and approved by the General Assembly in the State budget or by the budget amendment procedure under &#xA7; 7-208.1 of the State Finance and Procurement Article.</section>
  </text>
</law>
