<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="ghu" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="9-402" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghu-9-402</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">A county, municipal corporation, for profit organization, or nonprofit organization sponsoring a project involving the planning, design, construction, conversion, acquisition, renovation, and equipping of a juvenile facility in the State may apply to the Department for a grant under this subtitle.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">An application shall be filed with the Department in the form the Department requires.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The applicant shall file with the Department a statement that includes:<section prefix="(i)">a list of the personnel employed or to be employed at the juvenile facility;</section><section prefix="(ii)">all compensation and other expenses paid or to be paid to the personnel;</section><section prefix="(iii)">all other expenses incurred or to be incurred in operating the juvenile facility; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">a schedule of rates charged or to be charged for services provided at the juvenile facility.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">If the Secretary approves the project and the project plans, the Secretary shall promptly:<section prefix="(1)">report the application to the Board of Public Works; and</section><section prefix="(2)">recommend that the Board make funds available as provided in this subtitle.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The amount of the State grant for a project shall be determined after considering:<section prefix="(1)">all eligible applications;</section><section prefix="(2)">the total of unallocated State funds available when the application is received; and</section><section prefix="(3)">the priorities of area need that the Department establishes.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
