<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghu" order_by="" level="1">Human Services</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghu-10-455</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>455</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">A provider may not collect deposits to provide continuing care at home services until the Department approves a feasibility study.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">A provider that intends to develop a continuing care at home program and provide continuing care at home services shall file a statement of intent with the Department at least 30 days before submitting the feasibility study required under this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A feasibility study shall:<section prefix="(1)">be filed in a form satisfactory to the Department; and</section><section prefix="(2)">include at least the following information:<section prefix="(i)">a statement of the purpose of the program and the need for the proposed services;</section><section prefix="(ii)">documentation of the financial resources of the provider;</section><section prefix="(iii)">a plan demonstrating the financial feasibility of the proposed program, including future funding sources;</section><section prefix="(iv)">an actuarial forecast that has been reviewed by a qualified actuary;</section><section prefix="(v)">a study demonstrating the proposed market for the program;</section><section prefix="(vi)">the form and substance of any proposed advertisements, advertising campaigns, or other promotional materials for the program that is available at the time of filing;</section><section prefix="(vii)">a detailed statement of the covered services; and</section><section prefix="(viii)">any other information that the Department requires.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Department shall approve a feasibility study filed under this section if the Department determines that:<section prefix="(1)">the proposed use of new or existing health facilities is not inconsistent with the State health plan;</section><section prefix="(2)">a reasonable financial plan has been developed to provide continuing care at home services, including the number of agreements to be executed before beginning operations and the criteria to release funds from escrow;</section><section prefix="(3)">a market for the continuing care at home program appears to exist;</section><section prefix="(4)">the feasibility study was prepared by a recognized authority;</section><section prefix="(5)">the provider has submitted all proposed advertisements, advertising campaigns, and other promotional materials for the program;</section><section prefix="(6)">the form and substance of all advertisements, advertising campaigns, and other promotional materials submitted are not deceptive, misleading, or likely to mislead;</section><section prefix="(7)">the actuarial forecast supports the market for the program;</section><section prefix="(8)">the approved escrow agreement and deposit agreement state the conditions for the release of deposits and entrance fees from escrow;</section><section prefix="(9)">a copy of the escrow agreement executed by the provider and the financial institution has been filed with the Department; and</section><section prefix="(10)">any other information requested by the Department has been submitted and approved.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
