<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="ghu" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="7-703" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghu-7-703</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, "Board" means the Board of Trustees of Blind Industries and Services of Maryland.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">There is a Board of Trustees that is a body corporate under the name of "Blind Industries and Services of Maryland".</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Board consists of 11 trustees appointed by the Governor with the advice and consent of the Senate.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Of the 11 trustees, at least 4 trustees shall be blind.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">From among its members, the Board shall elect a chair and a treasurer.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Board may elect another member to serve as chair if it is inconvenient or impossible for the regularly elected chair to serve.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The term of a member is 3 years.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The terms of members are staggered as required by the terms provided for members of the Board on October 1, 2007.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(f)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Governor shall fill a vacancy on the Board by appointment with the advice and consent of the Senate.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A member who is appointed after a term begins shall serve only for the rest of the term and until a successor is appointed and qualifies.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(g)">A trustee is entitled to:<section prefix="(1)">per diem compensation for each Board or committee meeting attended in accordance with the State budget; and</section><section prefix="(2)">reimbursement for expenses incurred in the performance of the trustee's duties under the Standard State Travel Regulations, as provided in the State budget.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(h)">The Board shall:<section prefix="(1)">maintain in Baltimore City a training and employment center for blind individuals;</section><section prefix="(2)">operate the Blind Industries and Services of Maryland for the labor and manufactures of all blind adult residents of the State who give satisfactory evidence of character and ability to do the work required;</section><section prefix="(3)">use the profits arising from the operation of the Blind Industries and Services of Maryland to further its mission;</section><section prefix="(4)">acquire suitable quarters in the State;</section><section prefix="(5)">keep proper records of its funds and accounts; and</section><section prefix="(6)">report annually to the Governor, and subject to &#xA7; 2-1246 of the State Government Article, the General Assembly, and the chair of the Joint Audit Committee on the condition and operations of the Blind Industries and Services of Maryland, including a thorough discussion of its programs and the participation of the blind community in these programs.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(i)">The Board may:<section prefix="(1)">apply that portion of the endowment fund and annual income that the Board considers expedient to establish training and employment centers in any part of the State and to open a store for the sale of articles manufactured by blind individuals;</section><section prefix="(2)">extend the benefits of the training and employment centers and the store to blind adults of the State who do not reside in institutions on any terms and under any regulations that the Board prescribes;</section><section prefix="(3)">generally supervise and control the training and employment centers;</section><section prefix="(4)">acquire and hold real, personal, and mixed property;</section><section prefix="(5)">sue and be sued;</section><section prefix="(6)">make, use, and alter a seal;</section><section prefix="(7)">appoint a corporate secretary and other necessary employees and set their compensation; and</section><section prefix="(8)">establish, maintain, direct, and supervise each matter concerning the Blind Industries and Services of Maryland, including the purchase of any machinery and materials that the Board considers suitable and necessary and the barter or exchange of articles or manufactures entrusted to the Board for disposal.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(j)">The Board shall be audited annually.</section>
  </text>
</law>
