<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="ghu" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="10-413" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghu-10-413</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Each year, within 120 days after the end of a provider's fiscal year, the provider shall file an application for a renewal certificate of registration in a form satisfactory to the Department.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A renewal application shall contain:<section prefix="(i)">any additions or changes to the information required by &#xA7;&#xA7; 10-408 through 10-410 of this subtitle;</section><section prefix="(ii)">an audited financial statement for the preceding fiscal year prepared in accordance with an audit guide that the Department adopts;</section><section prefix="(iii)">an operating budget for the current fiscal year and a projected operating budget for the next fiscal year;</section><section prefix="(iv)">a cash flow projection for the current fiscal year and the next two fiscal years;</section><section prefix="(v)">a projection of the life expectancy and the number of residents who will require nursing home care;</section><section prefix="(vi)">an actuarial study reviewed by a qualified actuary and submitted every 3 years, unless the provider is exempted from the requirement for an actuarial study by regulations adopted by the Department exempting categories of providers that the Department determines have substantially limited long-term care liability exposure;</section><section prefix="(vii)">the form and substance of any proposed advertisement, advertising campaign, or other promotional material not previously submitted to the Department; and</section><section prefix="(viii)">any further information that the Department requires.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Department may charge a late fee if the application and accompanying information are not received by the Department within 120 days after the end of the provider's fiscal year.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Failure to file the required information within 90 days after the due date is a violation of this subtitle.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Department shall issue a renewal certificate of registration if the Department determines that:<section prefix="(1)">the required documents have been filed;</section><section prefix="(2)">any revised continuing care agreements meet the requirements of this subtitle;</section><section prefix="(3)">if the provider has been found to be in financial difficulty, the provider has complied with Part VII of this subtitle;</section><section prefix="(4)">when appropriate, the facility has been licensed or certified by the Department of Health and Mental Hygiene or the Department; and</section><section prefix="(5)">the form and substance of all advertisements, advertising campaigns, and other promotional materials submitted to the Department are not deceptive, misleading, or likely to mislead.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
