<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghu" order_by="" level="1">Human Services</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghu-10-402</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>402</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A continuing care at home provider is subject to each provision of this subtitle except Part II and &#xA7;&#xA7; 10-446 and 10-448.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A continuing care in a retirement community provider is subject to each provision of this subtitle except Part VI.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A continuing care operation that is subject to the provisions of this  subtitle is not subject to:<section prefix="(i)">the Maryland Health Maintenance Organization Act under  Title 19, Subtitle 7 of the Health - General Article;</section><section prefix="(ii)">except for &#xA7; 15-603 of the Insurance Article, the Insurance  Article;</section><section prefix="(iii)">Title 8 of the Real Property Article;</section><section prefix="(iv)">any county or municipal landlord-tenant law; or</section><section prefix="(v)">&#xA7; 19-310.1 of the Health - General Article.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If a provider contractually utilizes the services of a licensed home health agency or residential service agency and is not itself directly providing the type of services provided by a home health agency or residential service agency, the provider is not subject to Title 19, Subtitles 4 and 4A of the Health - General Article.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Except as provided in paragraphs (1) and (2) of this subsection, a continuing care at home provider is subject to all other applicable licensing or certification requirements of State law.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">This subtitle does not apply to an agreement that is regulated as insurance under the Insurance Article.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A provider that offers assisted living program services as part of a continuum of care in accordance with a continuing care agreement may:<section prefix="(1)">execute a separate assisted living resident agreement and a separate assisted living disclosure statement; or</section><section prefix="(2)">meet the requirements of &#xA7;&#xA7; 10-425(c) and 10-444(e) of this subtitle.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The liability of a provider to the Department of Health and Mental Hygiene under &#xA7; 15-603 of the Insurance Article shall be limited to the amount of the refund that would be due to the subscriber if the subscriber were dismissed under &#xA7; 10-448 of this subtitle at the time of enrollment in services provided by or paid wholly or partly by the Department of Health and Mental Hygiene.</section>
  </text>
</law>
