<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghu" order_by="" level="1">Human Services</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghu-10-504</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>504</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Any federal grant that is received for a project shall be applied first to the cost of the project.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Except as provided in subsection (b) of this section, a State grant for a project may not exceed the lesser of $800,000 or 50% of the cost of eligible work remaining unpaid after any federal grant is applied.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A State grant to develop a master plan may not exceed the lesser of $15,000 or 50% of the cost of development of the plan.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Board of Public Works may authorize a grant for a project that exceeds 50% of the cost of eligible work remaining unpaid after any federal grant is applied, if:<section prefix="(1)">the project involves the conversion, acquisition, renovation, construction, or improvement of a building for use as a senior citizen activities center;</section><section prefix="(2)">the value of real property and existing improvements made available by the local government equals or exceeds the amount of the State grant; and</section><section prefix="(3)">the residual value of the real property and existing improvements made available by the local government exceeds the sum of:<section prefix="(i)">any prior amounts used for matching funds under this Program;</section><section prefix="(ii)">any outstanding State debt relating to the property from another program;</section><section prefix="(iii)">any prior grant under this Program; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">any other tangible State investment in the property.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The amount of a State grant for a project shall be determined after consideration of:<section prefix="(1)">the density of the senior population in the area affected by the project;</section><section prefix="(2)">the proximity of the proposed center to an existing senior citizen activities center; and</section><section prefix="(3)">other localities eligible for State funding that have not received previous funding under the Program or similar programs.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A grantee who received funds for a project under this subtitle or a prior act authorizing grants for senior citizen activities centers may receive additional grants for the project, but only in an amount that does not exceed the difference between the sum of any prior grants and the maximum funding allowable.</section>
  </text>
</law>
