<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghu" order_by="" level="1">Human Services</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghu-8-406</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>406</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Each local care team shall include:<section prefix="(1)">at least one representative from:<section prefix="(i)">the Department of Juvenile Services;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the Developmental Disabilities Administration;</section><section prefix="(iii)">the Alcohol and Drug Abuse Administration;</section><section prefix="(iv)">the Mental Hygiene Administration or the local core service agency;</section><section prefix="(v)">the local school system;</section><section prefix="(vi)">the local health department;</section><section prefix="(vii)">the local department of social services; and</section><section prefix="(viii)">the local management board;</section></section><section prefix="(2)">a parent, parent advocate, or both, appointed by the chair of the local care team in consultation with the child advocacy community; and</section><section prefix="(3)">a nonvoting representative of the local office of the division of rehabilitative services to represent individuals who are 16 years old and older.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Each local care team shall establish the terms of its members.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Each local care team shall select its chair from among its members for a designated term of office.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">Each local care team:<section prefix="(1)">shall determine which of its members will have responsibility for its administrative functions; and</section><section prefix="(2)">if two or more members will share the responsibility, shall determine the rotation of the administrative functions.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">Subject to the availability of funds, a parent or parent advocate who is a member of a local care team may receive:<section prefix="(1)">the compensation provided in the State or local budget; and</section><section prefix="(2)">reimbursement for expenses, in accordance with the Standard State Travel Regulations.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
