<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghu" order_by="ghu" level="1">Human Services</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghu-9-212</section_number>
  <catch_line>The State Advisory Board consists of the following 19 members appointed by the Governor:...</catch_line>
  <order_by>212</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The State Advisory Board consists of the following 19 members appointed by the Governor:<section prefix="(1)">one representative of the Department;</section><section prefix="(2)">one representative of the State Department of Education;</section><section prefix="(3)">one representative of the Department of Health and Mental Hygiene;</section><section prefix="(4)">one representative of the Department of State Police;</section><section prefix="(5)">one representative of the Social Services Administration of the Department of Human Resources;</section><section prefix="(6)">one representative of a private child welfare agency;</section><section prefix="(7)">one representative of a youth services bureau;</section><section prefix="(8)">three representatives of the State judiciary;</section><section prefix="(9)">one representative of the General Assembly recommended by the President of the Senate;</section><section prefix="(10)">one representative of the General Assembly recommended by the Speaker of the House; and</section><section prefix="(11)">seven members of the general public.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Of the seven members from the general public:<section prefix="(1)">three shall be chosen on the basis of their interest in and experience with minors and juvenile problems;</section><section prefix="(2)">three shall:<section prefix="(i)">at the time of appointment to a first term, be at least 16 years old and under the age of 25 years; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">include at least one individual who has been under the jurisdiction of the Department.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The term of a member is 3 years.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The terms of the members are staggered as required by the terms provided for members of the State Advisory Board on October 1, 2007.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">At the end of a term, a member continues to serve until a successor is appointed and qualifies.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">A member who is appointed after a term has begun serves only for the rest of the term and until a successor is appointed and qualifies.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">A member who serves two consecutive full 3-year terms may not be reappointed for 3 years after completion of those terms.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
