<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghu" order_by="ghu" level="1">Human Services</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghu-10-204</section_number>
  <catch_line>The Secretary shall administer the programs and activities that the federal government delegates to ...</catch_line>
  <order_by>204</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Secretary shall administer the programs and activities that the federal government delegates to the State under the Older Americans Act of 1965 that are not otherwise committed by law to another unit of State government.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Secretary:<section prefix="(1)">is a member of the Governor's Executive Council; and</section><section prefix="(2)">shall cooperate with and receive the cooperation of State, federal, and local governmental units to carry out the purposes of this title.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Secretary shall:<section prefix="(1)">evaluate the service needs of seniors in the State;</section><section prefix="(2)">determine the extent to which existing public and private programs meet the needs of seniors;</section><section prefix="(3)">establish priorities for meeting the needs of seniors;</section><section prefix="(4)">coordinate, subject to existing law, and assess and evaluate all State and local programs and services, both public and private, that relate and are important to the well-being of seniors in the State, including programs and services in the areas of:<section prefix="(i)">income maintenance;</section><section prefix="(ii)">public health;</section><section prefix="(iii)">mental health;</section><section prefix="(iv)">housing and urban development;</section><section prefix="(v)">employment;</section><section prefix="(vi)">education;</section><section prefix="(vii)">recreation; and</section><section prefix="(viii)">rehabilitation of seniors with physical or mental disabilities; and</section></section><section prefix="(5)">develop a statewide plan incorporating local plans for a comprehensive and coordinated system of health, social, and community services for seniors, including housing and institutional and noninstitutional care.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Secretary shall:<section prefix="(1)">represent the interests of seniors by serving as an advocate at all levels of government;</section><section prefix="(2)">consult with and advise the secretaries of the principal departments of State government about the programs and services for seniors that are the primary responsibility of those departments;</section><section prefix="(3)">consult with the Commission on Aging on all matters pertaining to programs for seniors;</section><section prefix="(4)">provide consultation and technical assistance to communities and civic groups developing local services for seniors;</section><section prefix="(5)">maintain a clearinghouse of information related to the interests of seniors; and</section><section prefix="(6)">review and recommend policies to the Governor on publicly funded plans and programs that affect seniors.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
