<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghu" order_by="ghu" level="1">Human Services</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghu-10-307</section_number>
  <catch_line>The Interagency Committee shall establish and coordinate a program to provide single points of entry...</catch_line>
  <order_by>307</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Interagency Committee shall establish and coordinate a program to provide single points of entry within each planning and service area.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Department shall supervise the program for the Interagency Committee.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Each area agency shall operate a single point of entry program to assess the needs of seniors and their caregivers and provide appropriate services.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The following services shall be provided through a single point of entry:<section prefix="(1)">providing current information on available programs, services, or benefits;</section><section prefix="(2)">determining the service needs of each senior who requests service;</section><section prefix="(3)">processing requests for service from seniors;</section><section prefix="(4)">through widely publicized local outreach facilities and communications systems, providing access to available public and private programs and services for seniors, including:<section prefix="(i)">transportation services;</section><section prefix="(ii)">health and nutrition services;</section><section prefix="(iii)">financial assistance;</section><section prefix="(iv)">social services;</section><section prefix="(v)">educational services;</section><section prefix="(vi)">services available through volunteer organizations or private agencies;</section><section prefix="(vii)">appropriate housing arrangements;</section><section prefix="(viii)">health insurance counseling;</section><section prefix="(ix)">employment and volunteer opportunities;</section><section prefix="(x)">respite care services; and</section><section prefix="(xi)">other programs, information, counseling, or benefits for seniors;</section></section><section prefix="(5)">monitoring the outcome of requests for service or information; and</section><section prefix="(6)">arranging with other agencies for individual assessment to determine the service needs of a frail or health-impaired senior.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">To the extent possible, each single point of entry shall be:<section prefix="(1)">located in a senior citizen center; and</section><section prefix="(2)">available for access at least 5 days a week.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">Local interagency committees on services to seniors shall make agreements among themselves and with other agencies to provide staff on a regular basis at the single points of entry to:<section prefix="(1)">provide information and services to seniors; and</section><section prefix="(2)">administer agency programs.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
