<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghu" order_by="ghu" level="1">Human Services</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghu-5-408</section_number>
  <catch_line>An applicant or recipient may appeal to the Administration if the local department:...</catch_line>
  <order_by>408</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">An applicant or recipient may appeal to the Administration if the local department:<section prefix="(1)">does not act on an application within a reasonable time;</section><section prefix="(2)">denies an application wholly or partly; or</section><section prefix="(3)">modifies or cancels a grant of assistance.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The appeal shall be filed in the manner and form that the Administration requires.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Administration shall give the applicant or recipient reasonable notice and an opportunity for a hearing on the appeal.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">On its own motion, the Administration may:<section prefix="(i)">review any decision of a local department; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">consider an application on which the local department has not made a decision within a reasonable time.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Administration:<section prefix="(i)">may make any additional investigation it considers necessary; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">shall make any decision on the granting of assistance and the amount of assistance it considers justified in accordance with this part.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">On request, the Administration shall give an applicant or recipient affected by a decision made under paragraph (2) of this subsection reasonable notice and an opportunity for a hearing.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A decision of the Administration under this section is final and binding on the local department.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The local department shall comply with a decision of the Administration under this section.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
