<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghu" order_by="ghu" level="1">Human Services</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghu-10-211</section_number>
  <catch_line>In this section, "assisted living program" has the meaning stated in &#xA7; 19-1801 of the Health - Gene...</catch_line>
  <order_by>211</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">In this section, "assisted living program" has the meaning stated in &#xA7; 19-1801 of the Health - General Article.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Secretary shall develop assisted living programs for seniors in conjunction with:<section prefix="(1)">public or private for profit or nonprofit corporations; or</section><section prefix="(2)">State or federal units.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Secretary shall:<section prefix="(i)">make maximum use of rent and other subsidies available from federal and State sources; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">provide for and set, by regulation, the amount of subsidies necessary from State general funds to assist low-income seniors to reside in assisted living programs as an alternative to more costly institutional care that is not required.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Subsidies under paragraph (1)(ii) of this subsection may include, when necessary and in accordance with available funds, monthly subsidies for residents of assisted living programs whose adjusted gross annual income is less than their cost of care for assisted living services.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">When necessary and in accordance with available funds, the Secretary shall provide subsidies for congregate meals, housekeeping, and personal services for assisted living programs and develop eligibility requirements for these subsidies.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The Secretary shall adopt regulations to govern eligibility requirements for subsidies.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Secretary shall:<section prefix="(1)">find sponsors for assisted living programs; and</section><section prefix="(2)">assist developers in formulating design concepts and meeting program needs.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The Secretary shall review the compliance of assisted living programs with the regulations that the Secretary of Health and Mental Hygiene adopts for licensing these programs to operate in the State.</section>
  </text>
</law>
