<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghu" order_by="" level="1">Human Services</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghu-10-465</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>465</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Committee consists of seven members appointed by the Secretary.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Of the seven members:<section prefix="(i)">two shall be knowledgeable in the field of continuing care;</section><section prefix="(ii)">two shall be certified public accountants;</section><section prefix="(iii)">one shall be from the financial community; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">two shall be consumer members.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">In appointing the consumer members, the Secretary shall give a preference to subscribers of continuing care facilities.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The term of a member is 3 years.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The terms of members are staggered as required by the terms provided for members on October 1, 2007.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A member may serve consecutive terms.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Committee shall elect its chair.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">A member:<section prefix="(1)">may not receive compensation as a member of the Committee; but</section><section prefix="(2)">is entitled to reimbursement for expenses under the Standard State Travel Regulations, as provided in the State budget.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">A member is immune from civil liability as provided in &#xA7; 5-514 of the Courts Article.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">A member may not participate in a review of a provider's financial condition if that member has an interest, as defined under the Maryland Public Ethics Law in &#xA7; 15-102 of the State Government Article, in the provider.</section>
    <section prefix="(g)">The deliberations of the Committee and communications between the Department and the Committee, including recommendations of the Committee, shall be confidential.</section>
  </text>
</law>
