<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghu" order_by="" level="1">Human Services</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghu-5-309</section_number>
  <catch_line>...</catch_line>
  <order_by>309</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">Except for an applicant or recipient who is a single child, the FIP shall include:<section prefix="(1)">an assessment of each applicant or recipient that considers:<section prefix="(i)">the reasons for applying for or continuing to rely on assistance;</section><section prefix="(ii)">an evaluation of appropriate work activities based on educational level, job skills and readiness, and interests; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">personal and family resources available to facilitate independence; and</section></section><section prefix="(2)">welfare avoidance grants that:<section prefix="(i)">meet immediate needs so that an applicant or recipient can avoid temporary cash assistance;</section><section prefix="(ii)">may be granted as the Department considers appropriate;</section><section prefix="(iii)">may not cover the same type of immediate need met by a previous welfare avoidance grant unless the Department determines that the current immediate need is a new and verified emergency;</section><section prefix="(iv)">do not exceed an amount of 3 months of temporary cash assistance, unless the Department determines there is a compelling need for an amount not exceeding 12 months; and</section><section prefix="(v)">may not duplicate periods of temporary cash assistance.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Except for a recipient who is a single child, the FIP for a recipient shall include:<section prefix="(1)">an agreement between the Department and the recipient that:<section prefix="(i)">requires the recipient to cooperate with the child support enforcement agency to obtain support from a noncustodial parent;</section><section prefix="(ii)">requires the recipient to comply with reasonable requests for cooperation by case management workers in seeking and using programs and community and family resources that may be available to the recipient;</section><section prefix="(iii)">specifies the work activities in which the recipient will participate; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">specifies the supportive services that the local department will assist in providing and that are necessary for the recipient to meet the recipient's obligations under the FIP;</section></section><section prefix="(2)">supportive services activities, including child care, to the extent resources allow;</section><section prefix="(3)">referral, as appropriate, to family planning counseling and services that:<section prefix="(i)">are not offered or conducted in a manner that:<section prefix="1.">is coercive;</section><section prefix="2.">violates the recipient's confidentiality; or</section><section prefix="3.">violates the recipient's bona fide religious beliefs and practices; and</section></section><section prefix="(ii)">give preference to eligible teen parents; and</section></section><section prefix="(4)">temporary cash assistance, as a last resort.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">Except for an applicant who is a single child, the FIP for an applicant shall include a child care voucher:<section prefix="(1)">to the extent resources allow, if the applicant is required to participate in a work activity as a condition of eligibility; or</section><section prefix="(2)">if providing child care eliminates the applicant's need for cash assistance under the FIP.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">For an applicant or recipient who is a single child, the FIP shall include:<section prefix="(1)">referral to appropriate services; and</section><section prefix="(2)">temporary cash assistance for the recipient, as a last resort.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">To the extent resources allow, the FIP shall serve noncustodial parents who need employment services to pay child support obligations.</section>
  </text>
</law>
