<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghu" order_by="ghu" level="1">Human Services</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghu-10-428</section_number>
  <catch_line>A provider shall establish an internal grievance procedure to address a subscriber's grievance....</catch_line>
  <order_by>428</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">A provider shall establish an internal grievance procedure to address a subscriber's grievance.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The internal grievance procedure shall at least:<section prefix="(1)">allow a subscriber or group of subscribers collectively to submit a written grievance to the provider;</section><section prefix="(2)">require the provider to send a written acknowledgment to the subscriber or group of subscribers within 5 days after receipt of the written grievance;</section><section prefix="(3)">require the provider to assign personnel to investigate the grievance;</section><section prefix="(4)">give a subscriber or group of subscribers who file a written grievance the right to meet with management of the provider within 30 days after receipt of the written grievance to present the grievance; and</section><section prefix="(5)">require the provider to respond in writing within 45 days after receipt of the written grievance regarding the investigation and resolution of the grievance.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Within 30 days after the conclusion of an internal grievance procedure established under this section, a subscriber, group of subscribers, or provider may seek mediation through one of the Community Mediation Centers in the State or another mediation provider.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If a provider, subscriber, or group of subscribers seeks mediation under paragraph (1) of this subsection:<section prefix="(i)">the mediation shall be nonbinding; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">the provider, subscriber, or group of subscribers may not be represented by counsel.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
