<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="ghu" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="10-489" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghu-10-489</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If on issuance of an order of liquidation under this subtitle or at any time during a liquidation proceeding the provider is not clearly solvent, the court, after notice it considers proper and a hearing, shall issue an order that the provider is an impaired provider.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Notwithstanding any previous notice given to creditors, after issuance of an order under paragraph (1) of this subsection, the Secretary shall notify each person that may have a claim against the provider that the claim is forever barred unless the person files the claim with the Secretary at a place and within the time specified in the notice.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The time specified in the notice:<section prefix="(i)">shall be as set by the court for filing claims; but</section><section prefix="(ii)">may not be less than 6 months after issuance of the order that the provider is an impaired provider.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The notice shall be given in the manner and for the reasonable period of time that the court orders.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Each claimant shall set forth in reasonable detail:<section prefix="(i)">the amount of the claim or the basis on which the amount can be determined;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the facts on which the claim is based; and</section><section prefix="(iii)">any priority asserted by the claimant.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Each claim shall:<section prefix="(i)">be verified by the affidavit of the claimant or a person authorized to act on behalf of the claimant who has knowledge of the facts; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">be supported by any documents that may be material to the claim.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(3)">Each claim shall be filed with the receiver in the State on or before the last date specified under this subtitle for filing of claims.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The receiver shall:<section prefix="(1)">report a claim to the court:<section prefix="(i)">within 10 days after receiving the claim; or</section><section prefix="(ii)">within an additional period set by the court for good cause shown; and</section></section><section prefix="(2)">recommend in the report action to be taken on the claim.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">On receipt of the report of the receiver, the court shall:<section prefix="(i)">set a time for hearing the claim; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">direct the claimant or receiver to give notice as the court determines to each person that appears to the court to be interested in the claim.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The notice given in accordance with this subsection shall:<section prefix="(i)">specify the time and place of the hearing; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">state concisely:</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">
      <section prefix="(1)">At the hearing specified under subsection (d) of this section:<section prefix="(i)">each person with an interest in the claim may appear; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">the court shall issue an order in which the court allows in part, or disallows the claim.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">An order under this subsection is a final order subject to appeal.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
