<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghu" order_by="ghu" level="1">Human Services</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghu-9-229</section_number>
  <catch_line>The Department shall operate and manage the Baltimore City Juvenile Justice Center as a centralized ...</catch_line>
  <order_by>229</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Department shall operate and manage the Baltimore City Juvenile Justice Center as a centralized regional juvenile intake, assessment, court, and detention facility for Baltimore City.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Baltimore City Juvenile Justice Center shall include:<section prefix="(1)">the Department;</section><section prefix="(2)">the Juvenile Division of the Circuit Court for Baltimore City;</section><section prefix="(3)">an office of the State's Attorney for Baltimore City;</section><section prefix="(4)">an office of the Baltimore City Department of Social Services;</section><section prefix="(5)">Baltimore City police services; and</section><section prefix="(6)">courthouse security services of the Sheriff of Baltimore City.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">If a child who is delinquent or is alleged to have committed a delinquent act is taken into custody by a law enforcement officer and brought to the Baltimore City Juvenile Justice Center, the Department, in conjunction with Baltimore City police services, shall:<section prefix="(1)">for purposes of positive identification, obtain photographs and fingerprints and submit them to:<section prefix="(i)">the Criminal Justice Information System Central Repository; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">any other automated juvenile justice information system or repository approved by the Secretary;</section></section><section prefix="(2)">conduct a criminal and juvenile history records check; and</section><section prefix="(3)">conduct an automated search for outstanding warrants and writs of attachment.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">After the processing of fingerprints, the Criminal Justice Information System Central Repository shall provide to the Department, in accordance with State and federal law, information concerning children taken into custody under subsection (c) of this section.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Information concerning a child disseminated from the Criminal Justice Information System Central Repository is a police record under &#xA7; 10-101(h) of the Criminal Procedure Article and may not be redisseminated except in accordance with &#xA7; 3-8A-27(a) of the Courts Article.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">Subject to the authority of the Secretary:<section prefix="(1)">the managing director of the Baltimore City Juvenile Justice Center is its chief administrator; and</section><section prefix="(2)">the director of detention of the Baltimore City Juvenile Justice Center is its administrator of juvenile detention.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
