<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="ghu" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="5-205" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghu-5-205</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Administration shall be the central coordinating and directing agency of all public assistance programs in the State, including:<section prefix="(1)">the Family Investment Program and related cash benefit programs;</section><section prefix="(2)">public assistance to adults;</section><section prefix="(3)">emergency assistance;</section><section prefix="(4)">food stamps;</section><section prefix="(5)">medical assistance eligibility determinations;</section><section prefix="(6)">the Energy Assistance Program; and</section><section prefix="(7)">any other public assistance activities financed wholly or partly by the Administration.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Administration shall supervise, direct, and control the activities of the local departments that it finances wholly or partly.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Administration may visit any State-aided institution, organization, or agency engaged in public assistance activities and inspect thoroughly its management, buildings, and equipment.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Visits and inspections under paragraph (1) of this subsection shall be made:<section prefix="(i)">at reasonably convenient hours; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">with reasonable regard for the established discipline, regulations, and customs of the institution, organization, or agency.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">As desirable or necessary for the purpose of this title, the Administration may designate existing agencies or organizations in the State as the Administration's agents.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">Before the start of each regular session of the General Assembly, the Administration shall submit a report of its activities to the Governor.</section>
  </text>
</law>
