<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghu" order_by="ghu" level="1">Human Services</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghu-8-1103</section_number>
  <catch_line>There is an Advisory Board on After-School and Summer Opportunity programs in the Program....</catch_line>
  <order_by>1103</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">There is an Advisory Board on After-School and Summer Opportunity programs in the Program.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The Advisory Board shall consist of the following individuals:<section prefix="(1)">the Governor or the Governor's designee;</section><section prefix="(2)">the President of the Senate of Maryland or the President's designee;</section><section prefix="(3)">the Speaker of the House of Delegates of Maryland or the Speaker's designee;</section><section prefix="(4)">the State Superintendent of Schools or the Superintendent's designee;</section><section prefix="(5)">the Secretaries of Health and Mental Hygiene, Juvenile Services, and Human Resources or their designees;</section><section prefix="(6)">the Special Secretary of the Governor's Office for Children or the Special Secretary's designee;</section><section prefix="(7)">one representative of the Office of Crime Control and Prevention designated by the Governor; and</section><section prefix="(8)">seventeen individuals serving 2-year terms, to be appointed by the Governor, as follows:<section prefix="(i)">two members who represent the children's advocacy community;</section><section prefix="(ii)">two members of the after-school provider community who represent providers not included in item (vii) of this item;</section><section prefix="(iii)">two members who are parents of students enrolled in the State in kindergarten through grade 12;</section><section prefix="(iv)">two members who are students enrolled in the State in grades 6 through 12;</section><section prefix="(v)">one teacher who is working in a school in the State;</section><section prefix="(vi)">one member who represents the statewide network of child care resource and referral centers;</section><section prefix="(vii)">one member who represents the statewide alliance of licensed school age child care providers;</section><section prefix="(viii)">one member of a local management board;</section><section prefix="(ix)">one member of a local board of education;</section><section prefix="(x)">one member who is a professional in the field of recreation and parks that delivers after-school and summer programs;</section><section prefix="(xi)">one member who represents the concerns of disabled children;</section><section prefix="(xii)">one member who represents the Office of Child Care in the State Department of Education; and</section><section prefix="(xiii)">one member who represents the Department of Disabilities.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">
      <section prefix="(1)">There is an Executive Committee of the Advisory Board.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Executive Committee consists of the following individuals:<section prefix="(i)">the Governor or the Governor's designee;</section><section prefix="(ii)">the Secretary of Human Resources or the Secretary's designee;</section><section prefix="(iii)">the State Superintendent of Schools or the Superintendent's designee;</section><section prefix="(iv)">the Secretary of Juvenile Services or the Secretary's designee;</section><section prefix="(v)">the Secretary of Health and Mental Hygiene or the Secretary's designee; and</section><section prefix="(vi)">the Special Secretary of the Governor's Office for Children or the Special Secretary's designee.</section></section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Governor shall serve as the chair of the Advisory Board and of the Executive Committee.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The Governor may designate the Lieutenant Governor or one of the secretaries serving on the Advisory Committee and the Executive Committee to act as chair in the Governor's absence.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The Advisory Board shall develop a strategy to provide technical assistance through the Maryland Out of School Time Network.</section>
  </text>
</law>
