<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="ghu" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="10-903" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghu-10-903</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">There is an Office of the Long-Term Care Ombudsman in the Department.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Unless the Secretary is subject to a conflict of interest that cannot be removed, the Secretary shall select a State Long-Term Care Ombudsman.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If the Secretary is subject to a conflict of interest that cannot be removed, the Secretary shall designate another individual, who is not subject to a conflict of interest, to select the State Long-Term Care Ombudsman.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The State Long-Term Care Ombudsman:<section prefix="(1)">shall personally administer the Office;</section><section prefix="(2)">shall have expertise and experience in the field of long-term care advocacy;</section><section prefix="(3)">may not have any conflict of interest with the position; and</section><section prefix="(4)">shall, on a full-time basis, perform duties related to the Program.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The State Long-Term Care Ombudsman shall personally or through designated ombudsmen:<section prefix="(1)">identify, investigate, and resolve complaints from any source made by, or on behalf of, a resident relating to any action, inaction, or decision, that may adversely affect the health, safety, welfare, or rights of a resident including the welfare and rights of residents with respect to the appointment and activities of guardians and representative payees, of:<section prefix="(i)">a provider, or a representative of a provider, of long-term care services;</section><section prefix="(ii)">a public agency; or</section><section prefix="(iii)">a health or social service agency;</section></section><section prefix="(2)">represent the interests of residents before governmental agencies and seek administrative, legal, and other remedies to protect the health, safety, welfare, and rights of residents;</section><section prefix="(3)">provide information as appropriate to other agencies and the public regarding the problems and concerns of residents;</section><section prefix="(4)">inform residents, family members, and others acting on behalf of residents about how to access the assistance and services of the Office and the services and assistance of other providers or agencies, including legal services;</section><section prefix="(5)">ensure regular and timely access to and response from the Office;</section><section prefix="(6)">comment on, facilitate public comment on, and recommend changes to existing or proposed laws, rules, regulations, and other governmental policies and actions that affect the health, safety, welfare, and rights of residents;</section><section prefix="(7)">provide technical support for the development of resident and family councils to protect the well-being and rights of residents;</section><section prefix="(8)">provide for the education and training of ombudsmen;</section><section prefix="(9)">educate facilities, agencies, and staff members concerning the rights and welfare of residents;</section><section prefix="(10)">promote the development of citizen organizations to advocate for the well-being and rights of residents;</section><section prefix="(11)">provide services to assist residents in protecting the health, safety, welfare, and rights of residents; and</section><section prefix="(12)">carry out any other activities that the Secretary determines to be appropriate or that are required by the federal Older Americans Act.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
