<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghu" order_by="ghu" level="1">Human Services</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghu-10-306</section_number>
  <catch_line>The Interagency Committee shall develop and update annually a plan for providing coordinated health ...</catch_line>
  <order_by>306</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Interagency Committee shall develop and update annually a plan for providing coordinated health services, social services, transportation, housing, and employment services to seniors in the State consistent with the priorities that the Department establishes.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If the members of the Interagency Committee cannot agree on a plan, the chair shall refer the matter to the Governor for resolution.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Annually on or before a date that the Governor sets, the Interagency Committee shall develop and present to the Governor and the General Assembly a consolidated operating budget for services to seniors that:<section prefix="(1)">sets forth the relevant portions of the operating budget of any unit responsible for services to seniors; and</section><section prefix="(2)">is consistent with the plan developed under subsection (a) of this section.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Interagency Committee shall establish interagency agreements and adopt regulations to:<section prefix="(1)">implement and coordinate services to seniors consistent with the plan developed under subsection (a) of this section;</section><section prefix="(2)">maximize the sharing of resources among units of State government for services to seniors;</section><section prefix="(3)">consolidate planning and evaluation efforts at the State and local levels; and</section><section prefix="(4)">coordinate and expedite the delivery of services to seniors by providing technical assistance to local agencies.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Interagency Committee shall assist county agencies to establish local interagency committees composed of:<section prefix="(i)">the directors of the local health department, local department of social services, and area agency; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">officials from housing, transportation, mental health, employment, and economic development agencies.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Local interagency committees shall coordinate and expedite the delivery of services to seniors at the local level.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
