<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="ghu" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="10-408" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghu-10-408</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">A provider shall comply with the applicable provisions of &#xA7;&#xA7; 10-409 through 10-415 of this subtitle before the provider may:<section prefix="(1)">offer continuing care in a retirement community;</section><section prefix="(2)">enter into or renew continuing care agreements;</section><section prefix="(3)">begin construction of a new facility;</section><section prefix="(4)">begin construction of an expansion to or renovation of an existing facility; or</section><section prefix="(5)">collect deposits for continuing care in this State.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">A new capital addition to a facility that will result in the construction of a number of independent and assisted living units that is greater than 25% of the number of existing units is considered new development and is subject to &#xA7;&#xA7; 10-409 through 10-411 of this subtitle.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">A new capital addition to a facility that does not involve the construction of independent or assisted living units and that does not meet the standard of &#xA7; 10-401(l)(1)(ii) of this subtitle is not subject to review by the Department under &#xA7;&#xA7; 10-409 through 10-415 of this subtitle.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">A capital improvement or replacement that does not meet the standard of &#xA7; 10-401(w) of this subtitle is not subject to review by the Department under &#xA7;&#xA7; 10-409 through 10-415 of this subtitle.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A provider that has more than one facility offering continuing care shall make a separate application for each facility for preliminary, initial, and renewal certificates of registration.</section>
  </text>
</law>
