<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="ghu" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="8-903" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghu-8-903</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">A county, municipal corporation, or nonprofit organization sponsoring a project involving work specified in &#xA7; 8-902 of this subtitle may apply to the Executive Director for a State grant to be applied toward the cost of that project.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">An application for a grant shall include:<section prefix="(1)">project plans for the work to be carried out;</section><section prefix="(2)">a statement listing the personnel employed or to be employed at the residential child care program, including all compensation for personnel services and all other expenses paid or to be paid to the personnel;</section><section prefix="(3)">all other expenses incurred or to be incurred in operating the residential child care program; and</section><section prefix="(4)">a statement describing how the residential child care program will provide services in an underserved geographic area of the State, as identified by the Office.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">An applicant may amend the project plans submitted with its application during or after the grant application process if the amendments are:<section prefix="(1)">intended to meet the changing needs of the residential child care program or its residents; and</section><section prefix="(2)">approved by the Executive Director.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">On approval of a project and the project plans, the Executive Director shall:<section prefix="(1)">promptly report the application to the Board of Public Works; and</section><section prefix="(2)">recommend that the Board make funds available as provided in this subtitle.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The amount of the State grant recommended to the Board of Public Works for a project shall be determined after consideration of:<section prefix="(1)">all eligible projects;</section><section prefix="(2)">the total of unallocated State funds available at the time the grant recommendation is made to the Board of Public Works; and</section><section prefix="(3)">the priorities established by the Office regarding geographic areas of the State identified as underserved by residential child care programs.</section></section>
  </text>
</law>
