<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="ghu" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="9-237" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghu-9-237</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">The Department shall adopt regulations that set standards for juvenile detention facilities operated by the Department and by private agencies under contract with the Department.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">The standards shall reflect the following central purposes of juvenile detention:<section prefix="(1)">to protect the public;</section><section prefix="(2)">to provide a safe, humane, and caring environment for children; and</section><section prefix="(3)">to provide access to required services for children.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The standards shall include provisions establishing:<section prefix="(1)">a policy that eliminates the unnecessary use of detention and that prioritizes diversion and appropriate nonsecure alternatives;</section><section prefix="(2)">criteria for the placement of a child in a particular juvenile detention facility;</section><section prefix="(3)">population limits for each juvenile detention facility that may not be exceeded except in emergency circumstances;</section><section prefix="(4)">a requirement that staffing ratios and levels of services be maintained during emergencies;</section><section prefix="(5)">specifications for the architectural structure of a juvenile detention facility;</section><section prefix="(6)">staff qualifications and training, including training in recognizing and reporting child abuse and neglect;</section><section prefix="(7)">the ratio of staff to children in a juvenile detention facility;</section><section prefix="(8)">the rights of children in a juvenile detention facility, including the right to privacy, visitors, telephone use, and mail delivery;</section><section prefix="(9)">prohibitions against the use of excessive force against a child; and</section><section prefix="(10)">internal auditing and monitoring of programs and facilities in the juvenile services system.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The standards shall be consistent with this title and Title 3, Subtitle 8A of the Courts Article.</section>
  </text>
</law>
