<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="ghu" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="3-501" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghu-3-501</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">This section does not apply in Baltimore City.</section>
    <section prefix="(b)">Each local department shall have a local board.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">A local board consists of at least 9 but no more than 13 members as provided by local law enacted by the local governing authority.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">On July 1 of each year, each local governing authority shall designate one member of the local governing authority to serve as an ex officio member of the local board.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">The other members of the local board shall be appointed by the local governing authority.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">The local governing authority shall seek out and appoint individuals who:</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(e)">On July 1 of each year, each local board shall select a chairman.</section>
    <section prefix="(f)">A member of a local board:<section prefix="(1)">may not receive compensation; but</section><section prefix="(2)">is entitled to reimbursement for expenses under the Standard State Travel Regulations, as provided in the State budget.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(g)">
      <section prefix="(1)">
        <section prefix="(i)"/>
        <section prefix="(ii)">A term expires on June 30 of the year of expiration.</section>
        <section prefix="(iii)">At the end of a term, a member continues to serve until a successor is appointed.</section>
        <section prefix="(iv)">Once an appointed member of a local board serves two consecutive full terms, the member is ineligible for reappointment for a period of 1 year.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If a vacancy occurs during the term of a member, the local governing authority shall appoint or designate a successor to serve for the remainder of the term.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(h)">If a member of a local board fails to attend at least 50% of the local board's meetings during a period of twelve consecutive months:<section prefix="(1)">the member may be considered to have resigned; and</section><section prefix="(2)">the chairman may declare that a vacancy exists.</section></section>
    <section prefix="(i)">
      <section prefix="(1)">This subsection does not apply to an ex officio member of a local board.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">If a member of a local board is elected or appointed to political or public office:<section prefix="(i)">the local governing authority may consider the member to have resigned; and</section><section prefix="(ii)">the chairman shall declare that a vacancy exists.</section></section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
