<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="article" identifier="ghu" order_by="ghu" level="1">Human Services</unit>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghu-7-116</section_number>
  <catch_line>On or before July 1 of each year, each unit of State government shall develop a unit plan to impleme...</catch_line>
  <order_by>116</order_by>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">On or before July 1 of each year, each unit of State government shall develop a unit plan to implement the State Disabilities Plan as approved or amended by the Secretary under &#xA7; 7-113(e) of this subtitle.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The unit plan shall contain an implementation schedule and measurable strategic performance objectives.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The Secretary may request amendments to a unit plan if the Secretary determines that the unit plan does not comply with the State Disabilities Plan.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">On or before July 1 of each year, each unit of State government shall provide the Department with an evaluation of the unit's performance in accordance with the unit's plan developed under subsection (a) of this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The evaluation required under subsection (b) of this section shall:<section prefix="(1)">assess the unit's performance against the strategic performance objectives established under subsection (a)(2) of this section; and</section><section prefix="(2)">identify and measure:<section prefix="(i)">consumer satisfaction;</section><section prefix="(ii)">gaps in services;</section><section prefix="(iii)">numbers of individuals waiting for services; and</section><section prefix="(iv)">progress made on achieving performance objectives.</section></section></section>
    <section prefix="(d)">The Secretary may provide technical assistance to any unit of State government to meet the requirements of this section.</section>
    <section prefix="(e)">The Secretary may waive the requirements of this section for any unit of State government.</section>
  </text>
</law>
