<?xml version="1.0"?>
<law>
  <structure>
    <unit label="title" identifier="ghu" order_by="" level="1"/>
    <unit label="chapter" identifier="9-312" order_by="" level="2"/>
  </structure>
  <section_number>ghu-9-312</section_number>
  <catch_line/>
  <text>
    <section prefix="(a)">
      <section prefix="(1)">Once effective, the Compact shall continue in force and remain binding upon each and every compacting state; provided that a compacting state may withdraw from the Compact by specifically repealing the statute which enacted the Compact into law.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">The effective date of withdrawal is the effective date of the repeal.</section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The withdrawing state shall immediately notify the chairperson of the Interstate Commission in writing upon the introduction of legislation repealing this Compact in the withdrawing state. The Interstate Commission shall notify the other compacting states of the withdrawing state's intent to withdraw within 60 days of its receipt thereof.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The withdrawing state is responsible for all assessments, obligations, and liabilities incurred through the effective date of withdrawal, including any obligations, the performance of which extend beyond the effective date of withdrawal.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">Reinstatement following withdrawal of any compacting state shall occur upon the withdrawing state reenacting the Compact or upon such later date as determined by the Interstate Commission.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(b)">
      <section prefix="(1)">If the Interstate Commission determines that any compacting state has at any time defaulted in the performance of any of its obligations or responsibilities under this Compact, or the bylaws or duly promulgated rules, the Interstate Commission may impose any or all of the following penalties:<section prefix="(i)">remedial training and technical assistance as directed by the Interstate Commission;</section><section prefix="(ii)">alternative dispute resolution;</section><section prefix="(iii)">fines, fees, and costs in such amounts as are deemed to be reasonable as fixed by the Interstate Commission; or</section><section prefix="(iv)">suspension or termination of membership in the Compact.</section></section>
      <section prefix="(2)">
        <section prefix="(i)">Suspension shall be imposed only after all other reasonable means of securing compliance under the bylaws and rules have been exhausted and the Interstate Commission has determined the offending state is in default.</section>
        <section prefix="(ii)">Immediate notice of suspension shall be given by the Interstate Commission to the governor, the chief justice or the chief judicial officer of the state, the majority and minority leaders of the defaulting state's legislature, and the State Council.</section>
      </section>
      <section prefix="(3)">The grounds for default include, but are not limited to, failure of a compacting state to perform such obligations or responsibilities imposed upon it by this Compact, the bylaws, or duly promulgated rules and any other grounds designated in Commission bylaws and rules.</section>
      <section prefix="(4)">The Interstate Commission shall immediately notify the defaulting state in writing of the penalty imposed by the Interstate Commission and of the default pending a cure of the default. The Commission shall stipulate the conditions and the time period within which the defaulting state must cure its default. If the defaulting state fails to cure the default within the time period specified by the Commission, the defaulting state shall be terminated from the Compact upon an affirmative vote of a majority of the compacting states and all rights, privileges, and benefits conferred by this Compact shall be terminated from the effective date of termination.  Within 60 days of the effective date of termination of a defaulting state, the Commission shall notify the governor, the chief justice or chief judicial officer, the majority and minority leaders of the defaulting state's legislature, and the State Council of such termination.</section>
      <section prefix="(5)">The defaulting state is responsible for all assessments, obligations, and liabilities incurred through the effective date of termination including any obligations, the performance of which extends beyond the effective date of termination.</section>
      <section prefix="(6)">The Interstate Commission shall not bear any costs relating to the defaulting state unless otherwise mutually agreed upon in writing between the Interstate Commission and the defaulting state.</section>
      <section prefix="(7)">Reinstatement following termination of any compacting state requires both a reenactment of the Compact by the defaulting state and the approval of the Interstate Commission pursuant to the rules.</section>
    </section>
    <section prefix="(c)">The Interstate Commission may, by majority vote of the members, initiate legal action in the United States District Court for the District of Columbia or, at the discretion of the Interstate Commission, in the federal district where the Interstate Commission has its offices, to enforce compliance with the provisions of the Compact, its duly promulgated rules and bylaws, against any compacting state in default. In the event judicial enforcement is necessary, the prevailing party shall be awarded all costs of such litigation including reasonable attorneys' fees.</section>
    <section prefix="(d)">
      <section prefix="(1)">The Compact dissolves effective upon the date of the withdrawal or default of the compacting state, which reduces membership in the Compact to one compacting state.</section>
      <section prefix="(2)">Upon dissolution of this Compact, the Compact becomes null and void and shall be of no further force or effect, and the business and affairs of the Interstate Commission shall be concluded and any surplus funds shall be distributed in accordance with the bylaws.</section>
    </section>
  </text>
</law>
